no way
really is saying
this application should be able to access this file to another
design of this system was in the mainframe operating system back in the nineteen sixties
but sort of disappeared someone simple
so we want things again semantics so that's my website was trying to write the
password file something bad has happened even if the mission saying that i really like
not happen
and to be able to constrain things build models what service are expected to access
to the act as anything else
no it's not going to happen
and a of
stuff was done fast locking
because parallelism is great to spend all your time
trying to stop two friends doing the wrong thing at the same moment
so some might be empty people
and rusty russell created think for taxes
which is the whole thing is the basis of the post lock
that's nice about the
you can't just look at the current on its
and the idea behind this basically
just have law which you can take entirely in user space
where there is no contention
so thank make
system calls saying this look at some of the law
at the same time you want to be able to sleep
the lock is in use
that's hard to do entirely useful
because user space don't have enough information
so the way the way these locks were used
new space you take a lot
but if you fail to play a lot
there is a kernel space public
he worked with the space
which then deals with the weighting case and the like
the security which is what is really interesting thing which is persuaded particularly business better
is the notion of liability
the notion that you might actually be your fault if you don't secure systems
this has led to remarkable in rest the management level systems which are actually secure
system which pretend to be sick
unfortunately for the rest of the world sales one of the very good at telling
management people things ask you would not
going with that we see system which fails site
so the practice on especially if this does go wrong
can really make it go wrong in
preferred manner
there's a lot of interesting compartmentalisation
this place by fertilization the pollen working capital time to work
we would like to ask questions like
if i want people these things you
one my credit card database
and my web server
well i think one of the things that exposed to each other while they are
two different virtual machines when they divided up
how can a separate machine shop
and develop system which is much more secure
there's been real interest in natural strong encryption as opposed to make
crystallographic encryption as anybody with the DVD player all HD players there exist
on the other side a lot of interest to smart cards
no i think every for home users
although this not possible uses a smart card machines like keeping some of your password
safe and stuff
the legal side is also interesting
those that were temporarily outside the u
the european union has made it clear that it wants to do something about the
fact every software licenses
if this kills your grandmother your car blows up it's software not fall
but if the CV scratched will send you new destroys your business your ten new
nuclear facility well
the european union decided this is a bad idea i want to fix it
and therefore
they want to fix it and then we just need encourages people to write software
which were
the idea being that
if some people are able to to sell and ship
john software
without liability they'll never actually be the
that is likely to lead to
three things
one of the standards for designing software
another standard operating software
and so is properly stating software is fit
which is the last one particular will received free software
what would be you can distinguish between
this school had right next i wrote last wednesday you might like this
his five thousand euros what licence for piece of software we wrote last wednesday we
think is incredibly dodgy but we don't get a software with my
so the idea of let's say this software has been written to the problems that
this software is suitable for
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this MIT opencourseware
OCW MIT
but you
now this is not a quick clicker questions you actually need to maybe write something
down to figure out the answer is that if you have and i have clicked
any other if you want to change answer keep in mind that you may need
to jot down for example lewis structure before you can answer this question
the and getting your final answer to the question
after the you just walking in now you might not have a chance to get
all of the dark bros the that you need in on this clicker question because
it is based on lewis structure so we will go over
but for those of you that have been here for you thirty seconds or longer
see if you can get the right answer in here are a cell
OK looks like we have
a very mixed response in terms of the answer the other questions today raise your
hand if you didn't have time to figure out the lewis structure
OK so that accounts for some of you
let's go over the correct answer to this question so
we got the right answer thirty one percent of us
this is not the kind of percentages were looking for so let's go over there
on class i and class on monday
we did go over the geometry and the geometry themselves are very straightforward once you
know what the lewis structure is remember you can't just always look at the molecule
and automatically notable structure we actually need to think about those valence electrons so here
we're dealing with william hyde right so as he h two
i told you that there are six valence electrons in so we have the there
plus one for each of the hydrogen
so what we should have a eight valence electrons in our lewis structure
how many electrons we need to have a full
valence shells
twelve that's right we need
eight or it's twelve or full shell
that means that we need twelve excuse me
that means that we need
need twelve minus eight
four four bonding electrons
in our structure
so i try to give you one you can draw pretty quickly just has hydrogens
and so we have as e
h two
we can do our four
bonding electrons how many valence electrons to we have left
four that's right so we need to tell for selenium so one two three four
so this is our lewis structures here hopefully you can see why it's not linear
if it were linear which thirty two percent of you seem to have thought that
would have meant that
i had no pairs
right that that's not the case we have two lone pair so we thought about
what the bonds were everywhere would be one o nine point five
but it's that's because we're only looking at the bonds were not counting the lewis
structures in naming geometry but they do affect the angles
and it turns out that it's actually less than one o nine point five because
those lone pairs are pushing the bond even further away
does this make sense to everyone if you think about it
this way
pretty much OK so
well try i will try another question like this way there are some of the
questions that look very straightforward just naming the geometry have to remember to do the
first step before you jump in
and go ahead with the naming so you'll get plenty of practice with the linear
problems that if you haven't already
right so before we started with today's note i do want to mention that this
morning the nobel prize in chemistry was announced
this is an exciting week in science in general because we get to hear another
nobel prize every morning pretty much
so let
but settled down for a second start listening itself
today we're going to be talking about molecular orbital theory but first i wanted to
just mentioning his some of you didn't here with the nobel prize was
this morning in this way in chemistry one to three different cameras osama
she mu moreau who is the excuse me a lot of that name she mamoru
the japanese camera and then martin b
was at columbia and robert chan was at UC san diego
the three of these chemists with the nobel prize this morning for their discovery
and or other application of using green fluorescent protein
which is also called GFP how many of you have heard of GFP before so
great that many of you have heard of GFP for of that have enough to
say that it is it's the protein two hundred thirty eight amino acid which means
that a
about a thousand actually more than one thousand patterns in size and this protein is
four athens the protein was first discovered in first isolated from this jellyfish here this
was done
nodes so we can really see clearly what's going on and the of zero five
one just as i had before now
g i j of zero one
and g i j one zero somehow all had to sit on the stage so
a bit funny is happening here because i'm only allowed to describe one costa this
ed ge and yet the gene function is the two by two tables
and so the second of four numbers then how can i get all of these
four numbers onto this one edge something doesn't fit here well there are various ways
of dealing with that which are all
equivalent is just a matter of choosing a canonical form if you like so
the canonical form i'm going to go with the moment is that g i j
one zero has the same value of j i j i j zero one that
sits on an undirected edge here
and what about zero zero zero and one one values of g
well there's no way to put those and so happily in the canonical form they
have value zero
i think that's not just sort of skewing this beautiful model by making all these
restrictions on g but it turns out not that this is actually without loss of
next so we we all agree
a particular cut of this graph is the particular assignment of ones and zeros the
x's and also immediately gives you a particular
energy any problems with that because this is rather important yes
sorry what any gene
five to find
well she
reverend wright
well actually f is the log likelihood for assigning a single pixel
to foreground background
without considering any of the other pixels just you know you look at the properties
of that pixel harris colours they fit you know evaluate them under the colour model
foreground the probabilistic you know the gas mixture models are going to use evaluate them
under the and the foreground model about the background model the negative log of those
those two probabilities of what goes on go on the f
the GRR can that was the one that came from the ising model
so remember g
that was the thing where you get a penalty gamma
if if two adjacent pixels have different assignment one is one one zero and actually
in our model
you will recall
we gave the same penalty gamma whether it was one zero or zero one that's
good because that was one of the things i want to assume in this canonical
form that's the problem and when
the two adjacent pixels have the same value that's g one one let's say or
zero zero also we were giving zero penalty also have actually that's good that was
also fitting within the canonical model but with the current canonical form but as i
say actually the canonical form is not it there is no restriction
is work is clear so carry on
so that you also
so one where there is also
yes so just just to recap that there is a probabilistic model for colour in
the foreground
a probabilistic model for colour in the background you take a particular hypothesis like this
pixel is in the foreground and you evaluate the probability of that color under the
foreground colour models
so it's the probability distribution you simply evaluate that problem distribution for that particular color
now the negative log of that is what defines if i have one want
one reason why you want this and what you
growth wastrels
the reason i'm not sure if it's right to call the loss function it's it's
like is the negative log likelihood
this is not this is not something like that is not something i plucked out
of the you know the cost function is in some sense subjective thing you know
already sort of outside the problem you say OK here's what i care about you
know here's my probability distribution over over hidden states here's what is going to cost
sure enough it's a straight line
right three
that's right
that's true
when you when i moved my little bit
the difference has to be greater equals zero
but then what's next crucial step that when i look at the linear eyes
are part of the just multiply v alone
that has to be zero
and that's the
the tricky point
that's the tricky point that
the higher order stuff
can be forgotten because
because of because i look at very small v
so i'm just
describing the whole characters are very sincere in this tiny corner of the board the
main point is that it's
the general case of which this is the best example
are we ready for finite elements
and i work with the same example
so what's the finite element method
the finite element method
makes its problems
finite dimensional
why not
allowing every function u
and every
move move on to the
but only
a finite family of u
and the
so that's the that's the key idea
finite elements and
and that's the big decision is all what
so now i'm ready for finite elements
here come finite element
or the galerkin method in general galerkin
we want to get a finite problem
and how do i do it
i only allow
these use which are
combinations of
with unknown coefficients
basis functions
and of
so i only
i only minimize you see i'm uncertain down to the finite dimensional space
instead of minimizing over every u
which led me to this differential equation for the absolute winner
i'm not going to take
subspace winner
a limited winner
by choosing just a few functions
or maybe a hundred function
but not all function
and i will only allow those winners so now
these are chosen
we hope chosen we hope well
that's the big
big decision
it's so much of applied masses
what are the good trial functions these are the trial
because those are the ones we're going to try
and other functions
if there
if the absolute winner has
they could be like
sin x sin two x sin three accept sign
one hundred
of what this heuristic idea was just trying to find a decision boundary and then
collecting samples near the perceived decision boundary and this is what actually happens in the
what i'm doing here is the
applying the number of viable hypotheses the size of the version space versus the number
of sensors that you query so when you start off you have about ten thousand
possible hypotheses of ten thousand different separations of these one hundred sensors after
one query you eliminate half of them
after two queries you've eliminated about seventy five percent and so on and so forth
really are limiting roughly half of all of the hypotheses at each step and if
you plot this on large scale you see on a linear decrease which is this
or geometric reduction in the size of the version space you select these
sensors for query
now say more about that kind of idea this afternoon so active learning for regression
so classification is just one way that you can use active learning in regression suppose
we're trying to estimate a function
what i'm showing here
and if we're going to take samples what you might think is that you might
want take more samples in
where you're
the target function is
more difficult to predict the was wiggling faster changing more rapidly so in this case
is actual jumper edge in that signal you focus your sampling in some adaptive way
to try to localize where those discontinuity is happening
and so that's
the idea here is that image processing example reveals a little bit more about this
later but if we are just going to
satellite image like this
it's a scan number of points uniformly at random we might be able to get
a reconstruction light so at the bottom there
if we use the same number of samples but allow ourselves to do kind of
two-step process where the first step we can take a bunch of random samples uniformly
and the second step we identify
interesting locations and then sample more densely in those regions we can get a much
higher resolution
version of that image was better better localisation of
the boundaries of this lake and so forth and so the idea again is to
try to adaptively focus
on regions of the target function that are most interesting where there's the most difficult
in predicting the value
and you can also do it for fun are so this is the guess who
game i play this with my son and the idea is you just keep guessing
what your opponents player looks like this have had does it have blue eyes and
and so on and so forth and you saw earlier chipping away at the hypothesis
space just like
in this scale are GBS type of algorithm and the difficulty of and the difficulty
playing with my son is that he
he likes to win
and you can be a bit unreliable so
he'll tell you that the person has blue eyes when in fact they are brown
and things like that so i one one interesting challenges and active learning is how
do you deal with unreliable responses to your queries and so forth and this is
just another example of noise
OK so
so the the service framework and that we're looking at is we have some feature
or query space called ax
could be for example the unit cube in d dimensions or are key euclidean d
dimensional space who have some output space label space zero one plus one minus one
in the case of binary classification could just be the real line in regression problems
and we're going to use collect features and labels
there are going to be
they typically
coming from some unknown distribution px y
and the goal construct predictive and which
is a mapping from the
feature to label space input output space that minimizes sum x some expected loss of
the last is a function which measures
how well your prediction is relative to the correct label
and then your
typically something that's nonnegative and takes a larger positive value the more disagreement there is
between your prediction in the true label then you're looking at the average of that
loss that's called the
expected loss or risk
of your and this should be
this is a type of
there should be a chair
have here something you can try to minimize
so the optimal prediction rule ph star which would be the hypothesis for predictor in
you're set
h that minimizes the expected loss unfortunately this would generally depend on px y which
you don't know the joint distribution of x and y and so the idea and
course to take some training sample which gives you a glimpse at this unknown distribution
and then use the training sample two
learner produced
a classification rule or a predictor h at
one of the
things it's
you received a lot of attention over recent years is the fact that we have
a lot of unlabelled data in in many cases and labels can be very expensive
and there are two
approaches that are popular one is semi supervised learning
so in semi supervised learning the idea is that we have a large pool of
unlabeled examples of unlabelled examples and then usually
a much smaller pool of of labelled examples
and so there will be
ten million examples that are unlabelled and maybe a thousand that are labelled in the
like to somehow combine both the labeled and unlabeled data to help you design a
better predictor hypothesis and
the basis for this is that there's usually either explicit or implicit assumption that somehow
conditional distribution of the label given the feature or labeling distribution is linked in some
to the
the marginal distribution of x itself so one example andronicus we're not trying to maximize
learning too much
published talked about yesterday or other times but you know if you have
clusters and each cluster the labeling is this kind of homogeneous of one cluster maybe
labour plus one another label minus one if you can learn that cluster structure was
before we begin i just want to make sure you guys all remember about the
quiz on friday so
the quiz is going to be in walker
two PM everybody goes to walker
the quiz open book
you can bring your own notes bring class notes bring greetings from class
you can bring a calculator please don't bring any computers phones PDA is things like
that make sure you have all your stuff redoubt before a show you taking notes
we're going to do today is just quickly what we're going to do an introduction
to networking but quickly i just want to finish the topic of caching
that we began last that i sort of introduced at the very end of the
lecture last time
if you guys remember
we were talking about our our pipeline web server system
they consisted of these three stages
networking stage
connected up to your HTML stage
connected up are
this stage
and we talked about the performance we did a little performance analysis the system we
look at what the cost of each of these stages in terms of what the
sort of throughput in each one of these stages is
we said that as long as if we split this networking module up into ten
submodules we can get the throughput of this thing to be about a hundred
o requests per second
we said the delay of this guy was one that latency this one millisecond semin
can process
thousand requests per second with a latency of the disc
was ten milliseconds so that means it can also process hundred requests per second
and we said remember that when we're looking at a pipeline
these are the throughput of the entire pipeline is going to be bottleneck by the
slowest agent system
and so if we look at this we see these two stages are both are
both running at one hundred hundred requests per second
we have a very simple way of making this first network stage
be able to process more requests per second because we simply can replicate the number
networking sort of the number of threads that are sending data out over the network
so for example if we went from ten nodes here two hundred nodes we could
up increase the throughput of this stage two thousand requests per second
which means that now the bottleneck states that we have is simply the this stage
so the question is is there something we can do to increase the throughput of
the disc stage
and you think about at first it may seem like well there's probably no way
that we can do anything because the disc politics ten milliseconds to you know every
page text and the second street and so what we do about that
and there's a very sort of standard answer to that that you guys have all
seen before that answers caching
so the simple idea is
we're going to take this i o state this stage with its disc runs of
ten milliseconds and what i've shown here is a very simple piece of pseudocode might
correspond to what this
sort of the reader they get page i function for this is that for this
i o stage does
it's simply called summary function that reads page idea of the disk and then returns
the page
if we have a cash to this system suppose we have an in memory cache
they can retrieve that page in point one millisecond
in that case the way that we can use that cash just before every time
we go to the disk we can check and see if the page we're trying
to load is in the cache
and then only if it's not in the cache
we need to actually go to the desks and we get masonic actually go check
the desk and see if the page is available
we can extend the code in a very simple way
to take advantage of this we simply say
we look up and the cash first and then if the page is no empty
or whatever we can find it in the cache then we go ahead and look
it up on the disk
and then we have the result of the cash
so there's a couple of little details that we need to work through but let's
first look at what the performance of the system is going to be or how
this is going to impact the performance of what we're doing
if we come over here
we think about what the cost of accessing the page and the system would be
well the cost is going to be we're always going to have to check the
cash right that's the first thing we do so it's right c
the cost of accessing the cache
where cost is in this case can be expressed in something like the number of
milliseconds to do up in the cash
and then class
the cost of looking up in the disk but we only have to look up
on the disk some of the time it so there is some probability
of getting this
times the cost
that in this
from all this is the same as the red one so maybe we should classify
this is
so with this knowledge
and finally
you know
i have something like this i don't actually have to know the underlying
i just need to know some points on the contract set
so the graph to the graph can be something about the geometry of the
so you can use unlabelled little geometry tells us something about this the classification or
regression and unlabelled data can be used to estimate geometry
so that
so he here is the sound of his to example that allow
this is was of course a sphere
you have
you know the SVM was just like this
it would be good morning this point but if you
you know
you know if you have some parameter which can take
can become level they can
you can do that
o but again i mean of course we don't know if this is one class
and this is not the concepts our village
so now
i will talk about some sort of
formal notion of what
the formalism
more formally a more formal version of the manifold assumption can be put in the
following way for functions of interest which i classification regression function so this is not
very well on the data
so that's sort of small with respect to the underlying probability distribution
you we have for example for classification with
it's conditional probability right probability of being relevant given point x
this is a quantity
right foot point which the probability that this point is right and this was actually
where small along
well on probabilities
know how to formalize notion well so suppose we have a function
and i want to say that the function of small
what does mean well means well can mean several things but one of very natural
thing it's very very little
around this point
so when i integrate all around that basically this value should be close to zero
so the formalisation of
so in the growth in a all
well think this is small one thousand very much
this quantity should be small
and this quantity just a gradient of a function of the maps
and well sort of the corporation of function is something like the integral of the
gradient it's right a gradient point is how much the function this point and the
first of all racial if
in the middle of the graph and maybe you take this the probability of which
it's a
OK well it turns out that when you actually great
gradient it's the same
the cluster
so laplace operator so this by this by the way mean two
integral to its integral
so as to the approach so this is the first when of class separate comes
in local also operates basically tells you
that catechism
or because systematic theology center manual of religion
despite the fact that a much later time
very complex systems of theology are going to be spun from particular interpretations of biblical
and there's nothing in the bible that really
corresponds to prevailing modern western notions of religion what we call religion and indeed there's
no word for religion in the language of biblical hebrew this just doesn't work religion
with the rise of christianity
western religion came to be defined to a large degree by the confession over the
intellectual assent to
certain doctrinal points of belief religion became defined primarily as a set of beliefs the
catechism of beliefs or truth required your assent what i think of the catechism kind
of notion of religion that's entirely alien to the world of the bible
it's clear that in biblical times and in the ancient near east generally religion was
a set of doctrines that you ascribe to
to become an israelite
later on june the word jew doesn't isn't something we can really historically use until
about this time
so most of our period we're going to be talking about the ancient israelites to
become an israelite
you simply joined the israelite community you lived in israelite life died in his real
identity will be it's right law and custom you revered israelite lore lore
you enter into the historical community of israel by accepting their fate yours should be
the same sort of the process of naturalization what we think of today as naturalization
so he bible just isn't a theological textbook
it contains a lot of narratives and its narrative materials or an account of the
odyssey of the people
the nation of israel
they're not an account of the of the divine which is what theology
i mean account of the divine
however having said this
i should add that although the bible doesn't contain formal statements of religious belief for
systematic theology
it true issues many moral issues and from existential issues
that are central to the later discipline of theology
but it treats them very differently in its treatment of these issues is in direct
its implicit it uses the language of story and song and poetry and paradox and
metaphore it uses the language and style that's very far from the language and style
of of later philosophy and abstract theology
on our miss count
i would point out
well don't really need to cross is that this is something to discuss i would
point out that the bible was formulated
and assembled and edited modified
and sensors
and transmitted
the first orally and in writing
by human beings
the bible itself doesn't claim to have been written by god
that belief is the religious doctrine of a much later age and even then one
wonders how literally it was met interesting to go back and look at
some of the earliest claims about the origin of the biblical text similarly the so-called
five books of moses genesis exodus leviticus numbers deuteronomy the first five books we call
the pentateuch of moses
nowhere claimed to have been written in their entirety by moses that's not something they
say themselves
some laws enacted this the the book of the covenant if you think the says
moses wrote those down but not the whole five books that traditions later will ascribe
to him the bible clearly had many contributors over many centuries
and the individual styles and concerns of those writers their political and religious motivations betray
i leave aside here the question of divine inspiration
which is an article in many biblical religions it's no doubt an article of faith
for people in this very room
but there is no
basic incompatibility
between believing on face
in the divine inspiration of the bible
and acknowledging the role that human beings have played in the actual formulation and editing
and transmission and preservation of that thing bible and since this is a university course
and not perhaps a theological course within the theological setting
it's really only the latter the demonstrably human components that will concern
it's very easy for me
to assert
that our interest in the hebrew bible will be
centered on the culture and history in the literature and the religious thought of ancient
israel in all its diversity
rather than quite questions of faith and theology
but the fact remains that the document is the basis for the religious faith of
many millions of people and some of them are here now
it is inevitable
that you will bring what you learn in this course into dialogue with
your own personal religious beliefs
and for some of you i hope all of you that will be enriching and
for some of you it may be difficult
you know that
and i want you to rest assured that no one in this course
which is to undermine or malign religious faith any more than they wish to promote
or proselytize religious faith
religious faith simply isn't the topic
of this course
the rich history and literature and religious thought of ancient israel as preserved for us
over millennia
the pages of this remarkable volume
that's our topic and so our approach is going to be necessarily academic
especially given the diversity of people in this room that's really all that can be
so that we have common ground in
and common goals for discussions
but it has been my experience that from time to time
students will raise a question or ask question
that is prompted by
a commitment prior commitment to an article of faith
molecules that have atomic masses of or million
grams per mole
these are huge
so we call this an
i'm using and now in a new way and is called the polymerization index
and as the polarisation index
represents the number of repeats of the murder and the murders the repeat unit
what's the length of this thing let's let's get a sense of this suppose we
had something that was also a ten thousand units long
so let's say
and it's ten thousand
that might give me all
something on the order of about a million grams from
we do that we do the calculation in a different way
let me say suppose i had something that had an atomic mass of a hundred
thousand years
a hundred thousand grams from all this is the atomic masses palmer
and divided by the atomic mass of
part of ethylene ethylene is twenty eight grams per mole so this is the mass
of c two h four of four
and this is the mass of of the polyethylene one molecule
so that would give us that a
polarization index
three thousand five hundred and seventy one
thirty six hundred
and if we estimate the carbon carbon bond distance
about one and a half angstroms four
the carbon carbon bond distance
that gives us something that's on the order of about half a micron
have micron in length
one molecule
and to give you a sense of what that really means
i want to show you a demo here
what i've got is pull chain
it uses an
o downstairs in grandma's house two
turn on the lights
so this is a whole bunch of these
balls that are held together by
so let's
have each of these represent carbon and this one is about three thousand units long
it's about forty feet
forty feet and about three thousand of these
units here
so let's get a sense of how
think this is
this is one molecule
so imagine what happens when this
in the melt states flowing
what happens when melt
decreases in temperature in this attempts to solidify
what are the chances that this is going to
come out in one of the fourteen gravity lattices
vanishingly small isn't it
this is one molecule
i feel like i just came back from new orleans
then you have to with my shirt with all this stuff
is terrific
so that's one molecule
if we imagine we imagine what happens
let's say that it's pretty clear that that's solid
let's call this macromolecules solid macromolecules
favor being amorphous
the amorphous state is the notion of pure crystallisation
is not
and we can imagine for example
all of the rules that we learned for
the inorganic glasses the silicate applied to organic glasses so let's look at say
volume versus temperature for something like polyethylene so i'm going to call this p
we can imagine more appearing amount state we cool down we go through the normal
melting point and then we
a cylinder fication
some glass transition temperature let's say this is that a slow cooling rate
so this is changing slow
and maybe another occasionally cool at a fast rate
so we will have a different glass transition temperature and it will be higher
would be higher
let's say this over here at
room temperature
so there's room temperature
so what do i find i have two different volumes you've seen this before
so if i have constant constant mass
constant for constant mass equal masses
the one with the higher volumes
has lower density so this one should be low density
this is let's let me just put the fast cooling rate
fast cool this slow cool
so this will be low density polyethylene formed here
and this will be high-density polyethylene simply by
the different rates of cooling
constant mass means then that you have density
as of volumes of the one
higher volume gives us the power
so we can see how by different processing we have the ability to change
the high density and low density polyethylene
as a function of the cooling rate
other things can happen if we go at a very low rate of cooling we
you can see if you burn off
these flower
i mean there different these are all of the
so the very
you can see
it just using it for the US
you to work of similarity in a smart way one of
this one of the networks
of course
get this
since very interesting
for example
know that there
that is the agent of the
but its application of the top eight
but not how does not support
it is
so if you look at it
the the difference
thank you everyone for example we CDATA
well something
this ship on office
what you're seeing this
actually if you
use all passenger this is on
we get some
one and
that's why you were once
it's not the same as those conferences
the same thing
people can get out of policies because the disease is about one is
that's one a one
remember the interesting thing
this that's actually you're best
that is patient
this is a very
the authors most to europe in batch
because now
the reason very agent
also sent back to europe
people said to about the distribution
of course this but they
here you see a lot of published in the second part this is shown in
the comic authors there
even once twice in asia you find the similarity of that
but will find hard
this is the one just because
who here
it's very
about this
but if you use
have personalized pagerank also
you this
what you find is
that's the most i e
the so what happens is you for this is the
so if you want
opt not use it
what was the first time just
you see of the the original
so as i said he was
one slide here
you can see that
this is very similar groups that this is most
OK so that the passengers are said to be
so far that the first place
you can use it for
this is
to many
like this one this one many
so for example should
it's very
for example if you
he was this past
going further and
this is more like a home page friend
people have proposed that
if people don't want to get into this too much but if you're familiar with
with the with exact methods for solving pomdps there's this thing called alpha vectors that
represent pieces of the value functions big continuous value function what they showed in this
paper is that the the analogue of alpha vectors for these continuous space upon please
are alpha functions but on the good news there only multinomial polynomials
they could be worse
it could be some arbitrary functions but know they're just multivariate polynomials so there are
smooth in the max over them it's basically they worked at the form of the
value function and it wasn't as bad as it could have been and they approximate
various ways and throw in some point based value iteration but the fact the matter
is there being able to derive a pretty good approximation of the value function
some some small problems like this five state combination lock like environment which they solve
really really close to optimal so actually able to find
the bayesian optimal strategy
or something very close to it for this world so like explorers perfectly
it's pretty
they have a bigger problem which has to do with using soap apparently
some kind of self care monitoring system
you want to say that that's exactly what it is the answer for monitoring people
to make sure that they're actually staying on task if they have cognitive deficits and
even at this at this size we went from like five states to
nine their approximations are starting to really break down so they even nice it example
they couldn't find the bayes optimal effect the thing they found was really close it
still lead to decent exploration but you could tell it was not a whole other
heuristics are actually doing as well sometimes even better
yes sort of less optimal this bayes optimal into being less optimal if the world
this is sufficiently big can you approximating
yeah sure of
i'm not sure i could i could speculate about that so i think he was
he was sitting down under tree
and appl
well we're cambridge seem fair so
so what happened was the co-authors i should have listed as some of the courses
but ppoplp part was working on with some other people who are also solving pomdps
generalize their tools to continuous pompey's is they're working on just continues honey in the
general sense and i imagine they got together the competition something and said well
bayesian reinforcement learning is a continuous palm p and then they realize that it was
a very special continuous ponte people have these extra features to it and i imagine
it just kind of stumbled that
i've actually as the that but it's that was my rational reconstruction i was i
was i had the same question and that was that was my answer in my
own head
therefore it's
i don't know know if it's right or wrong or so
i think
many people in the field and me for a while but not me right now
have basically taken this bayes optimal behavior as being the ideal and everything else is
some kind of poor approximation of it
and i think there is an argument that would say that that's true especially i
would say that very gently around the billions and stuff because because you know based
on basis optimal so it's got to be perfect but the fact that matter is
that you
i could see that maybe isn't exactly what you want and i'll explain why but
it's going to take two steps really get so bear with me for a moment
so remember yesterday we talked about the PAC MDP
so goal
so so one thing one goal of
how do you try to learn reinforcement learning problem is this bayes optimal one that
says well it's not really about learning and then acting it's about just always maximizing
rewards smooth continuous everything is just one unified problems is one big hard unified problem
the PAC MDP
model says something different PAC MDP model says what we really want to do is
to be able to generate behaviour that is nearly optimal
with high probability
but we're allowed to make a small number of mistakes along the way they were
allowed to try things that are not going to count against us the actual reward
we get in those in those cases doesn't matter it just was no good and
we can we limit the number of no goods that we can have a number
of mistakes OK so that was the PAC MDP model
you can combine these ideas in various ways to one night when they came up
recently is the idea of near bayesian optimal and what this means is instead of
defining mistakes to be taking an action that is not
nearly the right action according to the true q function
here mistake is now taking action is what the bayes optimal thing would have taken
the bayes optimal approach would have taken
all right well that's
that seems closer to being right so it's not only is it is it trying
to distinguish actions that are
for the real
model correct not correct but actions that in the bayesian sense are correct and i
corrected actually take towards gaining information in the right way
got PAC MDP we got near bayesian culture and in
showed that they can they came up with an algorithm called bayesian at the bayesian
exploration bonus algorithm all it does is
keep track of UNDP the MDP experience so far by counting up live in in
the state i took this action here states and i ended up in you keep
counts on
on how many times each of those things that appeared but when you've solve out
value function for this you added bonus to any state
on the order of one over and where n is the number of times that
state was visited so in the beginning when you have this issue have visitor who
visited once you get a bonus of one
but as you visited state more often it starts to traylor
so intuitively this is a reasonable thing right this is saying that the more i've
been to estate unless i have to boost it up to make an optimistic
and in the limit as n gets really really big it's going to take on
whatever true value is
this is a very reasonable thing to do in fact i think people have proposed
stuff a lot like this kind of ad-hoc but what these guys showed is that
if you do that if you run an algorithm and no fancy planning in belief
space or or posterior based on like that all you do just straight up
while based MDP but with this bonus defined that way
then also very computationally simple it actually achieves this near bayesian property
so in all but polynomial number of time steps it takes the same action that
bayesian optimal algorithm taken
that's kind of cool
here's the other than they showed
in spite of that it's not PAC MDP
so the main
and they just
two days
so they have in common those
from another
during the whole way
so they are
for the query
number of iterations
right now
i mean
it is not
i always like
it's not something
also works in other words the point men desert
having only your
the also
this this one
the rangers
the most relevant to our work
if is no interest seam on the position of the
the image it is
we can also evidence of already
so we have have lots of images which
relative to each other
we can equally
just to belong to to the class
it will be
and that's what
this the case
and the fact that
this was later
one year
we have
well it doesn't
mean just to make system
big n is the total amount of the images
this is a
and for every
we have
which actually number of said that
this image is relevant to the query
in this case that we have a lot of
so the ones that have
seven judges for every image collection
and of course ability
this is a very well
not to the should be
more sophisticated than previous one
you can also see that we have to
is that all images that are alleged but in this case it seems that have
but in fact
so for every query
you have several users who made the answer and who
select the most people the the most was requires the next one infinite
so we right
for every
according to use that
and after a
the picture
the percentage of people
think the which is a
should be performed on the budget
these queries queries
and the
well these
the range which is done
and think it is the standard deviation
first we have judge and they have some
every frame
these which is the answer
and that doesn't follow the standard deviation of users that
so for example query one
again the cumulant function was thing
make sure that the distribution of normalized
then the expected expected value of the instances include two
the idea of data
which is the derivative of the cumulant function
so no
whenever you work with this kind of thing
you always have the notion of duality so this section second convex function
called the convex concave conjugate function you can write in terms of so
martin wainwright did that was
here i'm in the differential case so i don't need the super can write down
an explicit formula
this second functions f of mu which is the terms mean minus
g of theta
OK these are
convex conjugate
again little denotes the gradient of capital s and then
these two are inverses of each other
in in more
overview type picture
he sort of has two parameters
primal and dual parameters natural in expectation parameters right
everything comes in pairs
it's always
how these things work and i'm going to go for example in the moment and
this is also why it's confusing but want to get a handle on it
it's actually quite elegant
the natural parameter
is mapped we have the little g function which is the derivative of this function
to the expectation parameter which is mapped
we have a little function which is the derivative of
back to the
natural parameters
so the two tool parameters
and here the transformation
OK so this is sort of the overview picture
the simplest example is the gaussians and now i i do the gaussians even simpler
than alex it yesterday i do it for the experience
the distribution is e to the minus
the tragic you can rewrite it this way
this is the reference density
this is the energy function this is the linear park
so here's the cumulant function
now in this case
if you take the derivative
this function you get the identity function
and the inverse of the identity function is again the identity function so this is
one of the simplest case this is the case
it corresponds to
representer theorem corresponds to kernelizable algorithm everything sort of very simple knows the link function
is the identity function
and the dual convex function
if you plug in the formula now
also the same function in terms of the other variables
the log likelihood of this function is simply the square loss
so let me go back again and generality
two parameters natural parameter expectation parameter
the maps to hear the left maps back those the derivatives
of the corresponding functional these two functions are convex conjugate
first example
you rewrite it
linear part human and function
you take the derivative see everything is the identity function the two convex conjugate functions
are identical this one and this one the article
the very basic issues
it's the newly
density look like this
remove is
the probability
of it is a coin
and it's the probability of the outcome of the one
the natural parameter happens to be this actually moves the expectation parameters you will see
this is the natural parameter
now i can write my density as
p theta x
minus lenses just straightforward algebra
which i didn't show
so hard
if you have some time
it's linear minus the function this of course is a
convex function
and then
you take the derivative of this you get the softmax
as the little g
and this still
and you get this function
you can also
plugin and compute the dual
and you get this
the negative entropy
if you
take the log of this function and write it in the data domain it looks
like this
if you write it using the new parameter
it looks like this
and if you do this
o thing by solving this linear programme
progress on in hungary
the nice thing is you can actually solve this in cubic time
this is the linear programme
and you can just throw this at the standard LP solvers
or you could go
and you some specific code for that and there's nothing to three code available on
the net
thirty easy
now what we did is
we through exactly that's over
the the linear assignment problem
but these terms came from our distribution case
and then
it actually work much better
so we almost all of the time got everything right
so adding this external knowledge
but we know that you have to match the turns up somehow
really improved testament
now sample bias correction
so this is where
you have
one set of
observations for the training set
another one for the test it
and some are you training set has been biased
he would like to recover from that
following question so far
everything clear
very fast asleep
OK good
what's the problem
the problem is that
we have our training data drawn from some distribution
on the x and y
and the they start story from another one
going to make one simplifying assumption
and going to assume that only distribution on the axis differs
but the conditional distributions are the same
that's a fairly realistic assumption
for instance if you're
let's get back to the breast cancer example
if you actually have specific microarray measurements
then well
you have to assume that the biology
will be sufficient to tell you whether that person is healthy or sick
so while the distribution over the micro measurements might be different
once you have it
that should be all that you really need in order to assess whether that person
is healthy
it may not always be the case
but that's for the moment assumed
you could use it for active learning
you could use it experimental design as well
you could use it for brain computer interfaces
or adoption to new users
well those cases are actually quite interesting
so for instance when you put one of the brain computer interfaces on
and you do the test you work with the system ministers train for whatever very
you work with initially
and eventually actually do those tasty guitar
as you get tired
the distribution of the signals coming
out of your brain
getting different
while you still might be
thinking in a similar way
you might not be able to concentrate sunlight and all that
so you don't have a different distribution you would want to adapt on the
that it on the fly
in this system actually could do it
you want to adapt to new users like for instance here microsoft and you want
to train handwritten character recognise
if god database of fifty users
and the training system for that
and then at the end of the day
as the ship it
he would like to adapt to the distribution
that user uses inputs
i i d
and this is exactly if you will this is exactly the term that we have seen here
in the base equation
takes a prior
template parameter from it
and then we get a product
okay so what this theorem says is
if and only if the data is exchangeable this whole this whole idea
data is power plus noise makes sense
and the pattern
in general
is expressed by a probability distribution
and if we do something
like saying
on the previous slide here or a pattern is really a straight line this is
not a probability distribution then that would mean that we choose set of probability distributions
that are parameterized by straight lines
the cabinet you is
what this does not mean
you start with some
bayesian model very like you'd say goes
and now we say okay my data is exchangeable and therefore this assumption makes sense
because in general
this year
this district probability distribution here's an arbitrary probability distribution
and that means a set in which these probability distributions lived
is an infinite dimensional set
and the set of all probability distributions on a given space is an infinite-dimensional set
in general we have to put a prior on infinite dimensional space you from from
an abstract perspective this is a key motivation for
before being nonparametric and bayesian models if you want to really
if you want to really exploit the statement of this theorem if you want to use it
then you have to be nonparametric okay after using an infinite dimensional parameters
it has already mentioned clustering earlier
basically the very simple thing this this is just a cartoon cartoon picture of clustering
yeah so
this data was course generated by
sampling from constant
mixture model
can i can i just ask who who has seen
who has not seen a finite mixture model before
okay very good thank you
we're going to assume that the
we have observations x one x two and so on
the modelling assumption we make and clustering is
they the data is
subdivided into groups
partition into groups and that means each data point belongs to exactly one cluster
these in this case they pattern that i was talking before so i will feed you will
are not pattern is a partition of the data
in two
disjoint groups yeah
and if you now think of if
if you think of this
as an infinite sequence here than it has indices one two three four and so on
we can partition it by partitioning the instances
and so what we're looking for in that case is a partition
of an are if we only see
a finite number of data points one threatened then we look at the poor partition of
and d
you're on on the side i am
i have a very simple application of clustering so what i did here is
i just took a very simple image it
it's basically
the night sky
with with some trees down here and so we see this guy
moon and some trees
and now we want to segment the image
using clustering
and the way this is being done here is
we take a small sliding window
passes over the image
we slide over the image
and at each location where the window
is is positioned we extract the pixel values within that window
and write them into a histogram
and so we get a histogram associated with each other with each location in the window
of the window
and that's it
gives us a mapping from this image
in two
set of histograms into space of
vectors of histograms basic
and then we're going to
apply clustering on this histogram space
so we get clusters the histograms get sorted into clusters and then what i've done
is i've taken the first cluster of histograms
colour each location where one of these histograms was positioned group
right then
the other one in green and red so that induces
basically clusters in feature space
correspond to segment an image
there's a very simple application of
the other clustering methods and what we see here is so there's been talked about
the number of clusters early on about model selection in this case you
here we have three clusters and here we have two clusters now image segmentation is
an ill posed problem and actually people
if you let people segment images and they totally disagree on how many segmentation usually should be an image
i think in this case you pretty much everybody would agree that it should probably
be three segments are that at least the moon should be
like in with the trees
so this is probably
not as good as solution this one
okay so the way we're going to think about clustering
in terms of
mixture models
mixture model in general looks like this so
this here is in
o makes our distribution the distribution given by the mixture model yes so this is the distribution of data
some have
the end is something called the mixing measure so this is that are mixing distribution yeah
so is a measure against which we integrate some component
think of this for example has got distribution p e of x given theta is
a gaussian distribution with parameter theta
and then we have a distribution over theta here
and there's various things that you can do with for example if you said this to gamma
and theta is scale parameter of the girls and then you get a student distribution
but the way we are going to use and clustering is always going to look at
at a specific form of mixture r this year is
the distribution of i ninety many or sometimes infinitely many delta spikes
what mixture models in general always express
and what i think everybody should always keep in mind when they look mixtures is
they expressed two-stage sampling
and so what this mixture model expresses is
we sample x from this model you
by first sampling feeder
from this distribution
then we plug it into
into this distribution
and sample x from that
so mixture models are two stage sampling
now a finite mixture model
in this formulation looks like this
that's again simply a mixture model but we have a specific form of this mixing measure
and that's it some
over delta spikes at
okay possible locations
yeah so this a finite number case here
we have a k eight different values theta on some parameter space
place delta spike in each of them and then we wait them
with convex coefficients as a convex combination of delta spikes
so this is joint work these categories
i was opposed to ca
in our lab for one year and and
here is the problem we are going to address
so let's think about
protein protein interaction network
and you have
the graph which is partially known
and this graph
we present
physical interactions
between two proteins
so you know that
that's former nodes and another animals point of view you are able to describe your
pretty by different kind of features
or a description for instance we are able to say
what is the function of the protein
you are able to say
in in which
in which place is localized protein
you also
going to be able to do you some
the expression of the gene that
on code is pretty
so if you can
in fact actually rate
values district of supporting and what we want to do
we want to use this
in order to be able to complete the network
these new proteins
that have not that have not been used
in the learning process
and we want to
to predict euro between the test data but also between
the learning
is it
they're just interaction physical interaction so there is an edge
is the two processes can be physically can physically interact with seems that the protein
can be
OK to give
and it's sometimes you have
of course everyone
for things that can from big complex
OK so this is the
mean the edge
is there
a physical interaction between the two
michael cos on not
OK i understand
you go into deeper detail and it's interesting here we just one could the fact
it's possible to have in fact the physical interaction
OK but for instance we are not saying that we have in the in the
sense in fact these four days we will be always three of them
will be always interacting together so there is no meanings the interesting
but just
two of them are OK so what you're saying is interesting if you have the
point of view
this is the behavior of the cell
but here it's it's already a step which interest is about
we looking at
the feasibility in fact iterations
well and not only the physical interaction that is the interactions that that
so will be meaningful but only one to one another
we don't
speak about so the dates
this abstraction
so this is a good question
OK so i know what i'm going to do
i'm going to
talk about the tools that we're we are going to use supervised learning can analyse
output spaces so alpha going to
so again and again treatment in a new context
so that going to give you
one way to solve this problem
the interest of this this method
is that it is based on english and so it has some explanatory and interpretability
of properties
then we speak a little bit about ensemble methods
and it's closely related to to that here winning bets closely related to the talk
the first talk
the first two don't talk that we had
a second
so i'm sorry i remember the name
he spoke about gradient proscenium thermometer so it's it's related to
this kind of miss then going to
directly show you
experiments with the combination of biological networks
i don't know if i will stand getting a very much detail to the gradient
boosting and then i
OK so here's the problem we want to study
we have some training sample of object
o i
from i equals
one to n
it's drawn from a fixed but unknown
probability distribution
and what we are going to assume that
we have to
representation of the subjects
one of the condition of the subject
it's called x
and it's you can think of expenses as input feature
vector representation
and we also assume that we have another representation of the subject which is called
and why is not necessary vector space
for instance y
can be
so fine but huge set of glass
of size p
can be the set of
we some hierarchical
relation between classes and and so on so you can imagine any set of
but that could be interesting for for your application
this is not the the case in classic supervised learning classic supervised learning usually you
why which is just
the discrete set
of possible classes
or just
so the real continued
all eventually vector space so some zero output is some vector
so the goal is the same as classic supervised learning
you want to find some function that is able to predict y from x
you're going to do this
the principle is that you want to mine minimize expectation of some loss function that
you're going to define
and this is the expedition of the loss taken over the joint distribution of x
and y
but as usual
you're going to replace its expectation by some ontological
i mean
and you going to use a different kind of methods and this kind of criteria
usually based on
so the top of the complexity of the sister of the function that you want
in some way
now maybe do it very quickly and we only need
we better only need and log comparisons because we know that it's possible
so the death the tree may not be too big but it has to have
a huge number leads down there
mister branch enough to get an factorial leaves because it has to give the right
answer in all possible inputs
so this is in some sense counting the number of possible inputs that we have
to distinguish
this is an unreleased what we care about is the height of the tree
so let's call the height of the tree h
now if i have a tree of height h how many leaves could it have
is the maximum number of these that could have
two the h exactly because this is a binary tree and i spelling it correctly
because we have a binary tree compression trees are always have
branching factor of two
number of it has to be announced to the age
if i have a height h tree
now this gives me a relation number of these has to be
great equal to n factorial and the number of this has to be less recall
the to the age therefore and factorial is less than or equal to the edge
i got the right
now again we care about h in terms of factorial so we solve this by
taking logs
and i'm also going to
websites and h is at least log base two
this is the two over here of then tactoids
has the property that i'm using here in order to derive
this inequality from this inequality
this is the technical side but it's important that you realize there's a technical issue
the general principle of applying as i have
the quality
i do the same thing to both sides
and hopefully that inequality should still be true but in order for that to be
the case
i need the property about that
operation performance
has to be a monotonic transformation so here what i'm using is that log is
monotonically increasing function
it's important i multiply both sides by minus one which is a decreasing function
the inequality we have to get flipped so the fact that the article not flipping
here i need to
no the log is monotonically increasing efficiency in log
that's true
it to be careful here
we need some approximation of factorial or to figure out what it's log is anyone
know a good approximation for factorial not necessarily equation but the name
stirling's formula good all remember sterling
i just need in some sense of the highest order terms
i the is that
so and factorial is at least an hour e to the power
that's all we need here now i can use properties of logs to bring the
and outside
this is and times logo
and over the
and then log every i can simplify
just log of n minus log
so this is an
on log n minus log p log p is a constant
so it's really tiny compared to log which is growing with that
so this is america among all we care about is that
leading to
it's actually fata and morgan but the only interest because we have a greater than
or equal to all we care about is the
omega theta here wouldn't give us anything stronger course not all algorithms
i have an organ
running time make an organic process some of them do some of them are worse
we have this proves that all of them
require high to the reason
very easy proof once you observe
the fact that the number of leaves and if you remember sterling one
so you should know this for
you can
show that all sorts of problems require and log time with this kind of technique
provided you in some kind of decision tree
here you see
topics that will be covered by
this exam
twice as much material as last time
and of course the material is also more difficult
i'll touch upon most of these topics today not all
and i can go
into two great depth
for obvious reasons we don't have the time
i want to emphasise that what is not covered today
does not mean at all that it will not be
on the example
i want to ask your attention for
these two
the work energy theorem tells you that isn't even object moves from a to b
the work done on that object
is the kinetic energy at point b minus the kinetic energy at point eight is
always applies
four conservative forces like gravitational in spring forces but it also
all four
non-conservative forces
such as friction
the fraction can remove the kinetic energy
it turns kinetic energy into heat
and that is perfectly fine into work energy theorem
however the conservation of mechanical energy
only holds for conservative forces
there you have
conservation of the sum of potential energy and kinetic energy and now of course you
cannot afford
to lose kinetic energy through heat
because then the
conservation of mechanical energy
but not all
and so that can only be used exclusively in the case
of conservative forces
let's start
with a simple example
of a inclined
at an angle theta
i have here an object's mass and
friction coefficient kinetic is mu k
and the static friction coefficient
u s
this point here let me point eight
and at the bottom of the incline can be
that the distance between them
along the slope the
and the first thing that you want to do with a problem like this
you want to make what we call a free body diagram
that means you want to draw all the forces on that object
clearly there is gravity which is mg
and and then
there is the
normal force perpendicular to the surface
surface pushes up
we call this
and the normal force
object wants to slide down
friction hold it up
so us also
a fictional
and these are the only three forces
there are on it so were free body diagram you want know more
i want you to appreciate the fact
that the force from the surface onto this object is of course the vectorial some
between these two
and that's what's called normally to contact force
and that contact force better be exactly the same as mg but the opposite direction
otherwise could never be equilibria
of course we always permitted in two perpendicular directions
because of the way
that we analyse this there is no acceleration in the y direction
only in
x direction when it starts moving and that's why
we played but of course
the vectorial some
is really the force with which the surface pushes on to that object
all right let's suppose now that we increase the angle theta
until the object starts to slide
so now
i'm going to decompose these forces
x direction IFTM g
sin theta
and the component of
in the y direction equals MG
cosine phase things there is no acceleration in the y direction
the normal force
must be also ng
cosine theta
i lifted up the
inclined to the point that it is just about to start sliding
and so
that means that the frictional force
is the maximum value possible
which is
the static friction coefficient
times and
and therefore that is
u of s
times MG
i'm the cosine
off a
and when will that happened when the frictional force g
sin theta exactly equal if i go golden one they are further it will start
to slide
so that's the case
then this equals and
i data
and so you lose UMG
and you find
and the think that's wonderful
this is the way
you can measure the static friction coefficient alternatively if you notice static friction coefficient you
can predict what angle
that will occur
at that situation that
it's just hanging
by its own so to speak by fingernails
we touch it very likely would blow on it
and it starts to slide
and now
i'm interested in knowing what the acceleration is downhill
the reason why it will be accelerated that this
friction coefficient goes down now to UK so now to the net force
along the slope into plus x direction
so i can write down now
newton's second law and then
which is
force the net force in the positive x direction
would be equal and g
times the sign of the data
the frictional force now this comes
also there
i lose my
and so the acceleration in the positive x direction that's the way i find positive
x direction
the sign of the data
u of k
the cosine
that's acceleration and now a natural question would be
one is the speed
and which is reaches point b
well we would have done early on in the course
we would have said
well finally acceleration
and i know to distance and i note initial speed is zero
and clearly the distance l
the most popular database servers
and the
because of course we know that this conference
you see them
his ranking authority
with this goal much be for example
this one we show you all the right answers for XML
within the more sub articles XML exploring accepted
so we have the other are to be able to be on some of the
world's proper and offers
this is interesting is this one of the first time i chose this was the
and i see the end result
accident they by the third of the people
give you know speech
the web search can handling where is my last before the data mining those are
so all this time but you
but these are the guys at number one x and that's why we fight
of course sources
with this approach a lot of changes not only rank
like the paper
this one you can also read is that
if not for
well you're
get three clusters
the members the system
image processing we don't know anything about them
but we know the past take back
who is the
according to
this is the wrong way is by
i don't know whether you
by different boxes what is by a famous i think it's something
then you
one our
and this one is likely to remain so this is capital lot buildings
this rally and to some of the stuff that i don't know but at least
partition the brain
so we have to put this one system
what is it
all i next
according to the rescue
then use tools of it by
the interesting thing about c
as you can read authors or with different keywords a on this article saying know
what is interesting offers conferences so some
this is
we put it on the web if you have internet access google like i do
i remember last year hector garcia molina who was
stanford prison
well he was invited talk speaker UIC
it possible to my office was
so we got physical system or something like
says you can afford
he said i wasn't that stands for all the data that is
he had theories
eleven one
that means that black man said something pretty interesting but trust
one is because the stanford professor so you know
exactly what this this is not enough
this is not
nothing about them
this is about that class was also a paper published by joan she be last
year's conference
it was not
with this heterogeneous networks can be very interesting
now i'm going to do
but things on the homogeneous then these before
actually there are lots of people across networks
these are about
homogeneous network
show you a few interesting one
one interesting one there's is only one
the cost of actually started with this
was jennifer widom
OK stand for
she was on and just
this changed about a month ago
she got paper
this is all of this conference was a conference proceedings
OK based on this new
no computation
you the cluster as well
but is one problem with this is very expensive like i said it
you know
the generalized is this one
the former pharmacist
two of the system similar of the judges similarity
if you look at the edits
if they one
common is of course a similar
if you look at this
link of that
there a link out there
similar to keep going
you know
further and further
also have a company
but the problem for this algorithm
you just want to use a and b
but expensive
because you computer and the similarity
you look at the end of the
this is the whole sigma
what about sigma is the only thing is that many of the fact that many
of the things we look for everybody
we have them today
that's quite categorically don't think about it one more level one level
if you look at this one all
this is not very efficient
was very expensive
then the problem is
how can we make it cheaper without using
without using
the accuracy of what
but that's the problem
the problem was first hand before joining
it was first attacked by the
he got sick he
it was the
he served one
that year first year
this one
this is one of these were later
just in this lecture
to our approach four five is very interesting is just one of them
what is of the nation is
if you want to study makes
one study leave all the objects or the objects what want to study is something
you know
for example you may go by another five year-old btselem similarity between this so you
in the results
here is the asymptotic
i mean square in role
the expectation of the difference the square difference
what is what is important in this relation is that i have this
two dams the bias term and defiance down the first one is the variance expansion
the basic pension
i don't want to comment at all each what is inside each but the important
thing is to check
the kind of rates of convergence we have football clubs so k is the kernel
function and sigma and is the band's parameters using parameter
that appears when you apply some kind of estimation
and you see that for the barbarians them we have one over NC nine rate
of convergence and for the bias then we have a rating in sigmund to support
so if we compare
that's this rate is the rate of ten for the estimated conditional expectation to the
true one use in particular that he said was gain in defiance
usually for the conditional expectation you have wait in one over in the main square
so by
solving the differential equation you have lost square here
and you have this and this and wait for the basis to
so there is a again in the bias that appears very quickly and is again
is due to the fact that
you can transform your initial function and
which depends on two arguments into a function that depends on only one argument so
there again dimension and find is getting dimension in this in this way convergence
it's really quality
you can do for you
you have the depend on
you know differential equation which is one
i have a very very very very low resolution one of the major
it's a be done
you can see that the end of its life just exists for so long that
we love each sequel to fix
so lambda fixistas into one and c
so then you have a well-defined meaning of what it means is right in this
result i assume that n one depending on both arguments
OK for you to confirm that
i i suppose
the front and dependency in london
if of course and the land that it seems a lot of minor phonetic and
just want to
OK so this is for these if this first
expansion and this the second result going to show
uses the
the fact that i also have the game in regularity
since lambda should be
since then and since i solid differential equation and i expect to obtain these game
in the bias term
so the idea is to assume that instead of having the classical canon of order
i can assume that i have the kind of all the free
and without imposing some further and stronger assumptions on the form of an
i can go further in the taylor expansion of the body there
to get to achieve better rate of convergence so that's subjective of next
one of i things
the next result
so this is again i mean square there are expansion we i would still have
audience them in the biased and what's changes that is that they assume that it
mike cannot function is of all the free
so obviously if you have a function of all the free
cannot function of all the way you can go further
in the taylor expansion for the bias down but normally you have to impose some
stronger assumptions on your initial function and that's not the case here it's simply due
to to the fact that i sort of
and i differential equations so i have improved the way improves gravity and
the result is that i have
the rate of convergence for the bias term in sigma politics
so i have i can
sure this game in regularity in this by the by this extension
so to summarize article
this is the results
what about this change to the estimation of the conditional expectation what this change in
solving this
initial reports this problem
first i have
i have shown you that there is game mentioned by applying the integral right
and also we can prove game
we are able to expand the bias them as if
we were
continuously differentiable of all the free
without imposing it initially
and that leads to
this last