exact and that are with different shapes
these approaches do contain
some phenomenological
parameters especially if you want to describe the
so a lot of work will be done in the future to better describe
the interaction between alpha particles and neutrons and protons surrounding them
but it's very it's really something
that is important
some experiments are experiments three are related to add close to ground state
because i was talking here
what i find clusters in that state close to the threshold of the and five
but there are also looking at the heart of condensate
in the ground state
now i will talk about superheavy elements so
the search for a very very old
for example
when people before they were discovering fish and they were using actinides and collision with
the night and this
i have seen your raised
but the chances said all we have discovered a new element superheavy elements
in fact there were on the fission fragments range from fission fragment but it's really
really search there's really for the superheavy elements
so if you do
classic physic with the fluid so you consider an equilibrium so then you have
the balance between the coulomb repulsion
and the strong interaction
so what because your face takes so
and then you have maximum charge allowed which in one o four so you cannot
elements heavier years and one of four
with these liquid drop model
and experimentally there are many experiments back in their place
i don't know
guinea that in france in genocide germany where they have found that elements two
and right eighteen have been seen
so much more than what is predicted to limit predicted by basically with
so i mean that here you've really the stability
which is due to microscopic effects so this is really because of this existence of
microscopic effect that you
you have these superheavy element that are
that do exist
in order to information and approaches and the first is very important to know
which nuclei very giving you know you can
and then
you will tell me OK but
what i presented before was about them
there are magic numbers two eight twenty twenty eight and they were the same for
proton and neutron so why don't you have the same
magic number four
one hundred twenty six
so this is really a question but in fact is due to the different theories
because many calculations have been there from to all the conditions to find something else
he starts with typical example
for this is
the number of false stability for proton or neutron number
and you see that one hundred fourteen one hundred twenty and one with twenty six
is predicted
and what is predicted also that this number really depends on the number of neutrons
so here we have a real real disagreement between the different areas
that's why the search is very important
to know what is this
new magic
i will finish with something that
concern fundamental symmetries and interactions soul
so this is something
a little bit special from the user use of nuclear physics community which is more
dealing with such structure exotic nuclei
but you would see that in the future a lot can be done
two have some elements concerning fundamental symmetries
when you are weak interaction it is it is all these was a bit added
to the new trend is brought and placed electrons and antineutrinos
the experimental data that get can contribute to
first test unitarity of the CKM matrix
is fundamental symmetries of the weak interaction investigates
the structure of the weak interaction
for that
you need very precise measurements of the two values to vitality the energy really so
you really precise measurements of the mass of the nuclei
branching ratio between the different processes and fly
so far that moves among the riverside do you need these tracks
i penning trap paul trap
so to really to cool down the the elements and to two
and they almost that phrase to measure the mass
and even more complicated for that
unit correlations between the spins and momenta of the particles involved
so that's why you need polarized nuclei
so in some ways are don't think that the right some sorry some progress under
the direction here at his older again
i can promise
thanks everybody for
coming to the last hurdle that separates it from the
my name is alaska
the remaining our soul two
machine learning applications very exciting field of computer security where we have been working
that article from the first
about four five years
so i will
focus on the topic of network intrusion detection which is one
very important problem that you will see
before i proceed i would like to ask something for audience how many people consider
themselves how many people here consider themselves computer science
more than half
OK so
i was starting and to talk with it
short program included
one of the following program do that you can see on the slide
relatively short
c programs
a few minutes is located and and
we'll have some majority voting
i guess guess guess ready to justified so approach of what the program does allow
for the you know what you think and who thinks the right answer is a
you think that that this one of the great
one of the
he will be OK
one and he was see
let's see
think that you know what's going to happen depending on the pop
i can see let's see what's going to happen understood
in fact this
i cannot say
but this is going sl it's this right something this file
he received complaints something that's there
and that's the problem of
really not
going to sleep for a while in the second no more
do something so
basically this you know read the files
and text in print out of you know more
diagnostic information
we'll see what we're
this is something else
there are no
so i started the program and sense of the the file
while the program
and as you know
show something else
so it's really sort of waiting and
what's going to happen to the files going to see what holland
after twenty years after the waiting period has elapsed we the files
and this is what happened
OK let's try something else
now what
disappeared from the map
one the cycle
that's one
that's right
in a sense that it was predictable so it's funny here
o thing happened
one down
well OK
we don't know something
there's a difference
private sector that you can see from the
from the
the text that you my login prompts
now for something else
and writers programmers who
nothing happened
so nothing happened
again have a little more difficult to do this the
so that's the problem is not really
that's reliable is that
this act
to guess the return address of the program
and that's pretty tricky business
unintentional so if you see what it's trying to do
this allows us here
that we need some process information from the running process and
find where the fact of this process is located
and then
called the program actually exploit
that uses factor information to
well that rights information into the file
it's going to to read
the program that we seen contains about vulnerability
is the place from
but the problem
we can look at this
actually doing exploits
it contains something that will help
which is binary code used for system over
and then
yes the return address
build the barbarism from jump address the bar is not
except information
and while the rights information file
and this this this information to get overflowed into about
and the way it works is that you know if you recall how
now parameters are stored in the stack
the above still together with the return
overflow buffer
information in this graph is going to be allowed
into the area where the return address is stored
and if we are lucky enough to guess the right return address
you know this the
when returning from the function
this command is john back
two the return address
which is somewhere in the middle of the buffer
and this is what the shell code
at the end of the programme instead of returning to the main function to the
operating system we're jumping back to
executable code that has been written into this buffer and open the show
this is
in general how does whole flow words that actually
not easy to prove
the problem nine
exploits of this code publicly available
so i basically had to program during meeting for
a couple of hours
although i'm not really tacky outfits
OK so
what is about seven more alarming to think about it is
the hackers are
very good at distributing this information to the community
there some websites
the rank in l
OK where
r where the two here has two parts one is the access
and the other is the
so that's sort of what they did and one of the nice properties of this
is that if it turns out that there's locality in the access patterns
if once you
it's not just the static distribution
a rather one-sided access something if it's more likely and access it again
which tends to be the case for many
input types of patterns this responds well to locality
because it's going to be up near the front
if i access it very soon after i that of this what's called temporal locality
meaning the entire might tend access thing so maybe the axis some things very hard
for a while and get very cold
this type of album responds very well to the hotness
of the accessing
OK so responds well to locality
so i
so this is sort of what was known
up to the point that are very famous paper was written
by r
dennis later and bob tarjan
they took a totally different approach
looking at this kind of problem
OK in approach that now you see everywhere from analysis of cashing in
high-performance processors to analyses of disk paging
just a huge number of applications of this basic technique
and that's the technique of comparative analysis
so here's the definition
on line
if there exists
constant k
such that
for any sequence
as of operations
of s
using algorithm a
is bounded by alpha times the cost
bounded by alpha times the cost of of that work is the optimal
OK so the optimal offline the one that knows the whole sequence
and does the does the absolute best it could do on that sequence
OK that's the that's this cost here this is sometimes called
god's algorithm
not to bring religion into the classroom
or to offend anybody but that is what people sometimes call it case of the
fully on missions
knows absolutely the best thing that could be differences in the future
the whole works OK
just apply that that's what ops algorithm is
and what we're saying is that the cost is basically
whatever the alpha factor it could be a function of things you could be a
OK times whatever
whatever the best algorithm is
k clusters of
potential for constant out here
so for example if alpha is too
then we say it's too competitive
that means you're going to do and worst twice
the album has all the information but you're doing it online
for example
so really pretty pretty powerful
notion and what's interesting about this
it's not even clear these things should exist to my mind
what what's
which pretty
remarkable about about this i think is that there's no assumption of distribution of probability
distribution or anything
it's whatever the sequences that you give it
within a factor of alpha essentially of
the best our
which is pretty remarkable
and so we prove the following theorem
which is the one that's later encourage improved
and that is the MTF
this work compared
for self organizing lists
so the idea here is that
the adversary says oh i'm always going to access the thing at the end of
the list
like we said in the beginning
it's actually equal to
this sigmoidal function here or the
parlance the logit function
right so this is the
i believe it that as the log function
OK so i can just some simple
one all primary school algebra will get you to that the
so we want to define the likelihood function
so the likelihood clearly for each point is going to be the probability of the
class label
target values
given x and
and this will define
a binomial distribution
so we can write the component of the likelihood for each of the n data
simple is this unnormalized binomial
so when two zero
the likelihood component is one minus the probability of class one in other words the
probability that the
target values classes
and when it's one
the likelihood component will just be
this here
so given the definition of our log it functions which we obtained
the previous slide we just plug that
and here
some simple schoolboy algebra shows that
the component of our likelihood is just going to be
this exponential of our linear response
this to the power of the binary
variable tn
and then normalized by
this here
so the total likelihood
it's just going to be the product over all end of this year
we are all bayesians no overall business for the next twenty minutes
let's just take a bayesian viewpoint
as we are given in the previous lecture
we'll just encoder preference for simple models
well a lot of the w is going to be close to zero
so we will use the same kind used previously
as i said of likelihood
it's not just
standard product four
so the overall joint likelihood of our target values discrete target values given the model
is just going to be
the product of likelihood
on the
the product of of prior
because of bayesians what we want is the posterior
so we need the marginal likelihood
and the marginal likelihood requires to
former multi dimensional integral over w
of this function is here
so this is where the party ends
i'm afraid
for all
really reasonably interesting models this integral
is not analytic
and the nice analytic representations of the posterior and of the posterior predictive
all falls down
how do make any progress
we could
here's a monte carlo estimate
basically sampling from this which we can do
and then just taking a discrete something we know that
as the number of samples
of monte carlo estimate increases then we will converge
to this integral
but if we know sampling in c one thousand dimensions as we will be doing
this afternoon seven hundred then we're gonna need an awful lot of samples before we
can get a reasonable estimate of this and it becomes totally feasible
and so we could use markov chain monte carlo
to obtain samples from the posterior p of w given x of t
and there are methods like
well in this example here we could use the metropolis hastings algorithm which basically requires
us to
i define a markov chain for the markov chain states are the values of our
and although we need to do is they compute
the ratio
of joint likelihood
because computing every ratio the joint likelihood for one set of parameters and a new
set of proposed parameters the troublesome marginal likelihood the disappears
so we could use
very standard markov chain monte carlo methods
two sample from the posterior
and then use those samples from the posterior to do you wanted to make monte
approximations to predictive
another way
and problem we switch on vault was the machine learning community is that we make
an approximation of the posterior with a tractable distribution
the tomorrow and you mention variational methods distance available into a moment to finish
ten so
and the five minutes left
is that attains a quarter two
OK i think you should be able to get through this
well maybe not
tomorrow i'll talk in more detail about variational methods
someone straightforward problems but another way of
making a deterministic approximation is to just say well let's
every engineer will tell you yes every engineer will tell you that as a sort
for voice should not be the same as the sense for images
OK that's why
i'm using this as the microphone
and the ladies using that to filming
OK so the other way around
so this issue of universality is kind of
mathematically very interesting but in practice is very clear to everybody that we should be
able to do better
and this has been addressed
of optimizing this sensing
not taking random this has been addressed by making labarbera
five address that an our ago goal
his previous talk
there are more so upper bounded sum very nice work about and the sensing that
this actually optimise computationally
it does as good as as the random but computationally much more efficient
and k
we are going to try to optimize the sensing
and addiction both of them at the same time
that's what we're going to try to do
so here's the formulation and i change notation to be in agreement more with the
notation used in the compressed sensing bank explained to you
it's all my data
vector form
is now my dictionary
this site is what was the
and these are my qualifications
that i'm going to request to be sparse
so this is what i had before
and this is what they had before
this to tax
is that OK
so i'm trying to represent my image all my images in as far as fashion
with elements of my diction
but i have to make two more requirements
one is
i'm not going to see the image again in my life
because i'm in a sense the image
with a matrix multiplication
so this is what i going actually see
and it's going to be multiplied by
this sense in matrix
during the training i do have access to both
during the reconstruction this term will disappear
so this is my sense matrix
forget about this for one second case
look only at this
and now optimise for my dictionary
four michael efficiency
as before
and for the same semantics
all at the same time
in kind of according to the same type of approach
if i decide not to optimise for my sensing
i mean the previous case
but and better than the previous case i'm going to show you because i'm taking
into account the sensing
if for some reason you fix the dictionary
i'm still going to go
and optimize the sense in which is related to a work and you advise what
by the optimized for everything
there's one more conditions
that appears here which is related to the uncertainty problem before
these are that condition comes from the theory of compressed sensing it says that these
two guys
can now be arbitrary they should be related among themselves
and that's pretty intuitive you can not sense in the same direction of your dictionary
are not getting knocked
you're getting enough
and that expressed
as there are IP
restricted isometry property
and that's related to making the gram matrix corresponding to this
as close as possible to the identity matrix
so that also shows up here
so we have two new types
and we have an optimized for
before i show you the pictures
this is why we get forget about this this is just a parameters this alpha
this is classic compressed sensing mean square error
what i mean by classical compressed sensing do around the matrix
and one of the shared dictionary that's you somehow learned in this case we learn
a dictionary with case b
this is what we are
this is where we are
if we optimise for the dictionary and sensing matrix
about four times improvement
in our mean square
and these are intermediate cases
for example
you fix this same semantics
by optimizing dictionary
that you're not going to seeks you can see why
so it's a different dictionary
then you end up in the media
or you fix the dictionary and you optimize for sensing matrix i forgot which one
is the two because they are very similar
for the learning stage
i know it
why assimilated i multiply by feel
say that again sorry
why is fy x
why sphere x y is equal phi x
now they had this i know because i can see more like i know it
and i know what the sensing will see because i'm simulating the same sort
in the reconstruction you don't know this
so all the images i show you
after we have learned and you only do this
with this
that's a classic compressed sensing
OK but in the learning
i assume for this case that i know both there will be applications that people
say on all you never have access to the original image
then i will have this but we have this i we still value to optimize
for addiction sort
you see that
he said he said for
was all because i learned from images
i'm going to reconstruct images
and the my images are not in the database are used for learning
but it's not going to learn images
i reconstruct speech
i'm going to learn images to reconstruct images that that's part of the point the
point here is
university is fine
but i'm trying to design a camera
OK so let's use images to design my camera life tomorrow
you want to use the camera
four speech
classic compressed sensing will do much better and we will do
random mattresses with do much better and we will do
but it will do much wars
that if you tell me in advance if you're going to use speech
OK if you're to be me than
i followed
just believe the images
so i'm going to show you only these two extremes
classical compressed sensing
we have sensing twice
this sparsity level which is about what the theory tells you to do
our result with optimise dictionary and optimize sensing matrix
so these
it's really is not just numbers so if he was like point one db we
properties that can be computed
can be global property sold in
the global that means for the whole network so the number of net votes in
the network the number of edges the number of car parks and so on the
number of strong components we components and then low-cost so
this would be for
as a single vertex for single
line and so on
this will be the degrees of vertices the course each other
how we know how the court
number to each vertex belongs to the highest score and so on
let's look at for example at the edinburgh associative thesaurus network as one network where
we compute something where
what this network is about
it's about twelve
the survey was made
all students each student has been given a hundred sixty million words
and they had to
they had to write their associations to these words as
quick as they could so that's how we got here
words and associations to these works
so the
this this would be the words and
link the are would be associations
and what we can do here
we were we can first three g network and then get the general information so
global information about the network if i do that
and by
i first read the network
and this will be
the right one
it's quite large network so it takes a bit of time to read it
and if you go to
in network in general
sorry i just close this
so here we have in the report window we get
general information about the network and what we see from here that there's
how much
thirty more than
three hundred twenty five thousand
and there's
two to twenty two
and we get
also the densities
the density of of the network here
so there will be
three main
o thing
helps sorry
about this network and where is the same also here
and what we can do next for example we can calculate the degrees
of each registers and we see here that the
these are
the most
the words with closed
those with most links
they are probably the words the team words
i can do i can also show you how to
how to do that for example if you go to network partitions degree all degrees
so that's how you know
you get to the really degree for each vertex has the partition
this is already done in here's you get all the partition
if you want if you want to see
what what how they look
you can of course get to info and partition but i want to that because
i want to show you something else so
attached is degrees to each vertex is vertex it's degree to each vertex so i
want to get the properties of the vertices
so what i'll do
and go
the partition
and i'm going to make a vector
that means
the from the degree partition
we just transform the degree partition two vectors
and that's how that's that these that each vertex now has its well as a
number of degree
and there are
what i want to really to do with this
is i want to show that pi
it also supports an interaction with statistical
programs are
and here i want to use
this vector this degree british the degree vectors
two it's two exported to are and two
calculate world too
to draw
how do we do that we go to tools
they are in santa are
course we first have to locate are
and if
because we have to have it on our computer
and make things
and we
so like current vector
now an our
a window opens
and this is the director did we
what very
i want to do now
i will just
is this into our because this is
this is what's written on the
slide so you see
we get this
agree to it
the degree distribution
so that's how
some kind of
statistics can be computed with with
by combining are so and so
OK well that
that's quite an unusual thing here
but with this
i associative
network it can be due to that some words were similarly and also the response
but the others which is the response
so the question is it's intuition why it's OK to have six this bracket cut
off the whole region we should go to that sometimes when we sample high we
would go left and then when we extracted bracket we would go all the way
out here and we could get that region region and potentially go up again and
that would work
so the question is what about applying this multiple dimensions because i drawn one d
plot here and it's not clear what the algorithm for multiple dimensions
this actually
different multidimensional
slice sampling algorithms and
it's not at all clear which one to use but the simplest is just go
to each variable in turn
and move it using this algorithm that bit like if something you update each variable
in turn do this and that is something conditional
and that's very easy to do
may well be better things to do
so the question is
it looks would that inside the vast science and i explicitly told you in the
last lecture that you could be really careful when you that there was a step
size because you might not get valid algorithm say
that's the selling point of this algorithm is valid way
of doing something that looks as they are adapting the step size
i haven't gone through derivation precisely why this is valid but the intuition is
back to the basics of how MCMC works you need to be able to identify
any given move forwards from your current position the next position
how you would get from the final position back to where you are now
so once you've gone to in place you could imagine working at the probability of
selecting a height again
construction the bracket starting here
moving back to here and you can verify explicitly that they satisfy detailed balance when
you work out that the probabilities
that's why this construction is
this elaborate i didn't fail just double the width of the brackets something very specific
designed to make that prefigured three
OK so the paper in the annals of statistics on fly something contains many ideas
has ways of using slice sampling to adapt to the distribution in other ways very
different ideas of how to apply to multiple dimensions ways of using
different information that you may have if you do have it the long paper and
i don't think many people really exploit a lot of the stuff in they do
the simplest version that is here and it's in some of the introductory textbooks but
i strongly recommend the original paper
cover one more
deliverable method and then we'll have a very short breaks and i'll change topic
here's a completely different way
of introducing more variables so that your sample better questions
his son
what's the catch yes
none of the algorithms described
strictly dominate any of the others that you can always construct an example of one
of these algorithms are going to be better and that's often useful thing to do
with the help to understand
so the what how they might fall down what to watch out for
here because it doesn't have to send little information about the conditional distributions in maybe
that doesn't mean it's good missus gibbs sampler
if your distributions are very similar might and the main win here isn't technically will
markov chain because it's just this is easy to implement
so this is what i do when i don't want to think too hard and
i want to try something out if you're interested in really pushing harder application and
really wanted you tend be working better than you would probably try and do something
more sophisticated
for example the algorithm that describe
the here's a completely different way of using deliverables and here motivation is kind of
different the previous motivation was
i don't want to do things the hard like setting step size parameters of computing
conditional distribution so i'm going to introduce auxiliary variables to make the problem easy once
that so all distributions uniform
the method based on how opinion dynamics which they
the opposite think you know lots of stuff say
you derive probability distribution you can probably also derived its gradient so you've got this
high dimensional object is good if you have gradients to tell you which direction you
can move in which direction is the health like to areas of high probability they
went to be good if we could exploit gradient information
like optimizes do it would be a terrible optimizer to just ten points and accept
reject it's much better to use gradient and maybe we should be using gradient based
mcmc methods
so if we have a gradients we need some way of moving in the direction
of great
haldane in dynamic take your original distribution which we're going to write e to the
minus energy
we can always do that because we just say energy is equal to minus log
have some
fifty or sixty hertz depending on the country powerline interferences and typically have assigned this
and the cosine component and if you plot the science and the cosine in and
in two d then you get a circle
OK so this this powerline interference is intrinsically two-dimensional
OK what is the idea that the basic idea is to go
two to generate some sorghum
the sample
from the data that you have
make an estimation
sample again make another estimation and so on so forth
and then with this you can see how how much these estimations actually we get
because in the way you are trying to see what is the statistical stability of
the estimator
OK so clearly you estimate the mixing unmixing matrix for each so we're gonna dataset
and then you would like to calculate the stability
that's the program
so there are different ways
of doing that one this bootstrap resampling that's the first
option but there's also other things like if you could
to generate you're sort data by an additional applying an additional filter but this is
just a side remark so that the filter doesn't change anything in the linear model
as you see from the equation
so the a is actually
you can pull it through
through the filter OK
but anyway so so
in the case of of signals that have no temporal correlation it's more less clear
what you do so you do some research as you would always do it
in the case of temporal signals it's not so obvious how to do it and
the idea would be to have two resample
the correlation matrix is the temporal correlation matrices that that you would
the need for for actually doing this similar tennis taking the station
his the procedure first
OK so so
i mentioned this in my last lecture that
when you
so i see a problem you always solve up to scaling and permutation
so imagine
if if you would now
two doors served got then
you get some projection directions and you always have to match them with with the
other projection damage mentions of the other circuits this is quite painful because it's somewhat
in in
in fact if there are some miss estimates it's even more and more difficult
for this reason we
we are playing a trick
so because it
we can
it's actually
it doesn't matter whether we first
a separation step and then compute the surrogates from the already separated data
whether we
computer circuits from the original data
is no difference in that only convenience
OK so
this is the trick with this we avoid all the tedious combinatorics
why is that because we assume that that are
independent component analysis algorithm already gets on cuts is a decent solution
so this means that certain gods from the solution which is already on mixed
if we can if we draw surrogate from that
and if we
then do one
an independent component analysis again on the already and circuits it would almost be the
identity matrix up to some statistical fluctuations so there's no need for actually matching directions
this is
o thing
OK so
the first step is to
two blind source separation as i said the second step this also for convenience you
whiten the data
and then
you do
you draw some sobering surrogate datasets you do blind source separation and this produces some
rotation matrices only because you have widened the data so this is almost
o only irritation that that you know that you left
and this rotation is very similar to the unit matrix
and then basically you decompose dissertation into some
portation angles and you compute some standard deviation from the rotation angle so in order
to get this is zero boxing
so just have some some definitions
so you have to define samarra
i mean slightly more precise than this hand-waving thing
and so
we take the angle deviation between the source signal subspace because it could be of
a more dimensional subspace space component not the one-dimensional ICA components
and then you have this this matrix which we call separability in a matrix with
all these angles
OK and now our
definition of uncertainty is to take the max
with respect to each other
it's that column
i think
i mean this separability in the matrix page basically measures
how are you
DV eight and all
directions and
the uncertainty is the maximum of one you could also take the mean or the
median or whatever but maybe this is the most pessimistic one
and just to show you how we get this
we take the exponential
the rotation group representation which is quite convenient for this purpose and then this is
the are
this is just a convenience it's it's because
otherwise we have to work too hard
OK so
one of the things that is important if you do bootstrap
it is to that you prove that actually when you
when you do the bootstrap that you
that year the estimated that you approximating is actually converging to the right seeing things
so that it's consistent
when you do
with temporal information this is not at all clear that it would be a consistent
so in the case of all these other all these algorithm that whose temporal information
such bootstrap procedure might not actually estimate the right statistical thing
and for this reason we try to bound
the error
of our method
and we do this
on the basis of the correlation matrices and we see that it's actually bounded
and we also see that this
with strep estimator is actually biased so it doesn't actually
understood this
general purpose recipe for backprop you can apply to more complicated objects in the traditional
for example you can apply it to
of layers stack which correspond to be unfolding in time recurrent network where you can
apply to recursive networks which are shown in the bottom right here
where are you constructed tree
in some way
inputs or at least and at each internal node
you compute a representation
which summarizes
these subtrees below
this has been used on
by richard soldiering chris manning in a number of
applications of these that's to
natural language and also the computer vision
and with great success
in in lab with views recurrent nets fore
structured output problem where you want to help with something of high dimension
in it's not like classification where you have one choice out of ten out of
thousand you have one choice over an exponential number of states sequences of words
so you can use recurrent nets here
in aid
way meaning that you can use them to
one of these
high probability answers
the way that you can do without is first
the problem of modelling the conditional distribution of a sequence of outputs given some inputs
through the decomposition of the joint
in two conditionals wear
he avoid one to
he is decomposed into the product of the probability of each word given the previous works
so you're gonna have
the previous here were represented here by the state of the recurrent nett
the previous slide that vertical
o thing here
and this is is gonna be a deterministic function of the previous words that have been seen through
in mapping
after which
depends on the previous state and the current observation
and now what you do with this state is you use it to predict the
distribution over the next word once you have a distribution
you can
compute the probability of the next word if your training and you maximize the probability
or you can sample the next word so
recursively sampling the next word and then using data as input for something the next one and the next one
so what you can generate a sequence out of nothing
more out of the input here
so this is how we
we take an input sequence
at the bottom of the figure are here
and we summarize it with one kind of sort of simple recurrent nett which is just taking
the previous
summary and the current observation into the next summary
and then we take the summary for the whole sequence
two condition and other recurrent nett which is a generative recurrent which gives us a probability fore
the next element of the output sequence given
the elements that we already
have sampled
all right so i i you know i can i can imagine that if for
the first time you are seeing these concepts that might be a bit
obscure but
i encourage you to to read about this one shot one thing i forgot to
say is that i'm reading a book
another one called deep learning
not a big surprise
and some draft chapters already available
on and you can find those on my web page and there's already a chapter on recurrent nets which contains
a lot more detailed information about these these beasts
get these things o one interesting
consideration when your
when you're replying backdrop to simple things like the traditional
neural net with one layer you can write down the equations for derivative yourself
and-or the chances of making a mistake a pretty small but once you get to
these complicated graphs like we had war recursive mansoor other kinds of complicated
accommodations are doing through which like compute derivatives it becomes more and more error-prone and
humans make errors and little errors are
hard to catch their
so to make the life of the
machine learning design are easier
we've introduce automatic differentiation
this this world
so automatic differentiation is just
software that they forward graph that maps your value inputs and you parameters you to loss
softwar busy
create backward backdrop graph
from about and then you can write about
so different ways of doing
we have a binary code for you know
which is uh
um four pi expressions into siu chiu expressions
will only compound but also
the automatic differentiation
as well as
are optimizing code optimization
in order to save memory and computation
all right
so let's go back to
basic notion
try to understand
representation learning
in deep learning can give us
somewhat surprising an amazing
statistical power so how it can help us to generalize better
more traditional techniques
be basic reason why this is gonna happen it's something i've talked about already is that we're gonna be
composing pieces together it's thanks to compositionality not we can have this statistical game
all right so let's let's let's go into this
so before i tell you to
how we can get this game let me tell you know how a lot of machine learning is done
a lot of machine learning that's i call non distributed
and later
i'll talk about
distributed representations
which is
parents are bins and all these things but first of all
most machine learning about you see
in machine learning books
are things
i think
he input space
and break it into regions
like clustering so each region corresponds to the regions assigned to cluster or nearest neighbours
where each region corresponds to one example and andy
configurations that get mapped to it because the nearest neighbour or r are we have our kernel machines
oral or or
nonparametric density estimation classical nonparametric density estimation or engrams
in like in language modeling or decision trees so all these and more
like nonparametric graph-based manifold learning methods
they all work by taking the input space and breaking into the regions now those regions will have to be
hard here that could be solved you can have of interpolation between neighboring regions
but the crucial point is it commenting argument
of Newton steps to solve an LP with an accuracy epsilon is bounded by
an upper bound like this it depends on the epsilon on the accuracy and on the
square root of the number of inequalities in a problem so that's why it's
polynomial time worst-case complexity that's this gives you a bound on the number of
Netonw steps number of systems updates like this so if you multiply this with
the cost of computing this Newton step you get a polynomial upper bound
on the total number of operations right so this is a very simple type
of interior point method but this complexity is still the best known complexity for linear
programming worst-case complexity if you multiply this with the cost of solving a Newton system
you get actually the best worst-case complexity that's known for linear programming is that clear so all of the
of this is linear for linear programming so now we can see how
we extend this to general conic optimization with in the linear format so first
we'll have to extend the this simple logarithmic barrier to a general cone not
necessary orthant
then we can if you have that we can define a central path in
exactly the same way and then another interesting question would be this M over T
M was the number of inequalities in the LP will re will be replaced by some
other parameter and then that will affect the worst-case complexity here so let's start with the
barrier function so in a very influential book Nesterov and Nemirovski have showed that
any for every proper cone K one can find an barrier function that satisfies these three
properties and it's called a normal barrier function and it really can be interpreted as
the extension of the of the simple logarithmic barrier function of the nonnegative orthant to
a general nonpolyhedral cone so the three properties are that first it's a barrier function so I
mean it's differentiable it's convex its domain is the interior of the polyhedron
and it goes to infinity as you approach the boundary right then the second definition
actually extends the logarithmic property of the cone so it says if you take an
X in the cone K and you multiply it with a positive T then the value of
this barrier function changes like this it's the value at X minus data log
T so in other words the barrier function if you restrict it to a ray in the convex
cone at the origin on that ray it looks like a negative logarithm multiplied with
theta and this theta is a parameter of the normal cone of the n
barrier function so it's called a theta normal barrier function if this coefficient is theta
so you can look at this definition as just an extension of a logarithm to a cone to
a vector in a cone and then the last condition will be needed for Newton's method
or the analysis of Newton's method so if you restrict this function phi to an a line
so you pick some vector X you pick a direction V and then you st restrict it
you look at this function as a function of the point on that line it
satisfies this inequality so the third derivative with the function of alpha is bounded by
this function of the second derivative and the reason why that's needed is that the
analysis of these methods depends on results for Newton's method that's already true for
linear programming because these complexity results really exploit very properties of the logarithmic barrier
function when you apply Newton's method to it so to extend this type of analysis
to a more general cones you need this condition so and this intuitively makes sense
at least because this restricts the third derivative of the function by a local limit defined
by the second derivative so it restricts how fast second derivative can change so it makes sense
that this is useful if you analyze Newton's method right so if a barrier function satisfies
these properties we call it normal and this parameter theta will be important so let's look at some
examples so for the non-negative orthant this standard barrier that we use before is
normal and the parameter theta is just M if you replace X with T X then
that's the same as substracting subtracting M log T from this right so this parameter theta
here is M for the non-negative orthant in R M for the second order cone you
can show a define like this so scalar Y that's an upper bound on the
Euclidean norm of X that this is a normal barrier and the parameter is two
if you multiply Y and X by T then it's same as substract subtracting two log T from this
barrier function for the semi-definite cone you can use the negative of the log of
the determinant of the matrix as a normal barrier and the corresponding theta is M if
this is an M by M matrix so that's just a log that determinant for the exponential
cone you have a complicated barrier that you can show is normal with parameter three and
also for the normal power cone so that's the definition of a normal barrier so
then we can apply that to define a central path in exactly the same way
as for linear programming so now we take an LP with conic inequalities we use a normal barrier
as our barrier function for the inequalities and then we define the central path as
exactly the same way we construct these unconstrained problems with a weighted sum of
the objective and the barrier function and then the set of minimizers of this convex
function as with parameter T is called the central path and it has exactly the same
properties as for linear programming so the motivation for introducing the definitions or the
properties of normal barriers have to do with the convergence analysis of Newton's method when
you apply it to this function a function of this type where the first term is linear and
the second is a normal barrier applied to a linear function of X so
if you wanted to minimize this for fixed T then at each iteration you will have to compute
a Newton step like this so the inverse of the Hessian times the gradient and then
so that's the Newton step at X and then in the convergence analysis it's very convenient
to use to define an function lambda of X that's called a Newton decrement
at X so it's basically the norm of the Newton step delta X in local
norm defined by the Hessian of the function of X or if you use the definition of the
Newton step you can also write it like this it's the inner product of the gradient
the negative gradient with the Newton step that should be a positive number because the Newton step
will be the same direction and then the square root of that number so we'll use
this as a proximity measure to evaluate the proximity of X to the central point
with parameter T so this will be zero if you're on the central path with
parameter T because in that case the gradients will be zero of this function if you're on
and intuition
let's derive gasoline processes starting from linear regression
so let's think of linear regression imagine you have a linear regression with input
x i
and output
t i
so in a linear regression model t i is
linear function of the exercise was some noise
OK where the coefficients of the linear function are the WP's
so we're going to get the gas processes by
taking a few steps
the first step is that instead of thinking of linear regression
we can think of a linear regression with some basis functions OK so think of
david lowe's right so
we have a linear regression
but instead of being on the wrong inputs we're going to have these fixed basis
five of the
functions of the input
OK so this is also known as the kernel trick we're basically mapping from access
to some feature space phi
and this happens to be maybe a finite dimensional feature space that doesn't matter
so t i is this what some gas nice
now instead of maximizing the likelihood with respect to these W's instead of optimizing these
W's we're going to try to be bayesian about this we're going to say
if we put a prior on the w
then this gives us a prior over functions
and it turns out that the guassian process prior over functions
you know family guassian process priors
and the way you do that is you just give these coefficients gaussians prior
so w b
is normally distributed with mean zero
and variance of data d
and is independent of the other coefficients in some other wl it's a new make
the noise be gaussians as well
if you give this the gas in distribution and you make the noise the gas
in then you can compute things like the expected value of t i
the output
and well we gave this means zero also the expected value of the function at
any point is going to be
but you can also compute
the covariance between p i j this is that element of the covariance matrix sigma
i j
so you can compute that there has exactly
this form
it's a sum over the data the
and then it's basically the dot product of
and exciting fight xj but weighted by the state of these
that's what this does
you assume that each individual data point had some gas in noise so there's
delta function here that says if i cause j at
noise sigma school very with variance sigma squared
that's just like a couple of lines about to drive this but this is exactly
a covariance function
four guassian process missus guassian process
with zero mean and covariance function c
but the exciting xj
which we can write out as the i j element of the covariance matrix so
just to make it absolutely clear
the covariance
measures the covariance between
the target t i and the target TJ
and it's the a function of
input location x i
and in the location xj
so clearly you want the covariance matrix to be positive definite now if you define
any basis functions
regression like this
then you get a positive definite covariance
function but there are other positive definite covariance functions that might not be simple to
express in this one
the same sorts of ideas you might be familiar with the CMC carry over here
in terms of
kernel make valid kernel matrices
now in this particular case this casting process has a finite number of basis functions
like we just find some finite number of the basis functions
but many useful gases cross covariance functions correspond to infinitely many such basis functions
and in those cases you can just write out this function is positive definite covariance
function you don't have to represented as this infinite expansion in terms of basis functions
that's how you go from linear regression to get processes
so what do you do for regression well let's just recap a little bit against
places of prior directly on the space of functions
such that at any finite selection of points x one through x and the course
and the corresponding function values t one through t and have a multivariate gaussians distribution
that's the sort of the basic definition of guassian process
and in learning just like i showed you the devil
you might start out with some prior over functions that should encode your beliefs about
first how much does the mean move but more importantly
how does it behave this tail of the distribution here
because we were aiming to
cut off the tail that's what that's what the analysis was trying to do questions
did succeed well you know here it looks looks positive
and and so so does it here
means are pretty darn close and there is much in it you know so actually
the parzen window estimator at this point seems to be on average pretty good
you know the tail of the distribution
it is is being cut off
and as things get worse it seems to be you know still able to even
was quite small training set sizes to keep this sort of
the worst case performance to be
quite well controlled so we're getting out point two
maybe if we cut off maybe one percent of the distribution would still be a
point two
and so on so you can see you know the tail is growing but much
slower than the ones
of the past window
sort of nice feeling is cutting off at very nasty but there are you know
this already quite bad performances size twenty
and so on
OK so that just to generate OK
so that's that's in the case of the input you know just linear kernels were
if we use a gas in can of course we give the extra power needs
and then it can actually
for instance using this this kernel here
as encounter with it
appropriate sigma
we would offend you know effectively be far worse danger of overfitting but in fact
it makes use of that extra power
and gets the
the much better but also the tail is still controlled and even the worst case
performance is better than the average performance
in the in the most simple feature space
and this is where the slightly smaller
training set
so this was the conclusions of day one right so that so i give an
outline central results touched on this covering numbers and showed you this application to SVM
so now i'd like to launching today too
with some delay but my main aim here is to try and bring you
some of the ideas behind rademacher complexity
i think it's a nice theory it's quite nicely general in that can be applied
to lots of things not just
you know the classification can be applied to sort of regression and even things like
PCA and so on so there's sort of quite general
it has some weaknesses but it actually gives a lot of insight i think into
what's going on
in some learning scenarios but also into the proof techniques that we revisited so you'll
see some of the proof techniques we we've
i already looked at
kind of more often reappearing in the rademacher proof
and all gain given application two
svm so you can actually see that working
where you are allowed to take into account the slack variables so in the result
i gave here
i assume the hard margin SVM with a clear separation
with the rademacher proof i'll show you
the case where you allow you know soft margin SVM with slack variables
OK so
so the the starting point for the rademacher proof is really something that is
studied in
probability theory and concentration inequalities
and this is a quite natural because in statistical learning is really about the reliability
and stability of inferences made from a random sample as indicated the beginning
and this is really what concentration inequalities study so
let me start with the
a relatively
simple example of a concentration inequality
our very soon give you a generalisation of this this example of this is known
as her things inequality
what it looks at is the
so far
a random sequence set of random variables and random variables
and you sample each of them
and then you
compute the average
of that
set of values that you get
and the question is
how far is that average that you compute from its expected value
you can imagine if you do lots and lots of times you get an average
of that some of the story an average of an average
and what you're interested in how likely in the particular case
how far will you expect that the average to be from that expected value
basically the
probability that is bigger than epsilon is bounded by this quantity
which is an exponential
with notice the end here
twenty eight m squared but this is sort of an EM implicitly on the bottom
here so it's really an m r
epsilon squared
so there's an exponential decay
of this probability
with the
sample size
so this is what we expect to see in concentration what it means is that
the distribution is concentrating around the mean value so that the chances of it being
significantly away from the mean
falls off very fast in fact exponentially
the critical quantities inbounding this are
the range of the individual random variables so these are assumed to have potentially different
ranges AI BI i
and you some of the squares of the differences between the upper bound and lower
bound of the range
over the
random variables so this sort of an implicit and i mean if you think of
being dating the same values may be one zero then this would just be and
on the bottom and you get one counseling e to the minus two and epsilon
the important point is you get this exponential decay
and so you get a very tight concentration around the mean
and that arises essentially from this taking the mean of a set of independent random
variables it's important to these independent
OK so sampled independently
OK so
we'd like to derive statistical learning theory results from concentration inequalities and to do that
we actually need a slightly more general version of a concentration inequality which is due
to diamond
so it has a very similar favour to this thing
but is slightly more general and therefore i'm afraid a bit more
a bit messy
so here it is messy as it is OK
what we're looking at here is some function so it more general because it's the
general function it's not just the average of those random variables so it some function
of the random variables that we compute
so the idea is we take a sample one you know if x one x
two x two xn and we compute that function of that sample and here it
and we're asking how close
is it too
the expected value that we would have if we did that
and the same kind of bound holds basically the
the probability that this is further than epsilon from the mean
is bounded again by an exponentially decaying quantity
and the
o point here is that the
it's slightly differently formulated because i've got CI i
it is the amount by which the function can change remember
in the
through it and i do it so many times
so it
and then i have to multiply the value zero
and then i i e to find the book through i have current i
so what you see now
is that b
twelve new zero
and xi i
find and
divided by l
so that's our prediction
approximately constant magnetic field inside
so no it
and this actually
it's a very good approximation
as long as l
the length of the solenoid
is substantially larger
and the radius of the solar
the radius would be
the radius of these looks
work out
numerical example
which is aimed at the demonstration that comes
we have here is solenoidal
well by and is about twenty eight hundred
and l is about sixty centimeters is o point six metres
and i'm going to run through their current which i really don't know yet what
is going to be close to four and a half and you will see
when we do the demonstration
so i can calculate now with the magnetic field is going to be
so the magnetic field strength
it's going to be four pi
times ten to the minus seven
that's what new zero is
and then i have to multiply
twenty eight hundred
you have to multiply divided by point six
and then i multiplied by the current
four point five
and when i do that i find about
o point o two six test life
o point o two six
that's why
that is about two hundred and sixty gun
the duty experiment the current will be a little different
but you will see that indeed if you will be very close
two hundred and sixty gauss
why is is it
that the magnetic field is not proportional to the number of loops
but proportional to the number of look
per unit length
you may say well if i have one loop forever so the magnetic field two
loops i have twice the magnetic field had look i have had times the magnetic
imagine that we start sort or
it be seven
so here's is the sort of his lobby seven
here is that solenoid goes
all the way
thousands and thousands and thousands and thousands of books
and we end up here
twenty six one hundred
look at this
look i think of it that the first look
creates a magnetic field
one is the shape of the magnetic field qualities of current loop
we discussed last time
the magnetic field that one little produces is like a dipole field
so do you really think that you in twenty six one hundred we can sense
the magnetic field there is produced by this one doing it or look
practically nothing
it falls off so rapidly the magnetic field that we don't notice notice here
so it's immediately obvious that the magnetic field is not proportional to how many of
you have
if however you put all those links on top of of each other
then of course you can add the magnetic field
so it is natural
that you get how many windings you have
so that you take full advantage of a lot of information taking advantage of both
the gradient knowledge of the gradients analysis you taking advantage of 1st and 2nd derivative
information about the function
because that being a good thing they are so tonight I remark at the top
of page 3 today's price the method actually assumes that the Hessian is invertible at
each iteration which might not be so we look for classes of problems in which
we can guarantee that for we need some mechanism for enforcing or modifying that whatever
we do
we we've got something that's invertible and has a remark at the top of the
right there is no there there's no guarantee is written as method and my objective
function decreases as 1 would think in any intelligent algorithms as I go from in
the area of improving my objective function
but so far I have no guarantee that innocent
and we'll talk more about that later
and then as stated the next point is that
is step 2 could be augmented by a line search what I mean by that
so that if I think of method they here I am I came here
in a sense 1 can think of an algorithm as just being something at each
iteration each iteration the 1st computer direction in which to go
so I have they have this direction decay
and I need a mechanism for figuring out how far should go in that direction
and if I go my step length is 1 that means take full Newton step
I could and trying to solve the following one-dimensional problems clearly minimize over alpha xk
+ alpha decay so this whole here
I'm going to look for a one-dimensional minimum of my function
and actually there's a homework exercises we decided not to assign you where I could
have asked you to prove the convergence of Newton's method with all of inexact lines
so that that's the key features of Newton's method
even before I go any further
why is Newton's method was was developed
what is the most well then you end up into the following questions what is
the most well-known very attractive feature of Newton's method at least from a theoretical point
of view
you know
OK actually not necessarily
but if it does converge it converges at an extremely fast rate
and extremely festering will see that shortly
but before I do we get to that let me go over other features
of the method
so that you can read this
it is that is the direction
and the 1st thing that approved you before we talk about convergence rates Proposition 1
. 1 and find out where recall sold right we see matrix is SPD
that is symmetric and positive definite and what is positive definite me
I wanted to say about people so ingenuity is the person next to you is
I like land what is positive definite meaning
is multiplied by a factor of of the group as long as the vector is
nonzero very much so that means symmetric positive definite and Proposition 1 . 1
says that
get existing
then the Newton step
and the if 0 that is not 0 then D is the set of X
and Y and recall from the informally what it means for a direction to be
a descent direction
this is a descent direction
X was going to be a descent direction at x yeah function
OK for a long as 1 as go enough distances right this is the direction
of decreasing the function of the however proved that well 1st
is order t one over p
you the proof here
he said he
is most t one
over p
as t infinity
well this is or t
one over p the whole thing is for t one of
and so
now i
i have p
is or t one over p
and what we need is that to compute t one over
and that's going to be or p
everybody that so what that says is that if i have a certain amount of
if i run essentially on fewer processors than that heroism i get linear speed
phase rescheduling
one or more processors than the parallelism
some sense and being wasteful because i can't possibly get enough speed up to justify
those extra processes
so understanding the parallelism of job says
that's sort of a limit on the number of processors i want to have in
fact i can achieve that question
in this
and so
if you see
really in some sense this is saying it should be omega p yes so that
that's fine
it's a question of so so so i ask again because
if you know it's only if is bounded above by a constant is not
t one and t infinity are constants
the variables in this
so this is more you know we're doing multivariable
asymptotic analysis so
any of these things can be a function of anything else and can be
growing as much as we want
the fact that we say we're given it for particular thing we're really not given
that number we give a whole class of
dags or whatever of various sizes is really what we're talking about so i can
look at the growth
he was talking about the growth of
you know of the
of the parallelism sorry the growth of the
you know of the runtime TCP as a function of
t one and t infinity
so i am talking about things that are that are growing here
so let's
let's put this to work
in fact number
let's go back to here
it's a little bit of my own research
and how we use this in some of the work that we did
so we developed a
dynamic multi threaded language called silk spelled c because it's based on the language c
it's not an acronym
it's because silk is like nice threads
and although we at one point my students had a competition for
what the acronym so
could mean
and they came up with the the winner turns out with charles' idiotic linguistic clues
so anyway
you want to take a look
and you can find some stuff on here
and what uses
it is actually one of these more complicated schedulers
online scheduler
and if you look at the expected run time
on p processors
it gets the sack effectively t one over p
o as t infinity
and empirically if you actually look at what kind of times you get
to find out what in the big o there it turns out
in fact it's t one people plus t infinity
with the constants here being very close to one empirical
no guarantees
but this turns out to be a pretty good bound
you know sometimes you see it coefficient infinity that's up maybe close to four something
but generally you don't see something
it's much bigger than that and mostly it tends to be around if you do
linear regression curve that you get the constant here is close to one
and so you get with this you get near perfect if used
this formalism model here run time you get near perfect linear speedup
the number of processors to running on is much less than your average girls
which of course is the same thing as if t
infinity is much less than t one over
so what happens here is that
when p is much less than p infinity as t infinity is much less than
t one over p
and then we reformulate the original problem
so this is not problem is formulated in terms of
let's get the match is defined based on white
constant is also revised accordingly
thank you wanted and the constant throughout revised weights according to the
it and that is why
and now
to solve this problem we propose we
robert the theorem in the paper
this theorem states that the solution to this new NPC pollen that typically for
people one
if the you need less i can better
corresponding to the largest eigen value
i had a problem
the single
c is the defined
as follows the it the division is basically
based on the
the fermat
the according to the majesty
because each of the
coordinate vector
i'm not going to
give the details of derivation and you can read the paper all come to the
poster just outside of these
so by now i have proposed to the UN CC angry
so it's time to evaluate the problem that the proposed angry them
so this is the right from the top which was surrounded the face recognition problem
of sublime face recognition problem
that we have to is
the feret database and which was the subset
so that the maximum
pose variation in fifteen degrees
and the minimum number of face images per subject in is
this results in
seven hundred and twenty one thousand images
from seventy seven
and we have to the other
feature extraction so it
preprocessing by
many parking and alignment
and it is all the images are normalized to a by itself with two hundred
fifty fifth grade three level but because
and for the classification
we feel that features and is simple classification method
nearest neighbour classifiers
euclidean distance measure
and for the performance evaluation of classification we use the report
rank one identification rate
so here are the results
first of all i want here
you know the number of training examples presented to have good one is
the only one thing is simple
subject this this is extremely small sample size scenario
it's very difficult and
the estimated that the supplies mesenchymal kind of cells
the mission of supplies but cannot solve this problem because we have only one sample
you can now estimate the within class scatter
and here the results the first one is for them metadata different one
right from fifteen
two up to eighty
and the proposed method is marked by
i meant
from the results we had
i think that this proposed new entity
eight outperforms the other three methods
fifty and can see
he out
and the we
for the domain
l you could two seven
here are the results in the show
and we have a similar observation
the UN CC outperform the other three methods as well
and for the other results from two to six
it outside of the cell
you can come to the poster
and since we have
this method maximizes
and actually the observation from the previous results we of that
you can see it saturates
earlier than the other methods the problem is set route
earlier around ten t thirty eight thirty eight very fast so
this motivates us to examine the various captured by space here at the recently
plot the
variation captured managed by scatter
love you i love you
it is for one
at the two
the problem is that must by diamonds
OK although from the
that the british captured by UN is much
the other methods right
and this is due to
the very
constant solution
so we have their correlation and we also have the content of
it must be a tensor to vector direct projection
and this
parishes space
the saturation because we is to low the variation it too limited contribution
if the recognition
so it clearly is uncorrelated with mathematical proof here as a simulation study we
of the partition the average correlation between a pair i feature
and he had be done
the above is PC and you the
the other thing
today I'll be talking about Bayesian parametrics and I'll I guess I'll start
off with a bit of introduction to
Bayesian machine learning first I guess in in the last week you have
heard a lot about various Bayesian approaches to machine learning and statistics so
this this is a bit of a recapping it so let's start with probabilistic modeling okay well
as we all know machine learning is all about data and we know data has lots
of different has lots of noise and uncertainty and so forth and a big part
of learning from data is about handling of being able to reason with the
noise in the data all right and
the idea of probabilistic modeling is that the this language of probability theory is
have a very reach language to express all of these uncertainties about about data and and
allows us to to reason coherently
about this data and the so of a models that we use to express
these uncertainties about data are called probabilistic models
okay so we'll see a number of these examples later and I think probabilistic
models has been very successful especially in the last ten years in in both
statistics and machine learning and the reason is because well there's kind of a few reasons the first one
is that it allows us to
kind of like visualize
all models of the data at a high level
without actually worrying about all the little details of
about a model okay another reason is that we can do very complex models from
lots of simple parts and and we can do both of these using
the using the language of graphical models and which I which I guess you're
probably familiar with
and another reason is that
it allows us to separate out the modeling questions from the computational questions right so it
it allows the modeler to build a comma with a model and then it it allows somebody
else to build to derive algorithms
for doing inference and learning in the models given the models that the modeler
has come out with and this I think this separation of the modeling question
from the algorithmic questions is very important basically because
there's a few reasons
one of the reasons is that the people who known their domains well
may may not be the same people who can program well and the people who can
program well may not build to know
biology or linguistics domain well so that allows us
a separation of efforts into the modelings of efforts and the algorithmics of
effort and this allows the field to to advance a lot faster another reason
for for this separation of modeling and al algorithmic questions is because
when you do that you're modeling your data you'd like to to think about
the statistical questions without having to worry about all the different approximations that you have
to do to get the model to work on your data and this is very
nice because it allows us to think about in the ideal situation what should be
and that should be separated from what could be done on your data so that
you can so that
if it works if your
algorithms will orders and what you can count like localize
and figure out where is it that it's gone wrong
so what is probabilistic modeling basically a probabilistic model is simply a
joint's distribution over a set of random variables okay so so here's our joint's distribution and you
would typically be parametrized by some parameter theta and typically we can think about this
probabilistic models as
generative models so the idea is that we can postulate a particle of generative
process that could have led to the observations that we actually do observe
right so
all right okay I see so
and the idea is that
with this joint's distribution you can then do things like inference which is to
basically estimate what were the
likely states of our unobserved random variables given the states of our observed data
okay so this allows us to infer what we did not observe okay
and of course this conditional distribution of the unobserved variables given the observed
ones is simply given by base rule all right so this is just ratio of the
joint's distribution divided by the marginal distribution of the observed data
and of course
don't typically know the values for for the parameters for our model and we'd like
to learn about those as well
the process of finding the likely settings of the parameteres which could have
led to our data is called learning and this is typically done by maximum
likelihood right so we'd like to find the parameter setting which gives highest probably
D to our
okay there's lots of different things that you could do with probabilistic models you
could do things like prediction so prediction this is can be phrased as basically computing
the conditional distribution of some unobserved
data from the observed ones so you can think of this as your test set
and as your training set
we can do classification so
if we have a bunch of different models each of them indexed by C
and given by a different parameter then you could decide
given tested item which class it belongs to buy basically assigning it to
the to the category or to the class that gives at highest probably the under
its probabilistic model okay
and in addition to this of course there's lots of different other things that you could do
I guess these are a bit
these are things like visualization so you can you'd like to visualize
degenerative process that have could have led to your data and this is also very useful
in things like interpreting the data and summarizing the data and so forth okay
and as I say before there's this separation of the modeling question from the algorithmic questions
and the
one of the nice things with probabilistic models is that there are lots of
there're lots of standard ways in which you could derive algorithms for your models okay so you can derive
inference algorithms learning algorithms and so forth and this algorithms things like you know
the expectation propagation the expe expectation maximization algorithm junction tree there's variational
inference expectation propagation Markov chain Monte Carlo sampling and so forth
but i that's the count parameters
because i can't get publicity theory
but o
i did check should i guess that would be a good thing to do
actually cost you do that was not the original
remember the error rate
ninety five per cent
have to mine OK
one thing people who have been doing that algorithms seem to not which i don't
like so much myself the swiss roll data
additional dataset now what you have here is to say well this is a non
linear embedding is the swiss roll you can see that clearly have done this coloring
trick they use and to i get is a natural question to ask what happens
in this example you got three dimension example is in the phi is not initialisation
aside this is an initialisation aside if you see what i mean it'll be on
the unit shot PCA
you get what you might say all these embedding guys would say it is of
course solution
i could be seen
in what criteria judging things is the cornish isation what the sort
this is the map which is the sort of multidimensional scaling algorithm and the examples
taken from a nice man so obviously works very nicely friedman so initialize with isomap
of solution but many local minima solution
and that one can be dismissed much when you at least
i think interpretation this one so i can things like PCA
or isomap or anything else by using smart initialisation i don't use PCA for argument
is i not see any spiral structure
in this visualisation and this is because of his talk about visualizations now i you
can see spider this three d parts
but if this was really fifty six dimensional
then i would much of it seems to be this one is almost think someone
from the end of the swiss roll and a scorched on the floor
so you this spiral structure here which is telling you that some former spiral structures
are the best solution there so is that solution seems to be careful in saying
how well you've done
so i'm going to talk about
it is
for example people like to do is digits that's good example because it's much more
high dimensional than the oil data we talked about before
this is what it is is far from the the paper
zero is read the one is green that are associated with one very small is
RBF kernel MLP kernel to the blue one
three years in service of the between the ability using the threes and fours are
so again visualizations of those
sort of things and you can see with PCA
you get a lot of overlap GGM again we get a good separation
but we get this grading effect but once again if we look at the classification
rates GTM does the best services twenty five digits from USPS
dataset and that's what we needed space to take on the data to get training
data half the data
and take test data but due to performs the GPLVM
i it would be interesting to do that
gplvm rather my one and see what the results of and but i haven't done
how done
you mean
am i doing multi class
this is my idea
this the one i have code for is the same processes talking about same process
classifier is the same classifier in each case i guess the topic use isn't that
so non-linear one yet
so thanks for that clarification in case we do some down because one of the
things we can do
the sort of algorithms you can't do with kernel PCA
basically because we have
a mapping
the latent space we observe space
is we can take things in that space and quickly ask what it looks like
in the observe space
one was a real passion for calling this fantasy data
so what
this data set here
is the dataset you might be familiar with the attendant a video sequence of moving
brenda moving space around so these fantasies of brendan frey
it and this is the RBF kernel is the visualization is no associated label because
it's just to move it
now as i move around you can see i can make friends move around doing
different things
now clear is there twenty by twenty eight
he's up there
i should point out three twenty by twenty eight images so i hope it's clear
that you would to make it bigger
OK so i can move around it seems to kiss you
two point four
so you see there a lot of
where is on one side and then kind of movie five interpolated something wrong sign
that kind of thing that i've
so i mean there's no data to try to interpolate you see the uncertainty
yes hi
thing here
massive which is why you can't visualize the uncertainty so on
i don't because it's an RBF kernels i talked to just go back to his
mean phrase
i mean just move around and in doing and again that it has no problem
and it's not quite smooth
so they make shape
because we can
action is a little things you can think about these things are unlikely
one thing that if they to show you what i pointed leaves shade and side
he's facing left and on the right-hand side is facing my body is here because
across the system and there's no global correlation of that time
just to show the difference in effect you get if you don't use that covariance
if you use the MLP one
and of course you know this thousands of covariance matrices waiting to be discovered
all of which you can use
so this is the same visualization again
in this case we're using the p stock variance this one the saturates as you
back to the data space so if you the space he'll stay
he was
primary emphasis
for the next few minutes
in the mean
she said
it's important
so you want to get
it's it's it's good it's much more
you start with
these bonds are you not to
forty four
one of the distributions within each
the key
so we
and this is just one of these
so this is picture
o point of this
c is sort of a compliment from which is was written
so the company from which was
the main difference in each of these models
lord which features was
what makes
the said
three days
if you
you know
so this is
i don't know
for every one
not as
it is
it was
he was
as you know
so of course this is
one is that
she the well all these are some
is the way the way scoring and support
what will also each term match
phrases are little special scored phrase results in one to one score
four for the phrase match
and then we we some of us
so it's it's this in fact is treated as a vector
then each of these
is is a
is a component of the vector in the search term and this is just something
is multiplied into that component of the vector it's a little bit more complicated than
that in the nested trees are between a little differently
but that's the basic idea
when you pass the query
there is a couple of
special things that happened
is that a certain carey characters
form implicit racism is actually the same as that of web search engines do
because they don't have to describe this very much but
you may not be aware in this seems to be the set of characters that
everyone uses
so that if you take into your l
it's implicitly is exactly the same is searching for
this this phrase
because these characters
for all implicit phase operators
and same with email addresses
these researchers
i believe in the search engines will return exactly the same documents
so that's
something we do as well
we index also was established
the next time
let's start with a stop order in the query is normally removed this is again
a standard practice in search engines has as good
performance properties as well that unless someone explicitly requires with a plus sign you it
in the query or put it in a phrase
it's not
the international edition of this stuff is
evolving i believe
you have to look and see what the latest state of things and i think
which should be should different samples per language
and there but the thing is is usually
searching you declare your language at query time you don't you don't
inferred automatically so documents you and the language automatically so when searching you have different
stop list ending with the declared search
so it makes sense
let's see was so you can also use
so the the stop words can can be a performance problem because they are very
common in lots of documents that are not search for the convoy so
this this gets a lot of them but then they do end up phrases and
how can you help phrases well do n grams of its upwards
occur in
he it was that was occurring phrases we can
before hand and n grams of you if we say the word is is a
stopword if we have some some
running text
well also in the if in those words stop words then we get index in
phrase as a single word and even in a single word
and the grandson of a single word is well known that way
i'm automatically search for those of us and when you don't have to search for
the high frequency words ever because you combine them with their neighbors and make them
low frequency words
that makes sense
again this is all some stuff that you can extend and change this is the
the same with what is about how things are indexed as the default
the way things are this is the default queries translated but applications can extend this
modifier arthur presented here
subjects for performance another dimension by the
and rams
and so we can convert is automatically to ten gram queries
we also can convert common binary terms
two bit vectors surface if you search for documents in a particular language we can
accelerate that very easily by by catching a bit vector the matches
and the same with particular content types
and so on otherwise this can be very expensive if used frequently
the biggest probably speed that we get is by
sorting indexes and
this is the a technique has been described in the literature
it's been used in industry for
the longer i think
and the idea is that if you have some
objective measure page quality like pagerank or some similar things when you sort
the posting lists in the indexed by that so that the
in the ordered you see documents when you're searching when you when you're conducting searches
is see the higher scoring pages first