so imagine for example that removing different edges
i love the space of you know taking a given edge and removing it partitions
it into two pieces and now i have another piece not remove et cetera my
can end up getting a whole bunch of some problems that are similar in there
i am
OK you know if i take out this one then i take out say this
one here
and then i'll have another tree here here
OK that would be
that would be the same as if i had originally taken this out and then
taken that one out
so if by look at some wearing of taking out the the edges and we
end up with a whole bunch of overlapping subproblems
so what does that suggest we use as an approach
dynamic programming
what a surprise
yes you could use the temporary but it turns out
minimum spanning tree exhibits
and even more powerful properties
OK so dynamic so we got all the clues for dynamic programming
it turns out there's even a bigger club
it's going to help us to use an even more powerful technique
and that
we call the whole
four greedy algorithms
that is we have a thing called the greedy
which says a locally optimal
choice is globally after all
cause all these hallmarks
the kind of thing one boxes
take these are the clues that you're going to be able to do do so
we have this property
we call them
greedy choice problem show you how it works in this case
we haven't really choice property it turns out you can
do even better than dynamic programming
so when you see the two dynamic programming properties
is a clue that says dynamic programming yes
but also it says let me see whether
it also has this greedy property because if it does you going to come up
with something is even better than dynamic programming
so if you just have the two you can usually do dynamic programming if you
only have
but if you have this third one is like whoa
so here's the theorem and proof
to illustrate this idea
c and these are not
no these hallmarks are not things there's heuristics there
you know they're not i can give an algorithm to say here's where dynamic programming
work so here's where greedy algorithms work
but i can certainly indicate when they work the kind of structure they have
so here's the first term so let's let t
the the MST
of course paragraph
and let's let a be any subset of the
some subset of vertices
and now let's suppose
that is you
he is
is the least weight edge
are set a two
complement that has been my essay
and the theorem says
easy and the minimum spanning tree
so let's just take a look at our
graph over here and see if that in fact the case
so let's take
so one thing i could do for a is just take a singleton out
so i think a singleton node let's say this guy here
that can be my a and everything else is b minus a and i look
at the least weight edge
connecting this to everything else but there are only two edges that connected to everything
theorem says that the lighter one is in the minimum spanning tree
if you take a look at every
vertex that i picked the lightest edge coming out of that vertex
is in the minimum spanning tree
the lightest weight vertex edge coming up but that's not all the edges that are
in here
or let's just say imagine let's let's take a look at these three vertices connected
to to
this set of vertices three edges going across the least weight one is five that's
the minimum spanning tree
OK i can cut it this way
OK the ones above
so the it is going down seven eight fourteen seven is the
please wait it's in the minimum spanning tree
so no matter how i choose i could make you know this one and this
one out this one and this one out this one and this one this one
and this one out
take a look at all the edges are whichever one the least weight it's in
the minimum spanning tree
in some sense that's a local property
so we have to look at what the rest of the tree is i'm just
looking at some small set of vertices if i wish
i say well
i wanted to connect that set of vertices are as the world
and so
along all these patterns with the same number of black nodes and therefore every
leaf will have the same that
let me write down some of these properties
so every
in general
has between two and four
everybody has the same data
the black eyed of the room
this is by property property for
this is telling us alive
so essentially what this transformation is doing is ignoring the red nodes
and then you just focus on the black nodes height equals black i
and then
like i was telling us that all the root to leaf pads
i have the same
for all these nodes are at the same level
having leaves at the same levels of good things
the museo trees pretty much balanced tree where all the nodes are branching
so they all have at least two children
and all these are at the same level
that's pretty balanced cable proved
some form that now
i'm going to call
the height of the tree
h prime
the height of the original tree
this page
that's what we want to bound
so the first thing is to h prime and then we want to relate h
and h right
the first question is how many leaves are there
in this tree and it doesn't really matter which stream looking at because i didn't
do anything all these are black so leaves to change
how many leaves other industry and therefore industry
it's a
nine into her nine but i mean in general search
in this example there are nine
how many keys are there
so in general
the right nine is the function of eight
for large values of nine
or it
plus one good correct answer by guessing
and was one
and plus one
because whenever we have let's look at the binary tree case where we sort of
understand what's going on
so where you have the key
there are two
that's not a very good argument but
we have what he what is here called a branching binary tree every internal node
has exactly two children
and we're counting the number of leaves that you get from that process in terms
of the number of internal nodes the number of leaves in the tree
branching tree is always one plus the number internal nodes
you should know that
you can prove it by induction
so the number of these is and plus-one one doesn't hold if you have a
single child
of every internal node has
french infrastructure
OK this is an archive three
and now we want to pull out some relation between the number of leaves and
the height of the tree
so what's the good relations
to use here
we know exactly how many leaves are are that will somehow connected to an
what we care about is the height in this look at the height of the
so if i have
a two three four tree
hi h prime
how many leaves could it have
what's the minimum and maximum number of these it could have
two to the age to forty HRH crown
so we also know
in the two three four tree
it has to be
between forty eight times as the most i can branch four ways in each node
and it's it lists
to the age prime because i know that every node branches at least two ways
that's the key
so i only care about one of these
i think this one
so i get that to the age prime
is it most
and plus one
the number of these is and was one we know that exactly
so we rewrite the take logs about science so h one
is it must log and so on
so we have a nice balance tree should be into it if i had every
node branching two ways
and all the leaves at the same level that's the perfect tree should be exactly
log base two of n plus one it turns out not quite an
that should be the height of the tree here i might have even more branching
which is
making things even shallower in some sense
so i get more leaves at the same height but that's only better for me
that will only decrease the height in terms of the number of these
and plus one here is that
the number of leaves
why does it do that
why does not immediately after
it touches
the board why does it immediately repel
o thing
that's interesting isn't it
i can see the roles
would very much also
volume on
and i would call it very well the should but don't you stand up front
i will
the nice for you don't know
just just stand here come here
look at all
boy i have all i forgot this one this is a real big
that's a nice one
if i wrote this one
it's to do that
i think it will stick to the blackboard
who says it will to the blackboard come up professor model of all of what
you say irreducible postings
professor watson was a ballistic
he says no
o o
well stay
who says it will not stay on the blackboard
why is that
why doesn't this one stay in the others do
that's right it is so much heavier than the others
they have no problem with this one does that's all it is it wants to
stick but it's too heavy
i'm very careful
like for the little or maybe
so you see those who said it works
take a right
and those who said it's not going to stick rosa right
obviously not professor at MIT could make that mistake so that's why they will three
i now
one two
explore further
the idea of conservation of charge
and what i want to do
it is i want to
charge of
the student
beating students
was capture
and then
the story will get a particular chart plus or minus whatever that is
when i went to be here
we'll get the opposite charge
and then we will see
whether we can demonstrate to you that when we touch each other that indeed
charts from him
a former goes to me
i need to volunteer for that
someone who is very brave
i want to really a youngster
i know you've been
being a student of me for many years
when i was a youngster you're so close what's your name
alex alex
i have a little nervous
you should be
now you see this is called the right
not good not good don't take it off
but we need something more synthetic
and this is what you're going to wear
we're going to put you on this tool which is very well insulated
yes what you can always been used this is quantity
what i'm saying is that if you have the same value here
four different values of x x
next it is also
the point is that
in general function of x a b and c
i have
an arbitrary freedom
to assign
any value
all those
i was and still have to tell you
when you don't
so basically what the graphical model is is
the following
if you given a set of conditional independence statements for the fact
something of this kind
i have been impact
which is of the original object image or whatever it is
representation probabilistic
just settle off
all of the bibles and then we happen to
to know
conditional independence bowl
in biology we know
but conditions
and construct of condition
with the graphical model is
the family of probability distributions
where those
conditional independence statements
that's what the graph
so any probability distribution that set of conditions have been told is an element of
agra graphical model of a graphical model is not a single probability distribution is a
family of probability distributions that
i respect those conditional independence
so basically if you go to take the product distribution actually compute
compute the probability and compute the probability assuming this position get the same number
this is an important question is the basis of the
i will give a complete characterisation of
what the class conditional of distribution defined by a set of conditional independence statements
remember the questions we want to address
we wanted to estimate parameters of the model
given that
want to compute probabilities of particular outcomes
find particularly interesting realizations for example that site now stands between the most likely
realisation after five years another names are most like
joint realization
but you know not to manipulate the probabilistic model because we want to compute these
things we want to questions we
we need to
twenty member where we start this
quite the first lecture we saw what we we saw the
there are about four interesting question to me one way
but general probabilistic approaches model
and i
in order to us
to answer this question to manipulate
these probabilities
and to manipulate the probability function you to exploit the structures existing as it exists
in the problem
and that's what we went
so we need to find ways of computing efficiently
in that
yes will
this national department
but also more
OK and essentially learning by using this make the criteria
o thing and parameter from a sample from about this
you an estimate
and then we'll see maximum like this which
common types
you know the criteria five
if you have nothing meaningful to model the criteria for choose the
that's called in this to me
a function that maps the data to ground
so how does
p of x look like OK
let's look at these
probability distribution p of x one x two and x three
let's assume that these conditions depend on hold
let's work out
however these
prior distribution
if we assume that these hold
so if this holds
but we have
well the first thing we write just the conditional distribution of x one x three
given x two
this is
x one given x extra
times p of three given extra this conditional independence
remember the initial condition
this condition depends is exactly
what we're interested in is the marginal distribution of the state house where we have
integrated out g
so this is called the polya urn scheme so that's
in in bayesian nonparametrics there's lots of
there's lots of metaphore so we have heard about the stick breaking construction this is
called the polya urn scheme
the idea of this scheme is is as follows so imagine that we have and
OK so is a really large so
ball think of it as a ball
and we start with no balls in the urn
well we're going to do this
the following so at each iteration
we're going to have
this two possible events happening with probability proportional to alpha
we're going to draw
theta and
so at iteration and with probability proportional to alpha we're going to draw theta and
from from a base distribution h
and if we think of the fate has the value of the fetus as
as the color
and that so
so this tells us
the colour of the ball
and what we're going to have a ball that colour into our
so at the first iteration you and then with probability proportional to n minus one
region today and pick up a ball at random
and then we're going to
we're gonna rock record the colour of of the ball and returned two balls of
the same colour back into the
so the first iteration
and minus one is zero so with probability one
was simply cannot draw
theta one from h
and put the ball that colour into the so now has exactly one ball and
its colour is theta one
the next iteration with probability alpha over
alpha plus and minus one for over one plus
i alpha
we're going to do the same thing going to draw
the colour from each
and then put the ball of the column
and today and with probability one over
one class of work in the region to the and then pick up ball in
this case
well it will be
the theta one ball
and then we're gonna record its colour and put two balls of the same colour
back into the and which is going to repeat this in infinite and the colours
of theta one theta two and so forth that is
record and when we find this scheme is going to be turns out to be
a draw from theta one theta two and so on with g integrated
the conditional distributions are as follows so theta and
one two and minus one
so the colour of the and
given the colours of the first n minus one balls withdrawn is going to be
is the distribution of theta and here the conditional distribution is going to be
given by the following so with probability alpha over
and minus one plus alpha
and this is going to be drawn from h
and with probability one over
and minus one plus alpha theta and it's going to on exactly the same value
the the i
so we can think of this polymer and give some sort of a representative for
the dirichlet process because each of these conditional distributions is
it's kind of a finite mixture model
basically and we can think of this as some sort of a finite projection of
the infinite dimensional object
which is g
any questions
simple construction
the next process the next representation of the dirichlet process is called the chinese restaurant
process so this is yet another metaphor for the dirichlet process
the chinese restaurant process goes as follows so
if we look at
theta one two theta and the set of values drawn from this polya urn scheme
they will take on
this thing to values
so let's label them to test by one two three test talking
and that is the probability that
any two
of the three ties in this list will take on exactly the same value
so what this is is that
we can partition the state i want to an into
in two k different clusters each cluster given by
by a value
from this fate as stylist
so for example
they tell one is
and think that way
the rule
it actually is that they have all this
you know so
so this is that we can partition this into
theta one thousand three
so this is a partition of
of the sequence into
in two different fate which which take on the same value
and the chinese restaurant process is basically the distribution over partitions
that we can study this
this process so the nice thing with the chinese restaurant processes that
it splits out the
this kind of
two different effect what's going on here one is that
one is the actual value of the test is simply drawn from the base distribution
and the and the second one is the clustering structure on the state s and
the chinese restaurant process counter tells us about how about the clustering structure without referring
to the
base distribution h itself
and then the generative process for this chinese restaurant process is is as follows
so the first customer comes in and sits at the first table
customer one here sits at table number one
and in subsequent customers
so customer and
we'll see that table k
with probability
and k over n minus one class of so is proportional to n k where
and and even
even it's in but sparse so for example this does work fuse fuse although
strings of length eight and fourteen a inspection from its works for this matrix for
twenty of the feature space is ten to fourteen to mention a few some efficient
sparse data structure
and if is
so then you visit get speedup of up to factor and
OK so
you have to
two computers have to be to be able to
users w must be able to to access each dimension of the w using some
some index
so for example you have to be able to enumerate all these came as and
you need
and it's been need only future operations between able the two cities w two zero
in the to be able to have to eat some
scalar value to one component of w and you must be able to to look
up one component of w
so this this is what the operation this
that has to be quite efficient if you want to do
like the three large data sets
and quite quite important this use storage
so you should use an explicit
explicit that if you're dimensionality is it's quite a a lot of this to w
also them because in the of course of basically just
just and this one then we look up
you could use sort of area so
which is something else possible it contains and the look of course is quite high
because if someone
and there but it's still quite efficient if you if you if you string length
UK becomes too large
you want to look up then you should
use for example the suffix tries trees is so
so this this table just summarizes the
costs that exists in new
and you do use one of these data structures
and it looks like the suffix tree is slightly more
what the like the fastest one
because it just has a linear it's linear time in
look out for
for the
all the possible and in one sequence however
it has like it has a huge overhead in memory storage so at least forty
unit is forty by to store four four one
i came here to destroy this there's almost almost no
i mean you need to have w so it's not not really big memory we
had an explicit map sorted areas some more you need from some more memory but
not not that much more so you can you can draw the conclusion that if
you have like a very very small forbid that this explicit that this
they very efficient for like for the
for example
if you have sort to recent work much better for
large alphabets and you have
if you have like really low high order and large format and should use suffix
OK so
so this is not the only applied to that a spokesman classifier applied a huge
speedups using this i mean you can be really apply to support vector machines on
the whole human genome sort six billion data points
it is this vegetable problems
the only problem is of course that if you have many many support vectors w
may be extremely huge
and this does the trick two
decomposers w into into some some subparts and to do do with this but i
will continue to here
the same
so it doesn't tell you what it doesn't take a whole new home can speed
up the support vector machine training so this just another number of tricks which is
what you can do that
the new and usually self-supporting machine you have like a sum decomposition i'd like chunking
SMO and
caching is
fishing is
quickly becomes quickly feasible if the number of data points that you consider this
it's like one million or larger because in you just cannot store the all these
discussion anymore memory
so it actually where this district he also help because you don't come crashing at
all anymore
you can you can grow quite i mean you can go a lot lot for
the so basically the future sometime consented the ideas
i mean in in the senate ranking SVM you have to compute you just basically
choose select some working set or which optimizes the put the problems and the thing
is that at each iteration you have to compute the output for all the training
which is exactly where we could use the net trying to get the good news
is that only a few of these variables change in optimisation so we don't need
that many of these at operations to sort make sure to to this
to some kind of knowledge
OK so
so these are the the
the updates this sort of this you have to compute at each iteration does not
does not efficient at all it's quite often you suggest that you start with an
f of zero and just
just update the vectors which which which changed in the working
and now we
all have to do is just use this to that approach basically compute the w
on on the working set
which is
this this quantity and just
just apply
this technique and this this way we
we we can we can we don't need the competition anymore
get get a slightly modified SVM optimise and
first of all of course still if the number of examples highland and the most
draw a series of normal lines to this curve and start doing one-dimensional signal processing
for feature detection along these lines are now
this is very economical of course compared with the snakes methodology next methodology in principle
you have to compute feature maps over the entire image which is the reason why
the work here
if you have a good hypothesis you can restrict the work you do to simply
one-dimensional prior image processing along this series occurs we have these sampled normals to be
computed directly from a particular configuration of the contour and now we do the search
along those normal lines
now one one interesting thing is that
if i
you don't have this this is a little bit like a regression problem isn't it
i mean if i had a graph
one of x in some data points and i was in order to minimize the
sum of squares error to that that data points that there's a point where you
can imagine
doing something like what i'm going to have to do here
with the parameters x of that graph y of y of x but what we
have here is a little bit more difficult because it's a parametric curve in two
dimensions rather than the graph so now
when i search for features along these normals and i find the particular point intersect
the normal
i'm not really entitled to regard the feature as a two dimensional point in spacetime
not entitled to say that
this point here
is being mapped to or drawn towards this point here what i'm entitled to say
is that this is the section of the true curve corresponding to this
section of the initial curve is likely to pass through this point
so in other words i know a lot about the displacement of the curve along
the normal
but i should take that as being information
the position of the the curve is perpendicular to the normal
so this is this blue dot here should be taken as a sort of ten
observation of the tangent to the curve not of a particular point in particular parameter
on the curve so you know we're thinking about is that i start with the
initial curve rx best and they get a new curve rx of s and
can be some slippage of the parameterisation of the nuclear relatively ok we shouldn't assume
that these normal lines joined corresponding parameter values that would be
so what we have to do
to make the least squares measures which are sensitive only to the
displacement in the normal direction
so instead of having to
tempted to cover it up on the screen and of course that won't work instead
of having a term which emits
and investors which would be the normal kind of sum squared error term
we put the
dot product with the and as in the estimated normal curve
that will ensure that the influence of this particular data point is only felt along
the normal as it were not
so now what we have is
because of our best which is the initial estimate where we are and then we
can think of having an observed curve which was however only observed at particular points
as set by along that curve
and now
it's useful to define innovations which is the things we square to get those
error terms the innovation is the difference between the
the predicted position of
the point on the curve and the corresponding position on the new feature curve but
with its influence restricted to
the normal direction
and finally the way that we can absorb this into a least squares principle efficiently
is to define an observation matrix h of s little age which is like the
original observation matrix h of capital HFS that we had before
but dotted with this
normal vector so that it gets turned from HMS would be let's say two by
six matrix for the fine space is that the age of this is going to
be won by six matrix with its influence restricted just to that normal curve
i think
it's been a while while i covariance
not yet i mean that that's coming that's coming but quite a few slides down
the line so eventually yes we will be interested in estimating variances along these along
these girls but for the moment is just
a geometrical construction that is based on the initial k
OK so finally we could make ourselves a recursive least squares algorithm that would crawl
along the curve from one end to the other
this algorithm is in your notes and
a partial solution to this curve fitting problem in fact you can stop at any
intermediate point which is the virtue of recursive solutions to least squares problems i can
stop at some intermediate and and get what is my current best estimate
the position of the newly fitted curve to the data that i just got
and you see a each
step as he step i what happens is that this as matrix is accumulated with
a product of those two h vectors so what's happening here is that this will
see later can be interpreted as information matrix and the information associated with the latest
measurement along the normal is
so this is getting more like you're variance idea
it is a product
of the h vector with itself
information component into the total information sites that the point i along the the curve
it will turn out of the total statistical information with accumulated is as i
i would like to point in me
so what you do it
following dictionaries which are the first is
one of the things that you
so what is it for
one of
we have some day
somebody is going to
and what we want to find the location of the data on to the shore
in is going proposition exists then it means that the dictionary is one of the
key to the data
so for instance for images
people have been using for years these
then wavelets have been struggling vol twenty years to find the best dictionary which is
that the natural images
there have been some of the works which instead of
trying to find the dictionary by hand
have tried to learn it
and this is the kind of world that we follow today
it turns out that this disease
can be formulated as a large scale
the problem
and what it mean
intended to add these efficient
so that if you are able to do this if you can make some large
scale image poses problems tractable
and also it makes sense to
values matrix factorisation programs such as negative decisions
and the formulation of PCA
so we start by describing the
you know
and he thought that come back to from the first division which was not all
on the problem and image processing tasks
that is if you be nice
no the image y
how can we recover the original image ix
so i can give you a very simple algorithm
we can do it in three days decide
we almost state-of-the-art results
here is what you consider image you extract all overlapping
of the small size
o point for instance by itself
so that you have a large number of
but she
for instance if you have one mil mi eight
you you have about one million of small but the one that and that if
then you find a dictionary which is identical to the set of patches
so we know know which is a metric the here
which is composed of about a few number of it in one thousand two hundred
you want to there the matter with all of your
i want to i was born
so the point here is the
we are in the town the stuff the city where you have a single but
laughs about the problem you have we we have here they should of small sparse
coding problems
so in a that so that when you take the feature we may want to
do that again i will have between them to get the image of about twenty
then you have to solve these
but each
batch you obtain approximation the alpha i so that each you as many teammates
as such belongs to
and so that you can just outside the city limits of ten find ticket image
so here is an example of what you can get the same middle
which is called the state of the art in image thing
for image denoising this
so on the left hand been those emails i'm going to talk about
for the kind of applications images
for instance if you
that's the whole image i have to
you can do image compression
so here what we have done we have this image on the left leg
we have no
on the damaged image
knowing where the pixels are missing
and which are the said which
the missing
and we are able to pull
well we are able to recover some textual the house which is even visible
on the left
if you want to know how the
the looks like an example of
from the nineteen h
it has here to fifty six it was known the that on
that's the size a a and i think there is not much more to say
about this
so let's come back to the formulation of the training that
presented and give a little more detail
so i what presented
the c
we just
or you don't
two d
because if you look at the first is that he said
he could be arbitrary not we don't realize it
so that's what people usually do it just
the whole trained number of the columns of the to be less than one
so now we have here non nonconvex optimisation problem but
if you fix it
and you can make with the EU then the convex optimisation problem and should easy
you obtain a large number of small convex optimisation one that can solve the classical
just as a between the musicians on the
and the musicians of alpha so he quality that was all but there is one
this is
the other is thinking
and so you look at the first index i wear as you increase their one
variable x this be minus eight times the column with
be minus
that's called matrix
zero you pick out by
and that's are leaving variable
and now we just do algebraically originally equations that the variable x j on the
left and the variable w i on the right
and i will show you how to do this uh i mean show some examples
in just a few seconds' here
but it is trivial algebra it's just exactly like gas in elimination where you have
standard tyre girl which we zeroing one column in used in your process
inverting a matrix using gauss and elimination
and you'll see what i mean in this
we get this rearrangement now the y axis and the w is a kind kind
mixed up and they get more and more mixed up
as we do this several times and so in general the notation will be
like this that i have some nonbasic variables which are denoted by x subscript and
and that's the next so the original x variables and the and the and the
original w variables they get all mixed up
and our basic variables x be
and that's what the rest of the variables that are in the x and
can be a coefficients multiplayer it will change its orbital till period indicate that this the numbers here
are different because we don't discuss the elimination type step
which we call a pivot by the way
can be in any also get change so i put all those on top
come but all the variables are still not negative and this is a completely equivalent
way of writing the problem is this
and that's the whole point we go from this to this just by algebraic rearranging
the equations but we could undo the rearrangement and go back from this back to
so we have a much changed the problem with only
represented in a different way
we've taken
are dictionary and are defining different variables are taking
different variables are given fundamental variables and defining a different set variables x being
and the winners are all there but as we do these iterations we get a constant appearing here
is the current value of the objective function
and not will go up and up because we're maximizing so we started zero and just are all
go higher and higher as we iterate
so you find on the internet i can actually demo this
but i'm not
but i also have a local version so
let's get going bad
demo here
let me make sure it's feasible
the problem
tool here doesn't always generate feasible problems
so there's a feasible problem right here
so in this particular problem
i have to
objective coefficients are positive like a you one them as the entering variable you x two x form
we have to make a decision so
i'll pick x two
i picked it because it has the larger coefficient but
there's no
guaranteed benefit that's just
tempting so i'm tempted topic
x two
now as i looked down the column here so
at all these variables are equal to zero in the dictionary solution associated with this dictionary
and now thinking about improving the solution
o one x two which is currently zero enter increase
and is it increases
this w one which is currently five starts to go up at a rate of two
and so this one's gonna go up and i don't have to worry about this
the w one equals zero however
and similarly other ones that have a negative number inside this little box here and
and the negative side there are going up so
w one w three w five don't worry about but w two and w four
morphologically complex nouns
they are derived using the right kind of such suffix the verbal abstract noun producing
is the class of suffixes including meant in ireland
give semantics for those amounts
and it's
used in the derivation
such a key
this rule
sensitive to weather
a for
as the verbsemtrans canonical solution
it's as if they were not assertion that used
to conclude
the possessor is going to have the victims
and we what i what we i want to expand the coverage of the
in the future
and there's lots more to do
so i should stop talking and my there's ask questions but
to summarize
the cyc lexicon
it it's represented in the cyc KB
you have access to all the school ontological engineering stuff
so we use a valueable predicates
you can also have
exceptions to the rules you can do it very very expressive
means of representing lexicon
and it's also generative so you can derive new
lexical entries
mappings between form and meaning
inference rules
it's kind of an interesting enterprise but
innerstad copperhead forces you to come down on one side or another
i don't think so
one of the
i don't know
that can carry
i mean i don't mind
of course
this area
you know
twenty years
it's like
o five
don't want to find
you know
and you
in the
all known to
here you and
the rule
four days
x one
and this one
no of course
no no
the only
the room one one
you can see here
very very very small
o one
he wrote was one of four
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
so welcome back and what i want to do today is talk about his rap
about discussion on factor analysis and in particular we want to do this
step through
on parts of the derivation for me and factor analysis because
again there there few steps and in derivation they are particularly tricky and there specific
mistakes people often make on deriving sounds like factor analysis so i want to show
you how to do those that's right you can apply the same ideas of problems
as well
on and then in the second half also the structure of the principal component analysis
which is on a very powerful out of four on the dimensionality reduction c that's
what that is
just to recap on
in the previous lecture i just tried to the properties of gases distributions one was
that of
if you have random variable around the value back to x they can be partitioned
into two portions x one x two
on the axes
now assume i mean and covariance sigma
and you is
itself the partition vector and sigma
and so on
so partition matrix that written like that this writing sink in terms of
you know before some blocks
then you can look at the distribution of facts and ask what is the marginal
they have one
the answer is we said last time was the x one the marginal distribution of
x one calcium with mean mu and covariance sigma one sigma one one
is the upper left block that covariance matrix sigma to this this was no surprise
and also wrote down the formula for computing conditional distributions
on the first one is given one given x two
and last time i wrote down the distribution of x y given x which also
be calcium
the road has mu of one given to a sequence one given to
we have one given to a
this is just this one
what these formulas will be able to look at
on a pair of joint calcium random variables x one x example vectors and compute
the marginal and the conditional distributions of the periods one of the for
so i come back
and derive the east that actually well
o come back and use the marginal formula in the second and then when i
come back and derive
the e step in the lower of factor analysis
well actually be using these the form of the game
and again just to continue
summarising what we did last time we said that
no in factor analysis of
our model
see this is an unsupervised learning problem to give
and unlabeled training set for each side is a vector in rn as usual
we want to model
the density of x
and so on
a model FOR acts OF that
we imagine that the latent variables i generate
well this this to zero mean and identity covariance as you will be some low
dimensional thing
and we want
and we imagine the axis
generated as mu plus
lung disease was of ceylon where epsilon this accounts random variable with mean zero
and the covariance matrix
and so the parameters of the model
are all
which is an intentional vector
london which is by dimensional vector
the matrix and so which is
and the diagonal
is the diagonal and the diagonal on
the matrix
i guess the cartoon i drew lost time for factor analysis was set maybe that's
the typical sample of data point xei if on this example i had this one
so it's useful for analysis scale say ten thousand nodes
twenty thousand fifty thousand nodes and say
a billion is so communication events are two years is still open question actually how
you do it was a hundred million something like that this question but in fact
what accept the quadratic size structure is actually very fast way to update
you simply process all communication events in one pass through the sorted sequence
in time
and with each communication of any simply update the vector clock city is let's consider
time six
the message is about to be sent
here's the current clock uses
so when the census message how we process is very simply
with the message comes
the vector clock OK so this was all of these most recent news and maybe
that contains the potential for fresh information
think that we just take the coordinate wise max
of these two that right so in fact by communication see gets a more recent
potential viewers
we don't know what they are going on to have more potential to information certainly
more view these so we take this corner max that season
very very simple so over
billions of communication events we simply run forward in time
always max into factors to get maintains representation
so you have to talk about today is of course interesting it's basically the amount
of potential information gain you just got the communication
OK so with lots of mind was something remind let's think about what this tells
us about our
also ten thousand faculty and staff at the university of change email or use so
the first is that
it says we should think of people as residing in these balls different radii
around this
o point called now right so here's node
is now use everyone within twelve hours current within twenty four hours current everyone out
of here they don't know what's happened to them that right there was no information
can flow
and the reason emails are proxy for the full set of communication events
but the more data one has the more
precisely one can do so the the ball of radius tower and simply all the
information rate is twenty
what we find is that both sides growing sort of piecewise exponential fashion so quickly
first slowing down a bit but so much faster than polynomial efficient compared to what
call randomized
baseline what kept the timestamp in the centre of each email saying
but we allowed to spread like up at random epidemic so the recipient is completely
random so i keep exactly the same trace data but every time you post any
message and said he really sad to send someone shows around so i break all
social structure
this going spread information much much faster and have spread of the spheres around the
we find actually that
after about a day and a half the random epidemic
and the actual real social communication or growing the ball size about and about the
same speed well actually distinguishes the epidemic interestingly is this first
thirty six hours start there's very specific to you know this but in general one
might expect some started
now let's take much much faster rates so
in some sense in the real social communication this set on average you had about
twelve people within a day and after the final decision
here in this
of all of thirty six hours only really know
for people with randomized epidemic
bunches and merely that bubble reaching fifty people and that's that's that's the case
there's also gives way to think about the strength of weak ties this idea that
chance encounters with
this is the queen's can convey what information so the article in which mark granovetter
nineteen seventies
this was to think about the social networks and think about your
close connections with which are embedded in triangles and long range connections and by range
here we simply mean what's
the length of the alternative second shortest path the set
so is french b and c are embedded in this triangle was with d
it was somehow
so structurally essential because otherwise you have to go forth to solve
and the reason is that these long-range local bridges is like a d
when you do happen to talk to them they give you access to parts of
the network the otherwise couldn't see and therefore you operation
but this is sort of
interesting hard theory to test quantitatively because
was i to minimalist most of the studies have been based on interviews with people
really worried about the job opportunities
here we can try to formalize in terms of
there are are with the vector clocks uses that
you meet somebody
who's that long range from you who maybe that's a very frequently
they give you this gigantic vector clock brain to operate so they you clock with
all sorts of coordinates that really lacking in your clock really current and there's and
you get this massive cloud and that we can test so we have here is
a function that range the
in average advanced per message in the vector clock when you talk to somebody that
range we see actually that although the very sort of try capturing want to get
out to translate like four
things are really actually significantly more informative per message in terms of the amount the
advancing and all the information is
so in some sense it is a kind of large-scale wanted
support for this
originally called the theory of
the strength of weak ties as mentioned that reach infinity means is an actual bridge
right the disconnect the graph et cetera there
this only shows up in our data on one end of that is typically incredibly
incredibly tiny components and so you actually to start advanced
we talk about the network back
that information is flowing
your what you think about it
and sent to this guy
OK only cares about
the preference essentially oversee these two variables right so it doesn't care about which he
shared with them and so
that's what happens here when you some out
everything else that
this guy doesn't
doesn't care about this is the message from btcc some out
that b
that he doesn't have so everything in
pretty really just essentially multiply in your potential with the messages
except for you from the the message from you
and then i marginalise out and send it to you
so whenever i never send you can have your own message multiplied
so this is the well defined because there's really no
i wouldn't say OK
OK OK i'm about to wrap up so this is this is
this is one of the few slides since he was the all
you can show this well defined because the trees singly connected you're you're not gonna
get kind of conflicting evidence everything sort of comes in from all my things downstream
to me in the past upstream there's no way but i passed come back to
some cycle
right so
if i decided on something that you know all my children like and i say
that my parents there
then we can all agree and there's not going to be some kind of backflow
communication everything is bottleneck for me
you dismiss propagation and to be this one would see in in centralized version of
an down and then you have all these messages precomputed and what you do
in the end to get a possibilities you take your own potential
you multiply by everybody now every all the also the opinions from other neighbours
and the renormalized
OK if it's not normalized it's it's the your local of kind of opinion in
the opinion of others expresses as messages about your variables
and so we can show this is proportional to the probability as you just need
to normalize
you had do this but so
you can basically show that that was the algorithm is doing is running variable elimination
in all directions at at the same time right so there is a relation that
kind of sums out
one neighbouring and passes everything else to this one in some that name address this
one so this doing is passing this
but this information to everybody same time so
but the
and this could explain this
so you can i mean you can prove it by looking very information and
and seeing that
that they do not serve pushing pushing some
two four meaning that you you take into account all the
all of them
evidence it had to do with
and so
but the running intersection property guarantees the clusters containing i constitute
a connected subgraph right so what that means is that
all of these if there is a variable that share its shared among these all
of these have so woman pasaran messages between each other
what can happen is that always need to agree on what
now the the marginal of that variable is
you can you
sure there's core part that has a variable y in the core and part basically
doesn't have it all and then you when you computing
this message this guy you're something out
sensually i the whole cluster that contains so
by connecting to the variable elimination
procedure you can show that that
you compute the same kind of the same kind of thing that very relational compute
she ran it
you know in the way that eliminated everything here
and then created a factor with this
OK so
and if it proves because it takes too long but just to a summary of
the algorithm is the following is
the coronation order
you get to cliques u
build the cluster graph by pruning out the maximal ones
we find maximum weight spanning tree which is cheap
and then you can start this density that's on the junction tree
so the runtime here just really depends on
the size of these clicks
right because
the maximum weight spanning tree in this case is is trivial
compared to the
the thing to do and when you passing messages because pass messages your
you have
two days for a clique over
the whole set of variables that number is very large
you can efficiently so
so for example if you look at what i mentioned before grid
and if you look at what can you possibly called
two have when you do something like junction tree
for the junction tree so far
this kind of structure
he would be something like this structure start with this
and you would be something that basically
put together
these things
and also something that
the simplest one is just put
all of these guys
given point in all other points are sampled the points
are examined
is examined
and outliers are points that have a spectrum
future hyperinflation again
two more details later
so here is the outline we already survived the introduction and
in the rest of the tutorial i will follow the model of the
classification where we have a model based approach is omitted based approaches
and as the third
kind of last year
adoption adoption of different models with special problem just
picked out one special problem as the sample and i just a high dimensional points
because we are working in so
it's not an advertising for work but i will try to motivate why i think
high dimensional
data is still challenging for four
of the detection of
we will discuss these approaches
and give some sample models and sample rooms here
and we also try to keep in mind the other two
class classification schema
so the output and the rest the resolution of the reference set
are still considered
OK so first of all statistical tests of the general idea of this test for
outlier detection is
OK given a certain kind of statistical distribution for example gaussian distribution then we just
compute the parameters assuming all data points have been generated
by this statistical distribution in terms of the case of course you washington solution just
compute the mean and standard deviation
and then outliers are points that have low probability to be generated by this
distribution so this is very similar to that year
we haven't seen before
in barnet discussion of the case of the problem where we have a caution distribution
of the station periods
and the
observation that it's very much ten weeks
i had a very low probability to be generated by this mechanism
this would be considered as an online
the basic assumption obviously is that the normal data objects follow
a given distribution which should be known of course
and the core in high probability regions small schools
and the of lies on the other hand
deviate strongly from distribution then
to be generated by the switch distribution
and this basic idea here has been implemented in huge number of different tests
that are available
the most important difference of these tests are
which type of these data distribution
is the number of which number of variables univariate or multivariate data
dimension the data was
which number of of distributions only one normal distribution or one
distribution of one mechanism for
four normal objects or or several
and also
we have parameter
parametric and non parametric approach nonparametric approach histogram
or pragmatic approach be computing for example for caution distribution meaning
and yes i will try to give you a very short example which is very
similar to the one we saw
in honest discussion so
we just assume
gaussian distribution
multivariate data
just one model
and we use parametric approach
and what we can do is OK the probability density function of a multivariate normal
quite well known
formerly here
we have to compute the mean and
covariance matrix
and then we can compute the mahalanobis distance of point of any point to me
and interestingly this distance function the interesting
this distance function just follows the chi square distribution
of the degrees of freedom
he is the dimension of data space
and then
typical statistical test is
that points that have a a distance with distance
larger than a given threshold
i mean for all lines
and this is just the visualisation so if people compute the mean on the left-hand
side that crosses the mean of these observations here
and on the right-hand side you have the
so i summarized here the bounds that the
we're discussing this morning
so this is the standard of being bound for one function
the true
average so the expectation is less than the empirical plus
the system that now we have seen many times
one was called of of n
there is this refined version which includes the variance or
an upper bound on the variance which is in this case
the expectation itself
and which is slightly better when the expectation is small and as i told you
this morning what we want is to improve on this union bound and one way
was to
introduced this this prior if you want on the on the set of functions
and and also ways to use the idea of these variants and to use
this parameter here
get a better handle on how big is the class of functions because so far
the only measure of
the size of the class of functions we have seen is the the cardinality itself
of the of the class
now we see that with this trick we can
you know a little bit more precise
OK so
let's let's take a simple example
where we we have a set of functions
finite may be large
but which have the property that they all behave smaller similarly which means they all
make small is the same predictions or they make
all small is the same type of errors
right so
this can be quantified let's say
let's say we even know how different they are
let's say we know that if we take two function f i and j
in this
set of function that we have f
and we look at
how many times or how frequently the predictions of the errors made by the sanctions
are different
this is small and we we know some of that that is an upper bound
on this
OK then we can exploit this fact
in the following way
we just rewriting
the difference between for any function in our class the difference between two an empirical
the same thing for
a fixed function any that we fix beforehand
the difference between two and empirical average of
somehow the difference between f and
and you
where it is
any function in set of zero is something i don't like the centre of the
class if you want or any function in class
now if you look at those two terms
we have something that we know how to bound we have things inequality because the
function is fixed and here is something we can bound using bernstein's inequality
and using the fact that now the variance
of this
run valuable
is actually controlled by
the frequency at which the two functions make different predictions so we can use then
this like an upper bound on the variance of this
quantity here is
actually i
essentially the result that you can get this form
this is the having to from
but the fixed function and this is
the bernstein
i've been sloppy about the constant but that's not important at this point
where now the log in which is the size of the class of functions is
multiplied by these alpha which was the upper bound on
the difference on of the function
OK so what we have gained compared to what we had before is that we
have been able to reduce the complexity
are the
additional term that we gain from looking at me functions by the fact that these
functions they are
there are not too
different from each other
so we went from log in
two and five things look
and this is the first the first point where we can
that's what i call the structure or the geometry of the class of functions so
and this is very important i think maybe that's
the most important
aspect of this lecture of the set of lectures is that
the complexity of the class of functions
in the very precise way
on how this function har
position in the space
so you you have to think about a set of function as
some kind of metric space where the functions are
at a certain distance from each other and the distance comes from
things like
like this right so this you can think of it as the distance between functions
and old always these distance
the set of function becomes a metric space which has a certain structure and the
structure is the thing that controls how
large will the deviation b
when you come consider for example the supremum of the
empirical process
this was the simple case where we have
knowledge on how dissimilar the function so but you can actually go much beyond and
more of the structure
so the first thing to do is to repeat this construction
for the whole set
so what i mean by this is
say you have
you're set of functions from one two capital and and from the set of function
if you slam the brakes
well what happens at will go
what do you think you slam the brakes at the local forward
well go backwards if you accelerate the car all of a sudden
apple will go backwards and and forwards
you can
entertain you apparently thanksgiving
get some
of the twenty five thousand dollars tuition back
when fluids are moving
situations i
way more complicated
then when they are static
and this
leads to
again very
i nonintuitive
of fluids
i will
the rise in a shortcut way
very famous
equation which is called the new easy creation
which relates
kinetic energy is potential energy
suppose i have a
the fluid
non compressible
like so
this cross sectional area
it too
and the pressure here
the two
and i have a
of the liquid
which is the two
this level
is why two
you have a cross sectional area a one
i have pressure p one
my level
what i wanted increase
and i have a much larger
velocity because the cross section is
substantially smaller there
these fluid were completely static
if it were not moving
so forget about if you want to forget about the feature which is sitting still
one minus p two
would be
g and y two
why why why if rho easily
density of the fluid that's post-cold cultural
would just be sitting still
and we know that the pressure here
the lower
and the pressure there
this is also if you want to roll gh
if you call this difference
ro gh
that reminds me of MGH ngh gravitational potential energy
when i defined by
volume i get
so this is really
which is gravitational
potential energy
that makes the and divided by volume become density
pressure itself
must also
have the dimension
of energy
and if we now set this whole machine in motion
then there are three players
it is on the one hand kinetic energy of motion
kinetic energy
i take per unit volume
there is gravitational potential energy
i will take a unit volume
and then there was pressure
there are equal partners
and if i applied to conservation of
and g
the sum of these three should remain constant that's the idea behind
the new is low
noise equation
when i think of fluid element
and i move from one position in the two to another position
it traits b
four either heights
four pressure
one is the kinetic energy per unit volume
well the kinetic energy is one half MV squared i divided by volume i could
one have rome
the script
one is gravitational potential energy that is and why
i divide by volume
so i get
to date
i'd like to talk
with you about
my early days at MIT
and the research that i did here
is a long time ago
i got my phd in the netherlands in
nuclear physics and i came to MIT in january
nineteen sixty six almost thirty four years ago
and the idea was that i was only going to spend here one year on
the post position
i liked it so much
but i never left
and i don't regret it
i joint c
x-ray astronomy group here of professor ross
x-ray astronomy
has to be done
from above the earth's atmosphere we're at least near the top of the earth's atmosphere
because the x-rays
i'm sure
by air
optical astronomy and radio astronomy
which can be done
the ground
the kind of x-rays
that we measure
i'm not unlike those that
your dentist is using when takes an extra
energy range of these x-rays somewhere between one
and thirty forty kilo electron volts and if you don't know what to kill electron
volt is that's fine too which you never expressed
the energy of an x-ray in terms of joules because the number becomes so
ridiculously small
during world war two
on the heat germany
then from brown
the v two rockets
four destructive for purposes was developed in panama
and after the war
the americans use these v two rockets
scientific purposes
the first
rocket flights
to search for x-rays from the sun
two plays in nineteen forty eight
and x-rays were found from the sun
that was quite a surprise
and the power
energy per second that the sun puts out in x-rays
divided by the power in optical which is almost all the radiation of the sun
give it
the symbol of the sun
is approximately ten to the minus so only one ten millions
of all the energy comes out in extra
so from one energy point of view
it's very very little
it's very great deal two
but it is
very little
in nineteen
sixty two
scientist here in cambridge among them professor bruno rossi was a professor at MIT
and we can't check
and because q were working across the street at american science and engineering
i attempted
do an experiment to see whether they could detect x-rays
from object outside
our solar system
now the odds were very low that they were going to succeed
and the reason is very simple
if you take the song
you moved out of the nearest stars which is typically ten to one hundred light
wouldn't stand a chance to see
x-rays fact
the sensitivity of the detectors in these days was
too low by at least
nine orders of magnitude factor of one billion
the two everyone exp
surprised to everyone's
at least as far as i should say they succeeded
and they discover the object
which was later called it's one is in the constellation scorpio is extant to x-rays
and one
for the first x-ray source in the constellation
the total
output of that source was about ten thousand times more than the sum that didn't
make the source so special because many stars in the sky
that radiate way more
and then are summed us
but also very special
about go x y
that the
x-ray power
over the optical power
four scorex one
was approximately
one thousand
in other words
x-rays and dominate its source of energy
and the optical this sort of let's call it byproduct was the son
optical is the main thing
and the x-rays is sort of a by product
so to sixty four dollar question in those days was what can these objects be
they must be very different from the sun
and that's what i want to
discuss which when it came to MIT
in nineteen sixty six there were about six
of these x-ray sources known in the sky
today there are thousands no
there were six them
and they were discovered from rocket flights these rockets will be launched
typically from white sands
and they would spend about five minutes above the earth's atmosphere
during those five minutes they scanned the sky
and six sources were
i joined here the group of professor george clark who still professor at MIT
he was working on
observations made
to be made from very high flying balloons so we would build the telescope
we would launch it on the balloon
and go near the top of the atmosphere
it's not as good as it
rocket flight which
that's completely out of the atmosphere about
the flights on balloons can last longer than five minutes rocket flights we could fly
and if we're lucky even days with the price we pay for that is that
even though there was only very little atmosphere left by force
o point three percent of the atmosphere was left
still that
cause and effect of the absorption so we did lose
x-rays that the rocket flights did not
but we had the great advantage of many many hours
give you
a rough idea
of what it took in those days
i worked on this was graduate students and with many undergraduate students
telescope in those days to build the cost typically a million dollars
and it will take us two years to build one the balloons that we needed
to launch there were about a hundred thousand dollars in those days
and helium
that we needed to get it up was about
eighty thousand dollars
with the surroundings in terms of temperature at at thermal equilibrium equilibrium population of vacancies
and this is crystal and so what we're going to do is it's a comparison
of the binding energy comparison the binding energy
to the the energy of disruption
energy of destruction because you can imagine the binding energy of an atom is the
negative of the energy to form a vacancy how you form a vacancy can imagine
you go with atomic tweezers and you pull Adam out and what once you have
to break the bonds of bond that to others so this is the this is
minus the energy of vacancy formation of
and the disruptive energy is in our case thermal energy and so there is a
way of expressing this and we're going to say it's given by the following we're
gonna compare these 2 in an exponential model like the 1 you saw
course so I'm going to define the fraction the fraction of sites that are unoccupied
and which will be the ratio of the number of vacancies per unit volume to
the number of sites per unit volume so that in V is a number of
vacancies per unit volume and big M is the number of atomic sites number of
atomic sites per unit volume income and that's gonna be given by
the ratio of mediated through this exponential of
the energy and II loosely move energy and entropy back and forth this is the
enthalpy of vacancy formation of vacancy formation energy of the a vacancy formation of energy
over the thermal energy how do we get a rough measure of the thermal energy
the product of the Boltzmann constant an absolute temperature so what are we doing we're
taking this on to
the temperature distribution and we're saying where is this requires energy in relation to the
average energy of the system and in particular the high entail behind him so
and it has a prefactor a and is just an entropic factor and it's not
equal to 1 able to take values between the 10th of up to about here
and it's typically on the order of for 5 something like this but in some
in some cases it can even be less than 1 so this is a relationship
that tells us what the fraction of unoccupied sites as as a function of temperature
so that we could go in and and calculate what the effect bond energy because
we know what the thermal energy has to work backwards and calculate that side a
sample calculation was wondering you know which should be
the vacancy population a piece of copper so I said copper what happens that the
enthalpy of
the formation of vacancy is 1 . 2 9 electron volts per atom and the
factor is equal to 4 . 5 and look this up in tables this is
not from 1st principles calculations so I said OK let's look at room temperature and
room temperature upload these numbers in and I got on
the fraction of vacant sites as 10 to the minus 21
10 21 of you multiplied by the density of copper that turns out to be
85 vacancies 85 vacancies per cubic centimeter on this is vanishingly small
this is vanishingly small this is almost the inverse is almost none right because we
have roughly Avogadro's number of atoms per cubic centimeter for condensed matter so this is
really really low and 21 there's a hundred different insurance there is 85 there so
few you can't give each meaning of
and then so that simple whenever we go to the melting point at the melting
point of copper OK I'm not going to melt the copper like ice at 0