so i use the next forty minutes the test
and share some recent work
carried out by a number of collaborators one of whom is in the audience professor
the others the all about a significant fraction
i real economists
and the very first thing i'd like to emphasise with collaborators is not only
they do the work
but if we did not collaborate with real economies we would have many many many
more mistakes
i'm not saying there are no mistakes by collaborating interdisciplinary science with subject specialists you
minimize the number of mistakes i'd like to get that point across particularly to young
people who may
i have the confidence so they can do everything themselves or field that's expected of
them to do everything themselves
so the data
key question will ask the question that any physicist would ask when confronted with any
kind of economic fluctuations
we take any newspaper any newspaper a significant fraction of that paper is the bunches
of numbers which are the fluctuations in stock market prices then not the prices no
one cares no one even knows what they mean we care about the fluctuations
this is obviously the subject matter of statistical physics
but in statistical physics we asked the most obvious questions like how why what's going
on here near a critical point for example there are use fluctuations and bought over
their correlated so they're bigger than they would be if they were not correlated
and we ask why why why should a critical point may the fluctuations
so we'll have a simple question here about the economy
we have far more or less
the paradigm that worked in critical phenomena and that paradigm at the risk of belittling
the work very great people was first and foremost to start with the experiment to
form bonds between experimentalists and simulators and calculators and it was only many many years
later that people such as a wilson gallegati and others began to
formulate some kind of theory we are roughly in that stage we have mainly collected
experimental facts about the economy
and we have begun just begun
when i say we i mean in collaboration was obviously got there
one french writers prize year or so ago or the best kind of physicists under
certain major forty
i had to begin an actual possible theory
but you know theories come and go and most theories only one of them
generation people died formulated in the theory is over
and the experiments if they correctly forever because the fact so i'm i like to
argue that although experiments without theory is anathema
in the dogma of many economists
who refused to look at experiments or even to do experiments we don't have a
to guide us
none the less they are in fact in
critical phenomena the facts came first so let's start with some facts
will ask what really matters for these complex
financial fluctuations and in particular with zero in on some very recent work is still
not even rejected ones
much less twice
with tobias price very brilliant young graduate student from mines and his thesis advisor
your highness schneider
i always believe that nothing can happen without support because students have to pay the
and the rain comes from us our in this hour comes from the government and
economics you can imagine this is almost impossible because the gap between economists physicists is
so huge we simply cannot happen to their money
and after seven tries
and the last four of them with an economics collaborator that then this case we
finally got not one gram but three grants so i have to thank the grand
monitor more than anybody because none of this would have been possible without the students
and this would be possible without the money
i have to handouts one is a little one-page editorial
back on the so-called back
a free newspaper so what could be lower than to be the last page something
that's very
nevertheless it's something i'm really proud of it just to my views about the current
economic crisis in light of what some of us have been doing for the last
and then secondly out tried to keep this talk fairly broad brush because there's a
website which you can get just by googling any version of my name and and
that has the actual papers pdf
OK let's get moving let's start with the experiment this plot is the time dependence
of an economic
the standard and poor five hundred the average of the largest five hundred companies in
the US
by market capitalization over roughly forty year period deflector obviously
we all know that factories
we get the desired log scale and the y axis and
and we see that it sometimes is more or less constant for a period and
went appropriate and now we all know what to story
at the bottom curve is
the simplest theory which again as many of you know is formulated not by professor
but by student by showing a in nineteen hundred over one hundred years ago
and he model this fluctuating quantity by a drunkard walk a drunken for crying every
his wristwatch or we tried to going drugs
and and if if the coin is heads he or she moves
to the right in order the same down and if if the if the coin
is tails here she moves up
and using this simple
a simple model
but actually generated fluctuating to encourage that again at least to the eye looks identical
with the data they both fluctuating in fact if there are parts of this are
completely indistinguishable but that every now and then you know once a generation
there's a fluctuation such is what's called black monday
in eighty seven
it's much cheaper computationally
and the reason not
so there is an issue of
preserving independence
but it's actually probably possible to cope with that instead of taking the actual you
can just some sample from the in the two ways to preserve the independence
more worrisome
this may by augmenting the feature space
he made the problem harder
need to think about the
if you decide to actually do exactly this
so this theorem
sam is actually kinda nice
it is very classifiers
so classifiers taking this
future spacecraft
predicting one bit
for the distribution
on extrac zero one
this is what you want to write
this is
the probability of y
because one given x
is bounded by something that something is
OK so we have some
some distribution
we have this process
picking up p
and evaluating c
which is the new distribution
or binary problems so this is the name
the new distribution
OK so
is distribution
so we have the area specular distribution
minus the minimum error rate
it's possible
if i just talked about the error
this would not be convincing theorem
the reason why would i missing is because
the problems that are created are inherently noisy
we have to subtract off
dairy due to the noise
and then then this theorem so it does something interesting
so this is that
this quantity years regret right it's it's how that we do
so that we could do
which is
i regret
that says that if we have
a small regret
spec two
for the SE
do we have good probability estimates
so this is kind of cool because
we can actually observe this
we can compute this
i think this we on this
we know that
nevertheless minimizing this is equivalent to optimizing that
so all i said was
we have always as piece which the importance is
we just p
we have the name in the feature space
we can get it
it doesn't matter for the theorem
the time i in practice
the equivalent as far as the distribution is induced to this process
and that process of their
and this is same distribution over samples that you
evaluate the classifier
but the question is whether or not that any set
it's actually
depends if you actually
do this in practice
you probably want to do something like this
the point
any other questions
OK so
is there is a little bit
less trivial to prove
right so
here's a pretty picture
and what does it tell us
so the importance weight loss
this weighted loss
so when actual answer is zero
importance weight loss be editing wrong
it's like this red line
and when the answer is one inside the blue line
and it will turn out that
we have a convex combination of zero and one when the probability
imagine that the information that is would that we have to the world is exactly
what we have is an asian wandering around the world
so is h one around the world you know we have some state we see
and then we can choose some action
and then we have what happened next
going into some action what happens next
so in particular
and people doing reinforcement learning the think about other sorts of interactions the ways to
interact with the world so i think about the generative models where they can say
i suppose over here and take this action what happens next and support and here
i take this action instead what happens next
but we're not doing that instead what was going to be
it is it is if you are the reinforcement learning agent you can imagine
using the hugh durrant two to two
decide how much going to explore exploit
the way this works is
we have a current state s that we know
choose some action
and we observe the next state
also a reward
so the goal in reinforcement learning is so
in addition to
the distribution
the next given the action state
some kind of reward
which may be a function of
in general the strip
two other questions about the setting because
now's a good time to think about
the setting makes sense
i don't think this is the right most setting and actually if you find a
problem with the particular setting in machine learning issues in general think about
how you want to fix it because
it is not clear that we have the right settings
we had this modernization process
which has some sort of states some actions per state
and the distribution over the next eight given the state and the action
we have some horizon t
and then
the question is what is this by
what is this thing is going to hold of high probability right so
a seven complexity guarantee
as a statement like at the centre of example some guarantees going to hold
the question what is the guarantee
so there's
a guarantee
in the original EQ paper
this is something like if you
additionally assume that the markov decision processes and mixing time
then after some number of samples related to
the number of states actions for state the missing time perhaps long
you can act within epsilon delta policy
i don't have to be
so in these in these in these we did some
study about conditional independence test with and in class and
the then we
the idea here is to test condition dependence
we with we've we've
starting from the definitions
itself of conditional independence
we can we have tried to do some simulations
and by studying at
the above by
by testing condition dependence using distance measures between
kernel density function using euclidean distances as proposed by some
all told this skin
scale and reads baringhaus in france and the weighted hellinger distance was based on line
here of course we have a huge because of problems because the image and i
think is and if this is of course expected using a kind of
nonparametric approach which can be
partially mitigated using some people step procedures but
in case so in case when we talk about very few variables three three-foot
five and was so we can we can still use these these these methods of
but the it is indeed the case that sometimes we have few variables so we
have to test condition dependencies between very few residents so was simulation studies show that
using very few variables yes that is one can can can understand it
with a complete nonparametric approach
then we learn i'm going to present something about this
application of the independent component analysis part two
two recall the the the actual shocked affect the developers these the world could that
i'm doing now this is not yet finished with we don't censor but how you
and alex cord which we applied these
the lingam algorithm developed by patrik hoyer and and some coordinates in a paper published
in two thousand eight
the DA's hopes so
to estimate the reduced form VAR check that the residuals are non gaussian use an
independent components
and that's going to decompose the residuals matrix so to find
then to find a combination of of residuals
that are independent and of course in the independent components not identified we don't we
don't we don't know the exact order of
it is independent components
we have
the idea here is to use an article we two
to find the permutation of the matrix
that is close enough to allow one to three hundred six
so once the instantaneous effects are identified again as in the previous publications we can
identify the
he said this is interesting is that we don't need to strong assumption
such as from this
just an application about that we are considering
and the for growth so we have these variables in the number of employees go
talk to say is going to be
research and development expenditures and profits growth rates
and we can study here the model we use
we use the least absolute deviation estimation which is much more robust to outliers and
and he
differently from the mark application that should be followed here we would we really try
to to study the question is we live
about because i
because relations among among the measure but it's not just fish effective sharks and
interestingly enough here we we find that
it is the the BBC's go in
in the infirmary which is a huge is affecting the other variables and we don't
find the effect
from from profits growth which is the last available on the research and development
show you how to prove that there is a feature space associated with such such
that the kernel is the dot product in the feature space
but before we do that we need a few artillery results
and actually i'm going to ask you to prove them so if you have a
pencil and paper
that's first go through them and then
take a break the five minutes
you can also try to prove them and then we'll do it here and this
is just so that you get familiar with this definition a little bit
so let's look at these things first actually maybe it's better i
use this
so i hope the other room now as the
direct connection and not just the live stream which just ten seconds delay maybe we
can cheque to him in the other room you should have microphones should be able
to say something
singer song or something
can someone from the other room
carpenter the microphone
maybe you can text just out of curiousity because they might be
you might want to ask questions or something and they might tell me that they
can't read the blackboard or something like that so anyway you outlets
take a look
so the first thing is
what if i start with the feature map and look at the dot product in
feature space so i compute a function of x and x prime this way i'll
just assume given by take two points not them into that space and then compute
the dot product in that space is this thing going to be
you don't have microphones
should be somewhere because we tested last week
OK great
it was OK so
maybe they were shouting we just didn't here
OK so this thing it turns out this thing is a positive definite kernel
so the kernel
defined this way is a positive definite kernel that's the first thing that you prove
second thing is called positivity on the diagonal
so that means
the diagonal values of the kernel just means substitute x in both places
nine elementary matrix diagonal elements always nonnegative
so that follows also from the definition of positive this thing is the cauchy schwarz
you probably on the because schwartz inequality for the product there's also cushy schwartz inequality
positive definite kernels
in fact the products are positive definite kernels but this so this is a more
general things
this is the cautious about equality and also you can try to prove that one
in the last thing is it turns out if the kernel vanishes on the diagonal
all diamonds are zero then it would be easier everywhere
so let's let's try to prove these things
and maybe just
to help you so you have to always use this definition so maybe that's just
write it down
this is what of positive definite kernels satisfies
now let's go to these things and you can start playing around with this definition
of it so in the first case you'll have to prove that
this is such a kernel satisfies this definition in the other cases you'll always have
to start with this definition and derive these statements that i have written here so
just to get familiar with the definitions of topic few minutes and then ask
are you doing
so how people doing this to other people and they never resolved all the problems
i won't ask you to come to the black box can you can admitted if
you let's say who has served at least one
who has solved tool more
three or more
right OK so
it's a big mistake to one minute
OK so let's let's look at the solutions so i can show them but
but maybe someone else volunteers would like to present one of them
on the blackboard
more about biblical
religion and biblical views of history
it was an idea that ensured the survival of the ancient israelites as an entity
ethnic religious and today
in various complicated ways
the view of an utterly transcendent god with absolute control over history
made it possible
for some israelites
to interpret even the most tragic and catastrophic events
such as the destruction of their capital in the example of the remaining people's
not the defeat of israel's god
or even god's rejection of them
but as
necessary and necessary part of god's larger purpose or plan for israel
these israelites left for
the record of their religious and cultural revolution in the writings that are known as
the hebrew bible collectively and this course is an introduction to the hebrew bible
as an expression of the religious life and thoughts of ancient israel and as the
foundational documents of western civilization
the course has several goals first and foremost we want to familiarize you with
the contents of the hebrew bible
and we're not gonna read every bit of it word for word we will read
certain chance of it quite carefully and others we work we will choose selections but
you will get a very good sense and good sampling of the contents of the
a second goal is to introduce you into two in number of approaches to the
of the bible different methodological approaches that have been advanced
by modern scholars with some of which are in fact quite old
at times we will play the historian
at times we will be literary critics
how does this work as literature
at times we will be religious and cultural critic
what is that the israelites were saying in their day in their time and against
two and for what
a third goal of the course is to provide some insight into the history of
this is a really fun part of the course of the bible's radically new conception
of the divine
it's revolutionary depiction of the human being is a moral agent
it's riveting saga of the nation of israel their story
has drawn generations of readers to ponder
it's meaning and message and as a result the bible has become the basis of
an enormous edifice of interpretation and commentary and debate both in traditional settings but also
in academic universities secular settings
and from time to time particularly in section discussion
you will have occasion to consider the ways in which certain biblical passages have been
interpreted sometimes in very contradictory ways over the centuries that can be in a really
fun and exciting part of the course
a fourth goal of the course is to familiarize you with
the the culture of ancient israel
as represented in the bible
against the backdrop of ancient near eastern thing junior nearest and setting
historical and cultural setting
because the archaeological discoveries that are referred to in the ancient near east revealed to
the spiritual and cultural heritage of all the inhabitants of the region including the israelites
and one of the major consequences of these finds is the the light that they
have shed on the background and the origins of the materials in the bible
so we now see that the traditions in the bible did not come out of
the vacuum
the early chapters of genesis genesis one through eleven are known as the primeval history
which is very unfortunate name because these chapters really are not as read or understood
as history in the conventional sense but
these eleven chapters over a great deal to ancient near eastern mythology
the creation story in genesis one draws upon
the babylonian epic the known as in the male each will be talking about the
text in some depth
the story of the first human pair in the garden of eden which is in
genesis two and three
has clear affinities with the epic of gilgamesh that's a babylonian and assyrian epic in
which the hero embarks on this exhausting search for immortality
the story of noah and the flood which occurs in genesis six
through nine it's simply an israelite version of an older flood story that we have
found copies of the message pertaining story called the epic adventure has
the flood story that we also have incorporated in the epic of gilgamesh biblical traditions
have roots that stretched deep into
in earlier times and out into the surrounding lands and traditions and the parallels between
the biblical stories and engineer eastern stories that they parallel
it has been the subject of intense study
however it isn't just the similarity between the biblical materials and the ancient near eastern
sources that is important to us
in fact in some ways the dissimilarity is remarkably
important as the biblical transformation
a common near eastern heritage in light of its radically new conceptions of god and
the world and humankind
i will be dealing with this in some depth but i give you one quick
three we have a sumerian story
about the third millennium
BCE right going back three thousand thirty one in three thousand BC
so the story of the usage and is very similar to the genesis
the flood story of noah in both of these stories the simmering in israelites story
you have a flood that is the result of deliberate divine decision
one individual is chosen to be rescued that individual is given very specific instructions on
building the boat given instructions about who to bring on board
the flood comes and exterminate all living things the book comes to rest on a
mountaintop the hero sends out birds to reconsider the land when it comes out of
the ark he offers to sacrifice to the god the same narrative elements are in
these two stories it's just wonderful when you read them side-by-side
what is of great significance though is not simply
that the biblical writer is retelling
a story that was clearly went around you know everywhere in ancient in ancient mesopotamia
they were transforming the story so that it became a vehicle
for the expression of their own values
in their own views
in the math pertaining stories for example the gods act capriciously
the guys act on the
in fact one of the stories the god people there's so noisy i can't sleep
let's get started
welcome back from lunch
so this morning i showed you the simplex methods the primal version the dual version
how to put together
in the two phase algorithm
so the problem from beginning to end
on in
i want to show you
one more flavor of the simplex methods
and then show some things uh some applications that
are interesting to me and i hope someone interesting to you as well
then on monday for the third lecturer
o could switch over to
nonlinear optimization convex optimization and an interior point methods for those kinds of problems
okay so he
here is the last version of the simplex method
called the parametric self dual
simplex methods it doesn't have to phases
like the ones i will show u earlier as the whole thing all at once
so to explain it let me start with
this example
so here we have a problem
primal feasible because this minus the
zero solution is
in phases and primal feasible because the minus here
and the dual problem would be
and feasible because this plus eleven this plus to the objective function
so in primal
in the dual
and that's the typical situation
and the question is what should we do about it
idea here
is to introduce
if you like both a fake object function fake right-hand side all ones
um but also a parametric manner
so we have this parameter mu
that appears in the objective function
and it appears in the right hand side
so i'm adding five plus one new four plus one new six plus one year and so forth
so these are being added and these are being subtracted
and the point of doing this is that from very large
the solution associated with this dictionary in other words only x is equal to zero
will be optimal
because for me is sufficiently large all these things will be positive
and all these things all these coefficients will be negative
that's what it takes to be out o can be improved
in fact we can figure out exactly
what value of u
achieves the
by running down a bunch inequalities which i think i have shown
probably on the next slide
you may be able do it on the board so is here so you can
see it as i do it
we want
we live
minus three
minus mu
today a negative number
we want
minus mu
to be a negative number
we want to
minus mu
to be a negative number
we want five plus mutiny positive
we want four plus
community positive we want six plus mu to be positive
almost outer space but just making here minus four plus mu
to be positive
we rewrite these things that says that new is greater equal to
minus three
that's sort of no problem
this is new is greater than or equal to eleven
this is mu new is greater than or equal to two
this one says mu is
greater equal to minus five
this one says mu is greater than equal to minus four r and this one
says mu is able to minus six
and this one says mu is greater than or equal to the fore
we take intersection walls and plot them on
the new line
the all greater equal something in the
the most stringent one is this one here
new has to be greater than or equal to eleven
so far although is a new
equal to eleven
x one x two x three all equal to zero would be optimal for this problem
at mu equals eleven
we get we we we had the borderline here
it's still optimal
what happens in development is and for the most part the growth of neurons is
for the most part pruning
getting rid of neurons
so the neural structures change radically as baby is going to get rid of excess
neurons through development at the same time though
the connections between neurons
grow like crazy
and the and this this process of synaptic growth waters the connections across different synapses
peaks at about two years
finally remember myelination
where you sort of get this fatty sheath or neuron to make it more effective
that also happens through development and
and in fact it goes for development and even teenagers
are not fully my located in particular are not fully my limited in their frontal
lobes recall the frontal lobes are involved in things like restraint and will power
and so it could be the problem is the baby's brain doesn't develop here
another possibility is
this problems with inhibitor
this is related to get into the frontal lobes and this comes up with a
not be here
so remember
the baby reaches
reaches reach is is moved reach follow
he's reaching the same place
and it could be the babies don't know anything about objects but another possibility is
once you do something it's kind of hard to stop it takes a bit of
control to stop
and there's all sorts of independent evidence that babies lack this control part of our
brain that control
certain behaviours
it's just not active here
there's a very nice illustration
inhibitory problems from the simpsons episodes
that actually sort covers anything you might want to know
about developmental differences
basically made some of my to developmental psychology
the trial that the child essentially
he does a a a it's moving
and he keeps going forward
and there is some evidence that's true a dell diamond study this finds that are
located reach for a look for b
as if it they know it's there but it can stop themselves from reaching
and will continue to seem a little bit later
maybe kids don't know that's something you've got to work
and this is true
in all sorts of domains in the social world and economic world in the political
world and it's true as well in the physical world
in fact there's some things even adults don't know
so so here's a study by michael mccluskey with college students
here's the idea
you have it two
a transparent tube a hollow tube
and at the top of the two
you throw a ball through
so what's through the two and comes out
the question is
what happens to it
the goal in the path of a
what is going to have to be
without looking around the world for a
who votes for b
here's the weird thing whenever i do this at yale
everybody gets the damn thing right
johns hopkins fifty fifty
for a and b
i got to get better demo but anyway
college students
not here
show systematic biases of incorrect physical
here's the twist
and if you want it if you if you found people who were less
wonderful the new and and ask them you get a lot of people saying the
but here's the twist as somebody what if you took the two
and new squirted water through it we would water
nobody chooses b
everybody knows the water would continue in a straight line
suggest that when you have experience that helps you up and absence of experience
you kind of lost
we've talked about the physical world what about the social world what about the world
of people
well there's a lot of research on this as well
baby start off with some social preferences
if you take newborn babies
it's very hard to do research of newborn babies actually because the
consent procedure and everything so most of this work is done in france
and listing them defining class listening instances is also a lot of help you
two five
and alpha
the gates are open
what i will do have said most of this so i will
skip it instead i want to do is just provide information yes this is notable
trilogy so these are all the holocaust structures near the description logic
constructors to this is to substantiate this claim that all is just a description logic
is an XML syntax
and in
what's important is that i said well this XML syntax XML syntax is just as
unreliable as the RDF syntax is the same
you really don't want to read this and so on
therefore we design design difference is that the forms for the same language so one
in particular interesting cases there's human motivation from
humility sort of widely used in industry in data modeling and also large communities is
and there's a URL notation
four flowers
it's like
in some of the level of master so there's is no i don't know any
does that
OK there is also an alternative XML syntax which is already more readable for humans
and interesting there is a what's called the abstract syntax the last rites abstract collapsed
because called concrete but this is much more human readable and i will give some
examples of how in terms of abstract syntax and of course you can mechanically translate
in and out of city centre
so i will not spend the last few slides give you some flavours of what
you can do with OWL abstract syntax
just remembered for everything you look at there's really a piece of RDF XML serialisation
is about five times the size
before i do that i forgot there's also a list of things that doesn't
which is really important to mention that these are simple questions again get after out
presentations no i'll doesn't do people
so you can not have the typical examples
but always line except in a subclass of birds don't fly
because it becomes nonmonotonic and we don't have proper formalizations of that for is we
cannot agree on one so it will drive for standardization teaching already mentioned we don't
the closed world assumption that deliberately open world assumption you could not do property chaining
is also known as rules
OK so you can define what it means to be a sister of
brother of you can define what it means to be a father of but you
can define uncle over the composition of those
that's too
two to
the decidability of the language so you want to define rules saying now x is
the uncle of y if there is some z where
x the brother of z y z is the father of why that rule
language is in the making there is a good proposal by you ought to be
to build snyder and that's the obvious way to go before warm clauses were all
literals in the clause expressions
so the obvious thing to do when they wrote it down good
play and you should feel free to use it if you want to
OK those are the most important restrictions on movement for time
here are some examples
these are
is the answer
so there is no good
the semantics of what it would mean to do inferencing for all club
good question
there's a related restriction which is a unique name assumption which is also here how
can just because two things have a different names
you cannot infer therefore there are different things
it may turn out later
these two names correctly two names for
different for the same thing so we use different from databases typically database made unique
name assumption
match say OK this that each one of those could conceivably match some look like
and some dance some this some more each one for each
disparity each mostly matching pixel
you can give score
how well it matches and score
each of the d one to d and can be
different schools of pixels
and so you that usually something like colour consistency standards
the intensity i is intensity left image minus the intensity of the right image
probably square them and add them
all pixels then you have to find the pdf etc etc etc etc etc but
if you do that which minimizes this cost
try to to minimize the possibility if you do that usually you get somewhat noisy
image noisy depthmap
some reason this picks looks like the right one here but
the one above it doesn't really apply the same because after all of that from
the point of view so usually you put some other
type term in there which is called the regularisation term the smoothness term which says
pixels junior each other
near each other in three dimensions and hence have
and we don't worry too much about that
regularisation term other than to say there is one so
here is
what you get
if you take independent
one by one
i should say this also uses the technique
called well
dynamic programming which in fact
smooth them out and gives you
you better to pixel by pixel
but this ground truth is what you get from and scandalised the trouble is that
each individual scan lines done separately
and they don't really match up if you put the appropriate regularisation term something considered
using graph cuts and graph cuts techniques are
so that explains the exterior days
this is have look at
what graph cuts is all about
it's really that you have a graph
and you want to say separate separating two parts
you've got to find
between a few places the red all the red pixels by
and the forth
think t on the other side i usually called zero and one my slides of
people called s and t for source
and terminal i guess
then the question is
how do you find
the best
of separating the graph
what is the best way
each of those edges will have some sort of
or costs associated with it
the purpose is to find the least cost cut between those
so i can see how you think you can see how that
general idea would apply this mosaic thing have to find the least cost cuts
along the graph
and one of the nice things about this is
unlike many of the problems
in fact the general problem
in this area of suitable optimisation it can be done
in polynomial time
we look at some of these organisms
the ford focus goes back to nineteen sixty two
the way this works
is that you
if you look at this
you want to find out what is the best cut
between this each of those pages has a certain way which is represented here
graphically by its thickness so then you you look at
from source
so this is a little bit inexact they exact was going on be careful
we find
a path through that in the sense you sort of
think of these things the network of pipes and you can push a certain amount
of water through the pipes
and you
push some water some fluid flows
when flow
from source to sink and once you've done that
you can
take away that sort of past that amount st from each those parts and then
go on to the next one
until you cannot
you find another another part to push along until you cannot push any more fly
along any more
constructively interfere
to form a pi bond
which is the carbon two PY carbon two PY
every double bond is to find way it's doable with every double bond is made
up of one
sigma bond
and a sigma bond is always
the overlap between two
two s e two hybrid wavefunctions
and the second bond that always makes up the double bond is the pi bond
pi bond is always the overlap of two atomic wavefunctions
in the case your carbonate two
two p wave functions that have overlap
right that's what a double bond always is
it always is so whether it's the carbon double bond or nitrogen double bond or
an oxygen double bond is always one sigma
one part i
all right and there the hydrogen
and as we said those hydrogens there
carbon hydrogen bond is overlap between carbon two SP two
weight functions
and that hydrogen one s wave function
now what's the geometry of that we
well the geometry here
the point is that
the hydrogen carbon hydrogen bonds are one hundred and twenty degrees
that's one hundred twenty degrees because there is the result of the hybridisation that two
sp two hybridization
of the
wavefunctions around the harbour
this prime here is one hundred twenty degrees again because of the
two sp two hybridization around the carbon
the geometry of the molecule is planar
all these animals are in the plane all six atoms are in the plane
the binding those here are all hundred and twenty degrees
OK now
if you see i current that's got double bond
if you see nitrogen that guided albion to see an oxygen it's got double bond
there is always the call
carbon and nitrogen and oxygen
the hybridisation of two sp two
o double bond here at this hybridization always
so if you're in to tell what the hybridisation is around some and got double
blind to it
it's a two sp two hybrid
what i wanna do is i want to take this two sp two hybrid
and build little
larger molecules
i'm going to take this parents who are going to take the two problems here
that are bonded
here this
two sp two hydrogens so here ideas so one
here's another two and kind of strategically placed
what it is i want to do
and of course this is the
a sigma bond between the two departments
carbon to us two
here's the carbon
two sp two sigma bonds
right now i'm i'm going to do
is that i'm going to bring in another carbon
there is sp two hybridized
here it comes
and again it's strategically oriented
so that right here
i have now formed another
by another sigma bond between the carbon two sp two a function
the other
carpenter with weight function in the same thing right here
i just form two other sigma bonds
and now
i'm going to bring in
as the two
and it's going to come in from the side and again it's strategically oriented
so i just for here
i another sigma bond between these two problems
and another sigma bond between these two problems
look at that
he e
yearning to look alot like benzene
that might be required
they're hired to say is going to be banned the
all right so what i do here
i made some sigma
i made six sigma bonds
right between the current
two sp two wavefunction
and the hydrogen what wavefunctions
so now i got all of my atoms here in almost all of my part
we've got to do something here
half and how helen left actually know
one forty minutes not that
i would say that is what is interesting here is that for linear system only
it is easy
is it is easier to study the dynamical system using an input output representation in
taking into account the memory of the system through
this impulse response function
but only in this case can do this kind of of
anyway i feel able
move from the a state space representation
two in input output representation in dynamic systems i've always have to think
o two very important notions which are
crucial notion think that are one of the most important part of this lecture four
this two results related to the concept of reachability the notions related to the concept
of reachability
end of ability
as you that generic state is reachable
if there exists a certain time is that certain input to that can
bring the state the into certain improve the for into the state x
translating this notion means they're acting properly to the system with the search function u
i can always take my system
from a certain point to another one
so reachability means that i'm able to
manipulating the system
using our input variables
in order to support the systems data into
the state space into the point of the state space which is my goal
this is somewhat related to control
taking into account that not is not always true
the state is reachable
given a certain input i can even never arrive to assert state so this this
means that the system or single state is not reachable
by my actions
so this is very
also when we are going to model that this kind of system in the second
notion is even more important in this of survival
also the well is defined the starting from the definition of unobservable this that certain
in state the different from zero is an observable is
for a certain period of time in the output zero even if the state is
not zero
so this is the example actually we have to state that well we have a
certain trajectories over time of the state variables but we don't observe
we do not observe
any changes in the output
of course if you can understand these instances dramatic for
modelling of time series
it tells you that something is is happening inside the system
which i'm not able to observe
but but the state changes
i have different
initial state for example for certain here with respect to this point here
so you have a situation
in which our system
cannot be
reported into an input output representation
so for example for linear systems something which i would like to do
here i report what is called the kalman the composition of linear systems
in my point of view can be considered a good way of thinking
in general of dynamic systems even if they are not lead the composition can cannot
be performed except
but this test that the system
you can have four
one component is a component which is
the best one what we this one what we like
which is reachable and observable
this means that if i hacked into the system i'm able to put the system
state what i want
and if i am observing the system i observe the output is a function complete
of the state variable so
if i and performing
in the input output experiment i'm able to observe everything to control
it may happen
that even our output and all input to the portions of the system
reachable but not observable
so i'm going to the system something but don't of sort of anything
in this sometimes happens to make people that nervous
because because they try to manipulate the system that kind of sort of anything so
that it doesn't change but of course is not true it doesn't change because you
are not measuring the the right out with your notes
o serving the right state variables
the second part here
is that we have something which is reachable but observable
i have my system is under nominal conditions i'm not doing anything to the system
i'm observing was going on and this is something i said oh my god what's
happening whose main relating this is
external disturbances
and this is what is typically called noise
we observe something
which is
we say well noise
OK but maybe
something different is time noise thermal noise which would mean that i have a parliamentary
which is the temperature which changes with a with that but i mean i can't
manage using the input
and this causes some out OK
we have the worst of the worst situation which is the situation in which the
system is unreachable
a part of the system is unreachable and not observable
it means that a portion of the system is behaving in a completely unmanageable way
unfortunately nature some parts of the dynamical system
always present so i can do anything about it and maybe i can serve them
let's please let
we can use it means for nation
location location
and then what is that lot of
and this is one of
OK thanks a lot everyone for coming waking up it seems to me now so
what i talk about is basically dynamics and put
temporal dynamics of of networks meaning large graphs so we'll be taking graphs some kind
of data we try to analyse model
but if first if you're going to think about what we have today is basically
we have a large on line systems that have traces of human social and other
types of activities right so for example we have online communities like facebook that have
like myspace account like millions or hundreds of millions of users and and again see
that using this computing applications we have some of the activity right similarly for communication
have a lot that i like instant messenger
or four news and social media we have blogs and the estimate is that there
are two hundred fifty million blogs worldwide today and again we can easily grow
crawl blogs and for example observed in for how information propagates from block to block
and what also have like online worlds like second life and world of warcraft that
what's on that only have internal economies in terms of GDP and so on so
these are sort of different applications that there exists today and like millions of people
are using the using the so what is allows us to is to study phenomena
and behaviour is basically the skills that were before pretty much impossible
the second point is that most of these data is some kind of interaction right
so went to people need to something to talk to one another and such interaction
best modelled by network by right so for example
we can model of social networks as graph meaning that no here will be a
person and an edge between two two people some kind of interaction with the thought
that friends or something similar on the web we have web pages on the web
pages of knowledge and we have hyperlinks between the links in the graph again he
is is is a network of communication as i said like email exchanges
citation networks another example and biological networks sort of
another example of
the city each network data
if we go and see what we we know about the structure of these networks
i would like know a lot about how so for example you know a lot
about the properties of these networks
you know things like the scale free if you know the clustering of the data
that we can navigate through the you know they composed bipartite cores and so on
and i think is that each of structures as we observed that we also have
good models to to understand so for example of models like preferential attachment where the
idea is that you are more likely to connect to high degree nodes and low
degree nodes of high degree webpages and loading degree web pages you know like the
small world model the copying model and some other ones OK so
we know a lot about sort of structure of static networks but let me know
much less about is the
is the processes and dynamics of these networks and basically this is the topic of
this thing
so the far the focus will be on three different points so first point will
be about network evolution so the main question here would be
how does the network structure change and evolve as the network grows over time
OK so that's the first
sort of the first part second part to be a different type of dynamics now
we'll assume we have an article and something is probably going so so the question
how do more diseases information
influence propagates in such networks how can one and how can you explain
and sort of the central park because the disease is is large so basically what
kind of benefit i'm getting from large
and as i've shown here in in in a few examples of what can happen
is that means that many many times c
psi phenomena to be able to one things that practically invisible if you if you
don't look at you know
OK so to go into more detail that the plan for the day and please
don't get scared right so we have these three
three lines of work so
evolution cascade and examples of large data and then each of these three lines sort
of have to but first we see some empirical observations and then we lost modelling
it's an intractable scenario in the sense that well
you cannot
nice to decompose all the planning operations
and you get essentially the same algebra occurring in
now rather than
some in
we have the
i mean in plus some simmering
there's also the and and or so you can also use logics for it or
you can use
log plus plus
if you want to work with low probabilities
the beauty of this is
you can write your system
and instantiate
a different semirings
you get a large range of different operations quite easily fought
the beauty is that
you can basically invented the different hearing right to different pavement intended to different conference
which people have done
so this was
message passing
on the junction tree
the problem with this
with this intractable models
well with even with factor models they scales exponentially in the treewidth
if in fact junction tree
it gets very expensive because you have to send in same through a really really
long message
so this is what the OP asked before about optimality and so on
and the
use of message passing may or may not converge i mean there are now some
theoretical guarantees we essentially you're on the convergence monitor at the same time with the
same operations as you actually junction tree
so as the actually loopy belief propagation
and if the convergence monitor converges then you know also the algorithm has converged which
kind of OK
there's a few other workarounds
you can
well look at subset of the graph
and well solved inference problem with this and then the average of the spanning trees
so that's the embedded trees algorithm of will get out
then or the alternative is use sampling methods for inference
they guess those are actually the most promising ones
there's a couple of open problems in this context because they
depend quite a bit on how you decompose a graph and how you sample
as far as i know no very good definitive answers have been obtained so far
in terms of what the sampling operate
you know why
what you would be out to look for
the spectrum
off here
propagation operating time through sampling the case as you compose them
there's a couple of interesting questions in this context the result
now here's another way
well we use convexity
about a year and a half ago i would have said well this is actually
quite a nice idea and i imagine that this can lead to practical algorithms
at the moment i would say
it can lead to very good theoretical insight unfortunately don't use it in practice it's
just slightly
maybe you can make it run fast but
not so sure
what we do is
we take we look at the bag of
well tricks from convex duality
keep paper in this case will be the one by wainwright and jordan
no NIPS
o three
and there is long take report about the a hundred pages which builds on that
and manages to unify a couple of inference algorithms
in this context
so that's it
you might want to read the fort version
the first ten pages maybe
the that pain on you with a hundred pages but essentially that's the key
a place where this trick was proposed
the log partition function this function g theta
use of these concept OK for solution i use it is risk these
the rule that they extracted to describe the concept time predicting but practically the final
goal is this one OK can use this part to sort of this part and
and they can use this discovered back two-minute data for example i can perform query
the formal of i want to select all the side of what is not
well at the salle the landscape so automatically query of this form will generate a
list of size away by applying defeat the operational definition it is embedded in the
landscape if these are the official matches the description of the site it is a
selective dis that can be used to all my new online and in this case
we have performed some experimental value but just to check if a rule extract the
effectively predictive so we use it only for a positive example and nine negative examples
and a bistable we assigned to the results that we obtain on the entire model
in the case of one of the ground knowledge to we can look at it
and we can see that all around the running time of icarus and these are
different statistics to
describe the classification we can see that the precision and recall and
background knowledge a lot to the work of precision so we have the more descriptive
by tend to perform better when we practical use the for classification task OK just
to conclude that this is only an query that i'm unclear language it is just
maybe text that should be expanded to four
in different ways
the main idea is that the case is not just a statistic
need to but the statistic representation of dates back to drive a query
red band performing was about to step but it's a solution to the problem of
of integration of different technology because OK just to is use the that
users just to formulate a query and the query seem to summarize the entire data
mining process and in this case the query is different from the traditional mining query
language because it does that also the different problems and does our work is continuing
on this topic because we are working on discrete cosine and so on extending the
mining so just to integrate different tools that we have to perform
that can
that fact
well that
where are you
the long
o five one one side
OK then side is contains some ninety seven
ninety seven but you have to consider that one extract description of its and
complete description of sala the story in the first order representation it is about twenty
so you have a lot of descriptor for its opposite values than that of these
and on his experiment with the internet of these i have not so allow for
performing test and so this is the
in rule that they extracted by use all the positive example and all the negative
examples but in this case i interesting legacy again on the floor and escape what
of these
substructure age
and you can see that all cosets form the entire entire playing with the
can you see this picture i think the red is
hard to
in in this case this case there i was meaning subspace
this is the extent natural group
and more shipwrecks structure but here i'm just
i'm this considered here the analogy of the
of the euclidean space with the
this group
of the group
and here
you have for example the analogy is that x
o is the subgroup h
is there any point
this of the subgroup is age
in this case is the x
axis x
and the shifted copies of these subgroups
are two parallel line and i blocked them of course you have as many as
are the number of points in that the y x
and so
a course sect
a core set of
in this case the identities zero
in this case here the knowledge there the right side with the group
is that the of is the group that this the points the coordinates of the
points there
and then you have the operation is just the the standard translation in the plane
so you have you have
if you multiply that because that is
and number c one times all elements of h
you get the
the c one line there
the first one
this one
this line here
so this is the this is one that
this line here is analogous that
and with this picture is it too
two semantic properties of those schools
the first thing that you all the over
the quantum right corner
is that the identity must be long
two h
because h is a subgroup
so as it is subgroup it has to have
and identity
it has the former group
so the identity has to be the
so the identity is only in h
so the core set
they do not necessarily form social groups
and here in red probably can read that report
that cosets form a partition
of the group
in this case it forms the partition of the subspace if you take all those
for all c
you cover to cover space
so the core sets
you can decompose the space
in the collection of course it's
the last thing here
is this blue
if you take one point of the space
there's is only one cassette
this based on the this point belongs to
only one
so you take for any and point here the other one for example belongs to
this is day
another point here would belong focus across crossing there
and to
that concept only
that's why we're we're going to talk about here we need some generalizations in this
case here
the group operation
but we are
using to construct
course that
is this vector a vector addition right
you might like see here
all points here the age
and you get a higher level sets
that's the idea of parallel said that we have to
you know in this simple case the multiplication is
i could be in a group
which can get
quite abstract
so this is just the
to reflect the
because open as i will be talking about sets in many contexts
you have to be aware
this this sort of reasoning can happen
you know you get and you get a bit lost
with all these definitions
but they are important properties
this case here it's an old joy no the lawyer joke
person can correctly say
o we can correctly say of them they'd be better off dead
let me try to draw
some examples
again we're bracketing the question can the person
i think clearly about their case that come later let's just try to talk about
when i was a suicide makes sense
well would be
so a rational thing to do
to endure life
a couple of different places
good job brass
well let x axis represents time
the y axis represents how good or bad your life is at that time
for those of us who are fans of the neutral container theory the thing to
say is this represents the overall goodness of your content or the overall badness content
the higher up the better the contents of the lower down the worst the contents
for those who are fans of the modernist container theory
this represents the grand balance so it's
contents plus the extra bit you get from being alive but of course if you're
a fan of the modest container theory that even if the contents are negative the
ground might still be positive
but this represents the overall bottom line
whether you accept the neutral container theory or the models container theory
so here's an example
well i might look like
going along pretty well
and then things get worse
o thing sort of deteriorate
and i suppose
this point represents when you would die of natural causes natural death
so to be and what not as great as it was when you're young and
vigorous and healthy all sorts of opportunities and accomplishments but still until the very end
it stays
well if that's what your life line would look like
pretty clearly suicide doesn't ever make any sense
in particular you wouldn't want to say well look
is the place where i should kill myself because here is where things start to
get worse
yes things are beginning to get worse but they never gets so bad that you're
better off dead
so suicide wouldn't make any sense at all
four suicide makes sense
it's got to be the case that your life
takes a turn for the worse
not just any old turn for the worse but it turns so much for the
that for some chunk of your life
your life is worth the non-existence the zero line the x axis
all right i imagine that what happened here you are healthy and vigorous your accomplishing
things but you've got some degenerative disease that's going to make things worse and worse
as the period which is getting worse
and then
after a while existence is going to be worse than nothing
here we can at least wrote the question intelligible way might suicide make sense
i suppose this is the point where the downturn begins
should you kill yourself at that stage
because after all even though
the down turn things are getting worse
this going to be another period of life another chunk of whatever it is year
five year six months whatever it is well the like isn't as good
as it had been before
it's still
better than nothing
killing yourself at this earlier moment is we might say pre-mature
it's throwing away a chunk of life that would still be worth having
it's not the right thing to do it doesn't make sense rational
if not that moment what about this moment
here's the precise point at which
your life is becoming worse than nothing
for some initial structure that will be very much worse than nothing but still
the overall
if the negative
up to that moment your life was worth living from that moment on your life
is worse than nothing if you've got complete control over when to kill yourself
well that would be the time to do it
suppose you don't have
complete control
it's straightforward enough to say
if you if you like is going to become
worse than nothing and you have complete control over when you kill yourself
it seems pretty plausible to say the precise moment which suicide become rational would be
exactly that moment which you life became
not worth having
but you might not have that kind of control
suppose that what you've got is a degenerative disease that is going to
progressively strip you of the ability
to control your body
fast maybe don't notice or the plateau
and you might use better optimization methods i mentioned
some of them like adam i'm using better smarter you know learning
rate schedules and things like this and we've got it i think a bit
better at that also and it's the second hypothesis some of the
solution to talk about is unsupervised learning for initializing
weights which as we'll see his seems to provide a regularization
effect and of dropout training and also talk about briefly batch
normalization which is not a method
which sits kind of at least one another's seems to be sometimes really
helpful in terms of the optimization but also seems to have
a regular zation effect so actually these
two problems should necessarily think of them as
mutually exclusive yes
i mean yeah there's definitely evidence the question is when using
batch norm which are yet to describe but i'll get to
there's you know it some people reported that
you don't this need dropout of this point
which are cover a huge hits to but and that
that is seems to be consistent across people's experiences i believe
so yeah ok so say when situation we feel
queer are overfitting then we need a way of somehow constraining
the effective capacity of our model
and one way of doing ing this is actually have are hidden layers
to do something more than just discrimination something more than
just classifying the data and what option to be to have to do a
form of unsupervised learning
where broadly speaking what we mean by that this kind of understanding
the structure the of the inputs not even the relationship with the
label so that is for instance have a form of network that is able
within its hidden layer to capture that
if i'm doing and to character recognition classification
that this is an image of a character and that's random image
so this is a valid sample from say my distribution if i'm performing
character classification and this is a valid member of my input
distribution so here i'm going to so the idea is to try to incurs
hidden layers to capture some of that information
and so what's interesting about this is that
this is this is clearly harder task unsupervised learning
which means that the asking for something more of your model and
thus the effective capacity should be reduced so that will fight
against or fitting and is an extent to which the part of doing
unsupervised learning should be a form of classification if they
are separate classes in your data
well learning about the input distribution should involve somewhere
representing the fat that there are multiple classes in your data
so this potentially not entirely
i'm going against the ultimate goal of doing supervised classification
so one form of unsupervised learning what to do i'm i'm i'm going
to come you know talk about a very simple form is to
use autoencoders so don't quarter's r just feedforward neural
networks where you feed them as input well the input
and you compute the hidden layer lies we do their transformation
on the activation and we try to reproduce
the input so we do another non linear transformation
and maybe some non linear activation function at the output
layer and then the objective we're going to optimize is the difference
between or some distance between x at the reconstruction produced
by my doing quarter and my input x
and so i'm going to say whole lot about autoencoders for lack of
time but clearly dis is a form of unsupervised learning
in the sense that there's no label information being use for
performing this training if the number of hidden units
in the hidden layer smaller than the input you can think but
as doing a form of compression of the input which might require
essentially extracting what characterizes my input distribution
specifically compared to just random inputs
so this is why you might expect extracting some interesting information
about the input distribution over this will quick
and then the the idea here would be to essentially use my unsupervised
learning algorithms so my training milestone quarter which
trains a single hidden layer in a greedy layer-wise faction as one
approach in ways of doing this so what i would do is first
train my first hidden layer by having this hidden layer reconstruct
the input doing this for a number of steps than that number
of steps is actually going to be hyperparameter my complete procedure
and then at one point i stop i fix the first hidden layer and then
maybe i add the second hidden layer and that hidden layer could
be used to train on the first hidden layers representation of my
data so i'm trying to extract iraq a second layer representation
of my first layer representation of the data
and can continue like this one layer at a time
for the number of layers i would like to use
in neural net so effectively can see that this is if
effectively trying to learn features the features of features
but in unsupervised way
so you do this gives you initial value for all the weights
of my neural net at all hidden layers
then you add some random weights connecting the last hidden
layer with the output and then you do when we often referred to
as fine-tuning which is just a regular backpropagation
so really you just use this to casgrain descent procedure are described
so far the only thing that this change is how initial i didn't initialize
the parameters before i start doing
great in descent on my supervised negative log-likelihood
loss yes so the point quarter dimension is is one
let me turn the volume down here
so this is inverse kinematics and the idea is you got manual constraining them to
be on a skeleton and if you just pull on him okay it just looks
like an artist stole
because it's on the under-constrained what natural set motions is
but this is a high dimensional data set
um ants what they do is they learn that feel them so that's the latent space for basketball players
and just playing the latent space
what they do is they sort of decide to constrain where you see the white dots they've constraint
the figure and then moving the hand around and everything else moves in the most
likely position so it's like a missing
variable problem
so you've got a joint density over everything
going to maximize with respect to the latent point you can then try and fill
in the rest of the data the most impressive example i think they have about
is this walking person
so this is this a graph paper some years ago two thousand seven so
this is a model someone walking
and where you see the whites
they've got constraints always gonna walk in a moment
they'll play those
okay so now is i think is moving around the latent space
giving you the walk
now they providing white is constraints so they can take off and on and you can say
remove the are and do what's natural constraints on the on this day was most
natural on the model and you can see the arm moves quite nicely
and then morosely upper-body
i am
does the same thing his legs please give me the most natural upper body
and then you removed everything apart from the feet
and says giving what's most natural with the of body
it's quite nice it's all being done just by
joint model
over these things they've got some other examples in there
andy uh
i want to show you what i think some of the movies
well i'm so annoyed about outdoor and one
so this is recent stuff from a
i'm not very good pronounce his surname free occurring
hand in reach
it's been published in these years it actually i did some work well let me show you one
maybe this i see this first
this is our attempt it as non vision people
with my student collec
so this is there trying to infer pose from
from may um
using models we build joint models over pose and silhouette and then we present the
silhouette and ask for the post
actually it turns out just over
so the again
this is actually very innovative and this isn't quite executive helium
this is our prediction the ground truth
so is there
and that's our prediction from above ground truth
i do not if you do
motion capture
do not got one sided figure
thank you side the figure straight i want you to watch the figure
is what's set figure what what's the ground truth
and you see that something bizarre at some point
it since the turn around what we opposite direction
you see there
why did happen
that's the ground truth
what happened
it's vision problem because if you don't want side when the leg disappears
it's horrible and you don't even notice it when the when you get it selects crossover if the two dots
riverside the leg
even if that's so if the two dots on this leg
smart the web
that's that's
that's that sense and so on
and wordnet is a big semantic network
where various relations are established between the different senses
we see some examples here
you can have that this is similar to this
derivational related four billion c and brilliance and member of the set and what's not
shown here but i have an example later is you also have a parent-child concepts
hypernyms and hyponyms
i think it's of continue pointing outwards here this is called the gloss
of surpassing excellence
and that's just provided
so whoever is used
it's not actually that this is just a glass to help you see what it
is this is actually the definition of what the senses the set the synsets
and also
examples are given
but you see
that really seems like a very subjective word is brilliant brainy
is wonderful
but it has
sensors that are not not subjective
so brilliant a bright shining lie
like a brilliant star meaning it's great to ice about perception
or a brilliant brim rights and the trumpet section
a bright sound of the trumpets trumpets are bright sounding cellos are not
so for example method for identifying brilliant material pay us pattern and opening section in
the minor mode features are brilliant and the melody and then maybe maybe you could
say mellow don't probably no it's not the case where there a mellow telo
part attack
so words
often have mixtures of subjective and objective senses
so let's think about
how we might assign
can we assign
subjectivity labels to word senses and what might that means
we want to say there are subjective and objective you can go further broken down
by positive negative or neutral balls
well again i think you'd have potential disambiguation both ways and we've done some experiments
well if you if you had these links then if you had sensitivity analysis of
the context that might suggest that sense is more likely to be subjective or if
you knew
the sense maybe a clear case which sensitive that can help you tell you tell
tell you whether
whether the
the because the context is subjective
we've so far we have our group has just one direction where we use the
data the analysis to improve word sense disambiguation and this other groups working on this
as well
so think about what we mean
so here are some examples
i'm showing here that this is a hyperlink a hypernym
concept this is the parent concept so this alarm dismay consternation obviously that's objective in
the sense that it's referring to an emotion
and that's the type of fear fearlessness fry according to work
and that's subjective and if you're adding polarity tags that would be negative OK out
of all things equal if you expect
you expect that would be negative rather than positive whereas alarm warning device along device
that's just the device itself and its objective
so what is the subjective sense
i look dictionary stuff about
prior expectations
expectations you have without any evidence from the context so that's how i view lexicons
for my purposes
other people looking for different purposes so in a sense of you have attacked so
you say you it's being used with that sense of alarm fearless fears fearfulness you're
expected to express subjectivity
OK and you also express expect the phrase or sentence containing it to be subjective
well that seems
but i'm going to look at a couple examples of then we have to look
at the objective case
we already set his alarm grew he was boiling with anger is another example
let's look at what's the catch
OK and the point i mean if you if you see if you see cat
with this and you have to read the subject
similar with the doctors o'clock
as a an untrained person knows the untrained person is not this is not subjective
if you say he's aquatic has negative evaluation
by its nature
well let's think about objective sense now
the alarm went off the water boiled
he saw the statue of the market
the doctors quack was loud increase
these are from wordnet
so the problem is
you don't necessarily expect phrases or sentences that contain objective sensors
to be objective
considering what someone said that dunlop off to even boil water it is a very
even though alarm and boyle are used here with their object with objective sensors
so these are subjective but not due to
the senses of alignment boyle in these passages
when the senses here's our definition when the sensors used text conversations
we don't expect it to express subjectivity and if the phrase or sentence containing is
subjective this subjectivity is due to something else
not to that sense
i have pretty much in parallel with this there's another group that's been annotating wordnet
so at all used they
annotated senses of words from the general inquiry guesses my
slides got
ended up being ordered i have mentioned this before
so the general inquiry lexicon was published in the nineties and it's a little it
has word list of positive negative and neutral this and several groups use it and
it's part of our clique
it's a filtered version of it is part of a subjectivity lexicon that we have
a way to make sure mention and if you go to the web page and
you download our corpus part and our opinionfinder system part of that is our subjectivity
that second so anybody