let's imagine
can you see this over there
then i will right over there
i was right
alright let's see if this works
o point
here on the twenty first century we still have worked this out OK
that's really you could everybody can see this right here right
OK so look let's imagine we reaction that looks like this
the reaction profile that looks like this were these two images are
actually equivalent
OK i tried to run one
well not exactly but pretty much on exactly the same level
and let's say we start out with a large number of molecules right over here
now if there were an enzyme around the enzyme might lower the activation energy and
in so doing
make it possible
four molecules to to tunnel through this hill
and move already here
the fact that we want to get over here it has the same free energy
is over there
it means that the the catalyst may principle also facilitate a back reaction what i
mean by back reaction i mean going in exactly the opposite direction and so once
molecules over here for
the lower the energy lowering effects of the enzyme they allow them to move in
both directions
and and therefore what we will have is ultimately the establishment of an equilibrium
if these two energy states are equivalent then i will tell you
fifty percent of molecules and up here and fifty percent of molecules and up here
and here we're beginning now to wrestle between with two different independent concepts the rate
of the reaction
and the equilibrium state of the reaction
note that the enzyme has no effect whatsoever on the equilibrium state e these two
article free energies equilibrium state where the energy barrier is this high
or whether it's this high
is irrelevant
the fact is if the energy if the enzyme makes possible this motion back and
forth the ultimate equilibrium state will be fifty percent of molecules here and fifty percent
of the molecules there and therefore the enzyme
really only affects the rate at which the reaction takes place
will it happen in the microsecond or will happen in a day or will happen
in a million years
the enzyme has no effect whatsoever on the ultimate end product which in this case
is the equilibrium
of course there is already there is a simple mathematical formalism which relates the difference
in free energy is with the
the the equilibrium
here we we might have a situation where
eighty percent of molecules and up at equilibrium over here
twenty percent in that period
or we might end up with a state where
ninety nine point nine percent of the molecules and up here
and the point of point one percent of molecules and up here
but that ultimate equilibrium state is in no way influenced by the enzyme they just
make it happen in real time
and therefore the repeated call point i made last time
if most biochemical reactions are to occur in real time
i e on the order of seconds or minutes
an enzyme has to be around to make sure they happen in the absence of
such an enzyme of intermediation
it just won't happen in real time even though in principle it's energetically
so let's just keep that very much in mind in the in the course of
discussions that happen and let's just begin now
to look at
in important energy generating reactions in the cell which is called glycolysis
we already know these the prefix glycol like refers to sugar
and licenses l SAS refers to the breakdown
of a certain compound
i'm not going to ask you nor anyone else in this room and ask you
to memorize this sequence
but i'd like you to look at it and see what taken lessons we can
distill out of that what wisdom we can learn from looking at such a complex
series of reactions
perhaps the first thing we can learn is that when we think about biochemical reactions
we don't think of them as happening in isolation
here i'm talking about for example in this case i could be talking about a
plus b
going to see plus b
and there might be a back reaction
two weeks to reach equilibria
and we're just isolating that simple reaction from all others around but in the real
world in living cells most reactions are parts of very long
pathways for each of these steps here indicates one of the others what a step
in the pathway
what we're interested in here is how glucose which i advertised two lectures being an
important energy source is actually broken down how to sell harvest the energy which is
inherent in glucose
in order to generate among other things a ATP
which we have said repeatedly is the energy currency
ATP is used by hundreds of different biochemical reactions in order to make them happen
these other biochemical reactions are
and you're gonna they require the investment of energy
and almost invariably but not invariably almost invariably the cell will grab hold of an
ATP molecule
break it down usually to ANP or a
and then utilize the energy which derives
from breaking down ATP
it will invest energy in an organic reaction
which is otherwise wouldn't happen
so here we reach the idea
the perhaps by investing energy in a reaction it the equilibrium is shifted because by
investing energy
the terminal speed
is proportional to the square root of the radius
for a given
density of the the object
if you take a battle with a radius of about one centimeter
you throw it off a high building
it will reduce speed which will not exceed seventy five miles per hour because of
the and drag
if you jump out of the plane
and you have no parachute
and i make the assumption
that your mass
is about seventy kilograms
i wonder rough numbers if i can approximate you biosphere was a radius of about
forty centimeters that's also approximation you're not really like is for you but i want
to get some some rough numbers
then the terminal velocity
it is a hundred and fifty
miles per hour
so if you do job out of the plane
i have no parachute
you will not go much faster than hundred fifty miles per hour
i just read an article yesterday about skydivers will jump out of planes and they
want to open the parachute at the very last possible and they reach terminal velocity
is of hundred twenty miles per hour it doesn't surprise me it's very close to
disrupt number that calculated
was then they open the parachute and air drag
increases enormously
and then they slow down
even further
i told you raindrop
almost all raindrops
operate in regime two
when they fall to the terminal velocities
dictated by the descriptor
however if you make the baltics small
now comes the time
you really and to
regime one
and all assignment number four i've asked you
to calculate
where that
happens and i can do it for water because the radius of that water will
be so small
it would evaporate immediately so i chose or for that so i'm asking you know
simon for they can or drop make it smaller and smaller and smaller and smaller
and there comes the time
the two begin to enter regime one
and i want you to calculate where that crossovers
between these two
i have here
a ball
you may call it the balloon but i call it the ball because there's no
really mean
and this
ball ways
approximately thirty four grams
let me
raise some here because i want
so we know them mass
and we know the radius
the mass
is about thirty four grand
and the radius
is about thirty five centimeters
about seventy centimeters across
i can calculate what the terminals
then they will be terminal speed
i know i'm definitely going to be in this regime
so i know the mass
i know c two which in areas o point eight five
i know to rate is an ontology
so i find that i find about one point eight
the second
so if i drop it
from the a height of three metres which i'm going to do
you would think that the time it takes to hit the floor
would be about my three meters
divided by one point eight
meters per second
which is about one point seven
that's not bad
that's not a bad approximation
however it will of course take longer
and the reason why it will take longer is
the terminal velocity the terminals speed is not achieved instantaneously
with the ball bearings it was within nine seconds
i can assure you that it will take a lot longer
now if you want to
calculate the time it takes
to get close to the terminal
that is not an easy task
you're going to end up with a nasty differential equation
you're going to get MG
you going to get the acceleration which is the result of
set the stage for electrochemical processes
like chemical processing
so what he reasoned is that when you inject charged species into water
you do the same as we do when we
doped semiconductors and we raise the conductivity
and we solid evidence for that last day
let's look at two examples this is hcl as a gas
hydrogen chloride as the gas this is of a polar molecule you've done
analysis of this many times if we bubble this through water it will dissolve and
according to arrhenius dissociate to give us the
proton which is now dissolved in water denoted a queue for aqueous and chloride ions
so we can see injection of charges pluses and minuses and sodium hydroxide is the
prototypical example of a base it's solid room temperature dissolved in water it gives us
a sodium ion
plus hydroxyl
furthermore rainier said that there is an overarching reaction
it involves a reconstitution of the solvent water in this case is acting as the
water is acting as the solvent so we can run the reaction vertically now we
can take
hcl aqueous placenta o h aqueous to give us
in ACL
h two l
so what we're doing is we're reacting the acid with the base to get
the solvent back water plus salt and this is the neutralisation reaction
neutralisation reaction that is to take it away from either acidic or
the basic solution neutralisation involves recombination
the solved
i really want to talk about today is in reference to
aqueous solution chemistry acids and bases but these definitions
of proton donor and so on applied to nonaqueous solvents but for three online when
we're going to say
we're going to stay in
the aqueous phase
now one of the shortcomings of arrhenius theory it was good for the eighteen eighties
but shortcomings always manifest themselves through data and people had known for quite some time
so that they could dissolved ammonia
another molecule that we've seen three online one
they could dissolve ammonia
and when they dissolved in
ammonia and water
they found that they could neutralize
they got an aqueous solution
that neutralizes acid
they found that they got an aqueous solution and neutralizes acid so then they concluded
that ammonia dissolved in water is acting as though it's the base but there's no
hydroxyl here there's no oxygen so you can make o h minus here
so something was incomplete how to explain
how to explain in the absence of
in the absence of of
o eight minus
well i had to wait until the twentieth century and the explanation came from two
places simultaneously
nineteen twenty three
he's in denmark i suppose he's driving a volvo two and lowery in the UK
ronstadt and lower both independently in the same year enunciated
and enhanced definition of broader definition of acid and base
which is as follows that asset
as it remains the same as arrhenius a arrhenius it's substance that's a proton
proton donors
so that seems arrhenius
but then to capture the notion that
an aqueous solution of ammonia can act as as a base they define the base
in terms of something that is chemistry free and they said this is something that
has a proton
a proton acceptor now that's different no mention of
no mention of hydroxyl
anything that accepts protons would fall under the definition of branstad lowery
so here's the prototypical reaction
any substance that has a proton some right protons
plus everything else so a represents the rest of the chemistry of the compound where
h is a hydrogen that can be
dissolved in water and liberated so this is a proton donor
and for the rest the lecture instead of writing aged in the right little p
plus to indicate protons so a change is the proton donor and reacts with some
branstad lowry base which is a proton
it's a proton acceptor
when it reacts
b accepts the proton and becomes the eight plus
has lost a proton and it
is now simply a minus
well if you walk in the room or refute i know this never happens but
if if you had momentarily
i dozov and hadn't caught the last thing that i said you might look at
the right hand side of the equation say well BH class
has the proton that can give away
and become
they could be so
this BH plus
also is a proton donor
and a minus we know from looking at the left side of equation is perfectly
capable of binding to this a minus must be also a protocol
so now what do we see we see that the equation comes in
b and b h plants are donor acceptor in there
associated with one another so i'm going to denote
the BNP age plus associated with one another and h a
and a minus are associated with one another and we call such pairs
we call such pairs conjugate pair
these are conjugate pairs con is the latin for with
yukari is is the latin for to marry and also the the same word for
your book
i think if you pronounce the j is why you can see how you get
you in modern english and in fact i will designate these with your to show
that they are conjugate acid base pairs just to be clear about definitions let's look
h a this is a proton donor so this is both a bronze lowery acid
and it's also an arrhenius acid it conforms to the old definition of arrhenius
this is a proton acceptor b so therefore it's a bronze that lowery base
but it's not an arrhenius base because it has no hydroxyl so you can see
this is the case of in some cases there is a an overlap and others
of circumstances ok if you have a quadratic error function and
then you find the optimum in one step ok using this
so this is the multivariate setting here with where now instead
of having a second order derivative we have the multivariate
equivalent which is the hessian matrix the hessian matrix
has the second-order derivatives according to pairs of
parameters and so the iteration just most in the direction of the
gradient of the object and the learning rate is the inverse of the
hessian ok you do have to estimate the hessian
ok and so typically these methods in order to be used require
more data than methods that are just based on
step-size so this is called newton-raphson method
sometimes called fisher scoring what's bad
well that depends ok typically this kind of second-order method
requires a few error iterations in order to do the computation because
you sort of take optimal steps at the same time you need a batch
of data so it's not an online algorithm
and also there's this inversion of the hessian with which is
expensive there are actually tricks
h for avoiding this kind of explicit computation an inversion
which may hear about later on
but you can actually do this for logistic regression and it results
an algorithm called iterative re we cursive least-squares
and the hessian has a nice form in this case where you have the features
and and this kind of diagonal matrix of h times one minus h
and so the weight updates also become quite nice and it's it's
it's a good algorithm if you are going to do logistic regression
and you can work with these large sees
how do we do regular decision for logistic regression all we do
just what way we do it for linear regression
ok we're going to have to put a prior over the parameter
ok so for example we can just do l to regular izations we can just
say on the weight of a that the norm of the weight vector to be small
this means that again we have a sort of quadratic element in the
error and the optimization is easy
it's a little bit harder now to make sense of what's going on in
the sense that this is suggesting a gaussian prior
then the data comes in and we don't have a conjugate set
is not a conjugates we don't really get a conjugate pasteur
there are other things that one can do here error
a different kinds of regular izations that perhaps would be better
matched to binary data case for example you can consider what is
the error what does the error look like for by binary data will
typically the error is not a gaussian type of error
but it's actually flipping the label and so perhaps working with
gaussian here is not ideal however from a practical point of
view this is very nice ok and so that's one of the reasons why
like people use this
now what's probabilistic view of logistic regression just like
we thought about linear regression we thought about this
kind of noise model we can treat logistic regression in the
same point okay so we can consider the output as being produced
by hypothesis for us some noise ok
but this is actually kind of strange
ok again because the output is binary and what does this kind of
model really me
so instead what we will do is we will consider a continuous variable
ok why hot that's produced by the hypothesis class of noise
and then going to consider the output being generated by thresholding
this variable ok at zero so we're going to generate one if this
variables positive and zero otherwise and so in this case we
actually obtain a nice probabilistic model
for logistic regression now have the
the graphical models of this more complicated we have the inputs
we have epsilon these are used to go
into this sort of y i have a variable
which is then used to generate want ok
so again there's this sort of notion of of a latent variable somewhere
in there that we don't actually get to observe
but that controls the output gets now the other interesting thing
about this kind of interpretation is that it directly
shows you that logistic regression is not a generative model
in other words if i just consider the inputs
and the outputs is not a good weight for
for me to generate what this y hacked might have been
ok and so there are other models other probabilistic models
that are fully probabilistic that allow you to put to relate these
latent variables in in nice ways
ok so we're going to do recap now little bit
we talked about machine learning algorithms hopefully this
was more of a refresher if you've seen this now for the first
time sure it's like completely with by
so so whenever you have a machine learning algorithm have to
think of making a choice of a hypothesis
a choice of an error function and choice of an optimization procedure
very often we're going to make gradient descent kind of optimization
procedure just because they're convenient and they work
sort of in many many cases in some cases this optimization is easy
and in closed form in almost all the case you're going to see
for the rest of the week this is not the case in going to have
to work harder to to get that
and all the algorithms are affected by this kind of bias-variance
trade-off so the overfitting fun common-ion is always a concern
you always have to do cross validation you always have to make
sure that you're not building a model that's too large for the amount
of data that you have a you could do regular sation to control
that you can put priors on hypothesis space
and i should be a little bit of this patient interpretation i'm not
sure how much you'll see of this for the rest of the week but
it's a you're body graph that can scale
linear away was t
so you can
make a mistake almost every time
and here is
a simple example showing why this is so
so examples are drawn independently from
this distribution d
which has supported only examples with equal probability
and you have you want to compete policies
that predict constant actions so you have buy one predict and some action a one
and by to predict and some action e two
have just examples
and this is the these are the words and the words are fixed
if you draw x one which is the probability one half than action one has
both actions happening reworded some small reward see zero point one
and if you don't act still
the action
two has a large reward
of one and action one has no really work
so with probability one half
x one is drawn
and then
the learning
he goes either pi one or PI two problem randomizes because there's is no basis
for choosing otherwise so seeds it chooses pi one
and observes the words zero point one
and then from this point on there will always choose
by one because
the sum of the board
zero point one and it will never explore
action two
because this empirical some of words will always be higher
for a one
right that will be comparing
a one a two
the dome of the sum of rewards will be zero point one four one
because it has previously been chosen
and since it too was never chosen in the past to have
zero as it some of the word
and i don't have to be chosen
the learner will never discovered this one
and it will not compete it will have
you add that scales linearly with the number of steps
so this is about
let's modify the simple longer from
chosen randomly by exploring in the first of all
but just choose random actions for the first tau rounds and observe there
and then find
the policy that is
the leader on the first on the exploration data on the first tau rounds and
then just go with that policy for the remaining
it's i suppose that again examples are drawn independently from a fixed distribution d over
acts grant zero one to the to reward doctors so access and the words are
generated from some distribution and then we can show that for this modified
algorithm regret skills sublinearly
two million two thirds
and here's the dependence on the number of actions
and the
number of policies that are competing with
and you can use standard
arguments to substitute that by the BBC dimension of the set
your computer network
so you can do better than you can have a nontrivial statements saying that you
there is some learning going on because you regret this sublinear
in c
in the preface
very simple
so let's look looking at this quantity
was some and over
the examples
so acts
action taken the word of that action
and this is the indicator function
it tells
whether this one one the policy agrees with the action taken so it's similar to
the qualitative look at
before except that there is this key
in this case here because you weighted by
the probability of taking that action four and the exploration was uniform
so you're waiting instead of summing the words
over the rounds where the policy agrees with the action
you're some in importance weighted estimates of the word so this is your
then you divide by the probability of taking that action
so you divide by one of our key
which means multiplying by
and we'll see how this is important
so instead of some in the words
over the rounds were the indicator function is true you're some in
the you some way that rewards weighted by the probability
of taking the action
and so
if you divide that by time this is just
an empirical estimate of the reward weighted estimate of the war and you can use
standard deviation barnsley half-timbered two
by and the deviation from the expectation with respect to this underlying distribution
so this is the this is is perhaps by how much it can deviate from
the true expectation simultaneously for all policies pi with high probability with probability one minus
right so that bounds the regret let's see you
we can bound the regret on their exploration around by now
by saying that we've got this regret can be at most one in every round
so let's say it
for the bound and then
c minor style which is certainly upper bounded by c
the remaining rounds and this is by how much you can deviate
the true expectation
so this is by how much
how much you p four
going with this
an empirical leader versus the true leader
you've selected on the basis of the exploration around
and then you just optimise
tell you find
it out to minimize this upper bound
the information content
this suggests that really improbable
and smallest things that was written about the fact that something is definitely don't happen if you had probability one
that's got zero
information content
the at probability
then it's got
and information content of one bit
if something happened about the probability
no why
for example
getting tale from colonies
that's got
that's the information content of not to one hundred twenty nine
which is not hard quantisation test when you get
going to gain
fifteen hundreds a bit
well many exciting things happen the rare events
the catalog-based to all over the place
this which is three point three
he says
every had everyone in this file on the screen
is going through the bit bits the information content
so it claiming this is the right way to measure information content i don't know
it's the compressed file length that we should aspire to someone when we invent compression
all x
while like
to which we should ask why
okay so shannon's play
and kind of cooling this
the shannon information content
until convinced that at
and then i'll stop using the name of the school in the information content because
we will have established that really is
the right way
to measure
let's not do so
which we do
let's just make some observations about these
the shannon information content
five one
this side information content is additive
random variables
what i mean by this
okay this is really shorthand for an outcome so
i put outcome in there
so actions at age equal
i'll try and be
the notation but if you get to be
notation that's not fun anymore so
i'm gonna hope that
we clear enough without being too obsessive
the information content the shannon information content is additive for independent random variables
for example
in fact documents on the
that's why
we will be
from a single rule is the hat
the random variables x
with probability distribution that's why
this about
times fewer i
right that's the definition is independent
if we do
and so the land
the shannon information content of the random variables taking on particular
values and i use the shorthand age action might not means the outcome x being
one of the
i mean to
find that
rows and columns of the matrix
so it's about
no matrix factorisation
the next step
is so
all these
sure there will be more in the context of knowledge about
so that
no more
this was or
what's more
in this before
the last
time was
one is
so we get
four was
and he he
in the after the war
that's when
one twenty
i'm not just because you don't
the whole space
twenty five
this problem
this is
one is
so will
this should
so one
the next one
so what
and then
right it's
i want to see
what's more
was seen from the point
and then solve if primal fix equals zero
the solve the linear system of equations you thereby eliminating its but since then no
constraints on the lagrange multipliers everything goes away
so the unconstrained problem the lagrange function will be just the unconstrained objective anyway
this is just a way of incorporating the constraints explicitly
if you do this
you will get
this optimisation problem that you
i will explain it in a much simpler case later on their way novelty detection
so at the moment
don't worry that much about it but basically what it is
this optimisation problem
let me explain the various bits and pieces out five j of lagrange multipliers
y i y j x i x j
basically the kernel matrix
and here are just the lagrange multipliers game
now what happened is
i have considerably more
complicated objective function
lots of lagrange multipliers
but i've got very simple constraints
you just have to constraint that our y y equals zero
which arises from
the constant offset b
but the outline being great people in here that just happens because they are lagrange
as we will see
that is a linear combination
of the excise
and so the african right there
as a linear combination of y y
excited x the constant offset
and finally we have the so-called contact conditions which means
the constraint
conflict and multiply have to avenge
there's a simple example that i can demonstrate will assume this box into besides one
pack of biscuits
it's been a few more but anyway similar empty
the books imposes constraints on my random variable
the biscuits
now that's even assuming this box box were closed
so i've got constraints on all sides it's nice convexity it
the only place where the constraints will exert a force on the biscuit is where
the biscuit actually
the box
so these constraints might as well not be there
so for instance if i have to biscuits and there i can impose additional constraints
using the box
and it's not going to change the location of the biscuit
if i were to change the optimisation problem
and remove this constraint i get a big mess
this is
basically what contact conditions two
ponce force
so those of you have
the answer to the mechanics vol
just classical mechanics at some point
you would have heard of the virtual forces that again
from you know constraint movements of particles
and those virtual forces are exactly those out
those who have not done physics don't worry
who wants to see the prose
who does not want to see the truth
and the reason cao cao the the proof in that case
OK anyway so
his lagrange function it's going to be very easy don't worry
and all you need to do is you need to take derivatives with respect to
w and b
so it is with respect to w one one half the square w is just
w you
it's easy
and here
this expression here to accuse me alpha i y i x i
everything else disappears so that this appears to disappear
so w gives me is somewhere else y y axis
this is exactly what we have here
db of failed
just gives me
now he is the type of lesion across that are in your hand
some of alpha y i
what happens it just cut-and-paste from the max
so what you get out of this this summation constraint some of alpha y equals
so what you can see is actually the free variables
it will eat equality constraints
by the same token
constrained variables will only lead to constraints to inequality constraints
equality constraints will lead to free variables in the field
so that's the so-called theory
now once you can plug of those terms back in here
you will get
the objective function that i showed you
so we would go and maximizes beast but of course rather maximizing the negative square
we can also minimizes way
that's the only change that made
the the proof wasn't that hard was
now why is this really cool
this expression here is really independent of dimensionality physics
the same idea is what we saw in the perceptron here we can see parisian
and the other thing that we see is that there will be only depends on
basically is the pile of
other points which all of them correspond to the
brown point here correspond to all of the points on the brown clustering brown ring
the green one correspond to all the points
and the green ring
and the same for the blue one for clustering this dataset
the rules of
of view of the sorry with k means is trivial simply phi three points in
in in these locations and it became is its immediate this like a means and
the role of this of this idea mean pictures now doing the same thing with
images what wanted it is this is one way of defining an affinity an affinity
matrix or graph in an image is what it is they
took this image
and for this specific experiment they used an edge to edge detector to find an
edges and they use different features of each pixel
for example the use the information they got from asian vector and the used RGB
or the grayscale information they got from the image itself and they built the graph
fast cry for the connected neighbouring pixels
and the value of the edge depends both on the value of the pixels
and from the information they got from the edge detectors
the kind of of segmentation they get these four think six and seven segments
this is the kind of results so they get when the news segment images with
their technique with this with this technique
in questions
it here
what is the k means
o this is something that
they just suggested hand
i think it was in in jordan was in this paper the first suggested use
the k means and then they simply kept on doing it in other papers and
if you look at the way
that investors are
in the in the i can because basically you could call it if you look
if you look at that conductors then k means is not really a reasonable thing
that you could do something more interesting than that but this is simple
and you don't want to complicate algorithm more than that and i'm not sure that
it's it after doing all these all this computation much of it's justifiable to do
other the other other algorithms in the in the i can vector space you could
for example do
like i mean why not going to look right or something that simply itself if
you if you like if you know the k clusters and i can space you
could do against the clustering on that in the space
but we know what the founder what you could put to good experiment enough is
the k means often works good enough even if it something else in order to
get better results in the don't really have any good explanation to why we need
to do
they can better themselves
so this is what is what seen them in the that conductors themselves are the
ones that you need to look at but then came in a similar way to
looking for clusters in if you stack all of that this is one of the
other you could lead to things but you could also could also look at each
of the conductors myself i'm going to talk about it in the second and the
third one in the last one of them going here is is
the one this is the first one actually was published in two thousand here the
metrics to use is
the mine w
and they don't normalise it here but i can probably solve is this one year
if this is and the platinum
the miners w and i can make it so that the problem is solved this
and if we multiply by eighteen months one we get basically the minus one lv
equals lambda v
so even though it is presented like this and then present in the same year
it is the normalized laplacian problems that we're looking for looking at so they define
this matrix demons w they computer i can vectors and they do pretty much the
same thing as male and she did in the in the in the in the
paper i just mentioned before which means that they called k i vectors and they
k means on the rows of this matrix
and the kind of examples they show here is that if they take
this image which is the noisy step on it and the
the graph here
the graph here again each pixel is the name of the graph to compute an
idea to you basically get convicted tells you value it gives you a value to
each of the nodes
so you can plot bag vector
it's an image as well if this is the original images the second largest
the second smallest sorry good idea like correspond to the second smallest eigenvalue and if
you look a means and this kind of aiken victory
this is the competition and you get
the same thing with three segments in this image gives you one two and three
segments if you look at the first three eigen vectors of the k means
on them
and said it looks say pretty much the same thing this normalisation or normalisation so
this is what this light is about they are very closely related
if you look at the first one that they introduced into the wise we look
we see this kind of
matrix the matrix that the problem that in a second problem is always is that
four male and she was sold this one unfortunately the third one
now let's see what we can do here all can we move from different that
one if you look at the page and the njw the first one
i can problem and we multiply both sides by dt the manifold of we get
this expression here
and this is pretty much the same
is that expression if we define the to be
the minds of you so if we define beta beta minus one
but it myself you we get this fixed this problem and that problem to be
and if we look at it
additionally problem which is
this is most processing problems and we something similar we get that lambda which is
that the value of male and she
equal to one minus like my one minus mu were used again by the austrian
malik so simply on a mirror image of all of that values each item should
say each i value your
between minus one in one
so taking one minus
simply gives us a mirror image
one of the of the order of about this is why taking the largest because
i vectors corresponding to the largest values here
we're taking the one corresponds to the smallest here gives you the same i can
which at the end
so they are very closely related and you can move from each if you know
the solution of one of them you can very easily move the solution of the
other one the only thing that we need to keep in mind is that if
you want to use enjoy NYC to do this extra normalisation of roles in diagonal
vectors which you don't need to do
and the reason that you don't need to do that is exactly this which implication
if we is the normalisation of rows of u
we're trying to predict are not just is not just a single real value or
simple binary number but is something that's more complex in structure and in some sense
so we could think about you know sequences strings trees and graphs and what have
you that we now see on the output side cases and i'm not talking about
the input side you know where we can define give course kernels over strings and
trees and graphs and the like but i talk about the output side we want
to predict the tree we want to predict a sequence
OK and the interesting thing is that you know typically we so we have multiple
response variables and his response variables are not it would be very suboptimal in many
cases to treat them independently right we don't want to make independent predictions but rather
interdependency between the outputs into account so we would really want to look at the
whole prediction we make
right and not just to predict bit by bit in the way independently
so the question is how can we
how can we use state-of-the-art machine learning problems to generalize to to that family of
problems and the idea here is that we actually combine support vector machines with markov
random field ultimately but i will not really talk much about markov random fields here
but still try to get the main idea across
so whether these problems show up just to you know provide some motivation and background
someone is think about problems like handwritten character recognition right very often people treated the
way that they say well i have a window of a particular character and then
i try to predict what the letter is but that's really not what you typically
have in practice because in practice you often have a sequence of letters and you
want you know and handwritten words and you want to predict the sequence of letters
and there are some
regularities in a language like english for instance you know which letters are likely to
appear together right which has to do with genetics and so on and so forth
so it's not completely independent for instance here you know this letter he could also
be in the e
right or it could be a c
but it makes more sense to treat it as i see because then you know
this word would
because not yours is something like it so that the context provides a lot of
there are other things like protein folding
where what we might want to do right this is of course i'm not saying
that with these methods you can actually solve the protein folding problem but just to
give you some idea right at some point we would like to take a sequence
of amino acids like this
and predict certain things so for instance you know something
part of the secondary structure or perhaps even the serious struck structure of the protein
so the the input is a sequence and the output is also perhaps the sequence
or we could try to predict what is known as the contact matrix and things
like that
or from the closer to our application domain here and is something like information extraction
where interested we have documents like that and we are interested in in finding that
a named entities like you know like names countries organizations locations and so on and
so forth and somehow
mark them
kind of producing markup like this where we actually see we put tags in there
that they would
identify these entities and we can think of it actually has as of the problem
of producing a label sequence where with with each word we
we classify and this is another named entity not named entity not an invented in
the fourth and this is now an organisation and this is not not not and
so on and so forth and here we have country and country right so you
can think of this
i can be encoded information in the text can be encoded for instance in terms
of the label sequence and then there are certain dependencies right among these labels and
we would like to capture those
and then you know this is also a special case of what i'm talking about
here is another example is natural language that's natural language parsing where you know the
input is a sequence that in english what we want to produce to predict the
past tree like that right label parse tree and we will assume that the rules
of the grammar given OK so we know what type of rules are allowed but
we don't know
sort of you know how likely a particular posture is given a particular sentence right
of course typically that there are many parts trees that are possible for sentence but
we want to predict the most the most plausible the most likely one
and so we can also think of that as the problem given a string
o sentence in english language we want to predict tree
right so how do we do that
and it just so
the way we
we set up the problem is in a two step process first we define a
discriminant function or
you could also called the compatibility function and then we use that actually to produce
the output so the other compatibility function or the discriminative discriminant functions
we define in the following way at the function i call capital and here it
takes an input and an output OK
and is parametrized by some vector w and produces a real number how does it
produce the real number while it computes an inner product between this weight vector and
what i call a joint feature map that takes inputs and outputs
the a pair of input and output and maps to some m dimensional feature representation
available on the next slides i will give you some examples of how the people
that map actually looks like right so not as it if you think about binary
classification right then
this is
kind of similar only there you only take the input and you compute an inner
product of the inputs which actually within the wires is binary label would actually show
up in front of this inner product as a sign basically
and so we define a function what we want is we want to just the
in a way that the correct input output pairs get higher f values as compared
some x y prime with the incorrect output OK we just one basically for a
given x the correct output to give us high values and incorrect ones to produce
law values so that if we if we have to make a decision we can
take for a given x k x is an important is an english sentence and
we want to predict the past we take the argmax over all possible parse trees
let's say if we could do that effectively and look at this compatibility function and
choose the one that is most compatible with the input
and now we can adjust these weights in a way that we change this compatibility
function and we want to shape it in a way that you know four forces
in training patterns training pairs input output pairs we make the correct predictions
OK so the binary classification case a special can be can be thought of as
a special case of that in the following way that we define this joint feature
map psi effects come why just as y why not being one minus one variable
time some pizza representation
five x just
a typical feature map that's used in kernel and the incoming based method so
so then we can see that if we take the argmax over all possible values
for y of this function as we defined it
you know we plug is in here and then kind of you know this
can be seen to be equivalent to this just taking the sign of the inner
product which is exactly the way we define linear classifiers in the binary problems right
so you can see this is
and this is a slightly different setting from the usual generous actually in that sense
you actually have to take this is the set up that's how we we can
manage to
get that they morphine because this is where we have for lunch as well so
we have it set up this way hopefully you can utilize the table for taking
notes and what can again and we have an exciting they
of five sessions presentations and activities ahead of us and i hope you had a
good less last night was that get going for today
and maybe one more minute people still trickling in
hello everybody gives me great pleasure
to be introducing st
to be giving this talk today
on foster equalisation parts y coordinate descent
two what is well known in this community
his yellow book on elements of statistical learning for many of us
who have gotten into data mining through the nonstatistical part this has been
a very valuable book it has given us the much needed
foundations for understanding many of the data mining operators that we just take for granted
and hence the idea of this talk think that it's going to be really valuable
for us to understand the data mining from one of the strongholds in the field
of statistics
he has another book this one is far statisticians on generalized additive models which he
has co-authored with should
he has been working in statistics for thirty years and of course he has made
a diverse range of contributions in many different areas as a five to just use
two words to summarize the most of what he has done its nonparametric regression and
he's lying on these tools
for solving these problems in the bio
and may be seen in genomics kind of industry
on the computing side in fact many of the
libraries which are there in the famous statistical software packages like s plus and i
have been due to his influence and contribution
but he confesses that his favorite languages in fact fortran not the statistical languages
he has been with the department of statistics stanford for almost nineteen years first five
as a phd student
and then twenty twelve years as a free-floating faculty member and for the past two
years he has been on a sentence apparently he is the chair of the department
and he's really waiting for that turn to another one
and like many great statisticians he has spent late nineteen very productive and funnier as
in the labs in its he
so he's very fond of those that period too he grew up in south africa
in fact and he enjoys surfing and and he continues to live with that passion
although sometimes the t two goes into the important so this is very well known
in the field and he has given many talks in fact this is his twenty
first keynote talk in over the last eight years is a fellow of the american
statistical foundation and institute of mathematical statistics and i thought it was a big deal
but then he tells me in the morning today that he was a fellow of
the royal statistical society even before he got his phd so without further delay it
may moving come to vote to give us stock
my life
and everyone you meet
well thank you very much for small healing for organizing the conference and so need
for very nice introduction thank you very much
she asked me for
some background it and i gave a quite about shoes speed some of the worst
thank you
it's very nice to be
i know lot of you
the computer science field and
was really you talk and coordinate descent because
i think coordinator since being dismissed as a technique for optimisation city among my engineering
undaunted agree with plans to head and i hope to convince you today
at least in this application
so this is joint work with my
i two co-authors jerry friedman and rob tibshirani from stanford university
one of the favourite pastime
jerry's the class of carbon ions and actually to be fair to rob that's my
students young pop graduating and i wasn't able to be there so he
he went in
and congratulated for me
this is the story about linear models
and using linear models in data mining
probably ten years ago we would get such to talk because the new models were
somewhat out of phase fashion we were doing much more aggressive
but some things changed datasets have grown wide
which means we have many more features than samples in a lot of applications
and so the linear model has regained favor in data miners toolbox
there have so many variables from the linear model in some applications is all we
we can manage to do
and before we start overfitting so you some examples
so document classification is is a prime example
we often use the bag of words
we we take the collection of say words in english language and mark them for
his presence they were absent in the document
and that can easily lead to
twenty thousand features for each document and we might have something like five thousand documents
so in statistics job we'd say p is bigger than we always use p for
the number of variables and in the number of samples
so for example the spam classification example is is
is one email classification is spam or not
it's the document
we look at the the set of words
the some of the early spam filters would do that and classify document is spam
in fact
little embarrassingly
when i was first invited by sunita to be the keynote speaker in this in
this conference
message went straight into my spam back
so i didn't see
and then she said reminder two weeks later
they don't want to actually give this talk about and i have to tell you
that i haven't seen the misadventure enough i found in the in the spam black
so my guess my spam filter still work in progress
image deblurring classification images
notoriously have a large number of features if you use the pixels in
as features
and the number of samples can be relatively small
the area where we i worked a lot is in genomics
so for example in microarray studies
you can easily forty thousand features
which may be represent versions of genes
you might only have a
if you is a hundred samples
and more recently in genome wide association studies
where we measure snaps
single nucleotide polymorphisms
and they can easily be
five hundred thousand ninety seven million synapses mission along the genome
often they do these in
for specific diseases and trying to discover
cause us to specific diseases and you might say two thousand case control samples
so in all these cases
we've got many many more features than we have observations
and the linear model is very useful
and we use them such as linear regression
majestic regression
if we go just quickly go back to this picture
this is an infinite dimensional space right and if we use say girls in
the family of gaussians as a model
guassian has is characterized by a finite dimensional parameter vector so it has a finite
number of degrees of freedom right a parametric model is a finite number of degrees
of freedom
so it is
it is finite dimensional subset of this space here
and a finite dimension a subset of an infinite dimensional space is small
so we don't have it
it will be difficult if are in general it is if we don't know what
the true distribution is that it would be difficult to get close to the true
and the ideas
if you can make
if you if you want to make a more and more flexible that means if
you want this model to spread out more widely over space
and be closer to any possible
distribution of the of the data and then you have to use a nonparametric model
you can't do that with a finite
fundamental parameters
if u if you do parametric statistics a parametric bayesian statistics and you have to choose the prior
and you don't know anything about what
what the parameters should look like then of course
but what you usually do is choose a uniform prior right a
maximum uncertainty
now if we don't know anything about what our model is in this case
then would also like to choose something like a uniform prior something that spreads out evenly over the whole space
but as i mentioned earlier already
the space is infinite-dimensional in infinite dimensional this uniform distribution just don't exist and
we need we need something else can
we just at this point say a few words about what
about the interpretation of
of prior assumptions
in bayesian nonparametrics because they are a bit different
the prior assumptions that we make a parametric statistics these these
you know technically it's kind of the same thing but the interpretation comes out a little bit differently
so in
in parametric statistics if you say put a prior on calcium
then the prior assumption is
the mean of my data something something that says the mean of my data is
probably going to be over here
and that's what about putting a prior on august expresses
whereas in
in these nonparametric models
what expressed by the prior assumption is typically more and more structural properties so for
example in the jeep regression model
he so that
and if if if
if the unknown parameters the bandwidth
of course the girls in process prior
we don't know the benefits of the process prior
well if we if we choose the benefits of the gas process prior
we can send any continuous function from that model
and the prior assumption says it will probably oscillate at a certain rate and was
probably have frequency roughly in the range
that's our prior assumption
end in
remember what we talked about yesterday in clustering
if we choose for example if you choose is a chinese restaurant process prior dirichlet process prior then hour assumption
that the prior assumption that encodes is
how does the number of the does they distribution of cluster sizes behave
the dirty process could see assumption
it the number of of clusters distributed logarithmically in the number of data points right
it's an assumption on the decay
of this cluster weights and if we believe that for example
that we have
so i believe we have a small number of clusters and that's may be a good
choice yeah
and if we believe that the clusters follows for the distribution of class follows a power law
then we would instead use the pitman yor process
for instance you
just see how much time i have
all right so these these kind of results that
the people
like order that the mathematics statisticians are interested in
to quantify
how well behaved these models are there are basically two
two types of properties that people are interested in
one is a property called consistency
and roughly speaking what consistency means is
my going to recover
the right value of the parameters
supposing that have infinitely an infinite amount of data
so in
in parametric statistics are parametric non bayesian statistics
i'm consistency simply means that these
the estimator is going to converge to the true parameter values
now in bayesian statistics
we're not actually computing an estimator point estimator about what we want compute is a posterior
so we have to formulate what it means forum four posterior to converge and basically what that means is
the easiest way to think about is simply that the posterior as we see more
and more data becomes more and more people
and that in the in the limit of infinitely many data points that they become a delta peak
at singapore and that should be
if it's consistent that should be the true parameter about
now there's there's
a simple definition of of consistency bayesian models in which is following
there's a problem tell you in advance there's a problem with this definition this definition
has been used for a long time
and it's the following if we
if we
assume that we sample the data from
specific distribution which has parameter values theta not
so you don't what is the true parameter value that is actually generated the data
if the posterior converges
to this this true parameter values
with probability one under the prior
then we say that the model is consistent why do we have this extra with
probability one and the prior if you sample
if you sample from a bayesian model then remember we do stage sampling we first sample a parameter value
from the prime
then we plug that into the likelihood and we sample idea from
from the likelihood and that's the way we generate idea
now what we have to ask is if we say the posterior converges okay we
can take this data that we have sampled we can compute the posterior from there
but what it will what it will converge to depends on which parameter value we
have drawn from the prior right and hopefully it will converge to the actual value
this definition here says
it it always has to do with it
except fore
some parameter values
as long as there has probability zero
that seems perfectly safe
assigned them
assign each one of them a countable set
and show that i can use it to all of the artists
so the first
the unit circle in the x y plane
the second set is
on the axes
the sets with coordinates where with the in square loss for in
the distance from each BN
o point on this article is to a
well for this purpose for the last one
two in response to the assignment of scholars
to be assigned to call the
countable set and was one and so on
what about to be
well i think there a a countable subsets of the
its power is the same power is this set
there is a one-to-one correspondence
now if your site
colors to the b and you cannot assign a finite set of colors
it has to be in c
if it is infinite that one of these point p
will be assigned subset of the
and you cannot choose the kind of funny because all of them are taken by
OK we fool is
the this it
we just mentioned the all this and what the plane is not a useful
is this thing to see text us the point with integer coordinates
on the x axis
they will perform in infinite complete
bipartite graph
all the points will be connected by an actual the
we prove that the are two of but his car which is will
i will present this will it takes more than once
one slide so i don't believe
conference will take more than one slide
as we saw the full
space is not
how to choose the
as of last thursday
we call that the this one is
and if one chooses all
the surprising fact that these regardless of the whether you believe in the
so in any model of set theory
this is
and if one chooses
so this
however one problem the quality of this in the query and i hope we are
move to build a simple puzzle he was one
much that is suitable for high-school students
forget about the notation might be to compensate for them
it's not that FNB the minimal
the maximum perimeter of a rectangle among all possible partition the unit square into an
even number for us
so this is a trivial problem when n is equal to case where just politicians
this way
in two
k sports where each one of them all
size one one with k one
one of is partition into rectangles in case n is taking place plus one show
the picture and the second is just
partition the square into rectangles
of size one hundred eight by one of the first ones
OK i think
the proof that this is optimal is far from easy it was done by in
then you look like
so here is an example of what said he was a politician of the square
two four six forty nine
which minimizes the largest perimeter
it was the a partition of the square
in two
forty two six times seven rectangle
it's not obvious that this is the minimum
the limit
among all possible partitioning the square into four triangles but it will
for and one of the major reasons is that
having we didn't actually OK
let's start from those from another perspective
technically this would be no problem to make this
because you could just like changes system and allowed yet another parameter to the subject
in whatever it doesn't matter the day
we had a number of different ideas how to realize to define the syntax
the system can do easily to solve the problem
the actual problem comes fifty users
in the week wiki
you're expecting
or do users expecting to be able to change everything quickly
now if you have very
and you see some resolved
you want to be able to to change his her UG and you want to
be able to change did way use quickly you have to be able to figure
does this data come from
now if it would be possible to add
arbitrary triples to the wiki on every side
it would be very hard to use it to figure out to which
page has actually to go
to change that we're value
so we didn't know we were not able to solve that
problem from the user perspective that's why we don't have the ability to add arbitrary
the triples there are other semantic wikis that allow exactly that for example travel wiki
engine allows to add arbitrary RDF and i don't know about wikipedia does it to
give you
they also
because this is
the model
the neuron
the market
if you think want use
what they do is
so is the one
OK it will be pretty hard to solve that problem technically i think this is
the problem that has
be solved by the community that's using the wiki and if you look at wikipedia
it's definitely been issued their another example that i like to use because much closer
than to attend to taiwan is nicola test
and there's a lot of discussion going on in nicholas haslam website if he's croatian
if he's serbian or whatever other thing he could be
we during serban others here me up involves
to level hierarchy where there's one level of recurrent net
that is reading c words in a sentence but you also imagine a characters
in a word and another level which is working at the level here
sentences and and you can have more levels if you want and
but you can imagine many ways that you can implement these ideas
of hierarchy
now if we goes to something are very recent with which i think brings
fresh ideas to this question of long term dependencies
memory networks which you will hear more about
a you can think of the networks as some kind of
recurrent network where the state part of the state is now stored
in in a big memory big outside memory i'm going to show you next
picture because it's going to easier
to understand so so so you have a set of memory cells
and at each time step what happens is that those memory cells
either get copied from the previous time step or somebody writes
something into a cell and somebody is is
net right recurrent net and when you write something into the
cell of course you're you're going to forgetting all values but
most of the time if you have a big memory
and you're only writing one place at time basically
you're just copying and so information gets
propagated for a very long time other words
if you have like a memory it can memory of
during machine when you store things in there
it robustly stays for long time right so that kind of sidesteps the
the problem long-term dependencies or lease it reduces
so this is a nice recent paper from new
and also involving toronto people where
we try to think of how to characterize these recurrent net
architectures and we came up with three
interesting measures to help us understand an architecture
so one of them is the the a feedforward depth that's like the
yellow paso memory we stack recurrent net so how long does it
take to go from input to output through
different layers that's basically like going in the feedforward
direction then you have the recurrent depth which
tells us what's the longest path from a particular timestep to
later in the future potentially going through all the complications
of the architecture and in this particular architecture you see that
you can you can pack tool nonlinearities
for each timestep because you can go through this layer than then
the one above and then at the same time step and then go to the
next timestep at the same level and so this red path here
actually pacs twice as much depth per timestep than a standard
architecture and then the third quantity
that interesting to consider is the skip coefficient
which tells us about blue arrows that tells us not about the
longest path from beginning to the end but the shortest path
that's also useful when you want to have these paths
in order to learn long-term dependencies
so their experiments that i don't have to tell you about showing
how all these things through all of these things matter
briefly there's been a a bunch of work exploring
how we can playing with that the weight nature x
in order to make it easier to learn term dependencies so for example
you could initialize it to be father
or you can actually constrain it to be unitary matrix
which has all the eigenvalues equal to one
or you can play a game similar to what you have been
nets where sometimes the jacoby is just the identity because you
just copy the few state next state yeah and you can random we
do that and this is called zone now recent paper
also from yeah
ok i'm now earlier i said that in a standard recurrent net
we can interpret the computation and the the the model
as a directed graph model without any latent variables
and what that means is that all the randomness that is injected when
we generate something is happening at the level of observations
have the visible variables at the data level right
so if we're for working on pixels it's like the way that we
generated images that we randomly pick the next pixel and
then the next pixel given the previous pixels
but it would make a lot of sense if instead
that the randomness was about taking decisions regarding not low
level not the pixels but the high-level hierarchy like
what is this picture going to be about what is this text going
to be about what what is this music the about
you'd like to take these high-level decisions and then condition
on these high-level decisions you might want to put in the details
at low level so for this you need to introduce late actually can
variables not just the deterministic ones we have a regular
recurrent net we need to introduce the
variables so sort of a high-level of the current key
corresponding to high-level abstractions so like you decide on
the high-level structure and then given that the
decide low levels structure so we the last nips we had a paper about
combining ideas from what's called the original one orders which
hopefully will be also covered later this week
in recurrent nets you haven't seen these things yet i'm not going
to go much detail and how much time but basically you can combine
the idea is in some of these modern latent variable models
in recurrent nets can stick in high-level
random decisions in in the computational graph
in the model
so that the model showed you earlier which has
two levels of recurrent nets like one working on words the other
working on sentences you can also have random variables at each
timestep which control sort of high-level decisions about you know
maybe what topic are we going to be talking about the next sentence
given everything that we've said before
and then you know given that we can generate the next sentence
and that's that's also been work of julian serban
so there are other fully observed neural nets
there are directed graphical models that are
not really recurrent net but or you know maybe different from recurrent
nets and is worth talking about now
and they belong to a larger family which
uses the same decomposition i told you the beginning remember i
told you that we can take a joint distribution
p of x one two axiom we can write it as a product of conditionals
that's when one of the basic know things you should know about
probability distributions and so in general we get
three of the sort here
we need to know that all randomized algorithms require make model comparisons now we know
that so all is well
that's that's the comparison model any questions
before we go on
so the next topic is to burst out
of the comparison model
and try to sort in linear time
it's pretty clear as long as you don't have some kind of parallel algorithm or
something really fancy you can sort any better than linear time exhibit leask scott look
at the data
matter what you're doing the daily gotta look at otherwise you not sorting
OK so linear times the best we can hope for and logan it's pretty close
how could we saw in linear time
we're going to need some more powerful assumption and this is the counterexample
we're going to have to move outside the comparison model do something else with elements
and what we're going to do is assumed
that there are integers
in a particular range
and we'll use that to sort in linear time
so we're see two algorithms for sorting
faster than n log n
the first one is pretty simple
and we'll use it in the second half it's called counting sort
so the input to counting sort is an array is usual
but we're going to assume what those array elements look like
so each AI
is an integer
in the range from one
to catch
so this is a pretty strong assumption
the running time is actually going to depend on case of k smallest going to
be good algorithm case big it's going to be really bad algorithm
the worse than an organ
care goal
is to output some sort of version of this rank
let's call this
sorting a
so it's going to be easier to write down the output directly instead of writing
down the permutation
for this algorithm
and then we have some things iliary storage
i'm about to write down the pseudocode which is why
and for declaring all my variables here
and the ciliary storage will have length k
which is the range
on my input values
so let's
see the algorithm
this is counting sort
and it takes a little while to write down but it's
it is straightforward
the first is initialisation
then we do some counting
we do some something
actually write the output
so does that perfectly clear to everyone
no one could
this should illustrate how obscure so code can be
and when you're solving your problems that you should keep in mind that it's really
hard to understand
just given pseudocode like this
we need some kind of english description of what's going on because well you could
walk through to figure out what this means it could take half an hour to
an hour
and that's not a good way of expressing yourself
so what i will give you now is the english description will
refer back to this
to understand
this is sort of our bible what the other is supposed to do
sometimes and not even aware that that's what they're doing
and i want you to understand that on those occasions
our most likely respond by
inviting you to consider
the article of faith
that lies behind the question is creating a particular problem for you
i'm not going to be drawn into a philosophical or theological debate over the merits
of that belief but also point out how or why that belief might be making
it difficult for you to read or except what the text is actually and not
ideally saying and leave you to think about that and i see is wonderful learning
opportunities for the class
those are no way problem for me
all right so that's
if you sort of necessary facts and figures now about the bible and then i
need to talk a little bit about the organisation of the course so those are
the last two things we really need to do
i'm an overview of the structure of the bible so you have a couple handouts
that should help you here
so the bible is this assemblage of books and writings
i'm dating from approximately one thousand BCE we're gonna
here very diverse opinions about how far back this stuff dates down to the second
century last but within the hebrew bible was written in the one sixties
BCE some of these stories some of these books which we don't think roughly from
a certain date they will contain narrative snippets or legal materials are traditions oral traditions
that may even date back to stretch back further in time they were perhaps transmitted
orally and then ended up in these these written forms the bible is written largely
in hebrew hence the name hebrew bible
there are a few passages in aramaic
so you have to hand out that breaks down the three major components that someone
written in two columns per page OK
for the we're going to talk in minute about those three sections so you want
to have handy
these writings have had a profound and lasting impact on three world religions judaism christianity
and islam
for the jewish communities to first compile these writings in the pre-christian era
the bible was
perhaps first and foremost a record of god's eternal covenant with the jewish people
so the jews refer to the bible as the ten i
the term you see up here should be
also on that she turned which is really
the letters ten
and they put the leaving they're making easy to pronounce because it's hard to pronounce
the ten OK
and this is an acronym
and the the t
dance for torah
which is the word that means instruction or teaching often translated law i think that's
a very poor translation
since instruction way teaching
and that refers to the first five books that you see listed here genesis through
the second division of the bible is
referred to as navy even which is the hebrew word for profit
actually the prophet is divided really into two parts because there are two types of
writing in the prophetic section of the bible
the first or former profits continues the kind of narrative prose account of the history
of israel focusing on the activities of israel's profit
right so the for the former prophets are narrative text
the latter prophets are poetic and oracular writings that bear the name of the prophet
to home the writings are ascribed it the three major prophets isaiah jeremiah anything feel
the twelve minor prophets which in the hebrew bible get counted together as one book
was a lot of those twelve or very small
the final section of the bible is referred to as too vehement hebrew which simply
means writing from that
that's probably about fifty percent of the hebrew going to get the whole course of
please don't be scared by two or three other terms are useful along the way
but this there's really no need to know hebrew i just want you to understand
why to not is is the word that's used to refer to the bible
so the qu two v with ratings are really miscellaneous they contain works of various
and the three parts corresponding very roughly to the process of canonization or authoritativeness for
the community the torah the torah probably reached effects and authoritative status first
and the books of the prophets and finally the writings and probably by the end
of the first century all of this was organised in some way
if you look at the other hand out you'll see however
that any course on the bible is going to run immediately into the problem of
defining the object of study
because different bible served different communities over the centuries one of the earliest translations of
the hebrew bible was the translation into greek
known as the step two again
it was written for the benefit was translated for the benefit of jews who lived
in alexandria greek speaking jews who lived in alexandria egypt in the hellenistic period before
somewhere around three the third or second century
the translation
has some divergences with the traditional hebrew text of the bible as we now have
it including the order of the books and some of these things are charted for
you on the chart that i've i've handed out
the step two again
the tokens rationale for in the book the temporal
they've clustered books
through esther which tell of things past the books of jobs through the song of
songs the the song simon
contain wisdom that applies to the president and then the prophetic books isaiah malachi contain
hotel of things future
some copies of the set two again contains books not included in the hebrew canon
but accepted in the early christian can
this step two we get the greek translation became by and large the bible of
or more precisely it became the old testament of the hebrew bible
turn the church adopted the hebrew bible is the precursor to it's largely hellenistic gospels
was an important association for it with an old and respected tradition
our primary concern is the bible of the ancient israelite and jewish community
the twenty four books grouped in the torah prophets in writing on that other she
way of making decisions and the trick classify fire is making decisions according to the
lines that separate vertically or horizontally because they're just setting thresholds on the features
and now there is a so-called fit versus robustness trade-off
i told you that you know there is this problem of eventually of affecting what
should we sure you know a linear decision boundary for example or decision boundary that
that fits very well the training examples
well fist in new data
that are you not that we're not your training examples and i'm representing here is
filled and filled circles if you're lucky they're all going to fall on the right
side of the decision boundary that you've inferred from your training example
if you're unlucky you're going to make mistakes and are going to be more likely
to make mistakes if you have a simple decision boundary like that or if you
have a more complex one so here i'm making one mistake of one blue example
which is classified on the right side
and here i'm actually making many more errors even though you know i was fitting
very well the training examples
with my new test examples and making tons of errors so
obviously you know this is a made-up example i could also have drawn to test
examples of the deform the right side of the decision boundary in the non-linear case
but as it turns out there are theoretical arguments that tell you that in general
it's a better idea to use the simpler model and will go over that you
in future lectures there is another dimension that you can play with which is the
bias value
and as you can see here you can put more weight on the errors of
on one class as you put weight on the of the other class so if
you think that making error of classifying blue example into the red class is worse
than classifying in red example into the bill class then you might want to shift
your decision boundary a little bit upwards so that you have some safety margin and
you're not going to be making errors of classifying blue into the red class otherwise
if it's the other way around you might want to shift your decision boundary in
the other direction
in general you can vary that bias value and money to the trade-off between the
error you're making on the positive class in the area making the negative class and
this is what's is the so-called roc curve for our curve but the ROC curve
key is is you know by varying the bias
it plots
the success rate of the positive class so-called hit rate
versus one minus the
the negative class success rate of also called the false alarm rate
and the larger the area under that curve is the better from the point of
view of the classification accuracy
and this is one way people
measure classification accuracy was to be independent on the particular choice of the bias that
that you make the idea ROC curve is this one it has an area of
one and it's you know making no
on the negative class and then when you move device of making no error on
the positive class
the around the case when you making you know you're flipping a kind of making
decisions at random for the positive and negative class gives you the diagonal and so
are you get in that case an AUC of zero point five and this is
you know one actual roc care people measure things in different ways in different domains
so sometimes people measure lift curve ROC curves and in which case they plot you
know the fraction of good customers receive the fractions of customers selected don't want to
go into detail that but you shouldn't confuse both right it's just to plucking a
little bit something different you looking the hit rate versus the total fraction of of
people selected more general issue here is the the real picture
more generally if you have two classes and making predictions
then you will have several types of errors the false positive which are when you're
classifying positively an example but it really was of the negative class the false negative
when you're classifying an example as negative but it really was of the positive class
and then you have the correct classifications between negative and if true positive
if you add up to two negative plus false positive is the total number of
negative examples
false negative intra-party the total number of positive examples
and then what i call rasher rejected examples of the total number of examples that
you have classified as negative so when you made your decision so some of that
you have the selected examples the ones that you have split classified as positive
according to your decision function
and this is the overall total
so using these quantities you can compute virtually all the measurements that people use to
the performance of classic fires
so you talk about false alarm of false alarm rate as the fraction of false
positive over the total number of negative examples negative meaning belonging to the negative class
and actually traces the true positive over the total number of positive examples the fraction
of selected is the number of selected over the total number of examples
OK you have also precision so using this or you get a picture of of
you will see x-rays when hotspot here you will not see x-rays
so we observe from these systems
x-ray positions
think of the following
x-ray positions our clock the clock of the rotating neutron star
if the neutron star in a binary system because they always and the binary system
the x-ray binaries if it's coming to you
using doppler shift the text of the clock commanded closer together if the neutron star
moves away from you the text of the clocks a little bit further apart that's
exactly the doppler shift is all about
so by timing the policies of the x-rays you can get a handle on the
doppler shift of the
neutron star that means you can get the speed of the neutron star you can
get the radius of the orbit you can get the period just like we discussed
but now you taken off the x-ray observations but we have to be made from
outside to the atmosphere
because x-rays are absorbed by the earth's atmosphere
now you think an optical telescope and you look from the ground
and now you see
the optical spectrum of the donor
and what you see in the don't you see these absorption lines
and as the donor moves around the centre of mass this absorption lines move back
and forth
the doppler shift of the donor so you know the velocity of the donor you
know the radius of the donor not the radius of the domain of radius of
the orbit you know the period
so now we have a situation
but i just described earlier
that you have the doppler shift of both
and remember i told you that you also get
massive you get the mass of the donor and the mass of the
the creator
before i go ahead let me show you some
slides so we have to lower this again
it's possible
i want to show you an artist
conception of such a
binary system
so this is what it may look like
you see the don't know there
and you see the neutron star
right here so small of course invisible
and this is the accretion disk
swirls in the matter
hands up on the neutron star and is another view
give you an idea
one of the donor
and then this world of matter
and then this world and ends up here on the north pole
and here
you see
they that were obtained in nineteen seventy one
it's clear evidence for the existence of these rotating neutron stars with the x three
you see here the observed x-ray intensity as a function of time
and the actual data it is very thin lines
and this bold line was drawn over by authors to convince you
that you see
the signal which is highly periodic
time from here to here is one point two four seconds this object was called
hercules x one
so this is one of the magnetic poles and this is due to magnetic
one magnetic pole and other magnetic
so you see unmistakably the rotation of the neutron star the x-ray position
you see data from the same object
but now the time scale is very different from here to here is one day
this is two days
and when you look at this
they don't forget this for now
notice that you see
the source is active in x-rays the one point four two second oscillations you cannot
see of course anymore because the timescale is different
but notice here no x-rays at all
one point seven days later no x-rays at all
so what you're looking at here what we call x-ray eclipse when the neutron star
moves behind
the donor star all the x-rays are absorbed by the donor star you get extra
clips is another words you get independently from the doppler shift you also get
the period of the orbit
by the x-ray
and this really changed our concept of
of astronomy
the existence of these
neutron star binaries
now comes the part
well i the masses of these objects i already alluded due to the idea of
the possibility that there may be black holes
all the mass measurements that have been done to date of these neutron stars where
you UCD
both nations
all of them
very close
two one point four solar mass
and there's a good reason for that that's not an accident
in nineteen thirty
the physicist john cigar
that white dwarfs
could not exist if the mass is larger than one point four solar mass was
quantum mechanical calculations for which he received in nineteen eighty three nobel prize
remember we discussed wide or early white dwarf
it's about a radius of ten thousand kilometres about the same as the earth
and imagine that you have a white dwarf
you add that to the white dwarf you pass the one point four solar mass
more than the white dwarf will collapse and becomes a neutron star
and so when we measure the masses of neutron stars it turns out
maybe someone by surprise that they are all very close to one point four
you could add more matter to the neutron star by creating more and more matter
and you reach the point
that's the neutron star becomes as massive as three times the mass of the sun
we believe that the neutron star can no longer support itself and becomes
a black hole
so now comes the question what is a black hole
the black hole
is the most bizarre objects that you can imagine
and it is something that you want to stay away from two
a black hole
has no size
unlike the neutron star
it has no size
it doesn't have mass
and it has a lot of mass
three times the mass of the sun ten times the mass of the sun a
hundred times the mass of the sun
so it has mass
but it has no side
we identify
around the black hole
the sphere with radius are
which we call
the event horizon
imagine you're are at the event horizon
you want to
get away from the black hole
what kind of speed do you need
you should be able
to give me you answer immediately escape velocity
must be
two and
divided by
the radius of the event horizon
in other words the radius of the event horizon itself
equals two mg
divided by c squared
if you tell me what and this i'll will tell you what the radius of
the event horizon is
i when the little fast here i skipped an important step
v is the escape velocity from the event horizon which is at a distance capital
are from the mass and
so we see that here
now the escape velocity can never be larger than the speed of light
so the maximum value possible
and now you look at this part of the equation in you take
the radius on one side
you get the radius of the event horizon
equals two and
divided by
c square
that's how i found that equation sorry that i went a little too fast
if m is the mass of the earth
the radius of the event horizon is one centimeter
now we want to look at
so we have seen
an analysis of
the problem
we can also write
the following me
one minus two
so this is another way of writing the constrained optimisation problem that give rise to
the update
for the green we so before
this this algorithm and the solution of an iterative update
it's cool
passive aggressive
passive aggressive air
because of this
and the article passive-aggressive because it doesn't have more than which is not an aggressive
model which is carried out
aggressively to fix the date
and this is your
comedy crime out
yoram singer shy
shallow versus well
we also have to show that
a bunch of
the at all
the visit
paper in the journal of machine learning research but if you look for the great
OK now of course we can wonder
other variants of these are growing in which
you are looking at
the other version of the SVM the one we it gives rise to the so-called
boxcar track
in which the slack variables doesn't appear clear about here
when i'm looking at
problem like
one way of looking at the problem
in w
god one minus
class c
such that
your y w x being good at one time
but this is
this is called the
passive aggressive
there is another way
so both both ways
both of these are ways of coping
teams that are potentially non separable
you relax the aggressive
condition that is in fact
the analysis the reduction i was showing you
before that and work
for this second version here thought about properties of this algorithm will have to work
in different ways
by the way
in this paper
that proves of proofs of of
of the about the words showing you
giving using different techniques
so i am
by using some some of the things that the conventional to prove
about support for these
but the techniques that i think are
most suggestive for relating it and explaining new things
and what i did back any more usable
in the paper you will find another another
there is a different edition
first of all let me start by
let me start by the solution of it but want to solve this using the
founder of the
one of the musicians
to derive the up