it's it's it's the nice property that has some nice function which which almost looks
like a rectangular function but it just trails off to zero
and i say OK
if i want to construct
an orthonormal expansion
and i want to find another function
which is orthogonal to that function
it has the next biggest amount fraction of its energy inside of this
time time strictly inside this time limit
and as much of the energy within the frequency limit as possible what's next function
OK we solve that problem if you're very good integral equations and i certainly going
suffer but anyway it has been solved i mean physicist for a long time have
worried about that particular kind of question because it comes up in physics all the
time if you time limit something and you take the fourier integral
happy new also comes close to frequency limiting as possible
so this particular prolates spheroidin set of orthogonal functions in fact exactly solves the problem
of how do you how do you generate a set of orthonormal functions which in
fact have as much energy as possible both frequency limited and time time-limited
and what you find when you do that
is when you take two w two you have some
at that point
the energy in these two orthonormal function support of it inside the band really starts
to cut off very very shortly and t are large
so that in fact you get two wt these functions which have almost all of
their energy in this band
and everything else has almost no energy in the band
so if you ever get interested in the question
how many waveforms really are there which are concentrated in time and frequency
that's the answer to the problem
and no bother to read it now but just remember that if you ever get
interested in that problem which i'm sure you will at some point or other that's
where the solution lies
i hope i gave a reference to what there i think i did
anyway so we have these functions which span of two
this least one other orthonormal expansion that we have
which is both time and frequency limiting
either at the end of the day at the beginning of the month the
we're going to find another particularly important
a sequence of orthonormal functions
which we actually use we're transmitting data
OK so
so to give an example of what we're just talking about fourier series functions span
the space of functions over minus over two to three over two
and normalize dysfunctions become
one over the square root of two a
times what we started with before namely a sinusoidal truncated
OK before we were dealing with the orthogonal functions without the one over square root
if you want to make them more orthonormal
you get this square root of one over to because when you take the the
energy in this function
you get
if you don't believe me set set k equal to zero and look at that
and even i can integrate that when you integrate one from minus the over two
t over two you get one
then you have to
multiplied by the square root of one over time when you look view the fourier
functions in this why
it's nice because they are orthonormal
it's not nice because the square root of one over t periods everyplace but the
nice thing about it is that then when you expand in the fourier series you
don't find this t anywhere namely v is equal to the
to the limit
of these approximations were the approximation is just the sum from minus and and
about this OK k these these k
in office of k is just this enterprise
OK so again you get something nicer by looking at these things in terms of
factors you get
you get my statements about how these things converge and you also get a very
compact way
writing out what expressions are
you also get something a little bit fishy
which a lot of people
in the communication field especially ones who do theoretical work
you run into problems with
and the
and the problem is the following when you when you start feeling all the time
with vectors
and you forget about the underlying functions in the underlying integrals
you start to think that the subject is simpler than it really is
because you forget about all the remaining issues and when you forget about all limiting
issues its final almost all the time
but every once in a while you get trapped
when you get trapped you then have to go back behind all of the vector
stuff and you have to start looking at these general again and it gets rather
frustrated she you want to keep both of these things in mind
let's go on let's get back
from mathematics into
and the worrying about the question of how do you send data
over over communication channels
and this is just the picture that we saw
starting on day one of the scores
which says the usual y
of doing this
is you start out
with this
you start out with the source you break the source they in binary data
and then you take the binary data and you transmitted over a channel and this
is the picture of what you get when you try to transmit binary data
over the channel and here we broken down
the encoder is we call the into two pieces one of which we call the
discrete encoder
in one of which we we call modulation
now this is a little bit fishy also because
there are a lot of people who now talk about coded modulation
we're where it turns out to be nice to combine this discrete encoder with the
modulation function
and when you actually build modern day
full encoders namely the whole thing from binary digits to what goes out on the
you very often combine these two functions together
what is it allows people to do that
the fact that the first study how to do it when they separate the problems
into two separate problems
and when you separate the two problems what we wind up with is binary digits
coming in human societies binary digits
strictly strictly digitally
and what comes out is the sequence of symbols
and usually the sequence of symbols comes out at a slower rate than the binary
digits come in for example if you take two binary digits
and you revert into one symbol
a lot of applications to image analysis which i solely around one
the complexity of the reconstruction if you're talking about simplicial complexes growth terribly with dimension
because of that this idea of using this for data of high dimension is not
interesting if you stick to simplicial complexes but if you start working with more general
objects x CW complexes then this becomes more possible sort of something that it's something
that really would be worth looking into because it would enable going up now this
is what the complexity sort of
the complexity of the domain itself simplicial complexes big but the algorithm itself is not
because it's the recursive algorithm which works like quite well actually it's a good from
the point of view
OK so the
the result of this algorithm is not really a discrete morse function is just the
discrete vector field but we know
well here's the next result that would like to mention
here's how frustrating this transparency can see the next result this is the reason this
is from this year and it's done in collaboration with the dissident gregory set in
some other people and this is the crux torisation of the discrete vector fields on
noncompact domains in this case which come from
the discrete morse functions with a certain property which is called proper i don't want
to go into this but the question now is if we have the discrete vector
field doesn't belong to the discrete morse function and can we come up with the
discrete morse function which belongs to the discrete vector field well we can under certain
conditions and here we have a characterisation was which tells us when on the simpler
situation of compact this was already solved by forming in the very beginning when he
initiated the discrete morse theory so
the next thing that we're working with is a
this is something that i did together with my graduate student gregory said this is
the formalisation of the morse smale complex in this context OK so how do we
describe and what actually would be the morse smale complex of discrete morse function and
also an algorithm for the reconstruction of the discrete this more smale complex this is
a little remind you the decomposition into little patches for the behavior of the function
is the same practically on each patch we have the same behavior of the function
and then discuss a little bit back but this may be the most applied part
of all this this is the extension of others that i was talking about to
the parametric case because so
good move
what do i mean by
the parametric case what
are we actually doing this here
imagine instead of having one
single function defined on the manifold or the simplicial complex
a serious so we have this
simple complex which i'll just try like this just systematically so we have a function
given on this for example at time t is equal to zero and then we
have another function at time t is equal to one in the third function at
time t equal and so on so we have a whole series of functions given
on this domain
and now we're looking at the critical point of view this function and this function
this function with trying to figure out is how these critical points evolved from this
situation this one this one and so on try to follow the critical points along
the time scale
and the result is called something which is called the before case india diagram
for the
before question diagram actually tells us how these critical cells are connected a long time
OK so let me show you
a simple example on a one-dimensional manifold
so here we have
here we have a function of one variable x which depends on one additional parameter
OK so this is just a simple quadratic polynomials so in the beginning when the
beginning in our our cases t is equal to two
we have one critical point of the functions down here but now is the this
simple the function changes and also the number of the critical points changes
for example if you look at the situation
he is equal to two two well of critical point appeared over here
so far
at the TV quick before a critical point appeared over here it two and then
if we go on this one critical point splits into two different critical points so
this one critical point here at time for
evolved into the maximum this minimum style four point five and we go on and
at the time five well the maximum which was over here
more just with the minimum over here so from here on again we just have
one critical points in the the saint in between so here is the frication diagram
which belongs to the situation four times which are smaller than four we just have
one critical point and then share it is equal to four another one appears critical
because you have the data
and the putting on this can be computed because it's just the polynomial something and
so you can
just compute this approximation
and then you can start it back into
the law equation the kullback leibler divergence
and then you do
some calculations and then you get something like that
above the
so it's
no big deal so you
just as a reminder
we're trying to optimize this function with respect to w
in other words we can have some
we would like to slide down the gradient here
so in order to
we can write down the differential equation
this learning so this is like a learning rule
continuous time
you know for the moment it's not important
so this is the estimate of all matrix w
as a function of time
so maybe you just slowly go
so this is is the step size
of this differential equation
this unit matrix so if you should ignore for the moment
w also known for the moment
so then you have one minus u transposed
so this equation stops has zero gradient
so DTW to he zero
so you have the solution when
you have
diagonalizing this covariance matrix you transpose
OK this would be something like PCA
an online version PC
we are trying to enforce statistically independent means that we're not happy with correlation along
PCA would give us
we need some high order moments as well
this is where the company
if it does
say are polynomials
of course you
which means that the actually diagonalizing some so to say generalized covariance matrix here
the function
so to say which expansion i've taken when i have done my cup of and
things like that
this is for example
the polynomial that summary gets in his his learning rule and the w just makes
your life easier is called natural gradient
but just a technicality
as the wrap-up
to minimize this kullback leibler divergence so in other words to to be able to
in for statistical independence the only thing you have to do
is it is so to say diagonalized generalize the covariance matrix
and they also
you know there's a whole zoo of algorithms around
and of course
this is somewhat essential
there there are of course some as that
more appropriate for distributions that you after
and some of the algorithms that are around
you different as that reflect certain assumptions of what we are actually looking for whether
we're looking for something super colson as subgoals in order
so there's a different way of thinking
and of doing blind source separation the other all the other direction is
to take time into account
until this point
in all these equations are shown i didn't i just used
ten some i didn't use any temporal structure
of the signals
just some statistical correlations
most signals that we are like speech signals of brain signals they have the temporal
so we might as well use that we might as well use the higher order
structure of the signals and the temporal structure but let's go first to the temporary
OK so
the idea the assumption essentially is that
we want to have the correlation between say the street noise in the speaker to
minimize the length of the weight vector subject to these constraints and that's one constraint
for each data point of the constraint
a data point is on the right side of the separation
what do we do next is introduced like waterfront
maybe some of you are familiar with this
so this thing here is called the constrained optimisation problem
and it's an optimisation problem with inequality constraints
maybe some of you have seen optimisation with equality constraints
and this is a classic formalism development and launch how to deal with this by
introducing multipliers
here we have inequality constraints which is a little bit more difficult but it's very
similar formalism is basically it was extended by college school talk and others and what's
important for us that this is a nice
objective function so this is just a quadratic function in particular convex
and these are just linear constraints
diseasex i constant so the there that we optimize over w and b
so that's
that's nice
but we have to go through a little bit of formalism
and and the way it works
is we introduce these locals multipliers one multiplier for each constraint
and then we write down what's called language in like watching has as the first
just the original objective function this thing here
and then it has
the sum over all the constraints with the constraints
it's likely reformulated
i'm going to move this one over the other side of right this constraint is
larger or equal to zero
OK so maybe try to put this into your iconic memory for a second
and then i'll
put this could so this is not the constraint
this is greater than zero and multiply it with the corresponding levels must find some
all of them
and the results are subtracted from the
original objective function
so this is the definition of the audience
so you might be puzzled as to why
this thing here helps us dealing with our problems
so what i'm going to claim is that this logo as has to be minimized
with respect to the so called primal variables w and b
remember here we want to minimize this thing
and all variables of the variables in determining the position of the hyperplane with WB
and we get this is a hyperplane is determined by w and b
and we want to some hard WP such that all the positive points
and the value of this function at least plus one of the negative ones
the most minus one
so these are all variables
we went to
with respect to this primal variables that's not so surprising is the same as the
last slide but in addition i'm saying we have to maximize with respect to the
dual variables
so in other words we have to find what's called the saddle point of this
and it turns out if we do both of these things together
if the problem is solvable we find a solution which
minimizes with respect to the primal variables subject to the constraints that we had subject
to these constraints
so if you know it
it may be boring for you isn't it sounds a little bit like magic
i can't go through all the details that i just want to give you a
a little bit of intrusion why this thing
that's the right thing
so just so that you believe me reasonable thing if you are interested in you
look it up in the book on linear optimization
these are very very useful tools and if you
decide to stay in machine learning i'm actually you will you will use the
OK so let's assume we have a constraint which is violated so what i mean
by this
so constraints these where the constraints of this thing here minus one is nonnegative
now let's assume it's negative so this thing here minus one is negative so that
there's the point that doesn't lie in the area where it's supposed to lie
so this means this quantity here's negative
now remember the function is maximized with respect to the dual variables
OK so this is negative we have another minus over is positive this means the
corresponding phi can grow can start growing
in order to increase the value of the loss function
so i think i have inserted these language multipliers have to be
so this this like multiply allowed to change and it's actually trying to change such
that the value of l increases
if this thing here is negative then the value can be increased by the corresponding
goes my growing
so will grow start growing but at the same time
the primal variables one to minimize the language functions so they should start working against
the phi
and the only way of working against this five that w and they have to
change such that this
this is no longer true
they have two
prevent this constrained from being
not satisfied because otherwise the corresponding alpha will grow beyond bounds and held which increases
beyond bonds
so w and b have two
decrease they have to change such that the constraint get satisfied
which means that the position of the happening to change such that the point
o point x i is on the right side of the hyperplane
so this is going to happen and overall if the problem is separable so if
there a geometric solution w b
and this will ensure that this corresponding language multiple i i will not go to
infinity so there will be some finite value where it stops
then we can have a stable
situation we can have that equilibrium
so this one is not moving and this one is not moving
and then we can have t two
so a larger
twenty one
by using friction to our advantage
that's blow up that center portion
radius is
let's have this
wrote here
i'll give the role color
doesn't have to come up vertically of course
if you have any angle
there is so here is my t one
and here is my t two
and we take the situation that
the born this site is way larger than on that site
so that israel wants to in this direction
that's what i would like to do
if you look
small little
sections of the road
it is immediately obvious if the world wants to slide in this direction wants to
start stripping
that the frictional forces
in these little pieces here all in this direction
all the way around
and therefore
it helps to one so to speak
so because of the fraction
which is opposing due to
he two can now become much larger
what you have to do to calculated analytically
we have to evaluate
frictional forces for these very small slices of becomes an integral
and then you have to
over an angle which i will call
OK zero
and i remember when i last lecture
in one that was in nineteen ninety three
i the right that in class
the relation between t two and t one has functional this angle theta
and it took me about five minutes and after five minutes half the students
we're asleep
now i'm not sure whether you want to sleep five minutes but i don't think
frankly you deserve it so
i decided to not do the derivation
but to refer you to the book
which is page three hundred sixty one
and you will find
in this situation that the rope
once to start slipping in this election
that t two
divided by t one
is that our
i'm data zero if the friction coefficient
here is new be the static
friction coefficient
so that's the results and noted that it is independent of
the radius of this which is not so obvious funny things
but the bar is
this small
with this small makes no difference if only depends on this angle this angle could
very large you could wrap it around ten times
as we will do very shortly
so it is no restriction on theta
if there were no friction at all nodes then
at the moment that it starts to say
e to the power zero is one
that's twenty two equals the one that's obvious so you can play this game
new is zero
you need friction that is at the heart
of this whole
so now let's put in some numbers
so we get idear of what we did
so let's take a situation that we
that's a three terms
we write wrap the rope around three times
so three terms
that means that zero
we call six y
and that the friction coefficient u
the one thing
o point two
e two to power
times data zero
is now
about forty
so what that means is
with the force on this site
which is forty times smaller
then the force on that site
i have a balance situation
i can hold it in my hand
and contrary if you want to think of it that way
the force on this site
which is forty
times larger
but if i take six terence
then he to all you
data zero
will be about
two thousand
so now i can really control
and elephant
imagine now that
i have here
an object
which would be
five thousand kilograms
ten thousand kilograms
that's why i'm hanging here
i can hang you know
mass which is
two thousand times less massive
that means i could hang there five
attention here
the two thousand times less than the tension there the system will be about to
start slipping
it's not for being there is complete balance
so imagine i hold this point in my hand here is ten thousand kilogram weight
and all this in my hand all i need is the force of about
fifty note and i'm standing there and on the other side is ten thousand kilogram
and now
i just
make my for a little less than fifty students
and what will happen now it will start to see
how do you want to make that they can do lot
how do you get end users doing
so we get told us and so called for
so if you know if in your country you know which one word which one
you start with you get by six starts manage to set things
then you talk about the universe which is broken
version you know what
and it will generate uery tree you build history
you do deleted
you know what does
you then go back into the directory possibly having repeated again in tree doesn't
i need to get by saying that
give us a good
and it produces another tree
and you illustrate we need all the CPU
and you history
and you bad good
fighting you've got something which is
reliably reproducible which is not always the case
you will eventually end up where we have to figure out exactly which had begun
which changes within the game tree
the one which broke your system
and even if you're not to develop
being able to cite to develop a
this is what broke
it's really really useful
it doesn't rely on things being reproduced that problem
if you've got which happens one time in one hundred
doing a binary search doesn't work is you really you need to run each one
several hundred times show
well if only shows the about we
then it it by six to eight weeks
so thank you
probably three
three and a half months
you will find it
so we tried to use tools to
i mean this this sort of press easier
we have lot developers
what is right
they all want to write new drivers
this is not so good
fixing other drivers
less interesting apparently
it's cool to write your own right
i think maybe reading too much random
so we have
problems with
it's a big of the project
even the council science council because i
i want to what's level
it's a very very big challenge where do you start several millions of lines code
which has been documented by programmers in the custom manner documents programming
it is
not at all
the comments can
that's why i don't think there are books
i think that it is but learning device drivers is now one
which is a very good
there are some others you want to get involved
there's also a kernel newbies mailing list which is a mix of mostly people who
are writing their first drive because they decided they want to write driver
and a small number of
very scenic kernel developers try help
so gives you an environment that is fusion environment
if you ask questions like
i hello my module
i can't seem to print anything
i love and we open the file in module you you don't get met by
the ricci
one he tried to do
that you're dealing with people who are trying to solve some problems on the same
and so
the question is again as from the new pillars point why people are neutral
our environment we would expect so
where a lot of the people on the list of similar experience
so the fact better able to to explain things to each other
and there is an expert on when people ask hard questions
which put experts mysteriously the way for each
but there
the second thing is this
think of the kernel janitors and now the mallows started this
when he was trying to be
a serious learning development and chief technical officer
of a brazilian
many fans this tend to be difficult combination to manage
because you want
when is the right kind of variance of the right k
sometimes he was lost in management long period
so here had is idea should be in this where
thing post things in ontologies
so some good player it would be really good if we cleaned up something or
there are still like drivers using this old and lives
and that list there are people on it just pick up these jobs
you may be
don't get much kind time of people just new to it once stop
i think it's going to
it needs doing eventually
if i don't get it right it doesn't matter
if i get it wrong and have to go around by three months doesn't matter
it's not urgent not something critical
that's another good were getting involved and it also help get people involved in actual
use things like fixing the existing
rather than trying to become a writer new drivers
the final thing
prec from one of had the idea that is always drunk drivers and almost
and wouldn't it be good if we actually help vendors drives really drives into the
greg very rapidly got more developers to drivers
so large team people looking specifications so they can be cool and try to drive
it would be nice if they so i decided to it would be cool makes
it right
in this work
the other thing
we see here as well
is a sort of resource misallocation it's very hard to fix
and it had in the preceding decade
how did it spread it spread among individuals who had exempted themselves from
the immunization or its
so we have the first harbinger
of a threat to the public health
from exemptors
when you look at school immunisation laws and you ask
folks do they agree with me or not
what you will find is in fact
most people
i agree
with school
entry innovation loss
and in server we did it stated as the others so disagree
here means you support school laws
back then in two thousand eight percent essentially parents
children should be immunized
to attend school
and today one of those numbers may have changed someone there's still is general support
for school entry immunization
schools have work because parents rely on physician recommendations about whether or not to immunize
children and by and large
physicians have been supportive of
immunisation and school entry loss
what's changing
is that not all parents
advice today
and there's more heterogeneous
particularly in some areas
on physician's advice
so now i would like to now go through what i see as our immediate
and give you my
of what we need to do as a nation to restore the societal consensus
that we need to support immunization
the first is that we need to be prudent about mandates
that we need to have an exemption process that sure is informed decision making
we need to be much more effective about communication
about immunizations
that we have to greatly expand their investment in vaccine safety science
and then we have to engage the public in developing policies and the models for
each of these have been
australia has a rather different approach to ensuring high immunization
they do not mandate immunization in australia
and you can see that they have immunization rates that are roughly comparable
two are
so let's look at children under the age of two
we have mandates about entry into child care
that is
licensed right here
they have a financial rewards
four individuals were immunized
there are two ways to do this one is to a child care subsidy
and if you're entitled to child care subsidy everybody gets some child care subsidies and
you get a greater pay payment if your kids are fully
there's a maternal and infant health allowance of some sort and you get
a bigger check
if your child is fully immunized
at school entry they have no mandate
and by and large those
financial rewards apply only to the first couple of years
of life
interestingly in this country
we've created have used finances to achieve station but we do through penalties
a lower rate of medicaid supplements or
not through
it's so you are
other ways
achieve public health objectives and mandates
my belief and now this has been manifested in our state
you need to
develop a transparent process
four mandating immunization
i'm sorry i don't know if california has dealt with that
but i think mandates have to be applied only to diseases that are indisputable public
health importance
out of data
x one
it can
and notation and i'll try and use consistently
it is in general and can be mounted data we get
little land is always going around in one-tenth whenever you see a suffix you can
usually infer what goes up to without me saying
so any more and i try to use the same
fairly consistently
all right
and this is the gas in distribution so as to be completely explicit plea of x and given mu sigma
it is
on o
where have to figures where
he minus thank you
squared over
sigma squared and this has little things
on the
okay and the task is really want to infer
and sigma
the data
let's do that's
so let's walk through
the world that we're working in
and that it so that always distinguish two worlds one is hypothesis space where there parameters lived
um and another is the world in which data layers and in this case confusingly
they both look kind of similar to each other because of the unknown mean could
be anywhere on
the real line
and the data come on the real line
i'll try to keep track of when we're talking about data access label
and when we talking about
hypothesis axis that might be labelled new
all the data points come along the state register thee the hypothesis space actually has
two dimensions to it's got sigma
dimension to it as well so one way of telling the difference is sometimes will
show a new axis and the sigma factor he two dimensions we must be in
the hypothesis space the parameter space
so is a one-dimensional picture
and it shows
so it's possible different settings of mu and sigma
all which happened have the same value sigma what the prediction about the data would
be so these are standard guassian densities for different values have mu and sigma
these all happened have
different values and
and the same value sigma namely sigma is what
thank next
there are another six possible hypotheses about mu and sigma
the muse all have the same
and the standard deviation very from point five
up to
two so what i do there
i just bubble around in the hypothesis space
hand showed you want three four
five six point in this two-dimensional space here
maybe i'll quickly get rid space moment
so i j six hypotheses like
and then
why this is so a problem along the axis along a single axis showing you
in data space what each of those projects so any particular one of these makes
its prediction in the data space
which looks
says that's what i the data to be like if i am true
okay anne hear are
and other six hypotheses which have different views on different segments from each other so that's a scattering of points
in new and sigma space and for each one i've shown it predictions
data space
how to do inference
two hundred for mu and sigma
this is the correct way to do inference you get your data
here i'm showing what five
data points
which arrived these horizontal
coordinate in other flatten up above
the line
at an arbitrary like coordinate
right so got five data points
what is based here and say you should do
well you should update
your beliefs
about mu and sigma in proportion to how well each of those bodies new and sigma
predicted what actually happened
basically says
household mu and sigma are given the data
how well they predict
multiplied by how well they were
before you later
the normalizing constant
this sigma
all this stuff
i'm taking
in the next few lectures quite a hardline position that i think when there's a
well posed questions is the correct answer to it
and this is in contrast to the way a lot of people think about statistical inference
there's another way of doing inference where there's lots of ways inventing well posed questions
and i think that's an extraordinary
o thing to believe i think there is
a correct way events from problems and i don't think inference should be an exception from this
something make really explicit is that
all these inferences depend on assumptions
so people sometimes bayesian methods so subjective that kind of assumptions this you don't have
to make assumptions in order to do inference
i've got the right yes these all depend on assumptions
but how could it be otherwise
so everyone these things is conditional on age
and the yes
is this
so this is an age is assumption about the data come from a gas in
distribution andits whatever assumptions we want to make about what we believe music might be
and i think it's on an escape all that you do have to make
the assumptions
all right
what is this actually look like
well this is saying how well they do predict the data that actually happened and this is very
the native it
you know if we if we haven't got any particular
strong interesting prior knowledge about using we let it go and focus on the data dependent term
and basically says
you don't need to know how well they were creating things that didn't happen
tail probabilities are not relevant there's no such thing as tails in the correct way of doing inference
and that that
they are the following so one is i think goes back
five more of these i know it going back to all square number
that you basically think of a sieve
of models who have
the nested parametric models for instance think of
you know mixtures of
one galaxy into gaussians three gaussians et cetera etcetera index them by
and then
for each of these you act as if the model were true
prior to plug in the maximum likelihood estimate
and now what's left is
choose the m
that's not the trivial part
that's the nontrivial part actions
the parallel prescription due to volcanic is you basically think of the class
as the class of all decision procedures of all
classifiers are predictors
as the union of
finite or parametric the closure of a finite parametric classes right so
linear quadratic
court less if you think a regression
a regression based on the variable itself linear regression based on the variable itself
based on the variables square q the variables were q and so on
and that we can approximate in principle
any function of one variable
that's the idea if you want also behind
the support vector story writing that that's why you can always separate
the samples go high and up and you can approximate
one-dimensional down
but the public always insists that in this case you should always do is use
for the empirical risk minimization which is
if you take an empirical estimate
the expected loss and minimize
and then of course
from that point on one side to ask about
how well does actually do
in in comparison to what
the minimum value of the risk is
but again you're left with the issue of how do you pick them
from this point of view there's sort of two new criteria which again
run parallel and statistics and computer science
so you look at the minimum regret
that you can get
over all these possible rules
this is of course again quantity only god can get but god gets it's got
being restricted
right got can
knows what appears but has to use one of the delta hands
one of them has
and then you have to say something is an oracle rule if in fact the
rate the ratio of what you can do
by estimating and some data dependent way to work
god can do
ten is one
and then there's is an analogous thing
in statistics which is the so-called adaptive minimax us get that but really the the
main point that i'm trying to get to which and finally and is
that it is possible
four very wide classes of spaces right
spaces of functions
which is smooth
you look at this
and at at
the sphere in that class
it is possible to choose
in the data dependent way of course
so that both the oracle criterion holds
and the minimum that the minimax criterion holds
the thing that i want to point is that what you conclude from that is
but the best thing that in our
going in that direction
what you find is that the best thing that
even god can do given
behaves like an to the minus two k or two k plus the
where k is some measure the smoothness of p
and this information interpretation isn't that although some of the original interpretation was relevant logicians
wanted to do and i know most of nursing relevant logic for the new central
much for
if you look at
well relevant logicians wanted to do was avoid
what are called the paradoxes of material and strict implication
it's natural write a plus sign down for and but you know in in logic
classes you should never do that
it means or write them in addition is or
and think back to bowl
his his his edition his or was addition
materials to and strict implication
OK so
if we read the arrow
in inference
let's start with this one
this is my favorite
from any proposition we can get any
the topology in classical logic
we can infer that
this seems to be something wrong about that
the moon is made of green cheese therefore
you training or small
that's not a sound argument because the moon is made of green cheese
but according to classical logic is valid
classical logic is a very blunt instrument it's a wonderful instrument i don't like dislike
classical logic
i'm always accused of this but i don't actually dislike it but is a very
blunt instrument once the nice instrument because
using very little prior propositional
classical logic propositional calculus is you know
this fantastic themes uses truth tables true and false and functions extension functions on the
to represent
always connected
it is a very good job at that it just doesn't do a perfect job
and validity is done on in terms of those as a very blunt instrument it
it approximates and it gets a lot of things right it tells us modus ponens
valid modus tollens is valid affirming the consequent is not valid and so on and
you get a lot of things right
but doesn't get everything right
this seems on
relevant logicians say what's on but it is this
has nothing to do with this
the moon is made of green cheese therefore training or it's not the move could
be made of anything doesn't really affect the weather
last time i gave a talk on this i i i talked about this is
that in my
we need professor they making give a big public address thank you that the public
address last year they are
you likely the audience is not allowed to ask questions but i do a lot
of people receiving there because i talked about a beautiful beach in new zealand very
key beach i it's being beautiful has nothing to do with the money being made
of green cheese that somebody that was was as one one of my colleagues there
someone whispering yes it does it's got to do with the effects of the tides
and all the rest of yeah maybe
that's larger that it's still logically valid inference becomes
right you need to you if you put a lot of connecting principles physics maybe
you could get a logically valid inference you can always get logically valid inference that
of an invalid inference right if you have
that's not logically valid inference right
i hope not
you can and
you can add a premise
try to get a lot you know is that premises
to get a logically valid inference
that's so that's not the point
about whether it's train it's the fact is that logically they have nothing to do
with one another you need more premises to get that it shouldn't be just becomes
this is it at all it's always true
doesn't really
i mean then it follows from any and that's the problem
a lot of
relevant logicians
i think in a way groping towards what's what's what's really right
i talked about certain situations are structures in which
world in which this wasn't true what are the relevant logicians should be doing that
and i'll get back to that as we go along
because the problem isn't about the truth of the conclusion the problem is about whether
or not the fact that something is always true means it follows from everything
OK so we needed different notion of validity if we're going to capture more fine
so notion of good edits of argument than classical logic gives us
OK and there are various and connected with this
is it is the treatment of the implication
and that it's the paradoxes of strict material conditions
OK i was using is these before knowledge system was spears here's a better
that makes it clear that there is no common content
and things like that now
OK that's enough to go on with
will deal with these two first forget about the first
i those have a problem in one of the immediate problem you see there
is that there's no common content between antecedent and consequent
right of the main connective
now why is that the problem well
this has nothing to do with that that's clear
and this has nothing to do with that
these are all if we interpret the implication is either
material implication or or or necessary implication sense of
eight more logic who
you're going to get those is there
OK so what you are trying to do
for the next two-and-a-half to three hours or so
is given you
basic introduction to a class of machine learning methods that have become widely popular over
the last ten years
and this class of approaches to machine learning
can more or less meat as a kernel based approaches to pattern recognition machine learning
and so on although the most famous of these kind of a algorithms the support
vector machine
now in some sense kernel based approaches have very classical roots although there are many
modern twists to it
so there are many ways in which one can tell the story of the development
of kernel based approaches and
i want to emphasise that this is our own perspective on these matters
and so we're going to corresponding correspondingly emphasise certain aspects and the de-emphasize than others
and there are many other introductions to kernel based methods that you
i have access to especially on the web these days
there's a website called kernel machines that or
where you can get a lot of tutorials
the way we are going to structure it is that i'm going to talk about
an hour and a half or so
giving you are sort of setting the stage and introducing the context of pattern recognition
more generally
and motivating and developing the basic machinery for reproducing kernel hilbert space plays a central
role in approaching learning problem from economics perspective
and then we shall talk for the next one and a half hours applying the
machinery of reproducing kernel hilbert spaces to a variety of problems that you see what
the algorithmic consequences are
of these of these objects
subject is that the border of many different disciplines it's variously called pattern recognition and
machine learning classification regression
and of course you know and i'm sure you're aware that people in engineering and
computer science and statistics and mathematics and these are not all the disciplines
i have something to say which is often mathematical computational nature on these questions so
it's important to emphasise that
the basic problem of learning from examples more or less goes like this
there are these these basic objects there is some space of patterns which we call
capital x OK
this is somehow the pattern space the instance space in the example space where all
the patterns led
examples that people look at
i would be
are in the standard vector space
a manifold m
are finite set x
of which are interesting cases the boolean hypercube
and sequences
sigma star
OK so this is the set where all the patterns live
and then there is another set which we should familiarize themselves with that's why
which is the label space of the predictions based on the response this
called by different names in different communities and these are usually for our purposes at
least today
will usually be rn
and usually will take into the one
which would be the standard regression
classification which is usually
one of a finite number of labels
and most of the time will actually discuss the case where n is equal to
so it's the two classes binary classification problem minus one one
so you have then
given x and y
labelled examples that is x y pairs
OK if somebody preventing through about and giving a label associated with that that and
from these labels you don't want to learn
you the regressor or classifier
depending on the context
so i
david already talked about some examples here are some more so here the digit recognition
so in the learning from examples settings so these would be example somebody actually gives
you images of handwritten digits
two three five seven
and so on and so these are the examples you want to predict the class
of new data point
so from these examples you hopefully want to learn a classifier
which is a map from the set x of all possible images
to the set y which is basically in this case
has been members
a face recognition examples of these which
i don't know if you're able to see you actually
lots and lots of faces
so you get lots of examples of faces
and then somebody present steel picture
and ask sue is this picture of a grandmother
and the answer yes or no
and that
a face recognition example problem
same setting so the set x is the set of all images
and you want to predict the class of new data point
here is an example from financed
a lot of people
interested in this
so you want to predict now a real possibility of real valued
function the values variables
which is the stock price of stock the next day
and you have at your disposal
all the variables that you might want to make sure that you think might help
predict stock prices in the future
think these could be passed historical time series of this or related stocks other economic
indicators and so on
there are more examples here's an example from grammatical inference z axis sigma star
OK the set of all sequences take sigma to be the set of all the
words in english
here a positive example on the top here and from there with his money
let's label one
and here at the bottom is his money with their from ronny
minus one
and so you want to learn the imagine from sigma started minus one one
this is of course just the language in the sense
and the grammar would be
then a generator of the of the acceptable strings
this is a list of this actually because in grammatical inference usually almost always you
learn only with positive examples
so when you actually infer the grammar of a language no one actually samples for
you densely the universe of possible negative examples
sigma alpha mu
is the mean and sigma is the variance of covariance in the multivariate case
here have two thousand distributions with with different means of the mean is the for
the black distribution here the mean for the distribution here
and i have a marked also the standard deviation so this a bit wider distribution
because it distribution to one it's also going to be have a smaller magnitude
the one-dimensional gas distribution
which is easy to draw so i can also
more draw two-dimensional distribution but it's very hard to draw
high dimensional distributions and it turns out
that gaston processes are just very high dimensional
girls in distribution like so we have to imagine
high dimensional gaussians here's the two dimensional gaussians so instead of
instead of so showing you
b is
the value of the probability density i've just shown you here
the mean to showing you two ellipses here that
correspond to the one standard deviation in the two thousand
and the
and the the variance here is encoded in the in the covariance matrix of the
commercial campgrounds matrix in this case has
two i can make i can that to this one goes in this direction won
the gold in this direction and the i can value
going in this direction so the variance in that direction corresponds to the i value
of the covariance
here are written out there
the actual distribution is gory detail
OK so the true
properties of the gaussians that are going to be of central importance
one is called the the conditional distribution in one is called the marginal distribution conditional
distribution so here i've got my my two-dimensional gas from before
and the conditional distribution of one variable given the other variables
try to illustrate that here let's say that this is a joint distribution over the
two dimensional space here
now let's say that i serve
that the value of this variable
this variable has this
this variable sorry had this particular value
and i say OK this parable as this particular value
then what does that imply about the other variable
so what i'm doing here is to remind slicing through the distribution
and seeing what's left over the function of the other variables
and you can see or hear if i know that this is the value of
this variable then the probability that the this variable takes on some
some negative value of value here is very small because there isn't any mass down
the masses is over here the conditional distribution here
look something like this
and if you think back to the gaussians is that if you condition gauss and
then you get another calcium the conditional distribution here
it's also got some
and the last thing we need to know about the marginal distribution so marginal distributions
is just that you do some out or integrate out
one of the variables
and look at what is now the marginal distribution for the other variable just collect
collapsing projecting down this
joint distribution on to one particular
and again
the marginal distribution
of when you marginalise the gauss and you get an account
OK so now what is the accounting process
because the process is just a generalisation of a multivariate gaussians to infinity minerals
so just like so it's sort of a natural extension when you go from there
for univariate out into multivariate gaussians and i just go to
a larger model that calculates the gaussians that contains infinitely many
many variables
one can ask why are we interested in infinitely many variables that sound sounds to
be the sort of thing to be interested in
but the reason for this is that we can think of functions and function source
of natural things to try find in so infer properties of you can think of
the function is just being an infinitely long vector
because you can simply specify what is the value of the function for any
value of the argument x k
this would be an infinitely long vector
this is the fifteenth like very primitive notion
some parameter which is more natural in adapts the data
so like a new parameter which automatically controls how many points should lie outside the
tube so in a way you would like to compute the tube such that most
of the points are inside some of them outside you don't know what epsilon will
achieve this property so you would
back to compute automatically
so if we do this we need to
use this optimisation problem
so again like in the case of classification we have here the empirical error term
here we have this extra term involving new
and epsilon so now newest chosen
clearly an epsilon is the variable of the optimisation problem
and now may give you a little intuition for
how this works and it's actually similar in
pattern recognition in order to let me try to give you a graphical
OK so let's
let's assume
so it's the whether this will work with and be able to follow this explanation
of words so our cost function
this one here
our objective function of slightly write it by dividing by c
now if i have found a solution of this problem to remember the variables but
w and epsilon
so far solution
to my optimisation problem then the solution is optimal with respect to w epsilon in
particular is optimal with respect to epsilon
so let me forget about w from now
and just look at the epsilon
so optimal with respect to epsilon which means
if i wiggle around upset signed a little bit then
solution to it
you get large
so now let's assume that new
well it's not let's first try to understand these two influences here so here we
have to do so we want to minimize this function here we have which is
proportional to epsilon nu is the product chosen by the user this is proportional to
sine and therefore if i increase epsilon
this term here will increase
at the same time if for increase epsilon two overall after
i win a little bit because if i have some points that lie lying outside
that these two guys here
the corresponding excise will get smaller
so i increase epsilon
i was a little bit but i win literally a little bit here
since these ties will get smaller
similarly if i can decrease epsilon
then i went a little bit here is to get smaller
but i was a little bit here because of the decrease in epsilon so maybe
this line
we lie here and for this point i have to pay a large size
it's not for ask how much to you in how much do you lose
so if i change epsilon
in this term i will always lose win proportionally to new
on the other hand if i
decrease or increase epsilon will win or lose here
if i can decrease epsilon
well that's the increase in salary for increase of silent will when something here that
will win something precisely for those point that having non-zero i
the positive because i support points that are lying outside if i increase epsilon
i win something that will mean something proportional to the number of such points
and what precisely is instead divided by the number of points i would proportionally to
the fraction of such points by increase epsilon
i will win proportionally to the fraction of points that have a non zero positive
on the other hand if i decrease epsilon
what do i do i will
there was here
number news proportionally to the number of points that either outside or exactly on the
because if that decrease epsilon that's the point which was sitting on the edge before
it was exactly on the edge i really we already have to pay for that
point when i decrease epsilon
OK so that's the asymmetry here when i increase epsilon up pay proportional to the
fraction of points that have a positive side to the call point out outliers before
whereas if i decrease epsilon i pay proportionally to the point i have
outliers on the edge
in other words the fraction of points that are support vectors
so if you put these two things together you get exactly this problem well you
get the first two parts of this property
so the first part of this new is an upper bound on the fraction of
OK let me call errors here was copied for the question so points that lie
outside of the tube
new upper bounds this fraction of points same time new lower bonds the fraction of
support vectors
OK and remember the difference between these two sets where exactly the points that lie
on the edge of the two
in the classification case where the points that lie exactly on the margin plus minus
one lines
so we have sandwiched new in between the fraction of errors and the fraction of
ESPN's and we also know the fraction of its millions and the fraction of errors
are not two different they only differ by the points that lie exactly on the
edge of the tube and it turns out some fairly mild assumptions about the problem
he said what's the probability that the point lies exactly on the edge of the
two is zero
for asymptotically
these two fractions
the fraction of errors fraction of support vectors will be the same
and also they send which new in between each other for new will equal
the fraction of errors it will equal the fraction of support vectors asymptotically
so if you have a large training set you would expect that by selecting new
dr. Umberto Eco the floor is yours
good evening
as probably
you know thank you madam director
as probably you know I have selected these topic for my lecture because I have
just edit the book on history of ugliness after three or four years that we made
a history of of beauty so I since get some material visual material I thought that
it was
nice to entertain the audience with some funny examples in every century philosophers and
artists have supplied definitions of beauty and thank to their works it's possible to reconstruct the
history of aesthetic ideas over time but this didn't happen with ugliness
most of the time ugliness was defined as the opposite of beauty
but almost no one ever devoted the treaties of any length to ugliness
the first serious study on that subject was in eighteen fifthy three the aesthetics of ugliness
by Karl Rosenkrantz
but it was the only
consistant example hence why the history on beauty can draw in a wide range of theoretical
sources philosophers and so from which we can deduce that tastes of a given
epoche for the most part the history of ugliness must seek out its own documents individual or
verbal portrayals of things so people that were in some way seen as ugly
I must say that to assemble material for a history of uglines was more
funny than to make a history of beauty beauty is in some way boring
even if its concept changes to the ages nevertheless a beautiful object must always follow certain
rules so to speak beautiful nose shouldn't be
longer than that or shorter than that
on the contrary ugly nose can be as long as the one of pinnochio
as big as the trunk of an elephant or like the big of an eagle and so
uglinessas is unpredictable and offers an infinite range of possibility let's say
beauty's finite ugliness is infinite like god nonetheless a
history of ugliness shares some common characteristics with the history of beauty first
for the past centuries the only documents we have are artworks
we can only assume that the tastes of ordinary people corresponded in some way
with the tastes of the artists of their day but we are
not sure
visitor from an alien from the space outer space
went to a gallery of contemporary art and so that woman and
he are describing this painting as beautiful he or she or it might
guess the mistaken idea that in everyday life the man of our time find a female
creatures with faces like that beautiful and desirable but our visitor from space might
modify his opinion her opinion its opinion on watching facial in which you would witness
the celebration of other models of beauty second both for beauty
and ugliness we can only speak of the Western culture for an exotic culture
we usually don't have the theoretical texts to tell us if that
if that Africa mask was intended to cause aesthetic delight holy fear hilarity
laugh we don't know conversely believers believers in
some non-European religion might be disgusted by an image of Christ scarred bleeding
and humiliated why this operated corporal ugliness arouses feeling of symphaty and tenderness in a Christian
in our civilization we don't find this ugly so concepts of beauty and ugliness are relative
to the various historical periods of various cultures and to quote Voltaire ask a toad
what beauty is
true beauty the tocalom and we tell you that it consists of his
mate with her two fine round eyes protruding from her small head her broad
flat throat her yellow belly and brown back and ask a devil he will tell you
that beauty is a pair of horns four claws and a tail attributions of beauty or ugliness
are often viewed
not to aesthetic but to social political criteria marx pointed out how the possession of
money may compensate for ugliness
he said I am ugly but I can buy myself the most beautiful women hence
I am not ugly
I am lame but money gives me twentyfour legs
now if we extend this observation on money to power in
general we can understand why many portrait of the
monarchs kings of centuries past were no doubt very very very ugly
but their own impotence lend them such a charisma and glamour that they
subjects saw them through adoring eyes let's red let's read
fredric brown sentinel fredric brown's sentinel written in the fifties one of the finest short stories produced
by contemporary science fiction
I cannot but to say
he was soaked to the skin and up to the eyes in mud
and he was hungry and cold
and was fifty thousand light-years far from home
a foreign sun emitted an icy bluish light and the gravity double
what he was used to
made the slightest movement weary and painful
the enemy
the only other intelligent race in the galaxy
thought carefully about how to do it at the top
the concrete is less dense and bottom and has a different combination of aggregate so
that it
will stay up for thousands of years
so if you're going to build if you're going to try and make materials like
concrete or like a metal well if you welding something together that contains many different
for particular application you need to know how to combine these things
both of these applications have been places where people in machine learning have actually
made useful progress despite the thousands of years of experience in materials these materials are
very well understood if you want to predict
how well how strong the concrete will be how flexible will be
how much it will slump over time
that's actually very hard to do from just looking at the list of components is
very difficult to say i understand how concrete works i can build the model of
exactly how these materials or combined
instead what you want to do
is learned from experience you try out tons of different concrete and then you want
to be able to
generalize from that data how concrete is going to work in the future i'm sure
they don't just go out and make the pantheon i'm sure they actually sort of
i had made a bunch of small things country probably fell down first before they
went and so what we want to do is how can we use computers to
sort of speed up the learning process and take a load off of humans
another application which you can get on your PC these days is speech recognition software
services spectrogram representation of a waveform and this is an image of the word nineteenth
i'm told this if you work in speech recognition for long enough
there are people that can look at this image and for real tell you that
it's the nineteenth century
so in some ways this is sort of being reduced to an image recognition problem
there's a lot more going on you have to build models of language as well
if you want this thing to work well
but and this is a common story in machine learning that you want to look
at problems in different ways maybe reduce problems the things you've seen before
finally this is something i don't think works very well yet but
it's something that is being actively worked on machine learning
if i go to amazon dot com amazon kqk it says welcome
in memory i have recommendations for you and i look at the end
i don't like very much actually like i did this this morning and
this is a dieting book and
i mean
i might be posting but i don't think i need to go on a diet
and often when i look through the whole series of recommendations one is going on
here but there is actually pretty sophisticated recommendation system going on in the background here
and the question we could ask is how can we make these things better and
it's a question that netflix which is an american movie rental company asked and cared
enough about the answer that they put a million dollar prize on people who could
improve recommendation systems that is an important problem and again you don't want to be
building rules by hand so
i'm very weird maybe and it's hard for me and to understand what i want
amazon has tens of millions of customers' money and many of them are going to
be pretty weird and you can't employ enough stuff to go through and fix up
the their recommendations by hand you need to look at this vast messy complicated data
set and somehow pull out what you need to know using relatively simple systems but
the web server can run in real time
so where are we going to go this afternoon and i'm going to start out
by talking about something which is much less sort of sexy and exciting and the
applications are put up because
the complicated say
i'm going to start talking about binary classification so
by an example of the binary classification problem is his an image does it contain
the face or not and you have to a given an input you have to
specify minus one or one no image no face of face
the idea of binary classifiers work also machine learning is used all over the place
and is part of more complicated systems so i'm going to focus on that for
an embarrassingly long time so we
you can sort of see what a lot of the issues of machine learning all
with this one simple example
so i've tried on that island move on to other stuff
backing off further
an image of the face of the pretty complicated thing as well so the is
a binary classification problem i'm going to talk about is distinguishing oranges from london so
this is going to be very toy little example and you know i'm going to
try and build up the more complicated settings later
OK so i need to
i one for some reason to build a computer system that given in u
item three will be able to say this is an hour endurance element
and in order to do that i'm going to have to somehow put the oranges
and lemons inside my computer it's going to have some kind of what they are
maybe i could take a photo of them but i want this to be a
simple example and dealing with color is actually a complete pain so this is something
we might note is just with this project is green with the colours washed out
issue of
the canonical
lexicon is one is still one of the major problems
OK and just as just to point out we can really think of this process
of lattice rescoring as
something similar to this analysis by synthesis model that stevens posed as part of the
human speech decoding problem that when you get when the knee when you
get a hypothesized word sequences you sort of
risk or that using additional knowledge you might have against the actual measurements that you've
sort of
that that you've derived and and so there is that it's not that unreasonable to
think of this of the problem of a sort of generating
of generating hypotheses and using to verify
something that you have you know the hypothesis that you obtain from a basic baseline
ASR system that's not that far
from how we might think of humans humans working
any questions on this implementation
right is if you're doing perhaps words body without
well we with the
you're right though this actually to do this the switchboard and and
i suppose the biggest issue was which sport i quoted
that results towards the beginning where it turns out that only about two-thirds
of the of the
phones that occur in switchboard utterances agree with what's in the canonical dictionary
and so
and so i think this
their canonical dictionary is still the big problem here is is probably that's probably reasonable
no matter what if it is but but i think your point which is a
good one is
i guess that
we as humans are bringing so much context to bear in conversation decoding conversational speech
utterance that's the acoustics are necessarily going to be weak
i think in and
i guess
that is well quoting that result with the the lexicon being such a bad match
i mean that certain that
verifies your
your claim that there
i'm trying to think of what experiments people have done
switchboard in particular
i mean there's there's some good examples where they've asked people
to take switchboard utterances i think they did this at know maybe the successor i'm
trying to do this
when we speak we're not exactly careful
articulators to reach their targets and we
speed up and we
hesitations and filled pauses and all that and what they ask people to do was
take these utterances and sit sit down and read them carefully
and then
o the rerun recognition and there was a dramatic
increase in performance so
just just dealing with the issues of spontaneous removing the issues spontaneous speech
it was huge
and it when switch for first created it was started its telephone thing but that
actually is not not the problem at all
OK so good point thank you for that
all right
the holy grail so i'm a
this is some of the most interesting stuff that just doesn't seem to quite work
if i had a lot of interesting stuff that doesn't quite work way back twenty
years ago
the robotics
what became sort of folk hero he worked at IBM and IBM was always
build systems that will big systems in and he was sort of a an outlier
has since retired but
he he was working on this model we're basically it's not really a model for
speech recognition is is someone can we can see that it can be incorporated model
for recognition
but basically it's it's
how can we model
speech articulation here
basically by starting with the notion of there being sort of a set of targets
articulatory positions so we'll start will assume that we start with
a message which is
transcribed according to a sequence of phonemes
we can take for each one of those phonemes
we can
by one mechanism or another
to find the target articulatory position
for each articulator
i and
in this case strictly through some mapping
we can
through some subtle
articulatory dynamics
and and we can call these articulate coarticulation filters if you want to describe
the dynamics of the of the movement of each articulator
and presumably this model will
describe the situation where the articulated doesn't quite reaches trajectory if i'm speaking if if
the rate is too fast and so on
the last component of the model would be
mapping from these actual articulatory
to the actual
the actual acoustics
and so
and i've already said him to the number of people boxes worked on this and
a number of other people have tried to build models to sort of implement this
kind of thing
we can think of generally the attempts have been to think of this mapping is
just being some sort of
you know i could design a think of this is actually being
short-time stationary over periods of you know the usual for ten twenty millisecond that we
assume in speech and that's
we can sort of
i have some sort of static
mapping from defined by a set of these articulatory positions
acoustics perhaps formants perhaps so
perhaps some sort of spectral energy spectral envelope representation that we generally use
in which traditional ASR
more than
would so love
it's going
so this will be
a little more
hands on
technical about how
these actually
it will be a little bit
idealisation of more nitty-gritty about how how
sec actually works and
and it's just sort of a hodgepodge of
topics i find
if something related to the cyclic compounds it
there's no
the main point that i'm trying to drive out here and you're free to ask
questions about all alternative
connect to the
KB and browse around a little bit so you can get a feeling for
what's actually in there and what it's doing OK
the overview i'm going to start and talk about natural language microtheories very briefly that's
that just gives consider this
the very very broadest structure for
natural language stuff is encoded in the KB and then i'm going to talk about
kinds of
semantic predicates by that i mean ways of relating say concepts two
and then i'm going to talk about inflectional and derivational morphology in cyc and the
the teams that will
curve eight
all three of these topics
a practical theme how to modify and add to the cyc lexicon
it's say want to build a slovene microsecond
i'm going to emphasise the generative nature of the lexicon and by that i mean
the possibility for deriving new
lexical entries from
i started once
inference with sec
one of the things they are the first thing that you have to know in
order to make a lexical insertion in cyc is which microtheory to put it in
this does anybody know what makes
OK i want to briefly explain so microtheory
sort of it's a way of limiting the context in which an assertion holds so
they can be tapped temporal microtheories so today
barack obama is the president of the united states
four years ago that was not the case
in the micro theory
including the present time
that assertion holds but
that doesn't assert assertion doesn't hold in previous metric is in america
you drive on the right side of the road
in new zealand you drive on the left side of the road
assertions can also be relative eyes
spatial things
so we have some microtheories give you
so the limit the contexts in which an assertion holds
we use microtheories to organize the lexical knowledge and cyc so
things that are true of english are asserted in english related microtheories and things that
are true
polish are sorted in polish really make is in principle
and then
within english there are different dialects others
commonwealth english which includes british new zealand
australian english
and the american english
and so if you have something specific to american english then you want to say
that in the american english
so right favor
it's spelled in british english with the
not american english so
in british english MT
the infinitive form of favour theword favour theword isa constant
in the KB
all of these entities but it's infinitive form is listed as
if a b o you are in the british and he and fabio are indeed
well it's generally two that's probably because someone was lazy normally we just assert everything
in the
that is quite distinct from the background nevertheless
to do it in time using
that this is pretty
see in the slide i'm going to just
the mathematics law
what the condition is
it is required for
simulated annealing to work
it's very simple really
goddess lies somewhere in the right place wrong find just before so the idea is
we've got a cost function
i jv two nodes
x i
xj that's my
my two to cost function corresponding cliques of size two
i'm going to do
so these ex i j
my label set
i'm reduces to a binary problem
i do alpha expansion
and so
there will be
associated with the move which are called the alpha j
and there
i have
two variables
u i
u j
are in
zero one
so i'm going to do
a binary problem where is that each node has the options switching or not
and the question is
what is the cost
right so just look at this look at
now my rule is
URI equals zero
pixel remains
the same
if you i
because what
goes to o
that's that's the basis whatsoever nearly the same thing sorry
after expressions about knows look at
let's look at two notes here
and j
and supposing they have values x i
and xj
at present
and they're going to switch to the new value x prob
which new label
the label may be the same or maybe alps so what happens in the four
if you want to the cost
zero zero in other words you URI being zero and u j
being zero well that means
they remain what they were
that will be
the cost of these being zero
will be equal to my original cost of x i x j
if if my
w zero
there remains same so that cost
one zero then
one becomes alpha
the other remains xj so this is a
and the
of zero one
well that will be
x y
alpha because zero mean remains and finally the
one one
it means both pixels switch to have
so the cost of that is called the
alpha alpha
from these
what is my condition for
the thing to be solved my submodularity condition
zero zero loss
one one necessary equals zero
one right
substituting in
you get this means
this means that e
x i
must be
alpha has been this article to
x y
class b
which is exactly the condition
i stated on the slide
if you make that one e alpha alpha zero cost of having the same label
zero which is always
arranged to have
then this just becomes the same triangle inequality
one of the things about the triangle inequality
if you make the same sort of assumption as before
that he
x i x j
some function g
x i
minus xj
one of the rules called
you probably
distribution of and distributed usually
which rules
in you can drive distribution
the distribution y
because it's
so kind of into it
we have this in a situation where you have that
we have a and
least b or c thank you have either a and b or in c
make sense
so what we normally do is just add this in is another rule
that's what interests and l
that's an ugly thing to do but they just added to the rule
with the subscript is means to say
it's very
it block something called the normalized it in the UK is going to be cut
elimination from john slaney at least
wade NZ right he told me that i mentioned talk about for about ten minutes
OK the normalisation pretty much like cut elimination it's one of these
what it tells you
i normalisation is that you never really you never have to derive
in fact the same formula
twice over again in this kind of gives you a feel for it makes a
proof of decidability
full relevant logic with negation and everything else is not decidable
with distribution is not decidable either so makes the proof is possible
weaker systems of relevant to our decidable so they
it's nice to have to have proof that
this proof theoretic techniques as well as other sorts approves to to do that and
want to improve the the decidability results also came up with a away way
of treating disjunction that's a bit different than
and it's very intuitive
and it's
i think very elegant
show that he was not you know it's unfortunate the put as writing about writing
has also told that forty pages was about limit of thirty eight total
so the the thirty seven so i e there was a whole bunch of stuff
and also i don't think i'd be able to have time to include it with
the clear that idea
OK now
when we do this
what sort of
just to
forget about the set from its impact on what i mentioned this already
sort of
natural mathematical inference procedure you
representing here
destruction and anyone pull apart what's it called
and doing mathematics
the that through proof by
that's effectively what we're doing but we're doing something that in the relevant case that
seems a bit like overkill
we're proving that
if you have a or b and you have a implies c and b implies
c that there's these
errors there
even get c
and implications i said in relevant logic is quite strong
and that's it
it requires a fair bit as i told you that
so what i want to talk about first is how to fine-tune these nets to
be better at discrimination
so what you can do is you can learn
without knowing the answers, just unsupervised one layer at a time
and then treat that as fine--as pre-training this layer of features and then you
can fine-tune it and you can find tune it to be better generating the data
the images
that's the contrastive wake sleep algorithm which i'm not going to talk about
or you can fine-tune it to be betteratdoing discrimination
and that works much better than standard backpropagation
sothere's twosort of reasons why it works better
the optimisation view
which says that we can optimize these feedforward neural networks better
by doing pre training and then back propagating a gradient than we can by just back propagating a
one reason is we can learn layers oneat atime this way
so we can learn the layers separately
the other reason is that when we back propagate, we'restarting from a sensible place
that is we're starting from features in each layer
that are good at capturing the correlations in the level below
as opposed to starting near the middle of this big non-linear space and hoping that
going downhill is going to get you to the right place
it was always a sort of miracle that it worked at all
and then there's the overfitting view
which is that
if i've got labels, like i've got say
suppose i had eight classes
there are onlythree bits of information in each label
and so each training case only put three bits of constraint on the mapping from
input to output
so if i've got,say,
a million training cases, i've still onlygot three millionbits of constraint
which isn't going to be enough to learn millions of weights
whereas if i'm trying to model the data itself, the images, they're typically much bigger
or more complicated, and i've gothundreds of bits of constraint per image
so i can fit much bigger modelsif i fit them generatively,
than if i fit them discriminatively
that wouldn't be true of course if the
answers, if the output, the labels, there were sort of gazillions of them
but it's not normally like that
then the
local optimisation that you do with backprop
is not really going to be designing the features. it's just can be making use
of features designed by somebody else, the pre training,
using all the information in the
and just changingslightly, just slightly changing the discrimination values
and in fact when you back prop in these nets, things hardly change at all
i'll showyouevidenceof that later
so if you take the same model as before
but we just pre train itwith no labels
and then we stick ten labels on top and do backpropagation
it'llwork better
when we did the joint density model, we got1.25%
if you do backpropagation now, you get1.15%
and actually
i can now get that down close to 1% by doing the discriminative training
slightly better. but
basicallyit improves things,and this difference is getting bigger
this is a picture from yoshua bengio's group, the last--the next four slides i
took from yoshua bengio.
these are the weights before fine tuning
this ison mnist digits,
but with distortions in them
these are the weights after fine tuning and you can't see any difference
righ? it's just that these will be getting like 3% error and these will be
and what's happened is you've--you've got this feature vectors and you take the feature vectors and you
just changeit ever soslightly
in order to manipulate discrimination boundaries
and of course if i can change discrimination boundaries,
i can
just move it slightly, i can improve the error a whole lot.
if i gotthe boundary just slightly wrong, between fours and nines
tiny changes to the weights will
make big differences
this is a demonstration that pre training does something
this is this was done on a big cluster, andyou train lots and lots of
and look at
what errorthey get
on a version of mnist. there's lots of extra data.
and then you pre train them
train them again. so this is backprop, this is pre-training followed by backprop. and the distributions hardly overlap
that's with one hidden layer i think
this is as you add more hidden layers
something's banging. do you know what's banging?
as you
as you add more layers
this effect gets much bigger
and now there's really
there's a couple of these guys didn't work very well
basically there's almost no overlap. these are getting better
and these getting worse
the old
history of backpropagation which was putting lots of hidden layers didn't seem to help
it was to do with optimisation, right? these are the--these are the same networks
they got all theextra hidden layers in,and they doing better than these networks
yes just like
the problem was optimization
and if you do this pre training,you're optimizingmuch better.
OK so here is another picture, basically the same thing. if you don't do tree--
pre training and you add layers,
after a couple of layers, thingsget worse
things get betterup to about four layers
and they're all better these anyway.
this is a nice picture that yoshua's group made