it's any type of activity we do
it's really process so
short periods of very intensive of that type of activity and the long periods of
not much happening so if you think about the because it means that
the short periods where i know the user it is very precisely because he or
she make lots of phone calls and then there a long period that he or
she doesn't make any functlon i have no idea where they are
at the end of the day we do need to kind of deal with all
limitations here i'm showing you is that the inter event time distribution for people who
make phone calls and you can see it's fact distribution with the exponential cutoff
and you know we and many others actually have worked on on how the model
that it wasn't happening
but they
this very much affects our statistics but the question does it really matter and what
of the things that we found is if we look at the user's motion it
may not matter at all because we have such we have a very large number
of users in our dataset we have also six to ten million people and then
you always find individuals who who sent close enough such that you can collect sufficient
number of them and you can order location very precisely
at the end of the
OK let's just look how is he doesn't look like so
here we have a kind three hundred by two hundred kilometre region vertically two hundred
may not be visible
and here the trajectories of the trajectories of a couple of individuals and what you
can see that some people seem to be moving along you know this guy here
not moving too much you guys are going to much if you do a couple
of the jumps
and so it's a very heterogeneous process and the question is how you characterize how
you described mathematically even though such a huge differences between what people do
in order to do that what what we started to kind of fell on the
shoulders of broken and others is to look at the jump size distribution simply what
is the distance between
two consecutive foreclose like this
it was red one particular moment and later on admitted he or she made another
court and the nice thing is that when we look at the distribution of the
jump sizes
then it seems to be following pretty much the same power law very close to
the exponent the problem has found in the dollar belligerent
and what is interesting
it's because you know this is a fundamentally different process
because you have to realize that that here we actually following the individuals just looking
at the money and that will become very important in the second so the consistency
between the two dissenters was very very encouraging so we see we somehow seeing the
same process the same origin but really
what is the mechanism for this world that is not clear because there are two
very different explanations there's lots of it
each user finds truncated leaving flight
the other possibility is that
none the user's follow flight but there are significant differences between the users of how
they travel around so many people some people travel shorter distances most of the time
of the most popular long distances and this population heterogeneity made some follow power law
and made responsible for the process essentially that we see
and in this part of the atmosphere we're here so we need to somehow distinguishes
to processes and about germany not allowed to do this because the
material is not telling us where the person is moving and we need to understand
that every time the dollar
somewhere it's really following some other process trajectories of the dollar bill measurement was going
from person to person and sampling of many many individuals and so so it it
was not possible to distinguish whether coming from one person to tell whether it's really
kind of collective effect so we need to do that now and in order to
do that what we did is for each user we define the centre of mass
based on the trajectory and the radius of gyration and then go back to this
and you can see this is the latest so generation disperse which looks very misleading
because this person obviously makes a couple of travels very far away but the point
is that most of the time is in this neighbourhood and these travels have a
small statistical weight to the voting so therefore he is he's already generation is really
dominated by the motion in its immediate neighborhood of home or work at the end
of the day we can assign to each user particularly useful generation
and the question we're asking really here is what is the difference between individuals that
we find that there is such an issue for each of you for example in
this room for everybody in the country how different with be i will similarly very
different from each other
and for us to see to what degree we need to see to what degree
status generation is stable in time
and for that we can group the users into different categories people seem to be
travelling along people don't care so much look at the time dependence so this is
how to use the generation of people who
who was at the end you have less than a kilometre travelled looks and you
see it seems to be saturated now why is this interesting
because the saturation curve is a much slower dependence what you would expect this will
disability fly because if you silly flight then we have a very precise prediction for
and what is the previous generation should increase as the power law we don't see
the problem behavior if anything it looks to be going to constant or maybe it's
very slow increase and if we look more carefully turns out that the previous generation
is really kind of growing approximately logarithmically in time so this is the linear local
and you see that it's kind of roughly about the positive the logarithmic increase
you could pretty much take the saturation process because at the end delivery becomes so
slow but it's not it's kind of this is a very slow increase in time
the point is that now we have a generation that fought like after all kind
of flexible amounts observation more saturated not exactly then we can look at the distribution
of these values
and the nice thing is that you see yet again the same problem that we're
seeing here
that is what this is really kind of exploring how different individuals are and what
you see is that most people have a very small radius of gyration one to
ten kilometres if you never come to the table over hundreds of kilometres
so this is indicating that really the origin of this part of the data
the measurement was seeing and we're seeing them we look at the jump size distribution
across the world population to high degree is rooted in the heterogeneity of the population
the you know people people have typical region in which they move around and there
are kind of distributed differences between different individuals so most people just move in the
same neighborhood one two three kilometres if you have a regular travel over very long
now the what we find here is slightly different from what we found earlier
not so
not significantly but actually is different doesn't make sense
and to understand what this picture may so again showing this kind of trajectories and
the this distribution really meant that it was kind of the fact that people is
not so different from each other a few people moving this guy's pretty pictures suddenly
moved here this guy moving at very small distances and these few big chance are
the few travelers who really kind of had this very long radius of generation and
they the ones who contributed to sleep but that but this because its population heterogeneity
influence someone's breathing
how you can control someone else's breathing
i'm going to try and so i picked him up
shock immunities stopping criteria wouldn't stop so so what did i
held in very close
to my chest
and i started breathing
at the same rate that he was crying
so he was so i started breathing at the same rate and i had a
very close we can feel me breathing at the same rate he was crying and
slowly i slowed down
and he slowed down and probably the same way that all of you just did
i've done this in big groups and when i stopped breathing
the whole route no one's breathing and some after you can start breathing you know
it's OK to
but but the important thing if you're going to do something like this if you're
can lead people to for example your your sitting at home
and i do not and your partners at home
and you just had some great news
i know you've got to pay rise or promotional or something and you run an
annual really excited
and you
you get what you and your partner
calm down
calm down and you know i don't want to calm the how does that feel
when you're really excited and some you know
it's horrible isn't it
just think why don't you understand how i feel what they should do
if they want you to calm down you know what they should do as you
running and into a guess what they should jump up and say well what happened
and they should get on the same level as you first and then they should
start slowly coming down and so will you
you've got to match first if you want to influence someone
match them first and then control and and come down and they will come down
with you
it doesn't work otherwise
right i want to
i want to
demonstrate the power
ron paul
and the power of matching people
because there another thing that richard bandler and john grinder found was this is natural
it's totally natural
human beings
to start looking like each other and sounding like each other
when they are connected to each other when there
sort of in rapport wheels to start looking like each other
and what they found is this is an actual trade if you have rapport
you start
looking and sounding the same
and what they what they thought was hang on
can we do it the other way round
can we build rapport
because the cause effect goes this way
rapport causes matching
visual and vocal and they asked
visual and vocal matching cause rapport
and what they found was
you can manufacture rapport
which is
some people
find very uncomfortable
very uncomfortable with this idea of of manufacturing connection with another person but what you
like you know it's true it works
and so what we're going to do is i want to prove this to you
and i want to prove how important it is to be able
switches on when you need to switch it on so we can do very quick
the first thing we need in this exercise you need to have a partner to
work with so i would like you to find another person one person
who you gonna do the exercise to just decided upon the accessed
so you see you did did to do
OK all three of them
you're you're can someone come over here we've got one person
three here
because your straight if you come over here beta
so if you work with the have it
well why don't want to
this essentially
is equal to
pseudoinverse of that set
so n is equal to the pseudo inverse of distillation times the source matrix
because the pseudoinverse
so in essentially and the interesting thing here is that this and has a lot
to go into the finals really important because
if the reason i'm going on about find what is that when you because con
so that mesh measure the face and things and really what that is that's a
piecewise find a fine mesh so all those triangles are actually we treat those as
the final what's and so if you want more complicated what we actually use this
sort of case these little pieces of fine what together to build up a big
and so it's kind of analogous to gas mixture models quite big gas in this
kind of like your fundamental thing in machine learning that use if using a generative
model you've got what asking
gas distribution it's not because you need second order moments is the fundamental way
to deal with the distribution and the final something similar in computer vision so basically
i want to find can build up a lot more complicated what just from the
so far obviously there are kind of war there are other
how much what things like perspective and things like that but
we were able later and on the interesting thing about this and
is that
it will have a functional forms and one
and two
two one
one two
one three
two three belong here
this is always the two d case zeros or one
and important business e two is that i can treat this sort of clear this
now write this
and so on
give you a microscope back
all right this bigger
i'm talking about the final this thing i think of one way of thinking of
mapping one travel to another always think that is three points one travel to another
and then
i got that one
keep stuff myself up here
two one zero
in one to two
and one three
two three
zero one
now the important thing another important thing that we deal with these what functions
is the notion of identity
and the notion of war this is that
if all input x
should be able to
what function x
given that my wall is the is zero
so can i receive given that
so to think about the translation in the example if i'm shifting if if p
relates to
translation x translation one
this if this is zero zero effect
x has to be able to the wall function given that my parameter here
now can you can see a problem here
if i come from it rises to find more in this way
if i try if i try do that
so essentially what i do when i'm trying to do define what is it
i've got my source that my source functions and multiply this by n
i get my destination
so if
if i said all these to zero
multiply it by the source
i'm going to get the destination
so the other thing that we have to do when we're dealing with a funnel
is essentially we represent slightly differently so we actually represents p
and this is again going details with the final performance
o ports
the magnets
another way of looking at is that this
current loop is all by itself a little magnets will by the south pole is
here and the north pole is there
because is the direction of the magnetic dipole moment and the north pole attracts the
south pole that's another way of looking at it and that's the reason why magnets
attract each other by north and south poles attract each other and by north and
north poles repel each other that's exactly the reason is the current that is flowing
it is the world's force
that causes
the attraction or repelling force
so paramagnetic material is attracted by a magnet essentially is that this field is not
and diamagnetic material of course will be repelled
it will be pushed
away from the strong field because in paramagnetic and diamagnetic materials this current will be
running in the opposite direction because it opposes
external field
west by magnetism supports it
we have forum
and the third form of magnetism
actually the most interesting
its ferromagnetism
in the case of ferromagnetism
we again have the evidence
have themselves
permanent dipole moments
but now
four very mysterious reasons which can only be understood with quantum mechanics
there i domains
which have the dimension of about a tenth of a millimeter maybe three tenths of
a millimetre
by the dipoles are a hundred percent aligned
and these dipole
which i one direction
are uniformly distributed throughout the ferromagnetic materials
so there may not be any
nett magnetic field
if i have here but try to make a sketch
of those domains
something like this then perhaps here
all the dipole
recall the hundred percent aligned in this direction
but for instance here
they all the
aligned in this direction
and the number of atoms involved in such a domain is typically ten to the
seventeenth may be up to ten to the twenty one
so if you doubt i apply an external fields
these domains
i will be force
to go in the direction of the
the magnetic field and of course the degree of success depends on the strength of
the external field the strength of the vacuum field
and all the temperature the lower the temperature
the better it is because then there is less thermal agitation
which of course at a certain random randomness the whole process
so when i applied external field these domains as a whole
can flip
inside ferromagnetic materials
the magnetic field can be thousands of times stronger
that it is in the vacuum field
and we will see some examples of that
if you remove the external field
in the case of
so magnetism
you have again complete chaos of the dipoles
that's not necessarily the case was ferromagnetism some of those domains may stay aligned in
the direction that the external field force forcing them
if you're very carefully remove the external field undoubtedly some domains will flip back because
of the temperature there's always thermal agitation some may remain
and therefore
the material once it has been exposed to an external magnetic field may have become
permanently magnetic
and the only way you can remove the permanent magnetism could be to ban on
it with a hammer
and then of course these
domains were them
get very nervous and then they will
randomized themselves or you can hear them up
and then you can also
undo the
the orientation of the domains the remains themselves will remain but then they average out
not to produce any permanent magnetic field
so for the same reason the ferromagnetism
is pulled towards the strong field in case that we have a nonuniform magnetic field
ferromagnetism of course will also be pulled towards the strong field except in the case
of ferromagnetism the forces with which
the material is pulled towards the magnet
wayne larger than in case of
paramagnetic materials
if i take a paper clip
you can do it at on you can hang a paper clip on the south
pole of your magnet or the north pole of a magnet
we all have gotten magnets in your body kits so you can try it at
baker paperclips along
the magnets the amount on which side you hang it
ferrimagnetic material is always
full towards
the strong field
if you have a few of those paperclips on their
thank you very carefully and slowly removed
those with them is a hammer yet
you may actually notice that after you removed and that the paper clips themselves have
you can actually try to hang them on each other make little change
but drop them on the floor a few times in the neck mechanism neck visible
go away
so what you have written is that is that some of those domains
remained aligned
due to new external field
mister magnetism there's no way that you can hang power
magnetic material under most circumstances on the mac
there's one exception i was show exceptional even today
on the central path and then a very simple barrier method for general conic optimization is
like this you start close to the central path you pick an X and a T that is
sufficiently close so the Newton decrement is bounded by some beta for example one
over eight and then at each iteration you make one Newton step on X with a
step size one and then you update T but very slowly so you could take the
current T and you multiply it with a constant close to one so that's called the short step
barrier method  because at each iteration you stay in the neighborhood of the central path
you keep X  so the reason why you make these tiny updates in T is
to keep X after this Newton update inside the region of quadratic convergence so you make small
updates in X small enough to keep X in the region of quadratic convergence and
then you after one Newton step you update T by a small amount so it's a
very simple method it's not very fast in practice but it's a practical method
it can be implemented but you can show that the worst-case complexity the number
of Newton systems you have to apply is bounded by a function like this that's
exactly the same as for linear programming except that the parameter M who chose the number
of inequalities in the LP is replaced by the barrier parameter theta for the cone
that we use here so would be M for a semi-definite problem with M by M
Newton matrix inequality and so on right so it's a very simple method but it has
a polynomial worst-case complexity and again this bound with the square root of theta is actually the best-known bound
for these types of problems it's not a very fast method and it's easy to
see why it's not very fast because you make these very small and slow updates
in T in practice  of course you would like to update T much faster and
of course there's no need in practice to stay very close to the central path
because you're only interested in the end point of the central path the optimal
point of the LP so you can probably get there much faster by
making larger steps and not constraining yourself to this region of quadratic convergence so that's
one way to do this is toik instead of these short step methods you use
a predictor corrector method so the idea is again very similar you try to
follow the central path but  using a different mechanism as in these short step methods
in a predictor corrector method you take at each iteration the tangent to the central path
or if X is not on the central path an approximate tangent to the central path
that's the predictor in the predictor step so you compute a tangent to the central path
or an approximate tangent then you make a step in that direction you select a new
value of T based on the step you make in that direction and then you
recenter with the new T and that's a corrector step so you do one or more centering steps
with the new value of T and then again you take this predictor step
so the difference is here that using this mechanism you can increase T adaptively if the
central path is not very nonlinear you can make larger updates in T then using
a fixed update of this kind via than the barrier method so in  practice this is
much more efficient and you can actually show that for some choices of these
mak this predictor and corrector steps you get the same worst-case complexity so that's the
section on barrier methods so they're  primal methods that try to follow the central path
and you can use them for conic LPs  with general non pil  nonpolyhedral convex cones
as long as you have  a normal barrier function for the cone so the
last section is on symmetric primal dual methods so the barrier methods for and again
this work was motivated by methods for linear programming so the interior point methods that
are used for linear programming in practice are actually not the simple barrier methods that
I started the previous section with so in practice for example in commercial interior point
solvers people use primal dual methods instead of a primal barrier method and
they're symmetric methods so they treat a primal and a dual  symmetrically so people
have tried to extend these very successful primal dual methods for linear programming to conic
optimization and then it turns out that the most elegant extensions of these methods
are restricted to certain types of convex cones called symmetric cones that we'll define and
then for these types of cones we can extend this primal dual methods so what's the purpose
of a primal or how do primal dual methods compare with barrier methods so first
there are some important similarities so they're both based on solving the central path
to find a solution and they follow the same central path just using a different method
also it's very important that per iteration the linear algebra you need in a
primal dual method is the same as for a barrier method so in a barrier
method in each iteration you had to solve a Newton system that's  determined by the barrier
function that you use so here also the s system you have to solve at each
iteration will have the same form as in a barrier method so that's also important so
the cost per reiteration will be the same they follow the same central path but they
try to do it in a more robust and faster way so you have you can
arrive at a solution with fewer iterations so the advantages are that they're faster than
we can easily solve white just checking
well down constraint would be if it's not there will i just look at where
the boundaries and i get the solution
in general it's not quite that trivial
but the nice thing is that convex optimization problems with convex constraints have a unique
minimum value
they don't necessarily have to have a unique solution
but they have unique know that
so why do they not necessarily have to have a unique
well think of something that looks like a troll
it goes down
latin and then goes back up again
there is a convex function
however this convex function will have its minimizer anywhere on that straight line on the
however it will have unique minimum value
so what you might want to do is homework or
tomorrow the beach whatever
think about why convex function has unique number
look at the proof states two or three line
you will need the definition of convexity for that
i assume that everybody here knows what is
basically take the graph take two points
but the straight line through it
that straight line has to be above the function values
of the function itself
and the constraints obviously also convex is that they the nice thing if you have
a convex set
they take intersections between several convex it's the result is going to be a convex
again something tomorrow for the beach
you can do really nice drawings in the sand and this is going to be
really useful if you want to work at
yes try
so what you need is that the constraints are convex
and that the objective function is convex
if one of the two doesn't happen you're in big trouble
he this simple example
so for instance if i were told to
maximize this function
i'll get real problems
so let's assume this were a problem cannot quite we said that well but let's
say i want to
minimize the concave function rather than the convex one you can see that
the minimum is going to be obtained at any of one of those four to
so in general this type of probably NP hard
little difference if i just change the sign
so how do you solve
we've got the objective function one half the square got this constraint
we know that those constraints see i have to be listed here
so now a recipe
i cannot go into detail to prove why this recipe will actually do something useful
but the what usually do is if you have a constrained optimization problem where
vectors can be nonparametric on dimensional whatever it's a good idea to switch into the
and then optimize the u
and again
this has been
i would cite
the key thing for the success of support vector machines that people solutions to dual
the trouble is
that people pretty much forgot that you could actually is going to solve this problem
and the problems
and so only over the past four to five years people have realized there are
very efficient algorithm to solve these problems in the primal
and that's pretty much what the state of the art in optimisation is now
so things go
back from one face to the other and sometimes notation and tricks
are they useful to make progress
if you see is that in iteration we think well why is he doing this
can they do something else
you probably on to something good
either that or you
i realize it's a completely daft idea not to do it but
they have to ask why certain steps happen
this is the only way high feel really make progress
his prescription
you take the primal objective function
and you have to it
lagrange multipliers time constraints
so these are like virtual forces trying to ensure that this
remains within its constraints
and then
you get the function that is
a function of w
and b
and those lagrange multipliers
and what you can prove is that this function eleven
i will have a saddle point at the optimal solution
so in other words
it it will have a minimum with respect to w and b
for optimal out
will have a maximum with respect to alpha for optimal w and b
what this means is
if there is a saddle point where we can just go and take derivatives of
l with respect to w and b
so for that
get rid of w b in the equation
and just get an optimisation problem in the alps
actually know this kind of stuff you've done it before it's just that you never
thought of it this way
let's say i want to minimize a function f of x without constraints
one way of doing this is i could just go and computer relative if primal
i don't understand this problem without any graphs and formal
in equation
so this is this is
and how long and it's very very simple model
but it shows what we usually see in in the cluster or announcing plans for
biological computer
the idea is that we can
divide our program
into two parts
one is what that can be implemented completely in parallel
and the
is some part of the problem that can be paralyzed
because it means something in addition to that the apply for example what is when
and then we combine them into one in the extraction of what can be completely
parallel combine into one index need synchronization without
part of the of the system
he is percentage of our program that can be done in parallel
and is number of unique forest as
you see what's going on and actually the graph this is extremely naive model that
it doesn't take into account is not scalable resources such
but if you look to israel classes you you can see our real parallel computation
you can see that usually get something like this which is very close to the
so is simple models
and you can do we're after estimation of your program and using this equation
rapidly but
not so well
predict how the system works
and if you don't want to do this but want only
to get some intuition about
performance of your of the system in the class situation when you edit resources using
cortisone to scaling
you can
three things that would be something like this
so at the beginning
usually increasing you linear
pretty good
then you see that it's some point when you can get an advantage of additional
additional resources that to get
the main idea of all development and what is the system architect should achieve is
try to move
these parties as much as possible
and doing the and you can do this on only by reducing the number of
not quite a lot of what
he using part of your programs that can be paralyzed
well it's very simple model
and to be able to show you that it's the really important it dissertations
i don't remember from what company his
but it's attention from from
current media media about
well execution and the idea is that
as i said at the beginning
now we can to find a computer without the number of CPU
and it's hard to find information retrieval task that
actually more than one ball
usually even if you are doing
document processing for company so knowledge going to number of
the program is unavoidable
therefore for every election
later then we'll talk about other algorithms to analyse also parallel versions of this
and talking about parallel architectures online
so and there are two approaches
well architectures you have smaller architectural one computer number of CPU
and we can and we have well architecture cluster of computers because they can implement
in parallel other tasks they're doing other tasks in parallel
in real life that well
on one block when we are a very low one but
it depends on the operating system usually operation system takes care
about this
you need only specify programming language however going to do it
and in most of the modern persian system programming languages there are two approach
the right of the red and processed the difference is that threat is for elocution
in one program
processes is different from
well usually the rest broke it depends
processes and was safe because they usually use installation of memory and when you're process
that the q
all other product
but there is is not true because they all share the same memory usually
problem is one
he was all the threats of this problem
it's a very short introduction when creating this when creating program we always have the
they can create
that program the doing everything we you have control about everything and everything is threatened
it's good
the disadvantage if if something goes wrong all this implication does
or you can create a number of problems
in real life he is doing a combination of this stuff
if you're doing here is usually
the and because
for charge usually only read the memory and it's much less probable that you corrupted
and q the process if you're doing in the studio creating a lot of indexes
it's usually a number of threats because this memory separation can be useful for you
in this case and you need to merge in any case result from different boxes
and even
the so from this point of view of every everything is pretty simple and one
books and there is a lot of literature about it i even
but you don't know
what the what right for you if you have very little data and you have
a very vague prior assumptions then
you really don't know
what the outcome is going to be that and that would be reflected
in your here your posterior quite wide
there was a it would
it would have time you know close to fifty fifty
the kind of thing that would be the right answer in that case
that well
in this case you don't even know
the wrong answer is to try to
he invented some procedure to give you a definite
but there's something really wrong about that if you just get the answer
the data doesn't really contain any information about that
that was the top of the page
you can you can solve it
by doing that is statistics
so the question relates to the the the fact whether
even if you have a fairly strong prior doesn't in the limit of large amount
of data
so you actually get back the maximum likelihood estimate
and it depends on exactly what the in some circumstances you do get convergence to
the maximum likelihood estimate and in some circumstances you don't
and depends bit
i think it depends on the on the particulars of how the prior up and
what the model
it depends on a lot of detail so
so there there are many simple class the model for example see that you actually
get convergence the maximum likelihood estimate
so let me
let me know
kind that that's postpone the
discussion about how to get the prior
until tomorrow because tomorrow we can discuss the model
which is a has a lot more interesting properties we can actually specify
things that make a lot more intuitive than you're only looking at
at that controls or if you're looking at
so for example like this which is removed from the actual natural context then
it's all about it to worry about this kind of the problem but i promise
that talk you beg me to stop talking about prior to tomorrow
so the question is
in even even in classical physics you're you're you're basing your modelling on assumptions about
how not about the prior distribution because you don't have a prior distribution but now
about the likelihood function that's entirely true for two sets of assumptions that coming here
assumptions about the prior
and no assumptions about the likelihood and this is also some somehow
tone down a bit often because
some people think
classical statistics is being closer to an objective way of treating thing but of course
only objective
up to the point of
well you are agree on what the likelihood function as the people
focus a lot on arguing about what the prime
but equally important you should argue about what like
and things are not
objective you can if you can agree on what i like about
that's very very good
i just spent the last five minutes of going through
a couple of couple of words here i think are important to you realize that
people use to mean different things which is which is very unfortunate
OK so we a from the objective and on prior information but actually
you know if just point out
you can also think of classical getting objective because it depends on
on what you're
what you're assumptions are about the likelihood function how right
what i like about
right down to the conflict thinking things happen
it's pretty clear what the likely to be of more complicated example
it's not not not clear what like it
something i that i only only in over here but i'll talk about more letters
bayesian inference about the likelihood principle like
but that
the computer and only on the likelihood of of of the observation
and the assumption that you're making it shouldn't be it should depend on
on in particular should depend on observations have made
possible outcomes
that that you did not serve
but that
the result is not
not allowed to depend on that and there's something wrong with analysis
it depends on
in a nodes in the classical
testing your making statements about serving something or something more extreme you you making statements
about other datasets as well like that that kind of thing doesn't obey the like
i the more specific about later on
the result of the debate from the posterior distribution
and once you compute the posterior distribution then when you finished third mission tells you
what is your new
they of knowledge about
you probably about how the world
o thing i didn't go into in detail that how to use this posterior distribution
we talk about
a very simple example of how to make predictions about upcoming
but to make decisions you can minimize the
the expected loss the new term coming in here which is the loss function
the loss function tells you
how expensive is it
to make a particular guess about the state of the art of various when something
else happens to be true
so you think in things like thing financial tries action but if you if you
lost would be measured in
in a medical setting
last measured in terms of
however people are feeling feeling or or the risk of them dying things like that
but notice that the loss function is something that doesn't really enter into the into
the now compute the posterior distributions and then you sort of doing this
and then after you've done compute posterior and somebody can tell you know this is
my loss function
i actually care about you
OK that's what you care about then you make
this and the decision
you're expected loss
so this is the
come back to the to the notion of the of cost function
what i'm going to describe today and in the rademacher also it's slightly and satisfy
all mentions something more about that a little later the results we had yesterday typically
didn't have that square the square root of course makes the bounds much less tight
you know if you had abandoned one hundred you take the square root and it's
about one in ten which is seen point one inches
but the flexibility and the of course when you're far away from you know rather
larger errors then the the
and the square root is not so significant
OK so my first application of these ideas and this is like a warm-up
rademacher complexity
is this something referred to stability bounds
but that night and i just recently published we stability to just mean sort of
reliable estimations so it's slightly confusing with this user stability which is the technical term
introduced by olivia was going on a PCFG and the
used introduce very neat idea
and it allows the fairly direct application of these concentration results so i think it's
a nice way to start sort of lead into using the idea is to see
how they used in
example and then i will tackle the rademacher case which is which is more general
so they introduced this idea of a uniformly stable algorithm so it's interesting that actually
trying to bound the performance of a particular algorithm most generalisation mounds once we looked
at it yesterday and the rademacher bounds are going to be
so for apply for any function so sort of it doesn't matter what the algorithm
does provide to get a good result then this will hold this is actually looking
at the particular algorithm
and it says is uniformly stable with it's with respect to a loss function l
if this holds for all
as for all
training samples
we apply the algorithm to the sample
and we apply it to the sample with the ice come elements
thrown away back slash i means that
we remove the i th element so it's a bit like doing leave one out
that's the idea here and
what we have to cheque is that if we apply
the result of that function to new example
the loss associated with that and the loss associated with this when we apply after
removing that example is
for all
test examples less or equal to beta
so it's a fairly strong requirement but surprisingly many
and even the SVM in the case of the one norm SVM you can get
bound on this peter i'll show you later so that this is actually you know
remarkable that is so applicable it does make sense in some respects and that you
know you wouldn't want things to change too much just by removing one example
of course if you just take a hard margin SVM this doesn't apply you can
have quite
strong changes in
the output OK
so this is this is the assumption i'm i'm simplifying down what they've done they
have actually done quite a number of different variations on this definition in the paper
if you're interested you could follow and read that i think i put references to
all of these papers have made use of in the in the back and many
others as well
OK so
how do we approach this using this
concentration inequality strategy
what we're looking at is trying to estimate the difference between the
the expected loss
of the
this is a this is the function returned by the algorithm
this is the loss and its expectation
under the
underlying distribution
and this is its empirical loss
this is the loss on the training set
i'm using this notation
to denote the expectation on the training set so it just means the average of
the training set losses if you see that from now on it always means that
k case just work out the loss on the training set and then take the
average of that
this is the sort of what we can tell from the training set this is
what we want to know about
you know this is the true performance on on unseen data
and so the idea that is the difference between those two
so we're going to go for it you know just try and
get bound on that and we're going to diamonds theorem to this DNS quantity
but we're going to look first at how much this can change as a result
of the substitution
one example
i'm going to look at how much this can change from the substitution of a
single example
so this
we're going to first street this as
so we're treating this is i f of s
right in
the diamonds there
but we're going to see how much this can change first and then much this
can change and then add the two together for the total amount of change so
it is of course one
maybe i'm jumping too quickly but if you want to apply madame is theorem the
critical thing is to get about on this quantity here
one year then you see in the position that variations for the other know
and what we expected to have this two thousand ten that the genome sequencing only
like about how you
so again how is expected to live get it but that would give us a
lot of
i mean much much more than just imagine of the human genome and you can
everybody can get so
so this is like a big basis and the support on one CD with something
and then you can fill up hard to find
OK so typically typically b
popular with the population data recorded deviation from the the reference
so one typical
we will present a single nucleotide polymorphism where only one i j
but also decisions and deviation
so one thing which complicates things is that you have two copies of the DNA
and you don't necessarily know
which copy that one
so this
i mean it's just making the analysis book
when sequencing and you don't know which is which copy of it
but maybe one important part
please biologically what you but so what is the identification of haplotypes what is a
so what you see here is that you have different phenotypes different genomic sequence
and you see the variation here with the first be
always t here
the second we have always see
the next one you see the same kind of change
so you see variations
the same
and it usually happens when these
polymorphism next to each other
OK because it's unlikely that two we want this to happen or are separated by
so so mutation and there other what like the one here
then they show different
and whenever she several what business here together is called the haplotype
the thing about this haplotype is you only need to identify one of these twenty
one in order to understand the full structure
the haplotypes
OK in you're
in expression
so if you can
so you know the synapse are linked so usually appear together
i mean
so that they are close to each other it's unlikely that separated by way
by crossover
by recombination but i think that a very combinations so in there way it's more
likely to break
so whenever you have very close to each other and likely
and what actually see years you see difference NIPS on a and then you see
these red i mean this this final here shows you that these are correlated in
different people i want to compute
OK so that means the high correlation and why no correlation once and it separates
the upper block on this one
but it's
so expression
so the most prominent way of measuring gene expression by my very own article
the metric my
so the idea is that you have a glass plate and you put on these
glass plates small sequence
i mean sequences of twenty twenty five one sixteen hyperlink
the sequences are complementary perspectives regions what research and on a piece of the team
of DNA
so if
we are now using on a simple
which we took all of the cell so we can
we take them on a
i would i
to the
troops on on the page
and the label them on an NEC whenever they habitation has happened then we see
light sport position if you know its position we have a bot which are independent
which means that on a level
we have been from the cells
so what you get is with this kind of picture so we got me
the idea expressed in the red thing but this is for comparison of two
but there are many nontrivial level analysis tasks so you had this big place and
there might be a million different products and things happen like a lot of what
wanted after we are what this gradient hybridisation i mean concentration was on the true
remove all these different out and you can use a lot of machine learning just
OK guess is important just to recap we heard this morning because you've relaunched
we talk about
general models
and i said the general model you need to define
we can and i rise by offering here as well
how to specify problem solving
for general public
OK as our
OK i had the transition function in a market
markov decision process was something to think about the transition function
right which is
which is the mark of assumptions camps
the really you too much
the activation function
reward function gamma is what
discount factor
it is horizon wasn't able previous slide
OK these are general problems which is the phi gamma with this by asian you
also have the objective that you're trying to optimise the is discounted
and you can start to say what are possible the solutions this problem of properties
to have and so on
because only six hours sitting in the chair model i went with
popular model of the MDP
what i need an MDP
so if we what i dropped from here i don't need
don't states
in the end specifically markovian
an easy they often the average function
now because again this is the observation there are exactly the states is the bijection
so you don't need observation orientation function
and that the different you know how you should act what you reward for a
course you need to know what your position criterion is
so we said that the thing that we want to optimize
OK so we define the policy right
the mapping from states
the action
forty MDP we know that
what's one property of the optimal policy
pi star for an MDP
so we know that there exists
a price to such that for all states
and all
other policies
the pie star
the values you get underpriced of bns
it's going to equal to
the of one of us the of what here
right for all the calls
pi star
and we know that exists
and then i've got a nice property at the policy
it's also deterministic
OK as really nice
this assumes that the function is a fixed probability distribution
the transition function is not some person i can screw you
OK that can change there will be non stationary
this has to be stationary has markovian
you don't know it
the i mean what what are the weavers learning day we don't need no t
but after properties
so the
sition means that i made the changes
upon some suitable way apply which is not consistent so actually closest cluster markovian
uh in terms of
but so so for example if you
if you're playing a poet this which strategies
switch strategies on you their policy-making markovian but they might just change is simple
i just do their internal state
but but the
the point is that this is fixed
fixed probability distribution never changes
so is this
pastor satorras take we define
the value of some of the pious
as an expectation
notations but that it was just was used in the future
the expectation the following some policy pi
given that we started
in the initial state
which possess
we want to look at the expected sum of future this kind rewards so so
several times
out to infinite eight for doing it horizon articles infinity
and as i dropped the baby them sitting in
OK area
OK one
this the or to the data samples the executioner sample rewards the reward at time
and what
came into power to write this carry one
OK the defined policies
well defined
with the value function is OK now i got all the ingredients
i know there exists some policy part i for which
every state some examples by star
which which gives you the optimal value from all possible states NASA policy that's your
goal in in independent and certainly or we first learn the goal is to find
out why stars
now there are two reasons i justifying pi start
to model based algorithms
now start
cover value iteration which go by many names
also referred to as dynamic programming
relied on the bellman backup which
you quickly
it is this so
so long kernel methods
in fact what i to do the second there was
in the first bit actually did quadratic programming OK was
complextype problems
but i wanted to show in the second battle
in fact kernel based methods is bigger than this quadratic programming in fact i can
do linear programming and i can do
non linear optimisation
and also not really restricted to classification regression i can consider other types of problems
for example novelty detection OK
it might be for a system where
perhaps and try to classify objects and my classifier
perhaps is about classifier works OK but chemists certain things
why not detectors may still actually indicate the whatever it is is a novel
OK so i want to show that in fact the broader class of kernel based
and also
cover a few points really cover last time
for example had actually find the kernel parameter things like that
in the second lecture we show that the standard QP SVM is only one optimisation
approach we can we can do linear programming nonlinear programming semi definite programming it's OK
because of the drug in the whole of optimisation theory
right so we show that there are further tasks beyond classification classification regression
which can be performed using kernel based methods
twenty two
right comment on different learning algorithms and strategies for model selection
to find the culprit and and and also
another big
the really big cluster kernel based methods is i can actually use composite kernels give
you sample of this i think right in my previous talk i actually had some
material on network inference which i said that actually dropped because of time and network
inference i wanted to predict
the functional relationships in gene between genes OK
and perhaps a link to a plus one no link will be and minus one
now i could use expression data for that many people do however if i want
to build a classifier to my network inference which is sort optimal
i would use all data which is available
and what if i want to build a classifier uses multiple types of data
then that transmit additional composite kernel and data fusion again something i can do kernel
based methods that that have a problem with other techniques OK so it could cover
all these sort of offshoots of the story of kernel based methods as a linear
programming will continue programming nonlinear programming and non detection applications and other games
the problems giving up to now been passive learning for example in my previous lecture
taught about will stewart and how to use an SVM
to build the binary classifier to predict relapse non relapse that in all instances i
give you up to now
been passive learning in other words the classifier
i give you get the classifier datapoints learns these and tries to classify new data
active learning is the learning algorithm actually poses queries
to the oracle information source so as to will the rule much more efficiently
and it's been like me and trying to teach you some rule like arithmetic
so two plus two equals four three three to six and you could just sit
that i do this because the student actually just saw this sort these examples and
hope to generalize active learning which is called
which is the smart student i would say something two plus two equals four
and then you are OK well that's the case was the answer
two three percent by carefully posing your questions you can maximize information transfer OK to
active learning and something where SVM useful also in the second part of touch here
and they're quite alot on what was formerly my research areas for example in dublin
that give you was cooked up with christine bennett and the active learning was cooked
up with another and alex smola
right so also talk about radio SVM model selection different types of kernels and learning
with composite kernels but we able to cover all this right so i did this
quadratic programming type approach
but it's worth noting that there is also a linear programming approach which is very
similar popularized by christine burns and all the magnets are in michigan teaching
this was constant and its some one and it's sort champion
kernelizable so i can do a linear programming approach to show it to the second
but in fact
there's a huge number
and i otherwise i can tell you a kind of neural network algorithms such as
the perceptron mean over
and the adatron
OK these particular algorithms going back to the interface neural networks the data appears in
the form of the dot product scalar product so just like a scene just
i can take that dot product replaced by kernel
so i can kernelized algorithms such as the
perceptron winnow for control
if you look back on the constitution
you can see the kernel adatron somebody else did very early on and is relatively
time kernelized algorithm occurs in about forty lines much easier than the straightforward SVM still
quadratic programming and it'll handle non linearly separable datasets OK you're also take things that
if all of the variables and then states this is an m squared table i
have to work with
and so on can something up this table that's in m squared operation
and then i've got it sort of an order an operation to make another and
sweat operation to multiply this in here so all of these steps of order m
squared and the number of them is just linear in the length of the chain
so this looks way better than working with the joint distribution
so what's happening we started here at the beginning of the chain we
some the first variable
and then we multiply by the next potential some the next variables
we can take all of these things together we can give them
so we finish with this will left that i thing that we're not
marginalizing we get the whole thing and name
the function of x i will call it the alpha message
the messages going forwards along the chain
and then
this lot here when i
when i've some that exi plus one all the way up to x l
for the function of x i again which we call beta message
and that sort of started the the far into the chain so we're willing to
what now is the recursive algorithm for computing the marginals
so the marginal is just the product of the alpha message in the beta message
if we go back to here
we just had this much the products of this slot times this
but the
message themselves can be found recursively so the alpha message no x i
was obtained by summing over the previous node x i minus one of the clique
potential times message that
the alpha message that arrive from node x i minus one
so there's just recursive
computation of that alpha message in this case is going forwards along the chain we
start the message x i minus one
we apply this operation in the message site
then suddenly here for the beta message we start with that site plus one
and we were going backwards and we get the message x i
so i got one message going forward along the chain one message going backward along
the chain they meet select side we multiply them together
in order to get the marginal the only other thing we do is in general
will have this normalisation constant but finding the normalisation constant very easy because this is
just an n dimensional vector so we have an order operation in order to normalise
it so that we get the required marginal
so we have an algorithm
which has cost is not
and raised to the power l is not exponential in the length of the chain
is something like hell times m squared
o operations each which will and squared is now linear the length of the chain
rather than exponential
and turns out to be not one of them
and it's pretty easy i think you can you can see
to extend
that algorithm two
any graph which has a tree structure graph which there are no loops
you can see why
the problem with this is going to be the phi phi added one extra meaning
from here all the way around so there
this clique potential involving x one and x two also involves itself so i can
no longer just to the south asian over x one i can't get the process
and inference in that graph is actually extremely hard
so if we have a tree structured graphs have no loops
then we can just write down the recursive algorithm the kind of just described and
it takes the following form
so at each node we take
all incoming messages
let's take a little piece of the tree structured graphs here
it has three neighbours
and then we messages coming in
which are the partial summations from here on out with all the rest of the
graph here
there's another message arriving here which is obtained by summing over recursively something of everything
in all the graph which connects to here
so multiply those two potentials together together with the
local any local
potential from that no difference is if this is connected to an observed node and
we then some at node a site
and that gives an outgoing message
there should be a function of the
very about it's connected to here
so it's just a simple generalization of
all the algorithm that we derive the chain case
so what's going to happen is there will be a message flowing across every link
in general
we need to do something slightly more than that if we had a
OK so
this was an algorithm for computing the marginal at this particular note no in general
if we want the marginal let's say several nodes or even all of the nodes
it would be very wasteful
stupid wasteful to run the algorithm
every time the fresh for every single
no so to get the marginal for this node have to propagate the message all
the way from the beginning to that no but again this node after probably the
same message all way from the beginning i don't want to do that work
over and over again and the solutions very easy if you take one message and
frequency of
my hand i don't know
very far
go fast
our copy is
this is the
first of all
like this week
my hand is really not moving very much look look at my hands almost moving
and you see that
picture on the board
first of all
so now we have the fast
and it starts laughing again
when two fast that i want one
yeah yeah yeah yeah
the second
second harmonic
very happy
my hand is not very much
second harmonic
let's not go for the first
o to fast
he does nothing
a little faster does nothing
o faster
a little faster
it is
the knowledge
two points in the middle
not quite in the middle
two point of this free standing still
and of course joseph hands is also standing still
and now i try to go to from all i can possibly generate
you can't
you tell me then later how many
of the mountains and valleys you saw
if you see one point that is not moving
that is already the
second of all
the two point moving the moment so if you count four points
but i can do better than
i'm trying to push
you must this resonance
when the system
i lost
i love you
i got one
well for someone
they come on the UIUC
what you said
joseph unites all thirteen right
in some
is also known as
all unreliable
OK so you see
that's the way
that strings behave
and that's exactly the way to strings behave
of musical instruments
here is the string
that we can also
also late
by hand but we can we have a little more here that can make this
part go up and down
and the idea is we going to put it for you in the third harmonic
and the frequency so high in the third harmonic that you can really not see
that this is up
that this is down
goes too fast you could with the others being not here
and so then we are going to struggle with with strobe light
to make you see the
string more or less dense field though not quite but almost
literacy whether we can get into this homologous very delicate we may have to change
the frequency of pretty good
thirty he appointed is standing still
two stand still third harmonic
so the resonance now we call this address it's at its natural frequency
it's driven there
just the right frequency
he goes too fast you cannot see it stands you stand there the fact that
i going to put a strobe light on it
and the strobe light
throws light on it goes on and off on off on off on off with
about the same frequency
about the same we cannot exactly get the same so you're going to see now
the road will stand still or slowly move that's only
of course
optical illusion and reality goes like this
but it makes it we make it look standstill
the way that we
cast light on OK
if you're ready it to michael's
let's see
two and that of their
so i have a green light strobe on
where is the
order lecture one neuron
OK look at that so you see the green
the green
is that a
frequency very close to
the way that the rope is moving and so it looks like
standing still if i i can try to do a little better but it's too
to try to perhaps
no i went in the wrong direction
it's not so important that i hated exactly as long as you get the idea
what i can also do now i can turn it into a work of art
and i can put on the second stroke scope
in red
which i fleshed twice as fast
so it illuminates the role
to one
complete oscillation so you see the robot devil in red
and single ingredient
let's do that now
i have to
do the best i can
five ninety that becomes leaven eighty
to be very close now
the very close
she twice in red is he'd want green
nice to have a human
sure because we cannot exactly
he that there
it's is so therefore you get the phenomenon
very slow
we play with of the green and the red almost see exactly
they coincide
so i can change that very easily by
if we do this in the feature space
it will be equivalent
two modified directly
the gram matrix of the value of the canon metric
OK so
you know that you are so
so i was not completely i don't agree completely with what you see on wednesday
so seriously
overfitting with adaboost several papers actually that
and you must we need to take care of this parameters in order to avoid
overfitting and even in some cases you must change your loss function
it is the same age as of matching in order to avoid overfitting
you have kind of sea was just
there are several reasons instance peter back true
we're going to do this
and so fights for that
it's going to be a little bit more difficult when we're going to look at
what we have we cannot work directly with this five
of y
because we don't have a we have no implicit function
so we are going to use can and cannot do so
at each time
how problem which is defined by
some training input data and some output
a gram metrics
at each time we're going to change run metric
in order to
to capture
it was not predicted well i said previous
their combination
OK so one by
if you want to do this
in the general case
you have
to consider basis function but is research
in the following from
it's all in combination
the function in combination with the weights that depend of x
and so as a m and
he was key to solution
in terms of these
so the residual
only the future output space
OK it's
is it the cases
the moment where
i don't want to let people
OK so remember
adaboost gradient boosting regression
you change
your outputs
each time you want to make relation and visitors
in state of
the true output so
during all the gradient boosting change your output what to this
in our setting is the same but in the feature space
and of course
we have no
two the implicit function theorem
so we're going to do this
with one metrics
can an actress
moreover if we want this to be
particle physics
we have
if we have this
kind of functions
directly of five
i wish i might sedaris then i can go follows is learning
it's possible to do it
to do it
of course the trees
wishing tree that i would
one and just keep things the computation
so we have two stage in this is that with the learning stage
so in the london stage well
it's exactly the same as previously but in some computation three
two or three pages of competition but just linear algebra this year are very complex
each time you want to add some basis rigorous you're going to change from metrics
in such a way that you take into account the fact that previously you eat
some and interfaces to predict
that is sum output
so you you you are just two
to make the computation not
in that case the output feature space that we scanners
it is equivalent to do this competition research
you apply your proof and basilan
which is able to do we can analyse the spaces
you get
in fact this kind of functions
and then you can go on
and you can be tree
so so far you have these
you have been doing
but you are not able to predict
so can you see why we are not able to predict
in fact all the competition and in
was of course and
as for one
i was in feature space but all my functions in terms
thank you
in terms of the so the residuals
and it's not at all what i want
i won't
at least my my
function in them
so true phi
so if i
of y i
so this is possible i want to use the
competition but you can recursively get
get this
and you can rewrite your output always in the feature space by this combination
and then i'm going to talk about the classic cars
well maybe you can say that already
learning our gardens the monte carlo temperature friends and
and some new staff as well
so the learning problem solving learning problems increases the reaction that the and the sum
on all or you can send it sounds because of
the the and the like the next state and reward
in the learning problem you're just given this bunch of samples adar
you've got this samples by interacting with the environment or the just give
and you want to you have to learn a good policy and
then the question shifts a little bit so you can consider t
usually these two problems
are the problem has two sides
so one is computational complexity so you want to have an arrogant and that can
be executed and then it will finish
in your lifetime
so that's one problem the other problem is that you want to have in our
that's able to extract as much information from the samples that is just possible
so you want to have in other words a simple efficient learning
OK and you could have two different cause so one goal is that once you
gutter sound but just want to learn a good policy
and maybe you're interacting with the system but you don't care about the actual costs
during learning
we you want to learn an optimal way are very
plus they are very
she played
so you care about your losses
why are interacting with the system so the second problem is inherently online
the first problem could be offline
OK so
first we are going to consider learning
optimally are learning the fast lane
they're not to
too many designers that we can scale to
be aware and BP's for
for learning
in fast
we are
we will need to to look at the singular cases and we're going to look
at the very famous problem in the bandit problem
and inspired by the many problems are going to look at very briefly at an
the reason target and tries to solve finite mdps and
optimal manner are
just very efficiently
so i guess i'm going to skip this slide because this just
explains the difference between a supervised learning and reinforcement learning but that's
might already be clear to you
reinforcement learning is more general than supervised learning for i
supervised learning problems reinforcement learning problems but
but on the other hand
reinforcement learning problems are because i believe the more and limited feedback there due to
see if i just more difficult than those supervised learning problems
like in the mathematical society
so learning of optimality so that's that's both explore exploit
and so as i said we're going to look into bandit problems
and then into the problem of learning and the kids
imagine that you have two herbs to treatment for some
and you don't know
which one of the two is more efficient
and you want to test them out
how the these
so it's a ensure that we have this two treatments based on the success successful
with this
of course the the goal is to
well maybe this illnesses left and
either you to cure a patient or you lose the patient and of course your
goal is
not to lose too many patients by trying to figure out
which treatment to use
so that makes sense
the question is
imagine that you are in the situation where you already experimented with both of the
treatments quite a few times
to see that treatment and all riders herb is somebody better than the other two
and what the
use that
use the other
you saying
well i believe prior should play any role here so
if i'm trying to sell and are given to
clinical trial company then
was prior should second is the prior of the from c company or is the
prior of the patients are
was prodded should be no prior
so what to do
do you choose
o would go was the treatment
that looks bad
OK that makes sense right so because it works better in the past it should
work but in the future
goal the treatment that just not better
the first one
no one OK
so that's maybe a different problem so in that problem OK
member canada was down here
and we predicted it was what was here
there's they update
just got one here
gothenburg which was way up here
so it's an empirical
evidence the shrinkage
for those astute among you may have
that we lost are
in a sense
supposed to be funny but
so we lost our ass where they go
it went
way after this site so
this is stockholm and it turned out in stockholm
there are many more deaths in the control group
breast cancer deaths then you could have predicted
so it's like you know regression to the mean but then
there's wayne gretzky
udacity cresta the main stock and didn't progress me
on the two thousand nine this thing about brawling over mammography
the task force employed
anne randomized controlled trials to make their recommendation
and the recommendation was the same as the recommendation we made
twelve years earlier
this modelling including one bayesian model
and andy anderson model
andy tell you about the at
on the reactions to the task force recommendation
at the time said
new guidelines
draw opposition
sparked heated debate
globe says breast cancer screening advice appended
and there are lots charges at the time and if you remember death squads
so the charges with this as an obama death squad
keeping women from getting these saving
so these are the models that they used was francis
and cystatin is based on the following
this is the trends in breast cancer
mortality over time it's actually a broken down by race
but you see the whites which is that be the biggest group
the drop is substantial
similarly new came drop between
in nineteen ninety
and two thousand seven was thirty six percent
so what's causing them
andy screening people said this is screening mammography because screening came in
in this period
body treatment people said this is treatment
because screen treatment
got very much better
o including
two marks and including chemotherapy in the same period
so cystatin was a group of seven model is
funded by the and then see eye to
model this process
and we publish our results
in the new england journal
in my favourite
the headline was from sea and and statistical blitz helps spin down mammography benefits
the new york times editorial
these are some of the data we used e everybody opened up there are balls data
the city seedy and see i various other groups
unfortunately we don't have in the united states
uh i
database like they have in scandinavian countries where you can follow the same women over time
to see what happens you know how they were treated i how long they lived
we had only cross sectional data
so we knew who got you know what the proportion of women were the cut marks we knew
you know what their age is wear we knew that screen how frequently they get
screened et cetera but we know the two things together
on this was eight
i had to work hard to get my co authors to understand
and to agree to put this in the paper
this was eh
a kernel
estimates estimation
forty major things that we are addressing this is the reduction in
breast cancer mortality due screening
this is the reduction due to adjuvant treatment
andy we had individual models that were
spread over the board actually they are different
this is model him
framed in this is rochester assessments
georgetown stanford dana-farber
everyone except model him
as a point estimate
and i wanted to convey the variability in the modelling
by taking this rather grows
estimate it shows kind of the negative trend which is sort of expected because
if something is not do screening that there's something else maybe it's treatment
i did the same thing for modeling
because model hamas really many models we do lots of simulations
and we if we if we don't match
mortality then we rejected if we do then we accept that we accept the parameters
that we used to the simulation
so use using bayes rule and in the interesting
not typical
what you can simply write down the likelihood function for example
is it inventing these rules
because what we need is all the sound all logic
and complete
and terminate
so there are various
ways of getting this
and i just thought i
i'll tell you a a little bit more about different systems also we
we haven't finished completeness
if there is no
closedk k tableau for y OK so we're putting the icing on the cake now
so this was soundness
so what's completeness
if there is no closedk tableau for y then y is satisfiable
now closed
fall four
he said
OK so
y twelve
this is not a a blog during its construction
you get a model graph or hintikka said
you get something like w
list and
where each one here is downward saturated hintikka sets
there is a relation between them if these guys hold and you just like this
valuation take it's course
if the atoms in a make it true the is not in eighty you make
it false
crank handle and it'll work for larger formulae
what's the final corollary of in this special case when you let y equal to
not five
i suppose you could be some particular not then it says
there he is not closed
what four not far
not five
he is
k satisfiable
what does that mean that means that there exists some model there there exists a
world which makes not quite true
now what i want of the tell
if there is a closedk tableau for not five
ten five valid
if there is no closedk tableau not five
then phi is not valid
wise final value because it is model which makes it falls
so this is a decision procedure for validity
OK what about logical consequence
remember what we wanted and then calculate was phased introduction
from some set of assumptions
so suppose we
he a lot of what we do
from gamma
if there is closedk tableau form gamma semicolon not
now what i mean by that is that all
we want completeness what we want to say is is there is no
close to teddlie
there is some model
and some world that w makes
all the things in gamma trophy
so i not some world there is a moral
such that the model forces all the things in gamma and
the model forces
does not force
what is construction gave us
right i was
but how do we know
that we still got this camera
OK this is an example there
so the problem is in the k will you start off with here
and i suppose xbox p one
so gamma is this guy
five is the sky
we negate five so we get these
but in negation normal form of these
now we do and diamond jump get this
so these constructions is
he is saturated world which has diamonds
boxes there i need and some other guy
it's like how we're doing a jump to the successor world down here which has
formula without diamond all the axis come along with there aren't any voxel nearly and
is it gets thrown away
now i don't mean know all that this guy
as gamma in because we put it in the beginning just stay there
but when we jumped we lost again
right this guy doesn't make a w node
this guy making all truth
we've got this but we haven't got this
so we've got this time we don't want to be one of the negation
so what you do is a simple trees
of the weak classifiers themselves
so actually when we come back to that question OK because i'm going to say
something about that and then
we're using the same weak learning algorithm
but it's different weak classifiers
so it using the same algorithm to generate a different decision tree and every round
this example they don't this example the air raids
using decision trees often converge to something around thirty forty percent
as they do in this example which means the alpert's are converging to a positive
not necessarily converging but there
intending to stay around positive numbers
well it's way you can think it is discarding them it's more like it's more
like the entire ensemble the entire combination is converging to something is what seems to
be happening
five of
the district ellis
right so how do have to go on the training area zero so we're talking
here about the training area of the combined classifier so
the individual weak classifiers each have
positive area which is usually like thirty forty percent
OK so you can just even though the training of the combined classifier zero
you can continue with boosting is we can continue to reweight examples generate weak classifiers
and so on
that question
OK good so hopefully you're all intrigued by this apparent paradox this apparent contradiction of
occam's razor
a very
well so so
OK so
i'm assuming throughout this talk when talking about generalisation error
that the training data is coming from the same distribution which is generated in the
test data
because otherwise there's really no hope
saying anything theoretical
so i guess i don't have a clear intuition of that but i mean at
this point terms of expecting in terms of expecting this is not what we expect
at this point
right so we don't even understand this picture let alone a picture where we're
the current situation you describe
so the same as for the correct features available to them
we were
we were so weak classifiers we are see the same
so we have
overlaps well i i haven't looked at these decision trees but i would expect that
there would be a lot of overlap between them i mean because we're talking about
two million
decision tree nodes so
you i would expect there would be a lot of overlap between them
it's not very surprising
i mean there's computing completely different functions the features are overlapping but the functions are
completely different in every round
how do we choose the features for c four point five which is flooding
which be OK so we're just using c four point five is the black box
so we're just throwing in all the features that we've been given
i was just letting c four point five doing with things are just using it
as a straight black box
OK we're just running out of boosting exactly the way described
OK right so we've got this
this apparent contradiction with occam's razor
so how can we explain this lack of overfitting
this is a different story that
we told this is work with your friend peter bartlett we suddenly
so the key idea of this
the area this story is that the training year which we've been looking at so
far is only telling us part of the story
it's only measuring which of the training examples are right or wrong
so instead what we want to do
is we also want to consider the confidences of those classifications
so to high level the way the story is going is that with more rounds
of boosting we're increasing the confidences of the training examples so nothing is happening the
training area which is only measuring whether
the predictions are right or wrong
but the confidences with more rounds of boosting are increasing
and those confidences those increases in confidence
are translating into better performance on the test set
so that the high-level argument
that we're putting forward
now to make an argument like that means something we need to have some definition
of confidence
so we measure the confidence of our prediction
this idea of the margin
we've seen i think you've seen a lot of over the last several days
but the notion of margin is a little bit different for boosting
then it is for SVM so let me talk about that here
so remember that the final combined classifier
is just the weighted majority vote of weak classifiers
it's not about
so if you want to measure the confidence
in the outcome of an election in actual election
when you look at is
the margin you look at
the difference between the number of people voting for the
right candidates and the number of people voting for the wrong candidate
so you can decide which candidates are right or wrong for yourself of course but
so we can measure confidence in the same way using margin the margin is the
strength of the vote of those weak classifiers
so just the fraction really this should be the weight in fractions
of the weak classifiers voting for the correct label
minus the weighted fraction
voting for the incorrect label
and that's the definition of margin
so margin under this definition is a real number between minus one in class one
and if the margin is very close to zero and that's the low confidence predictions
if it's a positive number then that means that the weighted majority vote
a weighted majority voting for the correct label so that means the combine classifiers in
the correct predictions
it's a negative number
then that means a majority voting for the incorrect label
which means that this combined classifiers can an incorrect predictions
and if the number is
close to minus one or plus one
that means that very high confidence prediction which might be correct or incorrect
OK so what is the evidence
the margins have anything to do
with better performance on the test set yes questions
the weighted sum of the weak classifiers crafted by the
so to actually be y times backs in the notation i gave earlier
OK so
so there are two forms of evidence that we consider one is empirical evidence and
the others theoretical evidence so let me start with the empirical evidence
about the happen right so for example
on that one had here
this is something that we're trying to figure out what had trainer
as an attempt to approximate generalizations so the notation convention is usually the thing the
hat on top of things we're using test all the quantities
at h had this the hypothesis output by the learning algorithm to try to estimate
what the functions from x to y x y
this actually prove something about work on empirical risk minimization will do well this is
giving us little generalisation which is one here
in order to prove first learning theory result i'm going to state two lemmas are
the first is the union bound
which is the following that that's a one in a they don't want to see
events i mean you events this is of probabilistic event either happens or not
on and these are not necessarily independent
so there's some joint distribution over the events a one through a k and maybe
they are independent maybe not no assumption that
on the probability of a one
o eight two or not
how to write this as the unions involved
i had this just means just set notation but probably just before it's probably have
and one of these events occurring in a one or a two or up to
eight this is
this could probably close
her with her
the intuition behind this is just you know and not should be seen ben diagrams
the pictures are probably before we have and when about to do maybe a little
cryptic so just ignore that just about you haven't seen before we have seen it
before then this is really
you know the
this is really very probably a one union a union three is that have a
one of the two
this the right so that the total loss in the union of these three things
is the to the sum of the masses individuals is not very surprising
it turns out that depending on how you define a axioms of probability this is
this is actually one of the axioms of probability theory so failed
i want to try to prove this is the
is usually
written as as as an axiom says six sigma additivity of probability measures this is
what is sometimes called the flow
in learning theory is commonly called the union bound such as
on november i need hardly have been followed
making i want i want actually prove disastrous fate which is this one of dizzy
i i d
on the random variables with mean five
so this is the only one is equal to phi
let's say you observe an IID bernouilli random variables want to estimate the mean
so then defined by hat and this is game that notation no convention i had
needs and to attempt to is our estimator is an estimator solidifying it had to
be one over the other one says this
our intent the mean he's been using random variables by by so average
and let's any gamma
on prefix
the whole thing inequality on
is that
the probability your estimate of five
is more than gamma away from the true value of phi
the this is bounded by two two gamma
just some pictures
so this theorem holds this period this lemma the have been qualities is just the
statement that this holds true
but then we now draw cartoons to describe some of the intuition behind the test
the same exact this is a real number line from zero to one and so
if i mean if you have any random variables
you remember for you know whatever some undergraduate probability or statistics across the central limit
theorem this says that we have a shallow things together
you tend to get the calcium distribution
and so on when you toss a coin with bias by we observed is linear
in the variables
on any average day then you know the probability distribution
if i had
right well rafi peer gaussianity
it turns out to be a series of was actually the
cumulative distribution function if i have a conversion of the gaussians the technically phi had
only taken to the streets set the values on because these factions one of ramses
doesn't really evidence the but just cartoon figure is the conversion of theta c
so what have been called he says is that if you think about the gamma
that's one interval gamma i guess in the interval gamma
the same that the probability mass the hills
in other words the probability that
my value if i had to small then gamma away from the true value
the total mass
that year
tell the probability mass in these tales is at most two
e to make down the grid
that's what they have to equal
so we can read that this is this is just the right hand side of
the pond to you to to ask
so bounds the probability that you make a mistake in estimating the
random variable
and the
cool thing
about this bound is thinking behind these boundaries that form the easiest explanation the in
to so it says if fixed value gamma
as you increase the size of the training set is it has to climb one