including the start state and next state
but my only what is at the end
so if i start initiative is
zeros everywhere
then in all iteration if you think about it if the most recent if it
is zero all this reward is zero
i just added museo i do all of of competition for so i should not
do that
so the idea is that if you look at that have a self organizing your
computation and so these are given by TSR in my opinion this is the best
good for doing that
so this introduces a priority queue
and put states on the priority queue and science some prior to to the states
and then it also states from the prior to queue then
then it updates the state and it puts the predecessors of the state on the
priority queue and i don't think lf two
two to be specified in talking about these are given
is what's the prior to value
half of the state on the priority queue and this is nothing but
the difference between the all the value of the state and the new way of
the state
so that's that's the value and as target this is really efficient
so the good news is that these are these are given and so
i go into combat and prediction conditions
but still the i mean this very finite world and that could be added the
disturbing to use so
these are given some work if you can imagine the state space and then next
i going to be
how to
how to extend this arguments to the case when
you cannot only the states
so that's
the next four
when talking about the planning problem we have to make a distinction between
a few can so one cases
when you have more than
and you can avoid the transition probabilities and you can create the reward function
so in other words you know everything and
you can pose any questions to to the the mother is black box and you
ask was the transition probability from transitioning from state x to state y and his
the the other cases
you can always sample
and we're going to constables cases
so in the planning problem you're given either p our or you can sample from
and your goal is to find an optimal policy
and you care about computational efficiency that's why what you care
and it turns out that computational efficiency
if you
is the sample of these approaches so
so you
the computational efficiency
will transform into sample efficiency
for obvious reasons so
the number of samples that you have is at least the lower bond and the
number of computations that you want to do so
if it turns out that you need to carry the model
many times
then too many times we too many times
then you are
must be slower i
there exists quite a few methods for planning that are the exact solutions
these on dynamic programming and this is what we have covered so far
and those are only useful for pretty small problems
and already approximate solutions and
there are quite a few approaches that so you could do roll outs and this
is what we are going to consider first we are actually going to
relax the planning problem so we are going to change the problem there
and then there are the is america was that try to be an approximate value
functions and then there are policy search my thoughts and various hybrid models
OK so
i already mentioned first talk about balance curse of dimensionality so was that so
this is the final that the running time of most of the RDF media has
the tendency to scale exponentially
with the dimensionality of the state space around all imagine that the state space is
just the unit cube for euclidean space so to the dimensionality
so the problem is that if you want to that's the first thing would be
to discretize that right
but if you want to discretize at q
that has
you know the dimensions these sites
then how many points they need so
the the
you know
in proc
two of
you know what
point you want
plus lambda times l one norm of the coefficient vector so baby is the vector
of coefficients
and we put in l one norm and
on those and we optimize
combination of residual sum of squares plus lambda times about
as you increase lambda you're forced to go the solution of the coefficients force towards
so what happens
so this is a small example is a predictors
and we start off with lambda very big so all the coefficients are zero
and that's the left part of the plaque here this is the zero line
and each of these curves is the coefficient as we relax lambda
so as we relax lambda the coefficients grow away from zero
and in this case
there's more
n is bigger than p
unrestricted least squares fit is given on the right and we see the path of
the coefficients
so we call that the regularisation path
and it's very useful to have such a path because
at the end of the day
you need to pick the parameter lambda or the bounty
and for the coefficients
so having the whole party
did you mean for picking a sensible values
an awful lot of milieux
cross validation or some measure of prediction errors
to pick the value
but it's useful to have a hope of
so in the case of the lasso
solving this problem just naively to convex optimisation problem requires quadratic programming
and you can
you know that it's it's a fairly easy quadratic programme you can solve the problem
that way and that's originally to solve
but in
in two thousand one
efron and co-authors i was one of the
but if from really discovered
you could solve this problem
a much more efficiently
and the reason was that the coefficient parse profiles or piecewise linear
so if you look at this picture you'll see you can see the piecewise linear
parts and each of the vertical lines indicate the breakpoints as it changes
and that led to the what is known as the lars algorithm for solving this
this was convicted this whole part of
to summarize
you can compute the entire party
in the same computations as the single least queries for
so that's very efficient essentially unique there's the computation needed for each of the steps
so that later
you'd speedups in
computing the
so that is called the laws algorithm the names rather obscure sense for least angle
and as i said UTF
and that's what happened and so that was in two thousand one
and that in turn led to
to a you'd flood of path algorithms for all kinds of different regularisation problems
the idea that you can get the entire solution path
was very attractive
and because in any problem we regularisation
you need to compute the solution many points and see if you can compute the
whole path efficiently that is a very attractive thing
this is a list of some of the examples there's lots more
this is the biased because you see my name is is the the names of
my students in a lot of these
but the first one the group lasso this is for the case where a
we variables and actually come in groups we'll talk about that little bit later
one london two thousand six they develop the possible
four support vector machine
the cost parameter in the sort support vector machine is the a tuning parameter regularisation
and it turns out there is a piecewise linear path
for the solutions of the support vector machine as you vary the cost parameter
and that was very with with
some of my students and tibshirani
two thousand four
we'll talk about the elastic net
later on in the talk quantile regression leong yew
logistic regression and generalized linear models
my student union park
and more recently the dantzig selector that's the work of kansas and tell
so says
a different approach
to the let's use the criterion slightly different but the solution is very similar
this is the context of
signal processing and sparse representations
other extreme the mind
gareth james and and this doc
the village possibilities for that
so these all pass algorithms and this has become a little
many craze in statistics to develop of for four for the next problem you can
come you know that that you can
the problem is not
many of them don't enjoy the piecewise linearity of lars of
that made the laws are especially to compute the path very efficiently
four lot of these that some of them
two piecewise linearity like the support vector machines
and the group lasso
solutions but this is perhaps most famous these two tables
so what's what's the illusion here well
let's ask you to make a judgement similar to the kind of judgement next which
is a judgement just about what you see here on the plane
so let's take these two lines meticulously this the this some
the edge of the stable
and they said that table and the question is which one is longer just here
in the plane this one or that one
the right one
anyone want to the left one
is there another answer
the same so some people have already generalize from the one example that when people
show you visual illusion the correct answer is always the same
that's right
they are the same here
just to convince you that i will do my version of like what what nick
did which is show you a powerpoint build up here there's a
you know an outline i drew
on that guy
i haven't done this and so i switched to the new version of powerpoint so
anyone how to rotate
little green saying OK
so you can see no tricks you must have actually literally had powerpoint
but really is
the very same shape the whole table is the same shape in the plane yet
in the context of the scene
makes makes them look very different as two-dimensional shapes so what's going on here well
you know it's all the stuff that nick was talking about
in this
the problem
the problem is ambiguous
the interpretation of the image because there are multiple ways the three d world could
be that would give rise to the same two-dimensional image falling onto retina onto this
plane here
so that's what the that's the problem that's the sense which we're trying to solve
in inherently ill posed under constrained problem right i mean just mathematically the world is
three-dimensional the retinal images two-dimensional so of course you losing information and in principle that
an infinite number of three-dimensional geometry that could be compatible with anyone two-dimensional projection not
to mention all the other complexities that come from the clues in in the way
light interacts surface properties and so on
so how do you how do you solve an impossible problem how do you work
backwards from the two d image to the three d
structure out there well
our best guess is that the brain makes a good guess it's also kind of
statistical inference problem from a bayesian point of view there's some hypothesis space world structures
and some prior and by putting probabilities in the right way that corresponds to in
now in full detail the correspond just enough to the way the world is it
while still allowing tractable inference then that's that's going to be the form of the
by studying what the mind is here right it's not really getting it wrong it's
getting it right in the sense of the using the kind of logic needed to
solve the real-world problems that doesn't involve looking at this image is displayed on a
flat computer screens but involves trying to solve the analogous problem of discovering the three
d structure of the world from the image comic coming on here right now
now what is concurrent computer vision which
which does rely very heavily on the kind of learning techniques that have long been
developed in statistical machine learning things like for example perceptron support vector machines PCA dimensionality
various boosting these kinds of methods which you've probably heard about to hear more about
in this summer school cannot solve these kinds of scene analysis problems well here's an
example from great paper by some of my MIT colleagues
choi lim
torralba and willsky
i think it was just accepted to CVPR two thousand ten so it's state-of-the-art it's
uses a very large number of different learning based approaches it learns detectors for many
classes of real world objects like for example people roads so first
and not only that it also has a notion of context this particular paper is
trying to show how you can put together the result of bottom-up detectors which are
trained using boosting very simple kind of the very powerful supervised learning methods but also
put together some kind of top-down scene context and here the point of this figure
of course as you see this so far in the middle of the road and
its anomalous and their their models able to say
to that anomalies still recognise it is so for the but say that's kind of
violation of context so so here's the input and here's the output
with this very nice
method well
to what extent so what the method does it draws few boxes around some regions
in the image and puts words on the road so for person person person with
confidence now that to some extent approximates what you see when you actually look at
this input but how closely does approximate how how close to the richness of what
you see here to discuss
well on a scale from sort of here to here
i would say it's about human rights definitely a step in the right direction but
just think about all the things you could say here all the things you could
describe all the questions you can answer all the richness of surfaces in the end
and different layers of depth that you see you see these windows here this is
sort of a glass window you see
the car slightly bent and distorted there you don't think there's weird band car inside
that building but rather reflecting something across history all these inferences going unconsciously you're just
as nick was saying we knew consciously introspect what you get is the output of
the computation
but the but the richness of that output should tell us a lot about what
might and maybe even what has to go on a long way from here to
now let's turn to an example which is close to some of the work i
do this is this is from an experiment in our lab where we were inspired
by another kind of problem of
inference and generalization children learning concepts learning the meanings of words anybody who's been a
child or had a child it's easier to see this if you
are looking at somebody else doing this rather than being in the moment yourself
it should be familiar with the experience of word learning and the remarkable thing there
how few examples it takes to learn the meaning of the word so a child
might learn what which areas is or what forces producing one or a couple of
examples labeled in the right contexts and then they can pretty much pick out all
all the other forces they might make an occasional confusion seeing how
you know down the field in the same farming including that of course and the
parents say no no that's account
right but they're are not going to be calling the fence post horse or mum
three years
some of
two of my
have you been
early on
there are many are
because these
this page
i mean er
or they may
in the paper
you know
all right well
we all
i am with the department of computer science and department of statistics at university of toronto so
and by the way as i go through the tutorial
please feel free to ask questions you know this is gonna be
you know partly informal
what i'm hoping to cover his that's i'm hoping to cover a lot of different applications
that's we've seen
some of the successful applications and in deep learning
but also
i give you a little bit of theoretical foundations behind these algorithms right in particular we focus on
graphical models and such
so hopefully what you'll get out of this tutorial is just a little bit of
math behind these algorithms as well as a
different applications that that
that people are using wikipedia just start by saying that you know my area
of research machine learning and it's a very exciting area and i know a lot of people here traded
also experts in in machine learning but it's kind of a very
dynamic field right if you look at different areas like computer vision
natural language processing information retrieval speech recognition
robotics computational biology coming sciences right a lot of these
fields are using
machine learning
what's exciting is that's
you know in the last few years if you look at the space of data that we have
right you can easily get access to images and videos text-to-speech
if you look at
i'm product recommendation out companies like netflix and d and was on
well if you look at social network data or even if you look at scientific data
right it's it's a lot of data
but i would say that most of the data that we see today is unlabelled
it's basically that means that's you know i can get millions of images of the web
but i might not have labels for those images as
precise description as the what's going on in those images
so one of the things that we try to do it in particular in deep
learning community is is trying to develop models that can deal with unlabeled data or
models that can discover structural discovered some statistical dependencies from from the data and how
that can be done in unsupervised
without labels or semi supervised we have partially labeled data
and also it's interesting you know in machine learning with sort of obsessed with developing
algorithms that can work across multiple application domains
and i'll show you some of
some of the examples of debt
what i would argue is that's you know
models that can
do these things as one particular framework of doing this is building these deep hierarchical models
and deep learning models models that can support inferences was discovered structure multiple levels of
representation right now make it more precise as i go up through the tutorial of
of what i mean by that
but let me show you could be before i start going into you know the
definition of the models and not go through the tutorial but show you some of
these examples right
this is one particular model m
it's called the boltzmann machine model
and what you're trying to do he's basically trying to model images of
trying to model distribution over those images right side of the model can recognise airplanes cars trucks and such
and because this is a generative model what you can do is you can simulate
from the model or generate data from the model so if i'm asking the malta
sort of
tell me what it believes images of airplanes should look like
this is the model generating images of airplanes and the flickering that you see at
the top these are the states of the latent variables are hidden variables
right so it's kind of like discovering what airplane should look like so you can
see that goes from one plane to another plane
you know i argued at
sort of has some understanding of far
you know what what we should look like
now the interesting thing about this model is that there is no image-specific priors sitting
in these models the motives looks that
you know ninety six by ninety six images
in figures out what the point should look like
if you look at
no other kinds of data sets this an interesting dataset this data set was collected
at the mitzi u have about twenty five thousand characters from fifty different alphabets and
and if you look at these characters you know you have arabic have serial you
have sanskrit
right and the model has about three thousand latent or hidden variables over two million
parameters and then you can ask the model to
let's see what the image is of sanskrit should look like right
and this is the model simulating what it believes images of sanskrit should look like
they typically ask your new seceded do these look like sanskrit
i see right
yeah i have no idea how supposed to look like a but
this is what the model believes
a satellite images should look like
and this is useful for doing things like recognizing characters right now doing character recognition
you can also do interesting things like batting completion right so for example if i
give you half of the input
and i ask the model to simulate the remaining half
right this is what the model that's
again there's no image specific prior not telling them all at you know they should
be strokes they should be continues
right the model just looks at
thirty thousand different characters and just figures out what character should look like
so why why building these models is
is is challenging well
if you look at the simplest possible model right this is just a twenty by twenty eight image
it's binary image right
but if you look at the space of all possible characters right the space of
all possible images you could generate well it's due to be um twenty by twenty
eight a to to the seven eighty four possible configurations
right so obviously doing it
idea the brute force methods is is gonna be challenging so we have to rely
on some approximate algorithms and we'll see some of those algorithms
in this tutorial
you can also the interesting thing about this was that you can also apply to other kinds of data
so if you're looking at bag-of-words representation and this is just taking him
documents and representing them as word counts
if you take reuters dataset has about eight hundred thousands
web pages and you say well how can expect structure from the data
if i look at the high level
representations this is what the model is discovering
right so i'm just basically
there are no labels i'm just fitting the model a bunch of different web pages and asking it to
the discovered latent structure and this is what is discovery
it's interesting to see that
and i don't see how you teach them
you can only learn actually by experience
having said all that
i still think
that actually
the real that's the matter
is all the things that i've seen is teach
even the best business schools in the world i have been around to many
are useful i don't think they're useless
i think they're useful
that are not the most important things
i to be honest some of the graduates of our business schools in britain and
in america and in europe
i made a pretty ugly mess of a lot of capitalism
in recent years
they both capitalism to distribute
they've ripped us off
look at the banks have been doing this for some of the terrorist people in
our society
and they just lost their way
because i have been very concerned seems to me
and what they have learned about the how of things
sometimes about what all things you know
how does the business work we teach what sometimes we teach what does the business
we very seldom asked why
and i think that's a great shame
business leaders talk about what they do they make money
but they don't answer
in public why
they make money we basically
we make money with that governments and businesses
and indeed as individuals in order to we may do more
with that money to do more things
produce more things
different things
the government
we want the economy to grow so that we can actually build more hospitals built
more schools
we raise more taxes so that we can do more things with them
alas we do not talk about those things enough
we do not talk about the whole idea of business leaders get up and they
boast about having made so much money for that company onolysis industry say look at
these greedy people
they're making money for themselves and not making money for themselves but they do not
so to us it was very exciting recently in our last
two actually interview
and photographs
the people that we call
the new philanthropists
these are people who had
run their own businesses
and how in the end and so the businesses or has got very rich
and had decided to do something useful with the money
as one of them said to me he said charles
now i know why i make money
so that i can use it
on something useful for others
now spends use it
in other words he had suddenly found the y
although he did with his work
not enough people get
but to help her
find y
we decided
two just east to compile a still life
but still life
basically as designed and it's and developed by elizabeth my photographer partner
it is basically a collection of five objects and the piece of nature that resemble
represent what is terribly important to you
in life
this is my still life
by the time it and i'll tell you what it means what i want to
tell you about
is an experiment
that we did recently in claremont university peter drucker is business school
i was asked to be the first
distinguished drucker scholar trying to keep track tradition going over internment and this with an
i toward the course
an elective courses
we limited to ten people
are we had in the end for
executives d one
serial entrepreneur aged about sixty we had to MBA students two h two two phd
students and two members of faculty which is quite encouraging and what we are still
to do
the period this force which lasted five weeks
but the compiler personal still lives
to represent what was important to them in life
and then to do one for their organisation
to see how they compare
and and then to do what a third one
for the organisation as they would like it to be
and i have to tell you it was fascinating
because we're talking here about what's important about values
and actually
much more revealing
the words
because images contain a story behind
and the stories tend to have different levels of meaning
this images
you can use your imagination
which was
richard doll things really
unless they conjure up pictures
i would tell you just about one of these guys
he just bought
a business
this was the travel business it was
what he called a spiritual travel business in other words it took people around the
world to places
with spiritual connotation you cathedral monastery
a special holy place and a lot of americans
thomas with other people to like to do this sort of thing
he produced is still life
of the business which was dominated
by big model boats
because the founder of the business
and originally taken people around the globe
government officials right how can i sort of solicit citizen feedback about certain let's political
issues right so what are the issues that are being raised what what aspects let's
say of building congress is popular what is unpopular and so right so so one
one notion here is to understand what is what is the population thinking and we
will see some of these examples later later in the story right again that would
be very nice industrial park about how well how can you data mining for political
campaigns how do you how how do you figure out why in which people support
the candidate that was a nice article in new york times about law enforcement sort
of mining social media data sending police to the crime scene before the crime happens
and so on so what imagination here can get one but the idea is right
that sort of social media in some sense is the sense human lives we want
to mind that to get to get some useful data and other applications that that
is also interesting is what is called a real-time citizen journalism right the idea is
that people that use it and so on it provides real time and very valuable
information about particular events right and the of course the challenge is how to aggregate
this little little sets of this many redundant posts users who have made to locate
useful information right so the goal here and i want to mine this real-time data
to produce well organised summaries of events or i want to detect events and so
and of course another
the relatively straightforward sort of straightforward area of application is viral marketing right understanding how
influence spread recommendations how they spread through social networks i can start making personalized recommendations
i can all start
my in online forums and there have been studies that sort of show the people
that the users of online forums and sort of advocating brands online also advocated the
offline source of eighty percent of forum contributors friend that if had their friends and
people online make decisions about product purchases and so on so there's a lot of
sort of this enthusiasm about brands and so on the people share so by by
mining this online data we may get some insights about these
and the last the last bit of thing is what it means sort focus in
the second part of the the story is how to process led social media content
to provide tools to identify social networks identify groups often of course of
in the network or identify tightly knit communities how to connect that it let's say
evaluations topic sentiment analysis and so on so sort of this second application this this
this current slide this is what we will talk after the coffee break what i
mentioned the applications i mentioned before we resort to be more related to the to
the first part of the tutorial so here is here is as i said that
the goal for the borealis introduced methods for social media analytics i structured fully deployed
in two parts the first part of the how do we reason and the race
and the model the flow of information networks
the idea will be here in particular to lead to predict how popular how much
attention to a particular piece of information get over time we will do and then
maybe even like when should i place pieces of information so that they they become
popular and then the second part of the story will focus on interactions and social
network structure so the idea here it will be that you want to go beyond
beyond the reasoning about there is a link between a pair of nodes people there
is no link to maybe start thinking what people think about one another trying to
predict outcomes without seeing what people decided to do in particular cases and so on
right so the idea here would be to go beyond just people are connected by
poverty is OK so as i said the first part three parts with the first
one to be how to collect how do we collect data and how can be
sort of like the flow of information online
the second part will then be about modelling and predicting the flow of of let's
say items
information in the last part will be about how do we infer networks of information
flows because these networks and many times he the music
OK so that's basically the idea
and i will keep going right so
the idea is the following right so if i have a little a social media
platform site or just in general right information flows through its right so what i
want to do is i want to analyse
underlying mechanisms for the real time spread of information in this online networks and the
questions that i like to address in the next hour and fifteen minutes is how
does how the messages spread through social networks how to predict the spread of these
messages or information in these networks and how to identify how to sometimes even identify
networks or something worse
so most of the data that i will be talking about is coming from
a company called called spin it's small startup in san francisco and the basically collecting
online social media data so today there are getting around
forty five million articles per day
and they been collecting these data since august two thousand eight and basically what you
get is pretty much everything that google news has that is about twenty thousand news
sources plus
i think four million blogs and online forums and lots of twitter and facebook posts
why mentioning this is because you can go to this URL and actually been is
making some data available for free to academics you you can download it another good
reference for social network data is it real website for our website that is down
there so snap stanford edu we are making around sixty large social and information networks
available online for people to use OK so
we have some data that will be working with here the data is then sold
millions of articles per day
and the first question for us to understand what sort of the basic units of
information so what are the pieces of information that propagate through this let's call them
equal structure
if you look at whether or you look at most phenomenon
the power law is not what you're looking at structure is this is the structure
of an isolated thing comes some of them have powerful but it's
it's a it's not so much
now the problem not always mean structure in fact in many
in the particular situation of economics many of the problems that of of fluctuations in
the market and in fact is the analogue of the boltzmann law in physics in
fact there is an expression of maximum around on what exactly is this one and
in fact they can be put in court in in common in
relation with the
efficient market hypothesis which obviously is safe that the OK so in in effect here
yes in this respect there is agreement
so what really
is assumed
being made in general with one
in a
and there are really only the about five
and on the
a weighted average age
so that's not far
according to one million
can be that we need to be
so although this is far
so in a way a market economy
in the same
one we do
a lot of the problem is
the economy fell
he won the day of relational data
you can do
i mean it a lot more
it is before the
is that
two great
before in many more
the above the
man is there are more
that means that
you can have money for any of the
is shown to i one
you might
from the
my question is
that you
the problem is that the in really good
you don't need
any kind of
my you can use
i four
you can buy
changes course
why it goes
one thing to be the patient through well
it can
is important
it's important that only
only a few months
but the
you should
using the money
are there
so we see that there is what
and at the in
to go out of
you only
you know
there are two
to a great
they represent the images
well that
i a
is any
are there and
there you will by using
it also possible
to use my drawing only
that very day if you run
there was a or i
we've done in
is that
was it
after that you have to go for a moment has over five in the morning
or they have to go on
the same
that is that if really
there is no one so you really
if you use
my rule do
the first of may
excuse me for instance so
it's to represent the data thank
so a year they use
on that is the agent they
because of this
this is
later that day
the very
two through data feature
so if use c
in this play
the other issue
after a
you can our love
that is that
the string comes
this is what i just said
this is a typical query
finally in casualties corporation missus and jet engine discoloration and is located on component that
i give you
this is the level of semantics but also
i wanted to pronounce
the information comes from is the text contains somewhere
so we have the triples that have distracted
i got to the next day they derive from and so what the whole documents
must contain blatant and also
whatever is annotated
as something as component contains trailing edge
so the this is the
you see there are different levels which you can come by and it is possible
to show
that any
of the
different paradigms from providing can be adapted to do this extended to do this
let's try to put everything together and then i think you go to the conclusions
we had to pass through the
one of the many tasks we've done for also in the producer's chair manufacturers such
jet engines was to extract information from eighteen thousand documents
there are many forms
they were all different shapes but continued more or less the same information with thousands
of forms different forms
we had an ontology developed by the university of aberdeen
we try to train the system to do information extraction from the tables
we selected the
we use active media to train and two two
annotate hundreds of documents and then use machine learning a form of direct it is
to be developed and then we picked up all the pieces of information we could
identify with an accuracy was more than ninety five percent
so all these go to ninety percent
then we have developed tool for searching for a search
it enables both document creating and knowledge creating including graphics of knowledge so the quantification
and we have
testing the through the means and on the document itself using queries to the users
have centers and also with real users
now if you look at the accuracy
for every query in the first twenty hits
so we look at the twenty first of the first twenty documents returned to see
that for keywords in terms of precision recall if you know what it means is
basically fifty percent in this case so fifty percent accuracy
if you talk about the ontology based pure ontology base of high precision
because consisting of data properly
a lot of queries are not covering so you can't query so have low recall
but if enabled people to use hybrid search
you actually go something like eight percent eighty four percent precision eighty four percent percent
accuracy so you have the best two words
so then we gave it to the thirty two
you're looking at me two minutes
twenty four minutes started
but always g
so well
he gave it to thirty two years as they
test for quite a while and then we'll easy to the internet on the internet
and we wanted to understand if people could use semantic search for people to use
the hybrid paradigm
well you have to search
in what turned out to these days every night data to the really what the
fact that the system was faster
it was actually easy to use so they understood that to the concept of semantic
search engines
the fact that you can
integrated with keyword somehow
i felt that year the system was curator
the very acurate and it was
more life easy o
pretty easy to
then two years
but in the end it doesn't tell us if they will use it for that
system for their everyday work actually
what happened is that this system was voted for the two thousand seven rolls royce
director's creativity award it is an award
voted by
c or
proposed to be to by senior employees to the directors
it is
given to technologies that have the potentiality of
a disruptive potentiality within the company is a very large company and we were finally
out of three we didn't win
but also this was the knowledge management tool the other way about the core technology
of building jet engines so we think it's very good results and they also have
both sides of what both sides of this equation written in standard form and both
sides so it's going to be 1 over X and Y prime minus 1 over
X squared and Y is equal to x squared times 1 over X which is
simply xxx
now if you have done the work correctly you should be able now to integrate
the left hand side directly so I'm gonna write it this way I always recommend
that you put in as an extra steps of well unable to put it put
in as an extra step the reason for using the integrating factor in other words
the left hand side is supposed to be now
1 over X times Y
but but
I always put in that because there's always a chance you made a mistake or
forgot something to look at it and mentally differentiated using the product rule just check
that in fact it is turns out to be the same as the left hand
side so we get 1 over X times Y prime plus y times the derivative
of 1 over X which indeed is negative 1 over X squared
and now finally
that's a continue to do the integration so you going to get this if do
on 1 board 1 over X times Y is equal to M X plus a
constant exercise x squared over 2
plus a constant and the final step will be there for right now what I
want to isolate why by itself so why
will be equal to multiply through by x x cubed over to
policy context of but of solution
OK let's do 1 a little slightly more complicated
you this try this 1 now my equation is going to be 1 also keep
to y and x is the variables well values to in a minute 1 was
cosine acts so I'm not going to give you this 1 in standard form you
the the trick question of why prime minus sign X times Y is equal to
anything reasonable I guess that I think that was exciting to x
of many more exciting OK now
I think I should warn you what where the mistake for are just so that
you could make all of them so this the state number 1 you don't put
it in standard form mistake number 2
but that generally people can do step 1 fine but mistake number 2 is you
don't know This is my most common mistakes on very sensitive to it but that
doesn't mean if you make it you'll get sympathy for me I don't get separately
to myself
years so intent and so happy having found the integrating factor you forget to multiply
fueled by the integrating factor also you just handle the 2nd in the left hand
side of the equation and you forget about the right hand side of the both
the emphasis on the both theory is the right hand please include the Q please
include the right hand side of the mistakes are well nothing that I can think
of well maybe only when I can make any mistakes the rest of this lecture
so what we do we write this in standard form so it's going to look
like white prime minus sign x sign x divided by 1 . cosine x times
y equals my heart sinks because I'm I know so molten integrate something like this
and boy that that that's going to give me problems OK well
not yet so what's the integrating factor integrating factor is what we want to calculate
the integral of negative
sign x only 1 + comes that's the integral of PBX and after that we
have to exponentiated well can and you do that if you have if you stare
at a little while you can see that the top is provided is the derivative
of the body that is great than integrates to be the log of 1 was
cosine x is the right
1 over 1 plus cosine x times the derivative of this which is negative cosine
therefore the integrating factor is
lead to that in other words it is one plus cosine Iike therefore so this
was Step 0
the step 1 we found the integrating factor analysis step 2
we multiply through by the integrating factor and what do we get we multiply through
the standard form equation but the integrating factor and if you do that which again
well why prime gets the coefficient 1 . cosine x and y prime minus sign
x equals to x
well I hope somebody would giggle at this point was giggle about it well that
all this was totally wasted work called spinning your wheels now it's not spinning your
wheels it's doing which is supposed to do on and finding out that you wasted
the entire time doing what you were supposed to do
well we get in other words the net effect of this is to end up
let's go with a crazy we have
you see we have
he calls and g
and then we get minus
the this the force
and the resistive force as term the
and as the term in his square and
you see the MV squared
so this cannot be solved analytically
but i asked my graduate students they fully
who is one of your instructors to solve this for me
and i'm still going to show you the results
that he prepared is a nice view graph you can see the effect
of time
ball if you drop it from
three metres
all the numbers are that is on the web don't copy anything
you have the values for c one and c two are given at the top
you may not be able to see them from you see that they are there
and what you see here
height above the ground as a function of time this is one second is one
and a half seconds which is the three million mark
if there were no and drag remember we drop an apple early on
from three meters it will hit the floor
about seven hundred eighty millisecond
however with the and red
it will be about one second later more like one point eight
seconds so point seven wasn't bad as you see but if you look here
that's how the
build up as a function of time
you see it takes about three four tenths of a second
to build up
terminal speed which is the one point eight meters per second that you have there
needless to say of course that the acceleration
gravity does not remain constant but goes down very quickly
and when the acceleration
reaches approaches zero
then you have terminal speed
and then there's no longer any change
in the
so let's try this
give more light
we are going to throw subject and i don't think you're going to get one
point eight seconds you may
get something that is larger than one point eight seconds
and the reasons i the following number one
this is not a perfect sphere
and only for years
these calculations hold that's number one number two this thing is very springy
so the moment and let it go it probably goes in some kind of oscillation
that doesn't help either that will probably also slowed down
because what causes of course this slow down
in regime two is really turbulence turbulence is extremely hard to understand and predict
and so almost anything i do
i will only had turbulence
and therefore i predict that the time that it will take from three meters will
be probably larger than one point eight seconds
but it
will be substantially larger than the seven hundred eighty million seconds
which is what you would have seen if you drop an apple
so let's see how close
we are
two all this time
thank you i zero
i did
not too easy to releases by the way and start time at the same moment
it's not even so easy for me to see when it hits the ground
but as a huge uncertainty in this
three two one zero
what do we see
i see something to point zero not bad
the prediction was one point eight
you get two point zero
there's no better than sixty and wrecked into account and it's not even an approximation
it uses the entire
linear in v as well as
the square but it's almost exclusively
dominated by the descriptor
i also as they
to show me what happens when i throw a pebble
of the empire state building
and the petal
that we chose was a radius of one centimeter kind of
all of us could find no reference to density of pebbles
and with the throne of the empire state building we reach a terminal speed
of about seventy five
whilst body
without the correct we would have reached two hundred and twenty five miles
but our
i want to show you that two
now you see the empire state building which has a height of four hundred seventy
five metres
that's where you start t zero this one second five seconds ten seconds five seconds
fifteen seconds
and if there had been no and we're hit the ground
a little less than ten seconds
it will hit the ground more like
sixteen seventeen seconds
and you see that the
terminal speed built up
in about five six seconds
very close to the final value
and if there had been no and
the speed at which it will hit the ground
course grow linearly
when it hits the ground it would be somewhere here which is two hundred and
twenty five miles
our so you see that even the pebble
you wouldn't expect to be
they have a large effect on and make it huge provided that you throw it
from a
high building
now you may remember
that we dropped an apple
from three metres
and that we calculated
gravitational acceleration
given the time it takes to fall was one of your
one of the things you did in your assignment
we had seven hundred eighty one millisecond scifi
and i know that you can calculate genes
right because you know to three meters is one have gt squared
so i give you the three which uncertainty i give you the time seven hundred
eighty one millisecond was an uncertainty of too many seconds which we allowed
our property
so i believe what is the effect of and drag
on this apple
is it was the responsible thing for us
ignore that
the apple
has a
of hundred thirty four grams
easy to way of course
this was our apple
during our first lecture
and is hundred and thirty four grams
is almost the sphere really not quite but almost the sphere and the rate is
about three centimeters
and that leads to a terminal
velocity which you can calculate if you want to
using the
this criterion but i was not interested in that
i wanted to know
harmony millisecond
is the touchdown delayed because of the brain
and they've made the calculations and he found
that's too millisecond form three meters from one-and-a-half metres it's almost nothing
and the reason why is almost nothing from one-and-a-half metres you see
when you throw
and appl
is really in regime two
so you really dominated by
the speed square
and the first one and a half million doesn't get a very high speed speed
grows linearly and so does the last portion
where you really get hit by the a by the script
too many seconds
from three metres
three eight
three metres
there's too many second
let's call it delay
so we have on the area of being lucky unlucky
if you really want to calculate the gravitational acceleration using our data you should really
subtracted too many seconds
from the time on the other hand
since we are allowed to say to millisecond uncertainty we really weren't
very well in the first example
i was hoping for an average of about seventy five
class average was eighty nine
so that leaves us with two possibilities
you are very smart
this is an exceptional class
or the exams
it was too easy
now these examples taken
three instructors
way before you took
none of them thought it was too easy so i'd like to think that you
are really an exceptional class and like to congratulate you
that you did so well
here is a histogram
of course
if we had to decide on this test alone
getting you cruises forgetting your homework on this test along
the dividing line between pass and fail to sixty five
that means that
five percent of the class
would fail which is
unusually low we normally that is around
fifteen percent
time will tell whether you are indeed exceptionally smart
or whether the exam was too easy the good news also is
two pieces of good news
that we promise that the books will arrive
at the coop
today we're going to talk about
this brings about pendulums and about
simple harmonic oscillators one of the key
topics in
o eight o one
if i have a spring
this is the relaxed length of the string
i call that actually zero
and i extend the string which point was he
then there is the force
i want to drive
this spring back
the equilibrium
and it is an experimental facts
that many springs we call the ideal springs
for many springs this force
two the displacement
this is x
if you make x
three times larger than restoring force
is three times larger
this is the one dimensional problem so to avoid the vector notation we can simply
say that the force
is minus
a certain constant which we call the spring constant
this is called the spring constant
and the spring constant has units newtons per meter
the minus sign takes care of the direction
when x is positive
then the forces in the negative direction when f is negative the forces in the
positive direction
it is a restoring force
whenever this linear relation between f and x holds
that is referred to
as we explore
how can we
measure the
spring constant that's actually not too difficult
i can use gravity
here is the spring
it's relaxed situation
i hang on the spring
mass and
and i make use of the fact
the gravitino
exerts a force on the spring
when you factor new equilibrium this is the new equilibrium position
then the spring force
of course must be exactly the same as and
no acceleration when the thing is addressed
and so i could now make a lot
i could have px
and i could have here
this course f which i know because i know the masses i can change the
i can go through a whole lot of them
and you will see data points which scatter around a straight line
and the
spring constant follows then
if you take
call this delta f
you call this
delta x
in the spring constant k
is delta have divided by
in fact so you can even measure it you don't have to start necessarily
at this point where the spring is relaxed you could already start
when the spring is already
under tension that is
the problem
you'd be surprised how many springs really behave very nicely
according to lord
i have one year it's not very expensive
spring is here here
and it is here hold
on it so it's already a little bit under stress
it doesn't make any difference
this marks here i thirteen centimetres apart and every time i one kilogram of
you will see
that it goes down by roughly fifteen centimetres
goes down to this mark
i put another kilogram of
put another kilogram on
and it goes back to this mark
all the way down
and if i take them all also so what i've done is i've effectively went
along this curve
and if i take them off
if it is an ideal spring
it goes back
to its original length
which it does
that's a requirement of course for an ideal spring
it behaves according to law
i can of course over two things
i can take a spring like this one
and structure to the point that it no longer behaves like hooks law
i can damage it
i can do a prominent
look that's easy
we're sure workflow is no longer
look how much longer this spring is than it was before
so the comes of course limit how far you can go
you permanently before the spring
what i have done now is that spring
probably in the beginning i went up along the straight line
and then
something like this must have happened
i got a huge extensions
my fourth did not increase very much
and then when i relaxed when i took my force off
the spring was longer at the end
it it was at the beginning so i happen next
extension which will always be there
and that's not very nice of course to do that
two spring so law holds only within certain limitations you have to
o a certain amount of
there are ways that you can also
measure the spring constant
in a dynamic way
which is actually very interesting
i have here
and this spring
this is actually equals zero
is that is very small
and we got the idea that
so what we found was that the chinese
you see
these row
the people as
so basically it this is hundred problem it
mentions concept
this is one of several villages it presents
fifty percent this owned
willie and sentences
you don't
different cases all all the data points
the same instances
one k
the whole
is also used and is caused by this is the
so this and so the idea is that since so you know this is a
very small
he is large she will be reduced
changes for these things we want to along
who's who
this no
you to what is
so for example
so that for example you see very different from what it is
on this
so you don't
so he was sent
we did
that is
it tends to do best and it
so that was very
what was one of
it was a lot smaller
so what find
what's more
predicting this
this is the
there actually that of course is an image
the international space that's
you have one
one of the biggest one is
but not much more
his unit was you know
there are five
so we see to be to measure distance to as well
you all
the status quo
the best one
so that was of this all this one is
he calls on this
one is
this is months
i was in the international space station wonderful
it is here
the actually
across the
that is
so you actually is
is is that it is
it's fun
what about is
so this is constructed outside city hall
as are
so that was one of the ten rays
exactly does
you know who
put a bit more mass around
a third third third
that's setting up data there's slate ten ten ten distribution
put a lot of mass around the thirty third third
and by varying the different alpha as we can get it to put mass in
different parts of the space so you is that there are actually two ten two
which has a mean
value for data to
of ten over fourteen
which is somewhere
you know quite high
around here
a lot of mass here
this one was a lot of mess here and if you choose your parameters of
the dirichlet distribution to be less than one
alpha is less than one
put mass at the corners of this distribution so they take away message from the
this distribution
so hopefully you now have a bit of a sense of what the dirichlet distribution
and obviously
when you add up the actual healthy ends to your original out first what you
get is the posterior over the parameters that becomes a dirichlet distributions that the sharper
and sharper
centered around the frequency
the average frequency with which you you observe any particular settings of the variables
so here is just an example let's imagine that we started out with the do
actually one one one distribution
this corresponds to a uniform prior distribution over the parameters data
and how to say this isn't a very strong dogmatic prior
since any parameter setting is assumed a priori possible
remember it's important to realize when you do bayesian inference there isn't any right prior
you don't have to worry about getting the right prior all you have to worry
about is getting a reasonable prior a prior that isn't too dogmatic that doesn't
it doesn't say
that certain values of the parameters are impossible for example
once you have a reasonable prior like that then as you observed more and more
data your posterior will converge to close to
maximum likelihood parameters
in the limit
i'll talk about those sorts of issues may be in the last lecture we can
have a bit of
discussion about bayesian methods in general
after observing a data set d where the
what are the parameter posterior distributions well
it's very simple
the posterior distribution over
the table entries theta i j a dog
are just dirichlet a with the number of counts in
in that role of that particular table plus one
OK since one was the original office that we start out with
and and so what is this predict this predicts for future data
the probability of observing valuable alliance state k given that his parents are state j
and having observed the dataset the those probabilities are simply going to be an i
j k plus one
divided by
some overcame primary and i j k prime plus one
all this did
add one two of the accounts in the
in the
conditional probability tables
you know trying to make a new prediction so this is certainly much more reasonable
than what we had in the maximum likelihood setting because even if our observed counts
for something are zeros
this will not think that that setting is impossible
and this is a form of smoothing where you add one to each of the
counts is a very old idea which is called the policies rule
but the general idea here will work for any garishly prior you choose
and you can use that to encode any prior knowledge you have about what table
entries should look like
so questions about that
try to move on the it
let's talk about bayesian parameter learning with hidden variables
so now my life is a little more tricky
we have some observed data d we have some hidden variables x and the model
parameters theta
and let's assume that we have a discrete variables and dirichlet priors on theta
our goal is to infer the posterior distribution over parameters given the data
but unfortunately this involves summing
overall settings of a hidden variables the distribution of the hidden variables and parameters given
that's a problem because
the posterior distribution
over the parameters given d is the sum over x this distribution
times this distribution
and we know that this distribution here is a dirichlet distribution so for every way
of filling in the missing variables x
we have a dirichlet distribution over parameters here
but unfortunately there are exponentially many ways of filling in x
are hidden variables so it follows that the exact posterior distribution over are parameters
given the observed data is going to be a mixture
dirichlet distributions with exponentially many
terms in that mixture model
so this is a classic case of a computationally intractable
distribution over the parameters
and the solutions we can have to this are there are several ways of trying
to solve this problem
we could try to find a single best
completion of the hidden variables x
and kind of in analogy to what's done in hidden markov models we call this
the sort of turbie
the viterbi algorithm some way of finding the single best
setting of the hidden states and hidden markov model so that's why i use the
term to be here
that's an idea that silky and omohundro apply to hidden markov models but can be
applied more generally to any bayesian
graphical model
here's a slightly more interesting example grayscale images of faces that were taken just role
frames of
we can
so we got what can we ran it's you know low resolution modes give these
twenty by twenty eight images and and then different people sitting in in front of
the video camera and the consecutive frames per cent are taken as a data point
to eighteen people use their identities class labels the original frames
dimension five hundred sixty which you know hundreds
each person is free for
training nine hundred test so here the projection
so this is just eventually i two by
five hundred sixty matrix
but i have multiplied the raw data mining what
it's very hard to understand i mean it's big right so i think this is
actually pretty amazing that there is a linear projection because for raw pixels space to
this space in which the identity of people is fairly well separated out
so is asking what do the rows or columns
the image matrix so i should have displayed they look sort of like
the kind of thing you expect if you train the discriminative system so one them
has a lot of mass around four regions in another one has a lot of
over here i think in this dataset distinguishes
there some people who facial hair also women i think in our faces and then
you know shows background it's hard to interpret
they look so similar to what you get when you go train like a softmax
regression was arrested
remember this is all happening in a two-dimensional three-dimensional feature space
and again you can see that the errors are are substantially so that there is
inevitable experiments on
and it's good to for
this being traumas of experiments on the digits anyway so something in the absence of
strong prior knowledge about how to pick your king nearest neighbour distance
i think learning the metric from data seems like a good idea
we make this big idea we shouldn't just trying to inject knowledge by hand you
should learn everything from data that's what you should know that when the going to
k nearest neighbour which is
try and have the method by hand so we have all these labelled data we
should use that data
learn that
for k nearest neighbour and this seems like a reasonable way to learn
and then if you really need to go back to this is an easy way
to substantially reduce the dimensionality of feature space again not arbitrary
but by taking the principal components and that's kind of where i would think that
the dimensions with most variance would be the most informative class labels that no we
prioritise think that
and here is nice because it seems nothing about the form of the class distributions
doesn't assume that palestinian order to convex or even connected it doesn't seem anything about
separating surface linear linear in some feature space completely nonparametric memory based method which is
just k nearest neighbors taking serious
so i think that take
message to me was very surprising how far you can go with just linear mapping
there's a really good linear transformation you
based on the existence of energy trying to rob
OK so
that's all
they are shown here
there is more
so just you you know how to perform in terms of the spectrum of classifiers
like decision trees and support vector machines are used to and we didn't compare with
that the idea was not to try and
this the state-of-the-art classification here was trying to say
if you're going to change nearest neighbour
which is why people are already especially in the computer vision community to the usually
should try and do it in a reasonable way that leverages the data you have
and it doesn't
so we should think this is a conditional statement this statement is if you're going
to do the nearest neighbour
i have some suggestions
i'm not trying to make a claim
one way or the other should or shouldn't use k nearest neighbour he's not
that's exactly what we initialize the matrix a to remember this is non convex objective
function and the doing locals are so
that always brings up the question
it lies in the answer is we just initialized with all of the obvious things
a lot of random starting point we just take the one that gives us the
best function so all these things are the identity matrix
the the whitening matrix just this color is similar than the data fisher discriminant projection
you know essentially whenever you can think of right
because it doesn't matter what you do is throw that the initial condition optimise
but it's a good question and also i should be very clear that how initialize
important always start any matrix you might be missing out on some good local optimum
would never find myself
have to try
these things like PCA and LDA and random things to make sure to explore space
the performance in the case where
and that's what you mean winding feature space
well i mean i don't know what it means feature space basically non-linear decision surfaces
here certainly on the right
i mean if you draw the boundaries between classes
in this
you use some of these methods to interpret your data
i least here you you you can you can relax from from the bullion assignment
see you can relax everything and find here you have these these axes which are
defined on the interval between minus one and one and he oversees have to have
the the
values minus one and one so the relaxation to and cut can be solved efficiently
encoded by itself is is NP hard it was proven by
my colleague of of jitendra malik
and you are probably the
the type of of images you have seen before
from malik shi and malik staples
so that concludes basically the modelling part in the trial i still had some of
the methods but i think from a learning point of view
this this sort of couples the full spectrum of what you what you would like
to discuss on one hand conceptually methods which are fairly well
located in in the in the in the ballpark of of learning problems like a
means of this expressing parametric distributional clustering some of methods which are fairly popular which
achieves the same think partitioning local image characteristics feature values in in in in k
different groups but which
which look not be addressable analyzable in the usual way when it comes to generalisation
that's and cut and one relation is the one between pairwise data clustering and k
means there you see through this mathematical equivalence how you can go from from what
i would call a generative model k means in the embedding space two model where
it's not so clear how you how you actually
would generate new data
and that's something we have to live in the future
in this section too
i was focusing on on
on some noise
insensitive ways of robust ways and i think the notion of robustness in in application
domains is mostly related to be
so of invariant to slide show of very very little variance too slight changes in
your data and he basically is is what kind of a kind of
right you are a generalization ability of the methods from one instance in a slightly
different instance so maybe an instance where the signal quote unquote is the same but
the noise is different and sometimes it's not so clear what is actually the signal
if i give you to tag images in one the tigers jumping in the lower
left corner and in the other it sleeping in the upper right corner of the
signal i would say is being a tiger being present in these two images but
it's not clear how you distinguish on on on on the level of individual image
blocks i you would distinguish signal from noise
and the challenge for in particular the past project i think it is
clarifying these issues because they
they are very deeply related to what we mean by learning
so candidate solutions should be typical
and maybe they have to be averages of partitioning and the method which i was
advocating for for four
for a number of years nice maximum entropy principle and you have a strategy to
search through the the solution space and that is the space of possible partitions and
you you accept partitions which with costs expected costs here of
h small of being smaller than the constant in this constant is parametrized by the
temperature t so for those of you coming from statistical physics they know
these relations in the others
just should imagine the teaser parameter which allows you to tune the quality of your
the expected quality of fuel fuel costs you you can do that by markov chain
monte carlo meaningful approximation two
methods in that context and here you have one of these algorithms and MCMC algorithm
and i think the essential essentially what you should basically
what you should basically take from this transparency is that the algorithm explores the universe
of politicians which have a certain characteristic in the characteristic here is that in terms
of these empirical because they are below a threshold
and if you if you believe that noise sort of
as to the vari ability of your politicians and the signal was always for the
same type of politician an averaging over different partitions might actually give you
something like a prototypical politicians
and that's exactly what happened in these pairwise clustering because in pairwise clustering also wanted
to find the partition and going in the embedding space where you can do k
means by mathematical equivalence you find these generative partition by the centroid in that space
that is basically the model which which which was underlying these equivalence between k means
and pairwise clustering
here you can do that just algorithmically by searching through many of these politicians and
whenever they fulfil the criteria and you take them into you extract the statistics of
so usually what to do is to maximize the entropy with additional free parameters that
sort of one of the approximation schemes and then you have an OEM like iteration
where you you iterate between where u u maximizes the entropy and basically what you
do is you you you you you fix some some statistics which you have
four measuring how how costly it is for one of your objects being assigned to
particular class and the the the assignment function and that is very similar to what
we have discussed before in terms of k means
what you see is sometimes surprising you get this quote unquote phase transitions here you
have the data density
and when you have very crude approximations down here this is the the inverse temperature
better which is also often used then you will estimate six different classes and they
are all located in the same position and that's here around o point probably o
point three o point four
and then all of a sudden when you could use your approximation quality you you
lower the temperature and dew constraint on the acceptable quality of the solution is is
is is is is low and then you you you force the
the sort the the statistics to split up in form of the centroids are on
this branch in one centroid is located in here and a few lower again this
threshold in these approximation scheme you get further the break-ups until you have six different
six different clusters forty six different modes
log linear models
my point of view on this is that it's logistic regression
and structured output
in logistic regression
the input is an expert
a real valued vector
and the output y
is binary
we want to we want to solve a much more general supervised learning problems
we want to
x to belong to
any is any
space acts
and also in fact why to belong to
any space y
and so example
could be a sentence
he sat on the mat
and why
it would be
maybe a list of parts of speech
the proposition
and now
and so
this is a supervised learning problem is the classifier learning problem
we have training data which is consists of pairs and the tax is an english
and the y
a sequence of
part of speech tags and part of speech tagger the label for the category of
word and so this is a natural language processing problems that is easier than say
figuring out the complete grammatical structure of the sentence is really figuring out the grammatical
role of each word
without figuring out how the grammatical rules interplay with each other and
you know in
machine learning so that
search on generalizing on
two class output to multiclass output and there's also regression methods where you can have
a real valued output but we want to go far beyond this we want to
inputs and outputs to be
no real valued this input is not even in fact
because different inputs can have both
different lengths
and then this number output
it is more
not more
this is not a multiclass there is in some fixed number of labels and you're
choosing one labelled in that fixed number there's does much
the so
o here
the set x
might be
the set of words
and then here's the start the the set of all sequences of arbitrary length and
among the same thing for y
it's a set of tags
star so this is language notation
and the the only
assumption really i'm going to make about
is this why
it is much
he is an assumed finite number
so technically this is not even finite countable because of my
the tax can be of arbitrary length but supposing that i limit my sentences say
to be twenty words long then the y set becomes finite and that's the only
thing that i i need to assume much
more so
actually taxes the sentence
that it's rather pretty important to be able to do that for me to use
must imprecise terminology here so in this case so
one input
is one sentence and one output
is one
and the then that label is a string of sequence tags
so i was the question so
what i'm going to what i'm going to explain
in just one minute is how to represent x and y
as as part of everything that's going to be able to represent things like how
many times is of particular in fact is that
the question you asked
OK so i think i'll be able to answer that in a minute
the cell
his the the models
so probability of y
given x
for some reason i'm changing my notation instead of using data for the parameters i'm
using w for the parameters w stands for weights
so probably y given x and w
there's a there's the normalizing which underscores the axon w
i'll talk about that in a minute and then
i have an exponential
some of the j
so this is
fj capital fj
x and y
what i'm putting up this expression now so as to show you immediately
how this is this looks a lot like logistic regression so in the this is
an exponential
of a linear function
the probability is
essentially the exponential of linear function so it looks a lot like the just regression
and the just regression is going to turn out to be a special case of
the liquid of one composition and a solid the other composition what how i start
with two different
this is forty percent and this is thirty five percent
forty percent nickel thirty five percent nickel
these end members of the same there's only one variable left it's the relative amounts
of these because i need conservation of mass because at the end of the day
if i add up all the nickel in the liquid and all the nickel in
the solid it still has to be
forty percent nickel
only in here it's forty five percent nickel
up here
thirty two percent nickel
so i've got a vernier scale i got a sliding scale that i can move
so that if i have something that's thirty five percent of the words god
it needs less of this phase so the thirty five percent is going to end
up doing this
whereas the forty percent is going to end up doing this
the relative amounts this this line that tells me what the concentration of the solid
and liquid at a temperature is called the timeline
so the timeline defines the composition and members the liquid and solid in that two
phase regime
and we can take all of this that have been talking about and we can
we can clarify it
we can clarify it in terms of a simple rule that captures the notion of
phase separation and conservation of mass and that's called the level of the world
the level
the liberal answers the question
how much of each phrase is present
the relative amount
of each phase
in the two phase regime
in the two phase region
two phase region so for example i think and that's when i got this set
up here it is so here we are with the forty percent nickel is x
forty percent nickel and copper we've drop down into the two phase regime draw the
timeline and the thailand tells us that the liquid the liquid will put the proportion
follows so this is forty percent nickel
at all liquid
right now we drop the temperature this is thirteen hundred now we drop down to
twelve fifty and we know according to the phase diagram we're going to end up
with the liquid and solid and furthermore from the timeline the timeline tells us that
the solid is going to be forty five percent nickel
and the liquid is going to be thirty two percent because the question is what
are the relative values and interests but shown right up there on the on the
transparency that percent
of the liquid is equal to the
in this case the number forty five minus the individual amount at the
at the concentration of the bulk minus the divided by the end members of the
timeline will multiply that by one hundred percent and that gives us the value of
thirty eight percent
present as liquid
and why is it called the ever rule because if you look at the timeline
here's where we are we're at this value
which is shown in the phase diagram
xe this is our forty percent
and the amount of the liquid is x and the amount of the solid is
so what i'm asking how much liquid is present
i choose the amount opposite is as you do on on ceasar teeter totter in
other words to calculate what the forces here you take the amount between the fulcrum
and the opposite side divided by the total length so this is really this is
why xe over x y gives us liquid
and then the complement gives the amount of solid so you see that worked out
for you at
the transparency in this works for any two faces regime
so whenever something
drops in with two phase regime disproportion nation has to occur and the level rule
will give you the relative amounts the timeline tells you the composition
and the liberal tells you the relative amount
two things i want this to be like you're you know the and the manchurian
candidate you know this is your q
yes if you from now on if you here two phase you just go
the liberal liberal
one of the members taiwan thailand liberal thailand liberal
what every c two phase ricci
and else keep you out of trouble
he very troubling me
many times i get into trouble i just think of the living world
i'm going to try to so
now let's look at the second case second cases type two
type two phase diagram
type two phase diagram in contrast to complete solubility type two phase diagrams can is
characterized by
system that has partial
partial or limited
four limited solubility
so when you try to make a and b they don't mix in all proportions
the only makes up to a certain point
so that's like a solubility limit or
emissivity admissibility or solubility synonymous this leads to admissibility gap a range of composition over
which you can mix the two them form a homogeneous solution and in this case
there's no change of state
no change of state
so that's you always liquid
i always liquid or always solid
always saw
so let's look at the phase diagram for
one of these types of systems
planning composition across the abscissa
the ordnance temperature
and this gives us a
so climate phase diagram
this inclined phase diagram
so above we have single phase so this is either
just a single phase
and this is
dual phase
you'll find a single phase dual face so for example this could be
as solids this could be all liquid
and then in here we have two liquids
or it could be all solid
and inside here we have
two solids when it comes to solid solutions people use greek letters and called itself
and beta
so this is the coexistence curve
for the solubility limit what's the coexistence curve the coexistence curve is liquid is in
equilibrium with liquid one
and liquid two
in other words if you drop into this two phase regime
what happens as soon as you hear two phase
the tile i will give you the concentrations at the end or solid goes to
alpha plus b to both of these are solid solutions
let's take a look at
that some of these
this is gold nickel at low temperatures look what happens
classification that told it's going to be very easy after we've done that the initial
investment in exponential family it's all going to be
fairly straightforward
so we get conditionally multinomial models like given x
thing that the feature map if you think another feature map will ever get the
slightly different looking casting process multiclass more
people have actually written papers about that with a simple let's assume now that somehow
my labels are related to each other and maybe even want to learn is
and then when you would just be learning some kernel on the wise
so for instance you remember the error correcting output codes well the people use some
feature map of the wires into some aircraft now code you take product that we
what to get
the key difference is that here
you don't need to learn the code you know exactly what you want to get
as an answer for the inner products
sometimes they are appropriate output code may be more efficient to implement
but there is no there's reason why that shouldn't just be fine
OK so the optimisation problem is actually
very nice
the convex problem
they just looking
two the expansion coefficients these apples you optimize all
well that's wrong it's not the dual space is actually also called in primal space
removed that that's embarrassing
what i meant was problem space in this case it in some cases
actually this function for x and y
it's easy to compute
human but on from mossley
he was talking about bag of words models
in this case he has a very sparse profits and why
so it's a really good idea too
optimized was seated directly
or sometimes the things like string kernels to philippe was talking about that there are
also other string kernels
and sometimes these inner products can be computed very efficiently correctly
if you have a a very
compact storage of the data
so there's is nothing inherently
the same user offers rather than using the
it just really depends on
a specific problem
now is a couple of pitfalls
trooper series only approximated by the mode of the posterior
remember i told you will be doing and that's the story rather than the true
bayesian estimate
and sometimes that can be good
in some cases it's not such a bright idea
and that case you would want to use something like expectation propagation by thomas minka
but has written very nice paper on recently
so hard to read but it's a nice paper
you could also use some
so for instance if you read write for newspapers
he always use sampling
using a very similar
and the variables might look different but essentially the same
i mean he actually invented gaussianprocess classification
now the regression and will save the conditional random fields for tomorrow
so we might even finished five minutes early
now talk about the gets can have to just that
so if you haven't heard those converts that just means well i'm assuming that my
additive noise is the same everywhere
and heteroskedastic means well and assuming that my noise might change with the location
this is different from
i'm not really
sure at one location is another what my that it might be
this that might depend on what i've seen and often four
let's just call optimisation problem
must be you can kind of getting sick of the problem by another section it
so many times
so this is
i mean
now x and y
this is the normalisation term
and here's my
normal prior
now the key differences that before we had a discrete domain renault
so nations
we've got a continuous domain
it's our
written by BR to the a five vector valued regression
whatever conditionally normal distribution of y given x
well nothing easier than that the smell of the exponential family
we take the log partition function
do you think next
and this one is equal to compute in closed form
this also vision
remember that
the equation that had
the lecture
involved normal distribution you get your theta one and theta two is this big me
you want to compute what's
they just plug it in here
what we do is we assume that
if x and y is just wrong from august process you can go with the
OK now let's look at the the standard model for we we assume that the
variance is fixed
this is possibly also member of the exponential family are just fixing one parameter it's
still a member of the exponential family for one
so it's just one where we have some coefficients here times y and this quadratic
as you can see what i said was UBX
they get different means
quadratic function has different maximum depending on what your fixes
so thanks for fixing y
the y times for fixed and y squared nature three statistical parameter
so that you can do
but the way that some papers were
use this experience model
and then try estimating the variance
and i sometimes get the parameterisation wrong and get rather of
procedures which
they have no guarantees for convergence of the variance system
if you set up this way and then optimize was two
you will actually get the nice convex problem
and if you
to some very boring and straightforward algebra
my take page my take page but it's not terribly enlightening just sit down to
the masses
will get exactly the standard process regression model
now see the answer
this is really not much we can learn from doing the algebra me again you
might want to do it once in your life but never again
so what you do this
let's just assume we have some training data
i want to secretion that
so you can check
the mean parameters