portfolio optimization you will do optimal control you'll do machine learning
and do i mean like actually do numerical stuff and would just be stupid programming
it's going to be
learning actually figuring out what's going on it will be obvious and
stuff will happen it will be will be good stuff
OK so
i'm trying to think what else to say before we
we started on the class may able set in context out how different from two
sixty three and stuff like that would be a good thing in the was going
to start and so the two sixty three which is a linear dynamical systems class
that i would call that kind of basic material it's useful in terms of fields
it's very it's what very widely used
a lot of people know it so it's used in economics it's used in navigation
in all of these areas control signal processing is basically all done this way
a lot of stuff is done this way
and it's a great first what you know first look
at sort of how these mathematically sophisticated methods actually end up getting used
sixty four is is revisited and actually it's quite it's quite different a couple of
ways that the first ways it is you might even just say this is two
sixty three beyond least squares so in two sixty three
and by the way in other courses similar to that so when you first look
at statistics in your first look course on statistical signal processing or whatever it's the
same sort everything is gaussians
you know all all distributions are and you know all all objective and constraints are
quadratic and so on and you do this because
this analytical formulas for an and then behind the analytical formulas we have very good
computational tools to
your computational teeth
the the theory so
here there going to be all it is going to be way way beyond that
would have inequalities we're going to have all sorts of other interesting norms and other
functions so we see it it is out this it's a much richer class of
problems and is class
these are probably much closer to a lot of real problems once where
we can handle i mean you don't have the concept of an inequality into sixty
three linear systems concept you just don't have that you have no way to deal
noise with a lot class in distribution
in your first class
on statistical estimation for example so the things we look at things like that
it's going to be
i will be but i should also say that the number of people who know
this material is
relative to
two sixty three material very small
public couple thousand
so is growing rapidly but is just a couple of thousand so that means you're
going to move from
you know material it is city three material that's scale of this kind from the
sixties and seventies not a whole lot later on we maybe i mean somebody there
but it's it's kind of it
it's not stuff that's no
this was in contrast to the boundary of knowledge so
which makes it but
so means
who knows maybe maybe leading push the boundaries actually i hope you do because that's
kind of the point class to train u
due to go find your your corner of the boundary
and then start and end start prospecting
OK so
i can't think of anything generic to say
so maybe all to start the rest will actually start the class any questions
that is the problem if you no way of knowing no problem
but you take instead
the example one of the americans you know that's you find that that's that's no
OK so all i should also say this about about the something about the background
i i should say well it's obviously classes
list of electrical engineering and not actually sure why but anyway it seems to me
to tradition
last i checked that the department i'm in so it seems like it just seemed
like a good idea all around
i should say this you don't need to know anything about electrical in fact i'm
going to talk about we'll talk about lots of applications throughout the core
actually honestly
probably for half i don't even know what i'm talking about so
and that will surely happen now you'll be in some field out super-duper oversimplify it
and you can you welcome to point that out of the classes if lectures boring
at that point you can
you shake your head and
and say no it's totally off or whatever then i will have and continued
so the point is you know i'll talk about circuit design
in contrast to
i disagree with the human rights report that disagree with the doctor x objective here
it's how you're describing
that you end up expressing the subjectivity
you get this
and this is just an example of the kind of objective things that we do
markup it's not a major thing but the government added has amended this citizenship she
backed so on issues presented objectively is true but we will note that the source
of this information is the report for the reference of it
OK now sources the term for better for worse that we use for
so you are attributing the subjectivity two
other people use the term opinion holder
more general it's the experience in the private state anyway in this talk that's what
source means
and importantly sources are nested
so let's consider this sentence the report is full of absurdities and in the next
the entire sentence is attributed to the writer
because he or she wrote this sentence
and then you have
the words
attributes things by the writer to mean
and notice that the full of absurdities there
that subjectivity should be attributed to numa according to the writer
and so
that's the nesting source for this example
and here we have a frame based representations
our scheme of course you can translate into XML so
we have an objective speech of banker is the part of the sentence that's relevant
the text anchor
so the first one is for the entire sentence and that's attributed to the writer
know that the writer
the who the sources is implicit the writer could said i write that
and then it would have been explicit here its implicit in these are implicit ones
are pretty common they're not all just the writer is said that something like that
and at the outside level it's just objectively presented that someone said something on a
particular day
first we have the direct subjective annotation to the source here is numerator the intensity
is high and expressive intensity is neutral
so what does that mean
for intensity
that's the only when you interpret the overall private state
you judge what's the overall and
let's see
and so it's full of absurdities
the expression intensity marks how much
text anger itself contributes to the subjectivity so in this case the words set itself
isn't contributing anything so it's neutral
additionally we mark the expressive subjective elements full of absurdities and it's attributed numerator with
intensity high
right so consider this one the US fears spillover
name professor of foreign affairs at central university for nationalities to do that k
right so that it is the true is writer name and here you have us
numerator from the inside out
so this is the immediate source of you as its USS spheres
that year
is according to an email because it's in what name aside and then of course
the whole thing is attributed to the writer because the writer of the sentence
and here's what you get for this sentence
at the outside level of the writer
you just have an objective speeches because that level
somebody said something and there a professor of foreign affairs at the university it's being
presented as true and there isn't any evaluation or motion or anything of the writer
being expressed
interestingly this here is also an objective speech event
because name it just said that the US fears something it depends on the context
of the article all of this annotation is contextual bandit leaders are supposed to reinterpreted
as it is in that context and i
and judge whether it's being just objectively presented are not in this article it's
it wasn't it wasn't controversial
or anything
so here according to name of the US fears spillover
and then finally we need real down to the theories you have the direct subjective
and here you have subjectivity
you may not appear at all i mean that may not even set
the report analysis to a couple more examples just to help you understand more the
report been strongly criticizing condemned by many countries
so the entire sentence again is objective speech events
and i strongly criticizing condemned is attributed to many countries writer
this one is interesting
as usual the US state department published its annual report on human rights practices in
world countries last monday
and as usual the portion about china contains little to many absurdities exaggerations fabrications so
this is from translation of an article for the chinese press
so here's what here here's here's what you get for this one the first one
just that sentence it's it's just objective there's any subjectivity in that one
so the entire first sense is injective speech events and then the same with the
second and sorry for the second one is the second sentence
that's obviously subjectivity being expressed by the writer him or herself
because the second sentence is saying it's a little too so many absurdities and exaggerations
OK so
one you could have you could simply take the habitation data for the reference we
have sufficient for that you could type used that to define the features used to
be called up tree
we can do this for
all nineteen one reference you could
by that time we haven't used the information that states usually according to that means
snake at in its name appears in one one
then it also it's likely to appear in another
so there are relations between you could have some nodes are related to each other
and the more likely it is that if you get one of the few
that's why we had a kind of second layer which was combining all the scores
of the first layer using these predictions
the input features as well so this is improved predictions quite a bit
and here is what we want are
what you see here is the
false discovery on the x axis and the mean recovery over the twenty of the
nineteen sessions what you type
four different choices of special
and we looked at according regions at UTR intron entrance into the genital region
actually depending on special it what the false discovery rate of two percent
it like i said
it can be thirty five percent of all snakes
you can identify it
rather low of discovery rate of discovery rate is like
the fraction of positive
which are predicted to be positive
but are not about
ensure that
OK so in these starts here this was predicted by other company but
they are better on the core region about that much worse on the intergenic and
in trying to regions
OK so
it turns out that those ips which are close to each other are the most
problematic one
what we have here is what what got here is the accuracy what the recovery
and explores discovery surgery recovery force states which are part of way we're close to
another city or other one of twenty one
so those lips are very far away from each other and the
curiously here with the recovery is very high like fifty percent but as soon as
we get closer to the recovery is going very much
so if the distance is only one six i
then the picture probably looks like this that you are going to be able to
and compared the approach with machine learning approach
and what we have seen it is much better in identifying synapses which are close
to each other
so it wouldn't that region but not good in this region so it's nice very
complementing the predictions on the others
but the rest was of course can be water
first and this be used
label sequence learning
so the idea is that you have maybe a genomic region we have some known
labels we know that it's you
insertions here maybe deletion
and we
come up with a segmentation of the sequence so we define the region as i
wouldn't want it just density of
one other forty
and portable businesses are already that was
so this is like the segmentation which would like to be defined based on the
is written
then we have a simple data model which we would like to match to this
sequence positions and so it can be either could
what we want
and then this position states between which model like the UK of the habitation
habitation entity
so this model so it should i mean is
the state very simple and reason essentially sign every state
two label for every position that you know
but not the markov the model
now we can use just the label sequence learning approach which shows
it's just another example
so this region where we have no labels using the target page which we derived
from the low note label
these states which are detected by calling by
the prediction of those isolated can be predicted others are isolated cannot be pretty easily
this is the habitation signal and i would like to predict based on the hybridization
signal where the boundaries where the polymorphic regions
critical to the more recent
this could be point what it
prediction that
we want you to stop here and here
almost correct question is how
how do practice here
we defined kind of juicy measure and how to break overlapping by seventy five percent
of the
so in this case it would be great because and
can identify fifty five percent of all we want to the same the specificity of
nine so among all predictions nine or ten right
behind about half of all three one
so previously there was only heuristic method which had a much lower sedative
i think this is a bit
very few people
now the question is
we have this name calling i would have this prediction are with what we want
the vector and the semantics that we introduced before in the compression phase and this
is the idea that we call the
structured output discriminant analysis since it will be seen as in an extension of the
linear discriminant analysis two
this setting of structured output problems
so the problem that we have to solve this one maximizing
this the ratio of this is an optimisation a convex optimisation problem perhaps you will
see that year and to solve it the first thing for is we should have
said that if the matrix is not positive semi definite we should introduce the article
in relation to
and to solve that
the problem and out we can solve the problem by simple matrix inversion
but in theory inventing these metrics can be
can have high computational cost but we
we use the fast conjugate gradient methods and tools to speed up the optimisation face
i would just to give an idea about to these two radical stuff that perhaps
i do wonder what warren and we developed rademacher bound that show that the learning
with our upper bounds is effectively achieved and we wondered that my holds
even when
b and c are estimated by sampling
and what want to see in in this way we can really spread out
the motivation there
our algorithm so we can see the two directions of sampling the first one is
that for each input output pair in the training set we consider only a limited
number of incorrect outputs to estimate the
in metastasis by sampling and also we consider only if you need a number of
input output space in the training set
in the bound was show in the next slide that basically we prove
that year the empirical expectation of the estimated loss estimated the scenes we are computing
b and c by sampling is a good approximate upper bound for the expected loss
and we should also remember that
the upper bound to that we defined before is an upper bound on the ranking
loss so
effectively what we're doing is we're minimising
this presentation of the ranking loss
this is about and just to give you some insight the five times here are
and then the empirical estimate of the expected a lot of them such a loss
the time with something during the metric quantities that decrees that was the inverse of
the square root of n and have
and though the two terms
and here is the cost again goals as the inverse of the square root of
n and help so that means that
but they quantity on the right side go to zero when the number of samples
is increased
another approach that we can see a
by the end of the previous approach is that it in that we call the
true core approach
are since we asked ourselves for other we define the discovery of training set another
possible approach would be to consider that the contributor of feature
input output pairs is independent from the contributor of the order so it means that
the mean and they call and the right answer computed for each piece can be
summed in that way we we should assume to have an estimate of the
the mean of the distribution of the four on four of the input output pair
of the training set
and as well for the covariance
this is what we call the this core approach the
problem define problem is this one as you can see the structure of the problem
similar to the what one in
four decide where we again have a convex optimisation problem can with that can be
solved by simple matrix inversion
and basically they are assigned to that i will show you later are quite similar
in both cases is if you work it out of this form where you can
see that we are minimizing kind of upper bound on the ranking loss again
so that's why perhaps that you might very similar but for this one that we
try different strategy because basically when we maximize this myself of the linear constraints of
here is
the same kind of plot we had before and then this is the role over
which is one of our strategy it had the bottom of the curve
so we we may very well be tree
now he are compared
here again is
this curve that was
designed by doing the reverting using dynamic programming bestfixed
this is sort of
the best hit rate you can achieve when you
use the union of all twelve strategies
so this is the one
tries to
there the real cache with the idea of cash
it has very good performance but
in the sense that it has a small miss rate but
it has a problem
and the problem is
it has a lot of factors very far over in this direction
which is a lot of i you want to stay below this line to the
left of these lines
but if you do demand roll over
which is no prefetching
you some kind
close to the best fixed but if you do a little bit of refactoring
you beat bestfixed on this dataset
another dataset
there we were very close to this basically fitting curve
and in some cases even beat
this curve
we feel like we decided very stringent compared we actually needed actually i do not
i don't know how to design a better offline strategy
except well except the one that would look at the future and that some
so this was a very it's pretty stringent strategy
OK demand rollover which into any actually always as good as almost as good as
the best fixed small amounts of wheat
prefetching always beat bestfixed
remember best fixed
i was the one up here
and we have fifteen to twenty two percent fewer missus than bestfixed
and we always be LOU which is the defacto
that's the one that is the most
OK we can be the best three curves and the i behaviour is also pretty
operating system in many of these parameters tweaking problems
the suitable for online learning
the algorithms
from that area as heuristic to sign good online algorithms for practical problems i'm going
to do this now for disk spin down and
skip lists are talking a little bit about these other applications
so any questions that
regarding any part of the county
so again
what we did
caching application was
here lot miss of different policies
what you can and he is the best guys
over time
i have decided compared and again i want to compare against sort of the best
shifting policy
and they had to
online algorithms that could actually handle this case
we're the best expert is shifting over time
i couldn't it wasn't enough just to do the loss update that actually doesn't work
you need to do invented new kind of update and he is again the updates
you do
either minus loss update
and then you do
no weight is one minus all the time
well you just got a lots of times the past average
that's what you should remember
the combined update works
to update your beliefs on
a bunch of experts
special case of this is if the if the loss
happens to be long-lasting this would be bayes rule
and this
when you share to the uniform weight but if this average would be the uniform
with that's kind of robust base and you can actually motivated and it's
the probabilistic interpretation when new shared the past average
could not find
patient interpretation of that update
it works provably well but i couldn't find innovation interpretation
this is kind of an interesting so when you pick makes in the past averaged
what happens is the weights of all the experts that were good in the past
they still glowing that they don't go all the way down to zero they still
global little bit
and then when you come back need the same experts again
they pulled up very fast
and i'm very much fascinated by
this glowing saying
so you
i want to learn something and you sort of
and you need to do this in online learning you want to learn something
but you what anything that has been good in the past you sort of want
to memorize and remember a little bit
because most likely your data is going to shift back
to the same
type of data
and then you want to recover fast so this is sort of the first algorithm
was good at shifting
it was even better at shifting back to something
it has been good at before
and i want wanted do all kinds of algorithms that have this kind of property
OK i will give
a brief
actually less than
there's an introduction or overview
statistical machine learning
what the other quarters
will cover in much more depth and detail
so it
for those who have no idea about machine learning to get some big picture but
probably understand only ten percent of the stuff on it
for those who already took a course in machine learning it maybe serves refreshments
OK so
the first ever given me overview
then linear methods for regression
that sounds pretty boring
good old fashion statistics but if you don't master that forget about the rest
and the more powerful than you think of
non linear methods for regression
if you have complex problems
like in real life
you need to
select models and process models
you have to deal with large problems
are in so far as small as i i these independent identically distributed data
there are various other kinds of
and supervised learning this of unsupervised learning
learning for rick interactive setting its reinforcement learning
explain what that is and then to the summary
first we could ask i mean why do we need machine learning why do we
need to learn
from related fields
applications of machine learning
the three short months we talk to me
supervised unsupervised reinforcement learning from other to is
mini introduction to probabilities
most of the things that you on this slide this in in the evening
it's a wiki page about probability is if you don't know this stuff
OK so what is machine learning
so you could define it as machine learning is concerned with the development of algorithms
and techniques that allow computers to learn
OK that's pretty obvious this machine and flow
so it should be about machine learning
in this context it's the process of gaining understanding by constructing models of observed data
with the intention to use them for
the best related fields is artificial intelligence
some people think that machine learning is a part of the i
some people think it's different
i want to develop smart algorithms
this statistics
something that machine learning stuff just some obscure branch of statistics
o thing
i believe it's quite different from statistics
i think it's the same
but if you look at the journals and publications is hard to get the statistics
from the machine learning journal and machine learning paper statistics journal so there must be
some difference and machine learning is more concerned with either of them
and statistics more of it
best estimators and so on there is a large degree of overlap
OK data data mining a lot of data we need to process it somehow and
of course there is a continuum from two machine learning
and of course computer science because machine learning want to develop algorithms and computer science
a lot of
nice algorithms efficient algorithms for problems have been developed and then you can use in
machine learning
OK so
why should we learn
the first i mean there's something they don't need to learn for instance to calculate
i mean if you can add numbers many multiply you know the rules you just
do it you don't need to learn from
payrolls statements
so learning is used when
human expertise
it doesn't exist
i i mean
robert navigating en masse
humans are unable to explain their expertise
like in speech recognition that all
pretty good at recognizing
but it's
very hard to
right former model explicit model
so that's what we're
which is kind of funny because i knew to manchester
who was just peter might as well just this one thing that are
wilson the risk interest is known for is being a bit right
but i believe this thing but
well want to see what happens
concepts and models
no really really good that we start even for people who are particularly for large
one the of the
actually all of these are our what's going on but we were
what's going on there
it's more it's going to be an
it's hard work
so for example
i understand what's going on to say
well we
i mean this is this is getting
comfortable with just over an ontology looking
one of the things that makes it really easy to use
actually something actually useful
how do you know where the great
the language is that people publish columns
in the
the other dollars
you might presented in a public forum
now we know that
to years
and one of the canterbury's we can do is learning from them
so for someone to give a little bit background
ontologies are very high-level going to try
despite all the
will land
so i think the whole what you're
that by the way they are
OK so so
this is sort of very generic
he was
all is
well it is so small you want see the subject
usually conceptual
on what we're doing is an ontology as they are computer science is that there
computational artifacts
you know
all four were sometimes we can hide this
just like we can programs you know you can if you're using its own programs
the world
i don't think about this
here but really
so three percent computational
is there
or you get something that machine
when need to
during world program is that
right round something on this is also true for ontologies lot of things that deal
on a general way that counts were not part of the applications like
so that they usually do some form of inference help
so it's very important
it's one of these
these things are
because the
our world is generally ontologies are directed more or less
pieces of the world
other ways you can use them to do what is sometimes called structural also so
for example you can model
the part of the world in your computer and is here
but primarily it directed towards the world
that is that when you're working with
all were built on what is really
well i think about
what kind of world you want to describe
when i think about the world war and when you reading be also called
they want to
this right
one be
very general constraints in general only the the notation also consists of running things are
we don't want to be so
he first ran for
the program is well what are
computers are also
that would sort of defeat the purpose of doing this kind of model
sometimes it's best to
unfortunately we cannot do it
there so
the precision
was a lot
four great well on source
well that's
what are these just
but are twelve months which is
and i put it down on the table
now having a nice conversation drinking beverages
and it's about twelve thirty one o'clock now in starbucks is closing
and it's time to walk back
to a person
we walking back to pierce
and we leave this starbucks we make a left on chapel street walking up to
york i'm getting a little sleepy
my friend looks at me and says
i feel fun
what actually happening
the heart is beating a little faster
her palms are beginning to swell
progress is coming a little shorter than it otherwise would
how do we know
so war here
i don't think i felt this way in a very long time
could be the coffee or decaff
what could this be work
then she turns and she looks
and she says
one day this is been
what we have moved on and why it's almost like being in love
it is almost like being in love except what it really is is two shots
of cabinets
causing a rapid heart rate respiration rate increased in respiration sweaty palms
but i don't realize she doesn't realize that's what it is
turns the most salient was also psychologists terms of most salient objects in immediate social
that be
is one that's the idea of this attribution aroused something else i don't know what
that is
it's best if you don't know what that is or even if you do mistakenly
attributed mister attributed
physical attraction romance intimacy passion and commitment
it's love
i no
i don't necessarily recommend
that you do this thought experiment in
in vivo this weekend
although if you're lonely you might want to try it but
we can go we can take this idea
we can we can actually do research on this we could take it to the
last but before i tell you about love experiments the most famous field experiments on
this idea
we call this the rickety bridge experiment and there's a bridge at the university of
british columbia
crosses a river that runs through campus
and the rickety there is actually two bridges the rickety bridge
it is one that's kind of a rope bridge
it's hundreds of feet above the river
it's ways in the breeze it's only about three feet wide you kind of hold
on to it carefully and you cross the river it's pretty scary went across that
somebody better than using this bridge
still there yes another great OK there is another way to cross the river
it's on a low bridge near the water solid wood planks nice and why
the hand railings made out of solid wood
and you can cross the bridge
so what to investigators interested british columbia did
very simply position
once again
an attractive actor confederate
on one side of the bridge
she was one of
but you know that
crossing the bridge
and she would intercept them as they can cause
a rickety bridge or the low bridge
and she would have a few questions
and conclude with can you write me a story
it would help me out with my experiment just credible story right now
then she would collect the story
and she would say
if you have any questions about this experiment here is my phone number actually this
happens when you're experiments with the phone number
what happens
man male students across the rickety bridge they wrote these sexy stories with interesting content
with kind of
kind of little bit tribal themes
and the people on the road on the solid bridge
just wrote pretty
boring stories
the people across the rickety bridge were more likely to call up later say
yeah i like to talk about the experiment i was in
going into the starbucks
decaff don't you
and the people in the low bridge were much less likely to color
the idea what was going on well what this was interpreted as mister attributed arousal
on the rickety bridge you're swaying in the breeze hundreds of feet above the water
the bridge seems unstable
maybe i'll make maybe want your heart beating years palms are sweating you're breathing harder
you meet this person and
she seems more attractive
because you're feeling all these things in your attribute it
two to the attraction
now there's a reason why this study
is bad science
there's a major flaws
in this time
the clue to the floor
is that you can even call this study an experiment
what's the floor
people who take the rickety bridge might be the kind of people more looking for
if you already have the deduction of five from guam
and you have the option of fireflies from gamma
you can extend the deduction right that size deducible from again
so you see the modus ponens that's going on
five five site decide
the rule is different from biological
if there is the deduction of five from guam
then there's the deduction of box five get
that's just the rules telling that's the way the right
those are the rules i haven't showed you the axioms you
but what we're going do is this is how we can build derivation
now i'm going to move on to the axioms hopefully
i'm just formalizing what derivation what's the derivation
so to finite tree of judgments
with the route is gamma norton stuff i not let's rubber only semantic stuff because
it's forbidden
so what is it it's a tree with root gamma not stuff i know
so it's a tree like this
and the leaves
are either
judgement instances or i d instances
OK so the leaves over here i have to end with the rule i d
or have in with the rules
i x
and everything in between
has to be glued together
using these three rules
so if you have a binary step
and you know that this
and this will match this part
and you conclude
to go to the parents
which is the it's alive show you
so the only thing i'm showing you the axiom schema and here the axiom schema
or three
for classical logic
and one
which is the model shape which have already shown you is valid they should be
getting suspicious about my exercises of k they were chosen very specifically
so the exercises asked to show that these guys were valid
and this guy was valid
and surprise surprise they turn up as my actions scheme
how is the axioms
we use it in this way five is an instance of an axiom schema so
what you do is if i give you some five here
you have to look at the shapes and see whether that particular phi is an
instance of it
that's all that's independent of gamma are and i'm going to use some abbreviations for
the other connectives i don't want to go through
inventing more and more rules
OK so here's an example
i claim that this is the derivation
of box p one
from gamma which consists of pain or implies p one
it's just work through it
let's work through a top down not sure if
my lectures are in technicolor on location there
but still the other way will work bottom up because that's the the pictures that
i can claim that that's an instance of necessitation
and the colouring is supposed to help
there is the rule necessitation
all of this stuff is in gamma
gamma goes up there unchanged
this is supposed to be box phi one
so the green b is five
and we just drop the box
go up one step
gamma is now
the stuff in red again remains unchanged
the site is this gonna
p one
the phi is p nor
and over here we connect the find site using an indication
so the p norm is the same as that
the p one is the same as that
and there is an implication
and finally we have the maturity
in this case both of them are instances of idea because all you do is
you shake
it's p your member of this list yesterday
it's pain known implies b one member this this yesterday
that's it
at no point did i talk about model
o point to i talk about truth valuations all i did was to
applied pattern matching
but you computer cond
is a different derivation of the same thing
p not
you know it implies p one goes box p one
and by doing bottom-up or top-down
doing it all
let's have a look
that's the top down
this is an instance of ideas because this is in their a set membership
this is this excitation because i leave the left hand side alone input box in
front of the whole thing
i having written up the rules so you'll have to look at the rules on
your slides right
i leave the formula allows put box in front
now over here
i'm using
OK so let's let's think about
and symbols
let x be the
the outcome of a random experiment
and let's be very very concrete here OK
let's look at the figure first OK now
this will be the index
all of of my random
experiment okay so i perform sort of
i a sort of take
sort of take x
OK i'm explained differently
can take values from an alphabet
a a represents an alphabet right and actually to be quite quite natural in this
stolen from david mackay's book who has read david mackay's book
a little bit
all right
x takes values from a with probability p of x
OK so let's take let's take a concrete example
a concrete example would be if if the alphabet was actually an alphabet you could
also be
you know colors sizes anything you want
if you were letters from the alphabet
and he was the the corresponding probabilities that x will take the corresponding value in
one thing we could do we could go on download a manual for for linux
and this is how they like i was very religious about operating systems
this figure
and he basically counted
the number of times he so
later in in the in the whole manual and he just divided by the total
number of letters that there were right including and that includes the space
all right so once once he did that
he obtained some sort of empirical
estimates as it were of what's the probability of encountering those letters is in general
links manually
this representation here we're going to see later again
the size of the squares is proportional to the size of the numbers
so what properties
what properties do these probabilities
need to have
one of them is
they always
and the other one is a up to one
right now when you go and read papers
in the different communities you see that people use statistics are a bit more careful
they actually right
things more sort of
correctly right in in other sort of
papers in machine learning like the ones i right
people tend to be very very sloppy actually with notation which sometimes causes great confusion
because we have p of expert
then you recycle x many times and then p is always p and you don't
have the substrate that says
but with respect to which distribution is that and stuff like that all right so
people tend to sort of
right very very minimalistic
expressions here i'd like either p of the random variable or p of the outcome
of the random variable takes but actually
the way this thing should be written is actually
but just to train new i'm actually not going to do that in the rest
of the presentation
the alphabet
can also be can either be sort of a
so here it just sort of say a set x actually so these are these
this is like x taking values in the in the alphabet right
but the alphabet could also be
could also be continuous like like what is the distribution
of the height
of of the human rights so we can go on and measure the height of
all of you but if we had if we had instruments for measuring the were
precise enough
then in serie
the height could be considered as a a continuous
random variable right or a random variable that takes values from continuous alphabet as it
you find acceptable information the the information about orientations in the occipital cortex
this is this is obtained by averaging at the level of the accuracy maps across
so you basically war the the beauty of this is that now you can accumulate
the information processing across a large number of subjects at the level of the storage
of information
so you basically you can look at the average information stored for each person and
you walk the brains also the fit together and then you can do some second-level
analysis on that as well
and that way you can you can find things that you wouldn't be able to
see the current classical analysis and you wouldn't be able to see if you just
did according analysis on a single person because effects will be far too weak
so now you can for example run fifty subjects and see things that you wouldn't
normally see
so what you see here again
it's a matter thresholding as well
this shows the temporal development of the information about task rules target stimuli and motor
and what you can see is that the task rule first is instructive q has
a or b
instructive q first is in visual cortex we first see the information related to the
and then
you see information and pride cortex and then it goes into lateral prefrontal cortex which
is quite compatible with with data from previous lesion studies and so on
the target stimuli because they get the q first and then they see the stimulus
and they have to respond
but the target stimulus comes on later
and it's in the visual system but interestingly and this is related to the talk
by performing a professor from actually the this perspective information original spective information
so the idea that here you see the target stimulus information is first in the
visual system but there is the late coding of this visual stimulus after the response
has already been made in the lateral prefrontal cortex which is not exactly what you
saw but is set it again raises the question what is this information doing that
what is being used for and the motor response as you can see is that
they can also unfold these processes in time
so next show you how
we address the same issue with internally chosen goals
and to do this
i've done this same thing in the other talk the other day so i apologize
for duplication but i'd like everyone to decide now
if they want to add or subtract two numbers so you just do one of
the two you can do one of the two tasks but just decide now freely
if you want to add or subtract two numbers
and now the question is do you think i could read out of your brain
activity that you've
covertly made this choice
to either add or subtract two numbers
and the way we started this was
here are the two numbers by the way so he can i can do your
calculations fifty six thirty three
so we get people to freely select
one of two tasks they can either add or subtract numbers the different variants of
and then
there is a delay
until they actually see the numbers that they have to do is use the calculation
and then during this domain
the question is can we decode and from which brain areas can with code which
covered intention the person currently holding
and the reason to use adding and subtracting here was we wanted to use maximally
symmetrical operations they're not fully symmetric but they're are kind of more symmetric and other
so the question is now
we train a decoder to read out of this variable delay period so the idea
is between your choice and the time when you see the numbers there is a
variable delay this variable delay can be between two and twelve seconds that keeps you
on your toes you you kind of have to stay ready to quickly respond to
the to stimulate into two numbers you can see so you don't just make up
your mind then you can forget it again in ten seconds later you make up
your mind again we have to kind of keep on your tongue
you know blob this kind of thing OK
now if you learn a few tricks
in least squares
or you can do well if you learn how to do weight twiddling and you
learn about regularisation basically those two alone and you are now actually trained you already
or you're ready to do battle with using least squares is tool and you will
really well
let me tell you i mean so that the weight is basically
you know you're going to problem in some sense
this is no limit on the sum of the squares you know the limits on
this that the then you got no problem these weights around this you just you
look at the least square solution you like what you see you change the weights
and you do it again
but we in bowen engineering we do this all times called we twiddling
slightly derogatory term
but not not that and i'm sure they do in statistics and so like but
i haven't got i don't know that they don't have to be admitted
right so
because they like to have this
you know better smiling
you are a good because i like to have when making fun of the department
i like to have base to look at
i'd like to stick to that
you know
so think you would get if you doing real statistics you go back in and
i might change the prior distribution now admits you do you do that
that's right we have to warn you that this this the theory by of all
of these are being
put these lectures being put on on the web
because it's it's weird and find so
don't worry we'll find out your voice and and if the camera focus on you
will put like that squares all the way we if you like we can obscure
your department
so we could be put out actually would be good
ninety two two diplomatic to to say
i know so i'm just going to get in statistics right to make a big
story about like the prior distribution that i bet they don't like the way he
comes out they go back and change the prior distribution
and they cover up their tracks they don't say that they do this i'm just
because i like you know we know what we do in engineering OK
we're not embarrassed
so i do it
next topic is linear programming so some of you have seen
this may be actually how many people here just from sampling of people who were
single linear programming someone
so about
MST three ten
the morals
in the greek islands
along with the class
and weights
that's a lot of moore's law going down ten weeks so OK
OK so
linear programming
and that in my opinion it's what people should learn immediately after the least squares
single already comes in linear programming
i mean if you're gonna stop somewhere
you know that's a very good point i mean if you want to do you
actually really want to go on and field algorithms to real to real stuff you
that's a great place to start everybody nobody gets lost in a lot about so
many programs families like this minimize a linear function subject to
a bunch of linear inequalities now we're going to talk about horrible detail later in
the class so i'm not going to talk and not going to go into too
much detail now
but let me i one of the attributes
a linear programming so the first is in general except for very special cases there's
no analytical formula for the solution
just there is no formula there's no a transposing inverse transpose b
by the way don't confuse that
with our inability we can you can say
a huge amount of qualitative intelligent beings
about a linear programme
what you can do is write down the formula for the solution
there are reliable and efficient algorithms and software back in when year hold it as
a homework exercise you will right
actually something kind of in the top-class linear will be fifty lines of matlab or
python and if you take up our offer on that and you'll write something that
will solve huge linear programs quite well
and it's no asterisk on unsolved i mean you get best solution period
the computation time by the way is proportional and squared and
o and by the way that's exactly the same as least squares
that if you equate rose to the least squares
objective with constraints is identical that's not an accident which will get yes
m is the number of constraints here and k
is the height of a
she che well that's the best i can do
i think that's why not so this case this and is still many rose in
a great
over here
yes if i write that is in matrix inequality x less than b
yes that would be this same would be that k
so we carefully
my co-author of that we we had we spent hours discussing whether should be amateur
finally we can make either
we should be OK what about c or the edge sea
OK this is an hour and
OK don't see is an hour into
OK so i
so actually linear programming by the way it's very old topic free a wrote a
paper about that to hit the modern area starts in the thirties where else but
but actually the modern era
traces back to stanford
george stands for the by the way it it LP was something that you just
talked about
until you have computers which point all of a sudden look a lot more interesting
i was nineteen forty eight so
you know i think a lot of fun women also knew about a lot of
people knew about linear programming we will talk more about this when we get
i i think there's something like this couple's computers it many huge that that's immature
a linear programming it looks like it would be easy
to recognise and in fact in some cases the problem really has this four really
comes you on a platter like this so someone comes to you and says i
help me solve this problem i want to minimize this weighted sum of the variables
and they have some budget constraints or whatever there's about three problems or whatever that
actually have exactly this form
here's the really cool part of a linear programme
you will be stunned later in the class when you see the kind of problems
that we can reduce the linear programming
you would just keep this as free parameter
and then you would just optimizer with without parameter to
and and after you've done optimisation you with then open the hood and say well
what value is what is the value of
and if i have
i was very large and they all
this looks so there's only really one one lengthscale play here
but it out with various policies all
you know
we can draw some conclusions here
the interesting thing is although we're not really parameterizing
the functions
we can still parameterise the properties of the function
which seems in practice to be much more interesting thing to be able to do
OK so here is another example
these are the so-called matan forms so the the actual expression here involves something which
is known as the set bessel function
i don't really know what that is but i don't care about that i can
use it
so an interesting thing is you can prove
that that's sample functions from these mutant forms extra parameter new here
and the sample functions on numerous times differentiable
so here's an example
functions that are
what's interesting
OK the last five minutes
i could talk to us
let me talk
so i think this is the
the town forms
have this property that the set of functions that you draw
are differentiable a certain number of times
i was the one from the squared exponential functions were actually infinitely often differentiable all
derivatives exist
but you can also specify distributions of functions where only
up to second order
the french troops success
and if the project come back on architecture shows pictures of functions so again you
can also say well
how differentiable
does not function look like maybe you know something about the different abilities so then
you can inject that information directly into the process
or it might be something that you're interested in finding out
so you can do inference
over the parameter
i'll show you those
pictures and then i'll show you
one more
one more construction
which would be useful in
the application which are which and on
it is the problem with showing colourful pictures
this talk about some criterion third
yes that's the next one
i think i can come back to that in in the example that i been
looking at basically you can write down to the
for the noise process so independent
no it's just corresponds to adding a diagonal
on the
in the covariance
if you want spatial correlations then you can sort of imagine that
so that you can order the data points
if your data points then you would have something which is bandlimited
the saying well the noise
it is colored like it depends on on on neighboring points
but not over the whole scale historically
and you can also you don't have to have a constant on the diagonal
you get different values and i say well the noise
is very hefty in this region but it's very
very small amount noise
in this region
OK so here was this user's midtown fall and again a special limiting cases of
the midtown farmers out of the gaussians with that corresponds to the infinitely differentiable one
and again the crash functions look
rather similar
it turns out that the question about differentiability is actually related to it exactly what
the covariance function looks like
zero so there's a lot of mathematical theory that will tell you
these things here
this is just an just an example
here is the
the calcium again this very smooth function may be too small for practical applications already
for some applications
here's black is one which is twice differentiable
so it's not exactly a small this this one
but still pretty small
here's one which is
only once differentiable
and here with new equal to half actually something honest brownian motion
which is not even continuous
it may be just continue
so the question about
less than equal to see can actually be written as equal to c
our properties are going to be positive rate and they're going to some some to
some c value
and then
given the structure we can actually interpolate this is the probable you know in a
probabilistic framework and
we can think of the consequences of that city
and then we can write marginal deals so
we're going to define
two sets of marginals now
the marginal
and i'm going to consider all for i
why pairs
that have at the t position that have label
some summing over all of these
o parameters and
the the other set of tools are going to be
the ones
that that take the label interaction into place so here i am presenting the
formulas in terms of the sequences they actually defining more in general but i guess
it's easier to see here
right now
so for sequences we will have two sets of pairs two sets of of marginals
the marginals over
at each position
what is the label and the marginal over each
each position what is the labelled pair
OK so i'm going to some or all of these are all
for parameters that have s as prime
as as bar pair at the teat position
all right so
it it must be are it must be obvious to all of you that the
number of parameters to do
new parameters are only polynomial
it's there not exponential now for for each position i look at the labelled pair
or late label positions
all the alpha values there in my objective function are actually over some sounds so
i can really go to my objective function and plug in these values and rewrite
the the
l l
alpha in terms of these marginal tools
so now this is great i used to have an exponential
i have used to have an image of optimisation problem which has exponential parameters and
now i have only a polynomial size optimisation problem
one problem
here though is that the marginals do depend on the density of right so they
need to be consistent
by that i mean that
so the the the muse here really have an alpha parameter here
so the set of all possible values are actually larger than the set of
i mean parameters we can consider for a a given set of office
and that's the that's what i mean by by
but but by that the demand from illegal density
in fact the the number of wires that satisfy this and the number of wires
that satisfy this must be equal and
and this introduces some complex coupling over the these new parameters
and because of these couplings are taskar et al proposed to optimize really over the
alpha parameters that the that we've seen before using in some more like technique
but OK i algorithmically maybe didn't help at all it helps i'm i'm tossing of
some details but but in general we still have a we're still operating over the
exponential parameter space but really this this new definition of the margin and this we
parameterisation allows to
approach to two even two
to analyse the problem theoretically
in in an improved way yes
the other thing
this is the
i did not make it all the clear that this person is in our problem
does not only come from the sparseness of the hinge loss
it also comes from from the fact that are compatibility score of of some assignment
of some observation labelled pair is actually a combination of parts right so
the same parts can be observed in many many labels
OK so so because of the structure of the are labels
the there is the the sum of the sparsity is coming from the structure of
labels so the question you asked was OK we have explanation parameters and or some
lean years
if this person is only coming from the sparseness of the hinge loss we would
have exponential
parameters but it is not the case
actually in in our observations we need is that we do see that the number
number of support vector machines are
really various parts
so of they do grow
so for each position i actually i think they took away the slide i have
an example for from of from an experiment where i was showing some support vectors
and you will see that you will take the support vectors you have just differ
only in one position
he he's saying you have a sequence
and the support vectors you have i got to be the same for all positions
in justifying one position
so you're not going to of all possible label assignments here you're just really taking
a sequence switching build the label at that position which is zero polynomial
well thank you all for staying the very end i know you
yourself too
many talks and you will suffer too unlikely is quite amazing
so mean if you are still here and i guess
but it has to do with the fact that you
can't escaped
i'm sitting there saying the computer science and engineering department university of michigan
and my understanding is only really been one
proper reinforcement learning
though chris
this allows reinforcement learning these days are how much is talked about
power they quickly called because i can accelerate to the first tutorial part depending on
the full tells me i mean if you know of
BP's value iteration in
q learning
the quite
maybe i can but i
i was told that there is a fair bit of a mix of cognitive science
and machine learning people is not everybody sees are also solution would have tutorial
and then get on
the sort of thing that occupies my interest these data which is rethinking state action
reward so i will go through
i have a fairly quickly into or out
so first the obligatory slide of pictures of all my
collaborators and people have influenced me
on the top you see people i've collaborated with
at the bottom here all the students have done most of the work that i'm
going to tell you about i want to say their names
so here's the deal world
structural topology tutorial very quickly define MEP's tell you what the policy evaluation problem is
with the optimal control problem is and then give you one
idea for rethinking actions one idea of rethinking states in one thinking rewards and then
finish with a random thought two
OK so here is the power problem you an agent interactive environment actions getting perception
towards it's complete agent temporarily
situated in its world continually learning and planning and of course the
object here as opposed to most of the talks you've heard about to focus on
inference is to affect the environment so decision-making and action and of course other talks
and decision making
the environment can be stochastic uncertain so in some sense rl is like life and
here is the more abstract picture of this and the goal of the agent is
to maximize payoff for some time horizon so
this view of life is that light is an optimal control
thank you status
supervised and unsupervised reinforcement learning three legs in machine learning i guess
one thing i'd like to say is that if you've never heard of RL here's
one way to characterize what makes are all different from supervised and unsupervised learning you
play a game of chess
you make a hundred moves you lose
you have to figure out
which of two hundred moves were good which one of those are bad and this
is called the temporal credit assignment problem this problem is not there in supervised learning
unsupervised learning is what distinguishes reinforcement learning about solving in some ways the ends of
ten chromosome problems of course subsumes unsupervised and supervised learning as well as
for the shoes generalization and density estimation also that every possible OK lots of applications
slash slate up here is an MDP
just notation as state space and action space transition probabilities the probability of seeing state
i am taking action a in state j
the reward function function of state could be more general than that ties is deterministic
policy the notion of the return or utility of executing policy behind state i
which is the expected value of the discounted sum of rewards you get when you
behave according to policy pi
in some start state icivi of pi
we super is the utility
the policy pi the value of the return you all equivalent words in our forced
four state and policy pi the policies of course the one that maximizes utility
this is just a quick introduction mdps if you haven't seen this
four hopefully this
will do something for you for the rest of the talk
policy evaluation problem given a fixed policy evaluated the markov assumption is the key thing
i want you to understand this equation is an equation in the middle of this
slide for all s
in state space the pilot as the value of thanksgiving policy pi state s is
recursive four is the immediate reward you get plus the discounted expected value the next
state is an equation that takes the first principal definition of the value of the
and transforms it into a system of equations one for each state and the
the problem of evaluating how good a particular policy is amounts to solving the system
of equations
yes policy evaluation of optimal control the problem of finding the optimal value function or
in that the optimal policy can be written in this q notation in state action
values with the best you can do from state action pair is the immediate reward
you get plus the discounted expected the best you can do in the state to
get to again the markov assumption the markov assumption leads you to these recursive bellman
optimality equation and because the best you can do
in terms of action the state of the optimal action the state parks star that's
is then just the optimal
it's just the
greedy action with respect to the optimal q values
can just very quickly
in policy evaluation
on october twenty problems there are is often concerned evaluating a particular policy of finding
the optimal policy
OK so
i'll give you one algorithm for each of these before i know that that we
need to talk
policy evaluation if you have the planning version of it is you have a model
you know the reward function you the transition poverty you know the policy you evaluated
you basically take the recursion i showed you before and you know it
on the left-hand side on the right-hand side you can to left and right
simulating writing
who here is an undergraduate
a handful three who here is a
masters student just say
starting this year
there are two years phd student
growing around here is a
this just i'm phd
OK so everyone else for this year
this talk about reinforcement learning
which is
service centre task of artificial intelligence that is how do you
learn to make sequential decisions when i can do is get experience the world so
the robot walking around this room i'm trying to get to the door
a bump in
the chair
abundant here
i don't exactly know how my muscles my legs how it actually made me from
here to there were learned
how does that
you know i think i i a senior nectar
OK so
if i go through december punches me
OK i know that i want to see what about
but avoid punches me i don't know that is hostile
because the thing is i mean the world i don't know how to react to
what i do
but it does not to learn about that and i had seen my goals knowing
my actions affect the world
based on what i observe
OK this is the task of having every first learning it is very much the
in my view of a i
OK so this talk so has two
two aspects the first is RL itself
which is the exact appearance towards an unknown
so gas environment
so action is crucial here we need to do things nation has to affect the
OK so action is crucial
i know it is crucial for all i don't very far away and i had
to sample get experience in actions based on one you always lives in the first
two sections slide is slightly different what you have in your
handouts probably after that of
the slide will
will will be the same as what you have in your hand
also like piston inside the web but they're pretty close
OK this is the first aspect is the learning
OK but what happens if i knew
the full model
well that only learn and i if i know how to react to my actions
there's a learn i just have to do
so there's another aspect of this company and uncertainty
is the sequence of actions again actions
to do the same thing here towards and in this time non stochastic environment
OK so it realized two aspects this talk one is reinforcement learning we learn because
you don't know the environment and the other is
planning because you know the environment the speed the search
this too might in very different but once just the sampling version
the exact inference in the other so the very closely related
OK so i'll trainings
covers many many areas
a research from psychology
how do humans act
sociology how humans act
in the presence of reinforcement from other
in other groups
economics which starts to look at
how we act to achieve monetary rewards
how societies act to achieve
but rewards whether you're micro or macro economists
we answer is a clear science
agents anything it has to act intelligently in the world
has to some aspect of moral planning investing more than one action
if you want the rules theoretician about this is given to statistics house and environment
and decision theory which tells you how you make out up all decisions based on
what you know
this is a continuing here
from descriptive
we're in psychology sociology trying to describe how humans act
two prescriptive in
AI and that's the decision theory where we say
here's how you should act optimally given what you know
OK so we focus on the bottom half year on the descriptive aspects
so especially is especially relevant to a i how does in in agent learn to
learn to act on the environment
OK so there are two aspects one covered in this lecture
one is how do you model these problems
OK maybe not obvious but hopefully by the end of the
is y equals one over text
it's perfectly reasonable to do
we're going to calculate the areas of the triangles and you could ask yourself in
terms of what
well we're going to have to pick up points and given the name and since
we numbering have to do more than geometry we're going to have to do some
of this analysis just as we've done before so i'm going to make a point
and consistent with the labeling we've done before
i'm going to can't
so that's almost half the battle
having notations
x and y for the variables x zero and y zero for the for the
specific point
once you see that you have these labelings
i hope it's reasonable
but to do the following so first of all
this is the point x zero and over here is the pointwise zero
that's something that were
used to
in graphs
and in order to figure out the area of the triangle it's pretty clear that
we should find the base
which is that we to find this location here and we should find the height
so we need to find that out
value there
right so it's
let's go ahead and
and do it
so how are we going to
how are we going to do this
so let's
let's just take a look
so what is it that we need to do
i claim that there's only one calculus step
i'm gonna put a star here
for this tangent line i have to understand what the tangent line
i want to figure out what the tangent line is the rest of the problem
is no longer calculus it's just that slope
that we need
so what's the formula for the tangent line that over here
it's going to be
minus y zero
is equal to and here is the magic number we already calculated it's in the
over there
minus one over x zero square
x minus zero
so this is the only bit of calculus in this problem
but now
we're not done
we have to finish it we have to figure out all the rest of these
quantities so we can figure out the area
all right
so how do we do that
to find this point
this has the name
we're going to find
the so-called interest
the first thing we're going to do
so to do that
what we need to do
it is to find where this horizontal line meets that diagonal line
and the equation for the x intercept
y equals zero
so we plug in y equals zero that's horizontal line we find this point
so let's do that and to start
so we get a zero minus
one other thing we need to know
we know that y zero
it is
f of x zero and f of x is one over at of this thing
one over here
that equal to minus one over zero square
so another to find this
x value
i have two
plug in one equation into the other
so this simplifies a bit
let's put
but see this is
minus tax over breaks zero squared
in this class
one over zero because the axial axial square
council somewhat
so if i put this on the other side
i guess
x divided by x square
is equal to
two over here
and if i then multiply through so that's what this implies and if i multiply
series where i get x equal to two
OK so i claim at this point we just calculated to x right
almost done
i need to get
the other one i need to get this one up here
now i'm going to use a very big shortcut to do that
so the shortcut
two the y intercept is are you going it
to use symmetry
and i claim i can stare at this
i can look at that and i know the formula for the y intercept
it's equal to
two eyes
that's what that one
so this one is true y zero
and the reason i know this
is the following so here's the symmetry of the situation which is
not completely correct it to kind of mirror symmetry around the diagonal
it involves the exchange
x y
with y
the trading the roles of x and y so the symmetry that i'm using is
that any formula get that involves access and wise
if i treat all the axes and replace them by wise and trade otherwise replaced
by axes
now having a correct formula on the other ways of everywhere i see why
making next everywhere cnxn naked why this which will take place so why is that
that's because the that's just an accident of this equation
that's because
so the cemetery explained
is the equation is y equals one over
but that's the same thing as x y equals one final by acts
how people moved around the network
so you
is that
we do this for the data graph
there's always i was so
we're in this
some very interesting problems and this is is one of the system is free of
those trying
to communicate back to korea
time problems this first
some of what the things that help us
they come to your
and when you want to go full
well i don't so
it is personal
more well first of all
of course here is the some of this
well i
talk about west africa on
people charge mobile phones without electricity
the central station
public buildings that
well it
so we're going to see what the intersection of these is to
the first place
the other
this is important to know
and when controversy
OK a
well in the two thousand six
so you want the american sociological review all social isolation america that one question was
discussed before and that's where
and are
i found that the number of people
had declined for me to point nine
nineteen forty two point one two thousand five
and twenty three percent of americans were socialists
and this created a great deal of media morning radio
actually i don't know
what i like about sociology journal
in fact current question social graces the of translation
different question for you personally i think the level of the same year is a
in seventeen
for more see just sort
the state
but question sometimes referred to as the are things falling apart from the decision to
capitalism machine socialisation socialism and to change and the reason is the use of this
frances cairncross
on nineteen ninety six experimental data this
i would say that i still matter
and this i actually like
on the data format
so we go in the english channel once more
and given stuff that's all the food is that this is like
and this is very in the government national made and you have a few people
he was the same sex in the movie but it's
i see that we usually don't use these processes
but what to do
this is part of the new york times and changed use my name
this is
really wants
ten years ago so what's going on
i just to times it is also this but we live something
so there's an more about what happening from the into the
all of being close to be isolated four the numbers before
following along
actually for the shape of the
well these two
but this is a one
you are i am making a density is really
is that in
and we are actually not just
the new social network which is more informative
that goes some of the
one year
are produced for the
change doesn't want to
it's a great way to work in the future
and i wonder using semantic analysis and stuff like that
but i work many chances and questions
to be extremely careful online because they were interested in the question of the same
so people
social networks the world they but it's a
first formats
and if you look at how many people have not seen
this all of
if you look at the social network is not a social network
it so that e
will only going to to grow through
so that social classes problems in part due to surgery
also about its the root of the network and
right so people want to force network individuals individuals organizing unit
for organisation
and that's what we have
as someone was it was carried
the first of those agencies that we
in person-to-person contact
so place to place
the twenty news at ten this question is that for
also we have to move around twenty one community
under the assumption that all all hypothesis are equally likely
to begin with ok
the other thing that's a little bit interesting about this formulation
is that it spells out exactly what your assumptions have been
ok the data drawn heidi we had gaussian noise
applied on top of the true some true hypothesis from the hypothesis
space and this gaussian noise has the same standard deviation for
all the examples ok so under these assumptions the mean squared
error is the right error function in the sense that it is
giving you is going to give you the same hypothesis smacks
likelihood notice also that if your data violates these assumptions
then in some sense using a the sum-squared error is not the right
thing to do okay in particular error
if you have if let's say standard deviations that depend on
the input ok so that some examples are affected by more noise
than others then using the squared error is the wrong thing
to do and what you should do instead of to do a little bit of
math to figure out quite easily is to weight the examples differently
ok and perhaps draw some examples that are affected by to
much noise in order to to fit ok so i'm
not going to show you a little picture here
ok q kind of represent this process ok
and this is going to establish a link to sort of a general class
of machine learning algorithms called graphical models
ok i don't know much to see this pictures i'm doing this week
but i figured that it might be a good idea for you to
actually visualize things this way least once
ok so this is a cartoon of how the data as being generated in the
case case of linear regression that we've talked about ok and there
are the assumption that we talked about so we have some inputs
there's a random variable here x ok that's drawn from some distribution
p of x so each note here is going to be
some kind of a random variable ok and the errors are going to show
sort of influences between these random variables
and at each of these nouns are going to have a conditional distribution
of that particular now given its parents
ok so that's not parents is just drawn from some distribution
which is unknown ok epsom on the noise
is also has no parents is drawn from a normal distribution of mean
zero and some variance sigma that we have some standard deviation
sigma that we don't really know ok
and w here under these assumptions that we use so far is
fixed but unknown ok and so we're going to try to use this model
to infer what w might be given the evidence as being present
ok and the output y is in fact the deterministic note
that does it operation in this case
where it takes the output of the hypothesis that depends on w
and x and that's the noise comes from maps ok
so in this case some of the variables are observed some of the
variables are on observe ok we can see x and we can see why
but we don't actually c epsilon nor do we see w
ok and we actually don't really know the parameter of the probability
distribution that governs epsilon either
so this is going to be a very typical case where you have data
you have some observed variables you kind of know there
are some other variables that are important
but you don't see them those are called hidden or latent variables
and a lot of the time we're going to try to build the model that
infers these variables the probability distributions and the
values from data ok the other thing that's interesting about this
model is that it points out places where we could make more interesting
assumptions ok so for example here we have assumed that w
is fixed by know ok because when you're maximum likelihood but
now let's assume that w f the random variable
case of w as a random variable then it might be drawn from some
probability distribution ok then we're moving towards beijing
setting where we actually have priors over the parameters
and we can use the data to infer a posterior probability distribution
over the parameters ok
when you see
but if you plug in the numbers he needs to be astonishingly close to flat
but not quite
because if it was exactly zero
then if not to be point one
so this is the flatness problem
you quickly find that very early on one minus some again to be less than
ten to the minus sixty this is like balancing paying ceylon its the
coming back years later in still finding defensive that is balancing on stick
it's obviously quite unlike
that's the flatness
the other problem is the eyes and problem remember there are different type of horizons
in cosmology since lights travel the final speed the universe is expanding you can define
the particle horizon which is the maximum ca moving distance light can have propagated between
some time initial to sometimes fine so to do that you need to write an
integral you put a of team here in these kind of equation counts for all
the past expansion history of the universe remember it's function is that it could be
we may not have been constant the time because different components at different times started
dominating so this is a of the may like different powers of t and can
even go exponentially if you are dominated by the cosmological constant
on the other hand you can define the hubble arise remember se over HRC over
zero which is the
the age of the
universe today
and for an ottoman expansion is thirty these quantity and see over dates
at about the same
but before we the expansion history thirty be worse
four where this function is very c of h may be very very different from
this one
so there is some problem
the universe is homogeneous and isotropic and very large scale considered twenty people points in
the cosmic microwave background there are separated by
times these
these how would this time basically fifty thousand men parts today
so what was the hubble radius
back then
and first and the expansion history there but reduces the problem arises
well if i do that i end up to this point to make about six
so all the points at point omega passing distance could have talk to each other
what is
these the size of the eyes and back then the cosmic background of the last
scattering surface can i see with my i
the size of the eyes and the CMB
it's the size of about one degree
in other words to look at this map
the typical size of the block is the size of the eyes and then it's
fine to that six and indeed it's more or less that
pedigree scale that they see this speak
OK and it makes sense because an upper division college took which are they could
have acoustic waves remember that this sound speed at that time was very close to
the speed of light difference by the square root of three
so how does this by now that is the three kelvin this point also should
not have to because
if they could not the doctor it
now today is different because it seems the universe has expanded and for most of
the life of the universe expansion was slowing down then our set of about patch
has grown compared to parts back then because the this function has been slowing down
and sold well today we can see
side two spots on the CMB that are the opposite end but back then the
could not have talked to each
so the last surface can be divided in forty thousand pages of degree size that
is forty thousand eyes
how could they will be about three kelvin imagine forty thousand students taking an example
quite complicated one returning the same example down to the commas and the mistakes
now you start thinking they must have talk to each other somehow right
then there is what is called the monopole problem in the very early universe a
lot of phase transition went on and you know that when you have phase transition
and there was the fact the model that you know if you have one that
was completely messed up all your reservation
so the figures out of the main will cause means three except accepted accepted
so the fact that we are here it means that the maximum there is only
one monopole in the entire observable universe if there's more than that were talks
another questions what the heck this perturbation then come from if this is the eyes
of OK
what the heck this perturbation come from
well created them
so the theory of inflation come to the rescue
inflation started in the eighties with all angles and is still very very active research
area is still a paradigm in the sense that we have proven
but you will see that you keep one there the sorry