also help me choose the correct number of clusters
so it looks like a very promising tool
we view
stability is a measure of fit between the probability distribution and a clustering model
but it fails when the clustering model is not aligned with the input data
and so we we therefore can use it as a model selection tool and that's
the way it's being used is about selection tools you want to select the right
model the right algorithm the right number of k
for your data
you estimate the instability of your algorithm on your data
and you choose the algorithm all parameters that maximize the stability
that's the way it's being used as a model selection tool
and now we try
to prove that really works
we looked at two different algorithm basic on incentive-based like k
i mean the linkage based algorithms and we look at the very simple set of
that think this a synthetic state of the mixture of gaussians all
mixture of tree because
a this uniform distribution and we could prove that in all those cases
those two types of these types of that
we could prove that in all these cases stability correctly detected the right word and
the right number of clusters
this is the proof now it's not the
you could but in order to prove it we need to restrict our attention to
very specific distributions you can
very difficult to prove
that would be the correct number of clusters for every distribution but was the nation's
and we also have experimental results show that was very nicely so here for example
i want doing here is i have my distribution is this swiss roll with three
different components so there is chocolate vanilla and
something j
three different companies in your swiss roll
and you want to be able to claim and the and and doing a single
linkage clustering and my parameter
is when do i stop matching points
so if i choose the distance
for matching points too large then get this kind of
picture where it connects points across
different layers
if i choose my distances
to be a
my my threshold to be point fifteen i get is very nice but fissioning into
three rules
if i choose my
threshold to be too small
factions into small
and the question is so we know
the correct for this is that the correct value of threshold should be point fifteen
can stability detected for me
we have this very nice picture well
here i draw the instability with different threshold values
and here in order to know whether i got the correct thing or not i
what i draw here is the percentage of points that fall into the third largest
so if you have ten clusters are just looking at the
and what percentage of four of points fall
and because we know that it was generated by three roads
we want wanted to sound
largest cluster will contain a sort of the point
and if we compare the graph of instability with different values and
the size of the largest cluster we see that the instability beautiful it attacks the
values to give you the correct clustering police
this implies this this empirical but we can also prove that it does so in
the situation was
two o five the situation was very nice
we could formally we formally define the notion of stability
we could argue that necessary property of any clustering method we could prove that really
works for those very simple distributions like mixture of gaussians swiss roll
we so we could prove that it works very nicely and also very nicely in
so everybody was happy and we said
in the beginning of two after the beginning of january to the sixth or you
can look for domain was my student we set to prove you know to put
the final nail into the structure to prove that stability really does what you want
because they have all the possible evidence
it's a question of how do
from what is the correct job but i don't know about that
but then
we started working on this and
we started seeing some
things which are not so
satisfactory so consider for example
these two
datasets and assume that you have some k bigger than one
what happened here will be stable and not just take a random sample want to
cluster into three sets
then another random sample clustering trees that that's my generating distribution would be stable we
shift all the time
the shift over the time right but what happened here
if made that
it will be stable
but it is a very small change of my that
if i take the position into three sets
eventually what you get is just
three sets like this but here was unstable now
and so the the number of correct number of
clusters is three
you cannot really argue that the correct number three here
not you but stability doesn't detect it
so we started seeing those fun examples and then we could turn them into a
so the bottom line of our analysis which lasted more than a year
in fact only amplitudes at the same
that means the total effect
that you get some of the two
pictorial some of the two
is then going to be too easier realizing call it easier
and then i get the cosine of half the songs
i get the cosine
of omega t
minus delta divided by two
the cosine of half the difference
that becomes the cosine of delta phi phi
now you see why the light intensity
is proportional to the cosine square
delta all two
because when you calculate
the mean value of the point is that you have to cross we
b also has this and also has this
so you get the square of this term and the square of this
but the average of the square of is one
get that for now
so you see is going to be proportional
the square
of two
and so this function that you're seeing
delta is limited proportional to science data
this graph that you
is a cosine square curve
the experiment and show you
has a
separation of the
which is one quarter
my wavelength six hundred ten
thirty three nanometers which is very much the same
and the distance
is about five metres
so the way that
we have this arrangement is that two slits
like this so this separation is one point four millimetre
and then we put over there
a laser beam
and then the result is what you're going to see there
and so
i think about
you see there in order for you to see
i have to make it
when you're up here on the screen
you will see areas which i distinctly dark
you see areas where by
the light in other words
you see the pattern that we just calculated you see
constructive interference
and you see destructive interference
you're looking at an experiment
it is historically of great importance
it is one of the most mysterious and puzzling issues
in all
of physics
interference patterns
it was first shown by young eighteen or what
it's clearly convincing evidence that lights
is away from home
twenty century physics
has shown that light comes in the form of individual photons
with well defined energies
and photons
and behavior
like bullets they have momentum they use radiation pressure
and they can be localized in space
we can detect individual photons in a way that we detect individual
like particles
however the interference that you're staring at on the screen it can only be explained
if we assume that each photon
i went through both slits
but how on earth can one particle
through both slits
it will have to be
one slit
or the other
and here lies the great mystery
is both
it is always if you want to be away
and is the particle if you wanted to be a particle
if you manage
to determine for every photo
which of the two slits it went
and that is possible
do it low light intensity you can rename determined
through which of the two slits each photon went then you will not see any
interference anymore
the pattern on the screen will be like that all the tomatoes you get to
so the moment that you establish
the particle character of the lights
by determining
through which slit it when you have destroyed its weight character
and it will not
behave like we will behave
like particles
however as long as you do not determine through which slit the photon went
does as long as it remains your guess
so which one it when lights were revealed to you
it's wave character
and you will see interference
the choice is yours
but you cannot both ways
so you can now
that's something that had a huge impact
on physics
clearly at the time that this experiment was done
it was accepted
now look at it
in very different ways
i want to show you slides
all of this
what we call double slit interference in white light we did it in red light
that's the easiest to very sharply defined next
and the reason why you get so sharply defined
because you don't have the interference of the other class
but of course if you do it with white light
then you will see the light
it has its own spacing in the red light has its own spaces
and the net result of course is that you
c is somewhat different
and that also here
the dark for that upper
is that the double slit interference
blue light
you see clearly dark
o lines which
the destructive interference locations
and you see as i already indicated on the blackboard separation of the red is
larger wavelength and
and if you then do with white light
you see something like this more difficult to
actually see the maximum
and the minimum
now what you can do
with light if you can
two light was light into darkness
then obviously you should also be able
for some time
it's just a matter of scaling up the whole experiment
and that's what we have
so that for you here
we have two loudspeakers
so only equations that you have here
except that we can
so are d is no longer
according the media but are is no one and a half metres
so here is the source of sound
and was the source of
and they
i said by the same electronics
in the appendix
and the properties of trees that i want to read
OK because you actually prove that kind of thing rather than it just being
obvious which is OK
OK so we know that then
two is partitioned
call them t one
thirty two
so here's one seven three
and here's another tree partition
no matter what age i picked there will be two subtrees
this partition into even if the subtree
it is trivial symmetry for example just has a single node and no edges
so theorem proof
a property of optimal substructure
t one
now spanning tree
for the graph
g one
the subgraph
in t one
that is
v one is just the vertices in t one
this is what it means to be induced
OK so the one is the vertices in t one
so in this picture
i believe what is t one
fifty two
in this picture
these are the vertices of t one so that's the one
and the one is the set of
pairs of vertices x and y
that are
the edges there in e one such that
both x and y
long to be one
OK so i'm showing the edges of g here
but basically
given an edge one from here to here that would be in one
if one from here to here it wouldn't
everyone from here to here it would not
so the vertices of the graph subgraph induced by the vertices of t one or
just those
connect up things in v one
and similarly for t two
the theorem says that if i look at
just the edges
within the graph here
g one
those are induced by these vertices t one is in fact the minimum spanning tree
four that subgraph
that's what the theorem says
OK if i look it over here conversly
if i look at this
the set of edges that are induced
by this is
the set of vertices to vertices in t two
in fact he two is the minimum spanning tree on that subgraph
we can even do it over here
if i took a look for example at these
let's see what should we do if we cut out some edge like
five say we cut out five
i cut out age five then t one would be
four vertices here
and the point is that if i look at the subgraph induced on that that's
these pages here
in fact the six eight three are all
edges in the minimum spanning tree
for that subgraph
so that's what the theorem says so let's prove
OK so what technique many is to prove it
OK we learn this technique last time
and hand
something you do in your text editor all the time
and each crosses one person one researcher in the network network has roughly two hundred
fifty researchers
and it's so the idea of this reservation was to visualize
to visualize
all the people within the network in such a way that people which are working
in a similar and that they would be closer on the feature in the area
which are kind of desert so what would be represented as topics
and visualize them in three d then would see this geographical map
if we assign
assigned names to
to the people
and reduces down just the most productive people so this would be
based on the number of
publications in the database so each person here is presented by the abstracts of the
papers which he could contribute it's person contributed to the project samy bengio so he
was very productive so he he was the most active and then if he refuses
some other people would start appearing so appearing so this would be the most
product two
people seeing the metric
i'm certainly not the most productive but not last
OK so this would be the people in asia
the content of the people that
the next
element which we have a picture of so-called
common words
OK we saw the but
seven people appear in certain parts of the map but we are also interested in
what this part of the math actually talks about what the topic of this
it was the topic of the documents which lie
in that particular part of the man
here this
why would with
would be the most basic keywords
from the documents which are
kind of
positioned in that part of the
so here we can see
roughly that
in this part
this would be documents related to document natural language processing web mining text mining can
so on this would be documents from
multimedia mining division and so on and this will be dewey and and and
analysis of that here we have one small additional element which helps us to see
this article as well
the average the position the circle we get the most typical
keywords from that area so
so here we see that the area of their so described with this was like
images object features
segmentation it's also this would be typical keywords for the analysis of multimedia data
computer vision and so on while this would be more like text mining semantic web
and so on and this would be the theory
so this is another element which helps us observing this document collection
if we add the name sense
check this
document in
three d
it is not safe this environment so this is not the whole landscape
threat to fly a little bit into the
you OK see basically this is the same as we saw before
except that now we can
see the whole thing can be closed
five percent
the top is
why should be somewhere here
here are so
and this would be the worst which would become
so we can it was always important whenever showing these maps
these guys who is in the top of the hill because this is been you're
the guy
this is the view from text or the
this would be
OK so this this is kind of
fun at least i mean to to see
this was among media it's also here
so this is kind of
visualisation of
we can also in you of course see
this would be this text and visual arts like this
so this is really solution of static static database why this could be interesting not
by itself is already may be interesting to see
what's the structure of certain text corpus but as a component or some model which
is accompanied by some other functions
analyzing text corpus or a
let's say for later on we will see this ontology learning model then so in
combination with some other functionality this can get very useful just because it shows that
this high level structure of a lot of data
and this one single image
especially if you are not familiar with the content of that particular
cork was and this can be very helpful
now i will show in the same
how the text can be visualized also through time
so this is no visualization of
three hundred thousand news
stories new stories
which corresponds to
new stories from
you know it is tempered by choosing data this is hard to read here but
as you point nine o point eight six and you run this template the EM
algorithm you see kind of curse because like this right you can see that convergence
is slower
so it takes longer until it actually picks up but then you can see that
you you know that no overfitting takes place at least here in the in the
sixty iterations shown and also that what you reaching the end is better than what
you would reach for instance here he would do early stopping or something like that
right you know what you could do here to regularize this is basically just stop
at that point you know it would be
if you could hit exactly that point that would be the best you can do
but you know but with this trick you can actually get models that are a
little bit better than that
OK so this is not a very principled approach i would show more principled approach
if you know how how to do that
in the next couple of slides OK but so so this
this much about this probabilistic latent semantic analysis models
another i'd like to
talk about an extension
that has been called latent dirichlet allocation LDA
was proposed by david blyth and rating and michael jordan
and and that's basically an improvement of killers a or generalisation in certain bayesian sense
and in LDA
it works as follows it's actually it's a generative model for documents
OK so what we do is we generate
documents we ignore the sequence of the words
so we don't really
but so what we generate basically is is bag of words not documents in terms
of sentence structure and things like that so what we do is this is the
following we first sample
the length of the documents which is called the capital and
according to that's a simpler song
some rate parameter excited
and then we choose
four that document a particular
the mixing proportions
according to some dirichlet distributions
and we have hyperparameters of here
and then once we have these mixing proportions we now choose for each of the
words that we want to generate OK we decided we want to generate and of
the market so the loop over n
we independently choose a topic according to a multinomial distribution with these pies are now
the probabilities of you you know picking
you know what the spinal specifies is the probability of a particular concept
given our document right and what we do here is now is we sample a
concept actually from that distribution
and then given that we've sampled the topic we know sample the particular word
from that is from a distribution
that corresponds to what we've seen before the probability of generating a particular word given
a particular concept
right so
so this is
the way
and the a works notes that the main difference is
that we think of
these mixing proportions here
as another random variable
that's how the distribution immediately distribution whereas in the pillars a model we thought of
it actually is a set of parameters e for each document we would basically have
a set of parameters that would be these mixing proportions we just estimated and here
we just make it part of the model that also allows us to you know
this is a random variable we can basically also integrate out these variables OK we
have additional latent variables we can integrate them yes
we have already
so we will
you know we get the following
model we
i have a probability over these these high vector these mixing proportions which is unknown
the latent concepts now thought of as a vector of n concept variables for a
particular document and then actually observed
word frequencies of the observed word for this document
and we can then write down to the following model year
so the probability for pi just depends on the hyperparameters that additional distribution right can
be written like this
a bunch of gamma functions over there and then just
you know these probabilities raised to the power of five minus one of hyperparameters
and even here we just generated independently the the words that belong to this document
so we sample
the concept according to that distribution
and then we sample the word for each particular concert according to that
and what we can do now is
for instance
we can define now distribution over documents model by these words vectors right remember document
is now we think of as being a vector of word counts
and we can do that by taking this
and by integrating out the
latent variables these would be the highest
and then by summing out
the discrete latent variables these would be the concept
you can do to the independence of these we can actually pull is in here
and and some over here
for each individual
so we get these empirical distributions for player one and player two
what i regret things says is that look
how well i've done
in the sequence is at least as well
i don't list as well this is correct as the best they could have done
from playing any single action
in hindsight almost at least as well minus some small termites decreasing with the length
of the sequence in fact and doing almost as well as i could have done
within a mixed strategy
because if you compare itself to some opponents playing some fixed strategy
and you're look regret from playing any single strategy in the mixed strategy
it's the same
because you know
if i if i know what is going to do at least distribution i got
some best response and then i got a bunch of
or maybe multiple best responses but
i might as well just choose the best response to single and i don't have
to randomize
but anyway
what we're doing at least as well
as the best
mixed strategy response
in particular
what this means is that while the opponent is probably
this term here the point is probably best off choosing these babies according to
the right rule at least
to to screw over senses zero something he's going to choose them to minimize the
payoff to do that he knows that
released for this inequality to estimate minimize this inequality
the worst case would be where beta is the distribution mu that minimizes
player one's payoff if player two we're just trying to speak
we know we get at least as much
for the data which is bigger than if
we do just shows the distribution it's going to minimize that
and similarly for the second player you get the same thing except passing negative the
opposite of each of these so
when you negate this and do it in the opposite order so this new you
get the same
same thing here
but in the opposite order and you get that
the payoff to player two is most this
and this is exactly the opposite these two terms are equal here
so this is exactly the opposite of
what we had before
right so
we have the maximum we knew from before the going first is disadvantage and we
see these two things are equal because this holds for any enemy i mean
so we could imagine conceptually playing this game for a very long time and then
show that these two things are arbitrarily close together and therefore there must be equal
so not only is this a proof of minimax so it's it's kind of strategy
for playing repeated games
using this weighted majority and is pretty reasonable
i think OK so basically the weighted majority gives very simple proof of the minimax
in which essentially says this for every game zero sum game is the value of
the game and you can guarantee yourself in this value by playing the weighted majority
in fact is in the weighted majority
you get regret going to zero regardless of upon so if your opponent
is playing really stupidly
you might even be able to really tapped capitalize
on you might be able to be needed for playing tic-tac-toe this algorithm if find
that strategy
so i think it's a very
clean theorem for the zero-sum game game case
what's going on in the
general sum games where things don't add up to zero
there's a lot more murky there is still a lot of research going into what
what should happen what does happen what should go on the learning in this case
so in general game like take a look at this game
coordination games
we we really want choose a or b like let's say
let's say my friend and i like to both play pool
or you know good baseball game we prefer to go to a baseball game or
play pool
reaching choose but if one of us
to play pool and the other one is the baseball game
we're not very happy to one
coordinate and she's the same thing
and for this kind of game there actually three
for this particular game actually three equilibria
one of them would be
choose a relevant both to be
and the third being mixed strategy i think probably one-third two-thirds
where we choose where we mix between a and b k
in general these games can have very many equilibria
it's kind of interesting
as long as not to generate i think they number of equilibria
there's a lot of it's very hard factors
nobody knows how to find an equilibrium
one of these games
officially nobody knows how to find the nash equilibrium of
a two player game
represented in matrix in terms of efficiency when they think about it is polynomial time
algorithms that big open problem
in the theoretical theory literature one of the criticisms actually the big criticisms of nash
equilibrium is
if it's such a natural idea and you really think that explains how people play
you can find one
in the game then how natural is that
in proc
you know
all parties
long beach
gang member of the system of many particles could be connected with springs
could be chemical explosions going on the could flow into each other they break each
other up
and you know momentum will not change
if there is no net external to work on that system because all the internal
torques taught cancel out because actions
equals minus reaction
so if we know
compare conservation of angular momentum with conservation of momentum
and in the case
of the conservation of momentum remember when we had a system of objects
in the absence of external force
on the system as a whole
net external force
momentum was conserved
now we have
a system of particles in the absence of the net
external torque
angular momentum is conserved
in the case
of the
i scale is the light
when you pull your arms in
the moment of inertia goes down
and so you frequency goes up
when the star strings
radius goes down
its moment of inertia
goes down
and therefore
it's angular velocity
must go up
moment of inertia
because we are squid
what determines the size of a star
this is a the
inside the star is inference nuclear furnace
fusion is going on
that produces
and pressure
which wanted to expand the start
on the other hand there is gravity
which is sorry
you can do that
i want to
all together
in fact gravity would like to collapse
nature finds a balance between
the gravity and this pressure due to
and the nuclear furnace
now comes the time
that the nuclear furnace has been completely consume
for that takes an additional five billion years
the sun has already been burning nuclear fuel for five billion years
there's no five billion
and once the nuclear fuel has been consumed
there are three and products
of the
dead star that's left over
and these three and products
the following
number one
it's called a white dwarf
it has a radius approximately the same as the rest
ten thousand kilometres
and the mass of the white dwarf there's a whole range of them
but the typical number say is half the mass of the sun
that's one possible and problem
this will be the fate of our sun by the way
the density of such an object is quite high ten two do
be roughly ten two to six
cubic centimeter
another possibility is
that you end up with a neutron star
neutron star has a radius of about ten kilometres
it has a mass
of roughly
one point five times the mass of the sun
and its density
it's about ten to fourteen grams per cubic centimeter
which is even higher
the density of nuclei
and then there is the possibility
which is even more bizarre
thank you and up
with the black hole
i will not talk about black holes today but i will get back to that
in in one
and the black hole
for all practical purposes
has no size at all
the mass of the black
must be larger than
we think three solar masses
and so the density
it is infinitely high
whether you end up to be white dwarf neutron star or black hole depends on
mass of the of the
the progenitor star that collapses
when the fuel in nuclear fools garden
and in order to form a neutron star you would have to start off
with the star of probably at least ten solar masses maybe even more
so our sun will not
become a neutron star but our sun will ultimately become
a white dwarf
i would be reasonable question to ask why do you end up only with these
three possibilities why is there nothing in between
note that is a huge difference from ten thousand kilometres ten kilometres is there nothing
in between
and the answer to that lies in quantum mechanics which is not part of this
course but you'll see that in eight o five
why only these two
and then if you get into general relativity then you understand why
there is then this third
very bizarre possibilities
when the star collapses
two things happen
first of all
there is a huge amount of gravitational potential energy
that is released in the form of kinetic energy
the stuff full then we call gravitational collapse and the gravitational potential energy converts to
kinetic energy and that ultimately
converts to heat
and to radiation
if i take an object here
these of chuck
and i dropped that
that you can call gravitational collapse
gravitational potential energy is converted to kinetic energy
and ultimately
it goes
two heat
we're talking about star
which is
and the amount of
gravitational potential energy that become available
are enormous
in vision
so this huge amount of energy released
the trick will be that the empirical risks the training error only refers to M
and all functions take the values output values plus minus one so our functions on these
M points can take at most two to the part of M values so on M points
the function class has effectively maximum size of two to the power of M
oh there's a question
so this these are different sets they could they could overlap they don't have
to be disjoint I guess that's what you to mean it's likely before
so if they
if they are not disjoint
then this quantity here is nonzero which means when we are doing this upper bound we are losing
something if they were disjoint then we would be losing less than our
bound and then would be sharper so we might loose a lot if
these events overlap
so I mean through this jointness of events is something that's similar to what you mean by
independence right independence is a pro property of a probability measures if we just look at the
events we would normally be talking about whether the are disjoint or mutually exclusive so
okay so we use a trick to reduce the infinite case to the finite case and
this is the so-called symmetrization lemma Vapnik and Chervonenkis and
this I'm not gonna prove this but I think you will believe me when you hear it this lemma says
that the probability
that training error and test error
differ by model upsilon can be upper bounded by the twice the probability that two
different training errors
differ from each ofther by model upsilon over two
so if if these two
things if by drawing two sets of training points if you you if by doing
this you cannot get
training errors that are very different from each other then we can also guarantee that
the training error and the test error cannot be very different it's again some kind of triangle inequality type argument
so which means now we need a training set of twice the size
and maybe maybe we you ignore this down here now
this is just for details if you want to look at it afterwards
again but basically means rather than
having this quantity here which is the this integral over the whole probability distribution that we don't know
if we are only interested in upper bounding this quantity we can first upper bound it by
this thing here and the nice thing about this is that this is a term that only involves
M points this is a term that only involves N points so if we can
somehow upper bound this guys by using some tricks that rely on the function class being
effectively finite we can do it over here because this these quantities referred to
finitely many points and as I mentioned before in that case the function classes are effectively finite
so what we are therefore interested in is the maximum size of our function class
on two M points and this is sometimes called the shattering coefficient we denote it by
this calligraphic N so this can be also generalized to the case of real valued outputs
functions and people look at things like covering them was in that case but we only look at classification here and
this shattering coefficient and let me remind you what it means so the size of a
function class plus minus one valued function class on two M points is
the maximum number of different outputs
that the function class can generate on two M points
we will consider two functions that are that give the same outputs on
our two M point we will consider them equivalent there's no way for us to
distinguish them and therefore
we are only interested in how many such functions they are and
if you think of the output vectors so the output vectors are of plus minus
one plus one whenever we have
correctly separated the points they are minus one if we have done it the
other way round so if we have assigned a point to the other class sorry
the plus one or
no actually this that's true they are plus one or minus one so I was not sorry I
have to take back what I just said so I could also do this in terms
of the loss functions but it's not done like this here so these are just plus one minus one
how many output vectors can we generate them to M points in other words
how many how many different ways can we ways can we classify the points
in two classes
and of course each point could go either in the one class or the other
one and there's an upper bound at this quantity which is two to the part of two M
and if this upper bound is actually pertained
then the function class is said to shatter the two M points it means that we can realize
all possible class assignments using functions from our class so for instance the function class has
maximum richness or maximum capacity on sets of points of size two M
so now we put everything together
to get our bound so we first use the symmetrization
so this symmetrization lemma to get rid of this test error this quantity that depends
on the unknown probability measure that's integral over this probability measure to get two quantities that are both
only depending on M points
we then
say and I'll be cheating a tiny little bit here and if you want to know details I
can either give you something to read or I can tell you afterwards but I don't want
to go into great detail here
then I'm basically saying well on my my function class on these two M points
has a size calligraphic N this shattering coefficient so that means I have a calligraph
I can
effectively the size of function class is this thing here so I pick functions F one through F
sub N and rewrite this as a union of all these events then I apply the
union bounds so each of these things
stick breaking construction it counts splits those two apart so in the stick breaking construction
count very easy to see right so the values that is assigned to the clusters
is going to be the state that is going to be independent from the price
and the
and so we can treat those two parts separately and then we can now infer
is rhythms turns out to be more efficient
yes if you change one of the state state status is going to change the
of all the state assigned to that trust
should move on so
another interesting property of the dirichlet process is that it turns out that posteriors of
dirichlet processes also
dirichlet processes under the the following scheme so if g is drawn from a dirichlet
process and theta one two theta and
drawn i i d from g
then the posterior g
given theta one theta and
conditioning on one
the is
going to be a dirichlet process as well with the following update the concentration parameter
and base distribution
not that this base distribution is in fact exactly the same as
and this is
except that
instead and minus one half plus one as and in here is basically the original
base distribution mixed with
a bunch of delta functions one in each of the values of theta one theta
OK so referring to
one of the question that was asked
if we look at the polya urn scheme right so we have this conditional distributions
that we can now write down so this is in fact a density
so is actually the joint density of theta one two theta
and we can
and we can write this down as basically the
the probability of theta one times probability of theta two given theta one probability of
the tree given theta one and two
and we can
and the probabilities are basically given by this
because this conditional distributions and if you
right down the probability then it turns out that it caused to form which looks
like the following
one of the things the world
he is actually not as the
o thing
OK i look and this very naive something which is right now either the probability
of the densities in life multiply them together and you can work so i guess
you can
think of this as the density on on it probably on on the union space
where each
of the
each of the spaces in this union space corresponds to having a different number of
anyway sluggish easily see is that
this probability is
independence of the ordering in which
in which
the theta
in which the fate has come in
so if we had reordered the fate test so for example
in this case is they're calling this data one of this code the three four
and according to one
and maybe according to the two ends the tree
then the probability that we have down here
of this permuted sequence
it's still exactly the same because it actually doesn't depend on the ordering of the
so this problem probably this property is called exchangeability to say is that the joint
distribution is invariant to permutations of theta one two theta
and that's that's a pretty
that's a really fundamental
actually held by definitely
actually definitely didn't actually proved the most
most general result by people typically refer to it as the sister
it just says that if you have a joint distribution is exchangeable
then there must be a random probability measure which makes them independent
OK so
so i'll actually stayed
in the case of the polya urn scheme then this random probability measure turns out
to be the dirichlet process
so here's the statement theorem
so if we have a distribution on i want to see and
that is invariant to permutations what this is therefore any permutation
this probability is going to be equal to the probability where we have permitted the
indices of data
and this has to be true for every n
for every positive integer n and if that's the case then we say that the
sequence is infinitely exchangeable
and if a sequence is infinitely exchangeable
in this case here know that the only thing we require is that
that that
the distribution is invariant to permutations it doesn't say that the state has has to
be independent
in fact in the case of the polya urn scheme to think that are not
independent but what the theorem states that there exists a latent we can imagine
there is a random infinite dimensional parameter in this case g
such that
we can write the joint distribution of theta one and theta and
the marginal distribution
where we have a prior on g
each of the things ties are independent given g
so this is the probability of data i
given g
and we can do without g
so we can always write a joint distribution here
where the fetus may not be independent
but there are infinitely exchangeable
as this
the marginal distribution of
OK so and poultry eggs from the kunzman in canada france
i'm going to talk about
machine learning and vision
in the first lecture will
almost entirely the low-level features and the visual signals so when talk very much about
things like object recognition until the second lecture
that's kind of deliberate because
machine and people who start to use vision
often don't have the basics of vision
nineteen ten two
take an image turn into a list of pixels apply kernel to doesn't work very
and the reason is that there's a lot of technology vision itself so i think
it's probably bit of machine learning people to get an overview of what the technologies
and vision
seeing some of the object recognition things
OK if you have any questions stop me interrupt that's fine
OK so the two lectures
all start talking about the visual signal
so this is from human vision something about the statistics of natural images
now talk about low-level features in the next lecture we'll talk about things like object
prominent different order from this image classification and indexing things like that
OK so why is visual recognition hard
if you start doing defined it's really quite hard task we've made a lot of
progress in recent years so hard one thing is very close international natural object classes
so see some examples in the second
the second thing and all the fixed you have a problem
images so
lighting variations contrast variation shadowing specularities
then there's a whole lot of things to do with genetic variability so
translations and rotations within the image scaling and translations when the objects move and it's
also rotations and it's and perspective effects
the three d world is a complex place and when you created into an image
things getting more complex
and in this
carter inclusion so basically anything in the image that we don't want to detect we
don't want to recognise
is going to be a problem for us
this is common for the signals
the signal processing tasks
and the context is extremely important in vision c need to somehow get some of
context from this class that's bothering you
use for the detection task but you don't really want to be distracted by too
much in the other reason that visual recognition is how just seems so damned good
that they don't realize how difficult it is
if you start looking at
images in detail pixels in detail
you find the
you don't understand why you are going to to start working
if you look at the image little piece of pixel the algorithm looking at you
don't understand what it doesn't you see it in a bigger context so
humans have this amazing ability to kind of integrating integrate the information they see that
the whole image
which we currently don't really have
and we're working on but it's hard to do
so there are some reasons why visual recognition is hard
so natural object classes faces you can see got changes imposed got sunglasses
changes in lighting
inclusions and parenting modern telephones
anything can happen visual class dogs
it's difficult
and you have a lot of knowledge about the class to say what the images
have in common
have some things in common but it's not very obvious and then across light years
which is kinda
structural or functional classes the class defined by the thing having a surface that you
can sit on
it's not really visual class
we can probably make detectors which is the work for many churches but we never
going to make it to take two weeks for all chairs into we understand the
way the human environment works what kinds of services are allowed to be set on
things like this
so there's a lot of kind of domain information it's non visual
we have to do have to put into the system if we really want to
but probably
so given that small physical things
the effects of lighting so here are some images
the same face seen from the same viewpoint anything was changing the lighting
as a human you probably think OK let's face i've no problem seeing it
i can email you recognised it's the same person but if you actually look at
the pixel level
you find the
you know the value of a pixel one position just changes completely there's not really
anything that's in the raw image that will tell you what the thing is so
you don't have to do some kind of preprocessing to understand
what's going on with the lighting before you can start doing recognition similarly specularities these
bright spots on the sun glasses because the light they're very bright saturated skin here
cameras often saturate you don't see it if you look at it because you say
used is human but it tends to throw off image processing routines
may not be able to tell what it is it's two parts with lighting
they can
something here or with the graphical models the semantics
you know it too finely lunch
on at the beach
on the side bring is we go with another thing i'm making edits on the
slides and either the couple's lives plus yesterday
so i'm going to make the new set of slides available
at the end of this
actually during the meeting already copied
OK so
let's go to the case of expectation
we have proposed that some not unknown x
we have some data
we have been able to to learn the first let's assume we have estimated the
posterior distribution
of the unknown given the data so far
and what we're interested in computing the expectation of functions
f of x could be just x in which case we just want the mean
of the posterior
or if you're interested in the various we would have x minus the mean
and so on so
that is f of x to be something that allows to get any properties of
this distribution
so this is how we do it this is how we do
among the carla for these problems
we simulate
a bunch of points
from this distribution
and also and explain how it fact that's the whole point of this these lectures
had that simulation
but let's assume we have found simulation
so you have a bunch of points simulate sort of where this higher probability you've
generator these things
so it's kind of think of this as the inverse
in learning we have these data points and we try to come up with this
kernel density estimate that's what
we were doing yesterday
now we're doing the opposite we have the distribution
we generated data
in fact and you could use this to publish papers because they generated data and
then you say that this is the solution to it
and it will get a very good fit
it was in the paper that that called
they they to set selection
so basically and you come up with the model generated data from the model and
then you reconstruct the model from that date
o thing is that is lot of truth that a lot of people to separated
with the model in the reconstruc
the data with the same argument only works very well surprise
once we
sample these points
we've been them in some sort of way
for simplicity let's say that we doing an histogram bin
and that then approximation gives as an approximation
this is the posterior distribution
OK so we have an approximation of the effects given date in green
in reality
we don't need to construct this approximation to solve an integral
that's that's kind of it's very very important point
because constructing kernel density estimation in very high dimensions the not gonna make any sense
all we want to sample to computers
again if this guy is replaced by a delta function
so if we care about the mean motion is used to replace phi delta function
after me
then you only need one sample two
do this
we care about
this guy the estimate
we don't care so much about thanksgiving feast and this we really care about
but in general we focus on the estimate
so basically what we do is the same thing
this basically
you can think of this depends just delta function you could replace the centre of
the ben by delta function
and the delta function
can the colour
there's the delta function here of size two
delta function of size four
maybe delta function of size three and one of size two
and then one of size one
so you're replacing
the distribution by the the representation
and then again by the properties of the delta function
when you replace all these functions here
all you get is the function evaluated at each of those delta functions
so the monte carlo estimate than
this thing will be replaced just by the sum
of i call one
two and
one over n
of f of
that's monte carlo integration
i'm going to it here because i mean that that's the very much the most
important thing
so we have on equal
suppose we want to mean
let's say a new
call x
p of x given data
what we do is we construct an approximation of the effects given data
which will be equal
his it's a bunch of delta function
we normalize this so that they sum to one because we have probability that's why
i have one over n
and it dealt
and the one below there can kill this one so i can always identify two
pairs with kill each other
that means dark
so this must be a criterion for destructive interference that may not be the only
angles for which there is that structure but i want to convince you that there
is at least one for which is you know
i will now introduce
the phase angle bay
which is the phase difference between source one and source two
this is the
one side of the split in the middle it's not the phase angle between two
neighbouring sources because the neighbouring sources touch each other as an infinite number of point
sources to continuous working source
so it is the phase angle between the
edges of the slit in the centre of the that's the way i define data
so my better now
two by
divided by land
one of the
i'm sign
so you see
one of each of the two so you can
divided by lambda
sign of
no i will not the right for you as i did
so precisely for gratings i will not the rifle you what the light intensity is
a function of angle
again it is a matter of
adding vectors
but you can look it up in the back of your parents down in section
eight seven
so i will only give you the answer
i did it for grading
you do this one
and you can show now that
the intensity of the light as a function of that
base angle better
is i zero
times the sign of data
divided by data
and of course no surprise that you get a square there because that has to
do with the poynting vector
and this function is very different from
a great function
before i plant
let me
make a few calculations of the human center board so you can still compare
with this
so i'm going to
right on your side of data is
and then he might call from data
and then you come the sign of data
you come see intensity i
the first thing to sign of data
is zero
one of the sign of data is zero
it's immediately obvious that data is
it's also obvious sign of data is zero
you get zero divided by zero use low low-powered
and this ratio becomes one
now the light intensity
is i zero
well that's not so surprised that you have a lot of light
because of course if you have an opening year
you shine light through with you expect to see right on the wall there in
the middle of the street you expect to see a lot light so that's not
so surprising
this by the way is the way we we define eyes
so i zero is defined as the maximum that you will see
when you so to speak look
straightforward and an angle theta here
that's the way we define i zero
so now let's take
sin theta is land divided by
so now data is
fourteen years
sin theta
is land that divided by the way this so we you see that there is
so design of data
is no zero
and therefore he invented is zero
because the upstairs
is zero
but the downstairs is not zero
OK if you take this halfway take this half
you get the sign of saying i love that divided by d i when he
predicted that you would have that structure
destructive interference that's exactly this case of course
and now we have two lambda
divided by d
give me a baton of two pi
the game me again zero here
there is no zero so they are more locations in space
that is complete are not just one
in fact there is an infinite number of them you can go on like this
i will first plot the curve and then we'll discuss it in a little bit
more detail
and i will only plot
in terms of sin theta
because that an angle that i can relate to
i can tell my mother about data i can tell me more about phase angle
but i can tell you about theta one this is ten degrees twenty degrees thirty
degrees that's a real angle in my laboratory that is that a
then i can relate to always put things in terms of science a
so here is my zero
and that this be
let that divided by the capital b
that is the with
this is to like that
divided by p
here three lambda
divided by the
on the other side minus land that divided by the and so on
one more
so now
the curve that you seem not so obvious
when you plotted you'll see that you get maximum which we define to be i
zero in central mexico
and then you get you for zero
we train directly
on the japanese english
we can actually do better than that
a little bit and we don't actually have to do any machine translation tool so
it's stuck
implicit in the models
we can look inside w likely to call him representation in the same way resulted
in his talk and you get some similar kind of things so you
in the embedding space you find key in this case the cat and the sources
close to mccartney and so on
and that's the end of that part
of the talk we
showed this kind of models can be powerful supervised models for
for document ranking
and the efficient and scalable
and we should have nonlinearities that we could add to improve accuracy would actually be
nice to do is make
these these modules one and two here even more non-linear maybe put like the word
order into their of
work with bag of words about here we have have done
and that brings me
a glass of water
and powerful
so now
we've looked at
we've looked to tagging tasks which are not reflect retrieval music understand
text tasks
you want to do something a bit more semantic
we use
one way to look at what happens if
you're trying to learn language within the world so your yours you're doing situated learning
you know all these tasks like part of speech
tagging chunking
and machine translation semantic role labeling there
subtasks like syntactic or semantic sub tasks
this image invaded my talk and the these things don't actually you know try
situated learning within the world where humans do we understand language
often because it has a deep connection to the world we're in
you know it's often about that world
if you have sentences like
he passed the exam john went to the banque or john saw bill in the
park with his telescope you can
disambiguate sentences with your knowledge about the world if you happen to know that belies
the telescope and fred took an exam last week and john is in the countryside
not in the city then you know you can disambiguating words like bank here
so it might be riverbank and he might be free
for example
and we want to look at how can a computer do that almost specifically how
can it can be to learn to do that and can we learn
some representations of the world and of text
in order to make two to solve this problem
we looked at
a kind of simulated situated environment
by looking at a kind of computer gaming type situation so his the picture seems
so that means all the coefficients in the objective have the correct sign
would be negative
but but some other coefficients in the right hand side
we have the wrong side
the dual problem looks like this so the coefficients appear
have the right so you have the wrong sign that's okay
but all these have the right side so i can apply either
the simplex methods that already shown you to this problem
but do it thinking about it up here and we do that up here instead down here
so here's a summary
what we do
we choose an index i that's negative
first baeijs negative
the variable why is the entering variable
and the dual side
the variable w i will be deleting area very well on me primal side
we do exactly what we
what had before we looked at why
i increase
holding things are we figure out which is this these diseases are first exactly that
exactly what we've been doing all i just want to get on the dual side
we figure out which are these
variables must leave
by doing those ratios that i was
during mental arithmetic before r
so in the dual problem why is the entering variable and ceejay the leaving variable
but on the primal side we just to the corresponding to that word w i is the leaving variable
he i appeared in the column here and here the road here this w as the leaving variable
and x jay-z the entering variable
and after the pivot the primal and dual are so they are transpose eachother
and so we can continue in all in this way
and improving the dual problem until the dual reaches of melody and we've solved the problem
we solve the primal problem by solving the dual problem
so here is just go through an example
so if we have a primal problem that looks like this
with some negatives
we have that the negative transpose over here so five would be the entering variable
we look down here we see the three in the two here
this is hundred three six so this is easy to is the leaving variable
so the three as the pivot element so the minus three would be the pivotal
element here i just do their here so i can do that by looking i
i don't have to write this down the course because it's just the negative transpose
i can do this entire thought process here i look for the most negative that's
the minus five here i look across this role and in my mind and thinking
about the dualism looking here is saying okay look and the dual things can be
something starting foregoing is zero at a rate of three
there's something starting at six going to zero to
this is the one is gonna firstly nowadays can arrangement already shows ignoring minus signs and figuring out which one
it is the
entering variable in this case
and so
so we have the w two and x two
guess the pivot
and we do that if it's correct
but do one more pit so i picked the minus
six and a third
i look across here
the see so it was primal pivot cells looking for positive numbers and these text files
now i'm looking for negative numbers in the text fields because i think about the
negative transpose this will be the only candidate
and so
x four must be entering
so i do that's the on
we would say
that's just summarizing the role
and so we do that and we get a here
now we look at this one end
this variable must
leaving variable across here for positive numbers w one must be the
entering very
and more optimal
that's wrong
oh yes i did say wrong
my mistake
with thinking about these
do also looking at negative numbers and you're not positive numbers so i'm looking at these two
the the mental calculation five iterate over half to already tense
yeah i guess this is the one that wins so it's x one x two
so i click on
that's what do the pivot around moment and i end up
with an optimal dictionary so i just solved
the problem
that you didn't know an easy way to sell before r
by thinking about the dual problem
does to algorithms by themselves the primal simplex methods
which i should do first
and the dual simplex methods which i just showed do
are constrained in the primal simplex methods only works
if your primal feasible
the dual simplex method only works
if a dual feasible
here's the problem more
primal feasible
and do feasible
and by the way this is yet another version and my little tool here
cases and in some ways this can help you want
this model actually as articulate collaborators showed can be made also exactly supersymmetric and consistent
OK now
it's also easy to get
the family multiplicity free all you need is to have as many intersections families and
this comes out very naturally therefore these models against him to capture first of all
relatively straightforward you of course
beverly is often the case and when you work with them
or was something doesn't seem to work but one does get nicely grand unified theories
sort mister systems by thinking about this construction some have been discussed at length by
many people and here is a review on there are many more
let's think as i did for the heterotic string let's think about the effective action
in all these theories in four dimensions you see things will work very very differently
for the einstein action the thing will work in the same way because you basically
the graviton leaves and then dimensions therefore it sees the volume of the compact six
dimensions and effective for dimensionality gravitational coupling will be given by the same expressions as
but for the young theory things can work very differently because they're young meets theory
leaves no one is localized
brains share hypersurface is compact space therefore it only uses a part of this volume
namely the part of the volume that is all wrapped by these brains
if they are the brains that's v minus three if you have CD three brains
that to minimize OK this is just one
therefore you get a different relation for the young men's captain constant
in this theory is contradicted the heterotic string gauge couplings need not unify actually and
in the sense that the robot can because they do seem to unify unifying nature
you don't have to unify it can of course there is no no-go theorem i
showed you before a realisation refers five what they should
on the other hand because there's no universal relation tying this thing scale to the
planck scale there is much more freedom to play around with scales before pretty much
factor having a grand unified theory very very high up to the sixteen and seventeen
and then you know the experimental consequences
i would have to be looked at by the in the gravitational sector i'll say
you mean
something about it or indirectly through proton decay or other such signatures
here seems this case and not tied any more you can play around
for instance you see
that the black scale depends very sensitively on the volume of the compact space which
is transverse
the standard model brain namely the part of the volume which is the ratio of
six dimensional volume the p humanist three-dimensional volume
therefore one can consider very exotic possibilities
for instance if the standard model lives on a seven brane one hence blank scale
effective for the management of thanksgiving given by these
and this is the extreme possibility of taking more than one of things happening
but taking this transverse volume two-dimensional transverse volume to be in the micro or almost
immediately metric
the region
and this the scale to be very close to the TV and this is the
sixth in situation that is discussed sometimes one wonders about records in the LHC so
this is
priority not ruled out by the more the model building rules of orientifold vacua
no such extreme scenarios the weakness of gravity is due to the fact that gravitational
flux spreads out this extra dimensional space
and therefore that's why
the lines are less dense and
the forces we can
you may say that web
here there is at least something very nice and actually in the beginning it was
i felt so is you know have brought down the string scale to the TV
besides the fact that you LHC people will see all sorts of nice stuff next
year we have also made sort of the gauge hierarchy problem we don't need to
worry anymore
about why
the electroweak scale is still lower than the planck scale well the planck scale is
not fundamental what is fundamental the string scale that's
if UDVT of course that's a red herring with having to solve the problem
because we now need to to explain
an equivalent question why the hell is the volume of these transverse spatial large what
sets it
why it's not of the order of the string scale which would have been more
this brings me to the more general question which is actually
you know
the game theory a gradient over them
OK good so
learning theory in the eighties and nineties this problem came back came back by problem
called the problem of combining expert advice where we're really gonna now think of and
a very large number room and we have a lot of prediction rules so these
choices are now a bunch of different prediction rules we might be using it might
be a whole space of a whole class of different possible
classifiers prediction rules we might be using and we'd like to do nearly as well
as the best of these predictions
so our job to do nearly as well as the best function in that class
it's very nice algorithm littlestone warmuth in the late eighties showed how
you can get a cost which does nearly as well as the best function only
by one possible factor was an additive term was this type of log the number
of rules of repertoire if you said that on that about fifty two things out
it gives you regret like the previous but logan over where logan is this current
to the number of time steps regret and that's one of the DNA wrapped on
squared is like login that's great if the number of choices you have a large
a lot of different possible ways to pick from because
very much faster so that means that for that doesn't hurt you too much to
throw a lot more options into them
i don't really know because
fans know
to the thirtieth
logan is much better
yes that's right that
and i sure which is which can
his was not anyway
it's also
i went to this conference
yes that's esther so so they work also had this kind
and since then there's been a lot of other work the now optimal the function
then has been a lot of work getting exact constants king's second order terms in
various other things
but we're not going to worry about
now this is on the non bandit model this is on the model where you
get full feedback so you when you drive when you're done you find out from
your friends how long each other options and it's actually very natural in this context
because when you try to make prediction if you find out the right and you
can figure out how well you would have done had he chosen one of the
other predictions
in the bandit model where you have been choices and you only get feedback from
the choice you took you have to is try everything i mean you know maybe
there's some option after just have tried got things together with the the cost of
this extra factor
OK this is kind of as a quick history and i want to do it
is look at a particular problem in this series of the problem of combining expert
so imagine
whatever is and we'd like to predict the stock
i mean i still do
make some money so we're going to do is we're going to ask an experts
for their opinion i think the markets go up or down
so these are a bit different prediction rules can be actually people that could be
prediction rules that could be different statistics that we're looking at different you know economic
indicators whatever and each one is suggesting the market up down up and we want
somehow combine
and we'd like to use the advice of all these different indicators were people prediction
somehow make our own production OK so for instance you know maybe on the one
is very expert
they are down the property neighbours dog weighing scale and then we make a prediction
and then we find out what happened to the market
the next day down up down the road
i think it's my neighbour's dog always right
i got
the only two examples
i think it's quite good indicators
OK this is that the game to go to work to get this information organised
and make our own prediction and then we get the right and wrong and we
get you know
we get mistake we get it wrong the mistake right
OK our job is to not make too many mistakes
this i mean i assume that this conclusion is not true
but all the other things are true and negative contradiction
so assuming that these two sets are not the same means that there's atleast one
element which is in one sense but not in the subset
for simplicity on assume that x one
so x one is a member of the set x qx one is not in
the same way
OK so then of first move over this some to the left hand side so
i can subtract this one from this
so what do i get well actually the two things i moved this
to this site and then it might happen first excluded that these excess repeat otherwise
repeat but some otherwise might be identical to some of the axis i haven't excluded
that so if i move this thing to the other side i want to make
it nice again and make it a sum over pairwise distinct points and if it
turns out that some otherwise i could some of the excess i can just update
the coefficient corresponding
the only thing i know is that
x one is not in set y so the coefficient of x one is not
going to change all might change arbitrary arbitrarily about the coefficient of x one is
not going to change so i moved this thing over i can make it a
sum of pairwise distinct points
well i know that
first coefficient i one is equal
two the coefficient that had already full of one that is by assumption non-zero so
i was assuming all countries on zero
and all other coefficients
might be might be anything don't care
so then now i have this equality here i know that first cooperation is nonzero
dot product in the is encoded space with the same thing same expression again
so you remember was the dot product between kernel and the kernel
it's exactly kernel evaluated at these two points
so the product between this and this
usually this equation here
what do i know i know that the first go
number one is nonzero other grammars might be zero but anyway overall the effect of
grammars is not the zero vector
so i know this equality here is true with vector which is not the zero
vector hence the kernel is not strictly positive definite because that's exactly what the stipulation
of strictly positive definite this excludes
so our our assumptions
the kernel is strictly positive definite
cannot hold true
or contradiction is worked out and we know that the two sets so that this
thing cannot happen that two sets have to be identical
so that's
kind of interesting and it turns out
one can
make it more general because at the end of the day we are
actually it's hard to say but in statistics one is often interested not just statements
about finite datasets but also statements about distributions
the whole body distributions can we
can we generalise this mapping so there's nothing seems to be kind of interesting things
on mapping to recap
takes a set of points maps it into a single point and that single point
still remembers all properties
of the set of points
that's quite nice also because if you imagine just as side note this these points
that could be anything they could be strings could be vectors they could be texts
could be images as long as you can define a kernel function on these points
you you'll find so
we have set of general points we turn it into a vector of factors are
nice because we can do linear algebra with them and this vector
subject to
the conditions on the kernel function this vector knows everything
about that point to the victors and as representation
you can do it our department and you have lost in information
OK so
c so
so the mapping that we've been talking about all let's think of it as a
mapping on and called the mean mapping is mapping takes a set of points and
it computes the means
in the reproducing kernel hilbert space
so let's see what kind of properties this mapping has
first properties
if we take that mapping
of the set of points apply to this point and we take the dot product
with an arbitrary function of of space
so i'll just substitute this in here to take the product with the function of
remember the
kernel represents point evaluation of function
so the product between the content x i
the function exactly give us gives us the value of the function x i
so the dot product between these average of kernels just gives us the average of
function on the set of points so in a way this if the kernel represents
point evaluation then the
the mean of a set of points in the feature space this represents
evaluating the mean of a function over a set of points
so that's one thing the other thing is
take two sets of points x and y
met them into the feature space and then take the difference vector
so if we do that
one thing one way to write down the difference vector
is essentially the cushy schwartz inequality again
is the largest value that we can get
by taking dot products between the vectors
arbitrary unit vectors of factors that have maximal length unit
so i guess you can imagine if you have vector and you take all sorts
of products with vectors of length one the largest you can get is the length
of the vector itself you get exactly the vector is parallel to the first one
is just one way of rewriting this link here of course not and it's much
more complicated because it looks like this is complicated optimisation problem over this unit ball
in our potentially infinite dimensional space but it's the same thing but let's rewrite this
one using this inequality is this equality that we derived before
here we have is the products between means and functions they so just gives us
mean values of functions
so what is this thing here this thing here looks for
functions so you're looking for
the function
a function which has maximum length one so much the the maximum norm one which
this sets of points x and y
so we have two samples x and y and now we're looking for a function
which will on average take different values and x
and why
so finding the function
which gives you which best distinguishes the two samples x and y is the same
as computing the distance between the means to us
so this is also kind of interesting and we'll come back to that in a
so we can also look if we solve this optimisation problem five we found that
function best distinguishing the samples we can look how this function
how this function looks
for a given dataset surprising we can say we sample data points from a girl
in plus pleasant distribution so let's say x is sampled from goes in y is
the numbers in the streets of we end up level by level and an upper
that's going to miss the answer to this is the total
computed level by level was the
he went to compute it usually gives you
nice answers like geometric answers
so we have one time games plus five sixteen times square and if we believe
in fate
and we see this three number recurrence we know that we have the right answer
in general is going to be
in five the power k over sixteen to the power cables we hope
and so on and you know it keeps going it doesn't go on infinitely but
let's just assume it goes on infinitely that will be an upper bound
because on forever
this is all times and square
OK now
if you're in no one thing about geometric series you should know
the one class have lost according of the sum of the powers of two
you get
OK were computer scientists began at least the binary case this is like writing zero
point one one one one one one one in binary actually one point one one
one one and one one one one forever is the same as one the
this is even smaller we five sixty that's less than half the number is growing
each time so this is even less than two
if you want there's a nifty formula for solving the general
she metric series but all we need is that it's the constant so this is
order and square
it's also make and square
pretty obvious system against great because the top thing is square
so there's are lower bound and square and we have it within
factor two
pretty good you actually get better factor here
so that's recursion tree method so little shaky here because we have these dot dot
dot and we just
i believe that geometric turns most of times geometric problem here i would define check
it with the
with the substitution because it's not obvious to me it's going to be geometric in
the cases look at in the moment
it will be much clearer
so clear that we can state theorem that everything is working fine
OK and still time
so that was recursion trees
one more method we're going to talk about
and you can essentially think of it as an application of the recursion tree method
but it's
made more precise
this is an actual
theorem was recursion tree better if the data does obvious better check
the sad part about the master method is it's it's pretty restrictive only applies
two particular family recurrences
so it should be here then
equals a some constant eight times t and over b
plus some function of n
we call f
yes i call f
so in particular will not cover the occurrence i just solve because i was requesting
on two different problems of different sizes here every problem you recurse on should be
of the same size a some problems i think this is the recursive algorithm a
subproblems each of them is of size and over b so the total cost will
be less than a f and non recursive work
few constraints a should be at least one
at least one recursion b should be strictly greater than one you better make problem
smaller else is going to be
and f f should have some nice property
f of n should be
asymptotically positive
how many people are asymptotically positive means
no one can even read the textbook that's OK i haven't read either but until
and then he noticed and
what what you think asymptotically positive means that we can do a little bit better
his means from large enough for venizelos
this means
is greater than zero
four and every some and not for some constant
and so eventually should be positive i mean we don't care about whether it's a
good one for n equals one
not a big deal
what effect the answer because we only care about the asymptotics of that
good so the master method you given the recurrence of this form it tells you
the answer
that's the great thing about the master method the annoying thing about the master method
is it has three cases it's about long u
it takes a little bit longer to memorize than all the others because the others
are just ideas here we need to actually remember
two things
some of the state here
but not quite there is one very simple idea which is we're gonna compare this
non recursive work for them
a very particular function
and log base b of
KY and to lock base b event
you'll see
turns out it is the number of leaves in the recursion tree will
that's the foreshadowing
it's either less equal or bigger
and here we care about asymptotics and this is all we have to be a
little bit more precise about less equal bigger you might think well means willow big
data or little america
it would be nice if the theorem held for all those cases but it is
a bit some gaps
so let's start with case one is one is when f is smaller and not
just that's willow
it's actually quite a bit smaller it's going to be polynomially smaller than and log
base b
so for some positive and so on
the running time should be this and to this constant always be a minus that
you could assume that the annotation does not necessarily depend on the position in the
text where you are
this may not always be a very good idea
prince if you read the newspaper article
there are set up in such a way
the first few phrases contain the most important bit
and then the information content goes down and goes more into the background
so therefore
stationary model when you're dealing with text
may or may not be a very good idea
but to make our life easier
and to avoid spilling equations all over that slide
which is going to make that assumption
g of data given x
is this big
mister down here
so when we had almost the same expression yesterday
just the ones were missing and they were just axis here
again well i can write this
this is just some
number which depends on what in what he plus one for the sake of simplicity
let's assume that those wise just see one valued random variables
so i just need to store
four numbers for each of those terms
i want to some of the first of all of this
and just
as yesterday
i can push that summation in
actually if you look closely you'll see that's like
one very long multiplication of matrices
so that the two by two matrix
you multiply by the next time to the next one extended in
and so on
in the end you just summarily entries
that's really what's written there
and then
we just use dynamic programming or
in this specific case you would be much better off just using matrix multiplication
and then you get your data connection
likewise we can do
all those
partial sums by the forward backward algorithm
the same pictures yesterday
just did not operate on the wise
yesterday were or are operating on the axes
so there's no real conceptual difference here
the questions at this point because i mean what are they doing now is just
reviewing procedures we had yesterday and show you that the very same tricks apply today
everything here good
in the can do
message passing and all that now
the only thing that
change is a little bit is the objective function
yesterday we didn't have to y here and those you they just didn't economics
now we need to minimise that's OK so
we need to get the first derivative to banish first derivative of this is
you seem to just minus for fixed on y i
some are all of those
these are the conditional expectations
that's all comes from the log partition function
so in other words its expected value of the joint feature map here
given that particular sequence that i want to detect
and then this is just a small to keep status
this is just the regularizer the keep status more
now how to compute those things
after all that some joint feature map and what
you know i mean it's not easy to compute
but what we know is we know the conditional probabilities p of why i
because excise already known
given the entire sequence
so we have to do is
in the forward backward algorithm
just get those individual probabilities here
and then we apply those in
and come can compute expectation expectations
let me write it out in detail
i want to compute expected value
and why i
why i plus one
so with some slight abuse of notation
i'm dropping
the summation here
and and i will now go
all the points in the sequence
i want to get this
expectation given
sequence x
well this is nothing else
but the sun