it through and it does work but you are to get similar
one of the things i like to say
is this split merge stuff has really worked great for us
basically there are been a lot of cases where there some hidden structure we only
see the courses traces that we know there are some kind of incredibly complicated patterns
and are hoping that the model of learning and really does so one other case
where this work very well is in the sequence case looking at modeling phones and
kind of kind of basic phonetic phonology patterns here where this is the task it's
the speech recognition task this kind of the baby is to speech recognition tasks recognizing
doing for recognition
and kind of a kind of a
a good baseline HMM the kind of the standard approach circa maybe
i don't know five or ten years ago maybe more like ten years ago gives
you about twenty five percent error rate
and doing the same split merge thing for five rounds
i improves on that substantially what's going on what's going on is are starting off
saying is the sequence of phonemes i don't know what's going on beyond that but
i suspect there some kind of tricky phonological patterns and there's there's a bunch of
kind of phonological classes were kind of some sounds are similar and they have the
same contextually like all nasals may influence the next sound in the same way
and moreover this kind of duration patterns when certain contexts certain kind of sounds get
longer shorter and all of this is kind of being learned automatically in a by
the model so in this particular case i'm showing that the simplest structure here for
one phone and what you what what the models learned here is that in this
particular case that kind of stuff pattern one way on one side and
various kinds of sirens pattern and on the other side and it's kind of learning
these clusters which we could have imposed based on our knowledge of phenomenology but we
didn't have to
this is another case of linguistic structure that you know in some cases verifies what
we suspect in other cases can improve on it
so this works here too
so in summary has so far been talking about this probably variable grammar refinement to
take an kind of much more generally this is ICO ICO course traceable complex process
and how to learn about that process in in an unsupervised fashion
and to do this with grammars you get a very very good and interpretable grammar
this gives rise to state-of-the-art parsing in this works as well as can any other
class of techniques for passing and in my opinion is substantially simpler and moreover because
you've got this ontology of an ontology of grammars you can and cannot use that
again at inference time you kind of get your inference algorithm along with your learning
algorithm for free
i suspect there's a lot of applications beyond passing and the other linguistic i keep
cases we looked at so i encourage you to think about it and if you
can think of any find these great if you can tell me of problems that
you think this character looking
so back to outline
the next thing i'm going to talk about is a very different kind of linguistic
structure but we're going to be using some of the same methods so in this
case again we're going do some unsupervised learning but we're going to be looking at
the problem of co reference
what's the problem about so here's a short discourse
the weir group whose headquarters is in the US is a large specialized corporation
this power plant which will be situated in jiangsu has a large generation capacity
so what's coreference about there's a lot going on here one thing we could want
to do this course can break it up and some syntactic fashion with the past
very talked about that
the last five minutes
what i wanna do and co reference is i want to basically say
what are the mentions here
so what are the entities being talked about
and which of them are the same
right so each of these boxes what i'm going to call mentioned
so it some
syntactic item which evokes some underlying entity
and i want to know which of them is the same
maybe inside documents not across documents
i'm going to talk about model to basically ignore the rest of the structure of
discourse looks like this
so like the rest of the structure is important but we can model everything
so we're going to talk about models to which are basically view discourse as
kind of a sequence of
one of nominal mentions of various kinds
and that means we're going to have some kind of generative model
the generative model and i'm being deliberately vague because we're going to go through a
lot of iterations of this fairly quickly the generative model is going to have this
kind of flavor
there's a bunch of slots in which i have to say something
and i'm going to draw a bunch of entities that i'm going to keep talking
about for some reason discourses seem to be about
so i have some sequence of entities that comes from some prior distribution and we'll
talk about that
and then
i'm gonna go one by one to each of these entities figuring out some linguistic
how to render into a strength
so these underlying entity sometimes pop up as proper name sometimes they pop up pronouns
according to some other data process that the world's going to talk about go through
some iteration
an inference time
what we're going to observe is the mentions and we're going to want to infer
what the entities are
and the reason we're going to want that is basically so we can figure out
which of them are the same and so on
i want to repeat that this particular
it's going to take as input
a bunch of documents
each of which is basically kind of pre segmented into
these kinds of lists of nouns
but we're never going to see an example occurrence this is going to be done
entirely in an unsupervised fashion and model based
this includes the classical anaphora problem thank you a good point this includes the anaphora
problem which is what are the pronouns refer to but also includes is that bush
is the president and the george bush and this document is mister bush not document
so it is a generalization of reference problem thank you
so let's talk about the simplest thing that could possibly work
it will not
and then fix it
a simple thing you can imagine saying well i have a bunch of slots to
for each one i'm going to have a random variable which has to do with
this value is
among the space of entities
i'm writing things like where group and where headquarters really probably just going to be
integers or something like that
and i can imagine that i have some prior distribution over which entities get used
and again it says we're group that's probably entered the number three hundred seventy
then each one of these slots independently gets transformed into a string
what is this parameterized by
well the simplest thing that could possibly work and will not is that each entity
kind comes along with the distribution over strings
this with these would be the mention parameters these characterize
what strings are appropriate for each entity we would have to learn both of these
things from data in an unsupervised fashion in this kind of and
going to call this entity distribution can just the relative frequencies really of these entities
going to be data can be some vector proportions and the mention parameter is there's
going to be
one distribution
for every entity
which is here to the multinomial over strings
we're going to call this fee
those two
we're here there are k different entities
and what this would do
is any position you choose according to their entity and then you look at the
role of multinomial and choose the string
if we happen to have the strings that might even work because then we know
that bush and the president are both strings for the same entity
but we don't have the strings this doesn't work very well and in particular we
don't even know the number of entities k
so this kind of the easiest answer is just erase k right infinity
and we call it the dirichlet process mixture model
that's all going to do
we're not going to determine the number in advance is going to be some inference
that i'm not going to talk about here we use the sampler
that allocates its so how does this work group running numbers there are a lot
of measure of how well you doing in this task the measure can be reporting
here is the mark f one measure
and it turns out you get about fifty four percent this is not a good
number but it may be higher than you think and the reason is higher than
this assumption whether actually walk around in the environment and they touch everything right like
a bomb themselves in every because they don't know maybe that's the magic way out
of the box is to do this crazy thing so so we need to take
advantage of the fact that the world has some regularity therefore the transition functions can
have some regularity so quick learners have some regularity they can exploit that the whole
thing could go a lot faster
so here's a show you one concrete example of this idea
all right so we've got
same kind of environment as before the robot its environment it's got x and y
coordinates it also has an orientation and one more thing to it which is there's
of a ball and environment obstacle moving obstacle stationary obstacles or whatever they are but
moving obstacles are interesting because they become part of the state space so the right
thing to do at a given point in time may depend not only were the
robot is but the obstacle is in relation to the robot
now we've got
potentially very high dimensional even if we discretize the x and y the ball x
y the robot and the state of the robot molotov states and the robots can
you really really slowly it's very often going to encounter stated never seen before it's
going to be exploring for a very long time so you're going to use domain
knowledge to say hey you know what there's some structure in this environment we're going
to build a little
graphical models of that says
as the woman to win at the age and the the robot uses the forward
action the change in the balls x and y coordinates is independent doesn't depend on
anything about where the ball the robot are just move around randomly
i mean this ball really does show the video insects i thought it would have
all kinds of history but i think now it's it's pretty much like i i
d movement
the brownian motion so the robotics and why we're on the forward action the change
in the x and y doesn't change that is only affected by the angle that
the robot is facing so right so if it's space in this way to goes
forward then x y changes certain way according to go robust face in this way
that's why change differently when it moves forward but the but the robots angle actually
is again independent of everything else change in angle so that for the for action
we just write down this model but we don't have to fill in the numbers
here we just say it depends on what
moving but takes a right hand turn actually
there are also independent i think that's the model we use that that x and
y don't depend on the previous section why because it's really not moving x y
just turning
the robotics and why
so ball in the robot and the angle actually does change but it doesn't matter
what the current was going to change relative to whichever way facing so now we
have a model where there's lots of things that are independent of a lot less
to learn this way fewer parameters
and what's nice is that we can
can show you video and then i'll talk about learning so let's say that's not
robot but that is the number hears about wall
just rule all around like that and this is the robot again wearing patterns on
the back on its back so we can detect it from the above camera also
detecting the ball which is distinctive colour and trying to get to this goal location
at the end the reward function is it gets higher reward for getting to the
it gets
a big negative or every time it bumps into the ball gets small negative or
just for not being the goal yet so just can encourage you to get on
with his life
we tried to this is very sort of function approximation with with
with q learning that didn't didn't go very well so we're trying to get down
here and to forty five episodes now this is now thirteen episodes using other model
based algorithm which actually learning the transition probabilities with the conditional independencies from
he was quick learning
from experience
and so you can see it already doing a very good job of pointing in
the right direction the bottom of the falls out of the way this particular case
and it's heading fairly directly towards this corner
and if the ball is close to it you can see it it's a little
bit more
careful get by the ball
so it doesn't look scared but i don't think it's feeling frightened the value function
does drop when the ball gets closer depends on how you define fright now here's
the robot strider down here to the corner here's about ball
but unfortunately placed in its way
but that's OK the robot can wait it out since it's moving randomly it's a
just wait longer no no that's not helping
sometimes it looks less random than others
the the balls kind of attacking good an opening got opening i really had right
to the goal now here we go
just just got kind of face in the right direction and start tracking and unfortunately
the ball has other plans are so
i don't what the couple computational models of frustration look like
i guess if we ever saw the robot actually go up to the biologists
that would count as basically giving up but
it it's patiently waiting for the ball to be in a position where can actually
get towards to go just over there right there is so
so in this example the what's going on here is because we know the conditional
but really it's learning instead of learning the whole transition probability matrix says from this
combination of opposition robot position robert engle here's what the next one looks like instead
of just finding little want to say when you do the forward action what's the
probability distribution over the change in the ball's position robots position and robots state of
all independently and so what you things to learn these are all independently quickly ball
this this idea i think i had on on the previous slide this this observation
that if you know the conditional independence structure you can learn
the transition matrices really efficiently even though there is an exponential number of combinations of
the values of state variables we don't need anywhere near that we need polynomial in
the size of these little many transition
state diagrams so
that observation was made by color and
so they show how you can do this and so i'm not saying anything new
beyond what they said in this particular case but we did discover that for the
role of examples it was nice to have it be the change in variable instead
of predicting from the old value the variable the new values variables so sometimes sometimes
that's the thing that you want to be predicting that which is kind of odd
that's that's a different kind of representation of the transition function that is efficiently learnable
and applies really well and in lots of different circumstances here's another one this is
what we found to be useful in in several settings are continuing to work on
where we represent transitions instead of from state to state or from features to features
like in the DBN case we're going to represent them in terms of object attributes
to object attributes so talking about the world as consisting of a set of objects
so this is this is a figure from a paper which is the taxi problem
i showed you the beginning
it's very convenient in fact i think if you ask yourself what you're doing when
you're exploring in this game to talk about the state in terms of a set
of objects there's taxi it's in some place there's a passenger it in some place
there's walls there in some place that there's a destination it also in some places
and whether two things are in the same place is very relevant to figuring out
what's going to happen when you choose an action
so now instead of yes so so what happens when objects interact that's what the
learner is going to try to figure out and we run these sort of things
if you see this
they also from that
well in this region
next is that you're able to find some
if you want to
so the
this is the result
it is in fact
we years
there is some
if we have
she for that
we have
so this
here is
so these
this is
the universe is
all one
and i should
it doesn't
and that was a
so thing
at some point in the
very sensitive to the presence of
not all these
sensitive to the service
so we
and the the the the the and
point three
many of you
one four
it would me
this me
he's that trying to make sure that people said
thank you you
every image
what they believe that
you can
to use the next two years
the reason i'm trying to identify
where are you
article twenty three
they want to get
looking more
information about
so what
the action
actually they can
by this to me
so basically it is used as prior
if we model the FCC
crystal as hard spheres touching
how much of this is no matter how much of it is free space it's
given by the packing density
packing density that's equal to the volume of the atoms
divided by total volume
the total volume so if we choose the unit cell is the basis so we've
got something to count on let's
let's go back so we know that the going the other like this secure drawn
from ok so the volume of the atoms while I get Adams equivalent of atoms
and what's the volume of an atom it's going to be 4 thirds times pi
times the radius of the atom Q and what's the volume of that unit cell
that unit cell is a cube and now I need to know the relationship between
a and are assigned convert 1 to the other and then I'll have a dimensionless
group here so there you can see the relationship between an based where was a
squared is
the for the year 16 hours whereas if you go through all that you can
convince yourself that a equals to the roots of the 2 are in FCC so
plug that into their and you'll end up with the packing density will be equal
to pi divided by 3 times the square root of 2 which is value of
0 . 7 4
so that means in face centered cubic and face centered cubic lattice you have 74
per cent of matter this is assuming hard-sphere model hard-sphere model here so big that
they touch
so that's 26 % avoid 26 % voice and you go through and you can
see that as you look at this table that the packing decreases in the case
of a body centered cubic is a little more open spaces 68 % and in
case of
In the case of our simple cubic it's only about half pack so
this table here is something that
you wanna get confronted with but they're going to show you is the crystallographic notation
and whether they want to do is are invited to look at the website this
this will give you the answer
the nature of the crystal graphic notation position is basically as it is in your
math classes the only differences we don't put enclosures no parenthesis around the point of
the origin is 0 0 0 but don't put parenthesis around so point is simply
written as
follows so origin 4 . 0 3 0
and that's all there is to it in the case of direction so that this
is going to take a little more time than I have
a set aside because of got a few items of business that I need to
take care of so I think I'm going to have a little hold at this
point and will jump ahead to this is to always have a few things obviously
OK so let's let's go back to the beginning of when people came in as
is the custom we have music playing and what was the music today
yeah I'm talking heads and the song was
burning down the house so why would be playing burning down the house in a
lecture about crystallography well what inspired the inflated to choose that piece of music was
this painting houses that was status was painted by George Braque in 1908 stack is
a community down in the southern part of France
and about when fractionated this he outraged the critics of the someone in Paris who
condemned this painting they said look at it doesn't have a common perspective that that
but actually all of the problems
he talked about that i've talked about
until now
still exists
we're going to structure it can do the job
if we can pick these
OK so
one of the questions we might ask first of all is what does it do
this is the only equation early on in the show
i'm going to talk about this in terms of
minimizing the sum of squares error but this this similar results for
a whole variety of tasks that we might be
seeking to carry out
OK it turns out
it's not actually that difficult to prove that
minimizing the sum of squares error is equivalent to finding the conditional mean
the target date
it is precisely what we want to do this is this progression property
but it was mentioned earlier
so if we just look at the the theoretical problem rather than our real problem
which is yes we're going to go to the data
this question which i discussed you will look at the minute if we assume that
we found the set of weights that gives us the best possible answer
to this problem
and the we've got infinite amount of data
then we are in a position to rewrite the
sum of squares error
according j infinity infinity infinity there just to indicate
it's a theoretical
we we can rewrite is the sum of two components became
it's the average of the square of of this
o thing in brackets here
plus the average of the square
this thing
records here OK
the some asian here is because of this in the general form where you might
have multiple
it's just the probability
density function
of x
he is the expectation operator
so we've got two components here
the first one
is the
expectation mean value of
the target data
at a particular point ex
in particular
value of
the input
of the function
which turns out to be the multilayer perceptron itself of course
which is self is a function of x
and the function of these the curly w to indicate all of the weights
and the thing
not just a single vector y
so we take that
difference we square and we find the average of it
and added to that is
so the term here which is the difference between
the target data
the average of the target data a particular value of x
actually should be substituted with i suppose x is
look at it
should a
the crucial thing is this one here doesn't depend on the weights
of the
multilayer perceptron at all
this is just some
residual error
but cannot be
can be changed by the introduction of this
this neural network
OK so we can say is that if we want to make j as small
as possible we can't do anything about that by choosing w so we can ignore
to make
the error as small as possible we have to make
the function itself
equal to
what's called the conditional mean the expected value of z given the x
so under these very extreme
theoretical conditions we see that
what we're trying to do is
the right thing
in reality we have a finite amount of data so
it will just simply be
and estimate
of the right thing
nonetheless it's encouraging
if you knew it yes
what is indicating is that if you if you
in the
extreme case where you have an infinite amount of data
covering all of x basically
by making
by driving j to its global minimum by an appropriate choice of w
you get a quality there
right so this morning i'm going to talk about forces in this talk and then
we'll talk about putting it all together
in the next one
let me start with gravity
seeing as particle physics tend to ignore gravity but sometimes you can't but let me
show you what it is
the forces that we tend to deal with our electromagnetic weak and strong
electrostatic force
you know in hydrogen is an inverse square law
and gravity is also an inverse square law
so to give an idea of how feeble gravity is you could ask
the electron and the proton hydrogen they have an electrostatic potential energy
and they have also gravitational potential energy between them as is the ratio of the
potential energy
it is ten to the minus forty
it is a small number
and to give you an idea of how small it is if you took the
size of a single proton ten to the minus fifteen metres
and compared it to the size of the observable universe which is about ten to
twenty six metres
that is about ten to forty to to forty one
what is the magnitude so if you imagine a single proton compared to the whole
observable universe that is like the strength of gravity compared to electromagnetic forces between individual
particles therefore we ignore them between individual particles
of course gravity has the property adding up the wall part you have the more
the gravitational forces and there are some places where it reveals some unusual things not
just in falling apples in the problem of dark matter so let me to show
you the background to this
if you have a large mass like the sun
with small matters like planets going around and then you know newton's inverse square law
tells us the force between them
you equate that with these were are
you can work out what the velocity profile of those objects is a function of
distance you find that the speed drop like the square root of are so the
outer planets moving slower than the inner ones
that is indeed what happens to the planet
but if you look at some spiral galaxies where you can measure the relative speeds
of the stars by the doppler shift of the spectral line you find those there's
clearly a lot of mass in the middle of
these stars on the outside
but the velocity profile seems to me
independent distance rather dying away
this is large error bars on this and varies from one galaxy to another overall
you get this impression
stars are not following the rules
and one of two opportunities are either you say this shows that on these distance
scales newton's laws not correct
you can play that game is very difficult to convince convince you fit it with
other data or that small
stuff there
giving gravitational forces that you're actually seeing your telescope
and this is what gives rise to the idea of dark matter namely stuff that
does not shine
in electromagnetic radiation of any wavelength
in gravitational force which affects the motion
one of the
stars and galaxies
it turns out when you do the sums that you need
the dominant stuff in the universe to be this dark stuff unseen
so that's the observation
from cosmology and the nature of the dark matter is a big puzzle
one of the possibilities at the LHC is that we will discover new particles
call supersymmetric particles which have perhaps the properties of dark matter and i'll mention that
later on that if it's true it will be wonderful
synthesis between particle physics
and cosmology
so what is that we know that whatever consists of has to be electrically neutral
and those two scenarios called hot dark matter and cold dark matter hotly moving relativistic
for example
if neutrinos had about
small mass
it's possible that they collectively
because i wouldn't shine they don't feel electromagnetic forces the electric charge
but the gravity could add up and out why everything it turns out when you
do the details sums it doesn't seem to work
the extreme cold dark matter very massive electrically neutral object
that is
what city might provide us with and we'll talk about that the next lecture
that's not to say that gravity and i want to talk about the strong and
the electromagnetic and weak forces so the strong force
which we met i guess first of all students between the protons and neutrons the
biosphere the nuclei
we now know
is remnant of deeper force acting on the quarks inside the proton the neutron
and i'm going to show you how that force works
and show you
how similar it is
with the good old electromagnetic force
the idea is that quarks in addition to carrying electric charge
carry another form of charge
which we call color
nine of twenty one
and the rules of attraction and repulsion between color charges
are the same as you meet between electric charges
so for example
quarks carry positive
colour charges it whereas electric charge comes in only one variety plus the number of
minus the number
this charge
comes in three varieties and just to give them in a little red yellow green
red yellow and blue
three different coloured possibilities for quarks positive and clerks will have three
colours negative
the problem is somebody can turn this thing down
they apply some of the rules that you used to electrostatics where the rules are
and to reconstruct
it's an interesting thing to do
and if you feel like it
i would say give it a shot
all right so far
about speeds and average velocities
and accelerations
let's not go to
three dimensional
trajectories trajectories
thank goodness
almost never three-dimensional
they're always two-dimensional because the trajectory itself is in a vertical plane
and so we
when we throw up an object in a gravitational field
you have
the trajectory in the plane
so we'll going to
have long-term trajectory
this b
next direction
and that this week
one direction increasing values
why increasing values
of x
i think an object
and i throw it out
with an initial velocity
the zero
what is the object going to do
you're going to get bradley
and and for friends of gravity
and it comes down here again
and then we have this kind of problem
we will decompose it
two one dimensional motions one in the x direction
and one in
the y direction
we already decompose right away
at time t equals zero
in two
component which i call the zero x
and that of course is the zero
times the cosine of of
if the angle
it's all far
and the
o velocity in the y direction
at time t equals zero
i will call that the zero in the y direction
and that is the zero
i'm sign of
and now
i have to know how
the object moves in the x direction as a function of time and how it
behaves as a function
time in the y direction so here come the equations
forty x direction
x as a function of time
because x zero
plus the zero x times t
that's all there is no acceleration
the velocity in the x direction as a function of time
the zero x
you never changes
so that
x direction
now we take the y direction
y as a function of time equals y zero
these are white t
plus one half a square
g value that i'm going to use
is always positive you nine point eight meters per second squared or sometimes i make
it easy
to use ten
mine is always positive
and since in this case
i have chosen this could be the increasing value of y that's the only reason
why i would now have to put in
minus one have
GT square not as some of you think because the acceleration is down that's not
a reason because i could have called this direction increasing y
then it would have been plus
one how do you square so the consequence of my choosing this the direction which
why increases
therefore the plus one half
eighty square and that you would normally see
i'm going to replace that now
by minus
one half
GT square
than the velocity in the y direction as a function of time would be because
the derivative
that is the zero
any acceleration
equals minus two
so these ideas three equations that govern the motion
in the
y direction
there's only
holds if there is no
and ragno friction of any kind that is very unrealistic
if any earth but when we are far away from earth
as we
where was the KC one thirty five
which was flying at an altitude of above thirty thousand feet
that of course is a little bit more
and therefore the example that i have picked to throw up an object
is the one
by the KC one thirty five
at an altitude somewhere around twenty five thirty thousand feet
comes in at speed
of four hundred twenty five miles per hour
turns the engines of
and then for the remaining
whatever it was about thirty seconds
everyone including the airplane
has no weight
that's the case
and i want to work out
quantitatively with
in the case of the
KC thirty five will take an angle of forty five degrees
and we'll take zero
which was
about four hundred twenty five miles per hour may remember that
that lectures
supposedly if you walk towards the coast
with some cellphones you will be able to get some signal at least that seen
occasionally succeeding
three years ago so
now i mean i've seen people making phone calls them so
and i talking about wasn't very tall
for those united states was clock
third lecture after
this afternoon's present running can so now will be
to getting a little bit too
this is my around the fifties
this actuary get thing combination into the mind
moving slightly forward
we have
pretty much sidestepping the real networks
i will talk about him through all the perceptron
depending on how we go will actually do the convergence proof
and then we'll talk about feature mapping
i would start with heavy the have been the first you into positive feedback
then we look at linear separability
and then will go
and explicitly look at
features how we can construct another can do it efficiently
in the end well few shortcuts and get to the kernel
as kernels and nothing else
then explicit feature constructions which i can compute very efficiently
what i have always come from so this is where the biology was actually useful
so the idea is that that behaviour should be somehow rewarding bad behavior punished
so for instance
if you hit the target of the hidden temple you kill the tiger other the
this should be rewarded private i the big piece of meat and maybe you will
able to procreate
so the other thing is correlated means should be combined so for instance pavlov's salivating
dogs the
really for for example when they learned that the feature of him getting food was
you can have training mechanisms in the following way that you
what if i individuals are you know just showing them
how successful behaviours is rewarding but you could essentially also eliminate and it
all individuals from the gene pool
and that thing you could will put into interesting
the point is
the machine learning purpose that distinction doesn't actually matter very much
we're just talking about learning
it's just push this
biological knowledge a little bit further so these are two neurons and they talk to
each other
so that's the cell body like the CPU that we combined signals
then dried where you get all the inputs from
it's like an
input terminal
finances well that's connected between two neurons
accent will like an output cable
these are the cables can be
like one and a half metres long so there are neurons which go from the
somewhere through the entire spine
in two
whatever muscles
they can be
serious along
here's another neuron
the cell body
and at the lights
the inputs
so what i'm getting is an output here
y one on x one like two times six two and so on and so
you can write it like this
and then i have some
non linear function
of this linear combination
nothing the of
this output doesn't necessarily have to be exactly
this linear function but it could be someone tonic
function there
so this is what i can
now when people went into neural networks states
this realized high neuron is really cool
so when better if i had even more than one neuron
so they basically concatenated several of those functions and created one fairly complex maze
and then you had about ten years people writing
how to actually clean up the mess and optimize efficient stuff works pretty well
what you can also do is you could say well i know run with in
features is really good wouldn't it be better if i had a lot more features
this is basically the direction that kernel
they can just
now we have seen
really which feature space and the the things with it
cause somebody might ask
well wouldn't it be great if i you had a neural network and then crawls
in there
and sadly enough people have actually tried to publish papers
but you basically combining the worst of both worlds throughout
OK now
as a model of what we have here and i'm just ignoring that
that the function is just a fixed
w plus b
just the same in the next are in dimensional vectors and these just the scalar
OK so
this is not just an attic lights modifications just whatever the sun does
and then after summing over things in the so what was not quite exactly how
the brain works so sorry abstract the web of things
but this is something i can easily implement
on the computer
so what can i use it for spam filtering echo cancellation
and the cool thing is
well the weights are
what bothers you call you called the plastic plates another they can
and so you that there was some training data
now here's the same picture again
the function has its value zero here
but everybody has seen what the hyperplane looks like
basically that's the normal vector
and be just tell me what the offset from the origin is
and this of course will separate
right dots from green dot
and i'm going to show you the simplest
what linear classifier algorithms
and it's actually really nice very nice properties
people still use it even today
that's a few dozen an argument in a series of x's
and why status plus minus one
i initialize the NPV zero
and i'm thinking it's i want hear from the bottom
and if y i times the i plus b
is less equal in sierra
i have to explain what that means in a moment
and just updating w
i at one time so excited to it
and adding y to be
if that science
because the other way around i don't do anything do this until this sea
condition hope now let me explain what this means
what i want is at the end the w thirty six
plus b
is greater than zero
four positive y
and it's less than zero for negative one
so this means that this product here
has to be
greater than zero
for all y and x x and y here
that's when i'm done
how do get there
what we need for this condition is satisfied yet
the update the weight vector
essentially a copy of what i've actually seen
and i'm just playing according to whether it's positive and negative class
so i want to
talked about some
work that i've been doing jointly with
because that's who was a student of duncan watts in sociology at columbia more recently
was post-doc in the social department cornell re-joining
google fall
so we're
george in
can have been doing
looking at some issues in social networks as structures for communication and the flow of
so if you think about the kinds of social network data that we often work
with one property that has one more actually
science communities
on of work in the last few years is
so i started consists of discrete communication right around think of it as nodes with
these permanent links the title together rather we think of it as a collection of
people who
and various intermittent times talk to each other in way exchange information so this view
of the social network is dynamic
object with constant active communication and of course communication comes in many
many different forms like recent work has been about what you might call event-driven communication
so saw negation than what i call event-driven application which is creation triggered by a
particular strength here
will will show that this too microphone things
so during communication which is triggered by some kind of action rates
as for example here from work you're asking which led to mention procurement and cascading
book recommendations we recommend things to your friends there are many of their friends everything
triggered by the initial personal book or this small piece of the spread of a
gigantic chain letter across the internet or just redirect the
david liben nowell and i have been studying for the past few years so this
is things triggered by physical action that then spread rapidly
but i guess i would argue that this kind of negation is really israeli-born on
top of something that's
but for intrinsic to the social networks and has been largely invisible but arguably determines
a lot of how information actually flows we might call systemic communication and this simply
the rhythm of everyday communication
the rate at which you talk to
your colleagues co-workers or office made your friends and relatives just acquaintances all of this
is this sort of title patterns of communication that flow across time and
allow other information to
payback on top of it
now this is very hard to observe prey it's easier to do
log book sales or
she was the internet then is to simply watch minute-by-minute day by day the rate
different rates which you talk people which information flows that's what
we would like to to do to sort of watch this nearly invisible backdrop and
which these other events have
OK so what kind of questions to ask essentially the goal is going to be
to try inferring structural measures about the network based on these rhythmic patterns in which
information and communication flows so
we start with
the basic question and that's the following if i have to say
a data set consisting of communication among larger peoples in the social network five people
with the stamps which people actually communicate
i can ask questions like what is the most recent information that one might be
here could possibly have about all the other
right if these were the times which all communication to play some let's assume there
is no indication outside the group for purposes of this pedagogical example
that's of relevance to us so for example was most recent information because have friday
at five PM about body
and if you work it out you see that
the latter from c three p o information could piggyback from a is
as recently as friday night and when
there's a sort of the laws of nature going on
if this is really all communication of emails phone calls face-to-face whatever
nothing happened after friend in a very literal sense could possibly be known by b
friday five it simply cannot go there was no communication
any in this way we can find these view of the network is sort of
smear out in this strange time shifted away
it's too much things becoming increasingly
right so
different views of different people and also one of the things for example
it's clear that although a sometimes talks to be that's not in general the fastest
potential means for information flow rather the fact that a talks alot to CC talks
about to be is much faster interaction again we're trying to learn structural measures the
network sort out of date time shifted nature and fast communication channels when that we
know in particular what float is already gave the the potential for the
the axe so so
so all of this over again this is these are very good questions that any
colours have to worry about but i was hoping not to worry about here so
all of these models
i have a slightly different units and there
there are also sort of sort of transform to normalise the scales have the same
minimax so we we don't necessarily think that
this particular skilled people using is is directly meaningful basically there's what the the the
units of this are measured in
you know it this this is the this is the measure it's this bayes factor
but then we're putting it through sort of a non-linear power law scaling which all
the models go through that kind of thing which takes into account the fact that
when people use it every judgement rating scale they may not use the ratings
that makes sense
so there's weak nonlinearity for all of these models that's just a parameter that
two to the data
although actually it turns out you don't need that i mean it turns out that
if you if you just computed posterior probability you get basically the same so if
that's not what i'm showing here but that is to the right people are made
that many of the natural environment
so i didn't collect these data although we have collected we replicated the experiment and
got basically the same data and i actually remember those are data budarin change but
because the error bars probably data
no i mean just not that we're better just i didn't have there what some
sorts are with us yet people are placed on individuals that's a good question i
so one thing that i i don't i don't know exactly that we we
well so in in this experiment you have the basic quality shapes are the individual
subject so we tested for example do you have this linear effect in individual subjects
another thing we tested is do you have a slightly statistically significant kind of u
shape here which is interesting because the bayesian model predicts that and the other ones
don't so those are those that those are present in
and of individual subjects more more than you'd expect by chance so i don't i
can't exactly tell you what the individual plots the light but they have the same
quality shapes most of them do but yes there certainly certainly averaging here you know
on the order of
fifty subjects the standard areas so you know multiply by
square root of fifty to get the actual
standard deviations in judgement and you know there are some significant variation in that standard
thing in cognitive psychology
these once again
i think it's statistically significant in intuitively why for the real reason or
in general the i mean from the point of view of the bayesian model
the reason why and the there's a difference in the bayesian model but the scale
the the nonlinearity kind of scares but in general the reason why this kind of
well it's a version of the same kind of thing that was was going on
here but its most dramatic in this case as the base rate decreases the of
the there's more dynamic range in a sense for cause of the same strength to
express itself so you get stronger evidence from the same
the same absolute difference in conditional probabilities for the presence of course
and if you you can actually look at the form of the the posteriors over
the over the model parameters and see that
OK that i hope that helps for this i mean it's worth going through one
experiment in some detail which i i guess i should have anticipated that would be
a good idea but i didn't but i if possible i'd like to move on
there's much more but i want to cover all right
so tell you very quickly about two other experiments and hopefully many of the same
issues are relevant like if you want to know what the scale is it's the
and i'm gonna compare
bayes factor log
the likelihood ratio two
human judgments with some arbitrary nonlinear
monotonic scaling this this is also kind of causal judgement but it's one it's a
little bit more interesting a little bit less textbook in which here you're trying to
make sense of peoples
intriguing abilities
remarkable sometimes frustrating to see
hidden causes in from coincidences right we're off the ground we often sensitive to
you know coincidences that that in retrospect turn out to be wrong
and so when we think of our sense of coincidence we might think of it
as this kind of mystical thing whatever i write papers on coincidences i get a
lot of attention from the popular press
because they think oh that's like real psychology and we're mysterious
per something or other
there's there's the most recognition i've ever had in any kind of media which is
that same very much is this show called criminal minds
and then the some something i said about quences was quoted by
protect the by the suspect of the serial killer thing anyway was on CBS ten
million people watched it so i guess this is a good topic to work on
but but the reason we're interested in this is because so much of our actual
called knowledge of the world we think is driven by again noticing coincidence which to
a statistical point of view and you probably not remarkable but to provide some evidence
for hidden cause it's worth exploring so here's an example this may be motivated by
something you might kind of thing that sometimes gets written up in the press you've
may be heard of cancer clusters of disease clusters like somebody notes that you know
in a certain city
there's an unusually high number of cases of some rare cancer and maybe it's because
some evil company was making something into the water and we should go and see
them it turns out most of the time those all those claims don't turn out
the whole but sometimes that kind of reasoning really leads you to a new disease
like lyme disease and today have one disease here now OK well it's terrible thing
my daughter actually had it if she was treated for but it's this is this
thing you can get in the US from being bitten by certain kind of take
a deer tick and
if it is untreated it can cause serious neurological damage is kind of like syphilis
i mean that
you get from being that might take
anyway so so that this was only rediscovered you know maybe terror twenty years ago
in lyme connecticut and that's why it's called like this is
but anyway so imagine that you know this is this is one square mile of
the city and i'm plotting each incidence of a rare cancer in over a year
and i say well you see like little potential cluster over there in the upper
left-hand corner how much evidence you think there's that there's actually some hidden localized cause
some actual thing causing people to get this disease more often in some part of
the city than others
you know here you might say it's not
might be stronger reached this is kind of the middle in case the the way
we model this sort of measures we said OK again we're looking at the kind
of model selection thing but one model is just the this is a uniform distribution
of these events over this space but another model that the interesting one says there's
some hidden common cause which is spatially localized and it's it's kids giving rise to
some of these events but not necessarily all of them in this idea of picking
out a hidden common cause in in sea of noise again a lot of what
the brain is designed to do looks like that so that the space of
possible hidden causes we use we're just gaussians
sort of
gaussians of different scale not rotation in different positions
of the space so we so there's a sort of continuous parameter space here varying
in in mean and variance
these are all possible represent all possible
causes for these disease clusters and in computing the evidence for this model over that
when we have to integrate out those
OK so how how a particular piece of information propagates over the network and the
reason why we can get this is because these disposable timestamp so we know that
i know yesterday yesterday somebody had to write this one so that today i was
able to prefer OK
so this is the blogs and we have have a crawl of forty five thousand
books for you
which is more than ten million posts and we can extract like two hundred fifty
thousand cascades
so this propagation graphs out
the viral marketing programme i talk about
what's the problem with what have said that the followers of the recommendations and they
they they receive discounts on products of the recommendations of success so
here here's how the thing works let's have a person who buys a book
and makes recommendation to another person knows this person decides to buy a book also
they get ten percent discount and successfully commanded gets ten percent so there is an
incentive on both sides
to make
on one side to make successful recommendations and on the other side to buy products
through these recommendations and now you can imagine that this so both people have been
and you can imagine that this now spread over and people continue to call commanding
for the
the thing
and they will be using this incentivized viral marketing programme at some of the big
online stores where they can the data contained like sixteen million recommendations between four million
people and we have confirmation of products and i will go into more detail about
his life
and then the last
diffusion of the community membership is basically have a big social networks where people belong
to explicitly defined communities and
what we will be asking is how the people who
joined these communities
as more and more of their friends are inside so for example communities can be
on on livejournal blogging website people explicitly say what the want friends or a community
with computers i call scientific conference and now you asking what the likelihood that particular
that someone will publish the particular conference given the number of their friends or peers
that are already published in the conference
and again this data is
one of the same size we have a million users
two hundred quarter familiar of groups to join
so the first thing i want to touch upon are how do diffusion curves look
like it is diminishing returns or
or a critical mass type of and this comes from binary marketing when we see
people recommended is to each other and the the x axis is the number of
recommendations of particular person got
and y axis is the probability that
that the article the person buys the DVD after receiving OK recommendation
and what you can see from this is that it sort of diminishing returns
good where where the
where the probability such right so if you buy marketing company
you don't want to send i more than ten or fifteen recommendations for
on one particular DVD otherwise people will start paying attention
and the other thing is also that part
the probability that increases very quickly and then and then it flattens out so this
is for DVD purchases now if you go on on the livejournal we have communities
in the US what's the what's the probability of a person joining a community given
that they already have a number of friends in the community
you can again see very similar to the
the first few method along the
increases and then sort of let flippers and if you if you do if it
like a lot of such a logarithmic it would be to well this
OK so this is another diminishing returns
and then
a series of these for sending email when we have an email network of large
university and he asked what's the probability of
to persons exchanging email given the number of the number of friends they have in
common and again we observed seem similar type of behavior went on the x axis
we plot the number of
friends that he has in common that the probability that the exchange in inside some
and again it's it's monotone slowly increases
and at the lower numbers thinking is more significant as its like
so so these are the diffusion and this is the question i was asked
i want to be really is this
how much how much how much is it for example for viral marketing what what
what we see on what is in the data is that we see that know
the received recommendation and then purchased the product but we don't know whether they also
saw an apple TV
whether they also had personal communication with that particular command and so for example
four when people joining communities it seems i feel we only see the behaviour of
a particular particular time and the questions are again like how did the particular become
aware of the recommendation for how do they become aware that their friends join the
community or how what was the lag between the time the the null decided to
join the community
and the time the joint
things like that
and here is what i want to show you next is the things that maybe
not so simple as they seem as they as they look so one question that
very actually is how this so we saw the dependence on the number of fans
sort of sexual attraction had diminishing returns but
you can ask how does the connectedness of my friends in influence
what the probability of me joining a community or adopting a particular behavior yet so
here i have to explain examples
who is more likely to to to join the community to to join this community
so you know that's has his friends friends in the community and they are not
connected their independent node y
this difference in their are connected so
regional is more likely to join the community
and there are two competing so competing social theories theories that could explain explain
the vision the first one is called the information arguement and it says that
unconnected friends give independent support so that would mean that node x is more likely
to to join the community because they have different for know each other so they
have like three
independent opinions about particular particular thing and having independent opinions that's the other one is
called the social capital arguement which says that safety or trust
is something that that you want from the so if this is a community
i don't know why would be more likely to join because they have a very
they have friends they have a group of friends that are all good friends among
which among each other so if this would be
joining a community i would prefer i would know why we would be more likely
to join because then they could hang out these three friends and everything will be
fine instead of having concealed chemical conformation
these are these are the two competing hypotheses not going to see what's going on
for example if you look at the legend then the the community joining probability increases
as there are more connections between the friends who are already members of the community
announcements six
good time to use it earlier
this afternoon
it's like thirty
we can stop
the stuff about quite
so with
now before before and let's talk about
the slightly more specific
OK so this is a gibbs sampler
in summary the spatial
case of MCMC algorithms
will see the special case of the metropolis hastings
if you look at it
the right way
i do with the
this apparently because
if there is that it comes from
from nineteen
but was
used in the
the main community
from all over europe then me present things four
well i just
the top of all
i need to say about misrepresenting so
this is just just to give you a rough idea
about the principle
of the first chapter is that
there is this universal algorithm
that in principle were
for every problem
the same practice
the number of iterations required just two numbers
to be useful
and finally to it
to get
the right picture
i one and i mean i don't have time to mention
the work that has been going on controlling MCMC agrees and during this parameters according
to different criteria
if you want to know more
there is a chapter in in the book
there is also
this software
that is ridiculous and recalled but
the UGC gs
that is being developed by
people the north sea
need it
preceding throughout her
and implement MCMC principle
in his own language
and are associated with with bugs
there is an issue
unicode code
that is that kind of control
that the convergence
two hours to go to
there exist some
for example
a different slide you want to see the connection present because
it seems like a very different
that barroso
two from the
from metropolis hastings
is like when you do have an optimisation if you have an accumulation to do
not dimensional call
if you want to go
so we can
if you don't to solve the optimisation directly
you may want to start to look at one direction at a time
if you have to maximize the function
of XYZ
you x x and y and you maximizing c
you get
c one
and then maximise
if x y
insy the one you maximizing access to get x one and you keep going is
that and if you're lucky you get to the to the to the optimum of
the function of the function is is is convex
concave you get you get to the global maximum
well here
what to do is try to make this principle for simulation
we start
again the target distributions and here we assume we are in dimensional setting
of course all i said
the idea
didn't require dimension one was working for any dimension
but here it's require more than dimension one because we need to know
the conditional distributions as it was for all the components of x
so what i denote by f one
it is the conditional distribution of x one given x two x three x p
as it is
OK from
we define f one f two f p that are the conditional distributions as it
and if we know that of course we we know the distribution
f one
of x one x given x two
is by bayes theorem
directly proportional
if x y
x two
because if we know that we know that the missing the constant but as usual
the constant doesn't matter
we start from
now arbitrary point again ergodicity
say is that it doesn't matter and
we will simulate successively
x one x two x three x p
from this
full conditionals
and then we start again and again and again
so this is a gibbs sampling agrees to give some
the name is used to the wrong with score like that because
originally it was applied for gibbs
and it's just to name stuck
and structures
the markov chain is therefore
this sequence of p
OK you add xt x one x two x
x two x t
and you successively generate x one t plus one from this conditional could still depends
on x two t
next two
t plus one
is the full conditional text given those now six one t plus one
but still it's t
and we keep moving in one direction at the time to reach t plus one
which depends on the current values of x one x two x p minus one
we should now
all indexed by t plus one
so you can see that it doesn't matter that you can see that that as
one iteration of the algorithm
other sequence of p iterations of
and the reason
well the point is that
sufficiently high level to make intelligent decisions about in some cases you want to appeal
to experts who have special knowledge of it and you have to evaluate the knowledge
so by and large i think with regard to the second part of the question
that most human affairs are
well within the range of ordinary people's
judgments and decisions and there's a suggested in the talk
this in my opinion the judgments of the large majority of the american people are
far more sane and rational
justifiable on moral than those of the intellectual elites and the political class of managers
as the european union
the of course slovenia has a rather special history being conquered by everyone
not having its empire but the most of europe is somewhat different the history the
modern nation-state system was essentially developed in europe
and it's a hideous
that's why you one of the main reasons why europe such as savage history in
the past has many centuries a lot of the savagery of european history
results from the effort to impose
the nation-state systems and societies where they don't make any sense at all
the society diverse many cultural patterns different languages the cross every
dimension you can think of any effort to impose the nation-state system on
lead to wars massacres destruction it's not just the twentieth century after only the thirty
years war probably killed forty percent of the
population germany
i mean the entire history of europe is barbarous savages as part of the reason
why europe was able to conquer the world it had died that year europe was
mostly barbarian fringe the world the centres of world civilization and culture and economic and
so on were age
china and india that europe did conquered world primarily because it had a huge advantage
in a kind of a culture of savagery
and also in the techniques of warfare military historians often point out that in europe
the war became the science
in the rest of the world it was kind of
hobby it now and then
but in europe was just the science simply exterminated most of the conflicts in the
world today
are the result of the
efforts european invaders to impose the nation-state system on other societies to take horrible wars
raging in africa
the worst is in eastern congo were probably forming people have been killed in the
last few years and all over the place and the same and the same of
the major conflicts in pakistan and israel palestinians just go across the world plenty of
examples here by
those wars are
to a large extent not completely the result of
european imposition of
nation-state systems ons in societies and cultures within make any sense
which is just about everywhere
because every part of the world is
sufficiently diverse
so the forcing a nation-state system on them is going to violate human rights actually
the united states and australia
are two exceptions to this
but the reason is that they don't have much internal diversity the ways to europe
but the reason is what i mentioned
english invaders just exterminated the population
if you exterminate population you don't have the version
so in the united states now there is basically one language
but when the colonists came there with thousands of languages thousands of cultures want to
exterminate everybody uniform but short of extermination
it's extremely hard to impose the nation-state system with violence
europe finally in nineteen forty five
reached a point where it
it doesn't have any more wars and there's a big theory in political science and
international relations called the theory of the democratic peace
perspective cont the ideas that one societies become democratic they don't make war on each
other anymore
very hard to find any evidence for that
but you can find evidence for something much simpler one societies reached the point where
they realize that the next time they have war it's convenient everybody
then they don't have were
by nineteen forty five europe europe and its offshoots had achieved levels of destructive capacity
so enormous
that they simply cannot go to war with each other anymore for centuries from france
french and germans considered the highest duty in life to slaughter each other
same with the english and so on
but by nineteen forty five it's an impossibility they can go to war any longer
because the next began
the level of destruction is too high
so you get move towards the european union
and this is good or bad well maybe it has
both aspects
there's this centralizing aspect to the european union which is dangerous
so the power of the central bank in europe
it is so extreme that it's condemned even by the right wing right wingers in
the united states is just too much of an attack on democracy have that much
power in an unaccountable central bank in another
aspects of european integration by me raise similar questions on the other hand it's a
good idea to
have more integration among societies and what instead of sharp boundaries in conflict since all
the good idea to be able to travel from
linear to england passing through lot of complications and other interchanges as well one of
the reactions to
european unity which in my view this is pretty healthy
is the rise of
visible increase in
pressures towards regional
cultural autonomy
so in spain for example
catalonia and the basque country in the world and the others have a fair degree
of autonomy and independence
i was just in scotland
we care so go and scotland now has
parliament still part of the united kingdom but it has a degree
cultural and to a limited extent political independent and that's probably a good thing it's
happening over a lot of you're revival of regional languages regional cultures some political economy
and so on
and the to move towards what sometimes called the europe of the regions
with the nation-state system
being reduced
and with under the federalism but also more
diversity tolerance and support for diversity
you should say that
year two
maybe still
i was under investigation by the
turkish state security
authorities for the crimean separatism
the series ran three was based on the fact that in the talk in southeastern
o one beta one one beta two
and yes important
that if want to be to sum to one
we take
i one with the
i want i want i want to
you know think one of the things also one
so this thing is also a dirichlet
both of these are drawn independently
and the racially web this parameter alpha one is that the two parameters
in exactly the fashion
so that's the decimative property of interest
so now the the idea is the following so dirichlet process is basically an infinitely
decimated dirichlet distribution
so we started
is that recently of alpha
so this is
a one dimensional dirichlet distribution is simply appointed one
we take this thing and was split into two pi one pi two
the way we do it is
basically we draw
in independently with rock island how to
and that if i one
i could i want one one with one hand how to
because of the that the been decimated
we know that we can be helped by itself but rather innovative
that we can take i one i two
these i want to i want what i want to
so that this
o thing i want
we see the hyperlink i one two
so is end is some compact
and again this thing would still be dirichlet distributed with those parameters
we basically do this infinitely often
and let's see how the
however it lot
but little rectangle here
and the area of the rectangle corresponds to
the value of one of the high
so in this case
we have one because basically had their one is one the best possible probability mass
which we can find to the whole space
we take this thing i was split into who
and that i one and i two
so the area
within this rectangle i want
the area within the i two
again we take this rectangle with the two pi one one pi one two
take this thing was that i one and i two two
so if we repeat this we may get
something with the fact that
if we actually
do this of like
a lot of time
yes what we get
we had one thing each
rectangle into two parts
and we keep on doing it
thing it
basically draw from our trees the process
noticed that
it almost looks like a bunch of
o point masses
and in fact
so what this means is that draws from dirichlet process
it's basically a discrete distribution
property is that if
properly what is the dirichlet process dirichlet process is basically
a distribution over probability measures
what probability measures we can think of probability measures
as simply
functions as well
it it's a probability measure is a function from subsets of some base act
two zero one
which satisfy certain properties which makes the them probability measure
so these are properties which are things like
variable we eliminate everything else we can get any information about the ability of the
variable given to know something else so if you actually want to compute marginals for
everything which is a common occurrence when you're doing see learning is not very useful
the junction tree algorithm essentially
do variable elimination serve in all directions at the same time
right so that instead of doing so if you want to compute marginals are possible
running variable elimination and times your junction tree once you get all the marginals
it's basically the same amount of time
as everyone manage OK so it's just a way to organize competitions
so the things are removed because when computing the marginal for this guy and give
model for this guy
i'm doing a lot of the same kind of propagation
by the same sort of elimination so junction trees a data structure that that allows
you to
basically do everything at once and keep track of it without
retracing your steps
so individual modules is one thing you might want but you might want
things that are likely to unknown parents injection to do that
there are a few other things so
OK let's contention trees we have
graph right
and this is the set of
cliques in it right so cluster graph is just sort of a set of
groupings of variables
right so bring variables and things are connected in this in this cluster of they
shared nodes but now a cluster graph is the junction tree has the following properties
one singly connected so we want the actual tree
right so we have exactly one path between each pair of clusters are this questions
from the graph
they get
so the green cluster and the purple one
and the light blue
and i want exactly one between
OK so this is going to allow us to do
their elimination without introducing
any more cliques
it turns out the things covering free to create
this this the input graph then there's a cluster c
that contains
so if i had
you know click here
have potentials associated with them and we take the potentials and represent them in this
cluster of
OK so
i know a place to put this thing
OK so always ensures that i can take the potential
and stick it into the street it's going to be square present my
i graph
and the third thing you need is was called the running intersection
and learning social properties that
is that if you have
a pair of clusters
this one and this one and they both contain
each cluster on the path between these things contains b
france so
this is satisfied here because these here here is unique between them and these in
what that guarantees it turns out that when we compute all marginals are going to
be doing this running variable elimination or something like the information our computer models on
the street
so in the end get a marginal rate and marginal would be marginal BC
and these marginals are going to agree with each other and if if he was
missing from here
it might happen is that the marginal get here in the morning get here i
don't really know about each other
and they completely disagree so the running intersection property property
in nineteen here
the intuition for it's trying to essentially enforce consistency
OK so
we start with our
just to restate we start with the graph has a bunch of
clicks on it
there we want to build a junction tree with these properties it has these clusters
for each clique where we can accommodate all are
it it singly connected
and running intersection
so going from set of cliques in two clusters
so how do you do this how do you do this
basically you know you start was kind of variable elimination idea june ordering and use
node elimination
two things sort of these creeks
that gives you a set of these
so complete cluster graphs or
the mission figs are maximal so you don't take part the clique over a b
can c
the end creek or b and c astonishing click don't worry about it so i
we take the maximum ones
so i remember elimination i get these factors
right i look at the maximal ones and so
filter the ones that are subsets
and i believe that you know
compute cluster graph so now
clusters are connected if they if they share variables like a certain cluster of in
their connected to share it was so
now we have no proof those
the edges by running a maximum weight spanning tree OK so expansion is going to
to ensure that there is exactly a unique path between everybody and
and in this case running intersection
the property of singly connected bring section covering so the weight on each and each
it is actually usually done by
but this computing the size of the in c
the reason for this is what we're doing eventually is
computing kind of factors that can move back and forth
red and the weight of each edge like the expense the the expense that we
could incur by using that edge is corresponds to
kind of the number of possible values these things can take
passing messages that are the size of the joint assignments of thing
by finding
maximum weight one actually we ensure that consistency so
there's not going to go going to prove why this works but this is how
you do it i mean you need to pick a good orderings right and heuristics
for doing that
you but after that it's it's not you it's very simple
here's an example
to make this country
we sort of creeks
one we eliminated the order was
really the the then even see the OK
these are the nation cliques
and then what we have done is looked at the maximum one so e
it's not that someone is contained here
and the rest are sent from a complete graph where there is an edge since
so there is the kind of shot into this room
the receiver the person called the receiver is the one who is going to try
to be psychic
she in this picture is going to try to receive information
from somewhere else
the monitor is kind of like coach who going to explain to her what she
needs to do
the monitor has no idea what the right answer is and this picture here
is there basically just described her with her task is going to be and to
make sure that she does
OK so once they are in the room and assistant does not roll dice in
system uses a computer but harder to illustrate with computer so assistant randomly picks
the target
the target comes from in this case it's shown that there's a bunch of files
in if file can
in some experiments we actually did have folders with photographs and
the photographs were all taken from national geographic magazine
and so the receiver we know that it was going to be a photograph from
national geographic magazine that's all they were now
so one of the photographs is chosen as the target oh i should mention in
some laboratories especially these days instead of photographs they use very short clips from movies
maybe fifteen second
from the movie because it seems like
the more information there is to receive the more information
is received
we'll see that
OK so let's say came out as a picture of the town hall
the receiver spend fifteen or so minutes trying to describe what she thinks the target
actually is
and we have
this is what happens
so that's the basic outline of the experiment now how is
in evaluating
give you some details
so first of all for security purposes after the session the drawings and descriptions are
copied and secured so they can't be changed so the originals are locked away so
nobody can alter the
and then the person the receiver is given feedback showing him or her the copy
of what they true and also what the correct answer was
and then the results are judged now in some laboratories the person who actually did
the description is the judge
and then of course before they actually show the right answer
in other laboratories is an independent judge
so it just depends on the structure
so this meets condition number one safeguards to rule out cheating and ordinary means of
but i haven't shown you how we need condition number two about knowing probability the
here's an example of an excellent match this was one of the experiments done well
actually so the program moved up one point from sir i to another think tank
in the stanford area called SAIC science applications international corporation so here's an example of
an experiment that was done there and yellow
what about the writing it because it would be kind of hard for you to
but basically this is what the receiver drew
you just do this picture he said here there would like he mountain here
barn or large cabin
shadow trees road path american rockies or maybe alps
and the correct target was
better than i could have done if i had been looking at a picture
so this is the kind of thing that i would say once in a while
that would really be striking and yet the evaluation process is you'll see
it doesn't take advantage of how good that is it just basically
you'll see how do the judging
which is this guy
it's actually corrected mistakes
but the first
OK so here's a more typical example in the early days they actually didn't use
photographs they actually had
but the current outbound experimenter who would
the given a randomly selected and the target location based on an envelope would be
picked from a series of possibilities and the person would be forced to drive to
that location
and current trends send information from that location
they called them the outbound founder experiment so here's an example from those days
basically just says parking
a single structure building that brown's next edge water boats large parking area
and you are shown this to be subliminally give you a hand held and that
this was the location where person had gone
so again
pretty good match however not skeptics
this is the san francisco bay area
water gas lots of it's only the water that is surprising gas
large parking areas so this person supposed to drive locations
get out and looks of course let's choose locations that have parking areas
OK so what may seem like
a surprising match might just have some elements that would make sense boats and so
so we can judge it by looking in just trying to compare like that
so how do we judge well here's how not to do is an interesting little
story behind this but i just read this so scott adams i get delivered in
your countries but in the united states the popular comic
so scott adams did series and can skeptic and i'll give you a little story
behind but
so can the skeptic is saying i don't know the content of this and below
and so the i think it's a doctor
delivered anyway the guys who the characters as it to charcoal drawing which i think
is smaller and and can skeptics as nice try fraud that's a long way from
in trying to be reading a tangerine
so the story behind this is in nineteen ninety five government decided to declassify the
research because the cold war was over classified some of it
and the helen mentioned
i was on the team with ray hyman who is one well-known skeptic and we
were to do an evaluation of the research for congress and so we did this
evaluation and we published well we weren't allowed actually published results at first and then
somebody leads them to ABC news so we're on TV for about a week we're
on larry king live on CNN news here these TV shows and so scott adams
saw this and you wanted to know what was going on so called up and
may was the project director and then when i had lunch and then describe what's
going on in the series i can scale
so the point here is we can't use subjective probability of a match there's just
too much room for personal bias
so can the skeptics can pretty much dismissed whatever is done
infinite dimensional case
come to no surprise
then why should we care about this all the more to men with invasion is
the application to hierarchical bayes modelling which is
not quite the standard way of doing bayes modelling
it allows you to model situations where you have related but not
identical models for different situations example if your model
the outcome prediction in different hospitals these models might be slightly different
but also have a lot in common situation they can apply hierarchical bayes models
and then this is one of the core of the whole lecture usually processes
and then i will and its applications
and a couple more comments on nonparametric bayesian model
so this sort of two
get people want to to think about bayesian approaches to machine learning
so probability theory is considered a branch of mathematics
so you start with axioms and theorems are theorems
to prove things to be true or not
and statistics and statistical machine learning thirty attempts to apply probability theory
to solving problems in the real world
examples i effectiveness of medication so this is the typical problems statisticians want to address
is a significant improvement if you apply medication not in machine learning my text classification
you want to design a medical expert system where you want to incorporate the
the expert medical experts knowledge into a system and then you have to do inference
in the system about
disease is sometimes and so on
there are different approaches to applying probability theory to problems in the real world and
useful way
the classical way ways the frequentist way frequentist statistics and the bayesian statistics
in statistical learning theory
and there are couple more
so all of them seem to be doing something useful in their own right and
it's probably not very good idea to
try to start a discussion about which one is the
right one which is the wrong one there
situations where each of them can be very useful and but today we will take
a bayesian
o point of view on all of this
OK if that i was really started very far back
warming up a little bit cell
because if you haven't done bayesian statistics and what you might remember all these simple
bruce anymore so i will be with the review them briefly so the joint distribution
of x and y simply means the probability that that he observed that random access
in state x and y is in state y
then there is the definition of conditional distributions
p of y
given x
it is defined as the joint u of x and y
divided by p of x was just give experts normalizes this expression is the proper
probability the t in terms of y
this improves
then there's is the product decomposition if you have distance of two random variables you
can always decompose them in the probability distribution of one of them and then in
terms of distribution second one given the first one
and of course you can also change the order and get to
another decomposition
and this can be extended to repeatedly apply this rule we obtain the chain rule
of probability so any high dimensional probability distribution x one to x and can be
decomposed in any order by starting for example with x one
then you multiply it by the probability of x two given x one x three
given all the previous appear in the formula
and the last term is x given all
his predecessor this these are one dimensional probability densities and this is very general and
of course one hopes and that one can use exploit some independencies in the domain
for example x three is independent of x one given x two something of that
sort and this also the basis for invasion
network which are essentially implementation of the decomposition in in terms of the graphical representation
but as we have always who was also very simple PX given y is just
the definition of conditional probability distribution and then into the product decomposition up here and
you can through p of x
the enwise PY x two x divided by p of y
so all of this is a very simple very basic in bayesian modeling
formulas all the time and i think the last one which is relevant is the
marginalisation so if you know the joint probability distribution and you want to calculate the
one of the variables involved after integrate
this distribution over all the other animals
in the distribution
this marks solution mean this calculation gives you all the headaches if you applied to
the given problem
so so these are the basic rules which we use all the time the statistics
we simply apply these rules in
statistical sense so
same set of solutions that is given the upon daily mode of thought there exists
a unique density of new such that of the of quantized equals
the density said that
what uh purified is not defined in unique way so this equality holds up to
another measure such
OK and I would like to mention in passing a wide it's interesting to interests
in conveys dimensions
so that by construction quantizer subset
very dense and probability mass
for a fixed volume they maximize the probability mass while equal entry for a fixed
probability mass that minimize the volume and solar and they and tools of special interest
for investigating the structure of distributions and that's why are
and they are used in many unsupervised learning applications such that anomaly detection cluster analysis
probably many other applications
so now we're back to the 1 class is you and so this is the
algorithm exchange and the question
it is
what's the link between the acceptance region
computed by the algorithm and quantize or equivalently the density of
In the paper from coffin called
it was suggested that the algorithm might be for this problem but also I think
so far there has been no proof stating that this algorithm is effectively consistent for
this task and so that's the main from the main contribution of the work that
I'm going to presented now we have all of the all the of the all
all is name of the the of this program of and
so the main contribution here is to say that under certain assumptions and in some
contexts and want us as helium actually is actually consistent for estimating that set so
this context is characterized by the use of a fixed
the regularization parameter and that is whatever the number of training data points we will
work with a fixed values for the parameters and so this
this might be not in the spirit of standard liberalization since when we do regularization
the parameter
is usually a vanishing turns a syntactically but here we will work with the constant
that is 1 of the main particularity of the set up but in addition we
will consider the Gaussian kernel
and with a well-calibrated Bandwidth signal we consider a bandwidth that decrease starts at a
certain speed synthetically right so that know the very top can begin was sort of
introduction and uh so the talk is structured as follows in the 1st part I
will present the main result together with necessary notation for expressing the result
and also I will presented what I call the the picture of the whole machinery
so in in order to be viewed the inclusion of the main reason why the
main results actually holds
and afterwards so that the next 4 parts will be dedicated to the periphery proof
of that so that the
so uh unpublished use from the patients so
exploit accession that the data sample drawn from unknown probability distribution P the probability has
compact support well as support included in the reference subset subsets X which is assumed
to be compact so the accessories including on the
and the so really keep in mind that exist combined because it's strong assumption and
the result that I'm going to present are only valid for compact subset
than that the Gaussian kernel in here know that we used normalized to Gaussian kernel
so this this is the standard along with this constant that depends on sigma and
the thing is if we take the integral on audio of these functions with respect
to the 1st viable
that the interval equals 1 in
and page sigma is the associated Gaussians tests
entities and build with the normal denoted like that of denote by s sigma hat
the output of the one class SVM algorithms when used with the Gaussian kernel with
with sigma
and finally we use this notation
policy now that 2
this is something create
so this is the theoretical versions of this asymptotic there
3 of the emperical as risk so we just replace them by recalled comes here
so who who in this class is thinking of preparing a phd degree and who
in this class has already completed should degree so that's not something semantic many most
of you are actually preparing his it's so i'm assuming actually for most of you
know this material must must have been easier how many of you are working on
machine learning already gave so how many of you thought to know this
this introduction was easy to understand
who hasn't this is only the beginning of the intersection so how many of you
had heard before of kernel methods
how many of you have worked on the electrics on many of you have worked
on decision trees many of you have worked on monday to talk about it
how many of you had heard about our fitting
OK so the the development of of it so how many of you understands after
this lecture what is a risk functional i would like to see how many of
you understands what is a linear decision boundary
and uh
thank you
OK so let's go back very quickly then
and see how well we're doing here
so how many of you understands what on these axes
the index is the x and y here because of vote for the liberal understand
looking at this
i'm going on this year
looking at this matrix which is the data matrix
OK you have two dimensions
the number of features child the numbering of of input components and the number of
examples and so on on the axis of of these plots i'm showing the number
of features or inputs and the number of examples of this is the aspect ratio
of the data of the of the data and the aspect ratio of the data
is very important how many examples you have relative to the number of features that
plainly playing a lot with that in this class in india actually trying to take
these input matrix and shrink in that direction here discard features the features that are
not important because there are other cases in which we might want to discard examples
usually you don't want to discard examples right because examples are very useful in the
more examples you have the better you can train but in some cases you might
want to group examples because if your matrix is very sparse and and only few
features at the time are active then one example alone might not carry enough information
so might want to smooth things an average examples that's something people do but in
this class will be working mostly in that dimension how to compress data by removing
features that are useless or redundant
so how many of you understands this this graph here what it does so most
of you have understood that these are the inputs inputs so weighted
by some weights and to compute the decision function
and it's not which is this
so and is number of features in the conventions that i'm i'm using and is
going to be always number of features and and the number of examples
so it's very important to notice that because in the
percent from case you see that the sum runs over and so here's began because
we have transformed first inputs into new features so we have the original matrix which
have this small and here and then we doing some transform and you know we're
going to increase the number of features or to decrease it
in the case of the kernel methods actually usually increasing the number of features so
what happens in the case of the kernel method is that the sum now runs
over and but because of the kernel trick that i've shown you before you can
go between the two representations
you can transform the percent into a kernel methods and vice versa and the reason
why this is interesting is that then you can have few implicit feature spaces that
are of infinite dimension
why would you want that's well
the you want and a lot of expressive power so if you plunge your original
input into the very big feature space then you're going to be able to draw
decision boundaries that are very complex in your original input space
whereas in the feature space it it could be a linear decision function so that's
that's the main idea the main trick you gonna be taking original feature space and
for example the first people working on that they just make products of the input
features so one that when he invented the percent had this idea
well let's take random let's take random features this some feature the fund under the
and next take an arbitrary billion function and compute some feature at at random from
some of the original features and that many many times and by using these random
building functions he expanded his or original feature space into huge feature space and then
he said well not that had this huge feature space i'm just going to be
using a linear decision function and because he plunged his original they find a huge
feature space then he could make a perfect separation of the training examples with just
a simple linear separation it's a linear separation but there's hyper plan in in a
very very high dimensional space and you have big n now began can be you
know hundreds of thousands of of these features that are computed with these random building
now if you did that to address the problem that people would say well linear
decision functions are to simple they they can't express the complexity of the data there
are many datasets but are not linearly sufferable that is if you take the training
data you can't make is zero error separation you can't make an analyst separation that
will put all the examples of one class on one side all the examples of
the other class on the other side with a simple plane he said well no
problem i'm going to use these random building functions plunged original space into much bigger
i one
so i'm going to talk about this tool which he developed as
this recording
this one
so i try to stay
close to this mica that are
so i talked about this tool literally we've been developing at accenture as some of
you may know or some of you may not know the accenture consulting company
and most of our projects if not all of them
start by
requirements documentation which is
pretty important part of the process
so we've
what we've done is that we building tool which has got some very light-weight semantic
analysis and we're are moving deeper into
using ontologies so
so much of the things in the show this talk is going to be divided
into two two parts the first is the lexical and syntactic and syntactic analysis part
which is what already being developed and is currently being used by many of our
teams and then the semantic analysis part is what the talk about is what getting
into the reprobates with these but not many teams have used it yet
two stocks
to start the it like i said you know most of our projects started requirements
probably the for most software companies to
and it's by the number is really just do not picked up a couple of
numbers from a couple of studies it's been shown that if you get the requirements
it it can lead to lot of problems i'm not going to go into these
numbers but it's worth mentioning that you like we are moving more and more and
were distributed development model so so that put even more pressure on getting the requirements
right to begin with
i don't know if
people have seen this happen before
i'm sure some of you have seen it variant of
getting requirements wrong
the number of
factors which cause it
but the it is that in all stakeholders don't know what they want
another part is that the analyst may not understand what the stakeholder wanted and like
that can cause all kinds of problems and finally note
people may misunderstand what the analyst talk to that could cause even more problems so
obviously we cannot solve all the problems but that this particular tool what we are
trying to do
is that they're trying to
please make sure that
the people who write the requirements that i as clear and precise way as possible
so that some of these problems are elected
requirements pretty important part of the process
the many different people with a different skill sets who interact with it
so far
this is a really important point because get into it into the middle the next
light but it's important to understand that the different kind of people who are dealing
with a low you go to the stakeholders who are
many business people there are some technical people but ultimately the people were signing of
the requirements are pretty high up in the business and they're not necessarily technical so
you want to write requirements in every way they can understand them because ultimately has
the responsibility to sign and then the requirements team
first interfaces usually
business people
business analysts who are again
some of them may be technical but most of them are not
it's very hard to get them to
do anything which is farmers so they
if stick to
writing in english
on and then you want the technical side of the picture you want the design
team which are typically architects or designers who requirements document and
i try to create designs in architecture from them and then finally got the development
team who use the requirements as well as
the designs to actually create this office
so this
what working on is that in like number of problems for requirements can cause a
number of problems and others
a number of people have created a different kind of documentation best practices to help
avoid these problems and by many other best practices i just listed a few of
them and can try to organize them into
different categories
so lexicalized free the level you know that things like
they resemble things that don't use big words such as you know i don't see
a system will be easy to use are
flexible or so on and so forth
why this seemingly trivial i mean you'd be surprised home is
such requirements exists
which cause problems later on then that things like using consistent terminology making sure that
you refer the same system using the same name
again in the requirements document is about a thousand
pages are
you want to achieve what are the requirements some of these things start causing problems
then that things like make sure that each requirement the a single sentence and its
so and try to write requirements in in standard a syntax some things like you
know make sure that you clearly see who's doing what in this particular case using
the system
is the person who's doing something shall generate report
so instead of saying things like reporting generated
it's better to articulate who exactly the personal
the system is
doing a particular function
similarly and then there's
domain specific or semantic relationships like this comes more you like
this may be applicable during design or even for the business analysts like you know
knowing things like
including the security may include the performance
the main don't affect the kind of hard choices you make so that bunch of
dependency the the domain which
at least our assertion is that if you go into more than using ontologies you'll
be able to help either the business analyst on the stakeholder or the designers made
more intelligent choices and then there might be some enterprise knowledge where you may know
that you know certain platforms don't support a certain kind of technology
so it's much better to be able to look at this as early on as
possible so i'll talk a little bit about it on how we are trying to
get people who create rules and capture them
so that you know we can check
beginning to find these problems that
at the requirements stage
there's been a lot of work on requirements analysis and software engineering
they just
i mean if you look at it you were two options
one is that you try to get people to write requirements in the former location
and then you know
but then one two and the former location it becomes easier to analyse four different
kinds of properties
but the problem is that