find a good solution to o two two these cost functions and here here comes
the first sort of
the first i think conceptual challenge for the for the pattern recognition community for the
learning community is
usually what we did in vision is to
we we we we took that function h depending on the assignment c
condition on your data x and the following then the best possible
partitioning see star
now if you bring that in contact with let's say classification then the analogy would
be simply the following age is your empirical risk you have an image and then
you minimize the empirical risk for that particular image and see star then is the
best possible what you can do on training data
however we should also be wrong that in classification that is not the correct strategy
in the ending classification what you are paying for is the expected risk
so i strongly believe that we as a community have to extend these notions which
are very clear in in in in in classification and regression to more complicated problems
like the bands coming up in in computer vision and it's by no means so
clear what is the expected risk for segmentation
so when i right now and see star is the minimum the the argument of
the minimum of h
i'm sort of short cutting
the full problem of inference which might be hard be behind an image segmentation task
because i'm i'm i'm not saying by writing that down i want to get the
minimum of the empirical risk
but maybe that's not what i really want maybe i want to have the minimum
of some expected risk and i don't really know what it is
OK let's
just summarize we have two basic problems the choice of the cost function the algorithmic
optimization and the first one is is strongly application driven choice which we have to
make it and i think you can find a lot for the fells point and
you know different approaches sort of tend to emphasise different properties of an application area
and that's why people don't get a unique answer to the first but then after
you have settled following cost function h it's a clear combinatorial it's in informatics problem
you just find solution and you ask your favourite guy from from from applied mathematics
to give you an optimization
by strictly separating these two design steps i think we can you can sort of
separate the model
phase from the algorithmic issues which is very valuable when you when you look for
four new solutions to to your view data analysis problems there is the trade of
you know most of you have experienced that simple cost functions are easy to optimize
but they are not kept praying all the all the details of your complex problem
and the result is what we call as conditioning
and the reason because it was a strange because was
footsteps by themselves have nothing to do with the
i mean associations completely archer i would say that so how is it that
could trigger this very primitive
but when i think about last condition and the way to explain this is
is stimulus substitution this is the way that i understand classical conditioning stimulus substitution
so in the case of the dogs
the natural stimulus for salvation is
the natural systems
it is going to make it obvious out of my make use of
it makes me sad
and that's very natural
it's very understandable and that
it's either on
that's why they call it
on condition
because we never learn its natural in war
so it's the unconditioned stimulus
the unconditioned response is television
now we're going to substitute one stimulus for another instead
we're going to say
the footsteps of the last
and that's the soon we substitute
and now
conditions that this is the
footsteps of lattice systems are going to trigger that same response to response change
the response doesn't change
the only thing that's changing here
is on the stimulus i
it's it's it's going from the unconditioned
it is
substituting for
is the sound of footsteps
so that's why i call
classical conditioning still substitutions very simple
his appointment on more unconditioned stimulus
cases stocks
two conditions which happens to be
the footsteps of glasses or could be another
it could be an interesting it could be what it would be another example
some of them
it could be the flash of light
could be a particular color it could be
he knows what it doesn't really matter
all kinds of visual stimuli
we can substitute
for the conditions the
that sounds weird sounds esoteric
i don't want to dismiss it actually is very important
here it is important to understand
to understanding how students respond in classrooms
and we'll get to that just what actually is quite important
so let's look at this again
classical conditioning stimulus substitution we have the unconditioned stimulus which which is
produces unconditioned response
which is salivation it's unconditionally because on
learn is natural it's in more it's pretty close to reflux biological
that's why
the condition part we have conditioned stimulus
this condition because it is about or what steps or some other stimulus
produced consistent conditioned response television
response stays the same
what's changing here is stainless steel substitution
that is easy
the last condition
the skill that's life
let's add a couple more concepts to class conditional because
we need to run a little bit we can say there are two other aspects
of classical conditioning should be about
one is stimulus generalization and the other stimulus discrimination
so imagine now the power law has conditions
dream mall
that's the sound of a ringing bell
it brings into is like a failed as slightly different
pretty close
but not exactly the same pitch
well that are still
some of these
cover this this space here
how do you think you might represent this with
if you are
with with less information
at the moment we needed an x one and x two core we need two
numbers to represent the position of each of those
can we do better
sure has a good it so distance
maybe even someone else might be able to follow on from that distance from where
to where
what kind of distance by we been
right OK
so we might take a line which some somehow fits these and the distance from
the right so if we have a line in the starting point
then we're going to be able to say
how far along
along that line
it is far from
so usually we take something which isn't exactly the best
fit line the something
and we call
the principal component that's the direction in which the
data varies the most
given this
this distance up and down the line
we've got one coordinate representing two-dimensional date
and we've half the
our requirements to describe each data point
it comes in a bit of a cost
because we can only move along this line now with one
with one number so there are
kind of inaccuracies we get that we exhibit of information about our latest from the
front line
but notice we can always
you know we could always
think about how far points are in this direction and also how far along are
this direction too
we could take
we could take the
the next
orthogonal directions that is
the direction at right angles to that so
moving in each direction is independent
we could represent each thing in into numbers again
and then we'll be having you might think why would you do that because we
are two dimensional data
and then it would still be two-dimensional was still moving along this one along this
but we could we know the one dimension is thought more important than another one
so if you had three d data which
basically way on on a flat
two d plane this was this kind manifold underlying then we could do the same
thing we could take we could find the first two principal components
so principal components are directions in which the variance of the data is high
and the components are always
what focal which are always right angles so they form
a new set of axes
so basically take the x y and z axes that were used
and we're finding
new set of axioms which are in some way natural to the
to date is like the data is natural
coordinate system
and if we do that in the right way
and if the data does not lie in some kind of linear space
then you can pretty safely ignore some of the dimensions
so you know that the
it's the variability is very high and some very low another then you take this
natural coordinate space and that actually smaller than the original recording space the data
and maybe some you know this is an approximation so you're you're you're losing numbers
but you
i hope that your
losing information you're not interested in
you think that the position in this plane is interesting thing and not
how far it is above or below the plane
OK calculating principal components we've got the choice of things do this afternoon and this
is this is one thing we could do
but all this linear algebra is
extremely simple to carry out
if you have something like american python matlab octave one not the basically just a
couple of you need to calculate the mean of the data to remember the of
the line we need to have some starting point and we say from here
the distance
up and down the line or around this plane
we then calculate the
covariance of the data
the i can values in the i can vectors can just one function call
i can vectors are
these directions this kind of natural coordinate space for the for the data
they're always right angles to each other
i mean i can values give you measure of how much variability there is in
that direction
so and i can vector with i i can value means that most of the
there is in that direction
so for this
o thing here we have an i back to this way through is
unit distance one thing about the
there was right angles
this vector here would have a higher corresponding
i can value this one here would have low corresponding eigen value so by looking
at those values can see
we've got this
new axis here this new representation
had significant another one which is not significant
so it's very easy to calculate those things just three commands
and in order to work out our new
to change
coordinate systems we just need to project from one to the other
so far
o point was here
are axis runs along this way because one-dimensional axis and we just gotta projected down
to the nearest point on the line
very simple we just take the
data point we subtract the mean we take the dot product with the principal components
for this i conductors we may be take for citing that
so very simple
these the
that's that's right so we're finding the
basically reducing it to zero distance
from from one to finding the closest closest point
so this works
pretty well in a lot of applications in one
one application where it's really surprisingly
and surprisingly effective
find long time ago
is in face recognition and face data is high dimensional you've got these
image patches of different people's faces
surprisingly you can represent face is fairly well with just the low number of dimensions
so you know even like ten
ten dimensions can be enough to capture a lot of the significant variability in in
a solution and i think what we're doing with virtual organizations because of the way
that the structured exactly these kinds of systems
balance on the edge of order and disorder
all the time
collins work
phase transitions where you get a certain number of connections where you reach critical mass
of connections to get phase transition into a new form of organisation emerged
conservatives k
not going to use this point seventy people have been talking about twenty
what i think
possibly more common to
it's easier for us from the start because we've seen that networks around us all
the time so the notion can activities easier concept
for example the the notion of randomness or disorder
those of the lot emotional
babbage versus human beings so we have to kind
should tells us about the key with these ideas
structured graph
some structure in our world
variability now this is an old cybernetics idea
i'm actually
so increasing variability actually very to states in the system is thus increasing the complexity
of the system and this is not always
and then you have
and the second order cybernetics idea the relative subjective complexity the notion that it's just
like descendant of our minds the human lives now
actually i not a proponent of bounded rationality i believe it's incorrect ideas
and that
what we have is attention span problem
we have
and attention span problem and that developed tools and techniques in order to actually be
able to
do first stuff concurrently that we would ordinarily have to do
our attention to pass sequences so for example
instead of
going through the process of adding something
you might have a little mac in the spreadsheet that just as all possible
so that allows you to assign tensions
before that actually the self organizing system
it's neurons dendrites
in nature
gives instructions appear
we get four classes
we're not complexity and size or one of the board one problems with actually happened
to concepts as the successor
she would reward
because this particular slide might be very helpful to talk about
so we talk about structure we talk about landscape which is
the notion fitness
which is about behavior
i'm talking about organisation
in all the discussions where mixing all these things but there are actually particular classes
complexity measures
so we have a way of measuring structure we define the state space of the
last landscape the way of understanding the behavior that's right
and the way of understanding of
let's see the kinds of organisation might get some activated
over time
so rather complex mathematical tools actually
and the theories taken from dynamical systems theory statistical mechanics and algorithmic approaches to
two information theory
i'm going to start with the principles of self organizing systems that give me the
simple as i can have my ten of these principles
OK there helpful
if you disagree please say so because these are not stone
this is what we know so far and we don't they apply to all systems
will also organizing systems all like this will do this thing
so this is not
i'm not
so there's no interference from the outside the grand divide the comes from within
and this is one of the key principles
the key principles of self organizing systems that actually it's an interaction that destruction
the organisation emerges
this one
tensions were facing
is that were intentional bees and we create structure create order so
does that mean that this is actually a self organizing processes that is
but we actually are part of
the constraints we create this constraint
also the future is to find out what is happening right now
and my comments about her inside coupling this is what we call the system so
the principles of organisations such as the immediacy is introduced
in order to predict what there are measures that are being developed to be able
to predict different in system of both economic systems social systems large collective
and physical systems in order to secure what would be the next structure that might
from the current state
and that's i think part of what this would be interested in doing
what i can do
show you here
and indeed the direction of polarization is exactly
as i pointed out
by my sunglasses
why sunglasses
no i claim that
this is the preferred directions of polarization
and this is the preferred directions of polarization
of these pieces that you have
the light and that's exactly what's happening
do nothing
the line for there but if i rotate this
like this
you should like
i can see why
so i've demonstrated to you
that my sunglasses i design
so if you have some home
you can test that because you have a linear polarizer
you know
what direction those
all right so that was
let's see what's next
i have given numerous times my exams
when i was like doing here
famous course eight o two
but i mentioned to you which is called
electricity and magnetism
the name of that course
like the electromagnetic waves so
clearly when you learn about electricity and magnetism one about light
i've had numerous times
an exams
give them five pictures
one character
one picture i this
and in one picture i do this as the student in what direction should they
you get
all kinds
but some of them
and the right made for the wrong reason
then the question or exams
and i want you to look for a linear polarizer
and all the other that that we have here
around in the room
and on the table
there is no
strong sunlight
blind you out
there's no
beautiful not fifty degree fifty five degree angle
everything is random
but if you look very carefully you will take you linear polarizer very slowly
you may see
looking at the last few years
that you will this you will be able to change the reflected light
and if you look at the end of the year
you will not see
do it very slowly and with the last few years
the metal there
this the metal here
it depends on where you sit
i can see it very clearly
some of the light from the
fluorescent tubes
bounces off
at approximately right angles
and so then becomes
partially polarized it will not be hundreds
percent polarized because the angle is not exactly perfect
you're sitting at random locations
and these objects are randomly placed is not as nice experiment as i did here
which is one
we can actually see what you rotate them
clearly see that the light intensity
of the class object changes but it doesn't change
when you look at the map
and if it does change when you look at the metal
then i can tell you why
it is possible
it is possible that the mapping is very close to the glass
when the light bounces off the graph
becomes partially polarized and then bounds of the metal it remains partially
but we tried to set them up in such a way
but that's not going to happen
if it home
you want to test look around
off the record the reflection of the pain may be on the kitchen table
you may also tried is on the mirrors that you have
keep in mind mirror
has an aluminum
back which is meant
so if you look into a mirror you think you're going to get polarized light
you won't succeed
it's only the light
the boundaries of
the surface of the glass
like that part of the problem of the mirror which is that
the amount of light
responses of
like the mirror
it's not
linearly polarized even if you make the angle just for
when you look at the rainfall
a rainbow in the sky
OK so let me
let me briefly resume what we talked about this morning before lunch and where i
would like to resume here so we are talking about the problem of
structured prediction and so far been talking about how we will try to generalize the
multiclass classification setting how we will
basically define
feature maps that extract features from inputs and outputs and i show different cost functions
that we could define one most likely based cost function the other one
that i will talk about i think next is the hinge loss based
approach and then i will talk more about reasons behind this and what i should
just before the lunch break is basically what i why i think
actually the support vector machine style of learning algorithm that i will present is actually
quite attractive one and that has to do with
the sparseness properties of the solution if you look at it
as the solution to the optimisation problem over a reproducing kernel hilbert space which is
that you get this representer theorem that says as usual you can represent your solution
as an expansion over kind of functions evaluated on your training data but as far
as the output part is concerned you also need to include some or all possible
wise which makes this really large and it's interesting to
set the problem up in a way that
this something it becomes very sparse so that only some of these martin this is
i why some of these batteries actually zero
OK so so
the way i would like to accomplish that is by using basically minimum log odds
loss function here so the way you can define this is just is the log
of the probability of
the output given y
OK so this is for here this is called the probability of the correct output
divided by
the probability
all of the y prime that gets the largest conditional probability given x case this
is similar to what we've been saying before and of course this just amounts to
if we take the log of these things to what he called the margin on
the training example before OK when we talked about multiclass classification
so basically here
so we can do the same thing right we can say well we have this
compatibility function f which will be linear in some armature station or is it can
be represented as shown in the representer theorem and if we apply this to the
correct pair x i y i will get some value and if we applied to
some otherwise get another value and really what we're looking at is the maximum value
over all wise that are unequal y and then the difference in this we call
gamma i k and this is basically what you get here
and the way we can define the the usual hinge loss
to get like a soft margin and support vector machine type of solution is that
we say well
we define the maximum margin loss
by looking at the max of zero and one minus the max the minimum log
of right so this is the usual definition if the margin is large enough then
this will be zero as soon as the margin drops below one will incur a
penalty here and that it will be proportional to the margin
OK that we achieved
so if we do this now we basically just like everything in and we get
our first problem formulation
this is called also SVM struct
and so basically in the primal what we now get is as in the multiclass
just the minimisation over the norm of some weight vector square and
and then here's the part that has to do with fact variables and then as
far as the constraints go now you get exactly what we've seen before also in
the multiclass classification case we're basically this max constraint now is expanded and we get
the number of constraints that now depends on the cardinality of the output space so
already for multiclass classification i said that if the number of classes really large then
we get an awful lot of constraints and here of course assuming that the of
the space is you know some combinatorial set of possible outputs
this is usually the
in feasible right to deal with explicitly like this but we can still you know
right on the problem like that and it's interesting to investigate this
OK so here is the also again the illustration of this soft margin idea
basically what you have is the phi function maps x y into
this higher dimensional feature space you define the direction w in that space by your
you can never prove any upper bounds i think the amount of money
another way to put it is you can always prove there is pattern you can
never prove there is no pattern so let me try to explain this so this
is what's called a metatheorem
because this
talks about what you can or cannot prove
so let me let me try to explain in words why this is the case
this is the more precise statement down here
you can prove lower bounds but no upper bounds on pattern but i'm going to
state in a more general and easier to understand the whole
why can you always prove this pattern well what is pattern
if i have individual bit strings
the pattern means there is a program it's much smaller that produces that this individual
based on interesting is output well if there is such a program
i can just run it and confirm that it produces the best and i'm interested
and that shows
but that this person has a lot of pattern
right because it's a small program that produces that
the bit string that individuals from that i'm interested in
so you can always and in fact if the program that you give me is
the most concise program that is going to o the maximum amount of
you see
that's the most elegant in the that the program to calculate that
that particular bit from the interesting
so it doesn't mean we can find
this proof
we can find the program
program it is the most concise program play something
in fact we can
it is possible to prove that something has patterns simply by exhibiting a is a
small program that calculates
and then you just run
that's what about the opposite can you prove what if you have not found a
small program what if you haven't discovered any pattern individual bit strings
and you want to prove that it's not your fault that there is no program
that is concise that calculates that the small the gaza strip
and this turns out to be essentially impossible to do
except in a finite number of cases
you can never prove it
and maybe what i should do
it is the rest of the time i have which is a very of time
i've used about half my time for the first lecture try to explain to you
this result y it's too tempting to try to give you proof
proof of this result
which is
which is you can always well we i that you can always prove this pattern
hopefully that idea explain properly already this the other thing which is very surprising
but you can never prove that there's is no some individual this thing that absolutely
no pattern by the way
if you generate is betrayed by independent possible fair coin with very high probability it
has no
but i'm trying to prove it in individual case and give approval
the fact that this is true with high probability
with overwhelmingly high probability is not interesting
is not what is not to the issue
the issue is to prove whether you can prove that the drill bit bitstream
i had no other
in particular bits in that you're interested in
actually this may be a little too vague what can we let me just change
the let me just in the formulation of a little bit too
something that's similar but is much i think easier to deal with
remember i talked about elegant programs
an elegant program is why we use somehow fix your computer programming language i don't
know how you choose one and you stick with it
and then you define the program to be elegant if
there is no program that is smaller in that same language that produces the exact
same output
OK so that's a very simple idea
and there always will be inelegant program you know for any additional tests
there may be several there may be time
the question is
a question which is equivalent to the fact that you can never prove that there
is no pattern
is the following metatheorem which i think is a little easier to
to demonstrate so i'm going to continue with this version is the idea that even
though there are infinitely many elegant programs and their own programs which are arbitrarily large
and that's the way i don't care about the time
i only the runtime has to be finite
but i don't but otherwise i don't care
so that's important interested in the size in bits of computer programs
one my doing this jaw
well one thing i notice is it's
quadratic programming OK my
o thing which wish to optimize
it's going to be this alpha
this quadratic looks like like this
the prime started from was also actually quadratic in w OK by the like this
and this the same in optimisation theory for every primal for formation
the the dual formulation
if you solve we obtain solution of the primal
it's the same solution a solution of the jaw
this is actually the jaw
now forgetting all the story that lead up to this point OK i have now
arrived point i want to arrive at
this is the object i optimize who to find solutions
four i support vector machine
some comments first of all what you notice is the data appears in this block
this would be like input vector x number of components in it
and why will be associated labels but that's the data like OK
the the task you wish to do
well this is my previous task women to ask the joel tasks such max task
i wish to maximize subject
subject to constraints come onto in the second
maximize in the alpha
of course you can see i can maximizing
because the rest is just data
so i maximize is quadratic in alpha
now it is constrained optimization
first of all these alpha actually across multiple user requirements and of course what is
it must be positive
there was this condition
from dl by DB
this is equal zero
so it is constrained optimization
first comments
the data comes in here
and is quadratic and several convex problem therefore
it looks a bit like this there is one solution
it's not like in your network or on
approaches to machine learning where well unfortunately
a different starting point gets different solutions
different starting points will only get you the one solution
OK which it will be this maximally separating hyperplane
well roughly
roughness is alpha square
that's linear and alpha so this is a quadratic yes
this a quadratic time expressions
the multi dimensional quadratic
o quadratic optimisation well
you've got within optimisation theory got to linear programming which should be linear in alpha
i'll come on to that later became
you've got a quadratic optimisation which means roughly alpha squared expressions
you could have something horrible route out from things that that would be some sort
of non-linear optimization
now for quadratic programming has been a lot of work on trying to find efficient
routines with quadratic programming you possibly have things like conjugate gradient method and so on
actually first developed for quadratic programming so another big class
is that this pretty
rapid routines to find the optimum of this expression w OK
indeed such is the case if i had well twelve
are actually done this was sixty thousand data points in there
personally but i know people have gone way beyond that
that means i can have m is sixty thousand postal data OK
now that's because i can use very fast routines
from quadratic programming
and if you some darker many other approaches machine learning new network trying neural network
with a million
data points that some like back propagation will take you some time can tell you
so it's it's one big classes is very rapid
my task force support vector machines you could do this this afternoon if you wish
actually program this thing up
using quote proc in matlab
it is to actually optimizes with respect to alpha
subject to the constraints having found alphas
i plant them in here
and then i may have now a new test data point i want to know
what the answer is
the test data point comes in he said i dotted with my data axes
i have my alpha so just found from my constrained quadratic programming
FYI which my labels
bl to grass second but i therefore have set out my decision function
and it will make a decision
on this new data points
so this is my decision function i drive now some comments if i should do
this in practice
i will find some the alphas are nonzero and some of us zero
the ones which are nonzero alpha are the support vectors
if the office is zero
then they are
non support vectors in fact that sort of clear because go back to my
original picture
OK here it is
one of the learning task this non support vectors if i removed them from the
data set what makes the difference because that separating hyperplane will be just where it
if i remove support vector then my separating hyperplane would shift OK
so as i suspect when i actually do the optimisation tasks only alpha zero
none support vectors someone non-zero are support vectors
indeed is a little bit more
interpretation can actually get out of a support vector after this hypothesis
and just on the support vectors are not
it is often worth actually having to print out of these alpha
you'll find some of zero
not support vectors some alpha so non-zero support vectors sometimes alphas can be larger value
it there's larger value what it means that particular data points have a big influence
on when separating hyperplane should be
and i can be for two reasons one is is correct but just unusual data
point the other is it can be an outline OK
o give you an actual example of this used in practice
so this is actually becomes and the stick breaking representation and if you sample parameters
following the prior distribution to be determined by the best distribution
and then this is identical to the sampling the CRP water or in the representation
and a it's exactly the right sampling
usually process mixture model is another view which makes it more apparent that you can
think of this seriously process mixture model also as a generalisation two
a finite mixture model if the number of mixture components course infinity
but even if you do that in effect only a finite number of clusters will
be needed to represent the data with the number of classes is limited we cannot
be larger than the number of data points but typically is even much smaller smaller
and that
so this is another view on this and gives you more direct relation to the
inside in terms of
clustering structure here
we already have discussed and usually this recent case that this idea about collapsing the
model which means integrating out the g
it's quite elegant but might give the best gibbs sampler and there some advantages of
really also trying to sample from g is given a sample of the of the
all the become independent of one another and you can see this independence typically helps
in terms of proving the
properties of your if go
it's something process so that the idea is a simple i mean before he was
an infinite these are the sum from one to infinity and the idea is simply
to let the some only well from one two k where k is large but
not infinite
and so essentially what you think i mean
in the stick breaking process you can think of in if you have brought products
of broken of so many sticks there's not much left so you can set their
remaining stock to zero and he will not do much damage and this can be
done i mean the effort to be mathematically OK and that two
approaches to this
the first one is we do with the stick breaking stuff but at some point
we decide that the stakes are too small we can ignore the rest and we
have to set that lasted k two one to get a proper distribution that sums
to one
so this is called a truncated stick breaking
a second alternative is to which is continuously multinomial allocation is simply to say
OK maybe i don't want to have an infinite mixture model let's a mixture model
with a very large number of components
which essentially means that the pi
again find as truncated process but it's simply a sample of the isley distribution with
a very large number of components
so it's a bit like cheating is instead of doing the process to do distribution
but if you allow yourself to have a very large number of components
but five
and both of them can work quite well in practice the better typically than the
other simple process
so overview
hopefully happen that we don't get to confuse the two dimensions one is
the original model of the the model with the auxiliary variables e
and that this block gibbs sampling collapsed
gibbs sampling
gives collapsed gibbs sampling is model
based on the representation if you into the auxiliary variable you get the CRP representation
if you do the block gibbs sampling block means always that you can
sample of all these factors
in the block without taking into account actually you have to work with a finite
approximation the truncated stick breaking process of that usually multinomial allocation
OK so this is the end of the political section this i mean so far
we have mostly talked about the properties
usually process and some of these things can also be part of the definition of
obviously process but you cannot be in the finite case you could write it the
product of these parameters with exponent first minus one this is not so easy possibly
and reasonable give you any because so 1 occur in real life
like signs coastlines exponential defined the diversity of physical but you know this is just
my ignorance but on the seen physical problems that involve the function growing
as rapidly as the squared of maybe just my ignorance
but I do plus transform will be used to solve differential equations involving
about you know the minus the square that's
that's different looks almost the same between minus t squared as this is very well
behaved that's the curse of course that of freedom of the press
so I'd like to explain to you know how differential equations or maybe I should
so we need more formulas and
all put them what I say this board and instead also described you out of
basic wage differential will plus transform so used to solve differential equations of what they
call a paradigm shift the paradigm and then will fill in the holes so you
can some overall view of how the procedure goes and then you understand where the
various pieces fit into it I think you understand better
so what we want to start with the differential equation but right away there's is
a fundamental difference between what will plus transform does and what we've been doing up
till now namely what you have to start with is not merely a differential equation
let's say with linear with constant coefficients it's almost never used solve any other type
of problem and let's take 2nd order so I don't have to do work because
that's the kind we've been working with
but allowed to the inhomogeneous at
what's called something else that word and letter
of 1 of the 4 function they
now the difference is that up to now you don't know how to techniques for
solving this just as it stands will plus transform does not know how to solve
this doesn't stands will plus transform must have an initial value problem
in other words you must supply from the beginning of the initial conditions that war
is set for
now I don't know what I was saying any specific numbers solute generated by only
about what we do what we do if we get a problem and there are
no additional conditions that we can use all plus transform no cost you can use
it but just have to assume the initial conditions are unknown numbers
because they let the initial conditions the voice of 0 and Y. 0 prime whatever
you wanted a and B where you want it and now the answer then will
involve the you otherwise 0 otherwise 0
but you must at least give lip service to the initial conditions whereas before we
didn't have to do that
now depending on your point of view that's great defect words so what
let's adopt so what point of view
so there's no problem at all but rather
how is that solved by the cluster for the idea is
you take will plus transform of this differential equation and the initial conditions so I'm
explain to you how to do that not right now because we're going to need
1st will plus transform of the derivative the formula for them you don't know that
yet but when you don't know it will be able to take will plus transform
of the initial value problem solve for the elderly and what comes out of it
as well
y of t is the solution to the original problem
they want to use the function which satisfies the equation and these initial conditions
it's all plus transform let's call it capital why that's standard notation but it's going
to be of a new variable
so when I take will plus transform of differential equation with initial conditions what comes
out is an algebraic the emphasis is on algebra
no derivatives and no transcendental functions nothing like that of an algebraic equations and
lot the
right now
in the domain of it's easy to solve this algebraic equations not all algebraic equations
are easy to solve for the capital but the ones you will get will always
be not because I am making life easy for you but that's the way will
plus transform work
so you solve for war
and the answer will always come out to be
y equals
why there is equals some rational function some portion of polynomials in a polynomial in
now because remember the truth value of p three here it follows that was something
that i stipulated
OK so
can this be
the w two well w
the halls if this is the very that's fine
but in this part fails
because the truth value of p three at this point is not true is false
it's got here cannot be this one well
w north w one holds so they could be w one
and then the truth value of p three
i w one is true
OK so sorry that it's taken this long but
all of these is
one state
r success of
it is another way that i could say
it makes
three true
that's what i'm that's how you might think of diamond p three
someone step possible this makes three true
and then boxes the dual
boxes for all of the world which are related to w
phi has to be true there
it doesn't matter what happens in the world which are not our lady
but at all the i'd all the one step past successes phi has to be
so let's do the other example w one box p one
w one
box p one
OK so let's go through the clause
if every
if every world v
which is the one step pass successor w
the smaller formula true
that's it that's it
every once the successor makes smaller formula true
what's the smaller formula it's p one
what are we trying to do we're trying to say
does every
one is the successor of w one
make p one true
how many
r successors this w one had
to date and doesn't have any success
how do we interpret the every
there are two ways you can i would say well
it and find something like that
we just say well that's fine
if there are no r successors that every r successor does make something something to
the vacuum state right
so we interpret it that way
so actually the truth value here
so the truth value of
box p one w one
is true
what if i asked you about rail transport
what is the truth value of any formula you like that's boxed
this world
i'm not going to tell you what five that you can tell me what the
truth and
because it's the same thing right it's the same vacuous statement if it's data in
in every success of the black
you can
i mean anything you like
didn't make every box formula true
i we in problem here because look
this is going to be true
but now i can do this as well
santa problem
you need to be a bit careful these are not negations of each other are
not saying that some formula is true at w and the its negation is true
there some subtlety
so did behave in strange may ways i box formulae true
all right
i'll let you work through this last one here OK
simon box p one
roughly speaking what is this
there is
at least
some once some once the success of w all
every one step successor of that guy
makes p one true
and i claim that that's true y
because you can come
or you can go there too
because both the danes soapbox p one is going to be true but the
and i'm interested p one i one i don't care
OK i'll let you go that
and boy which got some catching up to do but i really really did need
to go slowly i think to try and keep everyone OK
what i'd like you to do is just go through some of these at your
own leisure
i hope that i've covered enough detail here to allow you to work through these
i'm going to skip this slide because i just have to
but the main thing that i'm trying to get across here
this equivalence holds
right that box five implies not time and not
and i'm find pleasant not box not file
trying with yourself through that
now we supposed to have a break ten
sure we just
just wondering how far
the pattern
OK the images
i've got
quite a lot because of this lecture
it might be better
right one of these all do one more slide
and then get onto this notion of five
implies a five logical consequence of gamma after the break OK
as you see the got in the things that cause
looks like it under the shade over there i just want to go through this
one thing
so what i'm trying to say here
is that
modal logic is sometimes known as classical logic
question is how much better than i if i would predicting the random pairs of
nodes connected to one another OK and what sort of the observations is that the
number of common neighbors already works quite well so this would be here and then
you can slightly improve by using more complicated metrics like
jakarta similarity for example works worse than the number of common neighbors and this damage
about it seems to be working the best but sort of the differences are not
not significant and this is the two graphs on the left and right each for
four seperate separate data so here this is comparing to the random baseline here it's
comparing to the graph distance based sort of taking the shortest path
between a pair of nodes and use use that to to do the ranking OK
so what is sort of the idea here is to say that even simple things
like number of common neighbors and damage that score sort of works much better than
if you want predict random pairs of nodes with one another but still these methods
are not perfect so what i want to do next is i want to talk
more about how to do how to learn how to predict links in networks right
and in particular example where the case study here will be was was was we
face social standing lars backstrom from facebook and was published is the this year so
the idea was the following right so i want to predict or learning how to
predict your friends networks right and this is really the
you may know feature of facebook right and here is a few facts about the
data so the first thing is that ninety percent of four new friendships on facebook
friend of a friend right so all new of ninety percent of all human beings
are trying to close links what i mean by that is that the surrounding his
the triangle closing right so if you want to distance BMW distance also now descending
close this particular driver right so this is this is a prior prior to closing
so in this particular case i only
because you on trial the triangle closing edges so on the ninety percent before the
friendships with the new ruling that was created was linked to this is a friend
of a friend type of relation right so that's the first thing to do that
however one problem here is that even though
this seems to be like a very easy problem right through the problem is that
people have about twenty thousand friends of friends on average every degree of a node
on on facebook is more than hundred so if you go to friends of friends
and the average person has about twenty thousand friends of friends and there are people
who have several million friends of friends this sort of instances hard hard drinking problems
so of our problem in the following we will make friends of friends of an
old and we will try to rein them in such a way that let's say
in the future use to create links to as many of these people are willing
to pop spotted so that the set the setting that would like to do so
the way to do this is as i said we this as a supervised machine
learning setting where we have training data and then try to estimate the model and
then we will make predictions right so the idea is the following is my note
for which i want to commend his original who his true friends will be
and imagine that i take let's facebook network in may two thousand eleven and then
i see quite a lot of the friendships that the person created between may two
thousand eleven in august two thousand eleven and imagine that has created friendship with this
a billion nodes and do not create friendships to to the red right so this
this is now my my labelled training data i know that as in the future
we link to green and one and one click through to read right so
the way
the sort of the problem is that i want to learn to learn how to
end this red and green nodes in such a way that green military ranked higher
than that right so i want to create a ranking of of nodes these are
all friends of friends of s
that you and i want to do this ranking in such a way that green
be high
and red military directly OK and we will do this is really a strong message
that that i i will i called supervised random walks and it become clear why
do i mean supervised and why why call it and walks any sort of based
on the on the work that was done by
i got while semantic about ICML like all five and so on so that's basically
so that the challenge can be how do we combine node node edge attributes of
interaction data in the network structure right in the way we think about this is
the following we will think that for every edge in the network we want to
what want to learn the at the strength of the same kind of the weight
of the edge OK and then once we have the data the weight or the
strength of the edge removed
pagerank random walk from the from the starting note as to measure the proximity between
s and these are green the right so the idea for example one one possible
way to set edges in this set edge weights in this particular case would be
to make this edits this is just the very sort of all here to make
them very strong and they just point to the to the
the very thing so that when the random walker walks around he more likely to
walk over the stronger edges so he's more likely to then when the random walk
comes here is more likely to go to node and to go to that right
and if i then rank my notes by the random walk visiting probability
the nodes are more likely to be visited so they will have higher weight so
higher scores of every rank higher than the
right so that inclusion vision is i have a graph i want to estimate what
the edge strands so that when i do
a random walk with restarts or personalized pagerank from s my random walker is more
likely to end up in the nodes then it is to end up in the
right and intuitive in this particular example of this is how i would want to
set my graduate so that when my random walk starts that he sort of more
likely to end up in between the end up OK so here is my random
walk right sort of he's more like to end up in green grenoble the then
the the walker then he has to end up in the
OK so now the question is how can i how can i do this
how can i learned is that transcends all OK so here is really the idea
this is my centre note and i have some some function that takes the identities
of nodes and the science and strength to each edge and the way i can
think about this this function is just each described by some kind of feature vector
and i want to combine these features to learn the
right so what what can for every edge i have long feature vector where where
this feature vector has profile information of node u profile information of note b and
let's make predictions that can be put to the test so this is a modern
chemistry so I've told you about the table of the elements why we call the
periodic table again go back to the website and down here is a button called
course where if you click on course where you get to this menu the 1st
of which
preferences is periodic tables of the click click on periodic table you can get a
variety of
choices 1 here actually happen chooses boiling point versus atomic number Mendeley of Mandalay is
the 1 who taught us that the properties
the properties of the elements are a function of the
atomic mass so let's let's get that down by the way the Cyrillic
the Cyrillic to Latin translation has not been agreed upon so you will see mandalay
of names spelled many different waitresses spell like this you'll see it's spelled out like
this like this and so on and so when you do a search it sometimes
frustrating but I'll use various forms of mandalay of wrote he wrote the following he
says that the properties of the properties of the elements
the properties of the elements are important state various properties of the elements vary periodically
periodically with
of atomic mass up with the atomic mass will find out later that that's almost
correct there's a slight variant on there but right now I'm going to give it
to you as Mendeleev enunciated itself atomic number will learn later is is the improvement
so that's why this is atomic number but for most intents and purposes we can
say this could be atomic mass so what I'm looking at here is boiling point
as a function of atomic number and what we see is it's not monotonic
continuously rising conditionally following it seems to rise and fall
and then arises in then it falls and then it rises and falls and rises
and falls and if you lay this out in income in a table as mandalay
of did with his cards you'd find that the local maxima all occur roughly in
the same horizontal position from the endpoints of the roles and then there's the trend
going from the least massive to most masses so that's where the periodic comes we
have a table of the elements with properties varying periodically with atomic mass so we
compress all that information can refer to as the periodic table here's atomic radius versus
atomic number you see the radius is higher it falls and rises and falls and
rises and falls and rises and falls we're going to now go into the Adam
try to understand the scientific basis for this observed behavior so here's the periodic table
1 its in its glory today following on mandalay of
the elements of the named up through 1 that you're getting it hasn't got the
latest information this was named over the past services element 110 which has been named
Advanced Study
after Darmstadt don't tell you why in a minute
if you do look down the periodic table you get you get above 1 all-night
you'll see the strange notations here you you and you you you you you be
what is all this these are elements that have yet
to be isolated there yet to be isolated these are elements that are from unstable
and so these are where no 1 as the super heavy so all elements of
of Parliament's beyond uranium elements beyond uranium these are synthetic
the user synthetic and were they made the manufacturing facility there's 3 places on the
plan that have the high energy physics equipment in order to make these these are
the 3 places 1 is good not in the former Soviet Union and Russia 1
isn't orange that in Germany and the 3rd 1 is in the United States in
Berkeley these are the 3 places where they have the accelerators and the kinds of
reactions here so they were able to make her on study and they take an
atom of led accelerated
and avid collide with minimum of nickel and if the conditions are right they will
combine fuse informed understanding and plus neutrons
so these these devices when I was a young star colloquially known as atom smashers
because they have the capacity to actually break these and have reform and because of
various forces that
a play in the nucleus that will dictate when this will be stable and will
be yeah they isolated but it decays very quickly on the order of microseconds lifetime
on the order of microsecond so you can imagine that's why we don't have the
boiling point in Darmstadt electrical conductivity right they isolated enough that they can actually say
the bare minimum about it and so we haven't uh and just so that you'll
be literate in the rest of the periodic table if you look at the higher
ones this is how you name use these latter prefixes so 111 would be boon
plus 2 plus 2 so 152 Pentium that's why you see these UUP you you
my favorite is 111 cause that's cool linear something to be said when they finally
get a good name for our together are
and and and when they are named their named by suggestion by the scientists who
have isolated them and there's a lot of competition obviously if it if it's if
it's a Russian team that isolates the elements they're going to advocate the name of
a Russian scientists the Russians location or what not obviously
the work that was done to isolate 110 was done in Germany and they propose
the name Darmstadt
and sustained understanding other there is a dual pneumonia is also helium and all you
look at the very high numbers you'll see these these nomenclature so there's study
after reading if you're really curious about some of this early history I can recommend
this book it's a mental lives dream right summer before last scholar out of course
and the peak there
i'm not sure what to make of that i hope that we recover
and this is this is the commits to the source
archive per month now doesn't go back as far i didn't take that data out
it also peaked around the same time and that that peak
as the mailing lists activity which has come back as those things would be correlated
that's also around the time of the last major release
active so i think there's there's reason to see there's a lot of activity leading
up to and following the release fixing little bugs that appeared that we did know
every it's like one
managing a paper you want to the copper and use part of the type of
right so
so is using up all these people were they doing what they were are doing
all kinds of things things that i would never have imagined when we started writing
software for chemical reaction engineering
i think it's great
it it makes sense a general purpose computing tools not really aimed at a particular
now is released i don't know if you if you
what active
five years ago
and then you look at it today you think you'll be surprised by the number
of changes in our new features and things that work better
in three
o point o we have sparse matrices which i wasn't sure we'd have we have
reasonable start on matlab compatible handle graphics
matlab compatible energy datatypes opposition functions all these things that there are new
we try to keep the user guide updated but this is always i don't know
how many people here right
right software a lot
the right documentation too
it's not it's not fun for me anyway so
that tends to lag behind
if you live but if there's a ideas like strike documentation you know see me
talk to me
the great thing about having the project had
so graphics graphics is always a kind of a sore sticking point everybody complains oh
graphics are never going to be as good as men so
i wrote an interface to newport
pretty early on
nineteen ninety three
it wasn't very good
i don't know what else to do we're using new planets it seem like a
reasonable thing reason way to go
nobody ever like that
so i'm glad we finally got this this
interfaces more compatible with
allentown graphics of people don't like that either
but i think they like it better that it's compatible because they can take some
code now that was written from alan
can produce graphs can
potentially produce graphs and
if you want to do
you know what really tweaking a lot of little
properties that nobody else ever uses you probably would probably work
and there a lot more improvement since the
three point release so things are getting better still
one thing i should mention
i meant to mention earlier about
the number of functions in now i just looked and
just want to the
the mathworks documentation page alphabetical list of all the functions
i stripped out the things that were like they were really functions there
just pointers to
you know line properties are axis properties for the graphics system
i think it would count was about thirteen hundred functions
the night
count the number of functions that are in the core distribution
it's about fifteen hundred
they don't over it's not like
now let's function set is a subset of active unfortunately
instead there they overlap in the overlap is about eight hundred functions
we're missing about five hundred some functions
if you want to complete
functional compatibility the core active
to the core matlab i mean in core active
and i looked at that list the five hundred functions
there were supposedly missing
i don't recognise very many of them
one of the
the what
i mean you know people really
we want
what happens you want to
one you
what is be
you might want to do
all of these
so what you see here please
one of the same
in one thousand
it is how the
o thing
he can be
is more
two in a one
what one
the thing that you want
you might
it's called
for one would be
one of my view
so far
they can do it
it is here that you
so i
q one
now i guess
one more
more way
he was
one of the that
the you want
we use the dual use
you what
as the people
what can't be
you know
i don't know what we want
what we
four four
in fact
he was
if want to play this song all that
you know
we use one
with all
do you know
you help
we all
he he
he's not exactly what i was going to be
the one one one
we that it's not very simple
what one
we are these well but
so i will
one one
so the police
which we
he is a markov
one you see what harm
you each
on the future
all the you are my
so you know
the issue of
so let me right in two dimensions
so let me
right that equation
which must be
the model
this study
partial differential equation
second derivative with respect to x
the second derivative vector y
we're just in two dimensions equals
it's a zero
OK it sounds so much studied for several reasons
one is that it comes up all the time and applications
i'm speaking about
equilibrium steady-state applications easy there's no time
in this equation so to steady state problem it's an elliptic so so some of
these words would be equilibrium
steady state or
all the data type equation if we were classifying equations
so it comes up
in many many applications
typical of more complicated
equation so you look here first for to try to understand what's going on and
it has special it's quite special also
it's special
work for this equation that don't work for other equations and they are quite fun
just to say a word what they are
they involve
the imaginary number i
functions of x plus i y
complex variables come in for me it's a completely real
and in but
the the key trick in understanding it is
connecting it to
complex variables
so i'll get to that let me start by
just figuring out just let's make a list of some solutions that we can
so so a list of solutions
i'm open to the simpler the better
so what's the very simplest solution to that equation
i can't say OK so i just put one
well you could say that zero is even simpler
debate OK
now give me one set
still very very simple but one step further what's another solution to that equation you
we call
a linear equation
you equal access
because the second derivative is certainly zero and the y derivatives certainly zero and then
or why
now you can already see i'm making this
i'm making two lists
for reasons
so now
move up to the next one
if this pattern
which is to sort of starting whole
the next one i would look for would be
the quadratic second-degree c so x one x times y
this at work
x times y works i'm going to put it in
that this
OK and i'm going to ask for somebody else
and this list
x plus y i'm not
gonna go for because x plus y so to speak i've already got
ah good good point that they once we get this list
any combination of these functions
will also be a solution
so these are
this family of solutions may look kind far to a few
well like the list but since any combination gives the solution we get the whole
white family of solutions and in fact will get all
OK so x plus y we already have is the combination but what else
x x one minus don't you spotted that one but it works right x squared
minus y square
x where minus rice chris because the second extreme values is getting more subtle the
second experiment was one
and the second why derivative is minus one and we get we're OK and then
we x y was OK because of the river zero that was is OK now
now we can we get to the next guy which will the
only x that's out of my league here i'm just hoping for cubic i guess
why if i'm seeing this pattern
he the idea i should
so either the x minus either wonderful
of the work
does it
you want right
i mean i never thought of it so most of these guys are if i
take the second order work does it
the second extra revenue would be what
in the acts
and the second wider derivative there will be
the males
wouldn't work but something like something like some some things we will certainly one OK
why are you guys are in these transcendental functions i'm just looking for polynomials zeros
does this
just slowly gradually this lecture will be over before it started for me OK can
now execute you're going get it right
i'm not happy with killed but then i think maybe we can fix it
so what do we get out of execu
well the
second x derivative is one
six six
what can we put over for what can we subtract away
three e three e y square
three XY square good three x y squared
because now the second wind-driven that is
minus six months six x and six x good
OK now that they have
somebody to go with
why why or why
a minus
during the next square
what work right the second why derivative would be six y
and the second extra but it would be minus six x and they were would
be minus six y second experiment would be two extra and was one minus x
then basically this is that we can truncate the tree
so you've got this tree
and the only variation compared to what i i discount to use in the deterministic
case is that sees
you're in the stochastic environment you have to try all these actions many times
as the only change
because the old concept the actions on search right
this is the answer type
you want to try to many times basically or sampling
now the question is how many times you need to to try these actions it
turns so that you don't need to try to
those many times
because because of life because you are interested in expected value exceeds the expected return
so when you when you want to compute any expectation
i heard from non though that well you can just sample
and if you have and some
then you will have have our squared off and quality estimate of the expected value
so that
and that the rate of conversion doesn't depend on the dimensionality of the space
so it seems that
you can use this argument and in many high dimensional spaces
you just need to try these actions quite a few times
european history
and then once this one this tree is been what you have to do is
that well these are the chance notes so i i take action one action two
and these are the possible outcomes so i'm sampling action won quite a few times
these are the possible outcomes those would be against it but i would try
one action or the other actions
and by the way this here as well and so when i'm i'm trying to
compute the actual values at the and what i have to do is that i
propagate values backwards from the friendly
so i believe i also somebody more average over the rewards and that's going to
the value of action one here i do the same for action two
i know how to propagate the value of course in the tree that is not
i should just take the max right because i'm interested in and
the best values so in action
that has the better right so i think the max that's
so that's going to be the value of this knowledge
and no i do the same thing for all the not so i think is
not here
so what is that
i just added sure these values
and once i that this knowledge has value these no also has value and no
one comes to choose
and action i just compared the two values
and the action with of is the highest values choose so that's that's the arg
so what do change so it turns out that you can prove
you need tree
half of this size and this is it it's impossible to get the this that
would be smaller
and this
so and in order to get an absolutely accurate estimate of the action values and
then you can have a good policy if you have a good action value estimates
what we learned before so if you are able to to estimate
the optimal action value function up to an excellent accuracy
you know we had this tablet to resided said that if you take the greedy
policy with respect to that
then that greedy policy is going to be
almost optimal
up to abseil on time some constant accuracy
so this is good news why because the size of the tree
is independent of the dimension of the space
so it seems that
we have done problem is solved
no the problem is that the the size of the tree is exponential in this
as before i saw
the problem is that if you try this i given in practice it
it takes too much time to the industry
it doesn't really work
this was state of the art in two thousand two and
well this is a colleague
we so that this is still a pretty good idea
just maybe the computation should be organised a little bit better
so what's the problem is this tree so that the problem is this tree that
is that it is zero
and all the action so it might turn out
that already
while you're building a tree that some of the actions are not that much interest
and i don't want to grow the tree
in other words the tree
in his original paper was drawn in first manner
and what you want to do really is to grow the tree in that first
manner so you want to
explore was parts of the tree
and grow those parts of the tree that seems to be that seem to be
from using
i would give you something like herding about here
so that would be the best you can hope for
so it doesn't really tell you something about robot
you know you can find people that is the difference between the loss of the
algorithm and the loss of the absolute best
overall that the best function the best possible
we have such abound
then we
i mean it would be nice you know it because we could say well
we actually
i can tell how good is our algorithm with respect to the best possible choice
of function
the problem is that the same because of the not noppadon here you you can't
have such things or at least you can't have such things if you don't make
an assumption on the probability distribution if you don't restrict the class of probabilistic you're
looking at
the only way you can get search result is by restricting your class of probability
distributions which means make assumption that you can't verify in practice
it can be useful
to understand things but it does not provide the justification so this is really the
distinction i want to make
there are bounds that are useful is also can be useful if you want to
understand what's going on like you want to get four
you know what are the
the situation is that your algorithm introduces or here if you want to understand how
your algorithm would be a in a certain context
that's very useful but
it does not allow you to to draw any conclusion of the form all my
algorithm is better than this other organism because
here it's not
of this one and i mean it's it's not many knew anything about i mean
you can't compare this thing
in this case and in this case
when you a obtain result about the result of this one you have to assume
something about the distribution and you cannot who or justify these assumptions
so what we're left with is
bounds of this one where we compare lots of our organism with the loss of
some of the things i mean the best function in a given a restricted class
which is not the best of all possible solutions but smaller
and this tells us something about the relative performance of the algorithm with respect to
some comparison class the arbitrariness is in the choice of this comparison but
once we
you know i agree like if two people agree on what kind of a very
simple as they want to use
then they can compare their algorithm with respect to this kind of vanity all
my one is better than so my algorithm is better at
you know matching the performance of the best in the
so this really
from this you really can
derive some statement of the problem this is better than this but in the context
matching the performance of some others of some class of functions
OK the question is what could be a practical example of the class of functions
typically here you would
i mean what people do in fact is the with the classification the algorithm is
speaking from
you know if you algorithm is building
and as we have for example then you with with
the class of all
kernel extensions
with a certain norms it's a
and this would be your comparison class
and the nom you could choose it to be the one that you're paying why
after running your SVM
it's going to be data dependent but you can tweak this bound to in this
way so you can have abundances if i
because function
three but
we could function as in effect you know
and after seeing the data i get some and which has some
on the
so i mean even though this may depend on the data you can use the
union bound
bounds of this form
you could say that the loss of the algorithm
minus the loss
of let's say let's call it start e
the best
function in that hilbert space within the ball of size
it is less that something
but this is the kind of
first class usually you would use the comparison class which is closest to what's wrong
with anything because the whole better algorithms
finding the right function in the class that is from
so you know RKHS or
linear function or
whatever you're using your argument
so i mean this is
re-stating this a little bit
this year now
in addition to these previous statements we know
that these quantities go to zero as n increases
what can we derived from this information then we can say in this case where
we compare it to an empirical test of ventricle will indeed
ultimately when we get an update
estimate correctly
the true
again if that's the case portrait algorithm so we don't get much understanding
here is goes to zero that's just showing consistency of the algorithms
and as i say the rate can only be obtained if you have assumptions on
the distribution
in this case it will tell us i mean this rate of convergence we tell
us how much we how fast we much performance usually
you know there is this
you could dichotomy between
bounds for which you're looking at the exact value and about for which are only
considering the rate of convergence with some constant that really doesn't matter so i mean
if you if you look
you know you can always have two views on the boundary organizer
look at the exact value of the bound and then everything that enters every element
interesting about it makes sense
or you can just look at the overall behavior as n increases they have symbiotic
the behavior like this it's one of the world's then or even one over n
and and then you don't care about the cost
if we look at this the typical quantity that occurs in the boundary this in
olog n that they said that point could be interpreted as
the coding length of our hypothesis
people usually
infer from the fact that the bound contain this login or something equivalent
i mean something that measures the size of the that as
you know
i mean the
we conclude from that that you know the smaller the class the better
on the single the class the better
and sometimes simplicity
is taken in a very direct and straightforward way so for example you q
if you compare the two classes of functions
and one
intuitively simpler in the sense of how humans understand class of functions then it doesn't
the that are
the parameters and the hyperparameters so we
we have an additional layer
so this is why it is called the article
OK and it's very straightforward to write the
sorry this wouldn't be here
because this is the likelihood so we we can write similar to the case has
these two quantities
right so just technical
OK so now the classification
if you want to calculate
the likelihood of a class as well as
but is this
yes if if we want to come together in this country t then we have
to integrate
the likelihood of the parameters
with respect to the posterior of the hyperparameters this is just what we we did
before with the parameter
and we will not use this from actually but we are will be rather using
this one so
we do that in this way we have an implicitly integrated over
the town
and in this form i do not integrate over theta
so this is p of x and theta and phi
but phi
the only information the finds already hinted at so i didn't write it and this
is the joint posterior distribution of den five
OK so let's see this was a little example
this is an iconic example imagine now time series
it is a constant plus noise
right so
OK so you might have some dots like that
and was another realization it would be a bit lower
and higher and so on
OK so with this example we can write plenty of things
so parameter here we want to estimate is
constant here and as you can see
it is distributed according
this is an it is distributing according to a gaussian distribution so
if you are doing civilization you do not always have the same value for the
parameters does this is a realistic for the case
OK that's what i've here
OK now
the article model
so this is the theta parameter that we don't know so we define
it is it is defined a distributed according to this
and here in this case
the hyperparameter is the for the unknown parameters of the prior distribution input and the
and the
and the parameter right
and we can select also a prior distribution for the parameter let's go from one
and then
we can
this is that we can calculate everything so if you want to take it in
my mind
put it on the web
right so but in the end we we can calculate the
for the class the
the conditional density of the one we want to classify with respect to the training
set and this is a gaussian density
OK well of course this is just an example but you if you want to
go through it and you see how it works
we have defined a framework so as to implement classification with the generative model the
problem is how to implement this in practice
i propose new solution but it's not so unique
so i propose to use MCMC but you don't have to follow means is you
can use something else if you
very important remark
there are several
it has
so what does this mean
for each of the training sample
it has a value of to each of them
so if you can you first you have the training set so this corresponds to
set of
each one is different from
each of the variables
OK so let's see how it lets us assume the hyperparameter is now so it's
fixed value for it
using the prior on theta
because it is completely non because we know the hyper parameters we can learn the
value of the sitters for all the training data
so we have a set of
it has
and what is nicely that from this that the town
we can now look the hyperparameter
if we now assume it is not known
OK and i'm trying to introduce the gibbs mechanism
OK so
from the parameters from the training set
they have some distribution
and this distribution you can try to fit a gaussian for example and then you
will find values for the hyper parameters
and when you have this parameter
then you could you know the distribution of theta
and then you have
this posterior distribution of the data which is distributed according to this
this is done here is no more
well this is the third year
in the training set just through isation of this random variable here
it's a bit tricky to understand it
this is india and reason so
so the way i propose you to implement hierarchical bayesian learning is gibbssampling so i
recall briefly with gibbs sampling is it's very very simple
so the something is as follows
as for the first you initialise the hyperparameter to some value so that step one
OK and then you iterate
where once you know the hyperparameter then you can write the conditional posterior distribution of
the parameters of the learning signal number i
so you take the training set and you start with the first finding a time
series with time training data
from the training data and the value of the parameter then you can learn the
its parameter so you end up with this posterior distribution and you sample
just one individual from this
with the
either directly it's simple distribution are using a metropolis hastings
OK so and you do this for all the training data so you have a
set of parameters and then
the second step of the gibbs sampler consists of sampling the hyperparameters conditional on
the parameters
that we just sampled from the training that so you have the training set
you have the parameters and then you can sample a parameter and then you put
you start again
and you iterate like that
OK so this is very basic basic
and once this is done
you end up with a chain of the hyperparameters
that i had in my
in particular
the poles of my body when you took the photo so joint angles are hidden
or latent variables that explain the data that you saw
but the continuous not discrete of all really continuous and so on
think about that kind of data is that the data lies on some kind of
manifold or subspace in your space not possible
pictures are
can be realized right for example there's no way for you to take a photograph
in which the distance between this
and this
under the projection is any larger than the actual length of my four
so that part of the data space which is completely inaccessible and so in some
sense the data doesn't really for the whole space it just on the manifold or
in the simplest case of a linear subspace and the idea is that the latent
variables are the coordinates inside that subspace those things you don't know and the data
that we observe are actually
lying on some kind of
subspace so
the to generate the first you generate a point inside the subspace are inside the
manifold and then you add some noise afterwards and the coordinates inside the subspace of
the latent variables
OK so
there is a very famous model in in statistics called factor analysis and apple actually
told you guys a little bit about the solar just over kind of quickly since
you already covered in the idea in factor analysis is that you assume that the
subspace manifold is linear
so it's a linear subspace of the data space in the latent variable
how the garcia distribution
the model here is now i have to apologize
switched i compiled some slides together from various sources and in this set of slides
the latent variables are called x in the data called y
even though not three minutes ago the deal is called x
you have to sort of adaptor brings to this i know it's annoying but i
i had a sort of moral dilemma about whether i should change it in my
slides and the slides are projected would be different from the ones i gave you
to photocopier eventually the parents are be so these things matter your of your book
the kind of music so variable is x and we assume they just has zero
mean unit covariance gaussians as a prior distribution on the actual data is called y
and the model is that given the choice of latent variables x what we do
is we take that latent variable x we multiply by this matrix
and then we add some noise and this matrix lambda is called the factor loading
matrix and what it does is it loads
x from the latent variable space into the data space
so matrix actually tells you how to take usually x is low dimensional the low
dimensional latent variables and push them up into high dimensional data space that's where the
term loading
comes from
and in this case the noise here is is controlled by the covariance matrix which
i call sign that's the standard notation factor analysis and that's called the centre
so the important thing to remember here is that this is a gaussian distribution on
the latent variables this is a gaussian distribution on the data given the latent variables
and so the joint distribution is the product of these two things and the product
of two gaussians is again it goes in
why is that
because the sum of two quadratic says the quadratic
this is amazing fact which seems amazing geometrically is trivial algebraic right addicted to parallelize
any two travels on add them up and what i get
and you parabola
that actually seems interesting when you draw geometrically right but basically it's pretty boring right
what the equation of a parabola it's a one x squared plus b
one was the one with the creation of this problem e two x squared
oppose p two was the two and the it's not really surprising that i get
another problem is
but still is important geometric intuition to have and that's exactly why the product of
two gaussians and the convolution by the way if two gaussians again OK so that
means that the marginal distribution over y
if you integrate out the latent variable x that's just what we did before but
now it's not some it's an integral is again against
so if the joint distribution is guassian marginals including the data marginal
our galaxy and in the conditionals including the
probability over the latent variables given the data was also just that the nice thing
about gaussians
so we can do this into general here in closed form and the marginal distribution
of y
it just turns out to have this form here it's again this year
with the new
and covariance
lambda lambda transpose plus sign
groups so
the important idea here is that factor analysis is constrained gaussian model
OK and you might think of the galaxy and it seemed so
cute and cuddly why would we want to constrain them but the problem of course
is that in higher dimensions negotiation has
i covariance matrix which has in a number of parameters which scales as the square
of the data dimension so if you're trying to model data a hundred thousand dimensional
space then you have ten to the ten or ten to the ten over two
parameters and the covariance matrix you'll never be able to learn
so we need some way
of modelling the covariance structure in high dimensions which is not as naive as just
assuming all the variables are independent which would be just assuming it's the diagonal covariance
matrix you to be able to introduce some kind of correlation but you want to
have a compact representation that's exactly what factor analysis gives you so in factor analysis
the covariance actually model is the product of these two and skinny matrices
each of which has a reasonable number of parameters in the
plus the diagonal matrix
now of course if we didn't constrain inside the diagonal then it would be pointless
because then we would have the same problems i itself would have
a quadratic number of parameters and then we'll be back where we started so it's
important that size restricted to be diagonal that's why it's called sensor noise because the
idea is that was part of the
guess distribution is just independent noise on each component that's like you can imagine that
the sensors which are measuring all data components each have some noise which are unrelated
to each other and in this part actually causes the correlation between the variables that's
the the data model
so o
how are we going to fix this this model and the answer is that we
can just using the algorithm
and again
and of course the room is going to play out in exactly the same way
but now
instead of computing the responsibilities which are these p of
the probability of each cluster or each mixture component given the data
we need to compute a probability distribution over the latent variables x
and that's that's going to be
the issue