is you
you have
majors are
these were released
is the
that's the
and that
the first
our minds
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
let me start by basically listing the main things we've round of about 3 weeks
or so and I had a few complement of information about that because there's a
few more details that I didn't quite 5 and annotation food you know probably make
it clear especially what happens at the very end of the of these classes so
here is a list of things that should be on your user fees for the
so the 1st thing we learned about the main topic of this unit is about
functions of several variables so we've learned how to think of functions of 2 of
the variables in terms of protein them in particular was not only the glass but
also the Contel plots and how to lead control
and we around how to study evaluations of these functions using partial derivatives so remember
we've defined the partial of F with respect to
some variables x to be the rate of change with respect to x when we
hold off your valuables constant so if you have a function of X and Y
symbol means to differentiate with respect to x tweeting y as a constant
we've learned how to bake age
partial derivatives into the vector of the gradient vector so for example if we have
a function of the variables that's just the vector was components of a buffer derivatives
and we've seen how to use the gradient vector of possibilities to divide various things
such as approximation formulas so the change in energy when we change x y and
z society is approximately equal to 1
there's several times and can we write this in vector form as the gradient of
the product the amount by which the position vector has changed
OK so basically what causes to change is that I'm changing x y and z
by small amounts and how sensitive is to each variable is precisely what the profitability
and in particular we can use so this approximation is called the tangent plane approximation
because it tells us in fact it amounts to identifying the graph of the function
with its tangent place it means that we assume that the function of the smallest
linearly on x y z and if we set these things or what we get
is actually we're replacing the function by its linear approximation will replacing the glass by
its attendant
except of course we haven't seen the graph of the function of the variables because
if you live in four-dimensional space so when we think of the profitability was a
function of two variables
but also tells us how to find the tangent planes to levels of faces so
if you want
so here's the first one
OK so we built this whole set of vocabulary
and a whole lot of them maybe even more than we like
and not just the vocabulary
but also
the tools
that we need
to build these vocabularies the tools that we need to deploy these vocabularies and the
applications in which reuses vocabularies bits of vocabularies are one of the city central pillars
of what built
the second thing that we build
it is the a whole set of names
OK so we gave names everything
we call these names you're right
this is the house is the tree
this is my house is your house that we did this billions and billions we
mean to millions of names
first of that's the second key ingredient will we built
and of course the third ingredient is that we struggle that those vocabularies and those
names we strung together in a joint work
OK so i think those three vocabularies names and the joint work of the essence
the very high levels of what we
and i said this in the introduction
mostly we have been and we are thinking about what we are doing as engineering
we're building this stuff and then were checking if it works
anyway it's obvious that it works
so i'm not going to spend a long time
celebrating our success
right so all you need to do is is i have the slide taken slideshare
called semantic web good news
and take a look at those lives and i i keep updating them every time
there are there to stories about how the government are now using our technology and
not just in the UK and the US only any more
the BBC's running their world cup website with our technology howl the goodrelations ontology is
changing the way the retail sector works out
schema org
he's pushed by the
the large search engines how oracle is including RDF in its primary database product how
the publishing industry
is changing with the new york times one of the leading lights yesterday you know
arcs explain to me your project is doing with the electricity to france where they
are generating three hundred thousand personalized energy saving plans for people every day
using semantic web technology so it's clear to that we have been an engineering success
and the question is
do we learn any site
and how they're going to answer the question
well the the thought experiment i'm going to run
is the following
so let's pretend
that the last ten years or one giant experiment
OK there were one large giant computer science experiment
so is this is still what we came out of the test tube it was
that it was giant experiment what would happen if you would run the experiment again
so we did all this stuff we designed languages we build ontologies we build BP
we built the linked open data cloud that's giant experiment now what would happen if
you would set back the clock and we do it all again
now then some things will turn out the same and some things which are different
i mean it's exactly that difference i'm interested in
so the things that turn out the same they must somehow be of crucial
meaning that if you run the experiment again and again in some things are always
the same and they they say something fundamental about the information universe
some things are not very crucial i mean all are vision examples of all our
ontology languages are full of angle brackets and i can imagine that we would run
the whole thing again we wouldn't use angle brackets again so somehow
the use of angle brackets doesn't strike me as a very fundamental of computer science
is an example of
perfect theoretical physics
occasionally works somebody sees through all the drama and reveals the key way to bring
the truth out
very very rarely but what relevant is beautiful i thought you might enjoy it
that's how well team discovered the
that is at the heart of the atom that was the best resolution where they
had those been turn the timeframe on
fifty years
and you have the discovery of the quantum approach on the same of idea qualitatively
but different scale quantitatively
here is the
it was a three kilometre long electron accelerator at stanford in california
the san andreas earthquake fault is about two hundred meters just beyond the back the
good place to build an accelerator
i mean wouldn't be replaced went through the middle of it actually is on the
the folklore is that they separated be on the bedrock
just move collectively
when the earthquake happens but palo alto down by the bay was built on jello
will wobble like anything it has been tested but the if that's what will happen
but i'm going to next weaken hoping you won't but the same is also used
have laser beam down
so monitoring very subtle
changes so this is the particle beam also being used for
monitoring the movements in way that is the electron beam that's
was three times as long as the target is the target of hydrogen which is
where the protons are and the detector is a huge electronic detector
and here is a picture of the thing being that fall of the left-hand corner
the beam of electrons emerges target
would be hidden behind this set of concrete
and the text
is there on the right and the little almost invisible figure down the bottom detector
is myself that was taking a long long time ago
and in those days there was a big detector today
the small picture is remarkable but that the scale of the things are qualitatively the
same idea electrons bouncing off the quarks revealed so electrons bouncing of the proton revealed
the proton had hard it's inside
and that's just the way that alpha particle scattering of atoms revealed the this is
a hard inside
the scale
it's going to be different so from that we knew
i discovered that the proton
it's not fundamentally is made in its simplest form of three quarks
together by will be called gluons
gluons are massless
particles with one unit of intrinsic spin just like photons are massless particles with one
in the intrinsic spin as photons r two
electromagnetic force so gluons are the force the quarks we'll learn more about tomorrow but
i just mentioned that so you can get the sense that have the similarity energy
now to make the proton and neutron requires two different varieties we call them flavours
up and down the charges
units where the protein charge class wall
the up quark has plus two thirds down to minus one for the quarks that
look like that as far as we know but it's used
and so
protons two ups and the downs
and the new tries to down to
so here is a picture of a hydrogen atom not to scale
and i should say this
to show that
sometimes there obvious truth standard interface
they don't
so i've noticed probably do the following things in a little experiment that we take
a deep breath from it and hold it and then read out again
thank you
right so you breathe in about a million million million million oxygen atoms which is
of course a very small but we now know know
since the data JJ thomson but there are negatively charged electrons in all those atoms
so you breathe in a huge amount of negative charge
and you go along these open days to university labs you're invited to stand on
its data plate and a charge up to very high voltage your hair stand on
and of course as you noticed my head in the sand and the
the reason that might be different than the reason some of your head and so
it's because
in addition to receiving a huge amount of negative electric charges that the whole story
what stood on and you breathe in a huge amount of positive as well
in the atomic nuclei of those atoms
and your has stayed in place
the negative charge of the positive charge
exactly counterbalance
now this is the fact that we would accept but just think about this now
the astonishing way that that balance was achieved as far as we know electrons and
quarks basic letters of nature's alphabet
if there is anything
because it connects them we have yet to discover
so how is the electron which is not made of quarks it's
it's itself
the negative charge counterbalance is the positive charge in protons
because the positive charges come about
because three
who are carrying fractional charges of two-thirds and minus the
not five or seven
three quarters
each carrying on the average one-third electrical charge combine to make plus long precisely counterbalancing
the minus one of the electron that is telling us that there is something uniting
these things which we have yet to understand
so it's a vector of zeros and ones in the index
and then
everything else is the same but now once we get to
the method f one x two that message
corresponds to
summing over the delta function at the value x one was a which is essentially
back here with x one set the value a and then when we run through
all these messages again we get just
a different
overall message coming in to explore and when that normalized that is the probability distribution
over x four
given that x one equals
so that's how you incorporate evidence wherever you want and that's how you initialise
messages and that you send them around i haven't told you how to schedule the
messages but essentially weekend
come up with
a few different scheduling methods there are some ways of optimizing the scattering but you
don't need to iterate this over and over again once every
variable has sent a message to every factor in every factor has sent a message
to every variable
all of the probabilities have been computed
so it's one we through all variables not factors in whatever order makes sense
i will give us the correct
any questions about that
sure we
we used to think that
in fact the
given that
i haven't thought of that question i try to repeat the question which will give
me a chance to think about it
so the question is we had belief propagation
for singly connected directed graphs and and we're back to graph propagation for singly connected
factor graphs
i cannot be that when you convert
a directed graph to factor graph
but you can get a multiple connected factor graph or vice versa in which case
it would seem that one propagation method can do something exactly the other propagation that
they cannot be exactly
and without proof my feeling is that the answer is no
i think there are equivalent
i don't think there's a sleight-of-hand tricks that you can do to do this but
i could be wrong
we have to think about that for
so that was factor graph propagation it very
hidden markov models or linear gaseous state space models and you and if you've encountered
algorithms like forward backward in common filtering kalman smoothing then the slide will be useful
to you
what we're talking about here are
very old and well-known models or
hi series where we have a hidden state evolving over time these are the axes
and we have our observed variables otherwise evolving over time
and the graphical model
for both the hidden markov model and the state space model is identical to look
like this
it corresponds to
factorisation of the joint probability
over all the hidden variables
and all the observed variables were time is going from left to right
the main difference between hidden markov model and then you get this state space model
are that the states are discrete in a hidden markov model and there going to
continuous real valued vectors in state space model
both humans and state space models can be represented represented as singly connected dags like
and independently
people develop the forward backward algorithm for doing inference in hidden markov models
the then messages
in the sequence forward and then backward to compute marginal probabilities of the hidden variables
given the observed sequence
people in the signal processing and control communities
back in the fifties in fact
i invented the common
filtering in common smoothing out
is which again sent messages forward and backward
and these are both instances these two algorithms are both instances of the general
family of belief propagation factor graph propagation of errors
so if you learned about these special cases you can forget about that can just
think about the more general case of
factor graph propagation
and this is definitely not how
control engineers or single processing people with each
common filtering for example but i think this
in a clear way of doing this because it becomes immediately obvious how to generate
generalized this trees or any other singly connected graph
and how to generalize the two
the different kinds of variables that
let's talk about the hard problem
so everything will be connected dags
half the exact algorithm for doing inference is called the junction tree algorithm i have
like a short one-paragraph description of it but i'll i'll
describe it a little more detail over the next five minutes or so
there are a couple of other things we can do it our graph is multiply
one of them is called cutset conditioning
which essentially involves the following
if you have your monthly connected graph
if you're lucky
you're graph is not terribly well we connect connected is just a little bit more
we connected
and Y are drawn at the same time but if we permuted for instance the set
of all Xs that we've seen then there is no longer a direct link between
X and Y but we haven't change the marginals so that's also just a short remark if you
don't follow this in detail don't worry but there's a nice way of constructing a
sample from this given a sample from this and then we test the difference of these
two so it will be tests just like in a kernel means embedding and testing problem and
it's also nice to point out that this has another interpretation and will turn
out to be formally identical to a different approach to independence testing which was
started  originally by Bach and Jordan they call it kernel ICA or
something like that  and there this is again this builds a classic
result from probability theory which is similar to the one that I told you about
before so this time the result is the following if I have two
random variables that are independent then well ignore the functions F and G
for the moment so if two random variables are independent then in particular their covariance is zero
so this covariance is the first order of dependence now if the covariance between
two random variables is zero it doesn't apply that the variables are
independent however it turns out if required that the conveyance be zero not just
for the variables X and Y but also for nonlinear transformations of X and of
Y and if we require this for a sufficiently large class of nonlinear transformations so again
all continuous all bounded continuous  functions then it turns out that this the implication
goes the other way to sort of requiring this is sufficient for independence of X and
Y so that's nice because it means again  we can use this simple criterion
such a criterion we can check directly in the reproducing kernel hilbert space
we can do this simple criterion but we have to do it over
a large function class so in in the general philosophy of kernel methods is
always you try to do something simple linear  in a large function class by
doing in the RKHS and it turns out with this kind of statement it's
then translates into a very nontrivial statement in the input domain so if you do
this you would end up exactly with the same equations that you get if you
directly test for difference of the means of this distribution and this one in the
reproducing kernel hilbert space okay I'll skip this one and now we get to one
of the simple theorems of kernel methods so-called the representer theorem so this one
I want to prove the proof is not difficult and I think it's it's nice
to see this so this theorem short version is that theorem tells us that all
reasonable or large class of kernel algorithms has solutions that are very simple in
the sense that they can be expanded in terms of kernels sitting on the training
points okay so what are their assumptions of the theorem assumptions are we have a positive definite kernel
we have a training set inputs and outputs  we have some a monotonic function sigma
which will scale the value of this so-called regularizer and we have an
arbitrary clust function C maybe look at this down here what does the clust
function do it depends it can depend in a general way on the inputs outputs
for whole training set and on what the function F produces as outputs so typical
the clust function would be saying well I'll take the Y value and I'll compare it maybe
I'll take the difference between the y the true Y value and the F of
X value that's predicted by my learning machine maybe the squared difference or something like this
and sum this up but this is a more general form that could also somehow
depend jointly or or in very complicated nonlinear way whatever so so every
function that minimizes this quantity here it makes the representation of this form so
such a simple kernel representation and why is this surprising well this minimization
it runs over the whole reproducing kernel hilbert space so for instance if we take
a gaussian kernel that's an infinite dimensional hilbert space and so we are solving an optimization problem
over an inifinite dimensional space but it turns out we can prove that any minimizer
can be expressed in terms of this set of functions that are known
a priori I have the training data so they live in this final dimensional subspace spent by
kernel sitting on the training points so that makes the problem a lot easier because now
the problem consists only of finding these alpha I rather than solving this infinite dimensional problem
so how do we solve this  so this is a simple example of a
simple loss function traditionally used loss function and this would be the standard kind of
regularizer that's being used we'll get back to this one later when we talk about
SVMs but it doesn't have to be that one so the proof is simple we decompose an arbitrary
function from our hilbert space actually I think it was called HK in the
previous slide into two  parts one  lives in the span of the training points mapped
into the feature space and the other one is orthogonal to it so one part is in span
the other one is orthogonal orthogonal  means in particular that they are all dot products between these parts
and these vectors are zero okay so I can do this in hilbert space
allow  orthogonal projections and if I then apply this does written function to
b of x is zero
and BOC is zero
what now
is the
dot product and cross product a crosby
you can apply that recipe
but it's much easier
go to the x y
x is that we have here
he was
in the x direction the unit vector and b
in the y direction
i think in my hand i rotate over the smallest angle which is ninety degrees
and my corkscrew will go up
so i know the whole thing already
i know that this cross product
must be
the magnitude must be one that's immediately clear but i mean have the direction by
using the corkscrew
now if you're very smart
you may say
you find places e
only because you have used this coordinate system
if this axis have been ex
and this one had been y
then the cross product in x and y would be in the minors the direction
you're right
but if you ever do that
i will tell you
you will always always have to work with what we call
a right handed coordinate system
a right-handed coordinate system by definition is one whereby the cross product of x with
it's z and not why minus e
so when we get in the future involved with cross product important angular momentum always
make yourself x y z diagram
for which x cross y
is never ever make it such that x crosswise minus c
you want to hang yourself
before one thing that wouldn't work anymore
very very careful must work if you use the right-hand court school
make sure you work
with the
a right-handed coordinate system
all right
now the worst part is over
and now
i would like to
right down for you
you get to pick up some of the
the fruits now although it will penetrate slowly
i want to write down for you
equations for a moving particle
moving objects in three-dimensional space
very complicated most which i
i can hardly imagine what it's like
it is the point
that's going to move around
in space and it is this point p
this point p
is going to move around in space
and i call this vector o p
i call that no vector are
and i give you this up in the next scene which indicates changing with time
i call this location
they'll why i'm going to call that
why of t
changing with time
i call these acts of t
it's going to change with time
and i call this point zero
which is going to change with time because point he's going to move
so i'm going to write down
the factor are
its most general form that i can do that are which changes with time
is no x of t
which is the same as a of x there before
times x roof
why of t
why rules
because the of key
i've decompose decomposed my vector are
in two three
independent vectors
it's one of those
interest time
one is the velocity of the particle
well the velocity
it's the first derivative
of the position
so that is the are
but every
the first derivative of this one
which is the ex
x rules
i'm going to write for the xt
x not because i'm lazy
and i'm going to write for the two activity square
x double it's often done but not in your book notation and i'll often use
because i see equations look so clumsy
white dots
times y rules
plus the dot
time zero would be that is these EDT
what is the acceleration as a function of time
well the acceleration as a function of time
so it is the second derivative of
x versus time
and so that becomes
x got
times x rule
that's why don't dot
why rule
let's see double dog
and look
what we have now
so there two phase one when the points get together and form clusters and the
second phase one
the point i really already clusters and very compact so compactly so and the cluster
centers that to start moving to get
and eventually they'll collapse in one
and you want to find
and the first phase but you don't want to go to the to the end
of the second place
because anyone see any clustering
so to do that
there is that is the a trickle
it's intuitively well justified
and it follows one way to start
is two
stop when the point move to watch
i don't have any more
and sometimes if you choose your and so this is the change from one step
how much has the point of one point being shifted
that you
and so i stand stopping criteria would be the next
shift divide that shift is more than some tolerance
but that's not enough because
it's largely because the clusters already moving together so every point is more that just
don't moving
two at each other they are moving
together in the same direction
and in that case is credited with what work so
but also another rule that also
which is
when the entropy in the histogram doesn't change
and i have to explain what and in the histogram
i hope you know what the histogram but essentially
so these are the points will be
the density would be like this
clusters here
plot here
and the clusters
and the next step the clusters together so
this with this much discussed this much and this is much
this is much
so if you look at the average movement of every point you're going to see
that it's very large because everybody moved
however because
however if you look at the distribution of the powers
you are the same for all the points
and the same for all the points you see here and here is the change
in the point is only for about this
no matter how many points
you can
so o point there for this thing
and it could have millions and millions points
also if you move the cluster together after one step it was still have exactly
four distinct so the number of distinct values of this e
doesn't change
and this is what this criterion express the entropy is
talk about entropy
and the only thing that is this weekend
so when there
o thing that doesn't change much from one iteration to another then it means that
the average to
clustering and you can stop
so this rule is that they are going to
so this is a very strange so this would be q here
i don't know what
so it
this is what it what's meant by cubic convergence
this was one of
OK so this is the mean shift the
the gaussian blurring mean shift that goes in is because you're using a gaussian curve
which seems to be better because it's smarter
and the learning because it means that only the task called learning
there's not much so this is one of these ideas which are not yet analyzed
well but probably will be because they seem to be interesting
there was
so what about the first
so yeah i mean if this is a better algorithm than the previous one
it is
OK so i mean it is better than the other means
the idea is that the meaning of logical connectives
is just its role
that plays
a proof system
so it's the rules that governed by the introduction of elimination rules in the natural
deduction system missing a few minutes
determine the meaning of the connector
tells you what it means and this goes back to the work of the person
who invented but natural deduction
sequent calculus carried against
and he talked about it and in philosophy came in the nineteen fifties
it with the work of ludwig wittgenstein and you might be the philosophers saying and
they can start his idea that the meaning of any concept
is determined
by how it's used
and that's a very similar notion that use
the connected here in the proof system
determines what it means how we're supposed to understand so
that between proof and it's proof theory and semantics as you proof from one side
semantics and the other is a little bit artificial or little question they
from philosophical point of view because
you might think of the meanings in proof theoretic terms and
although i'm not entirely convinced
and old model theorist from way back
i think that that
direction needs to be taught in courses in university in because we tried to adopt
everybody in model theory and then later on students read all this stuff proof theoretic
siemens i can no one ever told me about because we doing all this proof
theory you could have told me that that was could have been treated as the
theory meaning
OK now we're going to look at what that means because in different proof systems
you get very different answers about the meaning of connectives
and that's really weird and some of them just coming to
i understand fully now people been telling me this for ages
but that's one thing listening to people tell you that you know you and actually
working through it and saying
know this is really strange this isn't quite what i mentioned
and we're going to see that OK
now in the star
with the more formal stuff
it's not going to get hugely falcon because i'm right at the end of this
i'm not going to do
perhaps as much technical stuff
as i thought it might do some i mean this this
equivalence proof
the fitch style in the sequent style systems i'm going
sketch that prevent fourier it's a fun proof
i love this equivalence for different proof there was to them with my students it
comes from being model theorists actually has been transferred transplanted into proof theory because moral
theories the first thing we do is completeness there is a complete list
and call even as here's the post doc back in the late eighties
he started his approval serious and you still have things that have been mapped structure
any structures and to each other today in the because he got one structure
which is a perfectly good you know one you have proof theory prove things about
that forget about all this model here is that we have to build another structure
and show that they are effectively the same right
isn't that selling well i don't think so it's fun
that's what i do for these structures into each other so they are effectively the
same and feel better about things but
this the reason why we do that right
between model theory and proof theory is a very good reason why we do that
we have
certain proof theoretic intuitions about what sort of inferences are valid and we have
and what sort of formulas of
and we have a certain
model theoretic intuitions about
a theory of truth for that
and we want those intuitions to match
that's why we have to prove that they give us the same results
because if they don't then we got to say which one do we have to
give up
in which intuitions do we have to amanda
and that's i think it is
the heart of what
these completeness proofs are really about
i mean there are also about that is that there are these from you know
this is a philosopher talking about philosophy lecture so
that's what i that's wrecked come from
right the so that's what we're philosopher looks for a mathematician might say well look
right when moral logic here's the nice thing
you have these weird model logics
people didn't understand cricket came along in the possible world semantics all certain model logic
it begins to look like
theory of binary relations we know about that
right is also huge amount of mathematics about that and then we can go on
and study this
intensional logic we can study using an extension of language
set theory
and very relations
even before that
tarski showed that the logic s four in effect was the logic of
topological logical open sets that also sells well here's the theory we know about
open sets state apology for a long time because of their we don't know about
so now
we found that there are very much
the same theory we can transfer results we know about one to the other
and that's that's mathematically really important
so philosophically mathematically is completely stands are good idea but anyway let's get away from
the back
OK so now we know
so we want to non-classical logics all
we've got classical logic that's one system or released a class of systems of natural
deduction system hilbert style axiom system again a sequent calculus
that are all related in the sense that they'll give you the same results really
in the give the same valid formulas in the same valid inferences kind
gradient methods
these methods are also used the second derivative it's the derivative of the derivative so
the gradient of the gradient
and what that gives you is it's a measure of the curvature of the function
in rough terms if you have a direct method
you have to sample your function in many places and then you just try to
move towards the samples that look better
and that's for instance what evolutionary algorithms to
as many many other methods simplex
method and other methods that do this
i should say the nelder mead simplex method right there's two simplex
if you have gradient information
you can actually look at a single point and know which direction is downhill and
multi dimensions the gradient actually tells you the direction in which
is you have the steepest slope downhill
OK it gives you the steepest descent direction
so that's very useful
if you have a second order gradient information
it not only tells you which direction is downhill but it also tells you the
curvature of the function in that direction
which tells you how far step you should be taking
because if there's a high curvature and you take a step in the downward direction
but you're going too far
then you overshooting the minimum and you land on the opposite slope
if you're not going far enough will well obviously you could take the biggest
so the second order methods have the big advantage that they tell you also how
far to go
the first order gradient methods only tell you which direction to go in
and the step size that you pick is then something that's very i talk that
you have to worry about it
we have all these possibilities so why hasn't anybody come up and sort of decided
OK this is the best optimisation method period and we don't worry about the other
ones anymore
that is because
it's sort of like different kinds of car that they're very cheap simple cars and
they're very fancy expensive cars
the direct method
make no assumption about your function it doesn't have to be moved differentiable or anything
right they always work
that makes them very easy to use and that's one of the reasons why evolutionary
algorithms for instance are so popular
you don't need to know anything about what you are optimizing
and you know you can just
goal plug it into your like function into your code to minimize
they're very very inefficient
because they have no information about which direction is downhill
the only way you can make progress is by sort of random
mutations in recombination so you need a lot of cycles to to optimize the function
nature does it hate a works works great but nature has had no five billion
to do its job and so if you can wait that long
and you know something about your function for instance that it's differentiable
then you can get a huge speedups by actually
giving you optimize the gradient information
letting it work more efficiently
we can express that in in order notation right something that computer scientists like to
do i familiar with that we go
who isn't
somebody OK
briefly explain if i say something
it takes
order and
time to compute
what i mean
is there exists
a finite
constant k
such that the actual time taken is k times and
some other constant actually
this is basically saying in roughly takes and time
the actual time could be like any factor times and plus and the constant
because obviously these factors and this constant they all depend on the implementation right you
you might be right more efficient code you may have compiled code or or something
but the important thing is that
if two algorithms differ in the order of time or memory that they require
then this will override any of these constants for large enough problems so if i
have two algorithms and one is order and in one is ordained squared
then you can see that no matter what k and c are since they finite
this is this is
typical search
and if it just a game theoretic and i'm not going to present all the
area such
there are two approaches
first approach is what we're going to do it
we are going to divide our information to plant
it's like
correct classifications so we we have our key
invest saying OK
this he said that only the log to follow structural now come to part of
this coarsely
this is that the current branch and bound
a lot of structure
beginning from ordinary
sorted array
and ending to very complicated three
another way is to my
map the most important example of web cache
the idea that we have to keep in this thing this is the address
we can use this key directly to get information
there is only two
processes such that i know
and the first the most simple ones structure sort iterates what sort the right
this simply
got all this work
and for them sorted into a
how they can judge this structure
this structure is
local garrisons
you know what is binary search
i think that everybody knows one and here we are trying to figure out in
the middle
if we are in the middle is more
the OWL t then we
then trying his upper part of the
sorry if we less than their
trying to
the bottom part of this of this array
and repeating this request olivia reduce it to one element so we
i always believed this array
what we have from this story
by by by the current approach
with the exception not so good because i
i didn't support here that the first we need to do church
because we usually always before insertion into the selection model in the most of this
but the problem is that we need to move
on average half of the story
to create new slot which you can forward this information
what are the advantages of this sort
the advantages is that
it's pretty complex
we don't have any pointers or anything else that we don't need to have your
data simply we have your about order data
and what the disadvantage is that it's not good for
from this point of view it it could be a very good structure for some
fixed array
something that is
we have static information
but it's not so good for dictionary definitions for outdoor search engine
every assertion then it will be future dictionary
going to
half of his career somewhere
and removal of memory so we definitely
it doesn't feed
in two thousand four
CPU cache
and have all these problems and its laws
but first i think the show it's OK
but for social cause because it is not very good locality here because are
the film chicken always in the middle then
the next step is not good for fish
it is about what good for search that are always
if that have been talking about CPU what is good that there are always
actually at least in the beginning the chicken the same element
and in in the middle elements in the quarter and so on
and therefore
lows of performance based on not like alex
what started to is not so bad
so it's is
it's not so but structure people used to
to think about it
if you see plus plus programming by the way other than a plus plus programming
java programmer
i think the
OK i think that
you already have have a solution and you have named standard template library
you have
the same structure in java libraries
usually it
binary tree
the idea of binary tree if you're looking for something to happen
two point from every now
one point
is still
bigger and all other pointers to small or not
and when we had to at this thing our current northern with result moving
right and left
so it's good structure because force
we need only
on average lottery some of
size for dictionary because the y every iteration divided by we divide by two
four this institution actually is if it is only search
when we
church history and the search is unsuccessful and we want to add the already have
and it only two
an additional point
of course if you are encouraged right
i was a month ago and i was implemented one right
project and they're needed
some simple fast structure the church using map from
structure from the point of view it's pretty reliable and it's a in all libraries
and implementation
another very good properties of this
structure that you can
iterate over it and get over it again in alphabetical order that is important for
you think of index that are going to discuss tomorrow
on almost all four four
english language
the average length of world
why why
and imagine that using out of date thirty two bit compute so we are using
the writing to point
two every word
every point is
how many bytes
four right
so for the world wide web
you are eighty a white point more than that
but again
so like for maybe four
but they tend be tells us
the idea eventually running for space is very rare
go to i know what's the probability go higher than log n
the easy one competition
this time have fifty percent probability going up
one and the probability of going up log levels
because i have to the power law again is one out of n
it depends on them
but i'm not going to get too high
and intuitively this is
you know not so bad
so these are skip lists
you know you have the ratios right in expectation
pretty weak statement doesn't say anything about the length of these chains
but intuitively
it's pretty good
that's a pretty good on average
so i had to process into semi random processes going on here one is taking
the numbers and that i don't want to assume anything about the numbers could be
adversarially could be sequential could be reversed or it could be random i don't know
so the matter what he said
it shouldn't matter
i mean it matters here don't
still undecided twenty five cents
have the what the argument cares about is the outcomes of these coins and the
probability the statement this
this data structure fast with high probability is only about the random quotes it doesn't
matter what the adversary chooses for numbers
as long as those claims are random and the adversary doesn't know the courts
there's no the outcomes of the courts
so in that case
on average over all of the coin flips should be OK
but the
the claim
it's not just that is pretty good average but it's really really good
almost always
it was really i probability
it's log
so for example with probability
one minus one or and
it's waterlogged with probability one minus one over and square it's probably one minus one
over and so hundred it's sort of like
all almost statements structure for any value of one hundred
that's where we're going
OK i should mention the lead to the how do you do we in a
skip list
finally element delete it all the way
that's the way it is nothing fancy with we
because we have all these independent random choices all these elements are sort of independent
from each other we don't really care
delete i want to throw away
the tricky part is insertion
when i insert an element and is going to randomly see how it should go
probability one to the i'll go to high i
right time
and having too much fun here
the girl in the faster
so here's the theorem see exactly what we're programming first
with high probability
former national
i will find in the second
the second sample OK is another entire observation of my graph that many observations
these stations assume that we observe the power all the virus in the graph
so how do you do maximum likelihood estimation here
we can do some guesses here so here's what guess
one guess is that the maximum likelihood estimation
estimate for
variables x one x two and x three
will be the empirical observations four x one x two
and empirical observations for extreme next three divided by the empirical observation for so these
are the peak of marginal
observations so this is the doctor
so this is the distribution one like this is the real doctor doctor i'm collecting
so this the marginal
doctor for one and two and the marginal distribution of words
in the extreme
although don't know that just making because gasoline for the guess is correct
so that you can see that these problem to potential these potential is on the
or you could put could put has been nominated for example the
we can verify that these guess is a good guess
because if you marginalize over x three
what do you get here
you get the marginal thanks to
divided by
the marginal fixture
which is here
if you marginalize this quantity
with respect to x these
to marginalize this quantity here with respect to x three
you get
max likelihood of x two and three which is this
now we use when you sum over x one
you obtain
the marginal
distribution pfx divided by which
these councils and then we obtain these
in other words if we use these as the maximum likelihood estimate for those three
then we will obtain maximum likelihood estimates for the particles in the clique that indeed
are there
the solutions we know should be correct
because we know that the marginals in the cliques
needs to meet
the marginals in the
the maximum likelihood estimate should be should be such that the marginals in the cliques
match the empirical marginals in the clicks that's what this saying
that's what it is
he is
so far
the expected value of the sufficient statistics which is the average
of the distribution should be equal to the mean of the empirical
so it seems that this is a good guess and we'll see this in fact
is the case
how the real thing
these marks large maximum likelihood estimates india
for every maximal clique
you set the clique potential to its empirical margin so for every click you observe
every click you observe some data
and then you set
the distribution of that
facial for that
has basically been it's empiricalmodel it's not going to be the solution it's going to
be the first approximation
then for every intersection between different cliques
you associate the empirical marginals with the intersection and divided
into the potential of one of the clicks
because you cannot count
that observation one
you just include the observation of intersection one of the cliques
these will give max like estimates for decomposable graphical models are young laid graphical models
are called the graphical models these are all seen
it seems very simple but that's exactly what you
if you have a full observation
this is just a theory for the composable graphs
but if you have no decomposable
in other words what have non chordal graphs
well of course one technique is to make it chordal and then using junction tree
and basically we can learn using the same procedure
if not you need to use an iterative procedure
which essentially is
trying to
make sure that the marginal
with respect to every click
so that they is confined in as well
here's the really important
i will that unless told me went to see
the yemen with who has heard of the world
OK quite a few people
so let's look at the algorithm in its full generality
EMI with
so we saw how we can obtain maximum likelihood estimates in the case where
he is
virus are all so
if you happen to get doctor that actually tells you
or you observe all the viable
a few more
but that may not be the case
you may have what we call it inviable which are variables that correspond to some
abstract concept that you don't really matter in reality
well sometimes you may have idable that do don't represent abstract concepts they
the really exist but you just don't have access to measurement of of the bible
so in many cases basically you don't observe
some by
which for example in this case we don't observe this virus
we only observe variables x one and x two
how do you do learning in this case
now it's the last sort of mathematics of the day
use the rest of energy you've got your brain
try to foreclose because it is really beautiful
and also tired but since the so beautiful i will
drive all my images to flickr
this is one of the most used algorithms in computer science very
thousands of
citations of the original paper proposes these thirty
two years ago
so let's
let's take look
the first thing we do let's
those whatever that we observe
let's call them text
and those five that don't observe
call them
assume if we knew z
let's assume for a moment if we knew said
assemble charges
i have to do work we discussed earlier
and we call that the electrostatic potential energy
today i will look at
the energy content in different ways
i will evaluate the energy in terms of the electric field
suppose i have two parallel plates
and i charge this from the positive charge
which is the surface charge density times the area of the
this one's negative charge
which is the surface charge density negative times
the area of play
let's assume that the separation between these two h
so we have an electric field
which is approximately constant
two years
divided by
and now
i'm going to take the upper plate
the movement of
so as i do that
i have to apply for
with these two plates attract each other
so i have to do work
and as i move these up
i will move it up
of distance act
i am creating year electric field that wasn't there before
an electric field that i'm creating
has exactly the same strength
as this
because the charge on the plate is not changing when i'm moving
the surface charge density is not changing
all i do is i increase the distance
and so i am creating electrocute
in here
and for that i have to do work that's another way of looking at it
how much work so i have to do
what is the work
i want to do it has to do
a moving display over the distance act
well that is the force that i have to apply
over that distance x
the force is constant
so i can simply multiply
the force times the distance that will give work
so the question now is
one is the force that i have to apply
to move this plate up
and your first guess would be
the fourth
it would be
the chart on the plate
and the electric field strength completely reasonable guess because you would argue
well if we have an electric field e and we bring a charge q in
there than the electric forces q times e i have to overcome the force so
my forces q times e
yes that holds most of the time
but not in this case so little a bit more so
let me take this plate here
a large that played
so here's the plates so you see the thickness of the plate now
this is one place
we all agree that the press charges
at the
surface well but of course it has to be in the plate
and so on is here his layer of charge q
because at the bottom of the plate and the thinkers of that player may only
be one atomic thickness but it's not zero
and on this site
of the plates is that electric field
which is a modified by actually non-zero
but inside the plate which is a conductor the electric field is zero
and therefore
the electric field
it is in this charge q is the average between the two
and so the force on this chart
in this
there is not a few times e but is one half
two times so i take the average between these fields and this e
field is then this value
so now i can calculate
the work that i have to do
is not my force
which is one half
i in
and i move that over
the distance x
so what i can do no
replace q by
sigma a b
so i get one half
sigma h
times e
the exact
and i multiply upstairs and downstairs
i absolutely zero
multiplied by one
the reason why i do that is
because then i get another sigma divided by actually non-zero here
by the way films zero one that is e
and therefore
i now have the total work that i will tell you would have to do
has to do is one half
actually non-zero
the square
times a
i'm x
and look at this
if x is the normal volume
i have created it is the new volume in which i have created electric field
and this now
call for a
then by walter lewis
per unit volume
and that now
equals one half
actually non-zero
the square
this is the word
but i have done
per unit
volume and since this work
created electric fields
we call fields
energy density
and it is in jail
per cubic metre
and it can be shown that in general
the electric field energy density
is one half actually non-zero in squared
not only for this particular charge configuration with for any charge configuration
so now we have a new way of looking
at the energy that it takes to assemble charges
earlier we calculated the work that we have to do
to put the charges in place
now if it is more convenient
we could calculate that the energy
electrostatic potential energy
is the integral
of one half
absolute non-zero square
over all space
if necessary you have to go all the way down to infinity
and i have now
this is volume
it has nothing to do with potential between physical often run out of symbols
these sometimes potential in this case
it is volume
and the only reason why i chose eight there
yes i really have d year so i didn't want to do normally we take
the separation between the plates
and so this now
is another way of looking
at electrostatic potential energy
we look at it now only from the point of view of all the energy
being in the electric field
and we no longer think of it perhaps as the work that you have done
to assemble
i will demonstrate later today
that as a separate
the two plates
from these
planes that indeed i have to do work i will convince you
by creating an electric field that indeed i will be doing
so from our own
we have the choice
if you want to calculate multi
electrostatic potential energy
three years
my name is quantity that is the binding energy which depends on the
so first ever bounces then you want these mass of the nucleus lower than the
mass of the constituent so you want to have binding energy positive training energy
so in our age you have this binding energy which is close to eight immediately
so this is an average because more carefully if you look at that
so you have binding energy per nucleon depending on the mass number
so you have here
the term six very nine two i ran fifty six maximum
and then many points to uranium two hundred thirty eight and have
so here you have a me
but you see that you have an increased and then increase
and this is very important
pictures because from that you can understand many things concerning energy prediction concerning
a new search for
nuclear so
can you tell me from these care which nuclei could fission spontaneously
can you gain energy from these nuclei
in fact just consider the negative binding energy so minus the quantities of from zero
to so it is here you just minus
the previous slides
you have here
the most stable nuclei which is ironic
so if you wanted to efficient means that you have this if you do that
breaks into fragments
so if you want to gain energy you have
you have to start from having
and then having
like fragments here
because it consider
when you is here
sorry one nucleus here
that will be
fission into fragments it will go here
so you will lose energy
so the only way
to gain in energy is to start from one nucleus
after that i run here heavier than higher and
and is contrary for fish and you have to start from
nuclei very well
a small nuclei
here to go up to irony
so that's why formula one grand they are looking at fission of uranium plutonium of
it's because you can gain energy
and for fusion is contrary for example you have this either which i can get
so it they want to have to have a vision of the tree in place
just to to study the physics so that's why they are looking at this
systems that
so more precisely
i was numbers
so fission
is one frank when you is a
and then you have two to fragments b and c
and you have these energy
so far the energy balance if you consider the mass of the proton equals the
mass of the neutron economy and
you have this equation so it's time some
of the neutrons minus the bending energy of a
i equals p times the mass of the neutron minus the binding energy
of the
the same for c and these
so far the energy difference you see
that you should have
b b b b c bigger than me if you want to get energy
the same for fusion
so that's why four if you want to have energy during the fission
you need to have a vision of elements heavier than i ran
and and for fusion for elements lower than i one
so on and other things that can be deduced from these here if the
abundance of elements on the earth
in the universe
you have here the binding energy
in blue
depending on the atomic numbers
so this is the maximum for irony and here in abandoned
the elements in the universe and you see here that you have peak for i
and that correspond to these
maximum of finding
so it means that i won't do not want to recreate particles do not want
to emit particles because it's very very stable nuclei
so that's why
everything converge to
so i run is the most stable and abundant nucleus
and in the limit between the burning by fusion as i explained before
and red if capture neutrons so you have higher and then you can capture many
many neutrons
so what about lifetime so we talk about stable nuclei
so what about radioactive nuclei
those stable nuclei means their lifetime is infinite so bigger than the lifetime of the
proton together the support thirty three years
so the other ones are unstable
it means that they can transform into more stable nuclei
so what you want to have their lifetime
so is the statistical definition you are here the number of nuclei in the same
depending on the time here t
and you have this exponential decay here in pink
so you find the lifetime here
because he has the time for which you have only
if you're nuclei in your
so it's
very commonly used definition for exponential decay
there are different types of radioactivity so
and you can involve an image different particles so the most common one are these
one so
this is your nucleus in your somebody home
with is the proton and neutron
ganymede one neutron so that it like here
or any one credit
so you start from the and you have the minus one n
alpha particle is also very very common
so you lose two proton to neutron
you have the time and is to j
right that plays the king of electron capture
a few years ago exotic to what i read your activity has been discovered so
it means that it's not sequential two proton but i just ten times two protons
have been
so it's quite unusual but it has been
so they are looking now at protons are
other exotic radioactivity
so these are some examples that they can in the literature so just to see
you that you have
a lot of details but also for the same here you can have a and
i j
and finally shown
electron capture
it means that you have many many processing competition so when you are looking at
one case you have to consider all the neighbours to be sure
that i
when you calculate the lifetime
so you can get to the ground state are you can get to the excited
states of the ground state is the lowest energy state
of course
in the direction of play
it propagates with the speed of light
but this pattern
move away faster than the speed of light
and it can actually
get completely
out of hand it can be very very large
these raids
travel in the x direction
that means the red line will be vertical
that means l y will go to infinity
it means that k of y goes to zero
it means that the phase velocity goes to infinity
this pattern and here the intersection here
well then
goal was to speak which is infinitely high
and there is no violation of einstein's
of special relativity because no energy will flow
with that speed
and i can best
to ensure that
by showing that something similar
can happen with water
suppose we view shoreline
and we have someone away
coming in like this
maybe i should put him in red sort you begin to make the connection
between the electromagnetic waves
and what so here is a wave
rolling in
is by definition
the wavelength lambda
and all of that move
with velocity v
but the intersection
of these two ways here point eight
and here point b
i call this distance
alpha x i could have called it a lot of just as i did here
it's the intersection
this axis that i gave a symbol of why i called it there
of x
the difference in arrival time
between wave
and we have to
the the difference in arrival time between
we one and wave two
at point b
is the period of the way
it is simply land divided by the trivial but that's not only the case for
point b
that is also the case for point
this way form
reaches eight before it reaches the before two
which is point eight and this is the time in between
the arrival time
of wave one
and we have two
which is a completely different question
from what is the difference in arrival time of wave one alone
at a and b
that's the difference in arrival time
between one wave between point a and b
depends on this angle theta
and one thing that goes to zero that difference in arrival time goes to zero
both a and b will at the same moment in time
see that way
so that means that in that case when theta is zero
this al x becomes infinitely large
and so if you expressed that in terms of the phase velocity in this direction
the phase velocity then becomes infinitely high
so it is this pattern
that moves with the velocity that can be way larger than c
but no one will move with that last it's very clear there is no water
going from here to there
so this is not a violation of einstein's theory
of special relativity
so several very dedicated students wrote me email
after last lecture they could not sleep
and i didn't even feel guilty
and the reason why they couldn't sleep is that
we had this wonderful demonstration
whereby i have you an aluminum plate
and not all in one place
and this was the seat of action
and the separation between the plates was a
and we had
electromagnetic radiation
going in that direction
and we concluded
i will not go over the reasoning again
that the phase velocity
in the same direction
it was omega
divided by k of c
and that was larger than c
that's why you guys couldn't sleep
and in fact
i even demonstrated that if you
make the radiation
the frequency close to cut off
in this course we discussed
linear polarization of electromagnetic radiation
and i demonstrate this at seventy five megahertz
and ten gigahertz
today i will concentrate
on the polarisation
of light
which is a much
higher frequency
the light from the sun light from light bulbs
is not polarized
so i can ask myself the question
what does it mean when light is not polarized
let's think of individual light photons
as plane waves
was well defined direction
of polarisation
so each one is
linearly polarized
it's coming straight out of the blackboards
the first photon arrives
it's really polarized these are actually
the second photon arrives linearly polarized in this direction thirty electric field vector is also
leading like that another photon another photon from another photon another photon
what you see here very clearly
that there is no
preferred direction
when you average over time
and that's what we call call unpolarized light
it was edwin land who in nineteen thirty eight
developed material
that can turn this
in two
linearly polarized
light for which he became very famous in addition to these demonstrations
that i showed you last time
if i take one of
edwin land sheets
which will turn light into a polarisation in this direction
and i first
take one photo
for instance this one
that one comes in from the blackboards towards you
and so here it is
oscillating in fact like this
he zero is the maximum
the value of the electric field strength in that plane
electromagnetic waves
and this is direction
of the polarizer
but i have to do with this photon
i can now
make it simple calculation
by projecting this vector
on two
preferred direction of polarization
and there no easy victory
is now down by the cosine of data that
this angle to say that
this is a vector
is now is
he zero
and the cosine
of data
if you ask we know
whether the light is reduced in intensity
i would have to say yes of course
because light intensity
depends on the poynting vector
the poynting vector is always proportional
two is zero square
because the poynting vector
is the cross product between e and b
and if the
is reduced b is also reduced
so we get the cosine square reduction
if no i averaged over all incoming photons
so i think all of these which represent an unpolarized beam
so i get not only one like so when i get one likes o and
one like so o one like so o one like so
i have to calculate now
i mean value of cosine square state
and the mean value of cosine square theatre is one half
and so if the intensity of the unpolarized beam
unpolarized light was originally i zero
ones that come through this polarizer that edwin land gave me
i get one half i zero
but that is now
on the percent
all right
and it is hundred percent polarized
in this direction
and one half
it is the result
the average value of cosine square
if this were the case
would be an extremely ideal polarization
probably be reasonably confident that you have the because the solution is here so you
know if you saw the you know where you got it right or not so
there's no reason to be
we were involved in the world
like your chance to lecture the machine learning summer school
so you have done this before we usually always had one or two where
compared to
anyone courageous
i raised about to high
OK so this one myself i think you just want to see mister from the
bible here other this one myself but in the next problem someone will have to
do it so see shock
must be true because of the mathematics department
actually this
one which is the song song problems here are there
OK so we said we have to cheque whether the point is
closer to home
the positive meaning of closer to the negative meaning
this is the rule
should be easy in this is where we should be checking whether
artists find is closer to the positive or the negative media and
this is the right
and i'm sure make mistakes we have put interesting they also get a point because
i'm not usually lecturing i'm just a researcher at the max planck institute so we
don't have to have indicated lecture at universities so let's see if this is right
if the distance to the
if it's closer to the positive point and the distance to the naked to closer
to the positive mean means the distance the negative means larger which is this is
positive we assign the point of the positive class that to be the right way
so this work is art
so here we use the dot product is just part
the same thing
very negative
and then we have
the same thing over here
only with plus instead of
so OK of first is
the product of five x with
all this square is from OK so you have one point really actually the second
stage what
but point
as you
the man with the green teachers
a lot of people in the
only birds you want
so this
with this we've got through the complicated ones to some
here we always have done
three five x five j so
this can be
OK so
i think it should be obvious if it's not obvious to you
but one can
take the sum of the product and how these two sons combined to the single
or to this summons on think about it after the election because that's something you
you can calculate what is there a conservation
what is also interesting for this network to classical network is the property of small
world which means that the distance between nodes
in this network
is proportional to log n where n is the number of nodes so you can
see even if n increases very much larger still
reduces dramatically and makes it small and this is why we called networks small world
called also small world and it's related to the six degrees of separation that we
between people
in this concept of very important social sciences
but it was found in nineteen ninety nine that many real networks was on and
they don't not obey these degree distribution but there are there
the vision for example one kind of information can be represented by scale free skate
that is
power law distribution catered to minus land
the power of the case much slower than explanation that's why you can also in
this politics which can have also high degree nodes like you know which is then
but you can have also even if the book is very large you can have
a hundred thousand and many many a
links per node and this the suggests by by version of the nineteen ninety nine
they also gave presented to model what is the difference between the two one of
the different is that the former genesis in these networks of genes which means you
you see have the symmetry that almost all see the same labelled here it's not
the same from the see only very few
the nodes some notes in very many so these two engineers in this breaks physics
and all if you is symmetry translational symmetry is same every node it's not the
same so presentation of symmetry breaks
changes universality class changes properties and many many properties found to be different for such
complex network which are not
o mcginnis and for example
instead of being a PC to be one of the key average for this type
of network in the range between two and three
is a actually between two and three which for many many networks find the PC
approach goes to zero which means that even if you have a very you remove
almost all the nodes in the network still communication exist which does not carry that
explains many phenomena which are not clear before and they and they for example
this is constraint on the on the internet for so long time also called
people by the virus and put it so it was against this silly but if
the standard is so different network and you know that this is the only means
that even almost people by the was still the viruses can spread in the network
another property which is important for this network the distance which was your login
small world become even smell another look appeals look so it means they showing the
distance by these type of network scale free networks
and the logo was proved analytically in this paper with london between two so we
call it will be a small world and this is a soapbox who wants to
understand many and so many of the problems to just to indicate to
the country the between what sort the distribution
and scale free you can imagine they were not bald
they did not go forward in the united states which typical number of faults going
out from one node and almost the same number of them and today which is
very different sometimes have many lines sometimes have very low and indeed it was found
by this opinion and if go the that apologies vision also be an exponent close
to two full airline network which i will discuss later
now i want to show you some
which reminds but important in the field in which the networks are important in different
fields for example the first give an example of something that was one of the
first examples but they found also that the internet walk is also part it's a
degree part of the degree distribution is power law which means
you can have also on the a a computers which are connected to many many
computers and this is a y
we are also interested in now the question is why network study is very important
and and i will show you for the scene in biology and medicine
in the end you may be seen
in the nineteen eighties was founded the gene p fifty three is a very important
is the tumour suppressor mutation in this gene
the resulting cancer but still
it did not so if we know even the gene you the problem we could
not solve the problem and the reason was given by this three people
later the live in extreme with discovered the pieces the and they say the following
one is to understand the p fifty three network which is just like the into
this not concept supporting is an american actor control the activity of large and on
a number of other body which means that if we understand the point in itself
we know which fourteen called the scans so it's not enough we need to understand
the network and this is one of the reasons one of the main reasons why
people are very interested to understand better the network of protein local or in biology
and i like fixing one junction in all we know is not enough to fix
the traffic in the world
and for example paper that appeared in ninety two thousand five and immediately another that
they studied the mapping of human protein interaction network and this was done in order
so for the
and you can show that this this is a is also totally unimodular
by the way
the problem of the non bipartite matchings of the assisting molecule matching
there is no
linear programming formulation it looks very similar we have notes
and i want to get matching bright and i want to say concerning the degree
to build you know you are equal to one less than one returns after that
problem non bipartite matchings
the number of constraints need to add to the linear programme for it to actually
give you an internal solution is is exponential or these there is no known polynomial
you know for the last forty years so
that problem we're going have to talk with some other method to
this this kind of the method applies only to write down LP and the number
of constraints LP and the variables in LP
it is polynomial
OK so
the other piece of
piece of technology we need is is this duality that in out in the context
of stems
if this is our lt
in the primal the door that looks very similar to swap c and b
transpose the a
and and
so this is a mapping
because of the science
we wrote all the inference problems like this
now we can actually use this guy which is so
this problem is
this guy is going to be bounded so this value in this valley are equal
in more and more problems with considered this set of constraints always visible so now
we're in the in the case where the reality strong duality holds and we have
this max and this men are exactly so you can just plug in
then what i mean
in the change
OK so this was our formulation right we plug in the max discrete max all
going to do now is plug
continuous one
q i just abbreviated it's five and w class ally OK so
it's taking everything that kind of
hits why
and putting it into this matrix the now hit rate so there was w hitting
f x y
now we can write it down as the leading
OK in the same thing for for her loss
so that we had this and then heads e
OK and that gives score
and then
this is that gives you the loss
right so you see why loss was also important to be
decomposable because now it's can be a linear function of disease or disease vector in
this guy is a vector
and so that's going get you that computes
our loss for us
by LP duality these interchangeable so we can just
stick n
this guy
here the main
it turns out we can just move the men
of the activity was minimisation over everything in the same time
so that the only variables that appear in this minimisation appeared down below
so you might as well just move them in
out here
so now we have a joint w this lacks prominence slacks and these landers
which is basically the land this try to compute for us implicitly
what what sort of the most violated constraint is what is the the highest scoring
guy that's that's making us
look back right
and all that sort of
encoded into in this
because that's the dual of the max
that's it that's the whole track
you go from discrete to continue
take do all and you have a QP
there has finite number of variables that w is not the parameters lambda is in
numbers roughly corresponds to the number of constraints information which is
number of parts
this thing is