and on and so on his own
it's all
and each
link graph
so what
we don't have any other
we do not like this
this is for you
so to say
all right support she really just
during this something also to just
you know
you've s
is something similar
what we need to address
the signal
in some more
in some sense
is still
very common more
just to give you
and what's more
so what you
i just want to
all of this
this is a year or so you know
now is all so
all these
most people of know
you have your
which is
problem which requires that change
and this for all time
apparently mild strains just fine
also three
let me know
so called
and then most
much more
four or one
trust and so
so the information
one more test it so it
perhaps the key issues
so here are
it's very
also show here
first of all
so who would fit in a result
our problem by
it's very well mention is
one of the problems
people have
right right
it is
or something else
there are more
but what
one of the
number one
well we may have
and he is only
yes or no
suppose that more sure
what i want to
if i want to send a message
from this
is that all draw
make sure
if this is
x j
this is x y
you have
two x
incoming messages
if i want to compute the message
from j
two five
that will be a function of x i right
message if you want to compute
message here is another message
aerial graph
i want to compute this message here
which is the message
j two y
x y
this will be equal to what
next of GI effects
this will be able to this potential here
and as such
i effect size
because the potential of x
i xj
which is is incorrect
the conditional risk
just doing the
just marker of field version
the same
o silly
times the problem
overall k
where k is different from my
of the messages from can
of x j
this is a message from the ones
this message of a
two of acts
can use message here will be this potential
i'm the product of all the comments
it is not
once the computer all those messages i just compute the marginal by the product of
the the message
but c
and you can plot
you will see that in the fall
also partners works with three is OK
we'll see how that works in real life
we may also use the max product so instead of for example computing
the marginal probability may want to ask what is the most likely realisation of key
set for
because q
to talk about the same thing
this not such
as i mentioned so what if we have a bipartite graph
you have my photographs
it's going to be complicated more but still has also
that's the case
let's assume that we are going to use the elimination because remember we used the
elimination of previous before these graph here
and elimination of it and we can we don't need the three we can apply
to any
and you know
what you're going to the nodes to generalise the
information our
the case where you can make
more sophisticated version of the nation of four i've had such that you can reuse
of your application
in a similar way
as we
propagation with
for example assume we have this graph you observe divided x six
if you want to compute p of x one given x six
then you go and do all this
i want to go through this
showed you already how it works
all elimination
now in the end you compute this score
now assume you want know the query you want to compute p of extreme given
x six
first you wanted to create your x one given x six now
i created this p of x three given x
what is do
but it can also be the same thing
but you will notice that there are some of these functions the computer along the
that you've already computed before
for the first
we have something like this is the competition for the first the competition for the
second we
and you have repeated computation
these things are you using
still you want
somehow avoid computing these things
union a mechanism to actually avoid
we solve this in the case of the
if you have three
but what if you have a general graph
i think that becomes
more more interesting more complicated
the answer is something called the junction three of
which is basically what we want to work before the break
what he
the junction tree algorithm is a generalisation of belief propagation
so in theory
you can apply to any graph can be a bayesian network can be lot of
it doesn't matter
you can find some way to go
like the belief propagation with
my friend there's no time and no
and then there is one in the middle if you subtract one
three minus one is to in second harmonic
so now i will try to generate very high frequency
in residents and then you count the number of nodes subtract one
and then you know which harmonic
i was able to generate
about fighting
not so easy to get the residents in there
so i'm off resonance
two people
on so i
i'm going to come
we to
july twenty
i can
so that's standing waves
and you see the shape
use so the
the mode of operation
very characteristic for standing waves
when i plucked string
or i strike it was invisible
or is the hammer
on the piano is the hammer comes down
that is exposing the
the whole set of frequencies
and so the string now
besides which frequencies it like two
oscillating and so it selects
these resonance frequencies
so if the strange
as the fundamental four hundred hertz
that it will start to resonate four hundred
but simultaneously it would be very happy with eight hundred hertz and withdraw from the
and so the string will simultaneously if i bang it
or striking it or pocket simultaneously
also made
often have more than one frequency fundamental
and several of the higher
how monarchs
and all the others present all the other frequencies in this
striking was the ball
i ignored because of resonance
so if you decide a string instrument
and this is really a key equation
if you want a particular fundamental
say you fundamentalist four hundred and forty and this is given number
and so n is one
you can now manipulate
because the
depends on the tension in the string
and it depends on what kind of string
this breed
in the string
is the square root of the tension
if you take all three
you even see approval for that
divided by the mass of the string
per unit length
of the string
so you take for strings for violins six forty five
you make them out of very different materials
different bass per unit length
and so that gives you then
different velocities you can also
four around with attention
so the four strings and have all four
a different
in the violin they may have the same length
what are you going to do now to play the violin
all that is left over is albert the only thing you can change that's what
the violinist is doing
the finger back and forth over the strings make them shorter
it's goes up frequency goes up makes them longer frequency goes down the same
same was based on the challenge
so when you're playing what you're doing all the time is changing l
but as you get all these frequencies that you want to produce
if you can your instrument out of the closet
you may have noticed that it's not really into anymore it's slightly of two
well what you can do now
you can change the little bit
these little knobs
you can change the tension in the string
that's what violence do when they
their violin they
change the tension on the string to get just the right
but the playing means change l
i was different that's really luxury pianos eighty eight keys
and the length of each
a set of strings is fixed so you don't have to worry about that
it's a great luxury you may think therefore that it is much easier to play
the piano player violence
because you don't have to do this all the time and be exactly at the
right length
well that true of course but
given the fact that you have eighty eight keys you can imagine you can also
occasionally wrong key
and that's not what you want
if strings vibrating
it is pushing on the end it's pulling on the air and is producing by
what we call pressure waves
if i have a strange oscillates four hundred hertz
it makes pressure waves
pressure goes up down up down up down
four hundred times per second goes up
it reaches your eardrum in your neurons starts to shake
four hundred times per second
goes back and forth
your brain saying
i just sound
that's the way it works so it is the string
when you get
pressure waves
and then you get you drunk
and then
you get the brains if there are any
i want to discuss the issue before i demonstrate some of this
in this case you in some entries don't have straight i will call them all
woodwind instruments although
that's perhaps not an appropriate name
for all of them but i just call them woodwinds twenty
suppose i have here
a box which is filled with air
completely closed what has a length l
and i put it here
and i generate a particular frequency of sound
then the pressure waves are going to run
going to bounce off and they come back
and again reflect traveling waves
and when i get inside the box now
i get standing waves of air it's not the box that goes into was standing
resonance but is the area itself
and the frequencies that are produced which the system is in resonance
is given by exactly the same equation
except now
that he is non-negotiable
these now to speed of sound
which room temperature
it's about three hundred and forty meters
a second
so whatever you design
we we woodwind instruments
that is non-negotiable you can not
change the which you can do when you are in some of strings
you will say g
if i have an instrument by the sound inside a closed box you're not going
to be very well that's true
you must let the sun go out somehow
what is surprising
if you take this and out of
you take this and of
that this
box which is now open on both sides will still resonate exactly those frequencies
want to take a two three
we get to the bottom of this
they also resonance frequencies
in case
that the
sounds like everything i call it sound cavity
it's much worse than a transcendental number is transcendental yes you can prove it because
it work if it were not to break number
it would be highly compressible OK this number
has infinite complexity in fact each bit of this
number is one bit of complexity
there is no redundancy here is irreducible in other words even though this number is
well defined mathematically very simply the halting probability by that some that i showed you
its numerical value
it is a sort of a given human limitations it's like the perfect simulation of
independent also a fair coin in pure maths
because we can never know bits so it's not only uncomputable i mean turing in
nineteen thirty six already had an uncomputable this is computable in the worst possible way
the smallest program you know for any number of bits of this you know capital
and this is the smallest program for and bits of this
you know if you want to get the first n bits here
smallest program
also has and bits
and the smallest axioms from which you can deduce
what those things are sort of computing them
also and
in other words its irreducible computationally
the first n bits of this
the smallest program to calculate them will have about the same size and for any
n and also if you're just trying to deduce you know have theorems use axioms
to prove what each bit is for the first n bits
to be able to prove what the first n bits are you will need about
a bit of axioms so this is a irreducible truth
what that is not seriously intended the large
you get into trouble
yes and a friend of mine chris collude has
have done that exercise
for small for small for some of the initial bits in fact depending on your
programming language you can look at all the small programs and you can
you can get lower bounds and even upper bounds you know but very soon you
start getting in trouble because of the general result
well it depends on the programme language here
you know it's one of the first bits are ones you can actually prove the
initial once you can always prove that their ones by getting better and better lower
so the string of the ones at the beginning can be too long anyway what
it says
the idea and to tell you is that these bits are irreducible complexity in pure
so in a way
what they show you is is that pure mathematics is the beautiful
so let me just like this in terms
nobody has held up a sign yet OK so i still have little time or
i'm now
OK OK so let me
let me try to use latin in terminology for this which i think is relevant
light has a principle called the principle of sufficient reason
which says if something is true is true for a reason
you know and if something is true in mathematics the the reason is called proof
and if you want to simplify what mathematicians do is they find through their job
is to show the reason to find the reason something is true OK well
the bits of this number
each of them has to be user one mathematically determined in the world of pure
thought it's determined there is no freedom this is an individual real number a specific
real number but so delicately balanced between zero and one that we're never going to
know in other words
in a sense
but if we try to prove that are calculated you know the one thing is
the world of pure math platonic world of ideas or what god's mind you know
may contain the value of this number but for us
the way it works is
the region of interest
and use containing simplex instead of containing ellipsoid to do essentially the same thing
my guess is that that algorithm in fact is practical the body ever implemented and
this is from the he might
and it does work well that's probably the best thing to do
used to minimize a submodular function
all right so now you know you know the two theorems you know the two
theorems that are fundamental to minimizing submodular function and all the direct algorithms we know
for minimizing a submodular function
in use these two algorithms
and use these two terms in some form or another
sometimes are
and a disguised form but using these two basic
and there are lots of algorithms now
lots of direct algorithms other all the time
but they are all involved
we've got a set of points and expressing
we've got a set of extreme points expressing a point as a convex combination
and we
we move subject to be mixed
expressible by that convex combination
every once in a while we we
express it differently
that's where all the algorithms were
and very nicely
no removing the
the next terms that there go way beyond
submodular minimisation it's like submodular minimisation this is entirely analogous to
maxflow mincut problems
you have a general weights from maxflow mincut problem in general weights the dole problem
being the capacities of the primal problem right
its minimum cost flow
where you have
cos on the flows
in the primal problem and then you want to
as for minimum cost flow
prior to the ceremony talk about now
is a generalisation abstract version of the minimum cost network flow
whereas submodular minimisation is an
maximum network flow
this is a generalisation cost well for two in nature
pollinator i'm i in time
i'm almost done but they do it
you get two
following we tried
given by
i hope i've showed you few times now what
that p e
i mean
we had expressed
we've seen it several times
i was scared that that's it then that is
that characterizes the facets of the binary tree but we don't really need that
we're we're somewhere is our definition
here you find there we go
this is i just want to remind you of our notation
here that means the polytope
was set affordances e polytope
given by any qualities that forms
where this
is a polymatroid function right
and we applied the greedy algorithms
to find an optimum vertex of that single
but now
integer polymatroid
their intersection there
does the same thing for an arbitrary pair of politics may try
you can be given to
integer polymatroid
all in the same space that's all
according ties but the same vectors
vertices and each of those polytopes is given by the greedy algorithm applied to those
but amazingly
intersection of those two polytopes
is still in integer values
here we're intersecting two
polytopes with energy vibrancy but the intersection
the vertices of are also
that's what in fact more than that the two systems defining those two polytopes
are so-called totally
TDI i totally due
and to
that means that if there
if the objective function is all managers
even if the polymatroid is not an integer value
the primal objective function is are integers
there's going to be an integer values
and an integer valued one that optimizes the
now it follows from that that is the
parliamentary functions are integer values
then there's going to be an integer valued at
that optimizes in the in the
primal optimisation over these two
that's what TD and this means and total
that's used in virtually every
well solved combinatorial optimisation problems
by the way there are a lot of work there a lot of other well
sort of combinatorial optimization problems
i find it in this
the difference here
so not similarly to what we that we've done for the perceptron
we go to
and they can look
but now we take a look at the square this grid
the square of the difference
so we take can look at
minus that the minus one
we can use here
and what is what is known as the law
of course sign
i would say that
and to explain this
a little bit
to say that this is the most
the difference between
the difference between this
and some new
in the difference between
in the same you
where you
of the three
we them
the are
we are we are proving convergence here so i said in the beginning but it
now so we're looking at the list three just like in the pacific coming
OK so we assume the existence of some you that
is about a third and we choose to
long enough so that she separation with the nineteen one
it's just before we have mainly we absolutely terrible they were fighting over
is the same as company
why is this true
because the polymer remember the picture had there
so we have about fifty minus one
then we have a linear constraints which is the variety of the show that that
user modeling one
and we project this guy
on the
onto hyperplane
in we got that it
and then you
you a guy that satisfies all the contract so in particular which satisfy this conference
here so will achieve margin you so this is the constraint that is given by
example x y t
OK so you despite all of them in particular satisfy his car
so you
will be somewhere over here
by definition of the
but was looking at this triangle here
and the local sites such that the
the square
this criticized the of the
will then i'm you you've got me if i can engage people should force my
personality and what i do
to get better results will then you've got me
so we took that definition
and over a period of a year we use the system called our checkpoint three
speak to
forty thousand or speak to a bigger part in four hundred thousand people
about forty thousand direct reports
this is
the biggest
ever study
i don't ever into the topic of leadership charisma
and without technology would not be possible with blessed
we have a system
well we put about
a quarter of a million litres through every year we assess the competency and so
what we did was
we said to these forty four hundred thousand people
here's your posterity
here's the definition of leadership charisma
to what extent does he have that
o five he has solvent for
quite a lot
three days OK
hardly any
and one
charismatic leaders bypassed
the guy is a black hole for charisma absolutely on inspiring most uninspiring person you
ever met new life
and at the same time as we asked them to rate them on that
we ask them also
tell us
what do you see them do today
and we use the model
of seventy
leader behaviors
we've developed over thirty years
that we know from our research
are the difference between the best leaders
and the rest between those who get
great results and those who don't
once we have that we were able to say hey
what to the people of high charisma sharing common one of the things that they
do today
that have that effect on people of giving that our having that charismatic impact making
people want to as i say here inspiring an attitude where they want to do
their very very best
what we found was
those people who scored at very high and the christmas scale
shared twenty six
very specific behaviors in common
there are seventy behaviours in our model twenty six of them no matter where they
came from in the world in our sample
it was four hundred thousand employees
rating just under forty thousand leaders
from every country we do business in worldwide
and when we looked at what the find the difference between those who had a
charismatic impact on people who are they seen as being charismatic and the others were
twenty six things that they specifically ten first the most important thing is it comes
down to behavior
is not
a god given
it becomes easier to some people
then it does well
but charisma
it is what people say you have
when they like
the things you do
think about it
in your mind imagine the most charismatic person you can think of think somebody real
that you know charismatic and you put them in the room
let's make it difficult to put a bag over the head and you tell them
just to stand there and say nothing and do nothing and you run for five
or six hundred people pass
what sort of impact
do they have in that audience
you take the bag of the head maybe they make eye contact and all something
has happened maybe just in that i contact as a little spark bottom line
start to have a charismatic appeal
when they do things that people like
when they do things that turn people on it comes down to behavior
if it comes down to behavior
it means
any one of us
can choose to be more charismatic we wish to
i mean one of us can choose to learn
and developed
and assimilate and use those behaviors the charismatic leaders use to engage people now
can we all be at john f kennedy
i theoretically yes but you know you look at the look at those highly connected
to steve jobs of this world somehow there's something there
whether it's where they the way they've been raised or whether it's in the genes
i really don't know that makes it a little bit easier for them but i
guarantee you
every single person in this room
particularly those of you
who found yourselves are found your way into leadership positions
i have
as part of your behavior
some of those charismatic behaviors it's normal for you
but you also lack some of them
any one of us
can choose to
and some of those behaviours to the way we interact with other people
and increase the charismatic impact increased engaging in fact we have a problem
the important thing is we have to know what those behaviors are first
let we just go back from what is now
i said all about behavior i wanted to i i mentioned steve jobs has anybody
seen steve jobs speak i don't mean person i mean and OK so it's pretty
dynamic sort of individual who is piece of video
which was before apple computers
took off to any great extent it before it before he became who he is
and it's one of the first interview city ever had and what i want you
to focus upon the the sound from this is not going to be great is
pretty low but i wanted to focus upon with this young man is how charismatic
is c
at this particular point in time this is before it all started happen when apple
computer just been founded now let me turn that machine around and you have some
chance of hearing the sound because the sound of this particular clip is is not
fantastic so let's try that
so just just look and you see
does this
when it's going into the blackboards
i can put
these magnified needles
in its vicinity
and they will then do this
when i put it here
will go like this
and they follow
tensions of the circle
this is the weighted we define
the magnetic field and the direction of the magnetic field
that the magnetic field for which we always write symbol b
in that it field
it is now in the clockwise direction
by convention
current goes
into the blackboard
and if you ever forget that
use what we call the right hand
i think corkscrew
and you turn clockwise
corkscrew goes in the board
that connect to be with the current
if you take a corkscrew
and you rotated
then the corkscrew country you come out of the court
that's how you find the magnetic field
going around current wires
it's just a convention
i want to show you
how a magnetic needle
response to the current
i have here
a wire
which i'm going to run
a fabulous amount of current something like
three hundred
and you're going to see the wire
got my lights right
now i want to go there the way i want to go
OK to optimum
like there
when i draw current you see
the magnetite the recall of the composite nowadays and is lined up in the direction
of the magnetic field of the earth
we're going to run three hundred and PD through here
and it will change the direction it will change the direction
which is is one of the magnetic field around the wire like this
will go like this
because that everyone is so high
things began to smell smoke within seconds
the better is not going to like it when i draw such a high current
i can therefore do it only for a few seconds
so this
on his will
swing is direction and it starts to oscillate i can keep the current so long
that it stops the oscillation
so i'll stop by hand and conventions that that's really
equilibrium position
so if you're ready for that
so we get now
watch it
three two one zero
now stop it because still going that's so that's the equilibrium position and now stop
the kernel
and now i will reverse current
the opposite direction
now you will see
that it swings
on a degree in a different direction three
two one zero
it goes
i will stop it
two seconds that's equilibrium position
now let's go
so you've seen that in the
a magnetic needle responded
to the magnetic fields
that was produced by the way it was the great discovery virus that
the discovery
this demonstration all by itself may not
very spectacular for you but historically is of enormous importance i would argue perhaps the
most important demonstration the most important
researchers ever done in physics because it connects
electricity was magnetism it was the foundation of the creation of the whole concept of
a field theory
actually people's minds reaction
and that means
that if a
wire that runs the current
has the force on the magnet
then of course the magnet must also exert force on
the wire
and i'm going to demonstrate that the u two
i have a much more potent
magnet which i will use this one
the mechanism of move so heavy that can move so now we only see the
and the basic idea is then as follows
as it goes in
the marginal distribution of the four investigations is also goes in
and the ratio of two gaussians
it is also against
and for all of you are going to be working on these sorts of models
you have to do this by hand once in your career
OK but
if you want to build this afternoon in the laboratory but
what we end up with
is that the posterior distribution
is also a gaussian
it's a multivariate gaussian with a mean
which is defined by
this thing here so what is this what envious of
this sort of information matrix we saw yesterday plus
well we've got component related to the likelihood
and components related to
the the prior
and then we have the projection of about observations onto the coffee
and the
covariance of this goes in is just this term here
so we know characterize the posterior
although the model parameters
given that we've
got this independent prior
so this is great
why is this gate well i'll show you just a second so here's a little
example where
generated some nonlinear data
and here is the
this is the is the true parameter values point five and then about minus point
so as i said place the prior
which professors w norton w one
to be zero so most of the probability density is centered zero
clearly prior is not terribly accurate
after we observe data
we then get a posterior distribution which of course is multivariate gaussian
and now we see that the mean value
has shifted from the mean value of prior
well with the actual truth value
and what we see
is that the was a number of things that we see here in the posterior
possible see that i've truncated this one which should obviously extend further but
just to get everything into one page distributed between plus minus one but what do
we see well the first thing we see is that the uncertainty the uncertainty posterior
uncertainty in the value of w know it
which is the
intercept value and
a lot less
then the the scale values
the data has been more informative of the
the intercept on the scale
but the other thing that we notice is that there is no covariance
so there is no correlation i posterior already between w norton w one
and that actually makes sense because they are generated the data was that there were
cross hands
was w norton w one so the posterior no really
captures all the information in data
and all the residual uncertainty
from our prior
so this in many ways is much more informative than the the likelihood
based framework
now what can we do with this why is this so nice
and the maximum likelihood framework of course we take the maximum likelihood estimate
and we put that in to obtain predicted values
and we were able to get
moments defining our our uncertainty
but now we've got a whole distribution
posterior distribution where we can leverage or we can marginalize
overall of uncertainty in the the possible parameter values
so it means no when we make some predictions
so if you got some new attributes and we want to be do prediction for
the target actually is
and what we do is we take expectation
of what our model predicts
conditions so there's an expectation with respect
two our posterior
and because i chosen not very nice prior and posterior which admits to make scores
for then we find that the expectation of a simple linear model
prior posterior expectation of the prediction of our simple linear model no boils down to
just averaging
all four the values of the random vector w
over the posterior
i have already seen that we can get
an analytic form for this
this expectation
which of course is just this here
that was the key
at the end
and likewise
the posterior predictive variance
is just a simple matter of computing these posterior variances
and because the posterior is analytic then all this is analytic as well
so we now have
so our posterior mean
posterior predictive mean
and the posterior predictive variance
so this is all very nice
and again this handles a very
formal way
all of our uncertainty
and also handles in very far away
all of the
assumptions that we have made explicit
and defining our prior and this is very important
we don't lose sight of any assumptions that we've maybe we've we've been forced to
to explicitly
define what our assumptions are when we define our prior
so from my perspective this this this framework allows you to to put some reagan
and to not lose track of of what the assumptions are new model
for those of you who managed to stay awake
yesterday will recognise that this actually looks very similar to the maximum likelihood estimator
with the exception of this term here
so this term as i said corresponds to the ratio of the variance of the
likelihood of this is the
the variance of the
the prior
so what does this mean
well it means for example
in the case that you see when we are trying to predict the class label
small you get for cross products between clicks potentially as you can see here but
you can also get
a more efficient parametrisation of your problem and then maybe you can
you can actually so basically what you can do is actually you can read parametrize
the dual
with in this new representation and then you get more efficient
representation of the dual this is for instance what ben taskar did another listed in
his original paper
where they looked at cases where we actually they could we palmer tries do all
without using a cutting plane algorithm of o'brien selection of they would we parametrize it
then it's you know low dimensional enough they could actually exactly solve it
OK so that of course if you can do that and it's
it always depends on
what do you mean by tractable right it's more than efficiency
consideration here then that is the preferred over what i showed you before or
or it's not preferred so it's more of
performance tradeoffs and of course you the nice thing is that you really get an
exact solution so even you wouldn't have to worry about
the absolute intolerance although
that's kind of numerical noise at some point
so this is then also how you can set up for instance if you want
to do
basically something like conditional random field
with the label sequence as you know label sequence problem
similar to an HMM structure
you could basically define kernels as follows just try to indicate that here you can
have these dependencies of pairs of neighboring labels so you would need to define
a kernel function that takes
one of these pairs and another these pairs and another sequence and how you could
for instance define it if you want hmm like nearest neighbor type of dependencies it
should be one
this this this states agree and in these two states agree OK so basically what
you're looking at then is
the same pair
of states that are neighbouring in
in the sequence right and then your that with what you're what you can't always
he would be i mean the kind of functions strictly with i guess would use
counts as overlap but
anyway this is to simplify the middle so you could define a kind of function
like that over these types of cliques
and you could define a kernel function over cliques that are of the form input
output and the other being the
there's unobserved state in our sort of label sequence
and you can say well that if the state is the same
you define to be some kind of that you just defined over the input whatever
you want there
and then is zero otherwise
right so
using that you can just very easily construct these kernels that correspond to these interactions
you can also easily figure out ways of how to generalize so for instance if
you want to change HMM to have a dependency between input and in the following
right then you get clicks that are like that
three notes like this and then basically what you would need to do is you
would need to say well if you have you know one such clique in one
and another clique over here
how would i define the kernel and for instance then you could say well you
use again the kernel defined over the inputs if
y is equal to you and why prime is equal to you prime so if
you observe the same two labels here
and zero otherwise
and then basically what you have done is you've incorporated these types of dependencies into
your model
so this is just one example of how you can make use of this idea
of of the compositionality
in as motivated by markov network yes OK and here's the slide that i thought
i didn't have any more
it's basically then what you can show is
if things are nicely decomposable over
basically the way i think about it here is not coming from a probabilistic model
per se
but i say if my function then f is decomposable over an undirected graph sort
of in the sense that it decomposes into cliques functions the the maximum complete subsets
right of of the graph
then i can have a representation as follows some over i some over cliques possible
values of the cliques and then i have a parameter
a bit
i c y c and is that is much much smaller than
the total
state space hopefully this right because the cliques are relatively small and i have these
things up instead of multiplying the cardinality of these guys right
and then i have this part here which involves the current right so this is
another way of getting sparser representations there's some papers here that have explored this lafferty
and there's more work since two thousand four when two thousand three and two thousand
four when i first formulations have that been presented
OK so
so to summarize right so there are basically two ways of solving the structured prediction
problem one is
where you say well i have this black box that gives me the argmax
and whether that user some decompositions
of the function that sufficient whatever does i don't really care can also be something
and then there's the way that is more in the spirit of and then you
use the
basically the cutting plane algorithm right to generate these constraints using the the black box
argmax and the other approach would be my outputs right i can nicely decompose and
the dependencies are then only within relatively is kind of small i get relatively small
cliques and then i can use that approach and basically we palmer tries do all
and then hopefully solve the dual exactly k then i don't have to do that
constraint generation thing i consulted dual exactly
OK and these are these are basically two options that you
this is another clique so basically you know in
many independent you know
you might not always talk about the same clique right so if i have a
it's it's it's basically you know if i think about this sequence would have once
again another so there is a click click here see that is a pair of
nodes and another clique here that the parents don't you might just say you don't
care where you see the pairs of nodes train and then you just this function
k CD which has always been the same
it only this do you will pick out the specific variables that you need on
the other hand right so it's if i've seen whatever labelled c you know state
one two
in this sequence and one two somewhere over here
right all i'm saying is basically then
and i now have some overlap right because i found the same that that's kind
of in this definition here
the likelihood and then you get your your your solution
and then use of is doing
what you have your posterior
then you're and then you're done
but now
what we use the posterior for well
you can make you can use it to make predictions about what's going to happen
in the future
how do we do that well
the prediction that we want make it wrong make the probability distribution over what we
have future outcome be to start
the random variable
note that your
you can just write that has now
i have an interval here of the x dark high
and you high given the that when you multiply these two conditions get together
you get a star
given the the joint probability
x star
given the
and then i some out the high variables
that is the probability of x target p
this is exactly the thing i'm looking for i want to know
what the observed data
tell me
about what's going to happen in the future
note that this is not something this is not something i invented
just writing down the thing that i want to know
OK and then i can expand
in this particular way
by using the joint probability of
x starring high
given the
that can be written in terms of product where one of the time the posterior
you the term here is that just like your functions
the probability of an observation even
all right so that means that in in the and the thing you simply you
simply work out
the the the probability of the thing that are interested in you just use the
rules of probability
notice also that the that the posterior distribution
that is the probability distribution of the thing that we that we interested in
the parameters of the model is not a problem you know what data
but the data is considered to be fixed here
actually observed that has has a particular value
that that we observe in like that
and i think notice here is that the
that the region here are are averages over different parts of
but the problem with actually
you actually take the prediction
here and new average together
based on how much you believe in different
you might have so also
they seem unlikely
we have some weight in the control
the more likely they are the way have
the more likely one of the more
and the one that i have problem
we have larger weight in the simple
but you can pull them out like even if things have to have low probability
might still be
will be the true
you just had some unlucky
observation but they should also be taken into consideration
this also contract between
the maximal ideal setting where you say well
i believe that my problem has this particular value k over n
and i disregard all those things because they're not the most likely value
OK so a little bit more to
who's who
in the in the bayesian game which is related to model selection
so what say anything about model selection the frequencies
i think
come back to
how you can sort of two things like model selection but innovation
england's game it sort of it sort of
it then a natural component inside the inference
whereas in the
frequencies setting
you have to do something from the outside you have to sort of
you have do something separate to figure out how to do
model selection of tried to come back to that with a little example
OK let's say we have we have two different for different interpretations of how the
world became
now we make some
what makes observations and we want to know
which one of these models
is the right one of which one seems to be the most likely one
given those observations
it was repeated questions about
the question is
in a in classical music you can you can prove their properties about these estimators
for example that in the limit of a
acquiring an infinite amount of data and you have some notion of consistency you have
she put a will be question
do you know what it will because she this just
makes the sound of a lot of very loud farts
the person who told everyone the story with the companies yet
he was very proud to be married to someone like this
who is very proud to be married to a woman who put clear plastic wrap
over r one person super so when the person picked up the soup and try
to drink it went all over the person's lap
pomposity had to be handled in a certain way
but she and
are on the outskirts of paris
she became
more and more the character an alcoholic and
everyone would tell me that she was compulsive about getting away cigarettes
she would at first given out individual cigarettes later in life she gave backpacks
and i met a waitress
in southern france who told me that in the early seventies should we send giving
out entire her cigarettes to strangers
i have no explanation for the compulsion
only that it was part of a r
she told you
with the medium right in their bedroom she complained about it
but at the same time the core was designing private he was designing publicly his incredible salvation army building
ah which gave a great sense well into the urban poor
but then a private house
for the rich land
on the coast of
on the southern coast and france nearer to long
i learned there
and then demand the
rich woman who commissioned this summoned him to visit
she was furious
because there was saying
one on the living room floor
he took the training data from paris walked in
look said
and then do you have a clean
piece of white paper yes
she handed to him and he made a perfect model boat
he put the model boat into the pool water on the floor
floated around is that you see it works
it's quite shocked and then he said look don't you never waste my time like
that again here in engineering architecture you should have seen the way they were doing
those stories it shouldn't be my problem and in fact
he went to america
are we said that he complained about the height the skyscrapers his ultimate experience with
organism but in fact what bothered him about american skyscrapers with he saw them as
an example of capitalist greed and competitiveness and the captain of sunlight from getting into
people's lives as everyone tried to build the next week rather too close
what was very well known and
which i had the privilege and finding out after a few years of research that had been foundation
suddenly said to me
that you notice that for about two years i've written my bike occur
library three or four times we don't research and now
she wanted me to read some files product but
i went into a room i was told that i could show these files to no one
i couldn't make photocopies and i discovered incredible love letters
between the court lucia and the woman tighter paris
all things came from part of connecticut very near to where i grew up and
she was the reason that he often went back to america
it was a twenty year long romance
tells us
rather fantastic making a little island
in long island sound of the connecticut short
what player he was he went to chicago
and the day after frank lloyd wright refused to meet him he was so upset that he
hiring prostitutes one of whom took this picture of him with a room service
don't understand
this is a picture of his beloved marguerite when he left the united states
very very sad to see her ashore
in the late
thirty thirties
he was swimming
yes entropy when he got into it to recognise boating accident
you must create his letters about this accident he wrote his mother the most meticulous
description of the surgery and he describes the accident as if it's an architectural detail
why go underneath the boat
how he did the propellers how his name was practically severed why the boat
which was a yard
didn't turn around because they're rich obnoxious people but only humble fisherman stopped for him
there are always low enough so that they could pull them on board and then
about the wonderful treatment he got in the central state hospital and how the nurse
who brought flowers every day
and dropped him with rubbing alcohol
which is the essence of what human being should be
here he is with his car that he was quite right after the accident when
he was in these act painting murals all over the house violin great
without the authorization act
are widely available in southern france
on the roof in switzerland
this to me
the hardest part of his life to come to grips with it
i discovered that for two years
time and again he wrote letters
from these she
this is the only photograph corbusier
at these
he made every effort to work with ten
his mother referred to whereas
came as look on polish all the man who would save france
in nineteen forty two
he stopped working with attended by nineteen forty five he was changing charles two goals hair
even reading the dates of the architects
from here who are in his office
i was thinking about the office closed in the beginning the war was involved in
getting it reopened with the information out
the he she authorities
right so you have some over the vertices
of an expectation under the marginal whatever function you have at that node
and you have sum over edges
an expectation over the joint distribution
on the edge of whatever function you have on that edge
OK so what i was saying before is what we actually have is general family
of entropy like functions
and this parameterized by what way to put here
if you put weights all equal to one
you get something that's called the beta entropy that's well it's implicitly in the work
of hans from nineteen thirty five but the inside of yedidia freeman and y sin
roughly two thousand was to recognise that there was a connection to belief propagation
so that's well derive in a minute but i'm going actually derive the connection and
more generally for any choice of these weights
and the reason that's interesting is because when you put all one here
you get a function that's neither concave or convex it's very hard if it is
very hard to say what it is on a tree it's good it's concave
but the many have cycle funny things can happen
however if you use weights that have been derived in these ways that i was
describing for instance by taking convex combinations of trees you always produce entropy is concave
and because of that the optimisation problem and the derived it's called the bay problem
will always have unique optimum
and you can make algorithms converge to that optimum
belief propagation because it's an on
well non concave maximisation are known generically non convex problem you can't say anything about
you know whether you're getting max or local object so that's that's the advantage of
convexity in general
OK so
you've got two pieces so this average energy you sort of thinking this is the
function when optimizing over these marginals those are what's varying
it's the function of the marginals
the data is that came from your problem that's
fixed by your data set function of the marginals we're going to do is optimized
it is the sum of these two or the difference
very bad with signs
and optimize
the sum of the difference evidence it's going to be positive weight on this and
we're going to do it exactly over that set of constraints that we've been talking
about over that local marginal polytope
and because of that the messages in some product organ and i've been like
the branch multipliers again i in this case i'm going work through the derivation with
you because it's nice alexis size and lagrangian duality
didn't even talk about the origin duality
OK so so i want to use the writings and things like that
OK so the problem that we're going to consider is
this function that defined
OK so i'm not going to reiterate the functions in shorthand but all we can
refer back to them when we get going on the derivation so we're going to
do is i'm going to maximize a maximizing overall these
marginal distributions one for every node one for every edge
and i'm going to maximize
the term that involves the beer entropy
the term
which way is it
minus entropy and it should be plus
right so
we now also consider elaborated picture recently introduced and
the first come to it is so i will probably actually multiclass problems data storage
is given you is first of all we had well separated by class classification problem
then introduce support for you can map to this high dimensional feature space is the
data is mashed together
of course many real world problems you have many classes on come on to that
but only briefly
another thing of course is i mentioned just now that you may have a data
point which is well away from the rest of the data
it could be just a correct point but rather unusual or it could be an
what i wanna do is avoid the influence of outliers so then i will introduce
this idea the soft margin
which are added some knows this morning just to make it more formal then we'll
move on to other things like regression OK
the first of all
many problems involve multiple classes and we have to have a means of handling this
and if there are a number of schemes for multiclass classification using SVM
svm nicely set up bond classification we've seen that picture
leeds quite nicely to a convex optimization problem and also welcome set up for multiclass
to be honest
and there are indeed a number schemes for tackling
and i imagine it just can give you one will be the ideal introduced was
actually done by nello cristianini and john platt
so we years ago in and it's paper OK
now so the schema give you will actually handle small
if you have a small number of classes perhaps six of them then it should
be OK
now i did introduce the idea of
have introduced how you do an SVM for binary class
one of gasification two classes
indeed if i have done that then i can actually handle three four
o five class relatively straightforward and the idea
and i'll give you is directed a cyclic graph and
the the principal is as follows suppose fact have three classes one to three
and what i do is i make a decision
is it o one or three
suppose i find this one
i made the decision is one or two
suppose i find one then this one
here is the two i go to two
and similarly if i decided the three here
again go down the other branch
now what you see from this is that each step here
it's simply binary classification
and indeed
then the story of gatekeeping gave in the previous lecture for binary classification just supplies
so you can actually do binary classification this way
coded this up and it worked OK in practice
one of the automatically notice k is that
if five and a large number classes perhaps a couple hundred is going to be
a big tree
there's not a good idea
if god of the classes but first one of the classes OK
and easily connect with the binary classification
the they introduced earlier on
if you have many classes
quite honestly i would probably use an SVM but
what many people do is simply one against all classification
there have been other attempts to do it more elegantly
but to my knowledge
and none of them are really being
outperforming one against all
so one against all will be simply do one against all the other classes OK
so that's how i might approach it as i say
but the classification of small number classes streams are very nice
if you're talking about several hundred classes might be tempted to use other methods are
perhaps marjoram is a multinomial probit model or or suchlike
but this is how much do multiclass for one of the classes as long going
to say about multiclass so got a lot of the things to cover
the newspaper is just as essential idea around about
two thousand NIPS two-thousand
giving this
yes does it and it did number experiments and induce the theorem as well
each of these is just a straight binary
as introduced this morning
right that's what saying on multiclass they want to come onto is soft margins now
we've already had
when she says picture this morning of two classes OK
i had this and nicely separated data
my hyperplane was light so well life is not like that and generality and my
i have a guy here
perhaps open here
OK and indeed what he would do
is he would tend to push
the hyperplane into unusual orientation OK
indeed it would now be something like this
from saying is
points could have undue influence on the separating hyperplane i said earlier in fact how
that feature is as they have actually large alpha values being in really quite significant
job demand
that i could ever remember in my life right
companies are dying to get their hands
on on big data people
on data analysis people on data mining people and this includes banks
tell close
insurance companies
you name so i think you notice and i agree completely with all and this is not trying
ok yeah so
before we have two perspectives talk about your first or
the first of the two right
you tells like getting hired to link then that as me a river pretty big
startup startup never nevertheless
yeah that's right
so it was the beginning of two thousand and nine it was kind of
preheat stereo data science i guess
and i was approached by a small company name that phase book and they ask
me they they said that there are more building data team
and that they were looking for people my profile to kind of
the the the senior
person on the team
and my i actually
my response was know like you know it's
it's a small company it's a it's trying to by teenagers pretty much ok and
yeah and actually i wasn't phase look at that time i kind of even
connect myself to the value proposition phrase book
but that opened my mind to questions like that so
it's obviously to it's obvious that you know
social networks
war future at that point now it's like you know the our
everyday life
and i actually was really connected to value proposition of in matter social network
to the value proposition of
keeping your professional connections and knowing about what's going on the field and finding a job if you need
so i ii
i wanted to work for link team
was very surprising null link people are well connected
but id know anyone that
i linked game
so i basically went to their carrier side an applied
that's what idea and i got to me that and three years later right actually
well i decided to move back home to israel and it's a different story
we talked about this so so that you have an opinion on whether it's better
write a
hindsight is twenty twenty look like if it had been facebook you enjoyed it but let's just generalize
you know to say
what you think about joining a company
is still preoccupy all still very much startup
but is established
versus starting a very small early stage are early stage star you have an
opinion on
this for you which one of those as prefer
yeah i do actually i think so we can kind of to make some type of calculation right so
i think that
the it's very hard to optimize our life right but say
if we want to
do some very interesting job and also optimise for making money after all
so the function the objective function that we probably would optimize something like reward multiplied by the probability of getting
there's a war right
and and if you have this this function you basically
weak we can i say look at both sides like say are optimising for reward
right we want to get the biggest reward probably
a lower probability of getting a
best definitely to found the company right if l let's try to do i'm i'm i'm
trying to make a model just
on the fly
which is that if you find the company
and it's a successful company you can make something like that
down to
what's likely to happen when it performs an action
and from the characteristic function can compute expectation
not our expectation is have what the utility is with expected utility is
what's funny is that well
well one can can try and what is it
is the concept of
of information that one can community which
gives you some
what you should try and do
in order to get the best information order to act
so there are
there are two things one can do to try and get the best possible result
if you don't know very much
some things may be much better to do than others
and to have much idea but you may have a little bit of an idea
that was the best thing to do
right so
the distinction between rationality and science
so you know since
you know what's going to happen
and if the nineteen seventy and
it wouldn't be
maximizing expected utility
because it because and i was going to happen to be maximizing utility
so the difference between the main difference between rationality and this is the expectation
but the course i didn't and the sea and so we we have no real
way of achieving that no or we in fact
the point here is that the rationality
and you can be rational still get into trouble
and it's an example of such a thing that can happen
you walking along the street
and you see a friend on the other side of the road
and you can see that there are no cars
and you will start to walk across the street
the comet your friends
the rational thing to do
because of the different cars quite safe
there's a lot going across the top
this case was this form of
right so that i just wasn't missy otherwise damage did
they behave rationally
according to some reasonable definition
mesh well
couldn't resist performs recent definition of performance measure
so things may still go wrong but it can still be rational factors and can
happen to him human course
well autonomy
we expect these ideas to be
autonomous autonomous
to a large degree
effective autonomous the better
the ideal thing would be to
but i just was environment that lot of the performance measure the list
the typically
the agent designer has to do a lot of knowledge in
at the beginning
in fact it's one of the
the biggest problems at the moment you have to do so much and it's very
hard to get very far
so we want to be able to act autonomously decide what's the best thing to
given a performance measure
and act accordingly
and we really want
i just to learn
this is a really key idea in fact this is
in my view
the most important problem to solve
if we could find a way
of creating edges that could learn their environment
we can do that i could design and architecture
is sufficiently flexible and powerful enough
i think that the listening environment deployed in the learning
then we have effectively so much of the problem in fact this is the way
humans work
humans are programmed
they come with an airborne they can with a certain
basic architecture
in fact the brain it's got everything connected
pretty much
as a child goes through study part of his life
and experience is different things
connections in the brain change
and they get taught by their parents to get all the people they watch and
and eventually become capable of many things
that's a good analogy
what you want to do is build items
got an architecture that is capable of doing that
in fact
you can reduce the problem to that response is capable of doing it finished
everything else follows
give my enthusiasm
you don't want to have
three particular application the agent designer
putting in detail information about that particular application
what you want is the generic architecture
it's an architecture that can work in number different environments
it has got enough built in
and mechanisms to learn to adapt
so they can be trained
you can learn from this environment to deploy
it does something that you can tell it was bad and so on and so
and eventually it's able to
i very well exactly the way humans to
right task environment
so let me just introduce them
really is terminology so this
two pages of this system terms should be aware of
the first one
so in a fully observable environment
from the percept
the agent knows exactly what the environment looks like
and there are some simple cases
such situations
and typically example would be
so playing chess
you can observe the chessboard
and from that percept
you know
everything about the game actually is not completely true
x thirty
one of feature
because they
this is a good place to start counting
history but anyway it's time point roughly speaking the chessboard
that's good
much like this is modified
it's it's fully observable
partially observable means that this things going on the perceptron tell you about
that's the typical situation
deterministic versus stochastic
so in deterministic
the next states completely determined by the current state
and the action to perform
so there's no probability distribution you
the next states completely determined
OK good morning and thank you for
very kind remark
the younger
learning and told you the subject is supposed to cover today
it's the memory
i put up here
neurobiology memory
how do we acquire
information from experience
how to
consolidate it
also how to retrieve it
i'm also
director of this MIT's center called The Picower Center for learning and memory
so this centre is now
eleven faculty members many of them
lecturers in this course in the DB
in fact even [unclear] is a member of the Picower center
Marc Bear, Earl Miller
and so on
i want to go back to step back a little bit
this is ninety three
if the fifteenth anniversary of the discovery of the DNA double helix
and what
so there has been
many celebrations going on throughout the world
this is really in
what is called the molecular biology nineteen fifty three
and we come a long way obviously fifty years
from posterior year to the
completion of the focal human
genome project has been announced
and we now know
the entire
nearly entire sequence
all bar about thirty thousand genes there
human being has
now the human genome project also
extended to other
species such as the chimp models
four try
and brown wall while c elegans
and you can see here the the approximate number of genes while
and also
DNA sequence similarities
between one of these non-human species human well humans
as shown in here we have whatever their race is we've belong to
we at least ninety nine ninety nine point nine percent seven was
a brute force is also
we even very similar to chain ninety nine percent twenty one percent
this is a similarity in colder regions and called
the areas which is known to
called approach
and therefore
one meaningful for the function
that although it looks similar
most of these communities are manifested by
what what one might call
physical features
the way we
this is entire organs however internal organ functions
how the immune system works
those things
very similar between
three species of mammals
i wrote road gritting roads and as
in got involved in some of the wants better than human beings
nevertheless we dominate
the planet
because i one
the other half of a function with the mind function
much more superior to any other species
in terms of understanding
mechanism in general
it's my mental
there has been
interesting views on the history
so this is a picture of an attack on french seventeenth century
he view
well we can
this kind of my
by i and by natural science
is sort of
summarized in this wonderful paragraph
so he said people with the bodies
like machine capable of being studied by the mass of the the physical sciences physical
sciences with the natural sciences
but the full
by source also
but that's OK that's fine
so i i basically built the likelihood is going to be just the product of
these things and then finally this is the quantity that i want to maximize OK
so let's just do that
right now is one one
pulls up his sleeves and the
goes for all right
for convenience
let's just say this is defined the concept of parameters OK
OK so we first we first take derivatives with respect to the means and the
same as we leave the pie case for later the reason is the phi kz
little bit trickier
because we're can now take derivatives back to them but we know one thing
we know that the sum of the pie case for k goes from one to
capital k has to be equal to one right
so that means that we have to be a little bit careful here we take
derivatives so what is it that we need to do
exactly we to the lagrange multiplier OK but
we're not going to do that on this slide with that in the next slide
or or two OK
OK fair enough let's now say
let's just call generic name theta for the things want to want to take derivatives
with respect to just make it simpler and see how how it's going to be
OK OK so we want to take the derivative of this with respect to theta
far enough what do we get
we have
some outside over the data points and then we have the logarithm of something OK
OK so we can see that the sum outside is going to stay
and then we're going to get
you know the derivative of the logarithm chain rule so we get one over the
and then we get the derivative of what was inside the logarithm with respect to
expected to write a c
this state is this by k here
and stick it together in here then you can really see that this is what
was inside
inside the this the songwriting so the terms of the sun
and now
so why why did this some disappear that's because we're taking derivatives with respect to
the parameters of the case gaussians OK
so we need to go and pick a specific goals in since it refers to
things that are specific to girls right the mean and covariance of the case component
so that means that
once to have one over the whole thing then when i take the derivative of
what's inside the logarithm with the decay of this some i only need the corresponding
element OK the others the gas only then that mean and covariance
for now now i can take the pike k i can take it outside because
because by k doesn't depend on the mean or the variance right so i'm left
with this expression here
and i'm left with expression and i'm very happy because i'm taking the derivative of
the gaussians to remember
PIK is is the gaussians in right
with respect to its parameters and i don't like that i i i like taking
derivatives of of logarithms of gaussians
but that's OK and now
this is one of those moments where
you're doing your ratings and all of the sudden
magic happens
so how does magic happens
well use sort of
he sort of think about it a little bit
and then you remember a good old the rule of calculus you sort of remember
so it is written that abraham just right gonna rise again so if i have
a certain function
and i take
the derivative of this function
i know
that this is equal
two f of x
times the derivative of the logarithm of f
with respect to x right
and so
since i wanted to take
the motives of the logarithm of mikkelsen
not just do that
and then i think of it i'm gonna now i'm going to have this term
that that comes out
that's actually a miracle
it's fantastic to get that out
now why is that
it's fantastic because now this guy comes out and all of the sudden
this term here
has a meaning
it has a very very clear meaning
now what's that
let's think about it
one was
pi of k
by of k was
right supply of k was the prior probability
that's an indicator variables any of them was going to be equal to k
and what was pi
i k
well i k
was the probability of the data points
the indicator variables was k but what this is saying is is the pretty of
why i given that i have chosen the case goes in
but now
what can i do now when i can compute the posterior distribution that can compute
the posterior
why i what now is
the probability
one the probability that that the i th data points
belongs to to to the to the component
once once of seen and given given this two things so it's going to be
according to pi k
i i k
but now what did we learn about computing posteriors
we will learn that we need to renormalize right
because now this thing is not going to add up to one and how does
it in which space should this add up to one one should add up to
of s
divided by road
which is now
to the square root of one of the land
not have reversed
so now we see that the larger the wavelengths the smaller the phase velocity
none of this of course is intuitive you have no feeling for that i have
no feeling for that
what i'm asking you in problem set number six
it is to prove that in this case
the group velocity is one and half times the phase velocity
not all but that's what will come out
the group velocity was half the phase velocity
and the phase of the phase velocity
was larger for larger wavelength here it is reversed
and the group velocity is one-and-a-half times the face falls
shallow waterways which is also part of the problem set and on this person not
so intuitive
so if very shallow
what are weights which means than that
the amount of water that you have
the height of the water is substantially lower than the wavelength
then you get non dispersive relation which is not always easy to of course
in this room
it is not this person
thank you
imagine for a minute that the high frequency
will travel was substantially higher speed my low frequencies
then only the people in france you knew what i was saying in the one
in that had no clue
because the higher frequencies might arrive much earlier than the low frequencies
you could not
make sense of what i'm saying
imagine you go to a concert
if there were
it sounds very dispersive
you have to pay a very high price for the tickets in the front row
and the tickets in the balcony they would give them away for free because you
would have no clue what you're listening at any
because the different frequencies of the violins
and of the base
what reach you at different times
so we are fortunate that sound
in this lecture hall is known this person
the next lecture
we will and the domain of electromagnetic waves
in other words
you're going to love it you're going to see maxwell's equations
i know you love maxwell's equations you remember it to the good old days
and we will we will derive using maxwell's equations
that there is such a thing as electromagnetic waves and that they move in vacuum
with the speed which we call seen in physics which is three hundred thousand kilometres
per second
that can actually be derived
so in free space
that means in vacuum
electromagnetic waves
i know this person
call c timescale
and on the specific relationship
so to frequency
or electromagnetic waves
it's a discrete of light defined by lambda
and so we will encounter was eight o three radio waves
and we will actually produced
and let's say we take a frequency of about one megahertz
thirty six hertz
that will give you a wavelengths
of about three hundred metres
you can use this equation
if we go to radar
which we have right here in front of us
the frequency is about ten gigahertz
to to ten hertz
so we have wavelength
of about three centimetres
and if you go to infrared radiation UV wavelength
of tens of microns
and if you go to visible light
you get frequencies up to five times ten to fourteen words
you get wavelengths of about half a micron
when you go to ultraviolet and x-rays gonna raise the frequencies go higher and higher
and the wavelength gets shorter and shorter
non dispersive
in vacuum all
exactly the same speed
light in glass
or in water for that matter
it's not known this person
it is very dispersed
as we will derive
in all three
speed of electromagnetic radiation
this seems
divided by the square root
of the dielectric constant kappa e
and the
relative permeability kappa and
which may or may not recognise from your eight two days
and in vacuum
this is one
and this is one
but that's not the case
four water and that's not the case
four class
and in fact
that he e is strongly frequency dependent
so if i take water
as an example
four its kappa and
it's very close to one because what is not
ferromagnetic materials and all materials that are not ferromagnetic
in some direction
and the environment for you will be able to
so roughly speaking if you're working in a regime where
once you find a decent random variables completely determined that almost all fully observed learning
and then you might want to job almost optimal if you're rich you have a
lot of the neighbouring variables even given the parameters that you need very should you
take the first or second
o point eight slice let's try and consider the other places so for mixture models
was for discrete
the cluster or expert assigned
but you can have one causes the data which are really small but there are
like continuous degrees of freedom so if you think about the video example suppose my
body is not a discrete continuous to vector
because the best knowledge continues
geometrically the way you can think of this is your data lies in some subspace
for general curve so full
inside the meaningful coordinates there are telling you about the underlying causes and what you
see is that the inside an awful lot
so you people
these the word factor to describe these kinds continuously variable
and to generate the first generation within the manifold factors in
because many generations
so the coordinates in the internal
representation components of these
so simple
this form is called factor analysis can very all from statistics in a very simple
after i switched from x and z two x y
during his
so the very
and he observed variables y
i think you can get from that and so on
imagine this still alive
it lies inside higher dimensional space
so here's three and a half hours
in terms of coordinates x y or dimensional space pictures two so the model very
first the internal for causes x from guassian
and then given that in terms of you take a linear function that most of
lambda anyway so need to this is the mean vector and the
axes this subspace here are on the
during the
that gives you your data vector y
and on top of that you have some
so this
matrix is called the factor loading matrix name comes from the fact that loans
the factors from factor is into data space
and this no
here is is called sensor is usually that one
think of it as a measurement device which measures
y one y two y three one of those devices
that's only and the way
is that
remember that the product of two gaussians are still
and so
when i take this small compute the marginal distribution y
the marginal why is just
so this is just a fancy gap model for y
so you might think well what would having this will invariably here x if is
more likely to get some of my life not i just a small development of
and the answer is that
the effective covariance marginal density y is highly constrained
so integrate actually to pursue analytically marginalize what you see that
it's the gaussians
with mean mu it's surprising and covariance which has is very for it's the our
product of land
the land is
rectangular matrix has
as many homes as
and many
the the original surface
here's rank
as some of the rate matrix was
so this is a very constrained form now if you think about high dimensional space
thousands of millions of dimensions you know there's no way to estimate the variance matrix
has been
thousands or millions square
so it's very important when trying estimate gaussians
high dimensions you have some ideas for ALL
so i just race this year and happened at all your brain
but that can any correlation between the variables
four so this is a simple way of to model correlations between the variables using
not very many
five years
so that
constraint gets all its ideas were not that all
then this which just reduced to eighteen
just we want to win the ministers also we typically think of science being that