actually serious but that's okay
but a series is called
arithmetic series
wow that's some sharp people
can communicate
this is arithmetic there serious are basically summing one plus two plus three plus four
some constants in there
basically is one plus two plus three plus four plus five plus prospects
up to and that's
they have an square OK so if you don't know this map
this chapter in the book
or you could have taken the prerequisite
prior arithmetic series people have this vague recollection i
you have to learn these manipulations we'll talk about it next time
OK but you have to learn your data manipulations for what
works with data to be very careful because is a weak notation
so strong notation something like like its notation from calculus
where you the chain rule is just cancelling two things in the
fabulous but you can cancel the chain rule OK
OK let like this notation just expresses that so directly you can manipulate
data notation isn't like that
if you think it's like that you're in trouble
you really have to think of what's going on under the theta notation and it's
more descriptive notation
he is a manipulative notation there are manipulations you can do with that but unless
you understand what's really going on under the theta notation
you will
you find yourself in trouble
and next time we'll talk a little bit more about the notation
so is an insertion sort is fast
well it turns out
for small and it's moderately fast
OK but it is not at all
the large
i mean you know fast
especially of insertion sort of
we're not
one right on this later
OK so you taking notes
leave some space and left
here's were sort
of generating a from one UP
and basically three steps
if n equals one
we're done
sorting one element
so we started
alright OK
so recursive algorithm
otherwise what we do is we recursively
a from one
up to the ceiling of and over two
there're a
of the
ceiling of and over two
plus one
OK so we sort to has the ability of the
and then three we take those two lists that we've done and we merge them
and to do that we use were subroutine
joshi a
he subroutine here
it works like this i have to list let's say one of them is twenty
doing this in reverse are seventies i sorted this like this
and then i sought another one
no i do this order but anyway
here's my other list
my tool is that i've sorted
so this is a a one up to a ceiling of another two and ceiling
event over two plus one up to a and the way it will be called
in this
and now to merge these two what i want to do is produce a sorted
list out of both of them
what i do is the first observe where is the smallest element
of any two lists that are already sorted
so in one of two places
the head of the first list for the head of the second less
so i look at those two elements
and i say which one is smaller
this one is small
so what i do is i output into my output array
the smaller of the two
i cross it off
and now wears the next smallest element and the answer is it's going to be
the head of one of these two lists
so then i cross out this guy put him here circle this one
now i look at these two guys this one smaller
for about one now look at these two guys out our
every step here
is some fixed number of
of operations that independent of the size of the array e step
OK each individual step is just me looking two elements and picking up the smallest
advancing some pointers into the
into the red
so i know where the current head of that
that list is
so therefore the time
these were and
one in total elements
the time to actually go through this merge
since then minus two
call goes down to we end up with order one down here
what's the height of the tree
what's the high in the tree here
every step we're just documenting
the argument by one
so the height is an
OK so to analyse this let's first
up everything that's here
OK so this is just
as we understand what these things are coming from
this is just data
of the summation
OK equals one to and
actually of ck
so that's what's in there
and that's equal to
order and squared that's right arithmetic series is coming from
that were in square
and then all of these things here
are all they want
and how many of them are there
their were and actually and data ones
total amount
ran out of space
the total amount will just use appear
two and
it grows
have and
a square
and that's just equal to that events where
so just
to see what the structure is in terms of the
recursion tree
OK so highly unbalanced recursion tree
now i'm going to do something i told you should never do
which is really the best case analysis
OK so this free intuition only
in general
we don't do best case analysis
doesn't mean anything
once we get some intuition for maybe
basically it means nothing mathematically because it providing no guarantee
and so this is the intuition
so far really lucky
what happens
for partition
what's going to be the lucky case
yes but
all right in the middle
k which is essentially
essentially and over two
and over two
trillion over two and minus one or two ten minus one of the two but
we're not going to worry about the details because we're only doing intuitions
the best case because best case is not what we want
so if that happened what's the recurrence that i get
imagine split exactly in the middle every time
and then what happens
so you see that
two times t over to go on
plus the order and time for partitioning bouquet
what's the solution that current
that's log and that's the same as merge sort of occurrence
OK it's which case the master theorem
the case two
and log base
i of two
is into the one
the same so we attack on the extra log n
case two the master theorem
it more
he did it
in two pages just two pages of notes and some years ago i went to
see these things and i was expecting that the discovery the atomic nucleus would be
in leather-bound notebook with gold-leaf writing on the outside and i had to go through
a lot of
security to allow to see the things and then i realize why they brought me
some sheets of paper
click together
nine pencil
obviously have been about myself to raise a few things in my bottom that but
it was very nice was actually quite amazing i want you to imagine so seeing
these things for real rather than these copies because it shows the genius relevant had
and we were all told
several the probability that the beam scattered through this angle that angle and we set
students' examination questions on it and we know it takes twenty minutes to answer and
only given five minutes to do it
was how we did it in one line
and what he originally did
i was not think about the alpha particle scattering through random angle but very rare
occasion but it bounced right back
and this is how he thought it through
maybe on the next slide with no unknown OK but large and yet half MV
squared off in e over b you recognise half MV squared that's normativity econetic energy
on the right hand side is the product of charges divided by distance which is
you probably recognise
electrostatic potential energy
and what i was doing was very simple he said that you're
we now know atomic nucleus sort of positive charge
and here
and alpha particle also positively charged is moving in towards
he uses conservation of energy and nothing more
when alpha particles very far away from the atomic nucleus
it's not feeling an electrostatic repulsion in the distance is just too big so the
energy of the alpha particle is completely connected energy half MV squared
the new NET nucleus the more electrostatic repulsion fields to it slows down show
its kinetic energy is dropping
because the electrostatic
repulsion of potential energy is growing the sum total stays the same but the energy
is changing from one form to another tonight's moving again
sure and stop it here
this instant the alpha particle is momentarily at rest it has no kinetic energy the
energy is now totally potential energy the product of the alpha particle charge the nucleus
charge divided by the distance
and that is what the equations
half MV squared the total energy when it was far away people's court to charges
distance when the
came near you could get
he then has the higher mathematics taking the distance of the left to the the
top and so forth and put the numbers in those
the next page on the right-hand side makes a mistake using cross something out
that it highlighted that is long vision which the teachers understand what i'm talking about
the years ago by the students and the clue there was a time before pocket
and that's how we did it and that's how he did it
and imagine that you have writing on the page and you've got
to this point
you putting the numbers in for the first time are going to measure this distance
this is not the size of the nucleus but it is a measure of the
distance on which the nucleus lives
and he finds
six point six divided by ten to twelve centimeters
something of the order of ten to the minus
forty metres
ten thousand times smaller
found the size of an atom that is the moment when the villagers realize atomic
the positive charge in an atom is concentrated in a very small region and the
same excitement in because it says
since probably radius of atom is of order ten to the minus eight centimetres it
is seen that distance of approach to charged centre is very small compared with radius
about that is the moment of discovery
and look at that line again it's very small he's writing is so fast that
it hardly to the horizontal line that is the moment when he realizes
that's the eureka moment
is there
designs how to test this idea by causing geiger mars to work looking at a
whole range of atomic elements measuring scattering from different angles so that students can answer
complicated questions in years to come but that is about the discovery in
metaphorical as well as literal sense he really got to the heart of matter that
that language so all these features are monolingual
i do that for the other language to all these features are now target label
OK so now i've got these pairs and the things really going to make all
this work is canonical correlation analysis i'm sure is familiar to all of you you
may or may not be aware of the probabilistic formulation i'm sure most of you
are there too but i can quickly illustrate why i'm talking about CCA here
if i just had a bunch of vectors like this in the source space
right i might use PCA to describe them to represent them in some way
if i had a bunch of words
features in the target space and the use PCA to describe them too
the problem would be if they actually had pairs they came in pairs like they
do in translation
again the projections onto the subspace will be arbitrarily really unrelated
OK so what i'd like to do is i like to somehow find representations for
the data that correlates them and that's what CC does as i'm sure most of
you know
what i now get like these subspaces where these things are correlated and in particular
in the probabilistic formulation of balkan jordan what i can do is talk about there
being a single language independent latents space
the gives rise to these language specific concepts
OK so this basically means of latent space that i can wiggle around concepts and
out pops source and target translations
OK i need to model the model is very simple i generate source for a
bunch of slots resource words i choose a number of target words
i choose the matching
now i've got some pairs and some unpaired words
for each of the paired words i'm going to take a point in this canonical
space which is language independent
i can get choose that according to some simple distribution
i'm gonna projected to the source and target space
which with some transformation vector that of course i have to learn
plus noise same on the target side transformation plus noise
and that's going to generate all of my parents items
separately i'm going to have some noise model and the source that generates source items
and i'm going to have some noise model on the target to generate target
how i learned as well
and this my friend
so i might want to obtain some posterior matchings that turns out to be bad
because that's intractable and i want to kind maximize my parameters but even if i
had this posteriors i wouldn't know how to find those projections that turns out to
be bad but it turns on this case hardy amies might even better friend
we're finding the best matching is easy with fixed parameters i just look at some
kind of joint likelihood with some with noise
models factored in some way
and if i had to fix matching that i would have paired data even if
it's wrong repaired
and then i can find these parameters of the projection using CCA
OK so what do i do
quick experiment and then that'll be the end here
it is i take the two thousand most frequent nouns i take some text from
wikipedia so they're not translations but they do contain some of the same stuff
and i might or might not take a hundred translation it turns out you don't
need this these experiments have in the evaluation is going to be some kind of
the precision at some recall the reason why you recall o recall like thirty percent
because that's as good as the baseline seventy do
OK so if i use edit distance on englishspanish which is particularly easy case
i get sixty one percent because there are a lot of very similar words especially
if however i simply use features of the orthography
this kind of alternating learning with and ccn matchings gets meet eighty percent
so does looking at the context without any information about the spelling of the words
at all
this is surely context
if you put them together they stack
so this is a huge improvement over previous work which was not able to be
the edit distance based on
here's kind of precision and recall of edit distance drops very quickly is you get
out of the space of cognates
precision is much higher for much longer with this matching CCM
you might say that's not fair started with some select seconds well what happens if
we just take the lowest edit distance words as the seed
it turns out that works almost as well
o thing somewhat robust in that case
and the last thing i want to show you some examples of what's learned because
i think they really need
so these are the most confident non identical matches of course the most confident ones
the ones that occur in the same contexts and there are also identical string identical
here's some cases that are more there that are of course the cognates
for the spanish courses are going to be at the top but you are non
sports practice something we will allow that so please stick to the sections and right
now we're because the birth of burgeoning enrollment we've opened up
some sections of these three are underpopulated so if you'd like to switch into one
of these three
they have
very low numbers right now there's we've added an extra one eleven
extra one and two
and we've added one one o'clock
if that nature schedule
are in a better manner than
i can do it but only with permission from hillary glory
oh by the way talking about on one hundred rolled
subjects the complementary subject offered by
called history society and solid state chemistry needs two days on thursdays at eleven
two one thirty six
it is underpopulated right now so if you're still shopping for
humanities subject this one bears the pressure CI i h designation
think about that if it's a question about the time that
then perhaps raise with the instructor and see if if you're talking to smaller people
i suspect
enrollment is going to be
doesn't so
it could easily be
re-arranged if if the time is conflicting one of the other classes
three on one is different
i give homework as learning a i give homework and you see you have more
questions with model solutions at the outset
i want you to learn why
studying the homework i'm not going to have you
work long hours
on difficult problems to be submitted and then great
i don't do that
part of this is designed to
get you to start thinking about the transition from high school
the college
what i mean by that is i want you to take ownership of your learning
so i'm not going to come around and say did you do your homework
good evidence that you didn't do it because you didn't turn it is
so it's easy
it's easy to blow it up
and and those of you have a lot of chemistry for the first allows the
lottery going get complacent
don't do it
develop good study habits the homework is good
test that
make the time
to work the homework problems
but just to make sure to stimulate interest
every tuesday
in recitation there will be a ten minute quiz based upon the content of the
so if you were to problems
do the homework quiz handling
if you haven't looked at the homework problems might have difficulty with homework with
there is no homework grade based on turning homework in the the homework portion of
your total grade is the aggregate of all of those weekly test scores and you
must take the test
if you fail to take the test you get zero and i average to zero
if you don't make it to class
contact your CA your recitation structure and you can take a make up within a
week at the time of the
the original test
i want to give you every chance that
get caught
it's your education i want you to take ownership of
so all scores counted no dropping of lowest scores from the average
some of the other class is perhaps to do this
people have actually confronted me telling me it's an MIT rule
i've been here twenty six years i i know what the rules
OK so you homework is only number one
so it's assigned today
you've got the model solutions
and they'll will be a test recitation
on tuesday the fourteenth based upon
at homework
it is based upon the homework sections so i don't want somebody coming in with
an attorney sank
well the question looked a little bit like thirty nine but it's not exactly
i think you don't say
let's continue with the administration
in addition to the weekly homework
there will be
monthly tests
monthly tests and they've all been scheduled
so you can plan
monthly tests are the following dates
september twenty nine
october twenty seven over seventy
the test will be written
the normal class period
i know your you
harold is bonding and orientation period but you know i think that it's much better
when you write a test for there to be some solid state defects known as
vacancies in between the various people so when on the day of the test will
have shadow rules and will divide some of your writing here and some of you
right some of the other rooms which arise during the class period of fifteen minutes
likewise the
VHS running from
one o five one fifty five two different tests
of comparable difficulty i did this last year and that's the
the difference in the scores on all three test was less than one percent
so i think we were capable of
with the kind assistance of my
staff capable of sitting exams of comparable difficulty
but again you be required to go to the world
the assigned otherwise we don't have enough seats test papers and so on
by the way on the tasks you will be getting tomorrow these handouts that you
can use in working horse
so when you're taking the test you're allowed to bring in and
the copy of the periodic table of the elements
we give you a very rich
table of constants that's got all kinds of things from the mass of the electron
four age and for car power we have three fuzzy
fuzzy sets for age young old or middle-aged whatever you call that i prefer to
consider myself normal instead of middle-aged and then car power
so medium and high
every everything below if you could the forty seven horsepower and then somebody is medium
sort of the golf to see this and then appeared to get all these highly
tuned cars and then our output but he also loved the three membership functions could
be more doesn't really matter low medium high risk but we've been doing if it
was a different story got this into some sort of a premium calculator that uses
this fuzzy sets all the should pay
two in the next year or something for his insurances
but that's actually something we'll talk later about OK and then the fuzzy rules that
describe a here if age is young and car power is high then risk is
high is sort of this imprecise region of right and then and then the than
the guy is sitting down here in this is barely eighteen just got his driver's
license and has form of course our portal to the inheritance from his dead father
then it's clear this rule is fulfilled to a degree of one there's no question
about that so we don't need to bunch down here some of the areas are
got a little bit because to be but actually he's be
thirty three years something so we assume he is a little bit of sense so
maybe should really get such a high degree of fulfilment for this particular rule so
the world still holds the two very low degree right so we have this grey
zone here with the world stops stops being true and tried to paint here another
will saying bonds ages and car power is medium these tools will also overlap in
this country space and the some area here we would have both will be true
to degrees
that's one way of doing it
the other version are again come rules TSK rules where the antecedent again is a
conjunction of fuzzy membership but the consequent is simply a real valued function
of the input variables
i'd say taking some sort of a linear function or sometimes pollen on real function
five degrees of some sort of pollen on degrees are to do
one of the input variables
again here my drawing capabilities
and so very well we could looks like like something if age is young and
car power is high then risk factors some rates zero plus
w one times age plus w two times car power to have some sort of
a little local model that we use in this area
and here
painting three-dimensional surfaces it's not really my thing but anyway so he would have some
w zero here are some offset the risk factor this is our function w one
times age is linear function with respect to have linear function with respect to car
power w two times car power and then in fury for this world then they
will high young sort of down here is true he would get some sort of
inclining field to end up these three things see if offset w zero here and
then it goes up with this slope along
the axis car power and with this slope along risk factor in the middle it's
next sort of have the minerals surface that becomes activated when that will destroy and
that was the old people like to use these types of models even though they're
obviously not it's easy to read the previous one i mean the previous one something
centimeter risk high need to interpret these are easier though to just stood up to
date and that to right because you can actually fiddle with these parameters
OK so the point morris we can have sort of mentioned earlier you can towards
so of many many fuzzy rules that you're building for example something like if age
is young and car power is high then risk is high age small and car
power is medium then this is medium is that the standard driver normal ancient old
guys then again get high risk so but how do you draw inferences from such
such systems rules
if you can plot both of them
next to each other we can essentially
planning our measurements we have some some values for inputs
well first of all OK this just the membership functions that are of interest for
one young high and high for age car power and risk normal medium medium age
car power and risk will are two so that's just illustrating here but what happened
so you have these fuzzy fire crisp inputs
so we are now measuring something never client walking into our insurance company is eight
is twenty nine years old he's he's trying to get insurance for a car that's
a hundred and ninety what parts whatever it is a small downscaled corvette we need
to figure out the degree of fulfilment for these rules and then somehow combine
these and this consequence of this is what do we do first the first thing
you can do is find degrees of membership for these fuzzy sets we can find
out well how much does he belong to the set of young people how much
does he belong to the set of normal people how much does it car belong
to the
so the medium power cars to the high-powered cars
that's easy that's what they did before i just use the fuzzy sets to compute
degrees of membership so that the degree of membership to the set of young people
point eight
but i'm going to talk about is
given an image like this one
we want to build systems that are able to interpret what is going on here
there are many things that you can do with a picture
for instance you can the segmentation
and you know so the object label in you can find it put labels to
objects that on the picture
you can also give a little description of what is going on this in this
is a nice view of power canonize spring day you can also try to do
much more high level interpretation of what is going on the picture like this some
people walking on the street there is some life in the that science saying that
just remember feeling that that's probably this guy doesn't know how to read so that
a lot of inferences that you could start making all this picture
you could also belongs to the data representations connected to be
model of the scene and infer that that's exactly on top of the graph the
people in the shadows of the trees and so on
in this tutorial i'm going to focus mostly on the recognition by there are many
of the things that are not important in this assumption standard but i will focus
mostly on condition aspects
why is that we can all recognition of course we can see the three d
of a picture book and a lot of things without having to put labels to
but when you put the label something this concept of category encapsulates a lot of
a lot of knowledge will be able to do it tells you what can you
do with the object but functions can accomplish that object for instance for this animal
here looking at the laptop probably he has different intentions that what you will have
to drive looking at the laptop
so if you can see the three d he knows until the surfaces that are
building this computer but you know what to do with it
in fact the perception of function
is really something fundamental innovations so this is a quote from vision science book of
parliament in which he says that we include perception of function as a proper congressional
subject for some reason science so this is what i'm going to focus mostly about
and of course the people that think that the condition can be not necessarily done
through labeling but you can actually do the perception like this is the theory of
and give some in which you will
look at the other will extract some information about the surfaces that compose this scene
and from that you can decide things like OK that's not some sort of the
four is at the right height therefore i consider it in the or theory is
the mediated perception and that's the categorisation
you will take the picture you will start some properties from it you will recognise
that this is the chair and therefore you will conclude that can sit on it
and you know it just something like these kinds of devices such as this is
the chair but is this is chair
certainly can sit on it but probably other people will never happen to that
and some aspects of an object function can be perceived directly
and there are some some aspects of the function of an object that the directly
come from the shape it has notified concept sit on top of something the fact
that something can contain some liquid for instance that you can cut with some device
all those kinds of things that you can infer that from the shape
so here you could decide that all these have surfaces you can sit on but
sometimes noted that surface in which it doesn't look like you can see but there
is still a chance
i also like like just seems also have affordances they also have functions like you
have three kinds of scenes one is going to tell you that you can
you can write on it and only the college here another one is the place
in which you can have fun with your friends and then another census in which
you want to lie down and you see these fluffy piece of cloth you want
to just lie there and sleep so it also has functions
in some cases the function of a single just like an object can be also
be perceived from the from the shape of the space has like in this case
you see especially when there is basically only one thing you can do you can
only move forward so in this case the space is telling you what you can
do with it
here again you see an open space the space is telling you that you can
run very fast journey to recognise what it is you will just do it
and there are some aspects
that of an object of of function that are going to be of service dependent
so you can not just directly inferred from object what you can do with it
like the case of the of the data
from a couple of the idea of what to do with it you can find
all kinds of things on the web now
so propose perception has many limitations so one of the limitations is that in some
objects may have very similar structures and is still very different functions this is a
picture taken from the book of byzantines book parliament in which two objects they look
very very similar both have a hole in which you can put things inside but
they have very different functions
the bozeman is not suspect in for you to put rational this one here
so i you put the latter in this one he certainly is not going to
rise to the estimation
so there are many different functions
and again i go to the web to confine people that has been a mixed
here is another example of a scene
like an elevator if you know this is an elevator
well this just looks like a box you can get inside and there is absolutely
no reason to believe that you will get everyday life and i don't have them
unless you know what it is for
so the perception is not going to work most of the cases you really need
to recognise things
so i'm going to start with a very short introduction to object recognition because you
know this way is an important building block in this way we just get rid
of it as soon as possible and get into the interesting things
so the first question is
OK there a lot of people walking around is shown in the first question that
we may have this is this really difficult task is really so hard
so let's say that we start with the model of an object like this one
and our goal is to find the chair on an image like in this one
and so the simplest thing that you can do is to a scan
looking for the chair at all different locations and scales in this image so the
simplest way i can do just apply normalized correlation template matching in this case so
just take a window
and this is a very standard started in detection is called the sliding window approach
and we just by normalized correlation to each location
and at the end you will get an output
with a peak
the location where the object is and in this case you know you detect the
object but it was supposed to be because you have a perfect copy of the
idea of trying to find
of course place my the two are generally much under the same idea
just by normalized correlation just don't get anything
and this is when i was making this you always have this
moment of being afraid what happens if it works how to use the final fifty
years of research and of the commission with of course it doesn't work it just
by normalized correlation of a template like this is just give you garbage none of
what happens next
it still
relying upon
a more powerful mechanism for the interaction with the world
it is
this is not good theory standpoint
but it's essentially
as it what we know how to do it
OK so
it turns out that if you just have a generative model
it is possible
the perfect samples
in order to learn this natural policy
it turns out
the process of getting the samples is a little bit
rotten sense of you need to
query this generative model many many times
the way is
the very first action
sample k time so our case some prior so this is the first action so
i go here and then i'm going to do something go here and i'm going
to do something go here and then we do something stiller again was first action
then for every
primary result of this first action
for every next possible actions
use case things k times again
and then very result
in every
next action he things he times again
this is a very exponential tree
so we're going to actually initiate and both the set of actions in on k
so this is something like what the tree looks like to force you drive because
it it kind of explodes too fast as opposed to actions in case four
there are four times you keep the first action
and then depend upon each of these outcomes
you have
two actions available to us to each action four times
and then depend upon these outcomes each action four times of three
can only draw down two
is inserted
actually visible
so the i'm assuming for now the generative model is is true
generative model it as
actual has access to this this the
you can of course relaxes so little bit to have some approximate access but to
pretty good proxy access
it's true
and guess
the meaning of noise is a little bit
but suppose that
i have the time
machine learning summer school if you look at the door and then walk left there's
in half the time if you look at the door lock right this food
and that is sort of interpreters and i suspect two the learning as long as
which way to go is not
maybe the
the world itself is deterministic
but your lack of knowledge is treated as
it is
this is the probability of the outcomes
i think there is something
important to think about here which is
but we're always trying to come to think about our this work and the worst
it's not really clear that
the world is a very adversarial
and if we can
better think about how to capture the fact
it may be that we could get better analysis
so i guess in particular if you if you have an actual deterministic world
what happens is
you don't need to
simple k times
right two disconnected state of interactions in our actions and k
OK so we have this huge super exponential tree right
and the question is how do we actually
there are one of these samples
one is positive samples
what we do is essentially we run
we run this dynamic programming step i talked about earlier
on this trip
which are the bottom of the tree
taking expectations
so at the bottom of the tree
we're taking action and what to throw and then
we got our reward associated with each of these
different choices
so we taking expectation
for fixed actually taking expectations over the rewards we observe
right this is going to be a pretty good experts on this case reasonably large
of are expected
and then we have another action
and then we take the maximum over these
and then
we back up the tree right so
if we take
this actually end up with this history of observations
we know
which action
we know approximately which action
to choose and we know the value of that action in terms of expected summary
were suspected once every word
and then
one or here
look for each of the soviet union action
and then we have the next step
so we know the expected return
if we end up with that history
so in the expectation over
or the expected returns across the reward we observe taking this transition
and then we take an axe over the actions of this quantity
you just back the tree
we've done and
but there are some constraints
in optimisation problem
what is our constraints
for every one of these local function
the sum over access should be one
why because local functions in the case of vision that the probability function
factors here
in the case of vision that the conditional probability function p of access
x i give
is a conditional probability
so basically
what happens is that
these should be one
four bayesian networks for all s for all sets of children given parents
the sum of children given paris one
so you need to enforce the constraints in europe timisation problem
holding force the constraint optimisation problem
the end
lagrange multipliers
who has heard of lagrange multipliers
who remembers what they
it's very simple right so basically what happens is that
adding a lagrange multiplier if you want this quantity
two if you want is to hold
these constraint called
the trick is the following you just ride this constraint
this quantity minus one equals to zero
anywhere that into the optimisation problem
you're not changing the optimisation problem because you've added zero to the optimisation problem OK
and then you multiply that zero by some london
as you you need one lambda for every one of the additional terms that you
now we have another
to solve
so essentially now
you have to solve
if the as in the fourier london well
now the equations that you have the following this is the first question you're going
to zero sorry there's a problem here there should be is you have to do
is equal
these gradient should be equal to zero
this guy goes to see we've seen that we get these expressions and is one
so have as many of these equations as there are cliques
or in this case as there are sets of children parents
but we also have as many constraint equations as there are
children that so we have two times
here as it is just the number of
click on in this case the number of sets of children parents
how big system of equations
but what about what
um in fact
we are going to log off at OK
know that
that's right
the result was just
we need
to enforce here
the constraints on theta
so basically if they cannot have any value this probability distribution on one's true
it needs to be positive as well
so let me
see what the
OK so this OK cities later just r
but essentially you don't need to enforce it is positive
the moment here too
going to be just representation of the image and so you have like a filters
into a different orientations for scales and you divide image into four by four b
is just going to have five hundred dimensions and that that is going to be
your presentation for the entire image
basically this is very similar to SIFT but instead of being applied to local patch
is applied to the entire image of the ones
another the idea is to
use textons
here are what people will do so this was introduced by jitendra belong to show
the large and david is that they can emerge japan this image through a banque
of filters
two two different orientations in this case and also with different elongation
and at each pixel you're going to have a bank backed off if the responses
just like a means
to all those filter responses to all these vectors on a a very large database
and just douglas a hundred cluster centers
and those are going to the find your basic atoms
and then now when you have a new image what you do is you apply
all these banker filter do look for each location what is the center plaster that
this kind big excel and we'll histogram
and that's going to be integer for that image and now you have two images
the comparison will be dealt with something like a square or strong intersection
and that's what how do we compare images
similar idea is just about awards and special pyramid matching
so here are people choose be visual words interviewed by civic system and and basically
here the the idea is that you take
the image to like SIFT descriptors to compute c descriptors at all locations
and is the same idea but with text and to take its pick so the
SIFT descriptor defined vectors apply k means
and then it speaks of place the pixel value the color value by the the
index to the cluster centre that it gets closer to the descriptors
so that what you will just representation
and the way that images will get described is you image this is this called
scale send the colors them in this to the cluster centers
and so you will have a vector that is the histogram the council how many
times each particle of what appears
and then you can divide also the mentioned to by two and create histogram for
each window this will give you some idea of the spatial distribution of the pictures
you can do this in a finer grain and you get more histograms and then
we can concatenate all these different descriptors and that will give you a description of
the image that contains both global and local information of the picture
so the question now is OK there are all these different representations they have very
similar flavors all of them and most of the details are really technical details there
is nothing conceptually the about what is the difference between these techniques although the performances
differ by greatly because of these details but the question now is OK call for
tender go on this task and you have to do scene recognition using this kind
of descriptors without having to explicitly is precisely represent objects
so one of the benchmarks in order to test this task is the fifteenth in
category is said in which the advertising categories here they are offices skyscrapers oberst building
for science goes forest and so on
and this episode has been put together over time by asking the one and then
fifi and marketing reasons relentless and make them more categories against
to get to fifteen categories and the task is given an input image you have
to decide which of these categories it belongs to
so here i'm showing the performance is that you get with a few approaches in
this case and combining a pyramid match in the GS about awards and just using
pixels just arbitrary values for the fifteen scene categories here performance will be like that
one now
values of the confusion matrix
and you can see the
OK pixels do very badly
so i do values this doesn't do very well just do as imagined by the
doing this is the so surface what difference between color values that doesn't do very
well so is good is that we have room to improve with the structure and
and when use the approaches they all do more or less the same
and what is interesting is the the latter part of images that they find difficulties
and very very similar to the same categories have found difficult by the same by
all all the models so they all call it a lot
the performances fluctuate between general ten percent and so on
and here is just showing another plot in which a show
recognition rate as a function of number of training samples
where we have collected statistics about car accidents in rainy weather
so we have two random variables again
are being
or not train
car accident or not car accident
and again we have to wait of
raising this joint probability distribution as the the probability
training given that it's
the brevity of training times the probability of having x and given that it's raining
probability of
excellent given the probability of
rain even accident
this one
it doesn't feel natural you could estimate if you have the statistics you can go
back and compute the probability of rain given accent
counting the number that thing to say OK this state was training testing out but
it really doesn't look like the natural way of doing things so
there is that we prefer one of the two
the composition like being more
so the one that is showing
our believe and how you it should be
he composed and so again
we have this graph
we a
node representing the random variable for the rain and one four
the accident
that's what happened when we have
three random variables
now i have collected statistics for car accidents in when were and also
i have statistics on my neighbour going
two the movie the other when
have tree random variables
the rain rain rain accidentally accident and is my my never going to this to
the movies or not
as you can see there is six way of
the composing this joint probability distribution by applying the
for the role
let's say i i i order
the random variables
and always the same procedure two
to decompose it so taking first and last
the first the last variable and so on
so i can have rat art track and there's a lot of physics
but as we saw previously
there is in fact only two of them that makes sense
my way of looking
so the the ones
which are
i have to rain first and then have the probability of having x then given
the range
and the probability of going to the movies
all that the property that may
neighbours is going to the to the movie given that there have been an accident
and that it is raining
which doesn't make a lot of sense
that it seems that two unconnected to
and so in fact
we don't want this link
so there's there's
another thing missing
which shows
kind of conditional independence
given the range
having an accident
and that my neighbours go to the to the movie
it's it's not connected
this graph shows this independent
finished example
our defined directed graphical model is more in general
so i directed graphical mothers
which of course are composed of nodes
representing the random variables
and of directed links
representing the conditional distribution between the random variables
terminology if x is is the parent node of y
why is the child node of x you have this
this is graphical representation
we're not consider whatever graph
the graph that are using probabilistic graphical mother directed the grammars are direct that are
a directed acyclic graph
with that is that graph we have no directed cycles
so here
as you can see i can go from one
now to another
well tell me all about the easier
i mean the whole lot
what is the null space for this
it's all vectors of the form so what could what could be it could be
one one minus one
it could be
any numbers c
and number the same number again
in other words
any multiple of this guy
that that's a perfect description because
the zero vector automatically included because they would be zero
the vector i had is included because he be one but now any
and that's actually a
and what have you i was
and what does it look like
so what how would you describe the
knowledge space this
all these factors of the form c
the minus the like seven seven nine
minus eleven minus eleven plus eleven what have i got here
if it describes the whole knowledgebase on what if i drew it
what do i
a lot right
no spaces or line is the line through
it in our three
and the vector the long one negative one maybe goes down work goes down here
the vector
one one negative one if you gave me
and where the vectors these the negative see it on the fly
of course there is zero zero zero that we had
and what we've got them all
the whole life
going both ways
really are
and all places line north korea
for example
find all the
combinations of the columns the behaviour of that size
i just
take one more
go back to the definition of
vector space
and as you
how do i know that the null space is about
how and why entitled to use the word phrase never
space without meaning
two requirements are set
can we just said that they are
so i want to check that
i continue here
he was all
a seven
and the course the keyword
what do i have to that
i have to show that if i have one solution call
another solution college
that there's are some is also a
that's required to use the word base
i have to say i have convinced myself
if they are zero
a star
zero or maybe i should have said if a b is zero
and a w is zero
then what about the place
so i make use of
if they really were
and a w zero
then what
then what is the what if that and then what my
o point here
that a times
plus w
must be
that's the
but at the
and w the null space then there from the plus w mills and of course
now i've written down totally absurd ridiculously simple
matrix multiplication allows me to separate the two
eight people as they don't
i should say for very simple that was the done thing to say we use
a basic law of matrix multiplication
actually we used without proving it
that's OK we only along the
i thing it's called the distributive law that i can
let's please
with this in the two pieces
but but now you see the point
the a b
it is zero and a w zero so i have zero but there are get
and similarly i have the
to show that if a b is zero
a kind
any multiple say
well the
how do i know that
because i'm allowed to
bring that well that's a number a scalar control
outside psi as well
a b twelve heroes
it's really critical to
i understand the
and what of my what i was going to understand what the point of vectors
let me make the point
changing the right hand side
OK i mean change the right hand side one two three four
and that's what's called the agency theory and that puts human beings or possibly robot
at the centre of the stage
causality there is about
bringing things about
it's about what you can do
to bring about some desired and intervention agency getting in
the fiddling with things giving them the kick
and seeing what happens
so causality is about response to what what happens when you kick something
that actually solve a lot of problems to solve the the problem of which is
the cause of which is in effect
if i could q when you scream
i had the control over the k no direct control over the screen it is
obvious the kick off the screen and and not vice versa so they may be
constant conjunction but it makes an asymmetric different
so we've got to work very much with that agency conception of causality
and finally a very statistical point of view very important is that we usually interested
in comparison
not so much what will you do if i k cuba what difference does it
make whether i q or not
maybe if i don't kick you'll still screen
so i got to know i'm going to make a comparison between two or more
different actions and interventions and the corresponding effects
OK so let's
think about
a couple of
queries which are least
indirectly of an obviously cause in nature
and so on the toy example is taking aspirin to cure had a so let's
suppose that kill counters that they had a going away within thirty minutes just to
be precise a binary event
so here's question
i got a splitting headache and if i take an aspirin half an hour ago
we need to combine
what is it that's what we have been caused my
i had a to get the other side of that would say
i had a headache half an hour ago
i took some astronomical will
is that because i took the aspirin
now that is what i would call
inference about
the causes
of effects effect has been observed the have had not got a headache it's good
state gone away whatever something happened a little while ago i i keep the system
in a particular way by taking aspirin or not
and this was the recall the relationship i know i know what happened to the
interesting thing in comparison with say a lot of things
theory of probability and uncertainty everything is the what happened is not uncertain all i
know what happened i know what the esperance of back to front but know to
the astrodome it's gone away when i don't know is whether the connections causal and
one way of phrasing that is what did have gone away
if i'd done the other thing is the contrast
now we have
the question is that also sort looking backwards over the shoulder well into the past
everything's been observed was the connection causal a different question is looking forward
i got a headache shall i should i take aspirin
will my headache go away within half an hour and in order to decide that
i should probably also think about what would happen if i don't take aspirin because
it is going to go away when hafner anyway maybe you don't know what the
so that is the question of the effects of causes
now i personally think the best distinction is vital
that these questions have somewhat different nature and they require somewhat different approaches
they're both quite subtle and difficult to answer
but causes of effects is at least twice the subtle and difficult once as effects
of causes
one of the reason for that is because causes of effects involves what you might
call counterfactual reasoning in order to think about what my headache has have gone by
now i've got to think about
a potential thing in the past which i actually know is false
i didn't think the aspirin i'm conjecture in something which is counter to known facts
cont counterfactual and yet i got to sort of take make some sort of logical
sense of this and tell the story which makes sense going is kind of difficult
to have a framework in which we can formulate a query clearly
well on on the contrary what i call a hypothetical
reasoning is what's required for thinking about effects of causes i don't ever have to
think about anything which is counter to known facts here i am with my headache
i can hypothesize i'll take aspirin which is something perfectly open to me and consider
what might be the consequence
so i can hypothesize that i refrained from taking aspirin which again is an action
open to me not contradict any facts and consider what might be the consequences i
could do those two things make comparison is true i can't do both of them
but i can only have to look think about one one
not the other one then compare the in some sense the
and that is my comparison so i'd like to make this distinction between
counterfactual reasoning and hypothetical reasoning a distinction which i think is almost never made so
i'm i'm i make a fuss about it hardly anybody does people tend to use
the word counterfactual for all sorts of different meanings in particular for what i call
hypothetical reasoning again i think just as it's worth making the distinction between inference about
causes of effects and effects of causes the different kinds of questions so
we have to distinguish between the different kinds of reasoning which going to the to
the kind of
causes of effects counterfactual reasoning which which is the context in which that occurs allied
to this was this was the
the main thrust not surprisingly the legal conference i went to reason they want to
so that's the that's the importance of having allocation plans
this decided upfront right i mean
we nobody expects these plans to be satisfied exactly when you're doing online service that
will be deviations from this plan
but still this provides a rough guideline of how serving in real time
and adhere to the
overall business object
you you can only decide optimality if you have an objective function so what's the
the the part of the problem is coming up with the objective problem function rather
than solving and selling it is all the cover coming over the objective function is
more difficult so what could be the objective function here
if you have more than one feasible solution what objective function should use
to come up with an optimal allocation that's the next question
so the optimality
correct again would depend on the goal of the network
OK so one thing
which is
important to notice
advertisers don't like to specify too many
to find grained trade and if you do that you don't want to say oh
i want to target males from fifty five who
drink coffee in the morning and wandering off enough that's not that's not the sort
of specifications jervis you expect from advertisers and the say OK i want so many
impressions from yahoo sports and that's it i'm done i should get good order while
the fall of former camp so secondly you know even if they do specify it's
not good for the for because they have to really forecast inventory and those resolutions
if you don't fall because there is no in the world can guarantee
impressions in the future access
the targeting is done that course levels that are done very fine resolutions
so i'm not going to
enumerate all the objective function or the optimality or objective function one could
having this situation where i'm going to just give you some examples
again i mean depending on the goal of that we give you an ad network
you might have different objective function but i'm just going to give
so first objective function which is very natural is
can you do some cherry picking right
so give the advertisers what they want
so for instance if you do that it's OK one one million impressions and yahoo
sports i'm going to make sure i give you the worst impressions on sport you
not ask for good in britain is that i want one million impressions of sports
and i know that all people visiting yahoo sports generally
i don't convert as much
as a young people so i'm going to see if they are the only or
people because they not ask
we do not specify young people
so that's called cherry picking right but it's not
if you start doing that you start hurting your guaranteed delivery process
so that's idea that you thought okay well i'm going to buy guaranteed
advertising and naive and to you know and as one million impressions all sports and
you give you a crappy set of users
of course if you look at the article i e o i could actually got
to the sport marketing board better things than this and so you might want to
come back and by getting to do so at the end of the day what
has happened is the hard quality of premium problem
so that's not a good idea doing cherry-picking is not always a good idea
unless you have a very clear of future demand the
that the team would be to spread the wealth
right so anyone
if you if anyone coming to sports asking for one million impressions used
you know you proportionally allocate all kinds of inventory and yahoo sports to this is
so you old people young people
and i asked one million impression that eighty percent of people twenty percent young people
i'm going to get eighty twenty location
so that's kind of spreading the wealth around right end that that's actually better
even if you don't even if you forgot to specify somebody find attribute is still
guaranteed to get certain quality of just
by specifying that you want things in the support but that's called the fairness const
i some of these papers were built recently there have been work done by by
our colleagues at all these things people is not out yet but it will be
these thing are reflected in the CPM price let i mean
under CPM price
i recognise the fact that not all eyeballs good right there are many toolbox visiting
our site you know if for instance if you have a very good for detecting
and if you start figuring reward very aggressively and
you see people automatically go high road the market is just to these things
so so at the end of the day and yes you buying in bulk buying
ads you saying what impression what you're buying in bulk and the price the CPM
price you pay is going to be reflective of the quality of inventory right so
a lot of users and use ad blockers then
in the CP will go down that doesn't immediately figure out there
this traffic is not good
so this implies that
the first part
i will not be affected so this only depends on the function
through its values on the training points of the cost function only depends on the
training points
and therefore
this is the value of this function c will not change
no matter what
part if the particular we have in particular if perpendicular with zero we would still
get the same value here so this this is not affected the knowledge of the
second second remember was this one here
and i'm going to show you that the second term is actually minimized if f
perpendicular is zero
and that's actually straightforward so we just right on the second term
again we substitute the expression of the function
expansion on the training points plus a perpendicular
i'm going to use the
pythagorean theorem of possible
the quality
so i can since these two parts of i can write its length is the
square root of the squares of the two
individual links
now the square root is a strictly monotonic function and also
on the guys strictly monotonic function by assumption
quantity here will be minimized if the second part is zero
OK so if i in
decrease this thing here which i can do i said in the second part is
then the value of one thing i will decrease strictly and therefore
the optimal value the one that will minimize this omega
it will be the one with a perpendicular zero so the first object function in
two parts the first part is not affected by a perpendicular to the second one
is minimized by a perpendicular equal to zero therefore the overall solution has the property
that particular is zero
so therefore
in this expansion here the second part of managers and the solution takes this form
which is actually the statement of the theorem
so the solution takes this form
what can be written in this form
so here's a little application
if we use this cost function here we actually recover support vector classification
so this is because function that depends on all the training points separately
this looks a little bit funny here this term but all that does is that
it it measures
the slack variables if you want so this is this one ensures that you measure
the slack variables
already once point enters into the margin and then this quantity corresponds to the SEC
maybe it's not important that you understand the details you can think about it afterwards
and quite communities nothing deep
so this would be the cost function for support vector classification and as the regularizer
we use this quantity here and then you get the soft margin support vector machines
which is not surprising because we already so as a consequence of the the optimisation
problem that indeed the
solution to the problem is in act
the expansion in terms of support vectors
you can also give other examples
maybe i don't go into detail on them
you can
actually these cost functions of this time
you can also reinterpret in in the bayesian way
by identifying this with the prior in identifying this term with the likelihood of the
and i assume you will learn more about this ferences because chris bishop
and then maximizing minimizing this cost function corresponds to what's what's called finding the maximum
a posteriori
solution of the problem
so let's go back here
so we identify this with the likelihood of the data actually e to the polls
this thing
and this with the prior
and then the minimizer of of function the the representer theorem talks about is the
so-called maximum a posteriori estimate on MAP estimate
another algorithm that's falls into this category of programs of the representer theorem talks about
is called kernel PCA and i think i spend a little bit of time explaining
it to you
as an example of of some non support vector kernel algorithms and in this case
we actually need a cost function that depends
joint union all the data in this since it's
each individual term here also has been effects from the other terms
so we've only done this one
so now we can
move on to further kernel algorithms
so all the the kernel algorithms have follow some simple design principles they all have
occurred and in addition some learning modules
if you want to so far the learning model has been binary classification two classification
but it could be
a number of things could be for instance feature extraction and that's one thing that
can PCA does not tell you about this just before i do this let me
to summarise what we've learned about the kernel so far
so the kernel
we introduced some kind larity measure on the data
then we prove that if this similarity measure satisfy certain conditions
namely positive definiteness
then we can construct a feature space and a mapping into the feature space such
that the kernel is the dot product in that space
so in other words the kernel is not just a similarity measure it also induces
a representation of the data in some dot product space
independent of whether the data of vectors to begin with or not so the kernel
also gives you data representation if you want and finally
the kernel also
in this sense parameterizes the function class of possible solutions to your problems so i
told you that
under this very general conditions that apply for all that kind of thing that we're
talking about
the solutions are expansions in terms of pounds sitting on the training points of the
curve also characterizes the function class which is actually crucial in machine learning function classes
you will find that john shawe taylor will be talking about function classes or concept
classes a lot so
you can think of these three years s three basic issues in machine learning and
some kernel elegantly
o addresses all these three issues simultaneously
so now let's look at different kernel algorithm which is not classification but for feature
rather than just
transporting means and variances as what we have for girls in random variable
he was just distributing propagating statistics are fairly arbitrary distributions in sending that through
it was a bit more complicated but the communications architecture is the same
things get completely missing
if you have loops
if you have that
this piece will be expensive to store
that was the brief excursion
now let's see how much we can get
the last bit
don't let you don't get fooled by the number of slides
it replaced
but actually there's a lot in
so will start the multiclass estimation
and then depending on how things go
well the max margin markov networks
or we look at the page tracking
here's trusted binary classification example
separating surface from stars
and that's the large margin solution
somebody asked when the break well
you can actually find this well
freeze into the mentioned
you just need to look for the points are on the boundaries
and you know that well
three points most will determine whether that separates allies
and out of which two points along one line another one will be on the
other side
so that's reasonably easy to do
you might have more points sitting there as a professor place of the point there
but it wouldn't really change things
the just rewrite things
and this is exactly why is it before some notation can be a blessing and
sometimes you can really delay progress
so what we have
find classification issues
well i got excited when wireless and i define the following marginal
are required for i've been one
excited w
as we grow to equal than one
x i n minus the
so i've done exactly matches taking original martin scale
by factor of two
now drop the constant offset just because of the
annoying to deal with
at the moment
and for wiping minus one i can do the same thing
now what has happened and basically saying
the large four x
and w which corresponds to class one
that quantity has to be larger
then one
in approach between ics
and the corresponding to class
minus one
from one class is one of the same thing
the margin forex in the class minus is one of the great within one class
w four class one
some of these are
let me write about the overall
i could an approach between i and WY
has to be greater recall than one
last in the property i w one prime worldwide prime
equal to y
so what i'm basically saying is
i want to make sure
for the correct class
i am at least
why one more confident
of thinking that one
then for all the old correct classes
and then i could just do inference
by taking the y for which w exi is largest
the question is this is actually conceptually fairly tricky step
good so
what i'm doing is i'm requiring
the value of w and x
for the correct class label
at least by one exceeds the inner product between w and x for the incorrect
class labels
fact in class that got in w
now want to ensure
for those other nine values
then product with x is smaller than for the correct guy
and he everybody classification access define w one three w
w minus one to be minus w
seven look at pictures
these three classes this trying to break
these will be some normal vectors
this these are the hyperplanes
anything in this
region here would be
class blue there will be class this would be class green
to make my life little bit easier after just constraints make those three to be
of the same length but in practice of course they wouldn't
and sorry
now what will actually to do is we need to define margins here will do
that in
so let's look at the general theory
rather than carrying the w around for all possible labels i'm just pushing all of
that into five x and y
i can do this by
it's a instance i have ten classes
for x and y will be just the vector of
all zeros except for that row
is relevant then it would be for fixed otherwise serious offenses for fixed in one
week before fixed then all sierra
five weeks into
it would be zero
then for fixed and then all zeros and so on
OK i'll right after the like four
but the key trick is this can be anything
i mean OK that sounds pretty stupid now what
in fact this is what people have been exploiting over the past couple of years
and pretty much free choice
of all x in y where people could solve it they've written several papers on
that idea
that's the
that's the mechanical analog the delta e reaction this is the driving force for the
reaction in the first place
the driving force for the reaction and EA in fact is the gatekeeper
it's the gatekeeper it determines the rate of reaction
because on the basis of e a e eight mediates
the rate constant so all other things being equal temperature
it gives you the rate constant through EA
and i will recall the other
temperature effect you say what she has done is any of this stuff happen if
if room temperature you know the room temperature energy is typically on the order of
about forty thousand electron volts i just told you that chemical reactions have an activation
energies on the order of one electron volt according that we have to be up
to thousands of degrees centigrade in order to to promote any chemical reactions how do
we get chemical reactions at two hundred three hundred degrees centigrade
what we have going on here is
the distribution of energy
the distribution of energies
and i will go back to that plot that we saw earlier here's
t one
here's the average energy
at t one
and over here is one electron volt or whatever happens to be the activation energy
and so only the fraction of the population that has greater than the activation energy
is able to participate in the reaction and we've seen before the measure of the
area under the curve from EA o to infinity is given by
the relationship EA
cables t
exponential of
and so
it was boltzmann who first gave us this
understanding and maxwell gave us the distribution and a way we go so what happens
by changing temperature we've seen before we change temperature
the curve moves ever so slightly so that the
the average energy at t two
forty two is greater than t one the average energy moves the little bit but
what happens up here is the area under the curve between EA infinity goes up
large leaps and bounds and that's how i
modest increases in temperature were able to get substantial increases in the rate of reaction
so now let's look at some specific
reactions of various common or someone look at first order which is the commonest unlike
its second order so let's look at first order reactions
first order reaction
so here's an example example is
in two o five decomposes to give us
and all two
o two so there's the stoichiometry of the reaction
but on the basis of
on the basis of
measurements in the laboratory we can write that the rate of consumption
in two o five
so this is the square brackets denote concentration
it's going to to be linear
in concentration of two o five or into two o five race the the first
power so this we say is a first order reaction and i'm getting tired of
writing into all five bracket bracket so i'm just going to write c
c represents all of this and compressing the summary rewrite this equation minus described by
the team
he calls casey so that's a first order reaction why because this is the one
that's why it's first order
it's linearly dependent the rate of change of c is linearly dependent on concentration so
i do a little bit calculus here if i i can invert this and i
can then right
minus the c oversee equals k
the two
and we're going to do is integrate this thing out so that we can get
the timeline on this
and so
i can put an integration sign here k is independent so can do that
and i'm going to start at time zero or have some initial concentration and go
to some arbitrary concentration see an arbitrary time t
so what i want to look at is this if i plot this is some
initial concentration versus time
we know
all of these things are going to attenuate i want to know
what this curve really really looks like
and i know some of you are saying or wincing secular your math professors have
told you can make the limits of an mineral the same as the value of
the integrand so i don't want to go to mass jail also put little tilde
is over this sort all the math we happy here is right but you know
what you could do what i could do to really make it pedantic is let's
not do that let's let's use the carrier variable so i'll make this as
which now you don't know what i'm talking about i'll make this c
and that's mathematically beautiful it doesn't explain what we're talking about so i'm going to
go back and put to sea
little tilde over it
so everybody now is happy
so there we go this is t
kind of parametric or global model fuzzy effects and then gone after estimating the parameters
here not that's not what we're doing we're estimating values of c one point in
OK so once again you have this data
and one very simple way to estimate the value of the scalar remember remember this
is just the scale of pixel value
it is to do a very elementary least squares
OK so if i just write this least squares cost function and minimize it over
the scalar psi xj
then the solution would just be the average of of the pixel values that give
rise to this not very excited
going one step further from this you might say well
this formulation actually gives equal weight to all the data
so if you solve this you just get the average so the weight in front
of each of the data points is one of ran
so why not give different weights to data
so that gives rise to
a weight function k
this is what we call the kernel
and and this way function is not going to make this weighted least squares problems
not terribly more complicated than before
the only difference is that this weight function is now somehow going to measure similarity
between the data points
which you have and the data points around it
and in some sense penalizes things that are not similar enough
to this location hand
OK now the way this particular function
is measured is going to give you a cacophony of different types of algorithms many
of which will be
immediately familiar
OK so
the bottom line here is is very simple is just the weighted least squares formulation
but it leads to a lot of interesting insights
right so let me go
so the next step
so that's right away to discourse problem in this
vector notation so i'm going to stack all the data
y one through y and this vector y
i'm going define this vector ones once and and then
the values of this kernel function
we are going to be stacked into the diagonal of this diagonal matrix kj
so i can write the quadratic cost function
to minimize
and when i do this simple
minimisation what i get
is the value of the pixel
and xj
it is just this expression on the right hand side
OK in writing it sort of in longhand what you have is some
of a bunch of coefficients times the data points
OK now what's interesting here is that if you look at these data points if
you look at these cost so if you look at these weights
the weights are normalized
so the sum up to one there are also positive
OK and here the way i've written in the weights are a function of the
positions and also the actual grey values at those positions
OK so this fairly general
the bottom line here is that
the solution to this optimisation problem
is a convex combination of all the data that you consider
convex because these weights are positive and they also sum up to one
so this is basically an optimisation problem we solve for estimating every pixel value that
we're interested and we sort remove this
optimisation problem around in fact this is exactly what the way what the
moving least squares idea in in graphics as well this just weighted least squares and
move around the image
and you get a chance
OK so i'm just going to write this as a vector vector
inner product with this w contains these weights
and the y again contains all the
all right so now let's see what happens if we make different choices for this
for this kernel function
OK so here's the simplest case if you take this kernel function to be simple
with the exponent being the spatial distance sort of the euclidean distance between the two
spatial positions with these two samples are
if you want to measure the similarity between these two and you use this metric
then all using
is the the the the euclidean distance what you get is
the classical gas in linear filters
we all know from basic sort of signals and systems signal processing
OK now i should also say that these filters
even though they are linear could be spatially varying
so depending on how your data sample if data sampled regularly then that's fine but
the properties that the not very much
it was turning what should be done
this approach
words eventually learning its maximum expected utility
ninety involved many many cycles of learning
in fact typically people report the you know they got a paper cut in the
paper the reporter agent
and then use reinforcement learning to learn some task
after ten thousand cycles
well i mean
you have to have some way of automating that you can imagine having it
and artificial human with ten thousand cycles
incredibly be painful to get the rewards
so the down the downside of reinforcement learning is typically made two
i do a lot of
a lot of cycles in order to learn
well the
roughly speaking the is deployed in the environment
and the rewards discount
so well there's different kinds of cases
they can be the case where
there's no real into the task and it just goes on forever
probably more typical has learned play something like chess
the last thing louis loses especially minus one
and then you officially moved back to the initial state
so there's an action which forced to beg initial states of consensually considers only continuing
but actually is in this sense kind prosodic
because it goes back to the beginning and in the plane every again
so the two typical things happen
but the downside is used in a lot of money
in order to work
well this is this this is not completely unrelated to the problem of exploitation explore
exploration was referring to earlier
and the problem is that even if you make typically in them again the point
five gamma point nine
is the typical number
coming out the sea
o ninety four nine five ninety point nine nine but actually when it's quite small
liquid water
so it actually effectively has a fairly short horizon
the other thing is to not bother about and just to show is of finite
the possibly longer rising into the features
the reward
so as it was the first what you get
yes are you oxygen this is starting from zero
but in general
now have been in general you're not here today
and you're going to die t plus one is right
and this company
we're doing right
so there's a couple of
there's a couple of summaries like that there's much point spending time on
so let's just summarised
the first of one is that actually offences
a rational agent maximizes maximal performance to the
different kinds of environments
the importance of
the importance of learning in my view it's the
this the key component machine learning is the key technology
right OK
i guess some of you will
well study i starting
a few words about
how to understand the feelings whole
so what's happened and i i
is that
is diversified into a number of substantial subfields
ninety seven right
machine learning
automated reasoning
natural language processing
roger station reasoning is about i
and they to these communities
to some extent in fact sometimes july sixteen
divorced from the others for example robotics
doesn't have much connection
rest of a i
and you can see other examples of that
i'm gonna gonna go through for this true in the first few minutes
maybe even after that
so having started from the idea of
how do you build intelligent machines
as the decades gone by
i i was expanded and diversified
and formed these
largely autonomous subfields
i can i mean the machine does not care about anybody else
i get the feeling that just do it
in fact believe i i
many machine guns one billion
i said well this traffic opinion that i almost by definition there anyway
so these fields subfields developed
but what's really nice about this a idea
is it provides the framework
by which you can bring it all back together
so the asian paradigm
in IR is actually fairly recent
it's really only from the nineteen nineties
if you look at textbooks before that
they typically had chapters on the various subtopics
and then put together very well the by what about building intelligent systems and again
the planning
it's improving whatever else
one of the nice things and this is
exemplified by russell and norvig
they hang whole thing around the asian concept
so the
the concepts
is the basic paradigm of artificial intelligence you are trying to build intelligent agents
in order to do that we need some technology
but the technology come from comes from the subfields
but what you really want do was integrated
if you it's really into building intelligent systems
so one of the technical challenges is to take this
really nice paradigm of
the idea is empowered
and from the various subfields
pull the appropriate parts necessary and integrated nice way
so if you
studying artificial intelligence
and what
russell norvig subunit to make this page
but try not get trapped in one of the sub fields
think about the
the original question
the original question is
how do you build intelligent machines
this woman trying to sell
right so
the rationality idea was one attempt to try and circumvent that
so in a sense the given the mathematical definition
but intuitively we have something different in mind
i think it should have the most people and i i
even if they're not prepared to admit
we'll be trying to build
machines with human level intelligence
OK and particularly
bill machines that can go from one environment to another in and work well
so the the characteristic
humans have
is the ability to go from to operate in many different domains
and and be able to act
pretty well in almost any those domains
the ability be able had act different domains
you can't count the character characteristic of current IR systems
is really strange
you ask people
what's your favourite activity
and if you ask people particularly
college students
critically this fresh from spring break
i've seen the movie
of an answer sex or some
word that is synonymous with sex
but there's a kind of puzzle
about how much time we spend on sex and it turns out there is data
on this
so people say sectors are favoured activity
but it turns out we actually know
how much time the average american spends on sex
the data miner follow from was summarized by this what in this wonderful book by
james quite
the americans tell pollsters single favourite activity is sex
in terms of enjoy ability they rank secs ahead of sports fishing bar-hopping hugging and
talking with the family eating and watching television going on trips planning trips gardening
bathing shopping dressing housework dishwashing laundry visited and doesn't get in the car repair
on the other hand
these same studies suggested the average time per day devoted to sex is four minutes
and three seconds
as quite says this is not much
even after the four minutes this excludes time spent flirting and dancing going
cruising the boulevard
toning up in james toning up and beauty parlours rehearsing pick-up lines showering thinking about
sex reading about sex doodling pornographic ways
looking at erotic magazines
renting video streaming of sex looking at fashion magazines cleaning up after sex coping with
the consequences of sex buildings powers or otherwise repressing transferring and sublimated
i like this passage because it illustrates two points two important points one is we
don't actually spend that much time on sex in fact the four minutes and three
seconds an interesting number because when you when you do time studies on how much
americans spent filling out tax-related forms
three IRS it's four minutes in a few seconds
the package also points out that regardless of the brutal time we spend on it
extraordinarily important on everything in life follows from
marriage family and children
much of aggression much of competition
much of art music and creative pursuits much in everything follows from it
if we were creature without sex
everything will be different and
what's interesting is
there are creatures without sex
there are creatures that reproduce by cloning
and in fact this basic fact about people that we fall roughly into males and
females is the evolutionary mystery
it's not clear why animals that are somewhat large have two sexes
from a biological darwinian perspective having two sexes is bizarre
because each time you have an offspring toss away half happy games
my children only at each have have
my DNA
if i was to close they would have all of that
and so the puzzle has that ever evolved
this is not a course in evolutionary biology and that's not the puzzle will be
looking at the data
well that
a few questions
first talk from first theoretical point of view and an empirical point of view about
males and females are different
then we talk about sexual attractiveness
some research about what people find to be sexually attractive and also very little bit
about the origins of sexual preference why some people are straight others get others bisexual
and others harder to classify
now it
of all the topics i'm presenting sex is one of the sort of dicey ones
from an emotional point of view
these are difficult issues
because sex is
or by definition an intimate part of our lives
and it matters a lot
moreover sex is fraught with moral implications
and since i'm talking about this from
at least at the beginning from a darwinian evolutionary perspective
i'm obliged to start out by dealing with some of the moral consequences and moral
implications so for instance
biologists all biologists i would say well argued
that that
sexual behavior sexual action sexual desire
is to some extent the biological adaptation existing to spread our genes from that perspective
than non procreative sex
gay sex sex with birth control
six by postmenopausal women
there's not much
sir this reproductive gold and in some sense perhaps is unnatural
and one might argue that this mean is wrong
will also be talking about sex differences
the differences between men and women for instance in and how much you want anonymous
sexual encounters differences between men and women in social intelligence
in aggression empathy
regardless of what you think about these
well i you think the right or wrong or doesn't matter
the last to question to what extent are immutable that is if there exists through
darwinian natural selection to what extent
can we ever get rid of
and i want to address those two issues issues of morality and inevitability
from the very start and i want to start off with
with for each of them have a quote by prominent evolutionary scholars to the first
one is by steven pinker in how the mind works
he writes
nature does not dictate what we should accept how we should live our lives well
into micro procreating years i am so far voluntarily childless having squandered my biological resources
reading and writing doing research helping friends and students and jogging in circles ignoring the
solemn imperative to spread my genes
by darwinian standards i'm a horrible mistake a pathetic loser
but i'm happy to be that way in my teams don't like it they can
go jump in the lake
i think point i think is a reasonable one
it is true
that certain things we do
exists to serve the dictate of natural selection but that doesn't make them right if
you think that something is only right
it leads to the generation of more genes
if it leads to reproduction and you're not going to think very much about birth
you're not going to think very much about any sort of non procreative sex on
the other hand if you're more if you think something is wrong
if it's the it's unnatural you know anything much about flying and apply
a refrigerated food
or surviving severe infections
more generally our bodies and brains have evolved reproductive success but we can use these
brains issues around destinies
nothing more necessarily follows from the fact biology