given two
treatment strategies which are the same
but one of them include psychotherapy
so an appointment with the shrink once a week and one of them doesn't include
what's the difference of these two sets of people receive the same drug treatment
but half of them actually also made a psychiatrist on a regular basis and half
of them don't
and the reason it's important to compare these two strategies is
a lot of people don't really like
the extra burden of going to the psychotherapist and i just prefer to take their
drug in the morning and not bother with anything more
so can we see what is the effect of the psychotherapy
and what we see is that if you just look at expectation it seems that
using psychotherapy
has a positive effect
but if you also include the variance estimation well
it's not a meaningful effect and two standard deviation and this is for patient population
in terms of the number of samples we had for each of these
two different policies if you have many more
registered in the study
maybe it's a meaningful difference but based on the data we've collected in clinical trial
this would be the recommendation in this case
and this is the kind of results that are partners in health really interested in
that you could add some confidence bounds to your estimate of the value function as
opposed to just saying
my reinforcement learning system recommends that everyone be registered for psychotherapy
and by the way in this we didn't even include the cost of the psychotherapy
always included in terms of reward function was
the expectation of remission whether people will actually achieve
real reduction of depression symptoms over some period fixed period of time
and so at some point you could at the cost of
cost of psychotherapy if you wanted to two
the rate at which is
right so you could
we haven't tried it in terms of the empirical
sense in terms of whether there are some real benefit
in this case i think you
you get in terms of doing the analysis this way
if you get more i haven't thought about it very much
the hope the hope is that somehow
can leverage your data in a better way by estimating the error on these models
precisely and if there's some independencies in terms of the errors and so on you
can get away with better results with the smaller simple sample set
now that i have no
theoretical and empirical results support this
well that's certainly our intuition
that is
and you can
right right model
there's some of that there is a whole literature on that two and we're looking
at some of that that we haven't applied in this context
and and
so that's what i wanted to say on this particular question i should clarify that
the work we is actually a generalization of earlier work that had been done in
the MDP case and so some of the techniques in terms of the estimation of
the variance with there before was just a question of generalizing it to the public
in the
and the rapid controller finite policy control representation but we think this is really useful
to quantify performance when you have some critical task not necessary everywhere on the robotic
systems are really don't need to worry about it
but in some domains which have a critical component and this can give you a
lot of power to analysis
not just
there's nothing here about how to adjust the control online if you're doing optimisation of
your value function we don't quite know how to do this yet because then you
have this max operator which really complicates things a little bit
we have some ideas of how to do that but we haven't gotten there yet
it turns out when your data is collected in a batch
this works pretty well because there's a fixed ready to collect the data whether it's
a randomized strategy or whether it's a strategy prescribed by clinical practice
a strategy usually is they the same with dialogue system but we say nothing about
how to estimate the value function directly
so there
o suited thousand based on this
it was most recently
and this is true
of course if
six years
he's your
which is
and become
and this is shown in the country
it is the same
in this show
so this is
two so
and then you should
this is one the
between the
the next step in
so you to do is to explain the meaning of christmas
what i to be was the that schools
so the
to say
the meaning of this
that's of course is
there is
it is of course
no fuel
so this is no more than one
this is
it's difficult
this should not be able to propose to each person
this is the distribution grid pretty
so this is actually
is the most important thing is
this is the same thing
is it
well i think
just a few days for the
this is
this is the version of the model is exactly the same
it was
it is
it's so
this is a small but
of all sixty
the solution was
the information about its
we see the small so chapters
the special that can be
and in fact is true
two sources
but what she
in fact this is the same
should also be for
it is just
so that's what
this is
all this
so then
the action is
say no
it's just doing this
that's what it was
circumstances sets so
how should affect
this is due to the fact that
it's a
the first one
but i think it's
she was
and this is one of the social factors cues for instances
so the
all compositions which is the ratio of the for
so this is not
expression of same
this is
four should not be
it's the
the truth is you want
according to the
of the solution to do the same things so
strong on the basis that produced
four is close to
so he decided use
the public that his
good news crews
this is a list of course is that this is not
the average
because it
this is
this is a
much so
now it's obvious
to to use the
what is of this
the this was
so expect users
it is possible to control the
of to
the is
this is this
this is
the that exist
with the physical world
of course
he years old
this is much higher than average
so it's also the EMF
one is i times are five
you see is the lower than
the MS
and the reason is
this internal resistance here
if i shorted out this battery
a stupid thing to do but if i make are equal zero
so i think the better and i just shorted out
the maximum current
but i can
are is now zero
so you can see that the maximum i did you can
get is a divided by
of i
and the of b
the voltage that you would measure now between point being in a goes to zero
it doesn't mean that there is no current running
but it means that between these points
potential difference goes down to zero
shorting out of that area of course is not a very smart thing to do
you can put batteries in series
and thereby getting
a higher potential difference
this is the negative side is positive
i have an independent one negative positive
and independent one negative positive
each one
was an EMF e
i can connect the positive side of one
with the negative side of the of adjust to conducting y
the positive side of this was the negative side of the other
potential difference
between these two points
now three
open circuit
i don't draw any current
i draw current and of course i have to do again was the
i'm going to
built with you a
copper zinc
battery of the kind that we just discussed
you see here
he is the copper copper sulfate solution which h two s four
he i might plates
this is my
zinc plate
and this is my copper plates
and you're going to see
the voltage
i think over there that is correct
there is no potential difference now because they are not in place yet
so here comes my
here comes my copper
they go into the solution
you see about one four
in general these potential differences of that or wonderful
o point nine five
now what i will do
i'm going to create the double one
five two independent
batteries i have here
one have
and zinc
i have another one
i copper
and saying
i'm going to connect this one
you will see now
that the EMF of w
ready for that
my second one is going to be completely independent
here comes
two plates make sure they have the copper
zinc not confused
there we go
now you should see twice the potentially you do see that open circuit there is
no current running well this
if a
remove all spam and the problems of the real world
OK so
now we have presentation of our
many of our link graph
we have this formula
and what we're going to do
we're going to design the reason that can calculate this page around
for the internet which is
not not very small
all i don't know on my laptop
i can
let's start from
the most naive presentation
first of all it it
completely obvious
that we don't need
to keep our
structure of graph a memory
because if you look at this formula
we see that
i have everywhere
we are working his one
for me it's amazing are pagerank for one page
and on the right we have
this portal is to have all pages that are linked with this one
so what we can do
they can
o five live line-by-line we can get
for this particular page
you can get idea of this page
they can get a list of all ideas of all documents that are linked from
this page
and we can calculate how formula
the big disadvantage of this formula that we need a number of links from this
so how it works
we are eating
this number is actually the idea of the of the
this idea of the page actually it
some indication some array of result
we are going to
and to this i
weight is from all pages that are linked to this page
we then we are going through of course list
and they have a and because of this is iteration formula we need to erase
we need to raise of new ideas and all the way
it fails to be
i feel all our initial weight is real
this is constant
this initilisation first part of the sun
and then what we are doing for every where you're from all postings lists glk
getting previous value of pagerank
divide each by number of links from this page
and so it
of course after some them was appliance our dumping factor and safe to all output
when we are done with the whole
ar is is the whole matrix
have new result
then we can simply wish this arrays
so we are coping or resting place that pointers
and now this writer a is previously areas
and this rate will be
and for new way
so it's definitely it definitely works
let's assume how many memory we need
so we need festival
two arrays
i mean how pagerank
and size of the array is equal to
number of documents in our collection
so imagine that the
keep four bytes
so we need
and we have
a collection of four billion documents
so we need comment
OK even if the same you got so now sixteen gigabytes of memory it
pretty bleak and also we need some error is number of links that usually is
of course we can keep to whites i don't believe that there are many documents
with more than
sixty five thousand
link outgoing please
it looks like that we can feed into into memory
this is very simple doesn't work so definitely we can
calculate pagerank on our laptop for some small subset of the internet
but we cannot do it for some bigger graph
next optimisation start next optimisation first step of optimisation
looking again looking
here what we see we see that
every time
when we get you
actually trying to provide only one number is called
getting getting only one reason
and you see that this formula it works
based on
when we doing this
we are using
all leans the so we were trying to invert actually all matters because we are
trying to get all links that are coming to maybe we can reduce
amount of memories significantly
can invert of representation
what we get what we need to do
we need to
presented not going links
but incoming links
how can invert just metric
how we can
modify our
it's actually not so hard
you can you can do it using owl
well known approach
you can run through of wild ones and you can
created this temporary parts of this file and then merge them again to the to
the biggest inverted
i just systematic
and with this inverted one
all calculations is extremely simple
you need to keep only one error
and size of the story
is the number of places
what we're going to do are reading one and one element of one string from
from our input from our
graph presentation and also we don't need to
keep in memory of
previous results
because the process is
step by step
okay that the key on these things is how many variables you getting rid of by integrating
think about paean end
if any is larger than p e
you're getting rid of more variables by integrating out x
if p is large and and
you getting more variables by integrating out w
actually we know from all the
all these uh
consistency proofs and so on and so forth
it is large and then x is gonna become very well determined
if he is very very large large appears x becomes better determined so the last
piece small these parameters very very well determined
in the large and small pe these parameters very well determined but if any small
and p large these parameters are badly determined but that doesn't matter bayesian if you
integrate them out as matter having said all at it doesn't have a actually the
same solution
a little bit about stuff going on there because the special cases linear linear
the solution is the same but
your instinct should be to integrate out the largest set of variables and then this
is a nice trick integrating out the mappings i've used it in several different areas
since then
it's good because other people don't seem to spotted how useful it can be
on occasion
scale i just wanted
o point out what this implies and then we'll talk a little bit about gaussians
so this is an independent
so this is a
calcium density
with eh covariance is dependent on x
and what we call that's is a process
just as before we talked about the difficulty we talk about in models that independent across
it would be easy to add a feature difficult to add a new variable end
well that's what i casting process allows you to do to add new variables tend
to be consistent across that and the reasons calcium processes work is because they have
covariance functions that fulfill the properties of a massacre and all you know
i have to know the representer theorem to gaussianprocess processes because you can show everything
about it is called common graph consistency
but it's basically telling you the same thing about casting process and support vector machine
so i want just talk a little bit about galcians
which may be actually done right at the beginning
after and introduce calcium processes
i like using height and weight examples
for gaussians even though the positive variables so that they shouldn't be modeled with a
guassian but they can be well approximated by calcium so i'm gonna sample heights from
a distribution and weights from a distribution so his heights mean one point seven metres
weights means seventy five kilos cocaine and is the variance
i and here's the two distributions so
i'm around there
and i'm around there
and so
we can sample
jointly from these two distributions and the way we do that's want to look at
the distribution of heights and weights that sample height
sample way let's problem them
sample high sample way this problem
sample sample weights problem yeah
so this is independent gaussians sampling
what's wrong with this picture
and no independent yeah
it's not that
if you taller you typically heavier and body mass index is about that's so this
is an independence assumption but in reality they are dependent
the new model
this is correlated guassian
so here
i sample heights hand if i sample high height the weight is also high
condition on the height
the weight is not this is the marginal distributions the marginals look the same
well actually tend be a large height will tend to be associated with a larger way are low weight
and a low height yeah
so that's correlation is a simple thing isn't it
what we looked at before with really appreciate and peace yeah what it's doing is
taking a matrix like this it's rotating it back to the matrix we saw axisaligned
that's in fact what does the rotation does back and these guys the igon values
i tell you what the variances are any axisaligned state so to me and i
can value problem is that i mean i know it has other purposes but that's
how i physically think about and i can value problem that it's rotating calcium
not really calcium a quadratic form but that's how i think about is rotating about soon-to-be axis aligned
so that's given to the curvature are all the properties of the gas you
so gas in distribution the multivariate one is dependent on the covariance anomie now we're
going ignore the mean and it's
doesn't matter taller ignoring the mean some people get fuss about it
and if you want us about it with me and prepared argue till
the dogs come home or whatever the expression is an but i will tell you
is arguing me is not a good idea but we can assume means we don't
lose anything by doing it seems odd because people they all means everything in a
guassian well okay
you can do this without mean zero
so what i wanna do is i wanted to calcium with a particular covariance structure
we've already seen we've got gas with a particular covariance structure x x transpose is not gonna be about one
can be different covariance structure
and i'm gonna take this calcium is a twenty five dimensional calcium
i'm gonna take one sample from it
so it's gonna twenty five elements
and i'm gonna plot those those
those samples from this calcium against their index o and x one t twenty five
brought the samples against those index
and there you have it
this is the sample one twenty five plotted against their index
this is the covariance are used
i've drawn as a color map and because it's got unit value along the mean
you can sort of see by the fact that these guys fall within two standard
deviations above the mean the marginal
will be within two standard deviations
i can say this is also a correlation so what you can actually see is
these are very dark red hair up in this region these two points very strongly
correlated that's example model showing with rho equals point nine eight the joint density these
two points is strongly correlated
basically frequence of graphs ordered by frequency so this would be the rank
and you can look at them but what what you see is that most of
them are threes right we get a lot of these stars we get some chains more
complicated shapes are less less common and it's also not really clear how
what would be what is the relation between the structure and the
frequency or the rank right you can have some that have that are that are
big for example this one is on seven nodes and it's more frequent than this guy on three right so even
though more nodes more edges this is less frequent and so on right similar similarly here we
have this chains on four and so on right so the question is what is the
relation and just to say it again right what we would like to know and I don't
think we have the the very good answer is how to use like social context cascade shape and frequency relate
right how does the how can I determine the frequency of
the cascade from its from its from its shape and the questions we would like to
find answers to is you know why is why is this pattern more frequent than
that pattern and what is the interpretation of them one thing just to show more power loss
I guess so you can also go and measure the cascade size distribution right
so here we have the size which is means the number of nodes in the
cascade  and the count and this is now for books so again you can see an so I'm plotting this on
log so this is the relation between cascade size and the count and you can see it's
it's a straight line it's a heavy tailed distribution and there are few cascades that are that are large and they are
not even that large it's a hundred nodes and we had three million people that were making book
recommendations and the largest propagation was less than a hundred nodes
oh and maybe one more thing that also notice the exponent is very very
high right so the fail the the the decay is very quick very strong so this is
now for DVD's right here the situation is is a bit different again we are plotting the
same cascade size so number of nodes in the cascade versus count and you can see here
cascades go up to a thousand nodes so here we have like eight hundred thousand people making these
recommendations and the cascade size goes up to a thousand nodes and also it decays much slower
also there is this knee right and what we found is that since there are incentives right
there were websites or forums where a person could go and say I am interested
in buying these DVD can please someone recommend it to me right and both parties would benefit
right person who makes a recommendation gets gets credit and the person who buys
gets ten percent discount so there there was incentive so we think that these
big ones may be the result of these websites and same for blogs so count
cascade size and again a power low with a different exponent
so just to wrap up on the on the empirical analysis of the cascades right we saw the
they've the cascade sizes follow a heavy tail distribution power low  or something else right with different
exponents so this suggests that something more complicated is going on that that some kind
simple benching process on a tree because if it would be a branching process
we would have a the distribution should be exponentially in the size right so the questions are what does
the underlying social net what role does the underlying social network play and can you make steps towards
more realistic cascade generation or propagation models and here is a here is a
simple simple step that sort of works well its for blogs the idea is
so basically this is a SAS virus propagation model right the idea is that we have
these blogs and we have a and also we have these blogs and also we have a
social network between them so what we'll do now is we will we will pick a new
post and insert it to to the to one of the blogs and say now the information starts
propagating here and now based on the links on the social network this will
will just randomly propagate this information and once the node blog gets infected it can infect
it's it can infect its neighbor in the network and so on so
it's basically a simple virus propagation network where you every node heals with probability
one so that the information can go back and forth between two
blogs if they are strongly linked
and if we go and simulate this process we can see it matches reality quite well so here I have
log log eigenvalue versus log rank us usually you find a power-law
so now I showed you the properties of sort of static graphs, right, you have a graph and you look at it and you ask what can I see in there okay
now the question is what what if I have a graph that grows
right and there are two two things that you can thick think of graphs as they grow, first one is that
you would think that whenever a node would come they create about the same number of edges, right, so the the
average degree or the average number of links per node should be pretty much should remain constant as the graph grows, right, so this is one and the other one is you would think that
and the the diameter so the distances would slowly grow, as I grow my network, the nodes would sort of get farther apart on the average, as the network gets larger, right, so this is
something that you'd expect and what prior work would agree
so for for the relation between the number of edges and number of nodes over time
so we have this basically simple question, right, what is the relation between number of nodes and number of edges in the network over time, so we have these two quantities we are interested in and basically
the question is if the number of nodes doubles
T to T to T plus one, will the number of edges also double
pretend this is an animation and now it comes up, okay, it turns out it that's not true
this is what is going on
for example, if I take the graph of internet for two days
we we create a new one every day, so we have like more than seven hundred graphs and we plot the number of nodes
at some particular time and we plot the number of edges at some particular time
again on log log scales
you can see this
falls on a line
right and what is so
we see that there is this relationship this power-law relationship between the number of edges and the number of nodes in the network over time, so this is the graph of internet, for example, this would be citations
this would be all the high energy physics citations from nineteen ninety-three to two thousand and three and again I have
log log log log N versus log T and now
okay, this this falls on a line and we have this exponent A
now you can ask what would be this what are the usual va what would be the values of this exponent, right, if the value of the exponent is one, then I have no densification, then I have, average degree remains constant over time okay
if I have
exponent of two
that would mean I'm building
a very dense graph, so I'm building a clique, everyone is connected to everyone else, right, because in a graph I can have quadratically many edges as I have nodes, right, a graph can be represented as adjacent symetrics, so as the as the adjacent as the matrix grows, the number of cells in the matrix is quadratic to the num to the size of the matrix, right, that's the reason why A can be between one and two and as I said for one we have linear growth
and for two we would have a quadratic growth, which is a clique, and know you can ask what do we see
and interestingly
we are seeing something that is much higher than one, right, we'd expect one we see here one point two and here one point seven, so what so what this basically means is that our reference lists are getting longer over time, right, this basically tells, how does the length of the reference list increase over time in some sense
so this is this is one
let me skip this one, it's too dense
another thing that you can ask
is how does the diameter, how do the distances change and if you look for example at the erdos-renyi random graph
there and go and analyze it you can you can find you can get results that the the diameter of the network scales as log N or log log N so basically it slowly grows as the network would grow
so what turns in real life is that
which is sort of counterintuitive is that as the network grows, the distances shrink
okay and here here's what I mean by that so
for this again I have the internet and the citation network, so here i'm plotting the size of the graph for time and here I plot the diameter or this is the effective diameter so this would be some kind notion of what is the what is the distance between the node how how how much is the network spread apart and you can see that
it decreases as the graph grows and for citations
the whole thing is even is even more obvious, right, it goes from
more than nine
to something like five
in ten years of day that we that we had the data
so this is sort of counterintuitive, right, because he my network is growing exponentionally, right, so here I started, I don't know, with several thousands of nodes, here I have a few hundred of them and you'd expect, the more they are the the more far apart they are
isn't it a consequence
you could assume that
and especially
the degree
not necessarily, no, not necessarily, for example, if you take
now I'm jumping ahead, but if you take preferential attachment, right, and sort of force it to have densification that still has increasing diameter, so even though they seem similar, they are they are disjoint and also when I'll be talking about model
the first model I'll show is the one where you get densification, but you don't get shrinking diameter, so they are different
how how they are different is still an open question, so okay so I showed you all this about graphs
these these properties can be find can be found
in many different graphs coming from various domains, for example, worldwide web, online communities, telephone networks, autonomous systems and so on, so this heavy tailed small world communities' resilience to attacks all this
was was found in
pretty much any network that was looked up
yeah sure
if you don't then usually you have a very good explanation
for for example
how to say, for example, some some graphs that if you would look, I don't know, the road networks at some particular particular scale or particular granularity, then it would look a bit different because it has to leave
on on the surface
right, but normally, normally what I showed is what you expect, if you don't see that, then you start to ask, why I don't see that, for example, in instant messaging right there is a limit on how many contacts you have and
depending on where is that limit you will see the spike in the distribution, it will be cut off, it will end there, so I'll also show this later
so this is the motivation now for the second part, how do we think about these things, so now I was basically like throwing at you throwing them at you one by one and now the question is how do we think about them why are they there what would be a simple
generative model or a mechanism that would that could sort of generate them
holiday photos anything of that form
you might have graphs
well done
is for is something that occurs in social networks quite obviously so if you use
facebook myspace
a lot of that information is represented as the interaction graph
that's in a way where a lot of the money states or if you have
collaborative filtering they essentially have one big bipartite graph on one side and got all
the movies does of got all the users
and i have
and h whatever going around rented some movie and then decided that he liked and
didn't like it
you actually want to make use of that in some cases to infer
additionally edges in the graph
like well you might actually like my heart number thirteen was you've seen the die-hard
one up to ten right
things like that would be inference or you could say well given that the guy
has seen all those maybe you know i should send him an invitation to the
optical character recognition this is
it's actually very popular example
and this is what people
i used to work on the lot basically in the mid nineties
fact from the united
united states postal service one of the data
the dot actually play a very
key role in machine learning
the key role in the sense that somebody goes and releases about it
maybe for the specific purpose in this case of recognising handwritten digits
and people actually go and deploy algorithms for
and this thing takes on a life of its own because it becomes kind of
against which everybody benchmarks against as if you come up with the new algorithm then
it's almost
a matter of necessity that you try give me out on that participate
it's good if you can show that this stuff works better than anybody else
so for instance the netflix dataset is another one of those cases where a new
dataset actually has changed the way research is being done considerably
just actually one thing to bear in mind that you read the machine learning paper
and they only two
an experiment on a on a certain small subset of other
it's pretty easy to tell that OK well that's getting issues
so for instance if somebody just runs it algorithm was on so now i know
why located at probably didn't go beyond two hundred three observations
that would be the right to start the base so
the idea is to find out what they category it seems this will be
are and it's about the USA
OK if you look at this stuff from and you can see that
well not quite sure what they're selling here
some company reported some profit
fourth quarter returned with the
faces well
look at this
look at the next one
now what can i do with those who
with the start of
i could try to figure out who that person is
or i could try to find out whether the guy on the picture is happy
so it's not immediately clear that just because you're given a certain dance it
a certain question associated with it
as you can see here there are actually
well live different expressions
and this particular about this it has maybe a hundred people for what they probably
did is they went around the camera in the lab and
they had a hundred people in the lab and everybody had his picture taken
which also tells you that getting very large face recognition datasets unless you pay for
that is actually not that easy
there are not many free one
microarray data is another case
these will be different genes basically
i think of those reading queen
as information with the gene is particularly expressed or not expressed in other words whether
it's really working a lot with is
so somebody actually win class of this in some direct away
probably not terribly pretty
the point is somehow that within that cluster
a lot of those genes are turned on in here that are not well
doesn't really mean terribly much but if you now
i have something like the cancer diagnosis system
we might want to find out OK maybe ten fifteen maybe twenty different genes
which you can actually then used to find out whether somebody
a second order
and it makes a lot of difference if you actually manage to find those genes
so the reason i mean and usually with mission maybe one hundred thousand two hundred
thousand different genes so
after matrix i think at the moment
two hundred thousand three much the next what you can get
so why would you care about finding a small number
because if you now afterwards deployed as the hospital you don't actually want to happen
in talk
microarray was two hundred thousand genes measures
that's really expensive can cost a few hundred dollars
what you want to stick to is
move to cheaper technology which uses only ten or twenty of those
and maybe the experiment only cos i don't know maybe ten maybe fifty dollars
so there is immediate cost savings if you manage to reduce it to a certain
number of genes
as of course also the biological motivation of assuming that well maybe there's only a
couple of key genes and their relevant for that problem
but that's a lot more risky
so a lot of people have written wonderful papers on widely you fancy algorithm is
actually good at selecting g
i've done that too
that's it
there's no real good guarantee why this algorithm will actually be very meaningful biological
the only thing that we can usually argues that hey it actually works
here's another example of biological sequences
so this is basically
well triplets which tells you which proteins are
synthesized here and you want to find out basically what they're doing
this is something you can get very easily what sequencing techniques
pointing out that this is an interminable domain of vascular cell adhesion blah blah blah
it's actually hard is it means you actually need some
bioinformatics post-doc or about biochemist opposed stand in the lab and maybe spain's a couple
of months to establish that this belongs there
if you want automated
fortunately people have already done a lot of these
it may actually be that so
this annotation here is
well two point one point one point four point three means this is where i
need to branch down in my
ontology to tell me what the function is
sometimes you can actually have situations where
individual sequences have several function
we might have protein
simply playing several roles
he might have several of those terms here
this is the so-called gene ontology
directed acyclic graphs or in short kodak
so what you want to do you want to map this to that
not very it's a hierarchical probably labels
are actually in some
fairly elaborate structure
you might actually have a lot of different labels
and now it actually matters how wrong you get things
so let's assume
well you get the first
four digits here right and you get the first one wrong well maybe actually some
biologists might be able to
you know i just tried five different
ideas of what this protein might do you might actually be able to find it
is that
you compete with
a supervised learning algorithm
using the same number of labelled samples
you me you ask for some labels
and you're error area the classes that you choose at the end will be similar
to very low supervised learning algorithm looking at
the same number of labelled examples
in general
when you know supervised learning
the area rate is going to be something like the VC dimension
time is
the minimum error rate of the classifier
divided by
the number of labelled samples
because the
there's this controls the variance
of the minimum error classifier which is going to control the deviations which is going
to control the you can select this individual parts out
and if you just put this quantity and what you see is that
new square repsonse square
this is a square root but square
the new party cities council news cancel
the eighteen
so that says that
when you have some fundamental noise
it's going to
to put of four
the number of times that
that you ask for
for for this style
practical learning things like this
so the proof that this is a very simple
so what happens is if you have a VC dimension of it means there are
d inputs that you can label
either way
you can label all configurations
and then what you're going to do is even make there be quite a bit
no it on these input so probably the y equals one given one of these
is going to be very close to the problem y equals zero given one of
these inputs
OK so you want this level
every time you ask for the label
it's going to be
stem probability that's a one some properties here
this problem is to be very close to get it out so you have
the coin
the queen has some particular bias the bias is very near to point five
the question is how many times due to flip
this coin before you pretty sure that the most likely
is one
or the most likely choice is here
and there's the people have worked out lower bounds on the number of times you
have to flip a coin in to figure this out
chris restored
OK so
in terms of data
so there's something in
steve hanneke is paper where he introduced the disagreement coefficient
but it's not with independent or bound
so i said that
this where and i showed you
has all bound the of data
so it's kind of intuitive it should be lower bound the data
if you have some particular data it says there's some merit
for which you can have to require a substantial number of
of labels in order to
in order to recorders
and since we a logarithmic dependence if we are rehearsing
it's the the
one worst step of recursion which really dominates our label complexity
this is just another independent around which is
so far
yes of they data applies to
all of these mellow
active learning our lands
you can imagine there might be non mel active learning algorithms
first for me maybe even for the nonseparable case
but we don't know what those are yet
could be
so all of the same importance weighted active learning
the basic idea in importance weighted active learning is going to create algorithms which had
this to rough outline
you're running through unlabelled apples
and now for something about the streaming model
we're going to choose
some probability
we ask for the label
so we have some subroutine rejection threshold
which decides to ask the label or not
and then with
probability p we ask for the label
and then we're going to add
the features and the ability get and one over p
and importance weight
two and importance weighted set of examples
and they going to
learn using this importance weighted set of examples so the meaning of importance weight is
what if if one of p is ten
because i think this is the example ten times more important to get right then
one was an importance weighted one
often i think people use importance weights in various ways so for example comes up
and boosting
this is a very simple
however the skeleton
and the claim is that just from the skeleton you can easily construct
active learning algorithms for the
nonseparable case
so in particular
for any
rejection threshold if probabilities about some minimum
and then i was just to constant factor worse than supervised learning in terms of
the number of labelled examples that required
it should be intuitive right because we have some probability of of living anywhere
and these important base allow us to
it essentially reconstructs the draws from the original distribution
so if we optimize well
with respect to these importance weighted samples we'll end of optimizing wealth back to the
original distribution
OK so this is that we have some safety if guarantee but we still would
like to know if we can get label complexity improvements
in order to
to get label most improvements we need to fill in the rejection threshold subroutine
so this is one way to fill in for which we can prove some improvements
so we can have
the unlabelled examples are going to the history of
the model
and and at this point the information goes back into the cycle and the two
can move on and select for the
actions such as for instance provide hints feedback remediation and so on and so forth
now i should
bifida currency i said ideally in this slide because there is no tutoring system that
has all this
knowledge and can deal with old knowledge what's different different systems that focus on different
parts of his architecture or to to insist that have more sophisticated the presentation of
the target domain there are two theories systems that have more sophisticated models or the
kind of communication models for instance allow them to dialogue in natural language but you
insist on that does it all still doesn't exist
was there have we've seen quite good achievements in the last twenty years there is
there have been many successful i ts is that have been deployed in the field
and you successfully
to improve student learning in the classroom
and i won't be able to i don't like and we put all references for
individual achievements but what i listed there it's book they just recently
there has been recently published that provides a very good overview of the state-of-the-art if
you're interested and there's also been a company that a spin-off project funded by researchers
from carnegie mellon university that has been commercialized commercializing intelligent tutoring systems in for math
and science in hundreds of high schools in the united states and some of the
curriculum in general teaching of mine into schools have changed because of the introduction of
this to system so tutoring system are having an impact on education or right
just to quantify this if you remember the two sigma should where human tutors can
generate the standard deviation better learning the classroom instruction
up to now
the tutoring system that have been formally evaluated along these dimensions have reached up to
standard deviation improvement OK
not as good as human tutors but you know that's
to be expected certainly better than the most sophisticated case systems
kai systems that so far have managed to see trip to achieve in improvements just
half standard deviation
so we are done
well not really because mostly the eighty s is that i described that have been
successfully deployed
they usually provide individualized support for
problem solving activities via twitter let interactions and this is also a technique called coached
problem solving
and basically involves having students solve problems in science in some usually science or math
domain in this case for instance physics
the two to follows the student the student has to do
solve the exercises presented by the tudor could can provide feedback if this student makes
mistakes him for instance turns certain and read
can provide help
but this is basically the kind of instruction on which
intelligent tutoring systems have been successful however there are other forms of
educational activities that can actually help learners acquire
the target cognitive skills and knowledge and they can usually be useful perhaps at different
stages of the learning process and can be better suitable for different kinds of learners
with different kind of
cognitive skills and learning abilities
so this is where
the current trends of AI really of i'ts research are trying to push
actually advances in intelligent tutoring systems research
and i'm going to mention what i believe are for all the mean the four
of the most important areas of research current so one is to try to develop
adaptive learning environments that systems that instead of giving
helping students do structured problem solving try to provide activities that enhance that trigger free
exploration learning from exploration on the target domain and that usually done by using for
instance virtual worlds interactive simulations or educational games
meta cognitive tutors that his tutors that instead of focusing only on teaching helping students
learn knowledge about a specific domain they also tried to teach learning and reasoning skills
that in cognitive science are known as meta cognitive skills because they trust and the
specific domain tend to be in general for learning and research
affective tutors that tutors that can react not only to harvest and learns in reasons
but also what students feeling during the interaction this is very important because they have
been shown to be strong ties between affect and learning
and last but not least collaborative learning environments that is environment to try to provide
individualized support to help students learning
all this
areas of research have what i feel i think have two main common challenges that
need to be addressed their activities they're targeted tend to be more open ended and
less well defined than the structure problem solving that we saw earlier in structure problem
solving usually it's clear what the learner needs to do in order to generate a
good solution and was a clear definition of correct behaviors in this kinds of activities
such as for example and exploration of
an interactive simulation or interaction with the occasional game what is it good behaviour is
much more open and less well defined
also what we are trying to model with this new generation of intelligent tutors are
small are student raised their much
there are higher level than knowledge goals that were tracked by previous generation after systems
for instance meta cognitive skills and affective states
so what is this basically can be summarized by saying that now
this students have to deal with much higher level of uncertainty during the interaction because
of the nature of the interaction that they want to that want to support
i'm going to start going to be giving the second half of the introduction to
cognitive science
this is particularly funds but i feel like i have maybe the most fun spot
on the whole program because it's it's sort of the end of the first day
i could talk about picture general introductory issues but also playing off the team's very
interesting ideas and questions for debated in raising in all talks today so hopefully this
will give you further background in what we're interested in cognitive science what these two
fields of cognitive science machine learning how to say to each other and also laid
the groundwork for say some of the debates are going to be having today and
for the rest of the summer school
now as many of the speakers have emphasised there's there's a long history of interplay
between these fields of psychology and cognitive science on the one hand and machine learning
here i just put up
a list of not not complete but representative list of various approaches to machine learning
but in some sense have their origins in psychology and cognitive science there either invented
by psychologists were first published in psychology journals and that includes ones have been mentioned
already in that context like the perceptron was published in the journal psychological review which
is the main reading journal for theoretical psychology other things which have been mentioned here
factor analysis multidimensional scaling right which are somewhat old techniques and that we call those
unsupervised learning techniques but also things which you know you you you might all think
of as a psychological either psychologically inspired psychologically motivated learning algorithms things like spectral clustering
collaborative filtering with low rank factorizations
kernel based classification bayesian concept learning these ideas although i don't wanna not trying to
claim that psychologists that everything machine learning is just picking up the pieces but you
can find
either the
actual idea or key
intuitions antimatter that's not the case that psychology is just about cool phenomena and need
experiments or even it's not just that the rigorous psychology is contained to the to
the rigour of experimental design and data analysis but the that field just like machine
learning has long theoretical tradition and what's exciting here is up to you bring these
two theoretical traditions into contact and learn from each other
now as again
the earliest because it emphasised this the history of interactions between these fields it's it's
long but it kind of goes in waves and they come together and move apart
and so on and what what what motivates this summer school is the sense of
these two fields are coming back together again after a somewhat long history of having
been a part and looking back with you for inspiration and lessons learned in the
last moment in history when these two fields are really very tightly interacting this was
the connectionist neural network whom the the time when actually i think of all the
all the speakers today
maybe all the faculty here were about the right generation we kind of got into
the field around this time and this is probably a lot of what excited this
is that is that a fair statement certainly neale said that i think they could
say that i would say that so so what was this paradigm about what was
incomplete and what lessons can be learned take forward just to recap my own version
of the same kind of history
what was exciting about this view was that it did give in the sense that
nick was talking about the very and this multi-level analysis perspective on how the mind
the brain work formulating problems of cognition and really with a focus on learning at
what mark called the computational theory level the abstract logic of computation
the algorithmic level that made contact with traditional ideas from psychology prof what with the
steps of mental processing and even down to the neural implementation level and all these
things seem to fit together in a very neat way so learning is some kind
of statistics with the the general motivation that what our brains do is the fine
structure in the world this can be unsupervised could be task oriented could be driven
by rewards spread out over time as the paradigms of supervised unsupervised reinforcement learning
but it's basically some kind of statistical inference finding patterns in massive high dimensional data
finding clusters low dimensional manifolds and so on
so that's the abstract math problem we then knew how to formulate this
the statistical inference problem as some kind of an opposition or like some kind of
maximum likelihood you as as neil so those are kind of two different takes on
the same problem but there's basically some kind of functions some cost function to be
minimized we knew how to write learning rules are algorithms for for effectively doing that
these gradient descent chain rule back propagation sorts of things
we also this is where the connection to neuroscience comes in of course knew how
to make a link to these neural networks these networks of neurons like processing units
where the idea is that this is high dimensional data analysis problem that comes down
to learning lots and lots of numerical parameters say the what the
this picture here which is the dimension reduction from two dimensions down to one of
cartoon sketch a much higher dimensional problem if we think about the data coming from
sensors and there you have parameter specifying say the
the slope and the intercept of the
the the weights that linear surface in a very high dimensional space or the parameters
specifying say means and covariances of clusters all those numerical parameters would correspond to the
weights connected these units
and the learning rules were ways of adjusting the weights in response to the data
and then actually making contact with the real their science these these these pictures the
reason why we could say these are like the brain is because these circles can
be interpreted neurons these lines as soon as connections were one neuron sends a signal
to another neuron and the weights correspond to the strength of the synapses how much
when an electrical impulse comes in from from the presynaptic neuron how much chemical is
dumped into the space between the neurons that then picked up by the postsynaptic neuron
determines basically how strongly the postsynaptic neuron responds to the input coming in from the
presynaptic the more that neurotransmitter of the more sensitive the postsynaptic cell is the same
amount of neurotransmitter the stronger the connection
and were rules meant that pure clear how the strength of these synapses in the
brain adjusted in response to experience these are things like long term potentiation that's an
empirical phenomenon which was found to follow some of the basic characteristics of say heavy
or the are delta rule type learning
just basically just some function of pre and post synaptic input and output activations and
then you can find circuits in the brain this is a snaps in the hippocampus
the hippocampus is a structure in your brain kind of around there and it's also
in other mammals like there approximately there in the mouse brain and a lot of
neuropsychology and other kinds of neuroscience shows that you know basically without this structure working
well without the synapse is even doing long-term potentiation you can learn certain basic things
so that's very elegant picture in understanding the mind in the brain in computational terms
but it's also been useful not just for this kind of reverse engineering enterprise but
for forward engineering so on the technology side
these basic learning algorithms what we would now call things like principal component analysis or
k means clustering or mixture models and so on until i many of the basic
learning technologies that we now take for granted so face detection this is a classic
example of i can faces and more modern ways of detecting faces in images which
i think we'll was referring to
how does facebook
i suggest to your friends should be or how does amazon recommended products well they
do they use the various essentially very simple statistical pattern finding like this which is
scaled up
that's you that's the google recipe google does this past how does google organize information
on the web and return useful
search hits for your query well with the first technical technical innovation google there are
now for many but the one that google famous for what distinguished it from earlier
what that's going to use the twenty pull feedbacks it's going to be the intro
so i skip the step there
hopefully you can fill in this step is skipped
so i'm going to have
this integral
with the in front divided by
that same integral which is just
integral against qx
so in other difficulties zero
implies that
i nash moments
so i so the optimal q must have the same moment as p
and by and what moments means not very precise the moments are exactly the expectations
of these features that appear in the exponential family so gas in this would be
x and x squared and some preserving exactly those moments
questions on that
this is only true for exponential families
OK now
this projection step however we didn't do that globally we did only locally right so
we did a projection only for one factor at at the time it into production
of all the factors and i was sort of one of the approximations of made
so what's happening is we're going essentially from a global divergence to local divergence is
sort of the second approximation made in the first is your approximate gas
and the second one is not necessarily getting exactly the right moment to that out
in because of this approximation
and then we can think of that more generally is that we would like to
minimize the divergence between p and q
and what we do is going to write that out in terms of individual factors
recall that p of x
it is the product
one factors
q of x which is my approximation
is the product of all of the approximate factors
and throwing in the prior is one of the as one of the factors as
now i can rewrite that global divergence in the following way
this is this is completely going to the top line all have done is taken
one factor for the distinguished one of the factors
in p
to distinguish the corresponding factor and q
five and
you know what we did when we when we actually minimize variance in a b
it was we didn't really use that is our context we instead use this is
our context when we minimize the reprojection
so that that's the
that's that's second approximation the be so
we can use exactly the right context we should have to use approximate context
now having made his replacement you essentially now can just solve for
the FAA till that minimizes the variance and you get the
OK so
a bit of theory that's available three d
is if we're not exactly minimizing the KL divergence which were not what function or
we actually minimizing so there there is the function just justice for belief propagation people
found a energy function which propagation fine stationary points of three b you have said
that this is a generalized version of the same energy function
which is the function that taking fixed points
and is a particularly nice way of writing the energy function
which have given here
and what's nice about it is that this
this energy function is exactly
the model evidence approximation you get out of the
so what i was doing the bayes point machine i was comparing the evidence that
models the formula that i was using
here's our work so
it's a function only of the
approximate factor five approximated the factors in some way
and they don't have to be normalised so they can they can have negative variance
and so on the fly
what i do is i take all of those approximate factors
and i multiply them all together to get q of x
which is an unnormalized
you know got in density
and why do they take
i find the normalizing constant of the distribution that get for multiplying all those factors
and there is the power one minus and where n is the number of factors
number factors in the model
i take this product over all the factors
and this product is basically the normalizing constant
but you computed while you're running p of the thing you project because
basically this formula f of i x
times over f i tilt thank you have access is the same as of IQ
not x
right i
that's the same this
the only difference is that the normalizing constant is is in the in the correct
the normalizing constants work out correctly when you're it this way
but essentially
this is the
this is the form function it the project when you're running a p
the interesting thing is that
what important
of these
one the state of the aspects which are important in modelling dynamical systems
is that we can show that the rise of dynamical system
in the world in the first so-called phase space or state space so we can
the system page taking into loop was going on the state variable
because we have understood from the example of the lamps that are the state variables
which methods for studying the dynamics
one of the aspects which are important thing is to understand the for
the system doesn't change over time
if for example i put the constant inputs
what is important to understand if i reach
in certain point in which the system doesn't change any more
this is going to school a community
or is one of the six so-called fixed point of the
and of course
certainly equilibrium state i cannot serve in output
which is my mind things itself over time
this notion of the community is very important to study the dynamical system
a lot of theory available
so is new
what happens to dynamical systems
in presence of small perturbations around the circuit in equilibrium point
nature and we observe the equilibrium points which are fixed to the boys or for
dynamic behavior which are
also relations of course the summations over time so sometimes so that our system arrives
at a certain stage
well it doesn't change unless i change the name of the variables
in order to give you an example not to be too too much to ask
in this in this population
study these simple models
in this model
we observe what happens to the concentration
of the drug
which is given to the patient
this is
drug can be given in two different ways
by oral delivery so take appeal
in the city
i can be the drug through injection so
you have direct injection into the central compartment with the plasma
a lot of
c of modelling efforts have been devoted to it you can understand also for commercial
pop quizzes for industrial partners is to model those kind of dynamical systems so try
to understand what are the laws which characterizes the behavior of the system over time
and if for example if i have a fixed ingestion or injection
if i arrive surfing wikipedia which is what is the level of
drug which can be measured in the blocked
so this is an example of a dynamical system in which we just more than
states transformations
these equations are very simple because it just tells you that here
we are what we call the compartment
which is the amount of drug is is reported to elicit drug concentration in the
gastrointestinal compartment
this one
which is of course affected by
the whole
how much drug i do i take when i think
and the second equation and the second compartment also
we call it which is the right concentration the market compartment that for example can
be our goal
of the study
if we write must balance equations here
we are doing the states
equation so the equations which are rise
state transition
here we say that the variation of the drug the concentration of the drug in
the gastrointestinal compartment is just the balance of the input looks which is the
quantity of the drug we change ingesting in the output looks which is the quantity
of the stator flux of the
drag moves from the gastrointestinal compartment to the plasma
OK like it's very simple because i have to take the field
then the solution is the just the
it goes to the blast
the second equation is a similar equation here
and just as to how
much harder
the concentration in the multi compartment changes as a function of the inputs
one of the input is the quantity
which moves from the
oral ingestion into the compartment the other one is that if it's present that if
there is an injection also injection directly into the blood we have the quantity which
is directly injected into the
the combustion
here we have a lost
which tells you
but luckily the drug is used by the system so
there is a
what we call the in illumination and of the
of the drug from the body
we have the state states x one x two
reported here we have the two input
we have the equations are we able to derive the equilibrium points
yes it is to do it because if we if we think that u one
u two are constant but we put these two equations equal to zero
and we derive what is called what are called equilibrium point of the exercise is
we have the two equations
we can put the derivative is zero
and we see
and if you present all to constantinople was one of the two
can be zero as you can imagine
we have
in equilibrium point
for the two state variables x one and x two
we have yes of course because
u one constant from this equation
system is
because that's an important question
in practice a how things work that usually you have a lot of knowledge about
your domain
if you know both graphical models you
for example you sure your computer vision scientists and
you know about computer vision we also know about graphical models
you start immediately tried to a graphical model because you are the same person that
has both knowledge right so
you don't really get into the trouble of
figuring out which is the right spot but
formerly the problem right but i mean it turns out that in many cases that's
not the true mean these tools you can apply to possibly anything you can imagine
right because are basically stochastic processes where you have
interrelated viable so
i mean
you can apply for the factor example for any other examples
true that some works on graphical doing that for example i mean i guess
what i think one of the first works of
i think
probably single color and collaborators and stuff i mean
the beginning of this century yesterday was working on they were working on this to
trying to use graphical models for
figuring out probably
pathways in
gene regulatory networks
and yes there is some exploratory
work that you need to do is usually the models who is the first model
that came they were very simple
assuming that each gene for example would be
associate was single
pathway and things like that but
what you can
already see that even extremely simple graphical models
they sometimes you
impressively good results when compared with models that actually don't want assume an entire
network of relations between the part because the nice thing about graphical models that is
you have a complex model
what you have a reasonably disempower comes to perform approximate inference
in this
in this graphical model like belief propagation for example
other major theoretical problems there i mean in practice this thing works
very well and
people have been using full
many many rivals
thousands of images of
also three minutes of
OK now finally i mean
i think it was always some slides and markov blankets as well
so here they are
you need to look at what the markov blanket
a believe
so then what to blank
you may not much of it so let's see if you can understand what's the
markov blanket
so basically let's let's see what's written here
so the markov blanket of a given all
in in the vision that first order markov random fields
is the smallest set of nodes
such that when you condition on those nodes
you get the same distribution as you condition on all the rest of the norm
that's important why it's important
it's important because
obviously if this is true for
for some a
you want to find what's the smallest a four which is is still true
because you don't want to work with these
beast here
because these beast is too large
you want to work with these ones
so you look forward to a which is smallest among
but set such that you still have these equality
well the question is
what's that
i mean
what's the markov blanket of node
vision therefore
what's the markov blanket of a node in the market random field
so in the business of the markov blanket are the parents of all
the children of the norm and what to call the court parents often not
so called parents
it would be you know
we have an
so that capacity
in my markov random feel disempowered neighbors of the north
go back
it's not
exactly that because
x i
if you have a bayesian network or as you may have a markov random field
i have no observation
and you have no isolated
we saw that every node will depend on every no
there's no in the in the in the sense that
two it's own inputs and it's going to
you know past this relative to the next murder which i mean the previous motor
which is going to use that then to compute its
they are achieved with respect to its own parliament
so the problem here is
how can we interpret
nine network outputs as priorities
was is a very simple way
so many people use actually which is called
usually cross entropy criterion
you consider only outputs goal of knowledge through you have one outputs scope class of
tag of interest in you
in your task
well you know you pursue but it was exposure just so it's positive and you
know my eyes with respect to all the classes
so you get the conditional
so here for some
no reasons i defines this quite handy operation which is
and when i e
that's not true what i basically
get this
log likelihood that i want to maximize
so you can see the log as as a kind of you know
softmax in july so basically what you are doing here is that
you push this school
of the right last why you imposed on this course of years are classes
and actually the extreme if like those of max is really max you would personally
like the the school of
the class and s class according to the network
the problem this criterion is that it doesn't take into account that we are dealing
with light sentences
it's like just saying one world at the time
so it kind of sucks
so instead
we prefer to cluster don't like the complete sentence
it's one in the sentence
you apply on the network is going to produce you
first score
in your r and b task
and here we consider an additional school which is going to be a school that
you gave when you jump from one labelled with the other one
so we define
then this goal sentence with like
he wants
for bus of tags i to be led the some of the schools belongs is
plus as far as well as the transition called right
and once again we can apply the same before
and interpret the scores appointed
but by just normalizing over all the buses so before we went normalizing raise respect
to all the classes this time we normalize respect to all of the past
and basically these uses look like you that you want to maximize so
once again you basically special disco
after the right bus while pushing down the scores of all the other blogs as
the extreme if the
if so log and is like just max
it's basically pushing down to of the best past from maisonette
the only party that this
look at
it's not like all past and its
actually very expensive to compute if you do it you know very naive
but fortunately i mean it has been
a long time ago there is something called the
the formalism which are used to compute is located in a recursive manner
you just have to consider this logadd but computed
on the bus to the world to minus one
so you suppose you already uses computation
and an amazing simple or recursion you can just computes the log and over all
over the past up to the world
then you and then you can just you know trained in our network
back propagating this was this regression using like the chain or as you did before
falling you know there is no more layers using this in different to be tricky
mathematically that
it's it's OK you can do it you know it's important
so this
it's actually again
quite all stuff it's about your colour case of what is called like graph transformer
o posed like by early on with two young in ninety seven ninety eight
and well if you if you like you can compare it to the conditional on
the film
would be basically the female version of this
for sequences
so here we are really no no
and we do the same the conditional all which training by stochastic gradient descent
but it
yes the same notes you know what inference you need to find the best pass
and you do that by applying the viterbi algorithm
which is basically the same as in the goes on but when you replace logadd
so what we can apply the you know all networks straight out of the box
two of task of interest
we actually took the window approach
four part of speech part of speech tracking on any of
the window was of size five on the network like three hundred hidden units
we use the coalition approach for semantic labeling the come of the coalition with three
and it had a history of hidden units for the college london and surface of
we use both the world the tag like you and sentence tag likelihood
and we felt as features
was actually we took lower case was to limit the number of words in the
and to keep the information of the case we basically i'd like a capital letter
so we just played
that's what i get
on all the task and you can see the results are compared with the benchmark
is we run through each of these arguments say
i'm not convinced by and here's why
now since since i think that the argument about to get and i just started
getting the first of its fails
you know i hope you'll you'll think it over and you'll eventually come to agree
with me yet these arguments don't really work after all but what is more important
to me is that you please think about it of these arguments in this a
convincing argument for the existence of us soul
if if if if you if you think so
what response to you want to offer to the objections that i'm giving
if this argument doesn't work is there another argument for the existence of a soul
you thanks a better one
all right
so first arguement
you need the solar to explain the animation of the body
well from the physical point of view of course the answer is going to be
two quick
to have an animated body
you need to have a functioning body
and it's true
when you got caught she got all the parts there
but clearly they are not
functioning properly
but all that shows us is the parts have broken
i remember my stereo
i dropped my stereo
it falls on the stage it doesn't work anymore it stops giving off music by
boombox stops giving off music
that's not because previously
we had we had cd inside of it we have some batteries we drop the
whole thing it's not as though previously there was something non material
you've got all the same parts there but the parts are now
they're not connected to each other in the right way
the energy is not flowing from the batteries through the wires to the CD components
there is nothing mysterious from the physical is perspective about the idea that a physical
object can break
so although we need to offer a story
what makes the parts work when they are connected with each other and interact in
the right way
there's no need to appeal to anything beyond the physical
let's try to refine the argument suppose we say
you need to appeal to the soul in order to explain that is that the
body moves around flails
the body sort of
act purposefully
we need some things that have to be pulling the strings to be directing the
that's what the soul does
so says that we do a-list
and response to the physical it is going to say
yes it's true bodies don't just move around in random patterns human bodies don't do
so we need something to direct it but why could not just be
in particular
part of the body
plays the that part of the command module
suppose i got a heat seeking missile
you know which
tracks down the
the plane
as the plane tries to dodge it
the missile
correct its course
it's not just moving randomly moving purposefully
the better be something that explains its controlling the motions of the missile
for all that it could just be a particular piece of the missile but does
more gloriously we could imagine building some kind of a robot
does a variety of tasks
and it's not moving randomly but the test for all that are controlled by
the CPU
within the robot
so the the physical it says we don't need to appeal to anything as extravagant
as the sole in order to explain the fact that the bodies don't just move
randomly but they move in purposeful ways in our control
for each objection is the response you can imagine the jules coming back and saying
in that case the heat-seeking missile
the or the robot for that matter although it's doing things it's just obeying orders
and the orders were given to it from something outside itself
something program the robot or the muscle
so don't we need there to be something outside the body that programs the body
and that could be the all
that's a harder question must be something outside the body that controls the body well
one possibility of courses
why not say that people are just robots as well and we get our commands
from outside and
familiar religious views
god fields at order
dust adam is just a certain kind of robot then
god sort of breeze in the atom that are turning it on gets so we
maybe people are just commands robots commander from outside by god but that doesn't mean
that there's anything more of us than there is to the robot
that's one possible
the response of course is why couldn't we have robots that just building more robots
and then if you ask where did the commands come from the answer is well
when they were built
it were built in such a way as to sort of have certain instructions and
they begin to fall followed just like people have the genetic code perhaps
gives us various instructions that we begin to fall under certain innate psychology or what
have you
well that's the i quickly becomes very very messy
and the of the fan of the soul
begins to one approaches but look
we're not just robots
we're not just robot with some sort of program in our brain that we're following
we've got free will
and and robots cannot have free will and so there's got to be something more
less than robots can be physical things
this is an interesting argument but i think the new argument
so so we started with the the idea you needed to appeal to solve in
order to roughly explain why
human bodies move why were animated why we move non random ways
and i think it's
it's fairly clear
you don't need to appeal the souls in order to do that
appeal to the physical body suffices
i think to have an explanation as to
the difference between an animated and inanimate body
how bodies will move in non random ways of the brain is our CPU
will behave in a deliberate purposeful ways just like the robot will behave in deliberate
purposeful ways so this initial argument things not compelling
still we might wonder what about this new argument
what about the fact that so we said look there is that there is a
family of
arguments all of which have the general structure inference to the best explanation you need
sold in order to explain feature as plug different feature f and you get a
argument the one we started with
you need the body to explain the at the animation in either sold to explain
so this will be i would be tried to go very slow in the first
five minutes so that we can weigh the way for people come in because you
know people are still lying up for stop coffee
so this is the tutorial joint work we use my
phd student meanwhile and she's graduating so if you're looking for someone working on uncertain
data trees can occur
and professor UV in chinese university of hong kong and germany in the university of
new south wales in australia
and the statue of the talk will be as follows
you know
four KDE we are really concerned about the application how to motivate the problem so
we spend the first half hour to give you a series of examples showing how
uncertainty may come into data in what applications you see uncertainty and how why we
need to model uncertainty carefully
and then mean we'll talk about it from all those of uncertain probabilistic data
then she would how you was the simplest case and how complexity can come in
when you have all kinds of constraints and was the state of the state of
the art and also tell you what cannot be done so far
and then we have a coffee break
after that we in that switch
the order from the US slice you have
we first talk about olaf and uncertain
on uncertain public data
and we would talk about mining uncertain copyright status
after that you
so i say OK since we need to do data mining on uncertain
published data so
there are already some reasons on query answering
those reasons could be useful
for data mining for example there are some index methods
and there are some of the fiction query answering methods from properties data base committee
so we talk about a particular type of indexing and ranking and krisper preference korean
spatial queries
then you summarize the clock and then we can have some discussion
in fact
the first came we want to make why this tutorial is important why you in
the right role
is that uncertainty is inherent
in many many applications almost everywhere
basically this is due to
two kinds of reasons the first reason is that when we collect data we need
to use
all kinds of equipment
and we use equipment equipment has its limitations
that's the way we
observe the
the real world and the way we collect data
may introduce some uncertainty in the data we collect
and another way is that well in some application part degree those of social science
uncertainty is so in higher even
no matter how you improve your data collection you cannot completely
remove it
for example one question is that if there's is some way on say whether how
much you like or you dislike
mccain and obama
well you one object to give you a school
you know
the school is sort of like estimation
so this is where the important aspects
so let's look at a little bit more detail on data collection using sensors
we know that says the network is already a hot topic in these days
and we use all kinds different sensors to collect data for example we use the
most sensors electronic magnetic sensors mechanical sensors on the thickness and applications that involve like
in environment surveillance security
manufacturers extends all the all these different aspects
but was an ideal sense
and i do census you have such a property is that well
it is
so that the output signal of censor is
linearly proportional to the to the value you want to monitor
and also
if we have such an ideal sense then we only need to meet the need
to know old one thing is called sensitivity which is the ratio between the output
signal and measured property
then you you know there's a o point then you can calculate once you have
the output value then you can derive measure to measure and and monitor
OK so this is the general that's the ideal case
sensors have all kinds of different areas
in that not every error may be to uncertain
let's first look at some
not too bad errors which
do not introduce uncertainty
the first kind of
measure is that it is cos st
sensitivity error
that is when the sensor is a sign he has a specified
however when it says he's produced
and also deployed after a while
the sensitivity may change
so that there is a difference between the specify
since this value and the real sensitivity value so there is difference
but why this error is not the important because you can measure that
you can use these are the test that you can really calculate the difference band
you can correct
and another important is also is the bias in this case that the zero point
was the
and then this may
change over time
due to the a k of the all the
secrecy all those things but again this what these error can be corrected by some
and also
while we want the censorship in linear
it may be nonlinear
well no matter how
i mean it is as long as you can have enough test data you can
always you know corrected off the rikers so this is not the problem
there some errors which
that in terms of introducing a lot of uncertainty
we call these
uncertain errors of dynamic errors
this history
i wonder if there is that
it's estimated that deviate
you know by
rapid change of the measure for example if you want to measure the temperature if
the temperature change very fast your sense may not be able to catch up with
the change
and you never
can be exactly accurate exactly calculate was the you know the difference
heuristic which is that in that i showed you and what is it saying what
the number it's giving
measure the actual distance of this step from the walls
and since you have an actual plan in front of you you can say that
if you of the four state and the plan is fifteen states land fifteen minutes
before your post
OK and some other that that you're trying to predict
and so given state you want to predict what do and what they want to
bring in the training example for inductive learning is features of the relaxed plan sort
other than the data which they tried to but the thing that seems to work
last plan itself
and describe the relaxed plan in terms of some feature of the features that uses
the taxonomic representation
and they then of the class but each of these flat lands the class label
the that distance between what the like plan idealistic because they and what the true
heuristic is
OK so you actually computing that and they essentially do a straightforward in active learning
and that and they do quite well in terms of
guessing the correct difference
OK and things that we the heuristic level one of the nice things
that was the planner were going the wrong direction
OK but you know what give you an unsound black
OK and actually they present results showing that they do quite well at least compared
to f which is one of the better ones which doesn't
OK so one thing that the study of complete this part of the lecture
in terms of search for
that's control knowledge and learning
i want you to learn now
are things like invariances things saying you know if this you cannot have these facts
for any given
are you can learn simple search control rules of you that talked about you can
talk about you can learn adjustment rules in order to learn dual rules if you're
going to use on plants and so on but still open is the kinds of
complex state sequence rules that land uses you can do with a simple which is
that i work in general are better now i think the evidence can learn about
local knowledge
and that kind of the came that shop that's on the knowledge base planner uses
that do
also is not actually to learn
because of those that's about the state of the art right now in
learning such control problems
if you remember
i was talking about decided to improve the the existing planning to speed up planning
performance another way of speeding up
the performance is to forget about the planet and that the known domain specific plan
from examples
OK so i see enough successful plans and i learned how to do planning domain
OK there is in fact a large amount of literature this in fact this comes
close to some of the reinforcement learning work that has probably been discussed by setting
the saying might be discovered by the money and i'll talk about a couple of
points of contact with the fact this picture of me
so learning from scratch basically you don't have a plan that you're trying to improve
any more for all you care about is how do you do planning you know
the past
and one idea is that well i need to to know me global policy
OK so
what i need is
for a given state and the goals
i should know what is the action to be them
if i were in a state s and my set of rules that you want
to g seven this is the action but
OK so if you don't have these goals here then that just simple is an
MDP policy
now you're doing is that MTP policy assumes that that's for the single MDP here
you're talking about changing also learning
o estado de goals and then we're back into
OK and a variety of approaches have been done and if if you can learn
either this and the quality of the approximation is in essence you learning domain specific
that's wonderful
o the idea of approaches have been done for example in edinburgh in the last
sold do
explanation based learning and induction to learn domain specific planners to talk about a little
bit card rounded explanation is that the inductive learning but we expect that successful
i mean that article is about successful
and drawing directions on the edges not because we're looking at directed graphical models but
this because we're thinking about how the message passing updates work
thank you
right so got a bunch of other messages on
sorry about this
if hopefully we'll get it right over time right
so got
other nodes that are passing messages
there's no t
right so the arrows as i was saying indicate the direction in which the messages
are traveling
so we have for instance you want to t that the function of xt that
flows along that edge
then t is taking these messages it's taking the product of them it's doing local
computation it's either max or some
and it's passing that result
along this edge to its neighbour
so what we'd like to understand this
how is this message updated and the precise way in which it's updated is what
i've written there
right so you taken max
that's the max product
you maximize over XT
if you're doing some product you some over XT that's the only difference between the
two forms of the algorithm
and then
i'll use my compatibility notation it's the
whether we use the site functions or the exponentials of them it's the same thing
right so this
site he sits there and
so i t is the
function that sits on the edge
and then we have a product the red terms this product over all your neighbours
except the one that you're passing two
so everything and if t means the set of neighbors of node t
so this means the product over all you all vertices that are neighbors of t
all these guys
except for the guy that you're passing two
and what you do is you should collect the messages from the neighbours and you
should multiply them up
rearrange hopefully
i can see everything at once
to focus
closer for a different way
it's a little bit better
is it
right so now you have is you have an operation you have an algorithm
which at some level the nodes don't need to know anything about the rest of
the graph apart from their neighbors as the only thing they need to know
right so no t
at every time in every round for every one of its outgoing everyone's neighbors it's
can collect messages other neighbours multiply them perform local operation max or some it's going
to pass or relay the message along the outgoing edge
i the same time it would also collect things from u one u two and
as an would relay that information to u three
so t would actually compute in this case for messages every round it was in
one scheduled compute for messages and send them out along its outgoing edges
at the same time as would be computing things and sending it to t
as might also be sending things to other parts of the graph
OK so that that is the max product algorithm what we've derived and
what happens
is are used different she but so those are the message updates
at the end of the day when the algorithms converge to talk about convergence in
a minute
you can use this algorithm to compute
either what are called max marginals
or some marginals
so some marginals the thing you use to
it's just the
we will talk during the following forty five minutes of ontological engineering
and ontological engineering refers to the set of activities that we
we do when you we build ontologies
it is also related with the ontology lifecycle that we
that we follow the myth of the methodology that we use for building the ontologies
and of the tools
and languages that support the the building the building process
so i probably know there are several methodologies that allows you to build ontologies from
some of these methodologies
there was
method they have force methodology
i think this approach this ontology sense of
knowledge and the agent but you know this method were built at the end of
nine days during the last year and new needs appear to automated with the construction
and with the network ontologies
by distributed teams in the sense that
we can build ontologies collaboratively by people who were located in different locations
and this ontology should be
should be
by means of use of existing resources not building this ontologies so
in this talk i will focus on the process of building
ontology ontology networks
by reusing
this is the resources
the question we have is that we want to build an ontology sound like to
know which one of the activities involved in the ontology development process
which one is the goal of each activity
so they carry out each its activity what is the relationship of the different activities
with the others
where can i find ontologies with the goal of reusing them
and how
can i be the ontology for
my application the most important thing is if i need
a single ontology or if i need an ontology network
so first we
so the first question
that we will analyse see what is the neon glossary of
see what is in a table
of recommended and if applicable activities what is the development process when we build ontologies
in the network
so the idea already know there are a lot of activities involved in the ontology
development process people talk about
ontology specification ontology conceptualisation ontology mappings ontology alignment ontology evolution merging and
if you analyse it turned out to you will find a lot of activities and
sometimes the activities are not defined in the same way in different papers so the
continental city of activities to indentify and also which won rdf TV these two we
carry out when building ontologies
global collaborative and we have identified
fifty five activities they are publishing the
now website
there you can find definitions of
i mean after all these activities on this slide
for instance if we focus on knowledge acquisition for
ontologies you will get to the finish line
knowledge acquisition for
ontology comprises activity for capturing knowledge
from a variety of sources so we distinguish between ontology elicitation ontology learning ontology population
and for each of these activities you will
ontology elicitation ontology learning ontology population you will find a natural language definition the most
important thing is that these activities definition has been already in
there has been consensus weighted by
the thirteen parties participating in the near close oceans for forty forty five fifty
people has already participated
in this in this process
so the second thing i mean once you know that there is a lot of
david is involved in the ontology development process the next question is that of the
national that we have in this district is to provide you with a set of
recommended i enough if applicable table of activities i mean some sort of these activities
are mandatory
and other activities are optional when you build your ontologies and you can see here
that we end up with an ontology ontology concert twenty station to carry out
ontology evaluation
you should integrate the ontology with other ontologies are you should perform kind of knowledge
probably you will also do some kind of ontology served as well as kind of
ontology a specification
so maybe these activities could be
it could be i mean are required for the ontology building process but other activities
are up to it are not mother told in the sense that it depends on
the case it depends on your ontology
so in that case ontology learning which is the process of building automatically the ontology
is not always needed for
building an ontology or ontology localisation which means that to transform an ontology which is
written in the language for instance in these two core and or or two french
or german so ontology localisation could be seen like a kind of option at