company i can remember what it is
it you know and and you know in two years after the first computer anymore
be something else
even faster scales just unbelievable things just
you seem to scale
we're learning how to better distribute management you know the kind of the innovation of
the of the domain naming scheme again was that not only did distributed data but
it distributed the management you cant
and information systems you cannot escape maintenance
so being able to distribute that kind of load is critical to have a lot
of applications and is what makes things like knowledge acquisition on the on the web
if you don't know the story of captures a strongly encourage if this maybe if
this time at the end i can quickly go into a different for those of
you have never heard the story of how
spammers broke the the captures these all images on web pages that are supposed to
test if your
potter of person
but a great example of how
you know the human gray matter on the web make certain problems solvable
and then you know other approaches imperfect approaches that use heuristics or statistics or things
to just guess at an answer
you know in in the absence of
something perfect that will scale to the size of the web
i heuristic search fine i mean that's what people use
i again i never cease to be amazed at the extent to which
this is happening on the web the sharing of knowledge
we need
we need somehow to
you know to manage that you it's great that this is happening but you can't
ignore the fact that
most people are it's
so these kinds of things seem to work is not enough you know we need
notions of trust people are working on all this i think is very important
what time is
o i
thank you
this is a this is a completely personal view
what i see the promising trends
first of all
almost back to where we were when i symbolic was machine on my desk
not quite there yet
but some of the
software development environments today are
almost there
the kind of knowledge engineering i can do today is almost at the speed
what i missed my was which
there is right there control super hypermedia bought
those great days
i really like this idea of using wikis to do knowledge acquisition i think it
knowledge acquisition
i think it really fits in nicely with the way that non
expert knowledge engineers
express themselves i mean most people outside of this community express their knowledge in text
they write things down and in the in the business world actually wikis are really
catching on if not already caught on and established technology that people within organisations used
to share
the sort of knowledge of the group
to make proposals and to criticize and so forth
it's really very actively used within within businesses
and integrating that into the
in two and knowledge acquisition process i think it's a fantastic idea i saw
tripoli i this year demo
from the underworld guys markets and
that was funded by the halo two project to do
knowledge acquisition in the semantic media wiki
so i hope you guys can expose that to the to the rest of the
world i think that's really cool
so i i i thought i really think the powerset ideas are great when i
don't know if it's going to succeed but not going to predict the future anymore
but i really think it's really think it's a nice idea and i hope it
works in one of the great things i see there see happening all over the
place actually
very recently
is that the knowledge represent representation in natural language processing communities which split sometime in
the mid seventies to go focus on their own problems
we are starting to come back together again like like never before in the time
really seems right both community seem
to be mature enough
so that they can actually make use of the established work in the other fields
and really that was not happening
in a big way up until very recently
i think that's incredibly promising
i love the pedia
and and limited experience for free freebase but it also looks like a really nice
again pushing this collaborative open
but with a little bit of control
the idea of of
developing knowledge bases
and so
you know that's how you scale and let's not forget these are are the first
ones i mean one that's been around for while IMDB is
really big
collaboratively developed database
of knowledge about
the entertainment
the main and you know site
i started doing this twenty years ago course
they are done it all already
it's kind of a different idea site but there's analogies here
so i would have rejected the dbp paper for example things like the the twenty
but i think it's great i really think it's great to use it all the
time hey shameless
kind of
not really promotion but
you know these people IBM research built the scalable
OWL DL reasoning which is really cool you should check it out it's it you
know it's not complete all the time but it's incredibly fast for what it does
and it makes certain reasoning problems
possibly even if it's not perfect
and hey a totally shameless
the rules
working group has released
time a
for the basic logic dialect rule language which was edited by harold believe here somewhere
and michael kifer was not
i encourage you really would like to get feedback here so i encourage you all
to check it out
and you asked to brown who here somewhere which was here
i wrote a companion document for this describing how RDF can be used
with this
rules dialect so
check it out rules are
the rules are going to be
the next thing on the web based on the semantic web i think
plus you know as well but this is the story of the reason for beta
the contribution of its response to to
one know
and then if you want to know what the
the other
no the output of the amplifier they said you just have to feel it seems
which if you look at the formula it go to infinity of course it's not
possible under and also
just because you have limitations on the query
have to do with the notion that if you look some sort of the
once you know in in
but if you know that you are not interested in looking at all the frequency
of your signal so in certain frequency on
and this is what we do is shaper
so we just kept
the frequency so that would have just the notable conclusion which is in this particular
frequency of windows three
so to do that you know if you don't
lowpass filter on hypersphere
so long as is just campus don't series so that
plus is still the see all
so just very very similar new
so this is the goal
deposit to
and decorations just as it was shown on
on the indie
the capacity to hold and then you can put a number of them so they
can have
you if you doing so what is it
to know is is that you can optimize quite alot you you know
we that
in the nineteen
it is that there will be a lot of work in the past about making
optimal text
no today because of the ability that we have to make
did not have to detect conversion quite early and quite fast
all of these a lot of this filtering is done in fact in these stanford
from anything but
what is important is that this formula is shown what is the
output of the function of the capacitance of the
the band capacitance which is the sum of the detector capacitance the input capacitance of
the preamplifier the time shipping so the township in this
the time of maximum size that the users
the response of the filter uses
the want
in the late on slows in these cells is peaking time
don't thought
at that point and what is now is that you will find an optimum so
which is
for small value of between them this is not mostly contributing
four i of fifteen times but i don't know if this is mainly contributing and
you've got to humans
so that was for for for an application is to otherwise you know
signal to noise
what is important also to know is the most dominant demand is the capacitance to
detect soviet bloc data shows what the film between the
the technology in terms of knowing that you see
the is the value of the capacitance and i have a sort the noise is
whatever technology
in case you want to make design is the most important causes that you have
to make also optimisation
to define the size size
this is very much detail and they will
shortly finished
the new hall
design would be made directly to design would be made
when you so you are but in application where you know that you have to
charge preamplifier with you know what is that
the capacitance you know what does the word is again you won't accept
so you will have to to use some kind blocks of
using transistors in terms of amplification which is common basic common emitter or common credit
i don't coincide that and then you make
you have to make a first schematics to to
to see what it is
you can say i think the schematic of an open fire upon existing and just
compute but in fact you can simplify to it so you can you make your
and then you have to start
thinking about
what can one do i want to have mean because the challenge is important we
have seen because of the short knows what
again do i won't accept i on and then you will be fine
this three main elements
you can make your home which is not very difficult to replace the tallest told
by the equivalence between so of week on
which are just
which are driven by
by page
and then we define
convolutional neural audio amplifier on the which
things you can then you have to make aliens complete schematics which is that
in addition
in addition to these
this is the tallest of this one and this one which are just about over
the amplifier itself you have to have some chance sources selection bias everything
and then you want what you want to this systematic in
in this by simulator
and then you can you can then make a full and the simulation of the
system so so
money they took me out to dinner that's thank you very much you double by
earning capacity but that that's not what i was trying to be
training consultant manages now
let me means that we share with you now
one but i think is
we should have been doing first of all
let me say that
i think the business education
is an extreme things
two good in fact to be wasted just on those who want to claim
a business career
i remember
my son coming back from school aged sixty
and they just being done as a foundation course in
business studies
and he said that
last week we heard about opportunity cost
he said
that's how can anybody liver proper life without understanding opportunity cost
and i said this a very good question i know an awful lot of people
who through their lives away doing what they call a secure job the opportunity cost
of which was never get around to doing what they want to do opportunity cost
absolutely vital
in life was thinking about anything to do with the future and he learned from
business studies at the age of sixty
very good
i like to think that have more about politicians have been educated in business studies
both here and in america and they might have understood about the concept of theory
you might wonder why on earth was sensible
to allow laymen brothers borrow thirty five times their assets
when we normally consider it unwise to borrow more than four times around his salary
to buy a house
i don't think they understood the concept
i don't think any of them could we balance sheet
so when they talk about you know
we tuning
of re correcting the balance sheet i don't think most of our politicians have actually
talking about
i actually think the business education should be for everyone
but business education is not the same as management development
it's unnecessary
management but it's not enough
it's not even the important stuff
in the web
but we should give it to everybody that we we can find
because it makes life
much more exciting even such simple little things like the eighty twenty rule of thumb
eighty percent of your success comes from twenty percent of your efforts the work is
a wonderful way to stop people wasting a hell of a lot of the time
if they're to genoa
they don't teach those things in our schools only
in our business schools
i'd like to see therefore
everybody taught business education earlier on in life i'm delighted
the most popular study
in our british universities and business studies at the undergraduate level
and i have a horrible thing to confess to but i actually think
an NBA
is a compressed version
three year undergraduate course in business studies
compressed and delivered and told to people who are already graduates something else
there's nothing wrong with that
better late than never
they needed my goodness me
business education
you know it doesn't come to about thirty five is very valuable
but it just isn't about management
it's about analysing business problems
did the real thing that i believe in to be honest is executive education
particularly if executive education
it is in this sense of the part-time right
that the course
the institution of i'm proudest of in my life is the open business school in
england which i helped to start
well basically everything that is told
not in the classroom of course
and the open university but
through the internet and television
is actually practiced
by them in their own organisations and the essays in the papers so the right
based on putting the theory into practice as they say no hard
because actually
i think
the education
it's best to find
for people of mature age
this experience
finally understood
in tranquility
because i have to tell you
you can have experience but if you don't understand that experience means
you can't repeated
the best place to understand
it is in tranquility
in a place like a college or school
with the aid of concept
i like to say
the only thing that i learned the sloan school at MIT
was that i didn't need to go there
because i already knew it
the only trouble was that i had to go there to find out that i
already knew
to me it is a great compliment when somebody comes up to me
having read one of my books listen into one of my told
and said
i knew all that you know i knew all that
the thing was i didn't know i knew
until you tell me how i knew
the concepts can be very exciting
but actually this
the allied to experience it doesn't really work
let me see if i can make this work
i spend an awful lot of my time
drawing that line
of businesses and for people
which is of course
line of everything you see it gets the first because in order to get anything
one way to interpret this presenting these things called informational links
there's this we'll connections the world maybe laws of nature are things like that between
to consequent
causal connections or other but
inference is not always need such really or
certain connections
ross thought that like
they will be
the situation is and i think the situation c is the the whole meaning containment
it's a wonderful book called and you so larger brain he's at latrobe university
a lot of relevant are developed in science
and nationalistic thing to study
but he said well let's just do it this way
i mean come here means or
so if you remember sequent calculus like
the call on the right-hand side of the turnstile
forensic com on the left-hand side a turnstile today as well
when we get to greg restall
from literature
i used so the idea here is that so is we start off with a
or b
they were the two cases one which is true it is
the end of the century one which should be is contained in let's do them
and there's all sorts of restrictions on things on how you do this that needed
to make that's come right we won't talk about this i give you a flavor
this all these things two different strings per so we're going to them in parallel
with one another
OK so let's look at this is supposed we start a or and
b or c
from that we can infer
OK just by
and elimination
it's what he calls or elimination
that's his new for eliminations look it's here than that
that is both of these in so it's in the same stream and its we
can use
previous caesarean and
should not using them
which line numbers and
this is what
now what do we do we do something we do in the sequent calculus we're
trying to prove distribution and if that always seems a bit silly these you might
say yourself
here we just limit or that we probably could but
here's the rule he is this is the same as the sequent calculus
using or introduction twice
we can
and were working on parallel right we and
this is a list and destroying that to that
OK already do in secret can and with
how to get rid of one of them
well what
you just get rid of that we call
other the contraction
but it is a contraction wrong
he calls upon the national
so many have
in the first
so this proof
it is it's much nicer
then you have seen proof the proof in
the proof of this kind of
of the distribution is horrible it's huge
holger he really inside
so you see
john one
these improvements
reaches the also
i would say well received
and as you can see
see idea you in the
remember there is no
one the things that
but he's really
they tend be
a host to
the two
so c
and this
right approach to
so we have something to say
and he said
we do
choose a lot
the project
well as a whole
we will be
well said
in recognition use
right this
so is this is i the see
we also
and so
so since
so you
that is
so so
one this projection you'd
this is a region in which it was to
it goes without saying that the
here is this
right approach
for was the
so you know
the rows in the ropsm
the positive
this is
so this
that's you know the
during the two
so that's really
it seems that
the surface of the ball
then we
so what there
you will have to be
until two
is the
four d
on set
we must have
two keep
the minimum is 5 I can't do it with less how how you see that
I cannot cover those with 5
because of
that's right my line will have to my lines have to cover all 5 of
those those circle but I don't even care about
just a cover those 5 circle ones is going to take the 5 lines
so that's why that's the weak duality
that the number of matches is always glossary
the number of lines with any time I've got a match I've got someone's that
I need that many lines except those aligned can cover to NMF right there a
lot no line could cover 2 of these at once
aligned can only cover 1 marriage and maybe some extra stuff but it's 5 lines
security 5 matches
you see the weak duality then it easy argument but the equation the fact that
the number of assigned made made a statement the current change this problem by changing
some of these 2 zeros does that now
is that now prevent 5 matches for role occasionally make that is 0 also
the class
right so what else do I wanted to know is that this 1
the environment
make that is 0
it is half time right so tell
what to make is 0 all of what is 0 there yet but everybody and
you add up for 1 somewhere else well do 1 and then you'll tell me
that there's not enough arise
that is definitely not alright alright so
you say that's not enough
and get there I'm I'm removing them
yeah this this right
OK is that is a match possible there is still it's instant handling match the
can't take another 1 away
well which would I'll take 1 of these away like that when I didn't like
that 1 4 are now again OK now we believe that only the 4 the
we can only marry off for right
but now how do we prove
because you're gonna find for lines that cover everybody
and that would say
no water for lines way doesn't says question what no I won't buy it so
if I find 4 lines and cover everybody then there can only be for matches
because if there were 5 matches I could not cover all of us alright now
you really what for very 1st 2 columns and rows OK and that left me
a matrix of zeros submatrix of zeros which should should tell me that trouble where
the trouble
this this matrix of zeros tells me that girls girls and 1 2 and 4
uh don't obviously tells me that boys 3 4 and 5 are no good
are not acceptable and therefore
so the only boys that acceptable
far I have 3 girls and the only boys are acceptable and the remaining 1
and 2 here which is was this 1 2 5 1 arose when
I thought these heroes and the zeros and the zeros referred altogether refers to girls
want to far from work for 1st 1 2 5 and they will not
match boys 3 4 fiive only Match . 1 2 and here I have a
set of 3 girls and only 2 boys
1 2 and 5
the only 2 boys released to avoid yes yes yes I could express this in
graph language to that's right that's right yeah so it's it's yeah it's it's a
bit that's what the problem sounds like a joke problem but it appears all over
the place as a very quite a fundamental matching so that's right matching is the
or assigning sometimes assignment problem is were used matching is not a perfect matching is
complete yet so it's
so let's matching problem
so maybe I could go on and it connects to this type of bipartite 2
parts graph ok so that it can I
go to a 2nd problem but any question on this would
but 3 groups
yes yesterday that so a tripartite graph I don't know
you know I mean it's so that you're thinking like a graph here this is
how this subject grows and and the
and some directions lead to a beautiful theory of they're all going lead to some
duality if you give me a linear programs uh but uh
so as I say I could have formulated this problem as a linear programming problem
but and what's special about it is the corners would have turned out to be
images so that I only really had to look at images and the microsatellite OK
but I try to tell you about this max-flow problem
take them take the example shown on network
in the general english SMT because most assertions are
applicable across dialects of english but
strictly speaking that probably should be american english seventy
it is possible to have two
normally they would be
in different microtheories
we have common english misspellings mt
things go in there
OK so we have these language and we also have lexicon he's
the lexicon and is used for
establishing an infrastructure for defining the language so
predicates that are specific to certain language will be defined
in a lexicon entry
like slovene has to all
and english doesn't so to always be defined in the
in the slavic
any other slovene
mexican mt
and you don't use the lexicon MTV's for making
the concept were mapping so that's something you have to know
lexicographer OK
so much for microtheories forward
shall we
look at the key be a little bit
just see things
so we have
the english lexicon and t
is a constant in the cave here
it's constant like every other constant
as i said it's the empty for defining predicate specific to english
and they're all
all these
is organised in this hierarchy
english lexicon and t what's two english-language nt that's maybe a better example
american english to
american english and he
is underneath
english MT in this hierarchy and as indicated with this general ante assertion
american english antigen on t
english seventy
so this general and t
predicate relates to microtheories
let's look at the the comment for general and t
so we can see it will how it's
so channel and t
comment is is reflexive and transitive
if so have every MT
general antees to itself intransitive
binary predicate relates to microtheories
it means that the
the first arguement is a specialisation or extension of the second
this means that everything that's true in the general and t
is true and this
spec mt
and this is expressed from both in the second he sees general and t
the most general
microtheory inside his is based KB and every other microtheories
all of these assertions and base KB which means that
the number of assertions in this cave is very small
because of those only the ones that everybody wants to see so if you have
an assertion in general
english and
all of the spec entities general english and you will see that
the solution
so we want to say so american english MT
and if you
well we can just sort of
go along so english MT
it's more general than that
if you
if you click here
on the left-hand panel and look for the things
if i click on this this will give me everything
every assertion in which
he was and he is the second arguement of about relations
so this will give me all of the spec anti-social
two there
quite a
it's quite a large number and OK computer is lexical and he
cyclists MT the
see for the contents of cyclists and hikers for
clicking on microtheory constants k
the closed to bugs l above report
let's the
it's funny
well you can see these are all technical
so the technical
things about i see
the cyc system symbol
this is an assertion in the site question TV cyc system
symbol to what multiwordstring and everything mean but that's just illustrate that
the lexical knowledge is
organised in these
and entities
the graph
general and reflexive
and transitive predicate
so we
that's the question
it's this
that allows for cycles
empty circles are
to be avoided
i think an empty cycle leads to
so that the outside my
it's pretty well
so that was an o microtheories now i'm going to talk about the kinds of
semantic predicates
all dog and quote
and concepts like
castello dog
there are two
possible routes
predicate like namestring relates string to a concept directly
elizabeth coppock
OK so now
we are really going to move on to something else
factor analysis PCA
gaston in distributions are
simple to understand their easy to use
there have been there have been limited in what they can do right
we can we can summarize all of them
in thinking that what we're really assuming is that the data comes from a multivariate
distribution that's basically the common thing two or three right
and now
data doesn't need to data there's need to come from from a multivariate gaussian distribution
right so they could be organised in different clumps right so you may
you may need more complicated models right
in order to to to get there i'm going to try and interest you four
i was fast
look at this
this is borrowed from your standing about who go very nice NIPS tutorial
that's here
thank you wonder how
images of horses looked computer they probably look
the same as this things here looked to new
OK so here's a little exercise
we we label
three of these things
and we call them too fast
OK i know my question to you
think about
how many more two fires there are in this slide
OK OK OK OK OK OK OK OK
process three
who says for
who says five
ss six
who says seven
forces eight
OK so i
does anyone similar night
not really
interesting distribution
all right so let's come here
so in this role here is only to find these a so we are searching
for for the extra ones are right so it's not not for the circuit ones
so is there any need to find this role here
OK who says yes
all right so where is it starting from the left
this guy here
OK and why heard someone said there wasn't too far
that's fine
i don't know if it's too far enough
but can be you know it has a sort of flat thing in the in
the bottom it has like a little
stick and then some
o thing on top and what about in this role of the two thousand israel
OK with which the fourth is going to go anymore to first
what about this road
OK so it doesn't guy anymore to first
what about this right here
the guy here
what about this one coming two phases in this role
which ones
OK so this one two three four
so one two three four
five and six
maybe there six
maybe not i don't know
some of you guys said there were five when you want to change your vote
OK so which one of them do you disagree with
this one here is the metaphor for you OK
fair enough
OK so why why were you able to
to actually have a strong opinion on the number of two fuzzy that are in
this picture
well the reason is
you sort of see in the universe
here OK
and in different objects in this universe right
and then you using how different things can be so you have
an internal representation for
metric or similarity they have immediately built right
and they have decided
to do some clustering in your mind
and that's the reason why
you've found that they were actually
a number of additional
two fires in the picture
but you need you need the metric unit the metric i'm sure that at this
point you already have made up your mind about
i just i just sort of
i just sort of assumed that you had done this clustering just give you name
for for some of the things in it
OK i'm really scared of going into psychology here or perception or anything else
OK OK
but but when you but you
OK some sort of assuming that
so so one can of course the clustering in a hierarchical manner right because sort
i can sort of say OK make two groups or i could say make three
groups make for groups and you would sort of divide things differently
OK but let's not do because we are running a bit late i
OK so that's that's clustering so now
let's sort of
formalise things a little bit so the idea is that
you want to put an objects into into k groups that we're within each of
the k groups objects are similar to one another right
i think it's quote from david mackay's book you know things at the wrong runway
and think that are agreement on runway actually in david mackay's book this is nice
example of this sort of
picture where he sort of says imagine two scientists talking to each other and they
found some very interesting animals
and one of the most explained to the other it is
any sort of says
you have to walk that way and you go past
the big thing that has
a brown stand and lots of little
green objects that are of this certain shape and then you move on to new
places of the one that has a much thinner brown stem and that one has
also little red balls and it also houses green flat things would be different and
so on and like that three or four times and enough to pass he describes
the force of the concerns there
and it would have been a lot easier to say
it's after the fourth street
but that means that you have to define the concept of tree
OK so
a better description of of of of the data right being able to name trees
in in communications of course of k means is called vector quantization really
and it so it's a way of compressing the data
you can also
you can also sort of do it to detect novelty something doesn't really fall in
any of the classes you have you can sort of say oh here an anomaly
or something like that
and this one here is a little bit farfetched perhaps always has probably thinking about
you know
but that's actually a sort of
but i think the same because how do you know we data raised before you put your basis functions
so what's the solution to this well there's a lovely elegant solution which is u sprinkle
and i mean sprinkled in the technical sense
i use sprinkle your basis functions across the entire
space and why
and how many sprinkles put when you put down infinity of them okay
if it was a cake that would be difficult
but this is mass
so it's possible
this leads the kernel methods
well this is loose outline what you do in order to do this what you can show you're doing
if you decide to start putting a basis functions any and then you start placing the interval delta mu
so basically this is across the real line
in fact we can do this in a high dimensional space but for the moment
the high dimensional space is one-dimensional so this just to be clear that's the schematic
this is a one-dimensional input in practice this will be high dimensional input function you
but i can't plot so easily on the slides i'm doing one dimensional plot but
also for this process
using one-dimensional
if we have the location parameters in effect said the thought that some point hey
and then add a little bit in each time so we basically uniformly spacing these
basis functions out is also worked a few randomly distributed them as galcians you get
the same result
because the distances in feature space depend only on the inner product between two basis functions
it turns out that you can decrease delta mu to increase the number of basis
functions and then you can also take the limit where you put these basis functions
to infinity
and you end up with the kernel so the bit that i haven't sorry
that you can
you know the key trick
he says
the third
is the
those distances in
the expected distance between two data points in the function space is always given by the inner product yeah
these basis functions vectors
and what's going on is this is the standard trick is the length of these guys is becoming infinity
but because
they're both infinity
and you're only evaluating things in terms a product you're rewrite what was by
if x
transpose phi
x jay
you can rewrite it
as a kernel function
now that's
one way of introducing the kernel trick that you may hear more about when john
cunningham talks about guessing processes and you're also a little bit more about for me
so that's what's going on with the kernel trick
and that's a more a guassian process perspective on what the kernel trick is
so now
we've got kernels
and what goes on in the kernel trick is actually this scandal has interpretation as
being the covariance those functions we're computing the director variance
and the reference missing there is that
shall come from smaller but this is sometimes known as the kernel trick moving from
this to this so i u x when i wrote it on the
because i'm used inputs being experts had there actually why
so this is the
okay why
hatch all the properties of a mercer kernel and is also positive definite actually has
all the properties what we call the covariance function so can function is a function
that can be used to generate a covariance matrix
and in fact what's going on here is instead of
this is against gaussianprocess point-of-view instead of talking about functions like this
and then putting a prior over w
what we're actually doing
is putting a prior
on this guy directly
we don't need specifies a guassian process because we only need the covariance event
which is why i think people in the capital community don't tend to like
specify guassian process
because they're not means you're saying something about the other moments which you don't in some sense need say
just look can appreciate
you can just talk about the second moment the second moment being a kernel
there is some utility saying is calcium because you can do a lot more calculations only uncertainty
but let's except that it doesn't need to be galcians for the rest of what i say to be true
so the mapping from data distance is now a guassian process and if we sample from this calcium process
what we see is now we've got these basis functions over infinite space it doesn't
matter where you sample you will see movement you will see wiggle
because we sprinkle these basis functions everywhere and now the distances between
three and minus three
well give something reasonable on average there will be far apart on average to close
things will be close together and that's because the function mapping is a mapping from
to this at space in a smooth way
so there is some other samples
okay so what she doesn't come out very clearly
but then gives us now
our distance matrix so we can use the kernel trick
what i've in some sense introduced in around about hopefully where you haven't seen before
is that the kernel trick
on distances
so this is the distance in the feature space
this form here
why i why i
minus two
why i
comma why jay
so i plus plus
why jay
i've been losing my voice over the last few days
hopefully by the end of the
two hours of still have some voice
the magic microphones l
help that okay i'm gonna be talking about bayesian modeling
first of all i just want to mention i put the slides online just right
now it's an analogy dot and you can see that you can start
lacked one based on pedia
so if you all downloaded now then nobody will be able to use the internet probably
the rest of the day
so i'm going be talking about bayesian modeling and i'm
i know that you've had quite a lot of advanced materials so far
you know especially following from
you know yesterday talking about humans coalesce and things like that
it's gonna seem very basic what i'm gonna say
but i think it's still very important to
start from the basics
and try to really understand what's going on why do
you know bayesian machine learning people do things the way they do
with the philosophy behind it what is the formal
the theoretical foundations behind it
how does it relate to the rest of machine learning
so in particular i'm talking about bayesian modeling and i wanna focus on these two words
modeling and bayesian inference at the beginning and tried it just very clearly described you
what i mean by these things and then i'll talk about more specific and more
and more technical material as i go on through i think i have maybe six
hours of lectures
this usually happens
just as motivation
it's a really exciting time to be doing
machine learning or modeling where in the middle of an information revolution there's huge amounts of data everywhere
affecting society
the way sciences are done
the way business is done
you know all this will hopefully have nice jobs because there's a lot of demand more
what we are trying to do
but of course with huge amounts of data
we really need tools for dealing with data and it's not not gonna focus on these large and this
quantity to
other data i'm going to focus on
be interesting things that we can do
with the data
so we need tools for modeling searching visualizing and understanding large datasets
end up
are modeling tools need to i feel be able to do certain things
modelling tools should be able to capture some form of uncertainty about our model structure
they should be able to capture
in the
in the data and the noise processes in the data data especially stuff that you
get nowadays on the web is very clean experimental data it's incredibly messy
we want tools that are automated that adapt
there are robots that scale well et cetera
the framework i'm going to be talking about is probabilistic modeling framework
so let me focus on the word model what some model to me
to me a model is
the description of possible data
one could observe from a system
it's a funny way of describing a model but i've come to sort of like this way thinking about models
so model
is a way of describing possible data you could observe
in any kind of domain you're trying to
and if it's not there then i don't understand what a model could be
if the model can predict
then there's no way of
o five buying model there's no way of telling whether mall it's good or bad
because ultimately
we have to evaluate models with respect to
our real world data
of-course models have served other purposes
models might also be
much more interpretable are understandable that the raw data
and those are kind of side benefits of models but ultimately their descriptions are possible data one could observe
now the framework we're going to take it sees the mathematics of probability theory to express all forms of uncertainty
i don't know is that we have in our model
if we do that's the nice thing is then we can use the same rules probability theory
what used to be called you know over a hundred years ago inverse probability or bayes rule
but it's basically application of the rules the probability theory
to allow us to infer unknown quantities adapt our models learn parameters
learn from data etcetera make predictions
now what i want to draw an analogy for u
you know a few hundred years ago
dunedin lightness and people like that
developed calculus
calculus was a mathematical language fore talking about rates of change
probability theory is a mathematical language for talking about uncertainty
okay so it's basically
all right
way of expressing uncertainty
okay so this is the probabilistic modeling framework that i'm gonna take and you know
you've seen this stuff death but basically
you know that's probably not base as
you said that
i think in this talk
there are some arguments is the only image obeys that
anybody claims could be a bayes but
there is some dispute about it
famous bayes rule is just a basic rule of probability theory
but when u
but nonconvex there's uh more to worry about
if at
hash matrix is not positive semi definite
that's basically the the definition being convex because the hessian matrix was
the same eight matrix was the hash novi objective function minus the sum why i
times the hash and to thee constraint functions and so on
if the thing is
is is is is is and is nonconvex than one of those things is not positive semi definite and so
this might fail
o nine messing up my notations hold on a second
and they go back to refresh my own memory what ages
yes that's the right so is this
and if it's not positive if the problem is not convex
something here is not positive semi definite
and if so if age is not positive semi definite the net
normal matrix and the dual matrix might fail to be positive definite
might not but it might not get two pieces to it
this here is positive semi definite
this is
that's always positive semi definite i guess that's an important point
eight transposed times dy
times eh is always positive semi definite
the way you see it
is to multiply by any vector call see
on the left multiplied by sea transpose
this is i checked positive semi definiteness
and this matrix d is a diagonal matrix with all nonnegative entries so i can take
and right is one-half do one half squared
and so this is
now all this can be factored this is basically
do you
to the one half
times a
time see
times the transpose that's so this is the norm of the vector squared is equal to this
and so the this is greater than or equal to zero
and so
when so the matrix eight transpose
times day diagonal positive entries times eight
is always
positive semi definite so this matrix is being added on
is positive semi definite so the passions here that this linear combination versions
this may not be positive definite but that might not be a problem because you've
also got these terms here adding helping you out
hands and so sometimes a non convex problem is is okay
you know
but you have to worry about when it's not okay
all right
so what are we gonna do if it's not okay
if if the
normal a matrix is
the dual norm a matrix is
not positive semi definite
then we lose the conditions that the conclusions in the previous theorem
and so we don't have descent directions
so feasible is not going to improve
always we got feasible because we are lucky
we won't necessarily a closed optimally because it's no longer going in the right direction
that's really bad
but you can regain those properties and having at least
going in the right direction descent properties
in a very simple manner i have to do
is perturbed the hash and with the diagonal perturbation lambda
if you can come up with a
a scheme for estimating a good lambda
then the nearer than here
get the descent properties back
again easily
and so you perturb there
age with this lambda you replace it with age this age till the in the
computation step directions and you can show that you have all the properties
a descent that you needed
and so
just a precise
if we let until the
dual normal matrix associated with age told instead of the
one is with age
then we have the same kind of result as we had before r if this do this perturbed dual normal
matrix is positive definite
the step directions are descent direction for the primal feasibility
end all the theorem slightly different actually and for the non complementarity
so the deviation from complementarity as measured w transpose why
so this the second stage is a little bit different from before it's not be
barrier function
going in the right direction but it's this going in the right direction but duality
theory tells us if we are feasible
end we
i have no complementarity the more optimal
it turns out that in this case that's exactly what you need so having these
things going in the right direction
o i'm sorry i forgot one thing
my mistake
we also have to have dual feasibility and we don't necessarily
stem direction uh improvement in the dual feasibility
and so
we have to do a line search to prefer to find a value of lambda
this within a factor
so what we do is a line search to find the value of land within a factor to the smallest
perturbation because you don't wanna
you know obviously got a big lambda times identity and make it
positive semi definite but
then you've
distorted too much
things will converge slowly
there wasn't bad enough even more things can go wrong
convex optimization
so if the problem is convex
the size of the semantic web
if i have network
i can give it to you arrive at least
what's the point of about the publishing process and some
that's not at all
is i house data that is you show
not just one which is of the
systems that present the semantic web client library
as an example of how and applications use of consuming data
on the web
in the following couple of minutes i will be introduction describe how the lab folks
how you get into a how you can use the command line interface of the
library and how we can integrate the lighting applications
before i go into the details and let me show you an example of that
say we want to know the the interests of people tunnels
we can represent this question by parker clear like this
and so this can be
we need several RDF documents from being tons full five
the about us contact
and we need the full phase of the reference desk
the persons a interest
given that all the data is published following the linked data principles and applications automatically
retrieved this
documents from the that and
process query over the whole set of documents
for this could be
the semantic web client library tree twenty nine
documents on the web
if this results
so what's the main features of the library
it was used to create the basically the whole weight of data using sparql queries
of find SP all queries which are simple triple pattern queries
the library retrieves
relevant RDF documents during query execution
and in order to discover these documents references http URI as follows see also link
follows links and HTML headers and a curious this image is
retrieved documents are the or
the local graph set
and later q executions can use these local copies
instead of retrieving this data
furthermore the library supports crystal
OK so for the introduction that describe how the library works or more precisely how
preprocessing the
first of all communities as it
into single triple patterns
our sample
now some query consists of triple patterns as
this one
each triple pattern evaluated separately by the library
the results are joined in streaming manner
for each prepared to let
eleven executes
directed browsing i got the
which iteratively
retrieves relevant RDF graphs from them and finds matching triples
the following show you
and execution as i them
before this trip
as the first step the algorithm looks up a URI is that our sample code
and we have to you as you have put on
you have two and the fourth knows URI
but this fulfills property
tom's URI
we wish an HTTP GET request
receive a response which redirects to the document which is an HTML document in this
document defined
reference to an alternative representation finally from this year i retrieve an RDF graph
and at this graph drawing graphs
looking at the fourth knows
you i follow a similar procedure and we find
and the RDF graph from this URI
the second step
we follow see also links which means we
for for each of the
what you see also troopers and all of the graphs that the subject
is one of the URI sonata pattern
we must look at the object of the strip
so far for example we had talks here i the fourth knows property URI
which means we must fight
troopers that match this all this pattern in our local graph set
and all these attributes we must look up the eyes and object position
now we have some RDF graphs local graphs
next step is
our triple pattern against all graphs in the set
in order to find matching triples which are solutions to our
a triple pattern t
for this could be the retrieved
the set of
matching triples
upon the trip which states
OK you can read this
the strip it's those richard
all of these
matching triple
and the next step
we iterate in all of these matching propose
for each matching triple the first look at
the new UI is in the strip
let's take for example it is tom knows which true
and the new URI is a trip to new i'm representing richard in the semantic
web dot org
it does
looking at this URI
retrieve RDF data from semanticweb org of which can this graph to local graphs
and second for each matching triple
again follows the also things
for the u so
the district had this new year i
and following this
following see also links with this here i
we find tom's foaf document which has been retrieved on the first
in this document we have a see also link
for this URI refers to richard for five
looking up this year i
we find richards for and at this graph to our progress
since the the fourth step iterates over all matching triples form step three
not just in this tunnels which trip
the library tree
in this case twenty one years
graphs from the from the web
and in the next step
no don't worry toward work and i'm saying that if you want to align
x one and x i and y one to y and senators y one to
y is the entire string this time then there are two possibilities it even this
last letter here
is matched with one of these and that it is the oxford is giving us
because we use ox to compute that or is this i is not aligned with
any one but in that case i can get rid of it i'm saying the
number of the kernel of this
this is the same as the kind of i minus one and so i've got
my formula
this is the algorithm i'm leaving it can slide so that people can look at
it is not the most to say i just think there is this
this outer loop for the inner loop
ox is computed little by little
and then i'm looking to see if these last letters coincide which is the only
case where it's interesting to actually do these new computations in which case i must
make sure my ox
is is augmented is is is a bit larger and then what i've got to
do here is just the a
computation that just shown in the last slide which is the kernel of i and
j is the kernel of i minus one and j
we so why we had that plus
ok subject to say all possibilities where we want to match the IRS letter with
one of the preceding ones
i think that's this
and here is the running example served as you want to look at it
how does it go
the idea is in the same table i have put the k is
which are here
and ox values that are here
so if i take something like what could know
this is in this case here five is the result of four plus one six
plus one basically using the
the values we compute for
and hundred more
so as i said before why not try something that's why can't we think of
doing you know the all substrings instead of just the substrings of length something like
a pseudo an enumeration of all the strings and you wanted to count how many
times z each substring appear in the in the in the coastal city sounds nice
you if the all subsequences work with the weighting scheme we wanted to be able
to say that when the strings are closer than of this was important when can
try this by the reason is with the police i haven't reached and the book
doesn't mention any so i'm not sure they reached either any nice satisfy factory formula
to be able to calculate it so so you turn into a certain number of
choices because of what the
the combinatorics of the strings tell you need to say that what is truly with
strings is even more true with the case of the surface
is even more true with the case of trees or graphs where as soon as
you're trying to think in terms of finding some sort of nice kernel something that
you know intuitively you would like to use your face the fact that you just
can't computer
all i could do that as an exercise exercise shows session to try and do
an alternative edit kernel notice in this edit kernel of the thing the closest to
the edit distance we've just seen here with the all subsequences we're counting the number
of alignments but when we doing edit distance is not the number of alignments were
interested in interesting the best alignment so could we have something to with counting the
number of best alignments of could we have something that we just say what is
the length of the best in alignment
OK and the longer the alignment you know the the higher the value
well those things corresponds to so yes finding the number of possible much better sort
of finding the best
alignment is not going to be computationally difficult but we do know how to do
that we're facing another problem which is almost as conditions for the truth
the one saying know we saw yesterday that the metrics has to be respecting a
certain number of rules were to become so so really facing three way challenge we
wanting the kernel two two means something something that is appealing to us appealing to
the problem we're interested in we wanted to be
algorithmically interesting
right and want to be able to compute well i wanted to be mathematically correct
and it's hard to be able to fit the three things at the time
this is just another idea of one of counting substrings only once
here were also counting where the substrings how many times we can match them but
we're really interested in avoiding having to counter a counting it varies times letters being
user and if you if you pass it with an automaton for example you really
count how many times you go through the automaton without going back every time counting
all the combinatorics but same thing all these ideas don't don't seem to work in
OK so the very important well i mean i suppose you or what does the
tory machine learning labs will have it around the shorter christian book and in the
case of strings there's been some interesting things done by alex class and chris watkins
the authors in the last two years because they've been trying to use these string
kernels two
to define languages
and the to learn languages thanks to shrink
OK so the names or alex clark and chris watkins
right so here i'm just going to quickly go through two
as the alternative objects that we find in theoretical computer science and that or also
becoming of increasing importance in the case of
in the case of machine learning because the data is more and more structured so
you want more and more to be able to manipulate it's not perfect
the idea of just extracting features and then playing for the features is not always
the next one will be the pair
x two
x three
and so on
and then what you do is compute sufficient statistics phi
of those past
they do inference
and how to do this
how to get the gene functional explained
no that would be an extremely well
there is one case where c decomposes
which is when you have truly independent subsets of random variables
in this case the
can be computed by
computing disease on the subsets of the random variables
however in most cases
you will have a certain dependent
but you know exactly on the right track insofar as
graphical model is nice intractable so if it decomposes quite nicely in computing z
will be easy
but if the graphical model is
so if it is intractable
well computing xe will be
complicated or next impossible
and that essentially the question of dynamic programming in
will get examples
OK forget about the proof of this decomposition it's basically just using orthogonality
let's look at the specific example first
so let's take normal distributions
we know that for normal distribution are sufficient statistics for fixed just x and x
six transpose
now by the clifford hammersley theorem we know that topics must decompose into subsets involving
only the variables from each maximal clique
by the very form of the sufficient statistics
i know
well the only term that can cause interactions is the inner product between x
x transposed
and some parameters theta two
so in here
i can only have
i mean these are all
this only contains monomials of degree two
so it has any terms x i x j
so basically what they will get is that this equals the sum over i and
x i x j
times some coefficient data two
i j
that's just by the very construction of the normal distribution
i know that i cannot have any such terms theta i j
we're well i don't have an edge in the graph
just by the construction of
the maximal cliques and all that
so therefore
it means that the graph to them getting
corresponds to the graph
of nonzero entries in the corresponding curves covariance matrix
as the inverse covariance matrix
so this a very direct link between
sparse matrices
well independence of random variables
let's have a look at
the next slide that
shows it in a bit more detail
that's a that's why graphical models
and these are the terms here
and the data is the inverse covariance matrix
i can only have that any of those terms i j here is nonzero
if i and j share an edge
so this
graph here corresponds to a nonzero entries exactly in those parts
OK the mind of you have something anyway because
and of course connects with itself but everything else
really corresponds to where you have an it
and i can already see that depending on
hierarchical model looks like
you can
do matrix manipulations here
more or less efficiently
so if use
had to suffer through any well special matrix factorizations lectures in numerical analysis
like well what do we do with templates matrices with try diagonal matrices and what
have you
you've probably learned various ways how to solve for them
and it turns out these
map directly
into inference methods for graphical models
he would for instance go and start peeling away on this parable then you only
get these to live then you push it through here and so on and so
and so this is pretty direct mapping between what you can do in america analysis
and graphical models
two and three
well there's no age
whoa wait wait so one and two are connected OK good
yeah but
but both two and three times nigeria
yes sorry industry
he is this is your right
OK that's wrong and very good
OK so the
maybe i shouldn't do that now in the for
we have the evidence that the
the fact is that people are watching without any complete rubbish
very good
does that make reasonably since the most of you
so you get the district mapping between nonzero entries
this term here
is it has to decompose allow hammersley clifford
and the graphical model
the next step is so we done the graphical models are to some extent now
we look at this conditioning
this was normal density
this is the conditional density p of y given x parameters theta
well the log partition function here
exactly the same expression again but just that this XML becomes so say
variable with which i can
what if i'm the original expression
it would
if p of x and y parameterized by state is a member of the exponential
to get that expression but doesn't actually have to be
this is one of the
advances over
building a joint model in x and y
so here just to show that it's not one note just
so they were all the words that there is a complete
so you know
so just about works
if there was a same match
they're not enough much together and for every word senses have exactly
you can find a note in the
and so here as is you know to the right
these are heuristics no
this planet together
this is why i used for the opening the part of speech tags
so something that you can download job
opened p
so there is more than the text
open up so it's something
everyone use
well not
deep syntactic analysis the rituals
a second say this
well marksmanship the process which was trained on i don't know on which they
strange so
discriminant machine learning where you decided part of speech of words based on the context
so this is what
it's all about words there's nothing more to
there is some parts of
no no
you know it makes sense
what's the problem so it makes sense to assume that when you go and use
so the named entity recognizer practical what you also get a bunch of mistakes and
then those mistakes they always propagate so we have state and on the part of
speech level you would definitely get mistaken this is that if you have mistaken systems
are getting more mistakes the semantic
there is always a trade-off between accuracy what
what do you expect to get
so here is the result from activity in would
get the state is actually if you you look at a combination of the
grammaticality much easier to be this big
the extended version of the
shortest approach from this
that would be
they to be the same person
just to wrap up this very quickly what i've just been talking about sentence compression
in the context of matter excitation
so here
can be applied to
this theory to non system
an online system online service that use
i don't
different languages only
with joe MIT
that for require simulation spanish english there is also well known
this is a very good given all this information is used to give you don't
know anything about named entities that we don't know anything about since about
semantic information still the results
if you have to be pretty
OK so now
if there are no question about
sorry which is the
no i haven't done it also
see huge difference in the course
reporting in nineteen ninety nine dollars
but the
above all else
we can see that we had
eight hundred
floating point operations per second you should by you
while today we have we have
floating point operations saying on the laptop
do we have the limit
can we continue again we go on with the increasing their power computational power of
our machines
yes we have the limits of course it's a physical limit
if we
what is this linear
well let's assume we want to build the
and machine a sequential machine
which can issue one that flops
can we do that
OK let's try to understand how it works
if the microprocessor central
processing unit
as to issue one that i flocks
which means one one one there floating point operations per second we need to
the same amount of data to be lauded in the CPU
so we need to one by the data
somewhere near by the CPU
and we need to know the so much data
a second in the cebu to be
just distractions or maybe there
o pounds of the our operation
so let's assume that we can
in one by we can represent the operation of their organs and everything
and now we need to
the main memory around the CPU
and these must be
this is the
the main memory must
as close as possible
because of to transmit to move data
we can do better
let's assume that the speed of the light which is the maximum speed we can
you imagine is not true because we know that even the light in the medium
of doesn't go that fast it's a bit slower
but let's assume
but we can use the speed of light to move these data
so i'll be will be
the memory we have to use the space we have to use
it's simple if only assume
and infinity feat they seem
the centre of the sequel
let's see
how is
there are there
well because d this sequel around the cebu containing one terror
one petabytes
so we do them as they for you
and we find out we need the
a zero point three million square millimeters
an idea
so small c seems reasonable right
if we are able to put in such an idea one petabyte
we have the machine which can deliver
exactly one petaflops
the second
the problem is that we need to compute how much space we have first single
by the
it turns out what we need needed to represent one by the industry
and strong square and strong which is
more or less the size
a very small after
so there is a problem
sequential machine cannot reach
such performance will never accept such former please i believe in our life
this may be so these the quantum computing will change these scenarios but with the
current technology
we can not reach this performance
more say in nineteen sixty five
by way is he was the co-founder of intel corporation
after a few years he was working there
he noticed that
was very simple
a statement he made
because he noticed the
this is in the
o many devices
use the
in their components
they were building and sending
it means that in fifty nine days
something of his
in written scale scaling
but you know this there was a very strange relationship
among these points
OK they only five he was so brave brave enough at least to make this
statement he said
the complexity and for complexity meant
the number of votes
o devices
ten sisters for example used
in a tiny components like appeal
the number of these divided these new eyes so the complexity
and meanwhile
combined cost so far
combines the way building which was
where they were getting a revenue so which was convenient to being they were building
and selling
these complex as increasing at the rate of roughly
a factor of two
they so every year when they were
doubling the number of transistors in the components
so i said OK
i guess i better
that the in nineteen seventy five and we will have to do the other sixteen
ten sisters in our CPU
OK you got very close was he sixty five sixty five thousand
that's impressive
in nineteen
seventy five
he made a little correction please law
we say that the now on
the complexity we double
every eighteen months not twelve months
OK let's see what happens after
thirty years
it's true
these are
it up in the last thirty years still opinion
so here we have all day
intensive use here we have their memory components
the trouble with most realistic games as the number of pure strategies this could have
been a 3 by 3 matrix if if it's of course could 3 by 5
matrix we could have given are 3 choices and C 5 choices
and poker of course and number of different strategies would be of overwhelming
because we have to have a strategy for each situation
but generally speaking it pokers like this and that you might block
so bluff would be um yeah
bluff would be
maybe in the case of seeing going this way
so know and taking a chance that
yeah but anyway that taking that for a some fraction of the time of are
will be used making this choice and you only have to pay
so what I wanna know X and Y and the average payoff
so what's it what's the average payoff here event maybe I call these better these
X 1 and X 2 because there could have been 7 of them and I'll
call these y 1 and y 2 so the point is of course that the
sum of the X is if 1 and that all the all the exits of
costs greater or equal 0 and they had to 1 the probabilities of choosing different
rows and similarly the Wise are all non-negative add to 1 that's that's clear
but now what is the
if if I decided on playing these fractions the rows and see is decided on
those fractions of the columns what's that we well how often does a former get
chosen how often is the payoff for
x 1 y 1
receiver independent decisions
so the payoff
would be
x 1 y 1 that would that would account for the fraction of the time
the fraction of the time that that that we have a choice of X 1
and Y 1 times the war that you pay and then 1 of the other
terms well there's a to move from X 1 right
the payoff of 2 workers in the fraction x 1 y 2
and the payoff of one's occurs in the fraction x to y 1 and a
payoff of 7 occurs in the fraction X 2 Y 2 and I'd like to
have a nice
the mice matrix form for that
and I think it would be just
Y transpose A X and I can I write that wiped that's why 1 right
multiplying the
2 1 7 over know multiple about delegates X X transpose wives and as I
better get x choosing rose have to multiply the rows and these have to multiply
the call
is that right that if I do them multiplication X 1 multiply the foreign the
Y 1 X 1 multiply the 2 and the wife to not get the 4
terms and that's the and just getting a nice notation
so what is the job of the job of law
the person who's choosing the rows
what is the person is going to payoff so he's trying to maximize the place
so maximize this payoff
X transpose A 1
which you in choose that students you economists say it in words
are you more work to choose
here is is choosing there's his 0 0
maximize the payoff
X transpose A what
but now
and of course the constraint that is
it is fractions should that the 1 that's clear but is what's really constraining in
what is and this what is he actually
when he chooses the next what will
because after a year 2
Y is going to notice what those fractions arming and the thing about the big
picture again we we decided that you have to decide on fractions and randomized
but after a thousand 2000 million plays that x is going to be known to
why is
pretty quite closely what the fractions are so there should be known otherwise so what
will we do know is that once that's known to why what would why then
do this season and the common choice of columns
would minimized
yeah so why is gonna minimize show
so he has maximizes this but but
but has to recognize that why is it then the show you what's up here
it at the old 1 of them is trying to maximize over all the axis
is the minimum over the is of the payoff and the other is trying to
save money is trying to minimize the otherwise but as the realize that whatever you
when one has a set of pairs chrome it's one of the properties has to
go to one side one to the other
that itself is in principle also an error prone mechanism or error prone process it
mistakes could be made
and indeed in cancer cells where many of these processes down sometimes one has both
chrome and it's going to one or the other side and as you can into
it from that that leads obviously to disruption of the normal make-up of the chromosomes
that are eventually allocated to each of the two daughter cells in fact this allocation
happens here t phase the last of the four major sub phases of mitosis here
you see the what's happened
is that these properties have now been pulled apart and the moment that they are
pulled apart no longer paired up one with the other they now are recognised once
again to be card-carrying chromosomes so now you here you see the nomenclature is change
now the chromosomes
they're being pulled pulled apart obviously one wants an identical sets of chromosomes in both
daughter cells
and once they
allocated to the two future daughter cells
the entire mitotic spindle dissolves and as you can imagine there's a reef formation as
indicated here schematically and not very clearly
in the nuclear membrane
now the whole cell is reconstructed and now each of the two daughter cells is
able in principle to split off one from the other and to go off on
his merry way
and this looks like a really neat process and
in some eukaryotic cells it happens much more rapidly than twenty four hours that i
just indicated to you there are indications that in some lymphocyte populations it only takes
three or four hours
and some early embryonic cell populations where there's absolutely frenetic pace of cell growth and
it may happen every thirty minutes rather than the twenty four hours i just talked
about and you'll say also what that's who cares about that but thirty minutes for
replicating entire
six point four billion bases in DNA
and then allocating into two daughter cells is actually quite an achievement and we don't
really understand
how that happens
i've talked to implicitly about the process of cell growth and division
and what i mean to say in more detail about that is the following after
one gets these two initial daughter cells they're obviously only half the size of the
previously existing mother cell and therefore what must happen in the subsequent cell cycle
is that each of these daughter cells must actually physically grow in size so that
once again becomes a big momma over here
after the next cell cycle
and so that growth begins immediately
and much of it occurs just through the generation of new sets of riva songs
new proteins membranes in the cell all the complex constituents himself need to be duplicated
for the next cell cycle including obviously all of these organelles the small structures in
the cytoplasm and including indeed the mitochondria
so imagine now the complexity of this because not only is the eukaryotic cell is
so complex but its entire contents must be faithfully replicated during the subsequent cell cycle
and that obviously implies the intervention the involvement of very complex control mechanisms about which
we understand almost nothing
how let's get back to this from on because what i've been talking about over
the last sixty minutes is simply mitosis the m phase here
in fact in many of these early embryonic cell cycles
what happens is that cells from face directly into s phase
and from face to work directly in the and in other words they don't indulge
themselves in a period
over here long period in some cultures million cells this can be twelve or fourteen
hours of getting set getting prepared
for DNA replication
similarly after cells have replicated their DNA and as we just said for example
converted one chromosome into two paired incremented after they get through as face also another
for five hours most cultured mammalian cells before they go back in m phase these
two gap periods
well how do we actually know how long to these gaps takes will as usual
i'm glad i asked that question
and one way we can do so is the following
what we can do is
and here appears in well her hair braided into wrapped around her head fanciful virginal
kindly safely out of fashion full of
a kind of civic virtue the embodiment of a certain kind of popular idea of
poetry you
you can read it but there's a kind of stamp of approval here from the
governor nelson rockefeller
think of how far away this is from ezra pound in saint elizabeth's hospital
this is another image of modern poetry
but more hair was not always done up
this is the image of a child also named mary more with delicious prodigious blocks
it reveals maybe a little bit of the power and extravagance and glory that you
in her poems but that she preferred always to restrain and bind in control
in extraordinary ways
not always to hide
one of the enduring works
written in nineteen twenty two
the amazing year that the wasteland and ulises appeared in the criterion started his publications
one of the most amazing works is a merrie morris home called poetry
you've got a sample of it on your hand
revised your palms
just the same way she ended up finding her hair
republished this palm eventually in short form
very short
we're three pages were reduced to
two sentences
the first two sentences UCI two
dislike it
there are things important beyond all fill
reading it however with the perfect contempt for it
one discovers in it after all
a place
for the genuine
some of what she cut out of the palm coast cut out of its later
is the list of what she had in mind is the genuine as examples of
it which is the first quotation there again on your hand out the back holding
on upside down and so on a flea
the baseball fan the statistician
nor is it valid to discriminate against business documents and schoolbooks
all of these phenomena
are important
the drive to include the world
more is on the response claim for poetry
all the subjects that she mentions here and indeed many many more
all these are new
modern subjects because they represent dimensions of experience
formally excluded from the
elevated idealised discourse
it is poetry
dimensions of experience excluded as
more is quoting here in that phrase business documents and schoolbooks as she tells us
from tolstoy
prose writer
but it goes further than tolstoy in her commitment to the seemingly non poetic she
will not only include tolstoy's prose she will not even discriminates against business documents and
more exemplifies in this way a kind key aspect of modern poetry
it will to mix many kinds of materials and discourses to make poetry reach out
from the rarefied and limited domain of the poetic two
keep including more and more of the world
the next quotation on your hand
this is another example of this
i want to sing for you
or or give you my italian but this this famous lines london bridge is falling
down falling down
falling down
and so on these
come from the conclusion to the waste land
they thrust together different
different text different languages writing from different historical periods all their compressed in that remarkable
song that concludes the poem
in the next quotation
elliot tells us that
a various and complex civilizations such as ours produces
he says
various and complex results as if inevitably
unless we think that there's anything particularly
forced or outlandish or willful about his remarkable
poetry in lines such as those i just quoted frame
well it was there in that essay on the metaphysical poets i'm quoting from defending
as necessary
what is the primary characteristic not only of his own poetry but really of modern
poetry generally what is
often called its difficulty
whatever else it may be
everyone's always agree that modern poetry is difficult
you will probably two
by difficult it is meant i think well first of all that is in some
sense set apart from common speech
a specialized and highly self-conscious use of language
well it would go further and say that there is no common
form of modern speech and that's the problem
according to elliot the modern world lacks the centre a kind of a set of
collective beliefs and commitments that would
enable communication between us
modernity for elliot as for more
as for pound is marked by a profusion of languages
both national languages such as french or russian which turn up in the wasteland
also a bewildering array of specialized types of discourse technicals honours varieties of speech business
documents and schoolbooks
the basic gist of it i think is still very relevant and some of you
who saw the talk of hot lips and actually worldview reminded of what he did
in two thousand seven we also had genetic programming essentially plus regularizer which enforced short
codes as opposed to long collins and then
i think during his talk he said
the crucial thing was that you had different models for certain parts of the space
and then
focused on those where there are different opinions of these models as opposed to
looking at the other parts of the state space where there was no different opinions
so that's the very simple
that was two thousand two and and what you can be doing is we are
using just three d simulation of the
of the icub robot
the icub robot to be like robots which has a face like that of a
stereo camera on top and then we have a three d simulation of the icon
and using stereo camera you can improve this east simulation which you can use it
to predict but just incorporating the stuff that the the camera sees here using some
vision algorithm so you suddenly get little objects in the environment of the cycle and
and by having these objects here the simulation becomes more complex which means you need
more bits two stripes simulation however
it also becomes more powerful as a predictor it become it gets more predictive power
he has certainly you can for example predict that if you to move your hands
like that your eyes legs and then you will see that in that
the object is now in there in the simulation and now again you can use
the same principle you look at the number of bits used to describe the history
so far which is essentially the number of bits in the fall of the polygons
in the simulation plus the extra bits you need to encode the deviations of the
entire street you're trying to learn new motor skills just like a little baby we
have little baby here which over time
focuses focuses its attention on those parts
of the one which can make learning progress which in the beginning will be very
stupid simple things so it will be very limited scientist trying just doing very simple
experiments as opposed to
more complex patterns that lead to
in science like the general theory of relativity however the principle i think is only
that's all the same thing that led to the general theory of relativity
and the fun that you have in motor learning motor skills
that is just
well i mean why should anybody why should anybody learn juggling
it's useless in the however it's fine
because it's very and you get a lot of everyone just by creating this new
sequence which is
because it leads to a new type of regular pattern for your compressor for prediction
machine such that you can certainly save a lot of bits because it's
it's new to you pattern recognizer which first need to look at this and then
shrinks it down and that's how you get progress and we have now this european
programme project which is called intrinsically motivated cumulatively line once don't ask me who invented
the acrimony i'm clever without but that's what the name of the project is and
i hope i can keep you updated on the progress of so i don't have
time to talk about their low complexity what maximizes themselves i don't have time to
show you low complexity we can facts programmed by universal before you transformation based languages
i don't even have shined time to show you movies here
instead i should
instead i should just focus on the take-home message to take on messages
that for
intrinsic reward is the change of the number of bits you need to encode data
novel patterns
and you measured by looking at how many bits can you before and after learning
and you take the time into account the time to contact you automatically take into
account by having a limited compression machine which is only so good at discovering certain
patterns and is not good at is coming out of other patterns even if additional
patterns and and and the rest of it is down because you still have the
standard itself towards that you have in addition to the intrinsic reward and you
you have some evolution and i have more reinforcement learning algorithm or other programs such
techniques for maximizing the future expected reward
and i believe playing explains all the essential
things that are defining our behavior like attention why do we look here
i'm not science in general which is just very focused type of attention on various
very selective experiments where you can then formally named down what's happening and you can
formally down here compression progress but also the music as we
as we talked about
i wish to thank the organisers for doing a great job and
and also for the czech which i'm going to invest into the education of my
i wish to thank my mom and my dad without whom all of this wouldn't
even have been possible
and i wish i wish to thank my kids without whom