the second example
will discuss
is gonna be these unknown
so i could tell you look i've got bent coin in my pocket
it has been used to generate a great big file always and bees
and that's all i'm telling you don't know what the bias is but you do
know that it's a biased coin
you just don't know
he eh
and people be
are yet
nevertheless on-the-fly i want you just start predicting just like the headline you didn't know what language are in
you know what it is about and has we went along on the fly you
started to figure out what sort of topic it was
so an unknown then car
and so are typical outcome might be a lot surveys in just a few days
or it might be lots of these in just a few days and you don't
know in advance which
poses can be the case
and the third task will discuss is the general
situation where an article is available
the oracles job is
given any context x one x two
x three text e minus one
the article will supply you with the probability of the next character which you should
assume is be correct distribution for the for the next character
andy there will be an identical twin oracle at the other end who will produce
exactly the same distribution in response to
that's same context
so this is any context
and then the question is how should you compress when you've got the article
the article is actually a complete
completely general statement of the compression problem because the bent coin
could be
produced by the oracle he just ignore the context he said he has probability ninety
nine percent and be has a probability one percent
the this article has the trivial cases in it as well
the way the article would do the bent coin thing is
given the context he would look at how many a's and b's who have happened
he would make an inference from what i think he and he might be
and take into account uncertainty about pia pib
in making his next prediction of weather
i think that's one is and they are being so his first guess with no
context at all would be well fifty fifty i don't know
it could be biased his albeit at so fifty fifty then when he sees a day
right now let's weak evidence for being biased towards aims and he'd give a slightly
bigger probability to eight and his identical twin would behave in exactly the same way
so that's the three tasks that we want to solve
we are going to
defined at
but coding
i should mention in passing the arithmetic coding is not the only other way of
doing data compression apart from simple codes
but in my view is the only other one that is really worth devoting lecture
to there are many other algorithms some of which are quite elegant but for me
after coding is is speaking
of compression
so do feel free to leave repeat the textbook knowledge you can learn about other
compression methods
so here's how arithmetic coding works
many coding is based on this idea
you can view any transmission
in a binary
as defining an interval on the real line
zero one for example
is a little
as a binary string
hand you can view them as corresponding to the interval from o point two five
no point five in decimal
one zero zero
we can associate with
involving no point five
not by sixty five
what we're doing is we're taking these simple coding supermarket
and viewing
the top of the supermarket as being the real numbers zero
and the bottom of the supermarket is the real number one
and any particular
interval you can see zero one
lived there it goes from a quarter of the way down the supermarket halfway down the supermarket right
so we just
taking the super the supermarket literally at a real
and something you can notice about the supermarket is as you go to the right
if u length and string from say zero one to zero one zero
the interval associated with lincoln string is they subinterval interval
they very
interval you started from
so as you length a binary string you're always defining a subinterval uri behaving this way or this way
you get half of half neural ways ending up inside the place you were a moment before it
so what i'm saying
we're saying that you could imagine
any binary file
having a little
dot in the front of it
called the decimal point or binary point
and then
the remaining characters
are the binary expansion of any real number
is when the variance is maximized in the viruses maximise when you take a peek
was have
which means
this is one four times two
one half would gives
have things
it is this is just to illustrate
this fact
so here
step function here
is the
the cumulative distribution function of the binomial two
the binomial random variable to this is the exact computation with the some that they
should before
and these are the upper bounds
the very suburban
first then
the binomial tail is
one that we had
it's the exponential
what they call expenditure here
and the best gaussians
it is
ignoring the extractor in bernstein's inequality so is like just using this
OK and this is done for the worst case variance
p equals
the house
so four people have more less
they all being the same i mean you don't see a big difference
well you know that it's quite
significantly different from the step function itself especially when you are at the
regions here
we are very far from the value of the pub
but actually if you were to increase the sample size you will not that
this step function becomes closer and closer to
these exponentials
but it captures the right
now if you have a small variance the pictures look different and in particular
the the
upper bounds that take into account the variance
much sharper than those that do not take into account
the virus
here you see the heavy tailed behaviour
like here i have drawn this graph here is the best gaussians
so it's like ignoring one term in the first time inequality
and you see that
four large deviations so it this is assumed
of these graph rainfall in this region
so for large deviations
the tail is no longer gaussians because you you cross this discussion above
and it's better captured at least it's probably by the author
how do we use these inequalities
meaningful way
so the the first thing to simplify
we can keep the whole thing but to simplify
we just replace the variance
by the expectation which in this case is an upper bound on the right
in general it may not very much a matter very much because the functions we
are interested in a small error
and since they have smaller
this is what it's like one
so if we don't lose much by doing this
and if we
use bernstein's inequality and do this inversion again
same thing so instead of
working with probabilities we work with deviations
we get something like this so there are terms that are familiar
the square root of law one of the that over and that's something we already
we use having
comes in
the variance are
upper bound on the variance
which means
the smaller the variance
this model
and we have an extract from that comes from these
heavy tailed behaviour
which is actually
not very important because as the sample size increases
the weight of
this term becomes negligible compared to the weight of the history
OK so no way this is also
reminding you of this
central limit theorem
but in the end if you sum up enough independent random variables you will obtain
always gaussians behaviour
weight is you can see here this will disappear when n becomes large manger with
be this one which comes from this gaussians e to the minus
the square
so we can ignore essentially determined just remember that
the fact that we use the variance
and these
the main contribution
so of course we can
combine this with the union bound to get
so like the trick right this for all individual functions in our class and sum
up for
a finite set of such functions
and what we would think is
same factor before
we have this extra log n factor that comes
here i am
put them together for
base that this is just log n plus one of them
as a commercial center based on a single
the first one is is in mount see this a single
this other means
here there is an incline being cleaned homes
and the same is this building models
the stimulus and the same scene in another way callers with the same distribution c
horizontal beam is on
a vertical beam always on an incline being this in is built
and there is no still appear in the oncology center in here because they collect
patients coming also from the south of the north sea so that's how sweden
denmark and so on
in europe
there is a pleasant
already under construction for
carbon ions and
heidelberg five
now go thank you
and then the police have made of straw
under the direction of doctor benedict CSR is building a center for the knowledge that
this sort of all students in this audience faces south towards the end it is
based on the same design our teams they decided you can see
single they're totally unique outside and the middle east has made an agreement with us
now and the bald
the design so would be
reproducing the second which is being built in pavia finally
in europe in fact final one for the last apology in low call it twice
this is the place where a little bit in which is now
by the end of the year
choosing the constructed in between different constructors there to choose are constructed to start the
project which also find of france we have a carbon ions percent
there appointed clerk and
it using
coming in france
which is based on the new
superconducting cyclotron by being almost told for carbon ions
is based on single because this is the standard way to go to accelerate to
five thousand this company but i do you know that i just started a new
project which is a very big one is superconducting cycle ways to seven hundred columns
just feeling was six meters which is this form hundred the probabilities for
maybe carbon ions
which are extracted and come out
together with support
and then we start to believe this one as the
it is finalized
working on this activity is going on in the framework of what we call in
would be an extra full i don't so
which is not in phase in two thousand five and has been renewed
as like platform JSI project we simulated tree
the pair which is completing construction not going to feel sharing construction middle school which
is pull it one which is the
and we all remember of this platform which is coordinated by the nineteenth entries here
by the way to this
and this is producing programs for
complimenting accelerators because there's a lot more than accelerator treatment following new moving organs
measuring the doors making good images all that needs a lot of work
activities new research and three project approved
with this means for a total of ten billion euros
well as subject so well that these two chapters and i go back a moment
so that you make fools on the fly
first use of accelerators for diagnostic
and and of
we're beginning and thank you very very much for inviting me and that it is
a great honor that this book has been translated into civilian
and I want
To thank
To think Moran with his book was written and unusually who did the pictures and
I want to send a very very much regret women all organized all this events
it probably harm and income that they think of the child
and Simone was the words thank you very much and all copies of Boston Helfer
Sotomayor's this picture and this picture is showing them something that an Amish enables people
the 5 mothers and this is a picture but a strong
so to tell us something about what we are and where we're asking ourselves here
with our here I am a human being with certain features with certain characteristic how
the company will play in what is it that makes me Walter and wit when
were when we're asking this question there are all kinds of answers that we're giving
to this
and while think is there is this uniting the DNA our genes make us what
we are doing here is the 1st novel and this is where the transmission of
DNA the DNA is making sport but it's not just me and it's also what
is in the fertilized egg
what is the 1st to us that in addition to the inmate is also making
that's what we are public and the differences in there in in the cytoplasm which
make a difference to what would become the start of thinking about ourselves human beings
mammals we have virus the warm and the environment of the war is also important
in making us what we are and that there is a development very very important
very important things happen to the baby during the development which makes it what it
things that are transmitted to it from me for an early maternal here and that
there is this hold huge saying the great novel for us is the symbolic of
the mother culture and this is making that's also what we are so this when
we're thinking about what that is how we become what we are done many things
that we have to take into consideration many things which are important for our developed
not very interesting thing is that this thing I'm not just important for our development
that also important for our evolutionary and the resolve that are important for the part
of emotion is that information from slated for all this different rules and variations in
information transmitted for all this rules can be inherited from 1 generation to the next
and if the variations a difference of different types of genetic
every genetic here behavior symbolic can already transmitted from 1 generation to the next and
variations can be transmitted that this can have revolutionary significance and when thinking about the
very complex creature like ourselves humans we must take all this into consideration when we
thinking about plants of course we don't think about culture but we have to think
a lot not only about genetics but also about kitchen when thinking about plans for
example and it when we're thinking about rats will not think about the symbolic system
but we have to think about all the other aspects
so they are able to for the way we can think about this 5 models
of course Nova disrespect to fathers just below the picture because the storm watch
so so we're think about the provider of the denying the provider of the novel
The United out of there the provider of of enlargement in the case of an
numbers woman built the provider of home in Qatar for social creatures were granted carries
very important and the providers of social education with thinking about ourselves
and again it's the same kind of things just said that a little bit differently
with think about transmission from DNA from all that genetics of in hurricane systems
reconstructions of development and this is transmitted not the guy but something in a way
that soon wins the government's somewhat Osama calling for socially learned behavior are also somewhat
to so much and symbolic culture
that I will not talk very much about genetics because I'm sure that you all
know a lot about it I just want to say something a few words about
and that is the very naive notion that we can think about genes for this
genes for obesity James forced stupidity Janesville Wis the genes for those genes for that
this kind of native picture is no longer value there are of course genes which
have a big effect on the traits that the difference in a June particular genes
can make a big difference in the trade but in the majority of cases it
is the G network that is important if will want to understand the trade traits
the development of the trade how how this trade promised we would have to think
about the whole network of Jews disability black pants and where there are interrupting together
and also interrupting with environment to perform the development of developmental landscape this at the
genetic landscape as Waddington hold how development work because all the cooperation and interruptions very
complex interaction between all the genes so when we're thinking about genetics when we're thinking
about how genes influence what we are we're not thinking about simply genes but not
robots that toppled by the constraints with
it is all concert of this
collection of genes and there are a number of this way that are important in
this way interrupt with them but I want to say just and and another thing
and I will not all very much about it just want to point to it
and we can discuss it later the usual way of thinking about mutations in genes
from wherever this mutations are completely wrong but now there is an element of truth
in this
a bus
we know
that why however mutations will appear we know that under stress there is a bust
of mutations of all kinds win all that whereas mutation we look for ways wheelchair
this can also checked
this that this can be very environment could have a very big effect on which
thinks so
when we're thinking about genetic variation regained have a very much more sophisticated view than
the simple view that we used to have however we know quite a lot about
Genentech's so
and we know
well one thing that you put them with this is that they use this
as generic feature extractors they live
essentially taken the overfeat system or other similar system top
of the last layer and then we train the last layer to do other
tasks use this sort of feature extractor so with this you can when
competition that distinguish gas from dogs
which means you if you are kept overdub over you can eliminate one
of the other from your phys book the when suggested is facebook
said if you take the caste like half the traffic goes so
and this is team th that try a lot of different
conclusion tasks datasets by using essentially the overfeat
features chopping of the last layer training and got prima set
of the performance just everything tried or slightly below
the above except for one i was told yesterday to really just on
this the also teams said the it's actually not working very well
for the oxford dataset as a protocol used with appropriate so
this is kind of application to classify to recognize buildings from
in the oxford campus so it's kind specific object recognition
so that works ok but great
you can use to do similarity matching so this something we used
to call saying these networks we can
group this in name of embedding this idea as to get
to know as to how much function doesn't matter where they are
that are controlled the same
parameters the same weights and feed to images that images are semantically
identical so for example to pictures of the same person
you train the system to produce vectors on the by on the output
you'll specified vector just said to act as to the right
and then if you show two images of different persons semantically
different you push those vectors apart until they are a certain
distance because this technique so several loss function you can
use for this there is this one that we like
this kind of margin bayes loss function the called dr lim
that means dimension to reduction by learning an invariant
mapping one of those cute acronyms so that but
is used for rice applications and with this one thing like phase
work which is embedding or pieces of
media or whatever they are text images videos
people into a vector space such that
distance in that vector space of the products correspond to similarity
some sort okay so for example you have a vector for user and vector
for a piece of
like piece of news or error or image is the product between the
two vectors after mapping is large then that means this person
is likely to be interested by that piece of content
if you know piece of text and image and match that means probably
the text corresponds so the image could be query for the image
of the image could be a good answer to the to the text
so things like this or you know the text similar to to text
so low things you can do embedding and
well things we're trying to do is basically and the world
and what things we have we been using is embedding techniques for
is case ok recognition so this is work not involved in
although is taking place to look at my lab
says any tag man and on mostly at to book
yeah research and use a commercial net to
to face recognition is a bit of
f alignment of the face before and that's actually very sophisticated
and then there is training of this thing as classifier and then
there is another phase of sort of refining the representation by
using embedding also using quiteria to produce embeddings are
small dimension mostly binary so that you can store them on very
compact are very compactly and we can source who
you know hundreds of millions of faces very very quickly
and on ten datasets probably datasets like the label face while
this system is the performs human-level
essentially so this is really exciting
another very recent so as you less than other first people to care
about this working to this slides we are participated
so i had a is things to learn from
from the code uri you reach on our and he the
so fell into a habit of winning carol competitions
and i was getting lab and say what what curvature can when
well when you try this the stereo stuff so this kitti dataset
which is a large dataset of so grant with a stereo images with light
data and use the commercial that training course
to run this similarity function between patches that's what you need
to do is to matching you to find a patch in the
left image correspond to the passion right image and you find
it you have disparity in that one from that you can see that
f and we train a pretty large commercial net about six hundred
thousand parameters to basically tell it the
similarity between two patches using the the want to some dataset
and he managed to actually be the record so he's got to put six
percent error this some measure of you know what percentage of points
are discouraged as more you know more and pixels away from the
real one and the runner-ups is the team from from to the intro
spin around for a while and so that's a very impressive these are
samples of results and data so this is you get stereo with
relatively small baseline for those images are black and white
says from car driving around and you get those really beautiful
that images so he's going to talk about this that the worship
of the to the set today i'm and it's a was invited today
to come to the set of a because you just published results yesterday
on the board so and things like this you can do like body with estimation
stuff which may or may not show that if yeah
i switch topic to show you a demo of this system
c i might have to
the first
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
here is in a nutshell a reduced version of what's presented in hand out to
this is the syllabus
i have
several languages available on the board and what just one concept c
sequence one
programming language that's just
and then
it's official i'm actually recover height from from now on one of seven
people look at this and they go out i'm going to be able to legitimately
put all these languages on my resume
OK in this concept list of the bottom and it feels really good it isn't
so much about that certainly when we want to give you some mileage in some
very relevant languages that are very good for both research for industry but
the real intellectual value in in learning all these languages is to really study the
paradigms that they represent and i'll explain what that means in the second program in
c or c plus plus it's actually almost the different thought your you're following a
different thought process than you are when you program in scheme one pi
OK you all know enough
c plus plus and believe it or not you know let's see already just take
out the object orientation from people's party more less likely see when you program in
curacy and you have no classes
you're very procedure procedure oriented think about the main function is being high-level outline of
maybe five top functions to call
and those five functions it types of functions and there some functions of subset functions
et cetera
and to make sense is like a bit like it's like
i've outlined for history outlined notes for history class we have roman one in a
one two and mineral three many small a and b and a little eyes and
things like that
still getting out OK
your oriented around procedures OK
you program with side effects you pasaran references and pointers with the idea of updating
shared data OK you don't have both in c and c plus plus
but as far as c is concerned this represents
what's called procedural paradigm you also here called the imperative paradigm
it is verb oriented in the sense that the first thing you ever see or
do you typically see with the statement
it is the function call with the function name is usually has some strong verb
and its so i give you some idea as to what the function supposed to
accomplish OK that makes sense to people
when you study plus plus
and all of a sudden
rather than calling do this in passing the address of some object you do
my object arrow do this
that makes sense
OK then also the first thing you see on that line is the data or
the objects being manipulated and because the first thing you see is the object that's
why it's object oriented as opposed to procedural procedurally oriented make sense people
i think a lot of c plus plus programmers
really program in c and just incidentally use the objects classes that are available to
them which is a perfectly reasonable way to programme most people learn how to program
and c
but industry no c
very very well and in spite of the fact that fifty million new languages that
are better in many regards they still stick with what they know
that's why c and c plus plus still such popular languages
there's nothing wrong at all with programming and see if you really know very well
and directly readable code it's just more difficult it's sorry way it's much easier to
make memory errors in c because everything is exposed very little error checking going to
see plus was a a little bit better about it
in between here i have this thing called assembly i haven't decided whether going to
go with what going on with the past seven or eight years which is this
mark assembly language
or i'm going to really take a step and teacher real not states
it is a real assembly language although you don't see is in use very much
but there's this assembly language called maps which is very easy as far as some
languages go to learn i don't really care so much about teaching you how to
program in assembly i uses the vehicle for showing you how c and c plus
plus programs compile to dino and object files in the binary and eventually become executables
and show you how line like i equals seven or j plus plus or fu
x and y is a function call how that translates to assembly code
OK this makes sense when you know that when you write code that you when
you execute the program it's not supposed possibly more it's it's it's assembly code to
all zeros and ones eventually i want to give you some insight as to how
c is translated to assembly code how
all the variables and function the object and all of that eventually get boiled down
and hashed out to a collection of zeros and ones
and i want to do the same thing for c plus plus
it turns out that while c plus plus and c represent different paradigms that they
also compiled zeros and ones and after you get enough experience with this assembly and
the manual compilation process ever learn about how to look at c code figure what
the semicolon look like
you really going to see that c plus plus and c
almost look like the same language as far as the zeros and ones are conserved
we're really going to extend the compilation model we use for going from seeing assembly
to accommodate c plus plus references and classes and templates and things like that are
native language c and you have and i think very very good understanding of policy
and c plus plus work after the first five weeks of the cause
OK images so much better overseas suppose prospera we're going to demystify the whole point
of thing i'm going to be able to do something like after castro percent after
after p ro as protesters after people seven
and you know exactly what it means
and if i put in energy to put this
electron one high-flying energy all
right energy from here to
o two
plus plus an electron
this physically
is the ionisation energy
right because the first ionisation energy is always the energy required to take off the
most weakly
the bound electrons are the electrons in that most
high flying
energy state
the ionisation energy of o two
it turns out to be about twelve point
o one electron volts that's with that is the means
in contrast here
if i were to
paul poland electron off of an oxygen atom these are the oxygen and state
o one electron off the
oxygen and so i will plus
was an electron
well this is the ionisation energy
of oxygen
this is
a little bit larger than it is for molecular o two this is
thirteen point five a
and you can see the here
these two p states are lower lying in energy
then the
five states in the molecular oxygen this isn't in your notes
and likewise
if i were to look at the
i want to look at the electron affinity
and now i'm just going to draw here the pie
r two
i don't know
he y
here's my atomic states
the other two
five years sigma
here's oxygen
if i were to look at the
the electron affinity of oxygen
molecular oxygen so way up here
i have an old two molecule
plus an electron
putting an electron and i would have to put it in that state
so the energy difference here from here to here
minus the electron affinity
which is in the case of molecular oxygen minus point zero for five
so i just wanted to give you a feeling for what these energy is actually
mean we are not planning on as function of energy here
they physically mean something
right in terms of for example the ionisation energy of molecular oxygen or the ionisation
of atomic oxygen
i can see the light the relative
four hours of the energies of all of these different states
this kind of diagram that we've been drawing here
called sometimes called the molecular orbital energy diagram sometimes called the correlation diagram
it's called the correlation diagram because it shows you by the means of these
the dotted lines here
it shows you
how the atomic states correlate molecular state
that's why
it's it's called the correlation diagram again it shows you how those panic correlate
the molecular states
if not then i want to proceed there was one page and the lecture last
time that i can finish
i want to
talk about it right now
and that was drawing the molecular orbital diagram
the correlation diagram
heteronuclear diatomic molecules
and that's
in the case of the heteronuclear diatomic molecules
we proceed
in the same way as we do for a nuclear diatomic molecules
that is we had the states of the individual atoms out here and now i'm
just showing you
i two p states
two s are down here white as is down here lower in energy very and
run at all
and what you also see
is that
two pieces
states and the oxygen atom here more energy than the two p states and higher
pay and that's right remember we talked about
the there is the nuclear charge gets larger
those atomic state
are more strongly bound
because the coulomb interaction is greater
so the atomic states of oxygen are lower in energy than those of carbon
if you were to ask to draw the fano problem around you would have to
show that the oxygen
atomic states are lower in energy than those for carbon
but we proceed much in the same way
that is
OK OK OK e talking to a thousand we ready to go up to a
point where the frozen as a what are you doing I was only we 1 of those of
the strategy we used for the 1st time the back results but we're making some substitutions is the case of the
fact that we're not with real valued functions and Robin
just making a finite set of of the of of this covering of sources of growth function number of
our approximations when I'm going to have this covering of the functions which are accurate up to this gamma log amount to impact
on the training examples of it so that's that's the from it
appears to have a go at the stage 1 week we we going to
make this assumption that the stress zero training are
getting simplified things um well that this is going to
have to be true going have this property which is the
margin on the training set is bigger the rate of the Gamma
nominal define the margin I think you've using that we
learn how do with the other buttons tool console from and within a make this a further assumption that the
error a um the true error of this function is Graham Repsol
put in the here but it previously I left out the P but
that's just the underlying probability of error of so it's
the same thing as before so this is the thing that is exactly the same as we
had before except but now we've got this condition that there's a
margin on the training set and we're now looking at these
real valued functions um and there's a but you know they
could be very high dimensional so we're not total assuming
a finite told will certainly not a small BC dimension of character so
located we not using the double sample triplicated in the
Cape here's the double sample trick when I'm looking at a
double sample um and in place of this 1 on as before we just have an estimate of its error on the 2nd
sample that it is the least half of the true error uh and we got to case of the usual tree and character now we can uh about
making a different step and this is this is moving to the
cover of know what's going to happen is of any functions and which has the property that we're going to find the
function in the cover there's with being gamma on to so
damn around to cover on the double sample of up so its
output of is a function of a crime which is the in the
cover the it is going to be within gamma on to effect on all of
the training examples now that means that the margin on the
1st part on the training sample may reduce but were
introduced below gamma on to because the margin of the .
before was at least gamma now we've they may change their
value by a baby on to but it is still going to be gone to
so it may reduce it may increase I mean because we don't know which way this the approximation
works but at least we know that it's not the worst thing to our
to compare so that's that's the 1st property of this
function now the 2nd property that we know is the these guys that
will misclassified before right they were on the wrong side of the mountain when
they get a approximated with an accuracy gamelan to in my
become correctly classified because the my that over the
The playing but then not going to get to a margin of gamma
around 2 on the other side so that um margin of denoted
this by the the marginal wide brackets epsilon anova to
what I media is need their epsilon over 2 points in the in
the y sample of that have marginal less than gamma on to
them for the function as time pay so you can imagine you know the approximation is the
shrinking the gap that we had between what happens on the sample where we
had nice high-margin an on the on the go sample we have seen a
specifications but it's not going to shrink it so that they
could be actually coffee indistinguishable so on the left
hand side you got down to to on the right hand side of that the EP's on a over 2 points that were
misclassified not have gamma but the less than the amount
of into a game you can apply to use the translation
arguments essentially used for being permutations and the point is
that those points that were errors before cannot be moved to the left and to need to be moved to the
left hand side because if they did they would have margin
less than gallant 2 and this property would fail so these
guys a game in order for this property the whole have to be
kept on the on the right hand side and of gaining have the probability to to the minus that
on the mid to if you think I mean I was talking in the
break and some of you may be added to sort of make a clear
enough with we assume a translation thing you don't think
of generating remember we were generated probabilities would swaps cut
uniformly the way we can be good during that is designed for each
swap I'm going to choose to why this walk or not all the
probability off independently and so if you think you're
doing it that way and the probability of leaving or the bad guys on the wrong strong on the back on the go
sample side is a half times the number of times to the
o point has a neighborhood one of these centres
and then you do that mean field iteration mean shift iteration for the selected set
of points
so you get clustering for those
the point
so each of each of the corresponding to be
and then what to do
yes i the
the main point
by looking at the nearest representative j
and assigning them to the cluster
corresponds to the
yes so that don't
i mean shift iteration which is selected point is nearest its nearest to in
and put it in the same
and this is much more efficient because the mean shift iteration is done with what
you point
of the fact that you can actually cover the whole data set of your
now i common bodies out the
mean shift
first of all
you guaranteed to converge to peak but this final the peak is not guaranteed to
find the peaks
i don't know of any counterexamples or i don't know of any product it would
not find all the peaks
if start to it every data point but this is not the project to find
all the water distribution so if you are after all the peaks of the distribution
then this doesn't may not help
but it will probably find clusters
also there are many other variants
so you can think of several variation how to make it faster or how to
find the hierarchical clustering
and so on
again this small
parameter here the order parameter that is used in the current
so it's a very
and the kernel shape but that tradition around
or cement so
it's very carson parameters
it could
you don't put a lot of prior information in
in your clustering so don't have higher of
strong expectations about how the clusters should look like
what do you mean the two men
so you you to define what is men
and then yes if you think it's too many classes then you should decrease in
by the way there is another issue that
that not
current at output because that took many but
there could be
see here are
you may find two pieces of
so there is another
that you may
or something else that you may need to do to decide when these two peaks
one or or two different different clusters
and so they have matter common
so i went to see what the people
how do you evaluate and
and in this case probably you decided valley is not
and so
make everything the cost
the question that i it is so you need to have
besides the clusters
OK here is another interesting that
is clear or is very successful in feels like image segmentation
because it's fun
it's called gossip gaussian blurring mean shift
so it's just like
the simple mean shift described before except that
in the mean shift iteration
in each iteration before in each iteration was just looking for piece of this fixed
density estimate
in this particular case
what happens is that the rest of mean shift to move the data to the
new location so you should they don't want to be
and spend their technically the density estimation is that this is the history estimation
so you get the message
and because the data moving towards the people that they will have steeper peak before
and you take another understand the points move again to what's the new peaks
then you really committed in the peaks grow even more money more than point converge
towards each other very fast
and actually lower the further down the slide to see that for certain distributions if
you put some assumptions about the distribution being calcium they converge the cubic feet which
is extremely fast
means the intensity of the
here i haven't seen any method of all sorts of examples subsampling the data although
we can think of some but all the data points you are going to be
so here you have to do with all the
but it fast
so it's just model numbers
and i think that is is an efficient algorithm actually to do so it's not
as bad as you'd expect to hear organised so you have to take a have
to compute all these kernels for all the data points for
every iteration and it's not as bad as it looks so it can be
OK so this is called to be
and it's not only five
empirically found to work fairly well for cases where
again the cluster size very uneven and there are many small clusters of interest and
so on
but there is an issue here
you should not introduce
and the reason why is is that because
as this is it's very easy to prove otherwise
one week
yes and so
this article needs to be stopped when the points have
cluster just enough to baseball
it therefore there clusters but not before the class started to move to each other
are the facts meat
now there is a vast mythology surrounding eating animals but all these methods fall under what i refer to as
the three ends up justification
and i'm curious if you can guess what they are
meat eggs and dairy is over
i mean
my god that's really fast i didn't start typing this with groups before i heard
all three of them it's like within second
and necessary yeah i think this is the fastest group
say okay you get you get the points are saying
i don't
exercise with about that and people over the years and people always know the answers
what do you think we always get and i'm not even people who read my blog
and we've heard it we heard this all before r
these same arguments have been used to justify violent practices throughout the course of human history
now let's just briefly look at each of these myths turn
he is
what we call normal is really simply the beliefs and behaviors the dominant culture
it is
the current stick norm
and parties and has a social norm is so
in french but it's virtually impossible to seamlessly
step outside of the current stick box
stepping out of the box today
to help you step outside the current stick box and what to do another exercise
i want you to imagine again that are
are you winger your house has just told you that you are eating a golden retriever r
but now imagine that you tell you how how you feel
in she replies by telling you not to worry
i don't feel bad
because the dog
good life
she was able to run away and she formed friendships with other golden retrievers and even some people
before she was killed
at six months old
doesn't feel any better eating the golden retriever
i had people sometimes say no another friend misheard
feel worse
ask yourself
i would be opposed to a perfectly healthy golden retriever being killed simply because people like the way her
legs taste
you might not be opposed to the exact same thing
being done by somebody else
carnism has a social norms is so
in french blinds us to the fact that humane need is a complete contradiction
in terms
humane meat is a man
it is a mere constructed by those in the business violence
to appeal to those above who would ordinarily never support such violence
eating meat is natural
well what we call natural is simply the dominant cultures interpretation of history it refers not to human history
but to
current stick history
it references not are
fruit eating investors
but there are
eating descendants
in other words
through partners and we only look as far back in history as we need to do to justify
current artistic practices
and to be fair
and infanticide are are really
and therefore it natural
the animals
and yet we don't invoke the longevity of these practices have the justification for them today
in the words of the whole have control
do we really want to use the behavior of the neanderthals
as the yardstick by which to measure are current moral choices
and finally we need needed
when we we call necessary simply what is necessary to maintain the dominant culture to maintain the artistic status quo
and here i'm going to let a picture speaks for itself
can you see in the back
get the idea
are related
is the protein
you may have heard this before r it's one of the most entrenched vanessa me
but it is a complete man
in fact
did you know that you could be strong enough to lift the car
even if you've never been announced animal protein in your life
i'm not kidding
looking back on my own
witnessing the truth about the animals i could see how the mets had a tremendous influence on me
as they do on all the us
i couldn't closed the gap in my consciousness until i was ready to make the
behavioral change that would inevitably follow
and i couldn't make change until i felt safe enough
to do so
i had a lot of fears aren't concerns
what i
get stuck
what i go broke buying expensive vegetarian foods
what i have to
subsist on a diet coke fluent cardboard
in this last issue was really a serious concern of mine because two of my
greatest pleasures in life are cooking and eating
and what about my relationship with my father was and he is today a charter captain my father's professional fishermen
my uncle has been an avid hunter his entire life
my jewish stepmother made the best marked evolves
this side create
italian now
arrived on
stopping us full articles on you more and are
so a wide variety of
of different problems here
interesting seems like some of them are missing anyway
maybe the rover here we go
yes israel was one from the israeli air force
i forget
forestry planning problem i think it was africa with the shell oil company all kinds of different problems
so i make a regression model
end so the data that i just showed you as a bunch a valuesof
the number of iterations which other no by number of constraints which are the nobody
and the number of variables that not by end
and those problems does the number of iterations computed using the parametric self dual simplex methods
has programmed by me
so i make a model here is the model
when i say that the
number of iterations
some constant some positive constant which already to the alpha
times the some employees and
to the big power beta
for some data and often better my unknowns here
find the best approximation and what we do is we take the logarithm of both
sides and we say that the log ti is equal to
alpha times log to that's from not one plus data times larger than plus and
that's that's when they are plus some absolute
the absence not just random here
the data is perfect i implemented the algorithm i counted the iterations
but we don't really know
what the world of
i mean in some sense it's random
those problems are drawn from the world
i've real problems
and i don't know what the probability distribution
and the world problems is so i don't really know
with the probability distribution is on this up so on
there is this is our regression model
and i have a budget data
so we set this up like this
i got all my data here are gonna call it be
i've got my coefficients alpha and beta i'm call their acts
because that's the way i am
like linear programming
variables have to be x
statisticians dissolve differently i think they matrix is called that's very confusing to me
he any matrix is
this is the data but in my appears in my model it has
log to for the first thing all the time and the and so that's the
same constant everywhere in this column and then we have larger than one percent to
sorry in one thousand one and two percent and so on
so the the second column varies from problem to problem and then get is absolutely
different so this is my model
be equals x plus epsilon
the problem is defined x that minimizes the abseil on in some sense i put
minimizing quotes because there a variety of ways of doing this
one way is to do
standard least squares
every statisticians best friend
so we use least squares these were taking the euclidean distance the sum of the squares
square root like
so least squares is the square error the euclidean distance will find finally acts that minimizes
some of the squares
we can solve this problem with calculus
just like we could with the me
it's kind of
useful to go through this
little calculation
so function we differentiate is
some of squares which are running out of its gory detail here
and differentiate this this is multi-parameter multidimensional so get
x one x two et cetera
actually my real problem i just have often baited so
there's really only two
variables and the
problem was solved in general i have a lot to these variables looked at them
so i differentiate this at
with respect each other variables
said equals zero and my i surgical the zero that's gonna give me the thing
that's the analog means so put a bar over it
so what i've solve this equation now give me
the least squares solution which are denoted by x barr
and it's a vector so x one b objects
what are
okay so
rearrange this
equations here so i'm certain signals are i can do that too i can divide both sides that goes away
and so
on the whole with the summer be i times they ikea
and has a minus sign
which is music and put it
on the other side of the equation if you like
and they part double sum
and double minus which makes it a plus
o and i j
they ikea
x jabar
so double sum ikea i j x j bar
end so
going back to matrix notation here
because i got a i can be i i really want have that i'd be
happy if this were taken by but it's not it's actually okay
so i think that this is actually the transpose matrix times the be vector so that's that's
this double
some if you think about it again i would like to have this be eight kay i but it's a-okay
story can will be kay i i j
so there would then be able
today we will discuss
what we call uniform
what is uniform circular motion
goes around in circles
has radius r
the objective here
this is the velocity
the vector
and later in time when the object is here
the velocity has changed
the dispute has not changed
we introduce
what we call the period
courses in seconds
which is the time to go around once
we introduce
the frequency s
which we call frequency
which is the number
of rotations per second
and so do you need
i e the second minus one the most
is call it hurts
so frequency
is one divided by t
we also introduce
angular velocity
which we call
the angular velocity means not how many meters per second
but how many radiance per second
since there are
two pi
in one city conference
one full circle
and it takes three seconds
to go around once
it is immediately obvious that omega
two pi
a divided by t
this is something that i would like you
OK go
close to pi
five i t
two pi radians
in capital t seconds
speed v
is of course this conference two pi r
divided by the time to go around once since two pi divided by t is
you can also write for these
omega are
this is also something
i want you to remember
these two things
i really want to know
the speed
is not changing
but the velocity vector is changing
there must be an acceleration that is non negotiable
you can derive all that acceleration
must be in terms of magnitude and in terms of direction is about five six
minutes derivation
you'll find it in your book
i have decided to give you the results that you read up on the book
so that we can more talk about the physics rather than on
the derivation
acceleration that is necessary
to make the change in the velocity vector
is always
pointing towards the center of the circle
we call it centripetal
pointing towards the centre
and here
also pointing towards the center
it's vector
and the
of the centripetal acceleration
called the squared divided by are which is this week
and therefore it also omega
square are
so now we have
three equations
and those are the only three
you really would like to
we can have a simple example
let's have a
vacuum cleaner which has a rotor inside which scoops the air out in whichever way
you look at it
let's assume that the vacuum cleaner these groups have radius are
of about ten centimeters
and that it goes around six hundred revolutions per minute
six hundred rt
six hundred rpm will translate into frequency f
of ten hertz
so it would translate into periods going around
in one tense
of the second
so omega
angular velocity
which just two pi
divided by t
is then approximately
sixty three
a second
speedy vehicles omega are
is then roughly
six point three meters per second
centripetal acceleration and that's really my goal
the centripetal acceleration
would be only square are
or if you prefer you can take the square over are you will get the
same answer of course
you will find
that is about four hundred
the second square
and that's huge that is forty times the acceleration due to gravity
it's phenomenal
acceleration simple
vacuum cleaner
notice that the acceleration the centripetal acceleration
is linear in are
i don't think that is inversely proportional which are that's a mistake
because the itself
it is the function of our if you're sitting here
then your velocity would be lower
since omega
is the same forty
you really have to look at this equation and you see that the centripetal acceleration
is proportional which are
therefore if you were
this were this which was rotating and you're at the centre of the disc
centripetal acceleration would be zero
and if you were to walk out further out
it would increase
and we look at the probability of being there
and then the probability to actually go to i depends on the degree of that
note the out degree
right so the we divide that one over the out degree because we pick an
arbitrary outgoing and then this is the part that comes from the random parts of
with one month of we pick a random node and then n here just denotes
the total number of web pages so probably one over and that we choose this
particular web page i right
so then it doesn't matter where we were coming from basically you know if we
just decide to make a teleportation
you know the woman's after we do that and then with probability one over and
we picked that particular page no matter where we've been before
OK we can just compile these into this p matrix now
i just collecting
you know these terms here so it's
times that one month of over and
if there is no link between
OK and then
there's something missing
so basically there are two ways now
to compute the pagerank right we really want to do that we will actually want
to compute it one way is the naive approach which is we simulate the random
walk for sufficiently long time
and we just count
how often we into particular page
divided by
you know the number of steps to we made so that's the fraction of time
that was spent at a particular page
and as t goes to infinity that hopefully converges to pu i mean that is
actually the case
the way we set up the markov chain since we make random
jumps from one page to every other page with some probability you know this is
an ergodic markov chain so this is actually this lecture tour OK so that's one
way we can do that so imagine you know will go crawls the web and
they could no basically tried to simulate this process
four just you know a long time to do i don't know you know several
billion steps and then they just look you know what
these numbers here and they could just compute pagerank from that what is more efficient
is the so-called power method because what we want to compute the principal eigen vector
right of this stohastic matrix p
and that is by using
you know exactly the iterations that i've shown before
it is taking some initial
probability distribution over the pages and multiplying it by through p and then doing it
again and again and again
right we just always modify with peace with increasing powers and we look at
basically the limit as n goes to infinity so it turns out that for the
web i think talking to google people i think that you know she something like
around a hundred
is often sufficient with the web graph do a finite number a relatively small number
of iterations with the power method you're very close to the stationary distribution the convergence
speed actually depends actually on how you choose i because that's kind of the controls
the mixing properties of this markov chain right being this random teleportation step if that
is large then it makes it very well right because we can jump from everywhere
to everywhere with very high probability if we make that very small then we only
allowed to basically follow was sorry if it's actually the weights defined if we set
close to one for one month of small
then we always have to follow the link structure and then it's just more difficult
in some places might be
almost disconnected and the mixing process properties are not
OK so so that's the way of one computer
many questions about this
the global school
so in the simplest case i mean like google one point o version what you
do is you would use the boolean retrieval model
these before
it defines the set
and then within that said you apply the global rank
so the nice thing about that is
william retrieval is very efficient is kind of very transparent in some sense right so
people you have have an idea what the results are really means how you how
you how you got it
and then use that scored the and this core doesn't depend on the query so
that's very convenient for google because what does it mean when they can precompute that
score right it's a global score they can do that whatever every two weeks so
the other
the e
in the following
the first
the usual
one of the
so that was that
there many places
there also the from the
she she
thank you
i want to thank professor pisanski and thank you for your kind invitation
to have me speak today
i'm going to speak as he said about the many faces of symmetry
in the work of MC asher symmetry
the word that
as many many things both personal and technical
and the work of the dutch graphical artist MC is a wonderful article to illustrate
these many different meanings symmetry is found and used in science and mathematics in order
to other aspects
and i'm hoping that i can cover many of these
and obviously i'm not going to cover all aspects of symmetry but i hope that
some of these ideas that was created through actual will get you thinking about still
we have shown the screen shot is that graphic artist who was born in eighteen
ninety eight and he died in nineteen seventy two
and his work has been extremely popular with the public
and especially with scientists and mathematicians
he's pretty much ignored by the for
world through the academy
his work has been used because he himself was interested in depicting
abstract concepts in his art
and so in really
mean can you think when you look at his art so i thought maybe you'll
discover some new things in his art today
it's is also true that was done in nineteen forty three and i especially like
this because those piercing eyes
i invite you
to look more closely
so now to symmetry
the first is that the symmetry is the one i think that is the most
i think most everyone will agree
that's quite symmetry has to do with balance
and usually when people talk of something being symmetric that balance is one of your
symmetry to perfect mirror-image halves
matching each other
this is a very
reprint of vasher nude reclining chair it was probably done when he was an art
student and it was probably done as some kind of an exercise in symmetry it
has absolutely perfect symmetry mirror symmetry
and of course it's very static
and that one of the aspects of mirror symmetry whips scuse me among the wrong
there's another thing we actually do it all again you can see it has perfect
mirror symmetry the trees and the schools and the birds
perfectly symmetric with respect to a vertical mill line right here at the centre
there's another kind of symmetry of matching has been is much more dynamic
excuse me before that about this is again one that has seen
will symmetry but not really this is not the symmetry but i would call me
an equilibrium
on either side of this view of paradise this is adam and eve in paradise
URI matching figures the
human figures
the large cats
the everything
is balanced
with essentially line so we have both a little mirror symmetry but we also
however in this case not literal but no equilibrium
this dynamic symmetry of equal halves
is with respect to symmetry instead of having matcher matching mirror images
you can also have to have we have the blacklisted and matching white was and
they're not mirroring each other about the centre point right there between the rows of
the turning around a hundred and eighty degrees
if you turn this upside down it would still look the same except for the
interchange of black and white
this is still an example of what are some crystallographic school anti symmetry
i don't like that very much it sounds like against symmetry but anti symmetry means
an interchange of black and white
and the
the textile people have much nicer term for it
they call counter change symmetry
so that after you've preferment in this case a one hundred eighty degree rotation black-and-white
here's another example of of symmetry in ashes work used to symmetry off in in
his compositions here you have the load
all sorts of schools of fish
this print is literally meant using this i have turned symmetry right the central europe
where you can see that the centre have turned symmetry it wouldn't matter how i
put this slide
in the machine it would look exactly the same right side up or upside down
this is very interesting
use the symmetry by measure
you have to kind of zero size
o really
it wasn't easy sciences already image it was decided scientists used to decide those components
who which elements of the variable to be selected to be modified it is be
what you have the whole procedure usually you want to have to the do
tedious in the coverage you want to prove that some of the sequence the sequence
of that you are changing eventually converges to the optimal solution of the dual problem
is only four four four optimisation studies late for coordinate wise minimisation the coverage studies
mainly focused on and constant situation or or force
four situations without linear constraint but now we have a linear constant transport have so
so even for the very simple situation like this economic selection so so there simple
decomposition method is it the first iteration you you were the first to the second
problem and then the next iteration will come the first entered service
the first and then force
the first OK so basically one-for-one shree one four one five and you want
two or three to four OK so that's the secret way of selecting working sets
so even for such a simple situation the these sympathetic coverage was just was only
recently approved
so so these issues and land in designing the the whole procedure then you have
to take care starting conditions and not only that coverage is open whole face to
cover his so far has been here before it is even basic or it is
and what is worse than linear convergence so companies is is another problem also quite
a few other numerical features in designing SVM so we actually quite a few optimisation
researchers are not interested in in the issues but i'm not going to talk about
any details because i don't think you want to know things only for people who
are interested in
as you something you dual problem they all of but get short course some transition
researchers in wrong i the set of slides sort of more
that touches more optimisation issues in something as you do so if you are interested
in those issues you want to look
most slides
four so in training linear SVM that's one of the things i want to mention
so they were quite effective techniques to speed up the decomposition this is what is
called patient
so the idea of caching is to store recently used kernel columns in computer memory
already said that for the composition this is a list of current occasionally you when
they are needed
but you still have some computer so it can locate some some space to store
recently used or or or or some colours and you think they are going to
be used in the future
so this is called occasion so the idea is is very similar to the real
the page
the reason for using stolen credit card instead the company is communication so we can
see how can you help so for for what they say if we use we
can only GK GK space for for a case to store kernel colours
then it takes you live six months but we if we look at more
like forty megabytes is about seven seconds
so you can
he you if you have a lot of memory that use this technique
then shrinking is another
quite quite effective me
it's said
the dual problem the problem is about above the constraints of i must be between
zero and see and we have said earlier that we hold a lot of actually
remain zero so you few support vectors and those training is faced
and not only the lower bound for but we also
components they eventually will become upper body so that i five is equal to c
follows for football of components it is possible that certain iterations led those components really
reach the optimal solution so you have an optimisation easier or should we see that
there are so many iterations
the are a lot of it is in the middle of a centurion change so
this is the enhanced vision procedure we don't really have to consider that and then
we can resize the hard the whole people problem was smaller one
so we just heuristic releasing all those those components
we already have fewer solutions
so we can will remove that we have a small smaller do optimisation problem caused
no i don't notice anything
that's the posterior dirichlet
OK and so
i notice that your instinct earlier that as the as the sum of alpha gets
larger get pq pq distribution that's mirror here as we see more and more observations
are posterior gets peak during peak year
and that's very intuitive
as i as i roll the die more and more and more my idea of
what the distribution of the faces are is going to become more and become more
and more confident about it and so it's the it's the whole idea of the
prior speaking so loudly in the data speaking loud as loud proportional to how much
data you saw as more data you become more and more confident in the estimate
that data gives
we totally diverged from topic modeling
so any questions about this now we can get back to it
for fifteen minutes
from one in the audience now close to zero they're going to be like point
o or one
you can see that are
i will turn the lights off
by the way
when you sample from years in order to do it well a ideally let's keep
OK go
we're back
i'm going to wait on one second
so here we go again we have the LDA model LDA some mixed it's called
mixed membership model in statistics and really builds on the work the seminal LSA work
latent semantic analysis deerwester at all and probabilistic latent semantic analysis from thomas hobbes
actually let's not go into details about this reason it's called the mixed membership model
is that you can think of the model where each document comes from a single
cluster as like that's a mixture model where we have
each document is associated with the singles e and here since documents are associated with
data distribution over clusters then each document can be associated with multiple components that what
that's what the mixed membership ideas so when you're reading the journal of bayesian analysis
of annals of applied statistics and you hear about mixed membership models of rank data
on this data and that data you can think about LDA is an instance of
a mixed membership model that's in statistics that this is called
and for document collections and other groups data bold that group data this is rather
than thinking of the document as a single data point it's really a group of
data points the data are the words in the document represents the group of words
for group data often the mixed membership assumption is more appropriate than a simple finite
mixture which is the natural alternative
and i should mention that in statistics the same model was invented for population genetics
analysis and had a lot of impact there by stephen temperature so
there they don't care about documents with a care about is real science and
they are modelling people as being mixtures of their various
ancestry so you know
so it my my cases back cases everybody is from the same small town in
hungary but my wife like her family mom's from denmark and dads from
he is pretty user character is from
canada basically let's say and
and so you know her genes are kind of a mixture of the very of
the different populations that she comes from its of it's a lovely combination i should
say that the video and
and so this model is a model for four looking at how people's genes makes
and then what are the results of it you can think of the populations as
the topics in the people as mixing over the topics OK so let's get on
before i make some kind of
marriage air
so again the
from the collection of documents
this is all nice story but we don't get to observe any of the stuff
we get to observe the topics or the topic proportions or the topic assignments and
that's really the central algorithmic goal
of of
working with the model like this you want to infer all of this nice structure
so we can use it so the idea is to infer the per word topic
assignments the the per document topic proportions theta d and the per corpus topic distributions
beta k
OK and then to use posterior expectations basically the expectation of
all those things
given the words here's the hidden variables here the word use the posterior expectations of
these things to perform whatever casket is we care about such as information retrieval document
similarity classification whatever it is you're doing
it was one
OK so there are a lot of approximate OK we will in the second part
of this talk we're going to see
how we can actually compute the exact posterior like we can hear this nice conjugate
model and so a lot of approximate posterior inference algorithms for this model have been
developed including mean field variational methods this is what we're going to describe later on
expectation propagation which i know you learned about it yesterday
collapsed gibbs sampling which i'll talk about later on in collapsed variational inference which is
very exciting but i will only allude to it later on
and there's also been some work on how to compare these different types of inference
algorithms and and and how well they do those great paper from
i see no this year comparing them and also some theoretical work about collapsed variational
inference versus mean field variational inference that i worked on with the students working together
to details of approximate posterior inference
later on i guess on thursday but for now i want to show you a
little bit of
let's assume we have an approximate posterior algorithm that we like and let's look at
some real data on what this model does with real data
any questions about this so this is the model only things that are observed in
other words and so we want to fill in the rest of us with approximate
posterior inference
the that
was j
the sign of
that is this article which is real
this is the sign of data because this is one
have to multiply that by g
this now
according to boiler
great mathematician
hoy oiler
after all this was also mention
already in seventeen forty eight
he proved that this is the same
as to power g
sorry state
this equality is mind boggling
and when i saw this inequality for the first time
i didn't believe number one
and i could hardly sleep that at night
because i couldn't prove it
so i hadn't had any taylor expansion
so i couldn't prove it just my teacher in high school said
this is
this is the the case and i said why is that
this is the way
but we now can prove this you can do to taylor expansion of the cosine
theta taylor expansion of the sign theta and the taylor expansion of e to power
it's exactly
not an approximation
so why would we ever want to use this well
if you break this thing go around
going back to my
uniform circular motion here
if i make a point go around
and i only look at the real part i have a simple harmonic motion
and so if i change theta into omega t
then i get that zy
all the cosine
of omega t
because j
five signed
of the getting
the real part of which is a simple harmonic motion
and of course
i'm not stuck to
in amplitude of
one i can easily make the amplitude
eight times larger
and of course there's nothing wrong depending upon
my initial conditions
to have here
the phase angle phi
this them
is a times e to the power j
only got to
plus five according to order
what that means is
but if you
use this as your trial function
to solve the differential equation
you can manipulate
this very easily you can take first derivative second derivatives of exponentials extremely easy
then when you're done
you take the real part of
an out output
x as a function
of time
you done
as i said
it's up to you when you want to use the next lecture i will give
you an example of why it's clearly the way to go i wouldn't even know
how to do it in any other way
but often you do have a choice
so we
interested the real part of that
which is then are acceptable solution
so if we have a complex number z equals a person to be
then we should always be able to write that as an amplitude times e
the power
and then the amplitude a
is the square root
of a square
with the square
and tensions of fatah
it's been
of follows immediately
from that figure
so in problem set one
you will get some
chance to practice
give you a few interesting cases
in the classic case
but all of you
your lifetime have been able to do once
the very intuitive
problem j two the property
well i saw for the first time data apology i said to myself what all
of us can be more complex than j two apologies
but israel
it is not complex
annual wrestle with this
there is an infinite number of solutions not one all of them are correct
and i will help you
a little
the first time want to be nice to
but only the first time
i can also write j
as he apology
by over to you great
because it simply means that the angle theta
this by over two
here so and up here
but that's changed
i'm not saying it's very nice way of expressing j but this change
but not only is this j
i can also
i rotate
and in the true number
three hundred sixty degrees
by n
two or three
i rotate clockwise or counterclockwise and is against
because if i rotate
ninety degrees
i rotate another three six degrees again what if i wrote it back three hundred
so you see
is also a
and that will help you
i will always have a five-minute break
during this eighty five minute lecture so you can stretch your legs
if you can manage to make it back and forth to do battle that's fine
that's your problem
i will start exactly after five minutes
however every tuesday
during part of these five minutes
we will have many queries
it's really
this small
we will collected after the lecture and you get some credit for that
before this only on tuesdays
not today
before we go into this five-minute break today
i wanted to see something
these would be zero
these one
that means the here
the average crossing
from zero to in from zero to one which has infinite
so the cost of this partition
is infinite
so it will not
come on
as you mean cost
partition the graph so any min cost partition this graph
will only
this fact
note once
once otherwise you have
the cost
that's the way you encode something like this
and it turns out
you can
solve the problem in this way
in fact the conditions very similar if you if you cost function
because function is form
i mean i mean things which in this case just functions as a single variable
what about the functions of two variables if you've got a function two variables which
the form the
x i
in our
x i x j
in l
it is the cost of various various
cliques of size two two so
individual functions a function of two variables
now this doesn't need to be quadratic or anything just function to variables
in that particular case
construction always lead to graph you can solve
in other words submodularity condition
well not submodular condition positive age weight condition
positive edges
if only if you have a condition b
a b a
class b
a plus one
the plus one
it will be less than or equal to b
plus one b
the first one
this looks very similar to the the
the submodularity condition
if this condition holds for any a b
in l
maybe you know might my to variable functions satisfy this
the edges in the graph is the positive and the absolutely as the minimum of
the cost function
using this
using this technique
there are of course
there are all sorts of edges
joining the nodes for x notes why
a lot of it against l squared edges in fact in general this possible
one other observation about this if if you fall
the a b
happens to be
of the form
depend only upon the this the difference between two no
the difference between the labels right so i got to
the two images by giving this one some label
OK i'm giving this one to know anything
the label and label the and there's some cost
associated with
if i make the assumption that depends only on the difference in the label values
according to some function e
it's actually pretty easy to see this gives you then
a minus b
this list equal to g
a plus one
a minus b
or if you like
a minus b plus one
plus g
a minus b
minus one
so let's to g
it's less than GA b
it really means in fact that your functions
has to be
if the function g is convex function
you can always all things like this
is concave
you can't
so i'm going say about this is great but she column
which is done this gives
this gives a looks like that and that tells you what labels
pixel p
and i said if
the function is concave
convex like that she of
the difference between labels and convex
can solid
unfortunately a lot of the problems which are interested in
it's not like that so-called potts model
potts model says that there is a cost
associating different labels
but it doesn't matter what the labels allows if the difference is constant cost the
same there is no cost
that doesn't work
in this case the topic model
and is someone smooth version that doesn't always work so
obviously enough you expect to
you expect
it's probably difficult in general
just an example
here's an example of
some sort of segmentation multi label segmentation problem i've got
an image like that which is
the rectangles
and noise right
if you use the linear costs
which says
like this and says
the cost
of assign labels
two labels to generate adjacent pixels
depending just linearly
on the difference between those labels
then you get
something like that which is not a great result OK
if on the other hand you take the truncated linear
which is
we are merely forbidden then truncated if the labels are too far apart doesn't matter
how much differently
different is sufficiently different
doesn't matter that much more different than you get a much better result
but unfortunately council using she col
if you cannot find the exact solution in fact
in this case
the reason is i suppose
in a sense
does not convex it looks like this right
here is the
sort of scenario you could imagine happening in california
you come home and
you observe that the ground was wet
OK well outside your house
you find that
you're on is whether the ground is wet
you can infer two things one of them is that while you're working not paying
attention actually rains
so radio can cause the ground to the west
the other possibility is that your sprinkler came on and
you know
sprinkled water all over
all over the graph
and sprinkler
we're going to zoom are independent in other words what time the sprinkler comes on
is independent of whether it rained or not is not very intelligent sprinkler just goes
on some sort of time are they
but whether the ground is wet is dependent both on rain sprinkler
the following graph which is a directed graph and i'll talk about directed graph
in a many is a very natural way of representing the relationship between these variables
were saying that essentially what this graph says that rain sprinkler are marginally independent
there are some other variable grounding web which is dependent on rain sprinkler
OK now how do we represent this as a an undirected graph or factor graph
as the undirected graph
because the grounding web depends on rain sprinkler is a factor
that involve all three of these variables
and so on
we would have fallen together
and the fact that we were just put about a year and that of three
these things together
now the problem with that is that
all the possible causes some
the fact variable
i have to be connected to to each other to represent the conditional independence relationships
and that's really unsatisfactory so you can imagine
some variables may have many many different causes all of which are independent but when
you try is the graph you draw all of these
connections between them and that really doesn't represent the fact that those variables are marginally
the truth of the situation is that
rain sprinkler
are marginally independent i e given nothing their are independent but they are conditionally independent
given the variable
g the ground was wet
two things cannot be represented by
any undirected graph or factor graph over these three variables
let me just right
explain why
is there
john here
they use
in the jar
i can use this
in box
doesn't look like chocolate and approx
all right
let's try to do this let's say
and sprinkler well what does this represent this represents
that rain and sprinkler are dependent
because there is a path between
which is wrong
and it represents something else is wrong but given that the ground was wet rain
sprinkler are independent
so this is this is not
the basic idea is that you don't have just one weight vector but you one
weight vector for each class
and when you want to do classification
you just compute
the inner product with the
that's what you want to classify each one vector
and classify the example into the class that has the highest
you can think about this as this warning problem
and the fact that has the highest value get
this can be formulated against quadratic programme
and so
so the sun
so what you get is
for each training example
you get a set of constraints that that's all
class has to have a higher discriminant each of the integral
and you get that for every training example then you have the right to project
so it's again a convex quadratic programme
so if you wanted to
apply this method now to structured prediction we have to solve the problem
first how to predict efficiently can just enumerate all the
that's too bad
to learn efficiently eventually have to solve this type of optimisation problem
and so it
well how do we bring this down to a manageable number of parameters we can't
really afford weight vector for each class
after many classes
let's start with the last one
how do we bring it down to a manageable number of parameters
so what we're going to do
if anything one way back to class
going to reformulate the problem
and introduce a joint feature map
so the joint feature map takes input the act
and the label y be trying to set up the vector of features
and then we have a fixed size feature vectors
that we multiply
and then to make a prediction
we simply solve this argmax problem
we have now is
well if we pick
feature maps small
then the number of ways that you have to learn more
in this sense of our
first problem we know brought it down to a fixed number of parameters doesn't depend
on the number of that
well it was just kind of syntactic manipulations of right
really have to think about well how to actually build the p
so let's take a look that
again financial passing what i can do is i can take
the gram
let's assume there an underlying context free grammar
the way that constructive he is that essentially introduced one feature
for each grammar rule and featured in the
in the graph
and then to represent the feature vector for x y pair
i simply want
often was each grammar rule applied
and that the value of the future so as opposed npvp was applied one to
generate one this was their time this was one
if you squint
and think about this for a second
this is actually now
taking the inner product
probabilistic or more generally weighted context free grammar
you think about it general
context and these w here could be the log probability
and the inner product is just the
the probability that tree
what this means this
this argmax
we can now compute with a CKY parsing
we can do that efficiently
and in particular we can do it officially despite the fact that this argmax actually
goes over an exponential number of
you can just in the nick
what this means is that we solve our second problem right
we have
and by picking the characterization in a particular way
we can now do prediction efficient right once we know the weight vector
we can predict
given x one y
OK this is the most simplistic representation that can think you can come up with
much more complicated each as long as they fit into context
you can do that
but that non-lethal blast problems
the last problem how to actually do this
the learning machines
let's think about about the multi class classification problems
that was structured prediction
what essentially one is that for every training example
the correct parse tree has the highest them
each of these is the training examples here
i want to correct one the red one
to come up to the top want to tweak my weights in that way that
that's true and
that is true
i managed to do that then i zero
how can i know formally that as an optimisation problem well
becomes again a convex quadratic programme
i simply introduce constraints saying