so all
do you by
is this operator right so it takes a vector and returns vector
so you have seen
operators before i believe so linear operator just stinks of actor
apply some interested and that returns of vector
so this does
almost the same thing
so this is sort of a matrix right
so if you if you just constantly on this two things
so this is a matrix vector multiplication
so you could you could write that into a matrix form
so this is almost likely not operator
the only difference is that we are adding this other left
so compactly you could write
well this this thing here
so t of phi
at the
it's just a factor glasgow more times some matrix
apply to be
you could write
so that's the meaning of fear
and so
yup i takes so that editors of actor and so
the meaning of this expedition is that
if you
if you do this
for the
value function underlying the policy you get the same thing
we want to prove that
so they should hold in particle for every state so
you know this is a vector so for all components of the of the fact
that they should hold that the components the components to get by
looking at the values at the states right
OK so
what we do
is that it this is a very simple very straightforward
so you just separate the first and from there the rest so was the first
time it just are zero
so you know
expectations are
and it is so i can just pull out i zero
what's remaining is gonna time so i can pull out a gun laws for active
factor of gun
and here time goes
from one to infinity
and if i could have go on i got t
part of t t minus one here
the series was works
OK and former line
so what's missing here
so we can expand this saying using go
the low
after that probabilities by conditioning on the next day
so this is just
conditioning on next state
we have to take the probability
that x one
because the next state
given that x is zero it was max
take expectation
of are zero
given that x
so you know it was x
and i introduced this condition x money was
so that just
you see it
not anymore
oh my god
OK so
not in use
remember we started to sleep by fax
so i write did here again
you take the sum
all are possible next states what you do is that your condition on the next
so what you will have is that
you have the expectation was this new condition
times the probability of reaching the next given that you started with the first
so that as the after that priority i
and actually you can do that this false expectations so the first expectation was just
the main if you want timestep zero
the second expectation was or the future reward from time step t one
i don't much space
and OK so what i know i'm going to change the next thing that it
previously it it went from one
but i want to go it from zero
so that it looks more similar to what we
his father
if it goes from zero i should write go more to the point of t
but are t plus five
the scare
so now we have just using properties of expectations
i think fast
so what the first probability here
so this is the transition probability of transitioning from state x to state y
probability is just what's written here so it given by the
probability transition kernel p
so by definition
because we are following policy pi
so the probability of transitioning from a given state act
to some other given state of mind which is given by this one slide just
the sum of the y
x and
i have an axe
OK so one of the first one here so this is just the the
the immediate reward received step zero
conditioned on that
we started
that's the that's another
state y
and v
we are following policy pi
so by definition that means that was just this quantity here
so this is exactly the interpretation of you know the process u
so this was by definition
and what's left is good times
this quantity here
so this is the fourth
this contd
so i'm trying to define the notion of by the logical consequence of gamma and
there's a whole lot of mumbo jumbo on board which i'm going to talk you
through OK
it looks frightening it's just notation is everything can be compiled back down to have
truth values of five being true in the world or not
let k be the class of all kripke frames in the particular models
script k the class
that kv the class of all kripke models this when the car the kripke frames
and this particular one if
and let gamma be a set of formulae five one
what i want to try and tell you
is when pfizer logical consequence of gamma them
what i've shown you is that
there are there is one notion of formula being true at the world or not
OK that was what valuation did for
i want to live that
OK i need that in order to get to where i'm here so
and we use the term forces
and there are three types of forcing
forcing in the world in a model in frame and i'm going to define them
so when i say w forces five
i just means
the truth value of the w is equal to true
and i'm going to write it like that
we have vertical
o double bond
it's different to either of those
it's neither of those
right so when i write this i just mean fives true at w that's the
way she pronounces
and if i put a slash through it
that means that phi is false w
so this thing
this classical it's either
five find out the true w or false w so i can neither write that
w forces five or w doesn't force five
just try to keep that classic ality going
what about forcing in the model
so i'm going to say
that that model in november model is the triple
a graph with evaluation
like this
graph with evaluation
i'm going to say
the model forces five and write these
when this whole
what does that mean
so this quantifies the meta
many qualify right it's not part of the object language
i'm just using it as a shorthand notation says
every world makes five true
every world makes pietra
but nothing to do with the reachability relation r
nothing to do with the accessibility induces whatever world you choose it has to make
it's a very strong statement if you think about it right because i can put
an evaluation on the actions across here
thank you
others such things
what's the simple example of the formula that is true at every world
in fact all the classical tautologies are going to be true at every world right
because i don't depend on the reachability relation
so you know the six class is non empty there are only something that we
can put here
so again try to get into the habit of pronunciation
this means five through w this means five true everywhere
five true everywhere
what about
in know frame the one is the same
OK what's the frame is a frame is
the graph without evaluation
so what do i do i take frames
and it's is
what is the evaluation i and
i'm going to get triple here which is going to be wrv
well whatever evaluate whatever
the more i like it here
forces five
in other words
it doesn't matter how you change these valuations
that underlying graphs
sorry i e
i'm showing the data
nine and
you know what i'm saying is i give you a graph
so i give you the w nodes and the edges
what i've done here is to give you one particular valuation right i told you
a bit string that told you where the was true here and a bit string
was that what i'm doing now is saying changed the bit strings in any way
you like
you can change the evaluations in any way you like and the formula still has
to be true everywhere in that model
it's a very strong statement so to property of the underlying graph
it is it doesn't matter
how a change evaluations but the formula will still be true
of course if you delete edges changing the graphs right you can't change the graph
our estimates for the parameters of our model
is the inverse of this
miss here
which is the
the second derivative
the the lost mean squared error and then this expanse spores
t TV in the target values
it is so if we solve
so far
long jump data then we find that intercept
is about two seven sex and the slope is
about three quarters of of the unit
right so we've identified the model which will yield the least squares
but what we're really interested in is making predictions and this
so what we want to know do
it's project what the distance
in the long jump that wins the gold medal will be
in the two thousand twelve olympics in london
and then with that
predictions we're all going go to the bookies and we're going to put some money
on whether that distance will actually be the one that wins the gold medal and
not many of you are a confident about winning some money if we use this
least squares estimator
OK not too many of your see
well we can
we can protect all of target values by using our
the estimator
and what we end up with the course
state line
so nothing new there
it seems to be notable but not about models
to fit the data reasonably well
and to explain the sort of gradual improvement over time
so this is all of find
but again from a machine learning perspective this isn't really particularly important
what's important is how good our predictions are
as money is at stake
make a prediction
so what's the distance heart
in two thousand twelve
well our model predicts
a winning distance of three hundred sixty point five inches
that's all it tells us
that's the that's the answer
two hundred sixty point five inches
doesn't see anything about
that's a sure bet are
maybe this isn't such a sure bet that's all we get
well let's just think about this the moment
the current olympic record stands at three hundred fifty inches
and the current world record
which was sets
a long time ago nineteen ninety one is a distance of three hundred fifty two
what does that say about our production
how confident are we in in our production
we're running off to the book is in edinburgh to
ten time there are no
OK so it seems
there are all our prediction is
rather optimistic
and so
just on that basis alone we probably wouldn't trust us
so we use the linear model
maybe what we need
is a model which captures a lot of these
if you look here what was basically done is we've just looked at the we
just model the
the trained
in this
this data
you know there seems to be some sort of oscillation about the train so so
maybe we should be looking out a more rich class of functions to model this
data which would give us more
and useful predictions
so rather than using a linear model finally use nonlinear models
well use nonlinear model but
we'll stick with a model which is linear
in terms of the parameters
and florence will be talking about creating candles and so forth and how you can
still have a linear model was in the parameters and it employs a nonlinear transformation
and therefore half far
nonlinear class of of models so so we can
apply some sort of nonlinear transformation to attribute values and this will provide us with
a much more flexible models
we have much more flexible model
the model is still linear in the parameters
that's provided
that we
do not add any additional parameters
associated with the linear transformations
it would converge to something reasonable
something that i would like to to see an algorithm like that
one idea if you see this fixed point then you know you could get the
idea well we could use this need to directly update the parameters why not just
say theta t plus one equals to t plus b
and be done with
it turns out when you stochastic approximation this v six incredibly noisy and if you
use that directly it blows up your
yes systems very easily
snb my algorithm avoids that
by kind of doing double integration i use the value of the two
slightly changed my games
and i use the value of the games to slightly change my parameters
this is like a double lowpass filter so it filters away a lot of noise
also and the times g which is what's used for the
updating the games is well behaved because
scales like the inverse of the haitian times the gradient
times the gradient and that's fine invariant quantity so if used rescale you're your system
say by a factor of eight
the haitian skills by a is is square so in recession is a to the
minus two and the gradient skills by a
if a to the minus two times eight times a which is one
so that that means you can rescale your system and the algorithm behaves correctly
one little detail i don't actually use the haitian here i use gauss newton approximation
non convex systems so if the haitian can have negative i can values
you get in trouble if you use the haitian
it's sort of a standard problem in optimisation
and the gauss newton approximation is an approximation of the haitian that is guaranteed to
have on the positive side values
and with the gauss newton approximation you can play a similar trick to get fast
gauss newton matrix vector product
it's just sort of differs in detail but it's really the same idea
OK enough theory
in the remaining time i'll just show you what it's
what's it's good for
here's a little benchmark system
since i grew up with neural networks this is an email
even if it's not politically correct anymore
it has two inputs x and y is given as input the coordinates into this
carpet and that the output it has to tell which color the carpenters
OK just set up with two hidden layers ten h
activation functions
not because i think this is a very good architecture for solving this problem this
is allows the system for solving this problem
but i actually wanted allows the system
because i wanted to hard optimisation problem that is still relatively compact so i can
run lots of experiments and this is the hardest thing i know to set up
in a hundred and eighty four parameters
now compare four algorithms simple standard stochastic gradient that first order gradient descent
with the hand tuned optimized stepsize optimized game
and then one of these conventional game adaptation methods that just used eighty times t
minus one
so a stochastic meta descent SMD is my algorithm that i introduced
and the global extended kalman filter which is the
second order online method
which is really the best thing that pretty much anybody knows how to do
on this
and if you look at
curve so what i'm talking here is the loss
against the number of patterns seen
you'll see b
the common filters of course unbeatable it goes right down
the simple stochastic gradient is terrible
conventional step size the adaptation is better
and SMT is better still an interesting
if you plot this out to the asymptote if you go up to a million
patterns SNP stays close to the common filter
so they
both have the correct asymptote these other ones don't approach the optimum they actually have
the noise floor below which they don't optimise anymore
so this is one of the problems you can have in stochastic approximation the noise
of the approximation can prevent you from actually reaching
the optimal
you have to do
that's one of the reasons why you would want to adapt you gain
because once you're at the optimum you want to turn it down so you actually
can kneel down to the optimum instead of hopping around it
so that's one thing you can see here
of course then
if you look at
the cost of the algorithm computationally here's the storage for parameter
the flops per floating point operations per update parameter update and
actual millisecond
game back adaptation algorithms my newsisfree
numbers per parameter the other one uses four numbers
they all wind up being in practice about twice as
expensive a simple stochastic gradient the common filter of course is order and square and
now you see the difference between order in an audience with algorithm and its hundred
eighty four here
so these numbers wind up being absolutely huge and it's in practice it's forty forty
times slower per iteration
gain adaptation algorithms
so now when you reply on the very same data
but you replied it
we've CPU seconds along the bottom
the picture changes dramatically now the the common filters the worst of the bunch
because you simply don't get many iterations in
in fifty seconds of the common filter
the conventional game adaptation and the simple stochastic gradient i kind of similar actually these
two they cross over each other multiple times if you follow it further out so
basically what you gain for the gain adaptation you lose by the algorithm being
twice as slow so you only get half as many iterations
but seems actually by having this better gain adaptation mechanism
is the head in front of the others
OK here's some of correlated data of skip over that
the point is just that somebody can handle data are
and the sender and the receiver in order to make a compressor
and then we looked at thematic coding
and arithmetic coding is this way of thinking about a binary file as defining a single
in real number between zero and one to an extremely large precision
and any
source file can be represented in the same way as
corresponding to an interval on the real line between zero and one
i argued that when you do arithmetic coding
you will get compression down to within two bits of
the information content of the entire file services in terms of its overhead plus two
is potentially about a factor and smaller than the overhead you get
if you use symbol code so
coding is in almost all cases far far better
and symbol codes
i just wanted to flesh out how you'd use arithmatic coding in practice i i
talked about the idea of an oracle that being a piece of software
which uses some procedure to predict the next character given all the characters x one
to x two minus one that have been seen
i wanted just
give you an example of how this works in real state-of-the-art
so here is a fragment of
jane austen's emma
this is the last
fifty or so characters and the context is alarmed at the bureau
and the question is what comes next so how do real compression algorithms work
fairly new state-of-the-art compressor that very widely used is
compressible pee-pee element
his happy paean works
it's called prediction by partial match
hand it's slightly ad hoc but there's a bunch of theoretical justifications and improvements which
we can make sure let me just described the ad hoc methods
the idea we look at the context
the last five characters
the document
to define the context of all the next character
then we look at the entire file
everything that we've seen so far we say
have we seen the context before in the entire file
so this is how we're going to then predict what happens next we go and
find all those occurrences and here they are shown in blue
so e space we are has happened one two three four
five times already in jane austen's emma
and this shows what happened next movie avi and a paean that's
the first step would be to say let's use these six grams statistics the rules
six expand statistics say alright this
to stick
to one how many with one two three four five seven five times so there's a two-fifths extensive getting yvinec
the ones that can serve as o one fifty chance for paean want chance wellness
it also haven't seen them much data so we better allow some probability for other things happening
how do we allow for other things happening well the people i am approaches to say
let's back of too short a length contexts as well and say what happened in context space hero
we are are o o hand in any context at all
and fold in those other
one two three four five possibilities in addition to the six grams statistics
and weight them together in a small smartish way
hand that's how people and works and that gives you an extremely good compression state-of-the-art
on most files it doesn't do as well as humans do human audiences like yourselves
can predict english a lot better and clearly doesn't understand grammar induction reason and so
forth but it does a lot of learning overall statistics and that's
it gets you a long way towards good compression
so there must be paean
okay so the question was doesn't learn these six crime statistics in the document the
entire document and then compress it what does that do it on the fly and
important answers it's just like you guys that it be identical twin audiences
it does things on the fly so when were asked to predict in this context
we then say how often has e space we are all happened already before now
we don't look ahead into the future so the predictions are based only on what
we have already seen
any other questions
there's a couple things i want to mention about
mean coding one is as i showed you last time we can
make other users over many coding we can make an extremely efficient writing system
and the one i showed you was called dasher
that's based on the idea that
writing involves making gestures of some sort maybe wiggling fingers or scribbling with a stick
i am want to turn those gestures in detects as efficiently as possible
hand compression is all about taking text and turn it into a bit string which
in arithmetic coding is views that viewed is a real number
and so we can make a very good writing system by saying okay let's have
just just define a real number by steering our spaceship
in a two-dimensional world
and not will make us if we turn it on its head very efficient writing
systems to make gesture and outcomes text so that's the dasher concept
and i showed you events and it's free software
help is always welcome to make such better
and there's another application prior arithmetic coding i wanted to mention
and this is the idea for efficiently generating random samples
let me give you an example let's say i ask you to simulate
they bent
coin and i said okay
let's fix pe eh
in an airplane zero one
and he is arrested
please simulate
ten million tosses coin
and i will provide you with random bits a random number generator the question is
how many bits we need to use to generate
tosses of this coin
let's say and from now on instead of ten million
standard way of solving this problem is the size of well i use the random
bits you can provide me with
to make
real numbers
between zero and one
so all generate things that i'll think of as real numbers
uniformly distributed between zero and one
but we got a lot of thirty two bits per
real number
if it's a standard
random number generators are region thirty cubits interpret them as defining a number between zero and one
then we look to see if u is less than one pe eh
if it is then we spit out and they end otherwise it's better to be
this method will cost to thirty two bits
per character
can we do better and do we care
the answer is yes
and maybe
so yes we can do much better because we could take an hour many coder
hand think about it this way less
unlike the board
imagine sticking a pin
into the world of an arithmetic coder
what happens if you stick a pin
uniformly random
into this line that goes from zero to one
in two
one of those lines
what comes out what's the probability
comes out a few sticking up in the news it is selected
a string a text
habitat your neighbour
extra column y
so i won't be talking about unsupervised learning rule is going to be giving you
a lot of the classes about this next week so just for you to understand
the difference and here showing you the with people call heat map of the input
matrix so all the coefficients in the matrix on maps some color so the positive
ones to some orange color in the negative ones to some blue blue-collar
and the matrix b here is the same as a but the columns in lines
have been rearranged so that columns that are similar are close together and lines that
are similar are close together and you see appearing patches of
coefficients of the same color and this indicates that there is some structuring data so
this is what clustering that's for you know if you take the initial matrix and
you're undermines the coefficients so you just prominent the lines in concept in any way
and you try to perform again the same clustering operation then you obtain matrix d
showing that we now the structure is gone and so this is one way you
can test whether or not there is structuring data
in this class only talking about supervised learning so i'll be talking about building functions
f of x x being the inputs and that to allow us to make predictions
about the target y
so f of x should be as close as possible to the y that we
want to predict
the simplest way of building f of x is to make the dot product between
which is the vector so it's it's going to be one line of your matrix
for example
and the weight vector w then eventually adding about so these uprisings equivalent of you
know making a weighted sum of the input features weighted by some coefficients
so for them to the input features at the age the the the way to
the number of children et cetera all the information about your patients each one then
is going to have to wait and the decision is going to be for from
the according to some kind of the voting and the weights the the voting power
of each input feature
now these normals are very simple but they are powerful and then there is the
family of algorithm which are yet more powerful that are not linear in the inputs
like this one that are linear in the in the parameters so here the the
that the decision function i'm showing first is linear both in the inputs and in
the parameters you should retain only linearity in the parameters you obtain a family of
functions which are called percent rules and now the the doctor is carried against not
the original inputs but some transformed input in the future space which i call phi
of x
and if we developed this dot product you obtain this the weighted sum of the
j of x which are so-called military features in the new transformed space to for
example imagine that you are you figure that are instead of waiting in the age
of the patient something more predictive is the product of the two then you would
get another feature which is the product of age and weight and this is what
i would call the phi j of of x
of course you can have you know many much more complex operations that you can
compute on features so if you have images you can compute new features by looking
locally for example at pieces of the imaging and extracting say corner or pieces of
lines and things like that so one lecture will be devoted to feature extraction how
to transform original input into some newer presentation phi of x
now in the same family of methods they are kernel methods in this case you
see that replaced the weights w with all follows because now instead of awaiting the
features that are the columns of the matrix and now weighing the lines of the
and what we're doing is that are placing the phi functions but some special kinds
of so-called basis functions
and the difference is that we are
using the the training examples and comparing the training examples with the new example
that is under study
and the k is a similarity measure between the training example
and the new unknown example
so if you look you know it and the perceptual decision function for vector x
which is your input you're doing a weight weighted sum of the different futures doing
also weighted sum but the future is our special kind the features are similarities with
the original examples
way back you know in the eighties there was a renewal of interest i mean
artificial neural networks people have thought that by imitating the brain of the way you
know people understand how the brain functions we could get better
predictions of that
the machines that make predictions and the basic unit processing unit of the brain is
the neuron and has been modelled very coarsely by immaculately it's in nineteen forty three
and that's still the model of neuron which is
most used in machine learning even though you know people have made many refinements and
this very coarse model
is just simple
the linear model
really the only difference is that you have a so-called activation function at the output
so the unit makes a weighted sum
of its input and then this a weighted sum goes to what people call is
squashing function or activation function so that the input is bounded between between two about
the output sorry is bounded between two values
and as a special case the activation function can be just to step function so
making a decision between two values are low value in
high value in which case the neuron is in no way be performing a classification
task it's deciding whether you are in class zero or in class one
all these
linear methods end up making
close to one is much smaller
so that's the reason why we actually also try to keep to find a very
efficient closed subgraph algorithm
OK then finally we call this graph is called close-cropped it's very interesting i think
actually should see is there are lots of frequent subgraph mining algorithm but there are
not so many
closed frequent subgraph mining algorithm but we think the close one would make more sense
this way
after he published
the closed graph i actually try to find there some more researchers try to champion
to compete with this close was and we haven't seen them many yet but
two to the rear sense what we are really using the closed graph rather than
she spam because the close graph in any large graph region much smaller set these
are non redundant set the covers all the information so i think you know anybody
want to
to do more better graph mining have to think about this close graph method
so the ten idea if you look at the close graph centuries start from here
tried to use pattern girls to go but you try to check whether there's any
way you can do early termination because you you generate you check any parts this
part can be absorbed by the other parties you don't generally part OK
so for the same data set if you see
we actually is say
the generated close graph is much smaller for the same NCI dataset
the closed graph
you see you can lower down the support of ten thirty
the structure is fine it's much bigger
and if you look at the number of patterns generated
even this one generates all the frequent graph no matter what i was near you
think this one generate the closed frequent graph because chloe by close-cropped essentially if you
look at these are all the exponential scale
so these about this reorder magnets smaller
this for example using about the cameras like appearing yesterday we discussed if i give
them five percent support
if you generate one minute
OK patterns
and which in one
about one to two thousand patterns can is definitely like to see this to southern
rather women OK you don't have time to carry on this actually is most redundant
this is you know is this distinct there's no information loss
so if you compare with this was menagerie if you use closed
graph was and it would be order magnitude faster as well
so no matter even the space is smaller than the time is much shorter than
this one
i strongly recommend this close graph if you like to use are like to improve
really just think about this close was
are not give you very detailed error on this mining part if you like we
definitely i love to discuss with anybody
because of the time
the first thing the interesting thing for this new one is in this year PAKDD
conference we publish one car jeep wrong it's like cheese spent index we got this
call different centuries pushing the con straints deeply into this pattern mining process
just thinking about in real life when the chemist comic was computer scientist they want
to mine frequent graph
very often they give you concepts
OK for example the missing all the diameter of the constraints should be
least the greater and something too small i want to see get all of this
is that the maximum degree should be greater than ten thousand chemists quite often they
give you all these different constraints
of course the one way is to say
i mine all the frequent subgraphs based on some kind of the support the user
accounts for cut
OK but that's not efficient at all because
probably you cut ninety percent and why you have to
first find so huge set so the cost seems
graph mining region ideas
you give me the constraints
before the mining i try every to push this constant down at every iteration i
mean uses constant to cut
OK so the
the interesting thing is how can we take this constraint as effective knife to cut
through the search space
so if you think about search space cutting
they are generally generate there are two philosophy what we call pattern pruning what we
call data from
so called pattern pruning means you generate this pattern right in the middle east you
want to grow then you'll find this pattern actually does not satisfy constraints and you
also know
you for the grow this one there's no way you can say that they useful
the whole park we get don't have to grow this state animal because anything grow
out of this pattern is used
and what is data profiling data probably means you have many many graphs OK why
discussing keep growing you find the remaining
the set of this graph has no way to us
to satisfy
your constant
if you can sing for the growing
this one is no it satisfies and throw away this graph set
means if you have a very big so you can cut them you find become
a very smaller set
why do mining so
you have two knives one is cutting the graph the data
meeting point for governments which is seen by the detectors which is
based on the same principle in fact detectors used in particle physics
i was going to make the c word comes in so since there is accordingly
the easy to to call in to construct an image so eighty five percent of
all nuclear medicine exams may
this way how this is going news
at present this molybdenum ninety nine is produced in five plans fractals plants for thirty
million examinations hundred thousand
produced billion
this plant
by a two step process first the initial training the actors like mostly similarly the
ninety nine team and thirty six six percent of the times and then disband
if you have fast process in a very complicated way included in which is that
now what i of this kind this because in the last few years there's been
a big scar city of techniques many people could not get the exam to be
sure that the cancer over the world because these factors
in the netherlands had problems because getting old
and now
actually hopefully i think we come to rescue the situation i think this is very
interesting started a long time ago with neutron capture in practice now accelerators after so
many years of development come up to rescue disk all possible solution of a very
serious problem there are two proposal main but to propose one mostly one made in
canada by triumph which is blah blah blah blah blah and and this company
it is a superconducting linac which we could use electrons
five megawatts
but using a lot of photos and photo fissioning uranium no money doing it
similar to what happens in iraq and other possibilities been proposed we advanced accelerator applications
which is the second spin-off company
which could cover not only ten percent about ten percent of the market in which
is a bit of a superconducting linac falls photos producing one million one thousand people
just one megawatt and produced by capt
now i don't want to go into detail i wanted just to make the point
that this is the main which is being back the main and sitting in lot
of lives full
tell us about maybe will be rescued and i think will be by some of
i part of particle accelerators which are used for producing isotopes
this of cyclotrons this what i was thinking before for doing this on the next
this of the best this the best solution for producing molybdenum but for producing other
isotopes the hospitals and centers use cycle times
there are two types of that
baby cyclotrons
medium energy cyclotrons
i energy cyclotrons
below eighteen
we look forward to be between eighteen and forty by forty three
this now facility using ospital to produce short lived positron emitters which meet and elect
the blasters which useful what i will tell you moment positron emission tomography the the
most important one is for line eighteen
then there are many of you decide to centralized facility for producing majority of isotopes
which need high energy i would tell you something about i hired a but this
either use either for diagnostic or also for family therapy of the past is of
diffuse tumours and finally high energy cyclotrons which centralized which produced the kind of light
isotopes and say something about this one as in two hundred eleven so c
cyclotrons used mainly for diagnostic but also for
this baby cyclotrons by general electric
and i have been replication to axillary
h minuses
a hydrogen with an electron x-ray which is that of
for extracting the gold
and this exist out there is one which is only one kilometre far from here
is one in geneva
in the town of osprey that's all at the cyclotron to produce what
to produce line eighteen
by this reaction oxygen eighteen important news
this is
first of all
like to thank isabelle flowing for organizing is nice workshop and for inviting me so
my talk is
is about a method to uncover the
because of the structure and applying a particular class of econometric models i will present
in a we use graphical models has to learn to uncover his because structure in
in recent development actually we'll go beyond the graphical models despite a little bit to
the title of the presentation so
the classifica nematic models i'm talking about
vector autoregressive models which already
being mentioned in
some of the past in the previous representations of the the space station and when
particular class and what identified we talk about the structure of the vector autoregressive so
oops never view of
one of my talk is the following i'm going to define quite quickly the
and as mothers of vector autoregressive structural vector autoregression models i'm going to talk about
these causal search methods graphical models in order to identify
the structure underlying the unobserved structure like this and then
i will present an empirical application which this setting is is linear and gaussian and
then i will present some briefly some extensions one in the nonparametric setting and one
in the non gaussian case where
we can apply to based on independent component analysis so basically
the model is the following y
he is a vector of variables usually in much use in macroeconomics such
the kind of model than what is the vector of c three four five six
seven was
usually not more than that
the eighties metastasis of coefficients
we see out rest because each of these variables is the latest on
it's it's past that is not is that the UT
is the vector white noise and so on
there is no correlation across time
and the mattress of is
innovation terms is generally
number you got in the sense because of course in equation one we don't model
the contemporaneous interactions among the variables so the contemporaneous interaction will be captured by his
body by the covariance of
the innovation model is why we don't model of the contemporaneous interaction well for in
order to avoid the problems of the same type
economist much interested especially when we talk about microeconomics to study the effects of the
on the on the
relevant variables so in case of stationarity we have it is is the composition in
which these his majesty's feet a function of the original metastasis a and b for
you if you you well they actually shot of the economy in ft
we would have the effect of unit shock on the violence so we could
major these affect cost
but we see that
for any nonsingular metastasis metrics the we get an equivalent formulation an equivalent equivalent rotation
of the shock and and a new series of
mark this is
and so on
we we
the problem here and ification is to find the
actually rotation in which she we get the actual shocks that affect the relevant economic
so we have problems which is similar to get many scientific disciplines to identify
it is it is so
of the variability of the observed variability winter so it is not
not observe the heat and the
we see that if if we if we
have the right to forget
the right p
the light peter to produce the identification of the actual sharks we can
we multiply
model this way and we get to the structure of the animal model which is
not observed in which you have in this metrics gamma not the interactions among the
contemporary news reports
the idea is to divide this model is to find
and a then
in the matrix p government not
which is based on information about the contemporaneous causal structure
in the in the standard literature
these these information is sometimes impose up really
sometimes misunderstand arbitrarily
by imposing at composition of
the matrix governments much of the of the covariance matrix of the innovations terms the
idea here
starting from the estimated residuals
UTC the so-called reduced form for
studying the conditional independence relations among users doing infer the causal relationships among the contemporaneous
it was you know the to impose
these these metrics b
in order to identify them on in extension of the we presented in the last
part of my presentation i will show that this can also in case of non
gaussian eighty
so by an independent component analysis
so now i'm going to to talk about the graphical model it's two two interface
to address these this problem of identifying because action
i think i will go quite fast here because assume much of the audience is
familiar with these terms
graphs have two functions the
the representation
of course the structure it's quite obvious political that anger is directed acyclic graphs
so on the directed edges considered and the
to represent conditional independence relations under some conditions that you hear of graphical causal inference
and today we saw one approach for similar solutions but in fact last time all
we saw a couple of different approaches to resolve
whose values we don't actually know sort of step back and generalize of the couple
for example the three techniques that we saw
the different examples
so the general problem here on the specifics are you know how to identify the
how you can find out where these undefined symbols are defined or in the next
how you can take a big part name and identify which blocks contain which disk
blocks contain the files contain the data for the file that was named in the
but the general problem is you have a set of names
and associated with these names of with each name is
and these names get associated with are mapped
the to the different values in fact the names gabon to the different values and
in this example the link it taken in like the definition of assembling needed to
identify what the value associated with a simple value here in this context is where
is this name the square root or program the square root function where is it
actually find what locations
the way in which that
the solution is going to be done is done in general is using something called
in a mapping of
the mapping of million
on the value being done by name at mapping algorithm takes into account
all it takes is in takes as input something called the context
described this with an example of a minute
so named gets is born to value somebody's born into value and then when you're
link or when you're on you know part of unix filesystem and trying to identify
the value associated with the name of you don't have to all that name find
value and that resolution is going to be done on
in a particular context so for example you might have two files with the same
name to different directories and that's fine
as long as the same name could have two different values
because that resolution from the name to the correct value
in that case in the case and i know number will be done in the
context of the decree in which position is being done
so you know what we've seen over the past couple of days just last lecture
three different ways of doing it and it turns out that in almost every system
or every system that i know of any way of this basically three ways of
doing this in the solution
the first wave the simplest way is the table lookup
within the context of about o five
knowing with simple and which has set of defined symbols
taking one of the symbols the name in that case as input and finding out
where it's been defined in that five is basically a table lookup that's what that's
impossible table section of this graph
from the disk example from last time on the i know table is an example
of a table lookup and this of course of this that has in it or
the mapping between on
you know i know numbers and the corresponding i know that's just the table so
when you want to go from unknown number two nine
he took a book
and that's the simplest baseform these case of how
the name resolution
the second way of doing on name resolution is something called that name resolution
we can see an example of this today but we saw an example of that
name the solution the last you take a big unix pattern slash home slash fools
last part of what we did was start left to right along that path and
that down so are of resolution of the file
you know to get to the block that he wanted by going through a search
through through that same that's going to happen
names the item
the third way of doing on symbolism name resolution is what we saw today and
that's an example
of searching through contexts
there's really no that just tell you here is set about o five and years
that of libraries and
the symbols are undefined or defined different modules of a program effort to in different
parts of program defined somewhere among these modules and not really going to tell the
link what's being defined where it's up to the link to figure it out and
it does that by basically running a search through a variety of different products so
each dot file and each library is a new context in which the search for
previously undefined symbol happens
in this particular case the search within each context takes the form of table lookup
so those are the two
of those of the three techniques for how you do name resolution in general and
we start to of them today and we start two of them on the first
the last time we talked about the unix file system
so the last step of
in the process of what i think are does offer solution relocation
three locations
and in this case a particular kind of linking of i did use the term
but this form of linking is called static linking because we're going to take all
of these different object files and defined on the command line and the library and
built together single a single big binary that has been linked so
once probably because converts constant linking internally location that context is pretty straightforward but also
the talk more about that except to note that on this relocation tables maintain each
for the third step is a little bit more on a slightly more complicated activities
a lot of
depending on the system
and that's program loading
and the
problem solved by loading is that the link produces an output program that's executable and
you can run the program in unix you on it by typing something on the
command line
or you know and you go click on something effectively that invokes causes shell to
execute a program
so somebody has to do the work of
when you type something in common and somebody has to do the work of looking
at what file
o has been types taking the contents of the file
loading it up into memory
passing control to something that can then start running the program and typically the place
where the control as fast is the interpreter correspond to the programme
all of this work is done in unix by program called exact
it's actually an order in unix is a program colleagues at the it's job once
you type the command line is
shall invokes it what it does is to do what i said which is look
at the file name take the contents of a lot of memory and pass control
to the first on
basically the first line of the program it's usually a line of modern object files
more complicated actually having something that says with interpretive programs so you pass it lost
control two
that interpreter which in turn goes through by steps and then invokes the first line
that's what the c program the see of lauder
OK so i know all know mental but this is really
OK now
some definitions
and need to give you this section some definitions because i've been studied around using
some words
number one
the word gene
gene is one of these factors inheritance controlling interest
mendel didn't use the word genes or gene came along much later
various flavors of gene big are little more
are known as old fields
from the greek word meaning of
these are the alternative forms of the gene
it can come in the form big are little or
my great big a little a micro cluster normal and m from mutant
there are a lot of different notations geneticists use for that
the word phenotype
it means appearance
the plant was well the piece around that phenotype
the individual seven foot seven inches tall
that's the phenotype
OK those are phenotype genotype
it means the pair
of all only yields
by the individual
there are little are is the genocide they are big gaza genotype that are little
our genotypes important difference between genotypes
and phenotype
other important words so we can actually talk to each other
four homers i go
homer zygote
is an individual who has
genotype that has to have the same wheels
two copies of the same allele individual said to be homozygous and alternatively
an individual is said to be
heterozygous heterozygosity
if they have two alternatives
a couple of other important definitions
phenotype round is said to be dominant over phenotype wrinkled if
if the header zygote shows that phoenix
the heterozygous between pure breeding strains so
phenotype one
if you know one
is dominant
over phenotype so
f one of pure breeding strains
shows phenotype one
similarly we have the word recess
now mentioned and you will then proceed to probably forget because all my colleagues forget
dominant and recessive do not refer to williams
big are is not dominant
round is dominant
the gaza we'll
now you say who cares
the textbooks get this wrong all the time it's true union find textbooks use this
cricket built a big garston
what it turned out the big are controlled three different rates
maybe wellness
the ability to grow with low salt in the soil
and ability to bloom in may
some of the traits might be recessive some of them might be down
we know examples of that with the same we'll can control multiple traits some of
which show dominance some of which are set this so real hard carrying geneticists
try hard to use the word dominant and recessive to refer to phenotypes
not too only fuels
four genotypes
now since eighty percent of the faculty the biology department to use the word with
that degree of precision
i'm not have high hopes that you will either but i'm trying to say
the words dominant recessive refer to phenotypes because the geneticist kind and we all have
our but this is
one of mine is that these really do refer to phenotypes quite important because otherwise
you can get quite bollocks stop and i'll come to the case for sickle cell
anaemia where you were you will be able to describe the sickle-cell anaemia
as recessive dominant record on
good decision definitions they're worth knowing if we get those definitions right the rest of
it's pretty easy are
so many publishers this paper nineteen sixty five it's accepted appears in nature but the
proceedings of the royal academy of bruno and it's published and what happens
number sinks like a stone medals papers totally ignored nobody really pays any attention to
it this paper
mister what we might call of this digital communication
because the analog gets represented in binary digits because we've chosen
essentially because of having studied shannon at some point
the thoroughly analog sources in the binary bitstream
namely when you talk about the digital communication what you're really doing is saying i
have decided there will be a digital interface
between source and channel
OK that's what digital communication is that's what most communication today years
there's very little communication that i
the starts out with an analog waveform
find a way to transmit transmitted without first going into a binary sequence
OK so here's the picture
one of the noises
we're going to study
we have an input
which is now a waveform
we have
which is the form
we have an output which is the way for
this input here is going to be created somehow
in the process of modulation
from this binary stream this coming into chapter to the channel encoder
to some our we're taking a binary stream
turning it into
now i think a little bit about what might be essential in that process
OK if you know something about practical
engineering systems for communications
you know that there's
an organisation in the US called the FCC
and every other country has its
has its companion set of initials
which says
what part of the radio spectrum you can use and what part of the radio
spectrum you can use
and you suddenly realise that somehow it's going to be important
to turn these binary streams into waveforms which are
more or less
compressed into some frequency bands that's one of the problems we're going to have to
worry about
but at some level
if i take
but take a whole bunch of different binary sequences
one thing i could do for example
i could take the binary sequence of length one hundred
how many
how many such binary sequences author
has lead to one hundred the first bit can be one or zero second they
can be one or zero for combinations third but can be one or zero also
that makes a combination of three bits there two the one hundredth combinations of a
hundred binary digits
so theoreticians says
that those two to the one hundredth
different combinations of binary digits
in two evenly spaced numbers between zero and one
then i will take those evenly spaced numbers between zero and one modulates
some way form whatever form i happen to choose
and i was send that way for
in the absence of noise
i pick up their waveform
turn it back into my binary sequence again
what's the conclusion from this
the conclusion is if you don't have noise
there's no constraint on how much data you can send
hansen is much data is i want to know
and there's there's nothing to stop me from doing it if i don't know
somehow i have to keep these things separate i don't necessarily have to
have to separate one binary digit the next binary digit in time
i could in fact do something like
two to one hundred different waveforms
or i could do with anything
in between
i could take each each sequence of eight bits turn them into one of two
hundred fifty six waveforms transmit one waveform then a little bit later transmit another way
form and so forth so i can split up the pion anyway i want to
i will talk about that a lot is weaker one right split them up into
different waveforms which i send that space times i somehow have have to worry about
the fact that if i send them over a finite bandwidth
there's no way in hell
but you can take a finite bandwidth waveforms
and send them in finite time
anything which is which last for a finite amount of time
spreads out in bandwidth
anything which is a finite amount of bandwidth spreads out in time that's what you
want to from six w three
so so we're dealing with on soluble problem here
one night was back in nineteen twenty eight solved that problem
we say well you can make the waveform separate but you can make the samples
and people earlier i figured out they could do that with the sampling theorem but
the sampling theorem wasn't very practical
but not was way of doing it was practical so in fact you can separate
these waveforms but you still have the problem is how do you deal with noise
OK one of the favorite ways of dealing with noise
is to assume that something called white calcium noise
what is weight cassino noise white calcium noise
isn't noise which no matter where you look
it sitting there you can't get away from you move around to different frequencies noise
is still there you move around to different times it's still there it is somehow
uniform throughout time and throughout frequency
kind of an awkward thing because
if i
if i developed a receiver
which don't have any band with constraining on it
and i looked at this noise coming in which was spread out over all frequencies
in terms of collecting data
i can probably find a good number of people in this room and around the
world who are willing to let me the robot for a couple hours of data
i'd be hard-pressed to find medical doctors
we're going to let me to plan a reinforcement learning algorithm
on this type of system
the good thing is i don't need people quite yet and we have good partners
have that would allow where they do in the future work so the slices of
rat brain in addition they are letting us do a little bit of that
but again a lot of the same
difficulties arise in this kind of context which we see in the robotics context
so this is just the idea to motivate that there is a rich set of
real world problems out there
and if we want to be able to tackle these using reinforcement learning type of
approach we need to solve a few problems
in big one as far as i'm concerned is really this problem how do we
learn models
in a good way how do we do that in terms of being data efficient
and how do we do that in terms of having some robust models at the
so this is really
what's been driving my research since i left CMU getting a sense of how what
are the right models and algorithms to handle this kind of problems
one thing hasn't changed since i left CMU and this is the fact that i'm
really basing a lot of this work in the palm DP framework
i see most of you are relatively familiar with this work we told me his
teaching i think it's a machine learning class i think if you
places where people have picked up the back out the basic definition is quite standard
for any type of decision making planning task set of states that describe the state
of the system
is a set of action this is the decision making practices into passive system can
take action which causes some change
in the system and in the case of pompey that changes described using a probabilistic
and then there's also notion of reward our goal or something that
gives some indication of whether the right actions to choose in which state
and the pundit set up
there's a few
complicating factors
the biggest one being the fact that the state of the system isn't directly observable
so instead there's instead there's a set of observation which captures the part of the
state that is in fact observable in the case of our epilepsy
deep brain stimulation system the observations that we get these readings from the electrodes so
e g type readings which somehow capture what's going on in the brain what we'd
really like to know is which neurons are firing when and how we can get
that level of information so we have instead this reading
this observation probabilities that describes how the observation i made as a function of what's
going on in the system
and the last little bit that we have is is a distribution over state
and this is what captures really a state of information about the system
we don't know the state of the underlying system but we have a probability distribution
over the state
that tells us something about what's going on in the system
there's too
interesting things to do when you have a dynamic system models as the azzopardi p
the first one is tracking this belief so as you learn more about the system
as you observe the EEG signal you need to make some inference about what's going
on in the brain how does the probability of state changes
so you can do that with simple bayes rule bayesian filter in this case
the other interesting thing to do
is figuring out
what's the expected return of applying certain actions on the system
so this is a simple
version bellman equation for the palm case
this value function tells you if i in a certain beliefs if i think there's
a certain distribution over my state
what is the expected long-term return
of applying different actions
so if i take the best action i can possibly apply
get some immediate reward maybe it'll stop the seizure may be able to deliver electrical
born in iran so there's some immediate reward
and then there's the effect
of what my action has which takes me to some other part of my belief
state and then i can acquire more return
so it's standard dynamic programming kind of equation
in terms of the model of these things are really well defined they've been defined
for the the last sixty years
forty or fifty years or so what's more interesting is how do we do these
two steps the belief monitoring
and the value function
in real time
in cases where your model is not really clear and by model i really mean
the transition probabilities and the observation probabilities if you don't know what these are
a little bit in trouble here
and in cases where the state space is very large or observation space ultimately is
really large also
so i sort of set up a grand agenda is probably going to keep me
busy for a number of years
i'll tell you which part of this problem i'm tackling right now
i will assume we have a problem which can reasonably well be modeled using upon
the framework
and we assume we have the ability to sample trajectories somehow get some data from
the domain
and so
for the purposes today's talk i want to talk about two separate result
in this for the first one is assumed that the trajectories have labeled state information
someone's gone and annotated the state of the system
but you can't control it
the choice of action
we don't often work in this
like for example if you want
what if we are going to use this model several times we have about the
basis of you may want to perform several years
probably not going to deal with other bees in the first place
to be able to answer only a single query
so usually we have two lecture
so the number of queries
so you better way yes there is
there's something called belief propagation
are there other names for this plant propagation some problems
the same thing just different names for the same type of
essentially what belief propagation thus
it in the elimination algorithm with a specific schedule for that you avoid computing
we computing
the same quantities
because if have two different ways
and you don't
called computations that you've made on previous queries
after sometimes we compute
that you have to prove so how do we compute the partition function in that
year and that
query time just
competitions and
we bring them together to answer your queries so that's what propagation vol
in the experiment
the markley a
in fact it's quite simple
the idea is
maybe i should show something different first
just to illustrate
well here's the intuition i'm going to write piece for the change in the simplest
case was generalized by thirty three
in the world
my goal is to compute p of x
your of x
but x ten
can be anything and can be from one two
how compute
the marginal probability of x as well we need to sum over all the other
viable the joint distribution correct
we need to sum over the axes that are smaller than
and over the axes of the large and
the joint distribution which is this one
clique is just not right
because there is no
because i feel five
so these are my clicks on the click simple only two i
so the problem fixed
just separated this protein two parts one part of the model another part of the
and then i can perform this information separately here
in this summation separately
right because of the system
because these is a constant with regard to all the viable large and
these are also the got all the violence there is more than
just use the distributive law all these
a separate this into this problem
because this is a course
with respect to one set of summation what's happening again
a b
it's true
that's true
essentially can write is left
the expression this way to can write this
right expression is note
he is only a function of x and
i don't know exactly what these blocks but they are common spatial patterns which i
haven't introduced so far
ARR coefficients
and maps
these are all features that i expect with some statistical techniques a-ok efficiencies clear what
this is so it so if i look at the dynamics of the time series
i can model this by approximating just the linear coefficients of in a our model
and and then just
using these linear coffee coefficients and them plotting
and if you look at the covariance structure
then it's clear
that has the block structure
so you see that that
there some
some covariance of course within the same type of feature that we have to extracting
but it is actually true that there is almost no
cross talk so to say between the feature
which means that we can
do something like that
if i
we we would
user classifier on every single feature say and then these classifiers make different decisions then
we can
you know
king something
but again there
lots of different ways of combining
sensor fusion
talk about this
now this is something
just some theoretic slide you know what we can actually gained by independent features
let's let's let's say
so if if the classificati outputs are gaussians and we have an independent features
and indeed we have the the same classification error
for some binary classification of path for each then we can actually prove that
of all the classification error can decrease
so if we
and this is a very very somewhat stupid assumption we are assuming that all features
i sorta to see equally valuable are or invaluable
all features have are all of of c so to say
but if we combine them and their independent then what can we gain
OK so
he is he's different curves so if we
so if we have one feature to six features
if the single feature has five percent classification error ten and so on
so we see that this this
the below quote because or any classic n the number of features grows
in this direction
so so clearly
so even if we have an higher and higher on the single feature we can
actually improve the overall classification rate strongly
assuming full independence
in this very simple model so so we can we can actually hope to gain
the lot
in practice this
gauss in distribution assumption might not be the case in practice it might not be
the right assumption that to assume that all these these features are given equal classification
rates this is certainly not true someone want discriminant others are not
but it just gives you
an idea
why this could be
a very good idea
this is some small print
so so how would you
how would you
i mean the most obvious way i think it's just concatenate and just below the
large classifiers e
so that's the first one
the second
a third one
so you would
a single classifier
on each feature vector
with LDA
and then you would like to optimally
combine them in the way and if you're assume that everything is calcium essentially and
you assume that all the
covariances of all the classifiers are equal
it's it's a theoretical question completely theoretical question assume that you have different classifiers that
that you
train with LDA
so that's you have different covariance structure for every classifier
if you have to have a full covariance for all the classifiers and these folk
variants which differ between the classifiers it would be very complex model you have to
to estimate
a lot of
but if you assume that the covariances i actually very
similar or the same as we do
then you can actually give a closed form solution
to what is the optimum type of of classifier
and so it assuming that you have this covariance structure
then you can
build a classifier which is
taking the probabilistic assumptions that we have made of every single classifier into account
of course it this is not correct because the all the classifiers words have slightly
different covariance structures
and maybe it's not appropriate at all to train them all by LDA
but this is just an approximation would see how far we can get that
so that the meter strategy is training
for each
individual feature
training a classifier
getting this to classify output and using those
to go together with the labels for the second layer of of of classical classification
so weak keep those classifiers fixed
so to say in the first layer for every individual feature
set and then
combine the train the complete combination with regularisation
this as i said about thousand and one ways of combining things so these these
to be able to actually learn them into them from data
and finally and i think this was sort of underappreciated early
in a lot of this research is that the algorithm's going to talk about today are
actually based on a pretty small subset of operations that turn out to scale incredibly well
so there's sort of long-running phenomenon in machine learning
where you want to get really great results and go to a conference and published and so
forth a way to do that just get a lot more data with a lot bigger computer
you can almost always better
and with a lot of algorithms going sort of
build them by hand we have all these rules coded in
it's really hard to scale up and take advantage of all these things because you have so much
knowledge wired in
and what you're more clever
and you can get increasingly clever it's harder and harder to get better results
but if we have a learning algorithm
that scales really well with hardware and with more data
then it becomes easier to get results as we get better hardware we get
larger datasets
so one of those things it's really nice about deep learning
is that whenever we get a faster computer
or we get a larger dataset
we can train a bigger model
so hopefully you'll see by the end of this
that most of these things are very simple dense linear algebra operations and they run really
fast on a computer and it energy you
so just to sort of also answer another question upfront
one of the questions as have been here before
so a lot of deep learning
spawns from neural networks research
which some of you may be familiar with if you took like an introductory course
and a lot that was sort of having its heyday like nineteen eighties and so on
and so it's worth are
trying to understand
as anything really changed since then
and so the answer to the question have we been here before there are two possible answers yes i know
and the
on the yes side we say that the basic ideas here
are actually pretty common
to past machine learning algorithms neural networks
so for example if you want to do supervised learning with labeled data
it turns out very straightforward procedure i'm walking through that a second
but also
sort of standard machine learning development strategies if you take a machine learning course to learn about
how to debug machine learning algorithms
all that stuff you can carry-over
and a lot of knowledge from problem domains like computer vision
are different applications
has also been carried over
so this stuff that we we sort of know that's old hat and so in this
sense things have changed so much
but there are few things
that have changed that are pretty critical
so for example we have much faster computers and a lot more data
used to be the case that if you train neural network with a very small amount of data
in order to get really good performance you had to wire a lot of your own knowledge into
but now we have huge datasets really big computers to process them
we can actually get away without that prior knowledge and what we want is really flexible algorithm that
can just gobble up all data and make decisions
so that sense
sort of operating regime where we want to to work on applications has changed
so that's very new
we are better optimization
we are better at figuring out how to initialize the neural networks
and all these different models we want to train so there's a lot of
useful research there and in fact
one of the key results
this responsible for bringing all this stuff to
of late
was from geoff hinton and yoshua bengio
back in two thousand six which is effectively a very
very cool initialization procedure that made all the training algorithms work much better
and finally
i think there's also another underappreciated point which is that
we now have time of empirical evidence partly from having faster computers more students
running lots and lots of experiments with these things
we know much better what are all the various components that matter
and sort of neat fall out of using neural networks and using a common framework
for all this is that when your friend tells you conference ok i just tried this
new module inside my neural network
you can go home re-implement that thing very quickly mix and match with all the other components
so there's been quite a bit of work figuring out
what the right modules to be plugged into these things that we can all use
so this is pretty great and this is our this is
now having real impact
used to be is pretty tough
to do a real application because we needed all that prior knowledge had to be a domain expert
and deep learning systems our starting to really
come of age and we're seeing a lot of state the-art results not just in computer vision
but lots of feet different fields
most recently
very cool result by alex krizhevsky
elicits cover and geoff hinton
from nips twenty twelve
was this basically deep neural network that is currently holding the state of the art
results on the imagenet dataset
so very large data set
they hold challenge every year called the imagenet
large scale visual recognition challenge
and they're deep neural network was the first place system in this challenge
and i'll show you some results from that later
hopefully by maybe an hour into this talk you'll have all the basic underpinnings to
implement system like yourself
but we're saying that outside vision
the things are also are doing incredible things in speech
and natural language processing so
there's a whole bunch of other stuff to go along those fields
i that i hope you'll go in and read up on some point
this filling in distribution is
the correct posture appears at x
that is the q which saturates exist and so improve the article already do
from this
this is
that flight
the here
and again
four months later shows that if you apply this exact experience q you actually
exactly the marginalized so that you will see it
you can also show this by
essentially using variational calculus or by
using the fact that the difference between the likelihood of the ban is the KL
divergence between two and
this year
OK so
we now have the ingredients that we need and to try to sort concrete example
in the case sugar so make sure that you have the marginal density x is
just a sure
the law likelihood is
just a lot that
and here's how to
we need to compute the correct posterior distributions over cluster assignments given the current and
that's exactly what
doing so
i'm going to do about the probability of the cluster
signed privacy and data points
this k given the data and the kernel parameters
recall that q so can
and that q is just the ratio of the probability of the data and the
model divided by the total of the
so you say how likely is it under
they divided by is
some overall and ratio are the responsibility to secure distribution
so nice that we basically have
for each data point
do not want
which are the prime current parameters when i think about that you want to come
to london to street
so if you want to to put tag data
the tag q which says this point belongs to seven to john f
three to alex smola and zero zero one two
and the different data different
which makes it
and in the sense that something very interesting in the step i do
responsibility weighted more
so now
the k
but she got senses mean two
the responsibility weighted average of
so it doesn't remember all money to all of the data that was in cluster
k a b
back to me
well here
we don't really have a hard
soft labels to just take the weighted average
the responsibility weighted average of the data that you need cluster k and responsibility with
covariance is the new covariance and some of the responsibilities
the fraction the responsibility in total along is the u s
so it's very intuitive
so the first step is just the application of these rules but in general this
will involve writing an inference that and this is just the weighted learning in fully
observed case and in general to all the same kind of thing that you want
to learn about with weights on the data points instead of things
so it's still hard to this this model
so here's the data
in greek
and then when showing you erations each point drawn parameters going make sure to get
so the parameters the all one graph
the covariance and from all to blue and also colored points according to their maximum
posterior assignments so this the first iteration now he's and any
you want
are there
my i
but i want to are
o four
from this
all right
and that
he said
so here we are
one of them
here in manner
all these
i think
of the most
i was
you are right
you are
when this product
it's going to be shipped
from this
have an exception
life going on
our probabilities our small numbers
and all this
so is usually very close to zero
and logarithmic from zero it's
minus infinity and in many much is be exception
i can show you very very simple approach how to solve this problem
you simply need to
the biggest probability from this
more and more a movement from this form format
i don't understand how i got this result
i'm assuming that
he one of the biggest probability
in this case
is the biggest probability lasts longer is very close to zero
you can even if you need optimisation and they want to talk
this calculation you can even still based on
absolutely of
of these substructures of licorice
it's very obvious things but i don't know why but in real life usually people
i don't understand how to do
so we know how to work with probabilities
they have
our huge files with sculptors with work his by around his driver and set of
it looks like we have everything to create our
well suggestions or something like this
the result is too huge
use imagine that we have
dictionary of
one thousand words
and we have some big college
one thousand words not is not big dictionary you can fit into memory
at the same time
why graph
you have
and square by around in real life usually we don't have all the way around
so you have
maybe a number of millions by background this is a problem
again it cannot fit into memory
and intuitions about what they can do consider
we already has smoothing
i don't really accept that
a lot of work with low probability
it's simple and scene
so let's assume there exist
three and four
they're not interested for us
can simply remove them and to use for their probability estimation from schmoozing
i believe that this is true so
how we can estimate that it's true
we can look at
very simple very prone
language model when we have a language model is
the mosque
probably more of the english language in this article there
and the second most probable words
position or and you can see that
actually it's not not very
exact example that doesn't show a lot but you can see that difference in entropy
here is not so
so being
from zero two
if the using the simplest model is one where we have point seventeen
adding next word is adding one
o point one only point one to
very pretty easy
he introduced the long-range interactions or long range interactions in general
it actually can bring dynamic programming grinding halt
so you can get very very expensive
to the point where
exact dynamic programming is not used anymore
there are lots of
well beautiful not the beautiful approximations for approximate that program
this is one of the really i think the weapon right now
this basically what i told you before
you do the recurrence back
there's a lot of extensions of background structure but given the by that we will
be read to talk about the page tracking i will be doing that anymore
but the page tracking
what you want to i mean this is very different
estimation problem when not tried
i think when i'm trying to output a private
the permutation is the structured objects
so well i want to estimate the right permutation for
now the problem interested in more specifically is where you have a collection of documents
and associated query
and relevance scores
the reason for that is because this is actually
the way how at least some search engines
about it being generated from users
the reason why need this baseline data because of another like this brought let's say
for instance
i look for smaller in germany and somehow i'm opening up as the first hit
but maybe the third or fourth is incentives
i mean i actually then hire somebody to click on my link all the time
or if a little bit smarter i will actually
right the tried and which will then pick lots of
computers and they will also create google query for small and then they will become
this way you can have fairly nasty problem
and this way google at some point might realise how so many people are clicking
my name so therefore
what i'm doing must be super relevant and they will
increase my writing
and those that
OK well
well not always not with my name
but but i mean there are companies basically
well gain some advantage of that we lost when think about it but they can
decrease the rankings companies hold search thing and that the or loss of the single
searching you
find out about the very
and i know that
a well-known writer for support vector book
optimizes the site very much to
make sure it comes up very highly
some search engines and now it's not the book with bernard
OK anyway
what you get is about documents
a query and ratings with with that as i want you to do is we
outsource that india or china depending on which market target
so you basically get
user annotated queries
and and ratings for it and you seem to agree that the resulting saying that
may be and the pages
and the query on the right
and obviously if you look for britney spears then the machine learning summer school web
pages probably not very meaningful but on the other hand if the machine learning summer
school this page will be highly aligned they have a query and the document releva
rate dependent
and people use all of these are
scoring function like when discounted cumulative gain or maybe a normalized version of that
a better of version this is what they
that the permutation output
and that's what we have
there's not enough
try to the inner product between
the probit permutation matrix and the model parameters
why this well this is what i'm asking myself about
certain communities experiments course
and every companies still one so for instance
microsoft exponentiated who who
explain it but it uses a different
score for the relevant here
so and i don't know what to do this
we have you now highly nontrivial
scoring function we actually need to turn into a loss function electrons
and we want to find the optimisation problem for that
good luck the easy
i think the article
basically it performs they could have done anything that everything is sorted array one well
what i'm actually