so we have to know my name is written english as an incoming trunk at
stanford university in madrid spain
and then going to present their work sequence classification using statistical pattern recognition
done in collaboration with capitalism as an article isn't
so for as far as i say no they are not getting married
so there
part of this presentation will be the motivation and introduction of this research
then we will explain the main idea of this sequence classification how we have to
talk about this problem our approach after that we will describe the environment where we
have used this approach and the research
finally conclusions and future works
there are many different areas in which we can
it can be very useful to model classifier recognise the behaviour previous to this research
that we're presented today we have been working in the circus simulation the mind
and what we do is to
classify the opening team behaviour in order to improve our own team behavior
in this research we are interesting in their behaviour classification
but where the behaviour is represented that sequences of elements therefore we can talk about
sequence classification
when this sequence is the set of elements where are there is is essential
OK after this brief
into ocean we will describe the sequence classification and the main goal is
given a set of classes and a sequence
to classify we still determine
which class does this sequence belongs to
how we have tackled this problem
OK first in italy what we have here a set of sequences
and a sequence to classify
as we can see in this slide we have used for this example unix commands
sequences but sequences with any kind of elements can be used
the two parts
of our approach the library creation the first part and the second part is the
in the first part
but what we do is
to get there
whole sequence that represent represented by class and we create a set of others that
we are storing the special way that we will explain later
and we start betting what we call but in library
once we have created it
this library what we do is
weak with the same set of patterns for the sequence to classify
and we compare
this set of buttons with their
classes classicist starts in the in the library
and then finally the classification results depend of the results of these comparisons
we will explain now
two parts of our approach and for the first one
we are using their that their structure called try
and it's spatial search tree used for storing elements and its prefixes and in these
structure very node represents an element and every note also stores useful information mainly how
many times this node has been appear in the
in the sequence
we will explain very very quick how it works so it we have sequence like
first what we need is because of their
the length of this sequence we have to split the island into sequences sub sequences
of equal size so for example if we use a a subsequence of
length three
for this example
we have
two different sub sequences that we have to insert in the trie
that is the structure that we
we have
what we have so
first we insert their they hold subsequence and after that because of the relevant because
of their
and the dependence of the between their elements is very relevant so we is also
the suffixes of these sequence
so we have to consider that
they nodes who
the elements who have already been inserted into try
we don't quit and you know for these
for these element what we do is we change the number that we can see
here in brackets represent how many times has this note has been appearing there in
the sequence
after the first
subsequent we at the second one and also its prefixes
as we can see for its sequence we will have
we will start this sequencing
a structure like this
after great this right we have to evaluate the relation between an element and its
for this we have used and statistical approach
so what we do is
we calculate cheese square value for its
in the
we have
to calculate a two by two comprehensive table
and after that we started this tir square
value in
in its nose and we can see here
in red color
these this structure like this is created for each class
and this is the set of these
this structure is what we call
pattern library
once once we have created these library we have two
the classification
for doing that
first what we do is to create their it to it right for this sequence
to classify in the same way that we have already explained
and then we have to compare
these strike with their
tried that we have
story in the library and for this comparison what we do
four heats in the testing trie
we start this set
the same note in the class
try and they try
we can see that if the node and its prefix are in both tries its
we can we have to compare the tears square and if if these two queries
is smaller than a threshold value its mean that there is some kind of similarity
between both tries
what we do is we get a positive value
but in this case we have considered the tir square value of the test
this is the
the value for this example and after that we have to do this one for
all the nodes of the
testing try
for example in this case if the note and also its prefix are only in
the testing try its mean that there is some kind of different so what we
do is we store
a negative value
and and these negative values so that you square of the distance
you will have to do that with every note of the
of the distant right
and after that the were sort of this comparison
is a set of similarities and differences so
the final result is this room of all these
comparing come in
similarities and differences
so for example in this simple example that we have
that we have used this will be the comparison value
so the idea is that we have to
we have to obtain a comparison value
for it's claims that we have already
store in there in the pattern library
and finally
according to john economics american economic review but this particular paper is still working
so i think that he had some problems in the refereeing process in
having his ideas set by by the referees in any case he starts from a
stylised facts
and the cell fact is that firms in terms of size
our power law distribution
there's a huge amount of evidence about this and you can change the measure of
the size in terms of sales in terms of employment
in terms of total capital
you can change countries as well
united states
it's only
israel as well
in germany and some great britain damarcus from the evidence for all these countries and
in all cases it turns out to out that the firm size distribution is is
the power
the idea of the bayes that's well suppose that we have IID shocks
maybe coming from the oceans from normal distribution
so with the five minus
but this sharks affect
which are different in size
so we have sharks two very big firms
shops to small firms
so in this case it's possible to show
he shows hit that if we have an inference and surface firms apologists beauty
well the
i mean if equations
as the size which is proportional assign increases
the size was proposed with the is which is proportional to one over the natural
logarithm of n instead of
one over and square which is the
classical results for the large numbers
so the lower level numbers of as we can slow the application of the rule
of law
OK but this is this is nations
continues to assume that
total factor productivity shocks
five hours
so the idea that try to exploit
what about if shocks
i have infinite lives
so they can be modeled by means of letters simple solution
i have some results on some statistical results i'm not going to a i'm not
i'm not going to address this topic theoretically of i'm just working but i have
not resolved yet i just i have just some statistical results which has been published
two or three months ago
and i i xi started from from the data
from the data about the fact that it we have published a labelled data for
the united states usage amount of data we have data for forty years for more
four hundred and sixty sec tools
so we have really for economics this is a huge amount of data
and try to make some distribution fitting exercise
moving from this from this hints so this is
the time series
of the total factor productivity shocks his official
this artificial data published by the national bureau of economic research so probably one of
the most well-known research institute in economics all over the world
no they obtain the data from the production function approach
so the estimator yes you can find details in the paper by about my and
others in the national bureau of economic research working paper scissors
so here you have three times the standard deviation around me
you have four hundred seventy sectors these are just for example
items for distribution and you find that it's quite common to find some
it's really come common for some plants
recall that's
inside the last mile three standard deviation if you have a normal assumptions more than
ninety nine percent of the mass of the solution
so this is really
this really
events really really far in the tails of the distribution if we have if we
assume might
OK and when this happens basically for for for all the time series of distribution
so i tried to two
two to to see what happens if if we
the the war dead
because the this the separator is with this resource score so the unreasonable ones always
zero reason once deposit would have one
the reason was a negative weight minus one and so
so we need as well if you've got lots of features but most of them
are way zero so
when i was just an example of an algorithm has that kind of property
anyway so this is an example of changing the definition of
still if it's possible that it's still not quite as good as the standard SVM
anyway so
OK so
i because the main point of this is just to say that normally
the notions of kernel functions it has been very much the series all been very
tied to viewing them as implicit mappings and the idea is that we can still
make statements about what makes the similarity function useful for learning without talking about implicit
spaces so it's possible to filter theory includes the usual notion of good kernel functions
although we did end up losing something in the parameters i suspect that there and
actually i think it's this recent ICML the that some people have different notion did
it didn't contain all the notion of good kernel function but when a little bit
different direction i suspect there other directions one goes well developed other sufficient conditions that
that each suggest there are now
so so our definition we're motivated by trying to include the usual notion of good
kernels modulo some parameters theory also holds for some functions are
necessarily positive semi definite or even symmetric
i get to the symmetry aspect an expert in the the hope is this may
be helpful with intuition we're trying to come up with a similarity function for you're
given application you don't have to think OK which it is going to have a
larger margin in its implicit space you can maybe think which it is more likely
to have some so the reasonable points that such that things are on average more
similar me start to have some feel of your domain but it might be easy
to fix
OK so so that the second part
i want to ask the question can we use this angle
and i'm thinking about clustering
OK so i think of the following setting so let's imagine we've got
has the same things before we got a bunch of objects i think the documents
images documents about the documents
and so those are documents
and there is some unknown ground truth clustering
each of these has some true label
let's say
between one and TSC with what what's about to stop and think if t is
a relatively small number compared to n number of data big number maybe like five
topics about data documents
OK so everything has some true
topic this one's about this one's about that since about something else
the problem is
well no one told us what those labels are
we OK so of state state is are topic one topic
our job is to
from this data
produce hypothesis producer clustering that is pretty close to the ground truth
so we want to also cost the by topic and we wanna do pretty well
i'm doing pretty well we get them all writing up to isomorphism the label name
so if this is close to one
in this cluster to our algorithm call this cluster one cluster two
five right
we get lower so the same learning type but the problem is that we don't
have any labelled data
nobody really only unlabelled data so can we do anything at all well maybe we're
given the pairwise similarity function
somehow is related to the topic maps it's not right if a notion of similarity
is just based on how long the documents are
that's probably not going to be useful
first telling what they're about
now maybe
it could be but from this hopefully will be related to what we're trying to
do and the question is you know whether sufficient conditions again for how related it
should be
that we could then cluster one
because what conditions on a similarity function would be enough to allow us to get
a good cost
so what i'm doing and said it so i guess one thing i should mention
is i'm sending this up in a way that's a little bit how the office
of the usual way people so that cluster normally you are clustering is a your
input is maybe a graph attributes embedding of points and our already and you view
that embedding is the ground truth i got these points
OK and that's the ground truth
and then you analyse the ability of of algorithms to achieve different optimisation criteria will
be a good algorithm for
k median problem for
k means from in some parts of some objective you try to find a good
algorithm for that
and then you argue about which criteria produced better-looking results on your well i often
k means to test him into that means some i think spectral clustering to this
other thing this one was the better
this looks
so what we do is turn this around
i'm not going to view the embedding
or the graph is ground truthground truth is the topic for each thing i want
to know whether sufficient conditions on
the kind of graph structure on the on the similarity function allows to find that
and so in this way it's a little bit more like what we you do
in the model we say well do learning mixtures of gaussians are something we assume
the some underlying ground truth or probabilistic models by one thing it's
call discriminative rather than generative model i don't wanna
one thing it's more like a statistical learning theory
so so let's start with something that's totally trivially works and let's see what happens
when we try to weaken tiny bit so here's totally here's a really strong property
suppose any two objects at the same time is called documents and clusters for any
two documents of the same topic have similarity bigger than zero two documents of different
topic of similarity lessons suppose a hand similarity function satisfying the property now i claim
it's very easy to cluster documents but it a quite good symmetry that's went to
somebody else so much later OK
let's weaken this little bit
what if i just tell you that my similar function is the following property
object all documents are more similar to other documents of their own topic than to
any document a other top but i promise you that this is a function of
the property for any object if i were to sort the others by similarity to
this guy its own cluster would come first followed by everything else
that's still pretty strong condition
is that enough to cluster well
here's the problem the same similarity function could satisfy this condition for very different clusterings
of the same data to imagine data
documents like this where you've got four taxes this documents about football basketball math and
physics and let's say the ones
you know all these guys are all very similar to each other these guys are
all very similar to each other these guys here discussed here
the up and down the if the medium similarity in this way is less than
so and also what is this this could be
for clustering
OK four clusters before clustering
it could be two clusters could be sports
it could be two clusters or
i mean for those of us in this room for me it looks like this
is math and physics which is clearly different in sport
for people outside this building it looks like this
football and that's what really different stuff with equations over here
OK so
are all consistent with this property
OK so here this is the right answer
everybody if you you first get all these and then you get sort starting from
and in values for a number of
the problem variables problems variables but that's my not boring
we have
a more complete partial
evaluation of all proposed variables
you still have not you reach unit clause contradiction
and you continue doing the same so basically
going down the search for
browsing on another
from variables
the very best of knowledge this clear a point three
marked in red in the
at this point
you need to actually lasted
one two three
four five
values for
many problems there are in fact that's that's all the problems variables that you have
he that so had reached contradiction that this in class
and of course satisfied
so all
no course
been falsified there's no uniform no
and because it's been deriving this means that all clauses are satisfied
and as i
claimed earlier
this formula
being satisfied to being land that sort of planet problems begin to rise
and now we can
actually read the
planet from the evaluation for the
propositional variables that they lost which is actually what they can so i only those
lines here where there is
their actions
variable value through this
here's some of the variables
what this classes it's starts from
they can be
block e
starts from
this a
the action plan so
there we have
only accident stating one zero
this is taking you from the the top of the page
is what has happened
one so the second
so that they are all that this would not be possible with
first sources and we generally so
taken from the table and we're going to be learned simultaneously sees
from the top of the
these lectures
he was thinking about what you
c was
and to
is the end of the table that
and in the last
this point
taken from the sea
the rest the of thing from the one could see the
well actually is a
so take a
this is the
corresponding to this
they is
that has also
the same number of times more so than for problems from zero to five
but he has
your accent so
they based
this is an unnecessary moment somewhere maybe you can
finally if you will be
i can also find c
this intermediate
want the table that is story i think this block c
so that's the
the first
so basically you
but in the table and then with the
so how how does this
so once you may want to learn to make predictions
associated with the current business is revealed
y which is the label the the true label the one generated church
it is revealed
and so at this point the
the learner has a chance of updating
and the weights
with this i mean some update rule
which is another story
an algorithmic description of on how to
in in include the information
provided by the current example by the example in the stream
combined with the
parents of these produced in your pocket
no probability not sufficient statistics nothing
it's just not that there is an important question i mean
nothing to laugh about because we should be happy no more probability
up now
whatever whatever like i mean i'm not imposing any restrictions but but it's correct i
you might object that if you
if you're going to talk about online learning then
you must have some bounded membership function
i'm not making any bounded memory assumption right now
but you will see that the article many of the that come up with
are reasonably are reasonable in terms of memory
they don't have to
remember i will i'm not going to
explain any three yellow and green which is another remember or the
because is so what you what you could do
you can remember the
tactics of the stimulus is so far the the whole thing and then run at
the money back
this is this framework but probably you wouldn't be happy if i give you this
is the typical on library
there is some information about the fact that i'm not going to i shouldn't be
cheating here
rather give a formal definition
a a bunch of conditions you know full to defined family and got
this in as a as a progress in my description in my lectures so that
the end would be should be more satisfied with the kind of argument
then i mean if you want a things scale especially if you're using kernel then
the thing becomes more
a bit more it's a more subtle but at this point
if you might think OK let's suppose that the something reasonable here
i'm not ruling out online SVM point but them not focused my lectures them because
it's not a good thing we can do it here
OK so why
now why are you
why should we will be interested in this thing here
the first of all i just do not be clear observed that the learner
of classifiers
as it is exposed to more and more of the three things so we have
a sequence of classifiers which is the way the data sequence of
i thought this up by the
in the
and then of course we should be
it this but if you want if you want to evaluate arguments if you want
to compare algorithms in this framework we should have some sort of some sort of
a performance measure and there's no more risk is not worth the risk because i
don't want to make a mistake this kind of statistical assumptions on the way to
generate a stream in is an arbitrary object is an individual object is just produced
by and fibronectin
i don't probability here so i can define race in the statistical in this case
and the only thing i have is the empirical behaviour of the algorithm on the
specific stream it is observing
OK so
the only thing i can i made a reasonable thing can you use use the
performance measure
is the
eleven three number
of mistakes
on the stream
right so
what is the idea here
the idea here is that the
we're going to
there's something about the properties of the out degree by bounding the number
of mistakes were made in terms of specific properties of the tree
your model last year so the class where you're searching your model
it's actually corresponds to reality
so you're not really over overfitting you're not feeling come model that's more complex than
it should
you might have problems with overfitting but typically what love is really with active learning
lab under fitting because you know parts of the space that are important that making
the errors there because you that the model that's
kind of weak
just because you don't have much data that if you're not careful about the way
you are doing active learning
and i just added the notable trying to validate this active learner some hold out
kind of difficult and somewhat at odds with the goal of active learning because the
validation would say you're trying to get some estimate of the
error rate of the classifier
and i want to go to say just a random set of validation data then
you're going to be back to
the ability to get a handle on the areas back to the past kind performance
level and so it's very difficult sometimes no
we are not here active learner
and the model produces is actually performing well you engaging its actual error performance levels
but difficult in practice
so that's why this error a gnostic
procedures were trying to say well we can never know for sure
if our active or has really area but we can sometimes make a reasonable decision
of whether to a
instead of some passively learned model
focusing are sampling between those two models in their disagreement region
that's kind of what i talked about before but actually estimating the error rate of
of your class any classifier could be difficult because then you're back to just say
passively safe
right i
no there is also in terms of the the VC dimension
and active learning
it doesn't really
because of the nature of
he buys all the it's
he also even
four one
the thank all you you cannot be the it's
at a certain point you really the concepts are sort of uniformly over
spread over a certain threshold
a space of some dimension you're being going to be constrained by the way you
want to learn concept that you
you can do and actually in the third part of the last slide that can
illustrates this ability for regression it's not easy
surely you agree that it is very so
so far
yes it should start soon
OK so far
no the third
the final part of the
this one
will switch
in the middle
i'm going to start by talking
it's about the different problem with active learning is a regression problem
we're going to look at it may be more from a practical standpoint then from
all just analysis trying to understand what
but does active learning for you
we actually have some theoretical results but
nine inches of it is trying to find practical ways of doing this
just to pick up where we left functional boundaries and real-world boundaries
very different than this boundary fragments so
what can we do not reduce the problem to one dimensional problems
we go about it
the problem we are going to consider here is a regression problem
so you're trying to learn functions so you have this
airplane here and you have a range measurement so it's like measures the distance from
the point of the terrain and you're trying to learn this terrain the wonderland ellicott
just their stuff like that so
the is OK to train is sort of a kind of sport here's what here
there's a sharp transition there so with these kinds of measurements you see that you'll
need more samples
to locate
this kind of language
two really estimate is smooth
part of the function so in one dimensional
in one-dimensional version of this from this function you have
noisy samples collected nice examples CEO
but it seems that not too much interesting stuff is going on here are here
let me collect more samples may be in between
hopefully if you go about this correctly you will have more samples around this
and fewer samples
around the smooth parts of the function
and this is and that locating discontinuities the bottleneck
and this example rather were shown around since cystatin that was a bunch of sensors
are small tube
low battery life so you don't want to use them up very much so
can you somehow
figure out where what has is to activate to turn on to communicate
so that you can reliably detect this boundary of these i'll still are what's the
oil density around around this
so what are the rules of the game
it's similar to what we had before
we have a class of functions
that's going to consider
that's what we did this morning
now we look at conditioning in feature space
we already touched upon the hammersley clifford decomposition
will be looking at conditional distributions said
i would look at some applications
in fact
the nice thing is
we start straight away with graphical models
so one thing to
now in this context is
what conditional independence means
so here's the formal definition xnx prime
a conditionally independent
given some very e
if the joint probability of x and x pry occurring given c
the same thing as the probability of x occurring given c
the probability of ex-prime occurring giving c
simple example
got the light switch down here
have got a whole bunch of light bulbs
but turn the light switch on some of the labels marko and some of them
might not
some of my break
the probability of each of those breaking probably independent of each of the other of
so the probability of the light car lighting up
given that i know what position the light switches in
it is independent for each of those lightbulbs
will be
a simple example of that or
another case of conditional independence
let's assume
well we take care of the naive view of history and we say that well
what's going to happen tomorrow will only depend on today
and what happened today only dependent on yesterday
so that the words if i know about the entire state of the world today
i don't need to know about the previous states of the world in order to
predict the future
so in this case and also to look back into the past i don't need
to know the future
so in this case well given the present past and future independent of each other
they're conditionally independent
if i don't know the present state exactly
then of course
past and future are dependent on each other so somebody talks about well the policies
relevant for the future all saying is well we don't have full representation of the
current state of the world and looking at the past is necessary in order to
say something about the future
why is this useful because
if i have such conditional independence assumptions i can actually make the joint distribution over
a whole bunch of random variables much easier
is it
greatly reduces the complexity of the space of distributions that are operating in
markov network
it is a way how to draw those distributions quite easily
basically what you do is you switch from a statistics and wall essentially expression based
representation to something that you can easily show somebody who can understand it and pass
it and
well in the layperson can say well you know these things will probably depend on
each other and i'll just run amok
so it's actually something that's good for users to model
OK so
markov network is
with some vertices and edges
eight of the vertices correspond to random variables
and now subsets of those random variables are conditionally independent
given some other random variables
if removing the vertices from this graph decompose the graph into disjoint subsets containing is
in his prime
well that sounds like quite a mouthful
let's have a look at some examples
so here's
graphical model is another one
that would be
the thing about the past and the future
if i conditioned on
the present
remove this
this change and and that change decompose
so in other words there's only a certain place way
this set of random variables here
can influence the otherwise it has to go through this one
and i'll be exploiting this in the article
or here
but the slightly more fancy model
in that case well
conditioning on those right notes here
makes it the rest of the graph decompose
if i didn't condition on that one
then the rest will not be conditionally indepen
but you can see is
this is probably quite the an important random variable to look at
is this really separates using this happening here
everything that's happening over there
so what is also indicates that if afterwards they want to design an efficient algorithm
i should probably take advantage of this
but this will be my conduit through which a lot of the inference information is
channeled through in both directions
but it will also mean that if this variable is only very simple one it
can only takes a states one and zero is not so much information that can
go either way i can exploit this
this is probably a fairly complicated scenario which
transfer information from the live far to the right one
will get to equations to make the distilled with one standard
key concept in this context of cliques
so once i got my graph
define a plague to be
a subset of vertices which are fully connected with each other
prince instance this pair
i fully connected with each other
the green one here
this fully connected with each other all four nodes have a stall
the other three members
in their place
those three are fully connected
OK now
who can tell me the other to maximal cliques in this graph
any volunteers
you know that
it's very good
and yet
very good
so we have four five maximal cliques
o thing is as it will turn out the maximal cliques are exactly those quantities
that will play a role
in performing inference
because they also essentially the
ensembles of random variables that you can't really introduce very much anymore
and what people typically what do is you would write down a tree of cliques
and how they're connected with the separate estates being the points which those cliques have
down here
and then it flattens out like
and so that's what i knew
eighty inland actually looks like
and now the suggestion is take all the data take your one thousand points that you've measured to almost precision
and throw away all the precision and then just up
and people like
why did you completely new thrown away lot information there
we might worry and you have access to information
but you could do it
and then
you've gotta do something with this curve here
so are you work out what the actual data mining is
they bring along x by
we find the actual mean what they call x
which are not defining be the sum of its own
you bring along a news through this line here
plot the downstairs and he said okay there is an estimator
the lambda
what you had in mind
i like the idea
because that's you know that's
i don't have any beans in it
but it did involve a very big step and say i'm going to compute the mean
and you could have said
i'm going to compute the variance or i'm going compute fifth moment or you could
be in the whole load other things to measure
and then you could plot then
the function lambda so
another thing
could be plotted as a function of lambda
like the
and then you get your data and you come down and they could be anybody's three
so is
and now an infinite family of things that you could do i think this is
a brilliant idea and you'll see why in a moment
there is an infinite number of things you could invent which depend on lambda
and you could
pick one of those and then measure it and using it to come back and get an estimate of lambda
that's another thing that is done in classical statistics
hand it can often be done well
hand you can also get in trouble because what if the three data points as they
is being
what if they were
it could happen right
you only three points
hand there are also the writer
the midpoint
and i work out the mean and it's above the midpoint a baby
and i don't know what to do because you methods said
come across from the data value and return
and i haven't got an answer any more
there's lots of ways to solve problems the wrong way
i'm reminded independent television here where penn and teller a sort study a controversial topic
it's nuclear-power
hand they interview who who has also reasons for being anti-nuclear and they say we
believe in balance on our show so we give a chance to everybody you express
your code from the area now let's hear from look guys right
let's now
solve this inference problem using bayes theorem and there will be a unique answer
will be one answer to the problem and it will work in any case with
any case any metadata three data points three thousand data points
and you don't actually need to think
you get the right answer you don't need that she's been sizes you don't need to invent measures the goodness-of-fit
you don't need to invent interesting functions like the mean of the data
which in this case is a brilliant idea
but in other problems
you might struggle to think of the brilliant idea
with base you don't actually need to think that you need to know what you're doing
you get it right
but it is actually mechanical
it doesn't take years
get used to doing things the bayesian way
so how does it work
o has a list of other ideas that people like came come up with i think we've gone through them
often when i asked the question how would you solve this problem people say k i squared
and that's goes back to the beans story have counting the bin
and then measure the difference between the current and expected count using a single kai squared
so that's
we already have that's roughly in methods one and two
measures the error between the theory and data
look at the data mining
and see how the very lambda all pick some other quantity and see how that's very lambda
and okay so that's all the ideas
that are out there and i will do it using bayes theorem
so let's write down again what the probability of the data is
for a single data point
given lambda and assuming that there is one exponential
so the two of them are of the opinion of the euclidean norm
however because the one
so in the perceptron case i have identity
and the inverse of identity which
but if i increase the
the is that the change
so now it
it's interesting to ask what if i take p
what with things change
and i can improve different properties with respect to the property that proven for the
but that's not great
i want to be a little bit of machinery for the analysis
these properties of running experiments not just analytical tools to understand in their it's i
just need one two
the main goal would be in a special
data there
the gradient
integrating vector in the
all a
i don't know if a the vector is a vector from the vector valued function
from the product
the great
mapping vectors in vector
i'm a bit in a vector are are the vector
are the third and and
now i am getting coming and getting a gradient which is the vector of possibilities
they should get the support of s is really valued then begin about the great
the potential at the
that the this thing leaves in rd
these things need not be
so on computing the the the gradient vector of partial derivatives with respect to the
and then a mapping and this
so the gradient is an operator that maps vector are important factors of partial derivatives
in the the inverse mapping
it's me again from back one of the vector which is NOT to be
the gradient of the dual protection
believe me
it's it's it's a stand-up comics analysis nothing more than that i mean
but just use it in
you know in
algorithmic context so
it's very easy i want to just use theorem
so i'm going to expand i'm going to to look at the evolution of the
potential as
time goes by
so i'm looking at the evolution of these
which is
and let me writing gender breakdown potential which is something that
it's already analysis of perception but under the guise now
i'm thinking
OK there are human so that the expand this around these
i get inequality were i have the gradient
at RT minus one
are the mining are the main one with this is the vector in the product
and the last
of art a
that's right you know
i the minus of the minus one
and then let's write this is the passion magic
of phi
evaluate the certain point
are by our lives on the line between the art one
and and i have
but this is the last theorem four
the vector functional the defines function defined on vector
OK nothing nothing more than that
now i know something interesting
not that there is that there are here i can i can spot
i can stop and think about their work
provided i
at some unknown point that is in the line between the two point
in fact good now but but it's important that everything
so it's quality
now there's something interesting here is going on
so let's look at this the
so we would like to bound the guy this is again the caption also like
about the upper bound but let's look at this guy over there
what is the
this is
well that's right it
so we get something nicer so we get this is by definition
w minus one
i find it like that that be minus one
what is the difference between
up there
x the indicator function of
he had a different from white
so if a mistake was made this is the wrong
but this is the right
if a mistake was made and the
and this is the guy that made a mistake for this
thing is negative
o thing
so what you have to remember is the set
is the new of this guy that this guy
so that's all with this will be zero so i i get
excluding these
i get by recursively
the current i get
are you
is one of the liquid then y
at zero
which is the initial thing
the zero vector
the some of the second
let's take this
or the
what is the point that i'm getting back on this guy here and then getting
a lower bound on this guy in terms of the state
just like in the perceptron and then i get to prove mistake bound
four to professional now
second of the first bombings and something more
debate about the structure of the pension so
about the
one the second term
which for those who know is also bregman divergence
i need to all
i saw something about the potential so we do it for the real potential
i mean i want to do
the proof of bounding the second order
per minute there special because it's boring but just give the is that it's easy
when we choose one
intend to be seriously depended dimension dependent getting worse of course as dimension increases now
thissecondpoint may be less true of typical machine learning problems but certenatly in in statistic we're very
often modeling data almost as a as a one-off andwewe need
numerical methods that are easy to use on a new problem and don'trequire a lot
of a lot of you knowlife-timeexperimentationin exactly how to how tofit this
model and the last point is a little bit tongue in cheek I don't really
bel believe it but I think there is a bit of a fetish about supreme
precision in in computingwith data andI mean we're essentially modeling uncertainty in data we know
that the data we're usingthe numbers could've been different and
wear thatmathematical hats on I thinkI betterrestart this in thecoffee breakand without mathematical hats
onanything less than the best possible precision is something perhaps we don't really
want to contemplatebut we should remember that with the sophisticated numerical methods we've have
available now we may be computing inferences more accurately than the datareallysupport
okay typically in Bayesian statistics theseare themethods that have beenused over the years
I mean quadrature classicalmethods of the numerical integrationasimptothick methods that typically arise using
approximations based on theplus and so on andwhat really made a difference to the
usability of Bayesian inference is using simulation for computationsimulation where essentially we are
therefore at some level doing Monte Carlo integration but usually not explicitly setting out to
do an integral butbut doing asimulation calculation that effectively performs an integral for us
and you've seen you've seen four and a half hoursof that of thatbeing done earlier this week
and and now direct simulations using rejection samplingor oror or or whateverhas some
use but quite limited but what's really made a differenceto apply Bayesian statistics
is developerof theMCMC Markov Chain Monte Carlo I'll say very little more about that
something that would a lot of us hopped would be really useful and has been
kind of quite disappointingis the idea ofperfect simulation is that is that an area that's
made much impact in machine learning have you heard of itcoupling from the past that the that
it turns out there isa way of organizing the computations when you simulate a Markov Chain
so that the mark sothe realization itself effectivelydeclares when it reached equilibrium so it's
likea bit ofmagicthis happens after a random time random matter computation andthere was
a beautiful idea due to problem Wilson called coupling from the past which which set that
upit'slike a mixture of discrete mathematicsand algorithmsand probability very
nice paper and a lot of us were hoping that wouldyou know
letgive us a newI think a newgeneration of simulation methodsthat
will be usable in statistics this kind of been a bit disappointing and I think
that the thethe problem is thatperfect simulation methods turn out not to be easily
generated from the problem itself from the model and the datait has to besomethingwe
have to analyze an algorithm and therefore it doesn't fit in well with this kind
of one-off motive ofcomputing but I meanwell are two success storiesand it's realy reather a
nice idea that this completely solves the problem well at least it I say completely solves the
problem of knowing if you converged or notit it may still take a long time
to to get to that point and then more recentmore recent innovations in
in sampling technology forBayesian statisticsof courseinclude the particle filters that you've heard about yesterday and approximate Bayesian
computation whichwhich isa method or class of methods fordoing
Bayesian inference numerically using simulation where you can't write down the likelihood function algebraically but you can
only simulatefrom the corresponding model and then there's a huge area ofvariational inferencevariational
I put approximations in quotes there I'll say a word or twoin about amoment so just
very briefly on assimilation in generalthisare still as far as Bayesian statisticians
concern this arestill really the the the the main workholes of applied work and
with the obvious pluses and minuses that that that that you're aware ofthe fact
that the orderof therationship betweenthe amount ofcomputing you do in the
precision of your answer is effectively independent of dimensionis of coursefantasticthough a pretty invading in quotes
because of coursethere's a large multiplier that depends on dimension and really the total flexibility
of it isis isbeing fantasticit's realyliberatedstatisticians to to to to use
the models they think are appropriate not models for which there is a tractable numerical
methodI'vespent a little bitof time yesterday talking about loss functions and
you you you might be curious to to know howloss functions inter relate with
Bayesian computation in particular computation withwith sampling and this is potentially a little
bit of a problem because if you're doing if you're setting up an inference problem estimation hypothesis testing
or whatever it isif you aresetting it up by decision theory with a loss function then we seem
to want to optimize something as well as integrate and we we obviously don't want
to get into a positionof iteratively optimizing oversomething with that something is itself
alongnumerical computation but it turns out that some loss functions separat in a ratherconvenient
wayit essentially soolvesthis problem andyou you you you kind of know that such things must
be possible because we know we can compute the posterior expectation numerically by just averaging
a longer runokay sothat's clearly example of loss function based inference that doesn't involve
an iteration between optimization and integration and that the general and the general paradigm in
which that works is where the loss function seperateslike this into a sum
which in number of termsa function ofdecision times a function of
the parameter andwhen it has that property because of linearity ofexpectation and so on
the posterior expectation of the lossthen separates neatly and we essentially havean
average weighted averageof capitalR different sample averages from the run andI'll show you
one or twoexamples in thesecond talk today where that wherethatwhere that works
soi such situations you can separate the optimization from the from Monte Carlo simulation
rather neatly nowyou may be surprised thatI didn't mention anything about message passing
or oror such algorithms in my initial list of algorithms and butI'll just insert a
few comments about that that that the reason they're not mainstream in Bayesian statistics
and four
two two people don't like it
don't like now obviously can go further
to one battery life one of the
the rest of the same and do
i mean if you want to
two of visualization
you can do pass negative by budget departure
and today if you want to compare
different digital cameras
and then you know which one
trains so this is basically the possibility of a and a negative balance of each
individual attributes attributes
so this is actually
this model has been
as we actually actually actions somewhere you probably know simply don't know microsoft live search
have this can be
let's search this thing
if you go down to
so some products
the summary is here
we're talking about lexington based approach and we want to do
be better than that
the previous being has been done
so let's bayes approach essentially says
you are using
the opinion words
OK you are using the opinion words to detect
what a particular opinions also connected
so for example you can say
the battery life and picture quality are great but the view founder small so you
can see this
tell you something that something so i the lexicon lexicon based approach because obviously this
and what for you to express opinions
that was
this fact approach so what is what is basically the process of this approach is
very simple so say i'm just trying to identify
the words in the sentence which is
i have some opinions site
and they can somehow aggregate them as the aggregate them
so what are the positive neck towards the positive example beautiful wonderful amazing good amazing
the band were that things will be
in a lot of things and also idioms phrases
so this for obvious reasons very useful
so there's there's two ways of
getting this bunch works
OK good friends was no i don't have to do with this research is really
who said of this work
so the first approaches is dictionary based on you do
use one it
and they also can use the covers
so the problem the difficult problem is this
the opinion some of opinion words
context dependent
OK which means
depends on how the guys using
i was going to use it
for example something is along sometimes smaller short what i mean
the i
so the dictionary based approaches actually you get abundances you will do
romney around and the go to the warning
in one
so the advantage of course this approach is you can really get a lot
really get a lot
lots of them
their weaknesses
you can't use text in the text dependent opinions thanks
context dependent context dependent opinions
because one does not have the
so corpus based
again we use a set of keywords set of words start with
was something which is obviously have good opinions either positive or negative
and they have a big corpus do
so to some machine learning
OK tagging dimension and
so you need
so there's this approach is essential to help you define domain
in dependent domain dependent
so what we see that domain dependent is not actually good enough
not good enough
before talk about that so what is the rule people normally use
OK what do and use so this a bunch of rules was
so the proposed nineteen ninety seven
so what that hammond was studying adjectives what kind of additives policy will converge to
the negative
so this is called conjunction is very interesting
so the car is beautiful and spacious
for example this this and this and if we know something if we not beautiful
is positive
we're pretty sure spacious positive two
it's a conjunction you don't say
the guys beautiful and that
so these issues to see
see so essentially is using this type of thing
and using this is overseas and then you keep going green
now obviously you can sort of doing something
to this title things as well
can then you should learning and do prediction
so similar ideas we used by
about this thing about this
so our approach
we also try to explain the connection collectivity connected connectives can respond connect
and however we see the context is not to me
context is not longer the main
so the contexts you're going to say
it's going to be the feature and the dolphin
for the same in the same domain the battery life is lion takes long time
to focus not to see
pretty different ways possible negative and also tried extended this
two pseudo and inter standards
and again and also we don't need to be called
we basically accumulating slowly
so interest and this
basically internal is which is essentially the same rules as other people are using however
we not just
focus and great we also talk about the features
essentially we we want books the book
and then what battery life when not just talking about along with
recorded books
recall the feature and the
and the long
so this is why this working because obviously
since then no money you have the same
they can also stretches further
and they say
this camera has a long battery life which is great it doesn't have to be
it doesn't have to be and
again you have to have
post opinion words and the
and the the future
so again this is a
idea of the same senders should have same opinion but not always true knowledge
and also
another thing you can go into an interest in
in this and this how also do something like that
temporal resolution images typically measured thousand hertz or ten thousand hertz even
but from ri is this is very slow
same value
twice the second or if you have very fast once the second that's that's very
very fine
there is a diff distinction between
in fact
OK to pay between dependent BCI as an independent ones
so i said in my definition i want to be independent from peripheral nerves and
brain signals so in fact
i will be talking all the time about about independent BCCI's but
there are also people that use additional the eye movement and and things like that
as i said before if you want to the rehabilitation this is it might be
very good good idea
the way to
it evokes some brain signals saying your brain
if i can do that by for example handwaving some visual evoked activity of by
some whistling so there was acoustically evoked potentials
and so
requires some
particular stimuli
and the set of
and the ideal way of communicating as i
i think it is
is that
we can
have something independent of some external trigger or external pacemaker or something like that
you notice that i'm trying to
to push everybody on the side of the way in this
so called operant conditioning
and the detection of mental states so what does that operant conditioning me conditioning means
that year
talk to your learning in long sessions to control your brain signals such that
signal processing can
you can read out your intentions
condition to do that
and and on the side you would have some particular brain states that you
we have anyway
for example think about
subtracting some numbers are
rotating in geometric object so why you think about this going from the labor to
your home
so that different brain areas that are responsible for the this or
think about moving your left hand right hand
well your foot
so these are all mental states that
your brain will follow
the point is to detect them properly
and there might be no
big learning involved in the
but i
discuss that later
so there's a lot of people recently two BCI i think when
when i got interested in this
there were
almost a thousand groups in the world to have been pursuing this
on the
maybe more non invasive side
just store
through some names that you trawl genetically list and i will talk about their work
and then some
pioneers in this on this noninvasive side to be bomb into being
the beckman institute
and john will paul
all any
and get for cello in ghana
but lots of other people started to get interested also some in this room
in BCI because
it it's something very concrete so if you're interested in computational neuroscience
BCI i actually gives you
tool quite unique tool in your hands
test type of is in real time
men with
can talk about
it later
is it will allow us
to find the optimal parameters theta one and theta two
in some inference scheme
running convex of
number answer to explain to you why convexity is really really great
why this is really the quantity that you want to have for inference
and you know why what i'm doing some setting everything up
two things to convex overrated
because well convex always nicely nice to use they have nice convergence guarantees and all
that they don't get stuck in local minima by construction all that
who does not know
that a convex function so who knows that are convex function has only one global
who would know how to prove it
not many of you brought the show to the
OK let me we could all the picture books quite the useful piece of intuition
so first of all
a convex function
the function and that may not be just in one dimension but in several dimensions
where if i think two points
and it's craft
metro line
then all the function values underneath the line like
and that none of the points
underneath this line on the graph can be found about the line so that the
i wouldn't be a convex function
how to prove that there is only one local and one global minimum
well let's assume
but i have to look at
so this point
not quite
then by convexity i know
the function values between the those
o points if i just make the line
it will be less equal than those two values
now either those two values are the same
then well this must all be one global minimum so i get the function it
looks like a troll
if one of them is like this
it was quite obviously i can go from here to there
for the sake of the argument
and i have decreased my for my function values get the contradiction
this also works out this reasoning in more than one dimension
that's one of the
reasons why we all like convexity so much
the entire courses that you can teach and convex analysis so wonderful book by rockefeller
convex analysis
i mean basic it's really a treasure trove of a lot of optimisation
the station
so what i'm going to try some sampling is going to try
and find the optimal parameters theta one and theta two
as i might want to infer
the probability
that i'm seeing here it's weird tales
so therefore
at some point
i will need to optimize over those parameters theta one and theta
so one of the expressions that we might want to optimize
it is the negative log likelihood of the negative log posterior
so in this case it would take the negative log
of that well let's go up here
we're basically jumping a few slides and the negative log of p of fixed parameters
by theta within the g theta
minus some linear function theta
now that the overall expression is convex
and so it turns out that they can do things quite easily
i will be going through the specific equations in a few slides so don't worry
but that's the main reason for very question after got and so why doing something
that says that this is the main reason why convex is really really handy here
and we look at the maximum likelihood maximum history estimators
OK good so
it's looking example of binomial distribution
it doesn't look
a great deal well that's just one point four point six probabilities
now let's
when we start with the
a second
so there are various ways of chopping up the field of statistics and
typical way at least within frequencies frequentist statistics is to treat statistical tests
on one hand and in parameter estimation on the other and so that's the way
i've done it
so that's what we're going to talk about say what i mean by that and
then there are two very important methods the method of maximum likelihood and the method
of least squares
and there's something related to that which is called interval estimation and you probably see
that in the context of setting limits set limits on the higgs mass or limits
on various parameters
so first of all let me say what i specifically what i mean by a
parameter estimation
the parameters of of the pdf
are constants that characterize its shape
the parameters of
hypothesis of those numerical values that characterize that hypothesis
so very often we been using this notation
i have some pdf for a random variable x and the narrator sort of semicolon
and then it's characterized by some parameters
and they appear over here is greek letters
that's the probability law and then you have some sample of observed values say perhaps
values x that are sampled from this PDF and you want to find some function
of those measured values that can be used to
estimate the value of this parameter
i suppose that you only know the functional form of this problem probability law
but the numerical value of the parameter is not yet known so what we want
to do is we want to construct some function of the data to estimate the
parameter so once they found such a function what i do is i write it
with the hat
all right so theta had is the estimator for the parameter theta
as you probably noticed physicists are not that good always distinguishing between a function thought
of as a mapping and the value of the function so mathematicians are much better
that so if i want to insist on the distinction also estimator for the
actual function and then estimate for the value of the function
evaluated with a specific set usually from context it's clear what what i'm talking about
the function of a random variable is itself a random variable so therefore an estimator
is the random variable because it is function of the data
so therefore if i were to repeat the entire measurement many times and to evaluate
the estimator with the data from each measurement i can make a histogram of those
and it would have some shape so i could i could envisage looking at the
the pdf of data had
and that will depend in general on the true and unknown value data
but it will it will follow some pdf
different functions used as estimators will lead to different pdf and i can ask what
would be a good estimator what would be a bad estimator
clearly if the true value of the parameter is here
but if the PDF the estimator was shifted over to one side that would not
be good
that would be an example of a biased estimator
you can define in fact the bias of an estimator is the expectation value of
the estimator minus the true value
and so you would prefer to construct a function that has zero or very small
bias a bias in the sense is the type of systematic error
so the the green curve here for example that has an expectation value which is
equal to the
true value
it is more or less from the picture that's what i can tell and so
that we have a zero bias but still that's quite broad distribution i would prefer
that when i repeat the measurement that i get only a small scatter of values
so of the PDF of my estimator were characterised by the blue curve that would
be even better so you want a small variance or standard deviation
of the pdf
that corresponds to the statistical error
of your estimate the statistical error of your measurement
actually having a small bias or zero bias and small variance can very often those
are conflicting criteria you can have
the best of both worlds
it is what you can do is there's a broad class of estimators that have
very small bias or almost zero bias amongst those you can choose the ones that
have the smallest possible variants
but the point i want to make is that there is no golden rule for
writing down the right estimator estimators are characterized by certain properties such as the robot
bias and variance and you simply choose an estimator which has the desired properties optimal
properties so there are a few additional properties such as robustness and efficiency and a
few other things but there is no golden rule for writing down an estimator you
choose the estimated that has the desired properties
so what i want to do now
this just to write down formulas for a couple of obvious estimators and to work
out the bias and variance
so suppose the parameter in question is the expectation value of x so i've used
here the greek letter mu to denote the expectation value of some random variable x
in this case there's an obvious estimator for because recall the expectation value is what
you would get for the average of the random variable
if you repeated the observation
an infinite number of times
well i don't have an infinite number of observations i have
a finite data sample with a certain number of n observations
but still it's pretty obvious that
the arithmetic average of those observations that seems like a natural estimator
the expectation value
and so
that such an important estimated that we have a special name that's called the sample
mean and sometimes that's written with the bar instead of instead of the hat but
that is simply an estimator
for the for the media
so once you've specified that function of the data you can work out the bias
by computing the expectation value of this function and it's easy to show
the bias is identically zero
and furthermore you can work out the variance of mu had and it's easy to
let's assume
you doing breast cancer study
and new training set
it's got a lot of women with breast cancer
and it's probably heavily biased towards sequence
maybe not quite uniformly drawn from the entire
set of breast cancer
this maybe this is a specific hospital and women only go there if they have
a really serious cases
but then you want to actually is on a case that works in reality
you want to deploy it
and then what you get
the normal distribution of women coming in to see the doctor actually they're probably less
than likely to have breast cancer because they have probably already been screened many many
times before
it's very hard to model the distributions
i mean you would have to make a fairly good assumptions on the psychology of
women and on whatever the doctors who designed the clinical study in the first place
in order to really find a good reweighting scheme
now there are trying to do an exact model is hopeless
you can actually try to infer it
well all the data that you get
and this
is what's called covariate shift the sample bias correction
now thing that you could do is feature selection
so feature selection
in that case it would let's say i've got
data set of apples dataset for and
pictures of them
in this case might not necessarily want to answer the question are they really different
entities well short of course they are i mean that's what i've just mentioned but
you might want to answer the question well which features the doctors should they keep
in order to keep the data as different as possible
to feature selection
if you want to have a very meaningful features to discriminate the two sit
in that case
you would like to have criteria that you can maximize
as you
at features or as you remove them
and and obviously the end of the day
if you have a two sample test it works well
you can also turn into one sample taste
in other words around the selection
for instance let's say some engineer
or computer scientist has written a program and has a whole bunch of not
it spits out data
as some for some sort of stimulating he told you what he really believes that
this is a good simulator
and all these really willing to do is tell you i look it looks almost
like the real thing you just need to fiddle with those knobs and a little
bit about the world
and of course you don't quite trust him so well but you would like to
find an automatic way of tuning does not
OK so how can you do that
and we've got some real data
it's call it x
and that that is expensive
so we only have enough them
this black box if you engineer friend gave you
can produce an opportune umber of
so what you can now do is you can say well i want to tune
the not on the this
generating distribution for the y
such states as close as possible to x
as a matter of fact this is exactly what we've been doing yesterday
we had the sufficient statistics
we compute that x
then we have the natural parameters theta
if we treat it until
the expectation
for that distribution
i was this close as possible to the extinct
nothing really new
so just that this is now a little bit more general
so any question on the concepts at the moment
now to the math
well let me first show you
you would do that
in indirect way
well you could go
and estimate the density speed think you had
and then compute some distance between p had think q had
and that simple density estimator that
you might want to use
before you do anything fancy
this one's called the parzen window density estimator
who has heard of possible windows before
so this is probably the single most useful density estimator that you will ever hear
it works as follows
let's say
i've got some dots
lambertian distribution would look like this
now i give everybody would agree that this is a bad idea for modelling the
overall density
probably much better idea for modeling densities to smooth soul this out
they need to put some muscle bumpier hospital but there
same one here there
then just to add all this up
so it so that
we get this function here
something like that not quite true but
now this black curve would look much closer to
a real density estimate
the red line
the parzen windows similar does exactly that
so how do we do that
we have some
kernel function here
from the past windows system and this is not the same kernel function is what
john deep into been talking about
and that's a depends on the position
t minus
and maybe there's some scale
OK i'm going to ignore scale at the moment
so this just
we place upon
at location x
and then
so for instance this could be just the simple garcia
obviously what we want is that this thing
if we integrate it
OK of t minus six
equals one
and then what we do is
just estimate p had
of t
one of in
the sum of all terms
so far arriving going from one
of t
minus x i
that's it
these are the reasons why you might want to do observational studies sorry that's not
clear the lego
so even though observational study last second best there's often no alternative was start with
nevertheless we have to realize their second best work very hard
to ensure they have first of all the highest quality and and then to understand
what we can learn from them and
so the other thing to say is that there is no necessary components is necessary
connection between how system behaves when you kick it and how it behaves when you
just want to know about the room bumping into things
one of the big issues of statistical causality is how do we make the link
what kind of things can we reasonably making how can we use them between these
different kinds of regimes different kinds of behaviour
so that's the thing about the problems again with observational studies you often observing associated
but it's not really causal spurious in some sense so
i will give some examples of these reverse causation where you really know which way
the effect is going so
there's one night example about this which is the effective
parents behavior on that children becoming psychotic
but if you sort of just observe parents pay their children's behavior without it's perfectly
possible that site having a psychotic child is likely to affect the parents by a
rather serious way so which weighs about causality going simple observation and study we find
it hard to untangle that regression to the mean is a very important example because
a lot of
so a lot of fuss about two dozen installation of traffic cameras accident hotspots
actually reduce
typically i'm sure so many familiar with the idea of an accident hotspot has had
a lot of accidents for combination of two reasons one is possibly it's actually an
unsafe and anyway
but also
there the random variation and if you pick out those which have particularly high
accidents then the ones where the random fluctuation has been positive rather than negative and
so the next time you look
that random fluctuation part would have gone away
and you're likely to have the decrease and you're likely to see that decrease even
if you don't sprinkled holy water on the spot rather than installed traffic at
so that is not a very good comparison
and all sorts of problems which are generically called confounding with these relationships with other
variables which have not been properly taken into account there's so
there is a common cause well i will come on these moments of some examples
here's an example of what's called complete confounding
so this is to say if you what you want to discover which of two
petrol gives you better fuel economy
right you use both in some sort of but if you always say OK so
the idea is that a fellow use to try checking is fuel consumption using BP
to drive from london to leeds and nodes are still to go from london to
leeds and BP to go back and he always found that BP was giving better
fuel economy but possibly because he was driving up you one way
downhill the other
so that is completely confounding with something which is of no particular interest mainly the
height hyperlinks above london
is if you could randomise maybe and sometimes you should sometimes BP in either direction
then you can make a fair comparison
some important epidemiological studies which have been completely overthrown
by experimental studies so
for a long time it was thought that was an enormously positive affect women take
hormone replacement therapy after the menopause tremendously positive over the reduction in coronary heart disease
and then
eventually managed to
do proper clinical trial and in fact found exactly the opposite
these treatments actually seem to raise the
coronary heart disease by quite a lot
why is this is probably because the kind of in the observation and study is
a middle-class fairly healthy women who are motivated to take
they're the ones who probably have less incidence of the disease anyway
and so you are not comparing like with like the ones you didn't take it
was just a different kind of woman with different health outcomes anyway even if you
have made any difference to the tree
i think it was a lot of fuss about the the beneficial
effects of antioxidants
to reduce the risk of disease a lot of observational evidence so that was the
case with exactly the same story really
when proper studies were done
it was shown that in fact these are bad for you
and again there was confounding almost certainly confounding with general health status of type of
women who supplement and went to health food shops and things like that and the
time womanhood
similar sort of story with what's called a calcium channel blocker
now if it
that being or whatever
and again the same story show that actually although it seemed to increase the risk
and the simple reason for this for the observation of finding which is called confounding
by indication that gave this drug
two people with hypertension
what is for
and people with hypertension do tend to develop
my comment function rather more than those so even it was helping them it wasn't
happening enough
two to overcome the difference and
and this a problem because these studies these are cases in which it was one
of them will eventually to do studies but they were incredibly expensive incredibly complex incredibly
difficult to actually put into effect and took a long time and
and often we we simply can't we can't do
we have to rely on observational data but how can we
have we believe the message that the story can we analyse the data in ways
which will somehow bring out the more believable message
over time example from you may have heard of simpson's paradox
so this is a simple
so i example in which we comparing two drugs in hospitals for some nasty disease
which is quite a lot of people die
the standard drug
i was given to four hundred patients and forty percent of them
they're not very good but that's what was
and the the new drug out we're testing that
by this comparative trials that cells are given to four hundred patients fifty percent so
it looks like a clear ten percentage points advantage
the new drug over that could get out of the market
now exactly the same data would now broken down by the sex of the patient
so these are the men results these are the women adam up and show that
to the stable of top hundred ninety twenty OK
will the man
their cover right on the standard drug was seventy percent but i is gone down
to sixty percent of the new that doesn't very promising for sale
so surely the women must be counteracted but now
of the standard drug they were having a thirty percent survival rate idea that's going
down to twenty percent within the new drugs so is the case where if you
want to your doctor prescribing this drug
somebody water into your surgery with appropriate disease if you knew it was the man
you state above had the standard treatment of you know the woman what you say
the site but if it was somebody of indeterminate sex
because the coefficient here that is just zero
but is mu is just a tiny bit smaller than eleven
ten point nine or something like that
eleven minus ten point nine is
zero point one
end that's a positive number and then all the sudden this becomes no longer be optimal
dictionary and we have to do with it
and so it suggests a net would be the only
problem with this dictionary and so i suggest if we
do appear that money
x to be the entering variable
and figure out
with the leaving variable should be associated with it
and we do that's in the same way we saw thinking really has a value
equal to eleven or epsilon minus eleven but
it's not just thinking is a
this is eleven plus five sixteen a three
this is one plus fours fifteen iterative
three this is all of eleven plus six seventeen iterated three
this one is the one that has zero first and so w two
will be
leaving variable and we can do a pivot
so that's what i guess i said on this slide i didn't show you
okay stupid
well i also did this
how to figure out
which variables leaving variables w two leaves
and we can do that
and here is the
new dictionary
we can write down the new inequalities maybe again it's likely
useful to do them math the board here
how does this work
we want
minus fourteen
less than or equal to zero
it's not so easy
we want
three and two thirds
plus one third new
to be
less than or equal to zero
we want
to be less than or equal to zero
we want one
to be greater than or equal to zero
we won't four-thirds plus one third mu
be greater are
we want to
to be critical zero
and we want minus four hour
plus nudity graphical user
okay this one sort of automatic and this one sort automatic and this one sort of absent at one
this one's automatic
the inequality here says that new
is less than or equal to
o to one mistake here
i lost a minus sign thank you good
so we bring the three into thursday eleven-thirds
we multiply by three one you'd less than or equal to eleven
and here we want new to being greater than or equal to two
and here bring up to the side
our community greater equal to minus four r
for bringing
forty deciding new
to be greater than or equal to the fore
and now again if i plot this on
why new axis here
i have new lester equal to eleven
i so everything this way
i new great article that to
everything to the right at
those things are over new graphical minus far
i have new greater equal to
plus four r which so here
and intersection all these intervals
is this interval here
from fore
it's interesting
the previous intervals
was everything bigger than one
you begin eleven
not only has to be smaller than eleven
the bigger than four
and by the way it's useful to see what this eleven can comes from here
it comes from
that's second inequality wrote down which corresponds to the second column
that's the column like they use they have new greater than eleven before i did
the pivot so before i did that
that's same
give me the constraint that news go i did the pivot that's inverted the inequality
and now new is less than or equal to eleven
by doing my that correctly
by doing illegal pivot
legal primal
i preserves the property that for m u
tiny bit less and less than ten point nine
i preserves the property
that this is
as a legitimate
dictionary infected the pivot affects one thing at ten point nine
and so for me large enough close enough to eleven this should still be optimal
in fact equal to eleven this must still be optimal if i do the pivot
and i did
eight bits here
and i did not commit to a zero or one but i'm going to draw
this this is an zero one is the fraction of those in need right in
the middle east row here so i have to learn a little box around each
one of them
in this binary search way
OK and i was big exploited picture of what
well draw several times to represent a single byte in memory now the most interesting
thing to take take away from this drawing is that this little box here can
adopt one of two values independently of whatever value this box choose to adopt that
centre in factor eight independent choices free tibet assuming it makes sense to everybody came
that means that this as a group in a bunch of memory with it's a
bit like an independently taken zeros and ones
can distinguish between two vehicles for two hundred fifty six different values OK and that's
why they asked the table is as big as it is
sixty five to sixty five was twenty five represents
the alphabet forget where lower starts but every single character that the screen or printing
to a file is backed by some number i know you know that
when you look in memory to see how the capital a is represented you would
actually see
o one right there i'm sorry of africa was actually a one right there in
one right there are drawn to explain why that's the case
because capital is backed by the number sixty five we don't put things down and
s pole in memory we put them down in base two OK because that's what
that's the easy thing to represent in a bit oriented system
OK that makes it to people
OK so if i say the capitalized
is it sixty five to stop thinking about sixty five you have to think about
some some of perfect powers of two
so it isn't
sixty four nine thousand sixty five other it's actually sixty four plus one
is to the zeroth
two is to the the first there's none of that forest to the second is
to the third sixteen
it's for thirty two is five sixty four sixty is is actually to to six
plus two zero
make sense
as far as the representation in a box like this if you went down and
actually examined all the transistors OK the eight are laid side-by-side in a single character
but by the memory it would look like that
and in order to recover the the actual desk equivalent you really do do
you really do the the power series expansion
we say contribution of two to six because it's in the six
counting from zero from the right and the six position from from the end of
the by
this contributes
two this you can look at the location as having contributions of two the first
into the thirty seventh that are weighted by zero as opposed to one
OK that makes it to people
OK so that's good enough for characters
graduates two shorts
so people are very clever and when the shorter times that if you know store
lots of numbers and there are going to be small go with an array of
short for an hour or vector shorts knowing that they really will be some memory
savings later on
the short being two bytes just means the two neighbouring bytes in memory would be
laid down
those two bytes at the moment would be laid down and the two to the
sixteen different patterns that are available to be placed in that space
in this you can distinguish between
two the sixteen different values
that makes sense to people
so i'll just make this
put lots of zeros over here one right there
but many
and this is the wide
so as far as the number
that represents i should emphasise the technically
you can map that pattern to any number you want to as long as you
do it consistently but you want to make the computer hardware easy to interpret
this place right here means that there a contribution to the zero or one is
the convolution of two first contribution to the second so there is a two and
a four to be added together to the zero to the seventh to the eighth
to the night
OK so there actually is a contribution to the night
which is five hundred twelve
this really is the number that represented by this thing it would be
five twelve five sixteen five eighteen five nineteen we have that bit pattern down
OK that makes sense to people
if i have
another one
but some of their
i have one zero followed by all ones
and all one
i know
that if this had been a one right there then there would be no contribution
of two to fifteen
that makes it to people
zero followed by all ones
in in binary is like
zero being followed by all nines in some sense into small it's one less than
some perfect number that has a lot of zeros at the end
OK that makes sense but they about you have a binary o dominant on your
car and you want to take a mile off
OK because you're at
let's say one followed by fifteen zeros if you back it up you expect all
these to be demoted not to nine spata one
as far as the representation is concerned it's one less the two to fifteen
make sense
and that number is
two the fifteen minus one
which are not going to figure out what it is that we get the just
what's going on here
OK so that's enough there's
there is a little bit more to be said about this page right here
if i wanted to represent
the numbers zero to to the sixteen minus one i could do that OK that's
two sixty different values
i don't want to say the negative numbers are as common as positive numbers but
they're not so uncommon that we don't have a contribution
of the of the mapping to include negative numbers
so what usually happens is that this bit right there
has nothing to do with magnitude it's all about sign whether or not you want
zero there because it's positive or one for negative and that's usually what zero one
min when inside signed
make sense
OK so if i write down the this
and i have let's say four zeros followed by zero one one one that's seven
if i put all zeros there
this picture is the simple the this works fine
even if you're inserting
the same key over over
that seems good one thing we should clearly do
is inserted
into the bottomless
we now know where that
it should go
because we want to maintain this invariant the bottom list contains all the elements
so there we go to maintain the environment
this contains only on so
we search for seventy five percent seventy five goes here we just link in seventy
five you know how to do it close to home
so here is that pointer
that's all work on implementing skip list is the linked list manipulation
so i don't know
so the fine for now
because now there is only of a chain of length three here that have to
walk over here looking for something in this range
but if i just keep inserting o seventy five seventy six to seventy six percent
one six poster and so on and so on this pack all the elements and
here this channel a really long now suddenly things are not so balance applied research
or pay
an arbitrarily
long amount of time here to search for someone
things will take k time on sticks taylor again
only certain log analysts had OK for now
what i wanna do
is decide which of these lists contain seventy five
so clearly goes on the bottom every element because in the body should go up
a level
depends not clear yet my answer if you edited by some months ago in the
next level
so the goal and the
two levels of
maybe but even less likely
what should i do you
right so you maintain the ideal partition size which may be like the length of
the string
and you see well gets too long
and i should i should put in the middle promote the guy up to the
next level
and do the same thing up here this change it's too long between two consecutive
next level express stops
o promote the middle guy
and that's what you'll do
your problems
that's too fancy for me
know i mean i stinking counters
what else can i do
i try to maintain the ideal
skip was structure that will be too expensive because they will seventy five now is
the only gets promoted this guy gets
most all the way down and without propagate everything to the right and that that
could cost linear time of day
the idea
i one half the i could flip a coin
good idea
i for that
i'll give you a quarter
o thing is the color it's a good one
it's a
the old line state maryland
you have to perform services for that corner
namely for the coin can you for the coin
what you get
tales OK
first round
we're going to do is build skip list
maybe i should tell you our first came but the idea is to flip the
its hands so sorry if it has we will
promoted to the next level and again
so this is an answer to the question which
the other lists
optimisation problem so that will allow you to reconstruct x o
so this is the restricted isometry property
which is basically puts constraints on on the matrix here i used unfortunately different symbol
terror but replaced that of its feet are so if
this our IP
property exists which basically
say is in the third row all subsets of k columns are are nearly orthogonal
then one can use many algorithms for recovery indefinitely
there's one algorithm in particular which is known as the basis pursuit algorithm
which allows you to find the sparsest solutions now
this but then we have to know which of these metrices feasible have this IP
property OK so people have figured out for example of the components of the matrix
are made of random gaussians are how to mark and so on
we can have no construct this recovery algorithm in course
in practice there is no computationally elegant way to really check this property now
this IP property is is being interpreted in many different ways that is the argument
that people make about
incoherence between the basis vectors and this sparse signals and also something on honest phase
transition diagrams basically there's
when there is not a one
o thing cold and when it doesn't hold the
phase transition diagram is basically a car that separates these two domains and
i i p p is a very general property
you can hear if you see
i the
they are a key property has been defined using the l two norm can always
replace can also replace the l one norm and so forth and there is a
nice paper probably referred to later
which looks into ordinary be general enough lowercase p property so if you replace the
l two norm one then you can call it this one OK in english information
sharing kind of the problem the point actually shows up so this is relevant to
right so
the defeat what he can be has been looked at from the late seventies and
eighties and so forth and you will see now in the bottom of all my
view whereas i always mentioned with the slides come from because i sign
that give my permission for this lecture to be no videotape and it's going to
be on the head and that and so on and so i borrowed some of
the slides from
doctor j y so
i made sure that
is given proper credit for that so you will see these running acknowledgements or my
talk now
find how many such measurements tuning right again this is something that's been done here
is given
and one of the things you will see in the literature in terms of recovery
is always talk about high probability of reconstructions of the mathematical details are kind of
involved so i won't go into them to but for our purposes we can assume
that if you have this many compressive measurements and he has this property then you
can go through one optimisation approach for getting the original signal the the reason this
is kind of difficult thing for us to accept right away
is that when you take statistical
courses on estimation theory and so on
there are store collectlon of data about data we are wasting more data is useful
course even though we know that the signals that looking at spas
we always like to have more data and a very traditional
estimation problem the variance of the estimate goes down with the number of samples simple
scale and location estimation and so forth so
being able to just take the right number of measurements and recover noise is going
to take some getting used to now
the prime recovery problem is this given the so-called compressive measurements y now how do
you get
that's where the thing is going to be progress is right people who design
sensors to directly get y
are the ones who are going to be
more known
there will be more famous
in again the gradient cameras is an example of the caught aperture cameras that nineteen
years more building is some of the examples because with our current cameras that we
have always getting x
OK so but you need to have this
devices that give you why and then you should be able to get your ex
that's where the the
the core of the
you know the field is OK system but let's assume somebody gave us this why
and how it so how do you get your x scores you can try true
and it's not very useful here and you can try not
but then and not in l one they are a key property gives you the
sequence for so you will have framed the problem
as one of finding the reason why not is