so this is very rare
the computer
OK if i was really and coffee and to get a job to trying to
do this
i don't want to model this model is factorizations are distribution here to this
specify what is
one sometimes makes you parents of all this
as and with is is the sum over x two four x the size of
the right side over x two x one x five here right here parameters
he is this
OK that's door to
it's right star
how can you say work
you can say word by saying
this term some exciting
these you depending on the size of the question is all the way
in the here
and now i'm just going to do this calculation first
compute this five whatever i get all stored in some interval research and
push this
although it here and this intermediate is an assignment on each one of these much
were back from and i nineteen eighty
so if you look at the slide and is not totally clear we see something
if you see this history
the problem is going be be this treaty
these are unclear on this
this is just the distributed
that's the idea
we exploit the factorisation of the joint distribution to save
four by doing intermediate solutions in this
this is a very good and you could always just write down the equations
you have one
four about how you're going to see how do it you can solve inference problem
by writing down the distribution
rearranging solutions for in writing computer but what you don't know what we're going to
be for the future
so please consider
so i can just tell you anything about it
o model was anything else is query and still
well all
OK so computer
only has to answer query
observing x six
one could do
right wrong once but it has to be able to answer any queries like the
computer program inside the actors so that's what we're doing
just as bad before i remember the
general different problem involves
all special cases of all the things that want do one
so you know this then you can just
it's so you have very complicated distribution you want know
the marginal probability is known as the distribution is inference
with no opposition and with that query
this is something that all
so i don't know
parents you can read the article directly
graph of were
and in my direction model you can ignore all the the nodes that are downstream
from the query
so long as no
they're just marginalize on only are graph before so that we have to see
and then
also directed models you know
service must evaluate one because the conditional probabilities so so this distribution px x four
x two
when the sun x four i know one because the conditional solution rather than asking
my computer is
one just right is coded says if there's some conditional distribution over the first
that's one
so this
but before we can write a general
inference for directed graphs we need to know is the first few call explaining away
it uses correlation to me
the inverse problems
so remember we're trying to figure out which ones are coupled based on some sort
you might think could work at this size
the graph because the explaining away nodes
controlled by
observations which were originally
the graph so in order to
here is we
the g
some of the more
i first compute things coming from the
and i come from here
if i want to compute not query for x in minus one
four exactly the same argument i need to multiply these
message by the message that's coming from there to here
but only these message and i haven't computed these methods compute x
so what we do is
if i want to compute every query the p of every xn
what's a smart way to do do it
well i just compute all the messages
then whenever i have to compute p of xn
i just checked
which are the messages that they need to want
so in order to compute a single p of x
i have one cost
in article in order to have access to compute all p of xn
it's just twice the course
because i just need to compute all the message
and then they can query
it's called belief propagation these immediately translates to
because actually the three quite is
well you why only that the reason why the change here
it is because at some point this thing and
and then you can start to compute it
because from the perspective of the elimination of with them
what's really happening is that you're always something
on the leaf nodes
and then you eliminate that leaves
you can imagine that you were actually only some leaves just your
three string
every possible some that you do you do only you don't know anything unless we
choose the elimination order that comes from the leaves
these were eliminated by definition the next one will be only already OK
and then you keep on going
that's why you need
a change or three according to general case
i was
no they don't agree they don't
what is important to understand is that we have two steps
one step one step is exactly what you said we need to start from the
and propagate
these messages and next master will depend on christmas
and back
then you have compiled the entire set of mass
then it's just the query
what's p of x and just multiplying incoming message
that's school we completely correct so
at compile time basically you need to run this protocol starting from the leaf
propagate everything and then propagate that
you can start for example next one xn propagate xn then propagate back to x
one xn
we can
into this choose new route three
so this called belief propagation
it's really nothing more
what's more again
bars requirements OK so let's study the storage requirements here
well basically authorities limited to small tables you think think that table that these functions
are just
you have
a function which is
for example a real valued function of some discrete five
so you have some state space here
let's call
the size of these
is as for example or state space
obviously you need to explore
s square numbers
for these
quantities here
for every one of these quantities
you have in mind is one of them
because you have
n minus one
in the tree
so the complexity of supporting all these things is in one of times
and square
is because it's the three
what you see before we finish today is a generalisation of these are
for arbitrary graphs
that square can become cubic
and so on
it is a combination
for example one ratio
it's a
so all
one of these
that's something like that
the the we really
repeated computations here is by
is by writing the right political
so you just run the right protocol
and so that the query time
you just do very simple query
let's proceed because there's throughout
so basically that's what i just said
so the computational complexity we have
we have two times in messages to be computed
because you have in mind of the mass in one direction and minus one messages
in the other direction
and also obviously you can
if you just defining trivial messages from the leaves
as one
then you can write the general equation
the the more nice way
really help to run the of
but that's just in the official journal is just short
and you can run belief propagation in the tree as well is exactly the same
is just that
whenever u
come whenever you have an incoming message
you need to to take the product
of all incoming messages in order to send the next message
so what happened
message passing equation so the message that you sent from j
talked about the process basics and we've seen how to can be used in regression
so now
i wanna go slightly beyond slightly beyond the basics
so i this is one thing this is one thing that i want to say
but during during the break
is there for more details on this this is a book that was written by by
by carl chris williams
gas processes for machine learning and a lot of what we've talked about so far
and it's just it's just within the first five chapters so this is this is
available online
and in any more details that you want a lot stuff we talked about should be should be found here
okay so what's so what's next we've looked at the basics now let's revisit the
model and see what can be what we can mess around with
and so
i want to use that's it
in a very specific way states to see what we can mess around with because i wanna talk about why
normally when we present what's next and guassian processes we talk about gas prices for
classification we talk about different kernels
and it's and it's it's not always clear why why we're doing at and so on
so when we talk about is we developed this nice model
and we see how it can be used for regression
but now we start to pick different pieces of this we can see how it
can be used for some different problems are reduced in different markets and different modeling
okay so the first thing we might wanna mess around with in this model is
very high is the model hyperparameters
right what is that's model selection that's what we just talked about so there is one option
the second option
is we can mess around with the functional form of care for
this kernel choice here
we said that this is a canonical kernel choice squared exponential but there are plenty
of others and we'll talk about those
just now
another thing we might wanna mess with this the cheapy itself the cheapy prior
we're not going to talk about that here today
because we're trying to talk about calcium processes but what should be aware that you
can imagine having switching calcium processes or some other comp some other complicated system here
than than just the basic cheapy
and the fourth
is the data distribution itself so what the data we receive
what the data that we measure is not these nice continuous real valued variables but
something different like a class label or something like this well then we can still
use the same dupuy context we just have to change the likelihood function
and we and we'll talk about that's something that some of the problems that there is a likelihood choices
okay so let's start with kernel choices
we talked about how the guassian process gives us this nice probability distribution over functions
what the kernel is doing is it's helping us determine what kind of what kind
of functions that we get from there
there is this this this prior what sort of what type of functions we were
drawing out this so the squared exponential kernel
is the canonical kernel fore trying smooth
dry smooth functions functions from a cheap e
it's infinitely differentiable and we've seen these four draws ad nauseam at this point
so another kernel that we might use is the rational quadratic
i put this up here to show that that this is just the different this
is just the different functional form that will give us some
another interesting draws from a
it's actually
i don't don't worry about this too much but you see this term here is a squared exponential
and in fact
what this rational quadratic is actually
of gamma weighted
length scales so that the z here is is a gamma distribution over z
hands this is
this will be one one over the length scale
in these in this in this question is also what this is doing is giving us
a weighted sum of
squared exponentials if you will
and here four draws from that's and what you can see is there
for a particular choice here there's some longer-range correlations then we might have seen in the squared exponential drop
but also some some shorter wiggles as well
so what this sick
what is the point out is this just with a different form the kernel function we seem to be getting
we're still getting nice smooth continuous draws
but they have different different smoothness properties in different long-range properties
one the questions i was asked fours about a periodic kernel so
we've we've been talking about kernels that give us that give us these functions over time
but what about what about a periodic function and so what you see here
is that's
we've we've added what looks like
you know and this this this exponential term we just put it put a sign in here
and what this gives us
when we take draws from in the same in the same way so again we're just evaluating the kernel matrix
and we're taking draws from guassian so here four draws from there
and what you see here is that within a particular period
this just looks like a draw from something like a squared exponential
but now there's this extra property that periodic over time this is
this is this is this cute but also this is something that is very useful fore
let's say the heart rate example
four r measuring weather patterns are something like this this is something that is actually that that's actually useful
it up to now all the kernels even talking about are stationary kernel so so
those of us who take taken
some course in stochastic processes things like this remember you know about this notion of
stationary kernels which is we've been talking about kernel functions as a function of two
arguments but in reality all the functions that we've looked at so far are really
on the other
mention is the probabilistic language use
so you could use something like bayesian networks markov networks like we just saw
you could use some like for example probabilistic context free grammars or you know some
more limited
languages like say you know naive bayes which is a special case of these nodes
and so on
another dimension is the type of learning that you can do in this approach
so the generative versus discriminative like just seeing the structure parameters you could have knowledge
rich knowledge poor learning in principle you could do any of these types of learning
with any approach
in practice the not always available sometimes there's no particular reason for that sometimes there
is a reason
and then there's also the type of inference that you do
so you can do any he versus marginal inference as we just saw
another important dimensions along which is approach is very is how to handle ground
you could ground that everything fully
you could grant things partially that's actually the key idea not a small construction or
you could even do lifted inference
so again this
this is another important dimension to to think about
so let's start with the earliest example
which is knowledge based model construction and actually encompasses quite a variety of approaches
here the logical languages horn clauses and the probabilistic languages bayes nets
and the basic idea
on how to combine logic and probability here's is the following
every ground atoms so i have a first order the world so i have relations
i have predicted i have audits et cetera and i can construct patterns in the
way that we just saw
every possible run that is going to be a positive potential knows
innovation network
so so i have network over boolean variables each of which is one the termites
in france and abroad
and then what's going to happen is that i'm going to construct a bayesian network
from my first order knowledge base that's what is called knowledge based model construction knowledge
base is the more knowledge based on the model is the vision network
and the way i'm going to start vision of what is the following
the head of the clause is going to be the che child
the body of the clause is going to be the turbulence
and i i have
and now that i have more than one clause with the same here
i need some kind of combination function
to combine the predictions from the various clauses
so all the atoms
in all the clauses
have this
as their heads are going be parents
of the nodes
each clause is the is a deterministic conjunction and now what i need is some
kind of way
to combine with the different classes and this combination function can be something like logistic
or noisy or
noisy or is the most commonly used one it basically says that the child is
if one of the rules says it's true
but that does affect the probability for each one there's also often some probably they
might be true even if all of the current clauses
so what happens is that when i have a query
what i do is i do partial ground
meaning i construct just the network that i need to answer the question
which is good basically going to be composed of the prologue prove trees of the
query node or nodes and all the evidence nodes you can prove that network containing
has all the information that you need to the right probability i e you will
give the same answers as if you for the whole network with all possible moves
and of course a lot of the time it's going to be much much smaller
OK so we do ground basically by doing all prologue
and and then we can do something like per belief propagation over these networks or
it could be another probabilistic inference method but that is you know at this point
i just have a vision that was so i can use anything belief propagation MCMC
et cetera
so to learn the structure of these networks we can use ILP
you can you could learn a lot like this just by running any of the
system taking its output and saying it's the model not course you also need to
learn the parameters to learn the parameters often use something like the
and the reason is something like this that's typically you will not have observed a
lot of the intermediates
predicates in your inference is that everything you can impose for otherwise you need to
do something like you
they typically people do not have resources such as the is for closing pure ILP
and then you just the parameters using here which is actually not quite the right
thing to do if you think about it you actually like to learn at each
point learning the clauses using your ultimate like with the objective function
so that's what this model construction
the oldest and probably most very family of these approaches
here's another one
stochastic logic programs here the logical languages again when clauses
the probabilistic language is not probabilistic context free grammars
and for stochastic logic programs can just be seen as listing PCFG to the first
order level by turning production rules into horn clauses
so here's what we do is we take the prolog program
and we just attach a probability to each class
with the restriction
that the sum of the probabilities of course with the same has to be one
and the semantics of this is that
they that had is produced as one of its bodies we just don't know which
but we have a probability distribution over them
so unless we really gives you is a probability distribution over prolog prove trees
so if then you want to do inference then we have to do is you
just look at the proof start of whatever could you have to have used should
have to do all proves
but problem can do this for you what has to happen is that you need
to keep track of the probabilities
meaning as you go down the tree need to multiply the probabilities and then you
need to add the probabilities of all of all the trees
and this this give the probability of you create
they again to do learning we can use ILP to the structure learning
to do to learn parameters we can learn with a small record which is
there year
it's to be what's called just
what i mean by just o
not all succeed
but some of the prospect succeed by this scheme also has some probability
so what i need to do is to renormalize
the partition function in slps is not one
like vision networks so need to to adjust my you are not willing to take
into account e i need to normalize to subtract out
the probability mass of the precipitate
here's another
probabilistic relational models
a lot of work was done in this over the last several years
here the logical languages frame systems
you have classes of objects and for each class of objects you have a canonical
description of the arctic meaning the attributes of the objects of that class and the
relations of the objects of that class to other classes
the probabilistic language is once again bayesian networks
and the idea is that
we don't have differing systems where for each class
we have
a bayesian network that describes
the joint distribution of the attributes of that of the objects of that class
and this is the relational model because the attributes of an object in addition to
extending in an attribute of an object in addition to being able to depend on
multi CPU
computer was very rare at the and the
so you need you need to to use some error to get into a situation
when you run a number of CPU
i think that have much more mild CPU
machine that ordinary one
in the future i think that
usually you have got to be used in every country
but we start from
from memory
the good thing here is that
nearly all hardware that we can use
it has now the same memory hierarchy
in this little
in ordinary workstation
or in the data centre is specially designed to our
it seem
the same hierarchy of memory
the most cave commemorate is CPU register
how many to come when you does seem to have
does anybody know
what does it mean basic
then of course the case common
three candidates the
it's not so
there is that there is not is stop
you can you can to answer this question exactly because
there are
i think that's right now in production there are about sixteen models and all of
them have
different number of y
i hope it's not really
now it's usually called like super
random access memory or process random access memory and the idea is that something in
which is the
link wired together with arithmetic or logical you need and all other parts of the
what we know about the memory that we have
a small amount of this memory on the
congress white
but it's extremely fast
it's processes are running on you go by
so it's it's not a second story this memory is not less than on the
second is very fine
all one
then all modern process so that they
have CPU cache
CPU cache is fast memory that is also detached this process
but i think that usually
people don't know anything about CPU cache
only only what we know about it is that
for unknown reasons people who are doing it
computer hardware market
for this number one box
so you still have to with
two megabytes of cash four megabytes of passion and so on and so forth
this is an important number for all purposes and i think that it's not so
important for ordinary people who are blind
laptop for office applications because it's not so good
so this this number is not so important for them
but again was good with this CPU cache because his why leslie two
two there
central process you need
it's pretty fast
and you can always take abou that describe this
hardware and say
that you need
for example half of second to get data from the cache
you can always predict how when operations you need to get the data
so talking about complexity when we talk about when we
describe the number of operations
for these two types of memory
you always can
how long will take
computational this
if you have such a good collection
that actually
fits into
two megabytes of
to be married imagine the situation
you can
precisely calculate how many times
will take colocalisation indexing of the collection
because you know
for all other types of memory true
it it could be surprised but when you are accessing two
random access memory in your
you see different numbers
you cannot predict in advance how long it will take to get quite from around
the memory
when going on
the right number three
the reason CPU cache because CPU cache actually
campaign lots of random access memory it can simply
because it is real-time right here and it's one of the principles of self organizing
recall the first slide was
let's look at the idea that
this is our spontaneous
in real time dynamically driven organization
so we don't
at that activity happens state is kind of like an active and there's whole world
knowledge and we use that word
in the state so that
that that
what is not in memory states does
and yet
then there
the you've got
another direction
but you don't remember you
i to
the second thing you need
the they
the direction
the more you know
five minutes
they don't
this is actually a
you the fact that is we
yes that's exactly the problem
is that generally OK there's two ways basically that we know about the ones from
inside just from interacting so for example you could
because the person sometimes you have life events
completely reorganized the way of the world where you are i injury for example physical
injury he completely reorganized the way that i actually know
that's the next
motivation but if required adaptation from the inside for me to be able to sustain
the organization OK
right from the more concrete they have full neurons their interaction with the dancing
well there are going
so this is a very beautiful neurons
the interacting particle that your
well not to
you are the one is should be looking at the current affairs programme where should
we modeling things in the world neurons
in things inside the head or do we do new kinds of which is happening
which is
what's happening outside is as important and the is teenagers
red should be
so why can't the neuron structure
all i have a lot to me
the structure of sentence
there are people have different ideas and reviews for this to decide which of the
modelling ideas or to play with in order to look
and social mission that is common to see confirmation connections modelling
we have to develop connections model of collective cognition
by bias now back to
we need
a group of people
could not necessarily have a purpose from within
but immediate purpose that is
imposed from the outside or results
from from the so-called outside
in a similar way i have obviously talked about super advanced things but this of
all things and i want to talk about just introduce a couple of the concepts
of unsupervised learning
in unsupervised learning
i'm going to split into just two areas for the moment which i think you
could certainly do more but i'd like to mention briefly the idea of clustering
and dimensionality reduction so we'll start with clustering and i just want to show the
simple k means clustering algorithms
well basically
you don't have now you've got your data and you want to categorize it without
you don't have any labels or anything like that so the way to deal with
that is one example is the cluster and humans doing this all the time so
for example we
class two different animal species into different groups so you think we say it before
we knew the genetic different we say all those those rule frogs they share similar
characteristics we can get confused with things like duck-billed platypus if it doesn't fit into
one group or another by classification
so we like to do discrete categorisation thing so
at the moment because it's election day in the UK a different political parties i
would think it's very funny that you you are allowed to have for example in
britain any one more than one of three political different political opinions because those are
the only three for on the states you only have two
one of two political opinions bits of the clustering of many different opinions people talk
about even being on the right to left so i think when people talk about
being on the right to the left the talking about i dimensionality reduction yes so
your further to the right or your further to the left politically that there seems
to be more to politics in the one-dimensional dimensionality reduction but if you then go
beyond the dimensionality reduction you say your left-wing socialists so then that
clustering you're right wing your
conservative so
that's another sort of classification so you know we obviously like to these things even
when underlying people actually generally probably have a continuum of opinions and very little different
ways so
the idea of clustering to some allocation to the groups and much harder but perhaps
more interesting the number of different groups i will be talking about that this be
showing this is simple
k means clustering so
for example we have a set k cluster centers so in k means clustering what
we require is a set of k cluster centers on an assignment of data to
each of the cluster centers so what we do there is we can initialize perhaps
each cluster centres as the data points so we could start we have to some
starting idea about cluster centers and one initialisation would be just to take cluster centers
the data points and assign each data point to the nearest cluster centre then we
can update each cluster centre by setting to the mean of the assign datapoints so
here is objective that we're minimising their so
if we were if is cluster centers and we have k of them
then we got why is data
we basically look at all the data that is allocated to one of the cluster
centers and we compute the say the squared
distance between across the center and the data is allocated to it we some all
of that
and that's basic model of what's going on in clustering so we're minimizing the sum
of euclidean squared distances between points and their associated centres
so this minimum is guaranteed to be globally unique to the other stuff we doing
so far you're actually looking for global and unique minimum but this is i think
this is much more interesting case is worrying i think if your memories global and
unique it says that you may be doing something too simple although lots of people
disagree with that so the objective is non convex optimisation problem but the algorithm works
very well in in lots of cases some data
i've artificially generated
and it's sort of an
well we might see it was actually that was
potentially three clusters that
and the way the algorithm works if we initialize cluster centers by sampling randomly from
the data we happen to sample two sensors
two data points in one cluster one data point in another
we allocate
data points to nearest cluster centre so here we've got three all these blue
the nearest cluster centre
is this one here
so already we've got
sort of
identify cluster here
the red ones
all these part of these guys down here allocated to this one part of the
relegated here then we update by setting and cost centre to be the mean
of the points currently existing and that moves and then and then we reallocate so
now we've got to guide in this cluster allocated to here
but the rest relegated here we do again reallocate
and we do it again and now none of the allocations changing we converge so
that's k means clustering which is perhaps the simplest clustering algorithm you could envisage it's
got several limitations in the distance is being measured just in terms of euclidean distance
of this perceptually if we had
an example
where we had a bunch of data in the middle here and this is the
famous example people have used to demonstrate other algorithms and then you've got a bunch
of data entering outside here
this algorithm would work because there's no cluster centre
that all these guys are closer to here
then they would be to hear so what you end up doing there is if
you wanted to cluster them also these were in different cluster to v these you
would have to have cluster centers going all the way around
and i and i think very impressive a again i remember being very impressed when
it comes that came out was
papers on spectral clustering which do allow you to to clusterings like this and what
they do is clever transformations on the data
again using sort basis function like approaches and they do k means clustering in a
different space one of the popular algorithms does that
where you can actually cluster these things that are connected so that shows one of
the things that's interesting about what you might think is your impression what clustering is
of how things should cluster and one algorithm two when you find an objective function
so it's perhaps dangerous you define an objective function like this
and it seems reasonable
but the way functions isn't necessarily how you might expect clustering to function because really
what goes on i think
clustering you're not just looking at how close things are but you're looking at whether
there gaps so when you look clustering you probably
using these are all the data points are close to each other on this outer
ring here so they belong together and then there's a gap to these data points
here see also interested in ensuring that the gap between these different points where the
algorithm doesn't doesn't do that so you know it's an example where the mathematical formalism
is slightly wrong
spectral clustering is away
out of that
one way of trying to select the number of clusters a lot of people have
been looking at is say things like the recently processes
which are probabilistic approaches to clustering which try and consider
prior distributions to say that the could be infinite classes is i mean i won't
i go backwards and forwards forever
if i want to generateacompletely unbiased sample
that'sdefinitely a boltzmannmachine, and it's tedious
once i've done that
i then take thisbinary state that i'vegot here and go chunk chunk
and that's an unbiased sample from the composite model
so the composite model is not a big boltzmann machine
the composite model is
a restricted boltzmann machine
and then deep belief netstuff as many layers as you like
so what we've got now is a way churning out lots of layers of deep belief
net stuff
by learningthis undirected stuff in the other direction
it's kind of, not the kind of thing you'd have thought of doing.
we just started doing this and then realized what weweredoing later
you wouldn't have thought of learning lots of layers of
directed stuff
in the wrong direction using undirected stuff you'll see later why that's a good idea
i'm nowgoing to go into some slightly complicated math but then we're gonna have
a nice example
i'm gonnato try and justify what the greedy learning is up to, and why it works
why it can learn a layer at atime like this
first i need to get some, sort of, properties of factorial distributions straight.
given the visible units
the distribution across the hidden units is factorial, that is, they're independent,
the hidden units, given the visible units.
theposterior of the hiddens
but if i now add up those posterior distributions, or rather, average them over many different data
what i get is something that isn't factorial
just like when i take a mixture of gaussians, i get something that isn't a
here when i average thesefactorial distributions i get something non-factorial
i'll callthat thing that i get the aggregated posterior
it'sthe posterior distribution over the hidden units,
aggregatedover all the data vectors.
here's one picture of what greedy learning is doing
we're learning some weights,
that connect hidden units to visible units
and these weightsaredoing two things for us
the weights definitely define,
given a hidden vector
what the probability is of turning on each of the visible units.
so given a distribution over hiddenvectors,
they define a distribution overvisible vectors.
in particular given the aggregated posterior distribution
they define somedistribution for the data
which won't be quite right.
so this is a kind of parametric model that,
given this aggregated posterior,
a distribution for the data.
the very same weights
also define a prior over the hidden things
so there's two things that are different.one is the aggregated posterior
that you get by puttingindata
and looking at the states of the hidden units
a separate thing is the prior that you have for this,
defined by these very same weights
and the way theprior is definedis that, suppose i took a boltzmann machine with these weights
here, andjust went backwards and forwardsfor a long time and then sampled this
that would be a sample from this prior.
notice i didn't mention data when i did that
that is just what the model would like to put here
if it's a perfectmodel, of course, it'll be the same as this aggregated posterior
these weights are playing two roles
if we view it in a directed kind of way
they're defining
a prior over this stuff
and they're defining
the probability of this
given these states
so we could generate from the model by going backwards and forwards for a long
timethensampling from the prior, and then
doing one small samplinghere
and the trick of the deep learning is going to be to say
we're gonna keep this bit
we're gonna allow the W's to keep defining that
but for this bit, we'regonnareplace them by something else. we're gonna take this
term, throwitaway, and replace it by something better
which is what we're going to get when we treat this as data and learn another boltzmann machine
with different weights up here.
this is tough stuff to get the hang of
it's going to get easier later.
so a way of saying thatinan equation is that the probability of a visible vector
is the sum over all hidden states
of the probability of generating that hidden vector from the model
times the probability of the visible vector given the hidden vector
so that defines the probabilityof a visible vector. and if you've already learned the weights
that define boththese terms
then what you could do is leave this term alone and go off and improve that term, and you'll
get a better model for the data
and that's the trick of deep learning.
just to sort of keepyoustraight about what'sfactorialand what's not:
in a directed belief net,
like the earthquake example,
a bit
OK let's get started now
i'm assuming i'm assuming that a UN to recitation yesterday
the that even if you didn't you know how to separate variables and you know
how to construct simple models
of sort physical problems with differential equations possibly even sell them
so you should learn that either in high school
four eighteen o one
so i'm going to start from that point assume you know that i'm not going
to tell you what differential equations or what modelling is if you
still uncertain about those things the book has a very long and good explanation of
it just be that stuff
we're talking about
first order
all these of the
all use three two akron two acronyms these ordinary differential equations i think all of
knows that were
taking a course i
so we're talk about first-order odis
which in standard form are written
you isolate
derivative of y with respect to let x let's say
on the left-hand side and on the right-hand side you write everything else
you can't always do this very well
but for today i'm going to assume that it has been done and it's doable
so for example some of the ones that will be considered either today or in
the problems that
things like
why prior equals x over y it's pretty simple
the problems that also problems that has why prime equals
r move
minus y squared
and it also has
why prime equals
why minus x squared
there are others too
you look at this this of course you can solve by separating variables
so this is solvable
this one
in neither of these can you separate variables and they look extremely similar
but they are extremely disimilar are the most dissimilar about them
is this one
is easily solvable and you learn you don't know already next time next friday and
solve this one
this one which looks almost the same
is unsolvable in a certain sense namely there are no elementary functions which you can
write down which will prove give a solution of adequate differential equation
so right away one conference
the most significant factor even for the simplest possible differential equations those which only involve
the first derivative it's possible to write an extremely looking got simple guys up with
this one up in blue to indicate is there that
o three
i mean that you know not really bad
it's not solvable in the ordinary sense in which you think of the equation equation
is solvable
and since those equations are the rule rather than the exception
i'm going about this first day
two not solving a single differential equation
but indicating to you what you do
when you meet a blue equation like that what you do
with it
so this first is going to be devoted to geometric ways of looking at differential
numerical at the very end all talk a little bit about numerical
ways and you will work on both of those for the first problem set
what are geometric view of differential equations
it's something that contrasted with the usual procedures by which you solve things you don't
find elementary functions which sell them a call that the analytic method
so on the one hand we have the knowledge
the got talent ideas
in which you write down explicitly the equation
why primary equals f of that's why
and if you look for certain functions which are called it's solutions now
so far there is the only e
and why one of x notice i don't use a separate letter IOU's g or
h or something like that the solution because the letters multiply so quickly that is
like gravity multiply this is of
then after a while if you keep using different letters for each new idea you
can figure out what
i'll use y one means
it's a particular solution a solution of this differential equation of course the differential equation
has many solutions
containing an arbitrary constant so so-called this silly
the geometric view
the geometric guy that corresponds to this
version of writing equation is something called the direction field
and it's not normally--this relates to the very first slide--there's not normally an
issue of,there'sso much noise you couldn't tell what this was by looking at
that. in vision, you look at this and you know what this is.
occasionally you're wrong, but you pretty much know what this is
so if you want to get from here to here
trying to learn your way directly like that,
whilst ignoring the fact that was really going on, iscrazy
in particular because this is a very low bandwidth path
you'd be much better off just inverting this first
and then
learning this simpler mapping--this mapping, this mapping's gotta be simpler
than this mapping, right? if it happens like that
once you've got this, then learn that.
i'm sort of labouring this point
if you buy this picture, then unsupervised pre training makes sense. you're finding this.
OK i want to talk a little bit about modeling real values because so far, it's
all beenbinary values, sometimes treated as
real valued probabilities
so for
mnist digits, you can treat intermediate values like probabilities/ you can think of them
as the probability that pixelhad ink orsomething like that
but it doesn't work for real images
so in a real image
then, the intensity of a pixel is almost exactly the average of its neighbours almost
and you can't get that sort of exact
you know, you can't get an exact 0.7 and not 0.69
out of these logistic units. you need something else
yee-whye teh and i
tried using integer valued variables
which you can make quite easily by saying i've got n identical copies of a
binary unit
so now
i can get myself integervalues. it's still hard to get them very precise because
the noise grows with the value
in fact, if the binary unit has the probability pofbeing on,
which is the logistic of the total input it gets,
then you get a number that has--
your real value has this mean
and this variance.soin the middle there's quite a lot of variance
so we got--we managed to deal with some real valued images like that
matching faces for example
yee-whye did a very nice job of it
but that was mainly to do with the fact that yee-whye does a good
job of everything, even if he's working with a not very good model like this
a better way to model
integer values
you take our binary unitand you replicate it many times, but each time you replicate it, you shift it
that is, you give it biases. they all have the same shared bias that's learned,
but they're shifted like this
there's a reason for the0.5's
so this is what they look like
and here is the total input. so down here
the aboveoutput'szero
and what we're gonnado is just take the sum of all their outputs
so if you ask whatdoes this curvelook like when i add up all
to within the thickness of the line,
it's this curve here.
it's very accurately this
if you take an infinite number of these
this curve
can be made out of
these guys
and because you've got a learning algorithm for these guys
i mean i can always put some constraint on sharingweights and things,and the learning algorithm still works
soinow have to learn these guys
i know a wayof learning these--this, this thing with integer noise
and what i've done that i'm happy, thatcontrast divergence learning will work for this
thing with the appropriate integer noise
and therefore
i then throw away the theory and say, i'm gonna learn withthis thing
and have somegaussiannoise that's got the same variance as the appropriate integer noise
and so i end up with this kind of unit
it's--the output is the max of zero
and the input plussome gaussiannoise
whose value is--whose
standard deviation
whose variance is the logistic of
the total input
and that's roughly right and these guys workvery nicely
and you train them just by--i can now have these rectified linear units instead
of binary units
so i can deal with positive real valued stuff here
especially if lots of the values are zero. it's very happy with that.
and use the same units here
and i can trainit upwith contrastive divergence just the same way as i did before
it's very importantthatwhen ichoosestates for these guys
i stick in the sampling noise
i don't have to stick in the sampling noise when i choosethese states or when i
choose these states.
sampling noise heredoesn't do anything, except add noise.
it stops you transmitting real values accurately
which regularizes things lot.
so i can learn with those.
so here's some experimentsthat i did withunits like that. unfortunately,
the units weren'texactly like that
they were very like that but not exactly like that
because i hadn't yet figured allthisoutwhen i did the experiments.but i'll tell you the results
and hopefully the experiments are only going to get better by doing it right.
in some way three is the father of y two and could write for the
chain as long as i want to just made an example with the chain of
length three now
that's after this we again to our system we have in there
let's see what we get
again we get the same three doctors
namely johnny cantoni and why do we get johnny cantoni i mean the reason is
essentially the same
we are not asking for explicitly giving the father of this person we just asking
for the existence of a chain of ancestors
and since we know that the
each person has a father and the range of the hasfather property is again a
the father will again be a present the following will again have a father and
so on
so however long we make this chain we know that have
the instance of person
will be in the answer to such a query
the existence of the father is implied by
the constraints in our ontology
now let's make it slightly different query sorry
suddenly changed
it allows
it is again very similar to the earth
to the previous one in the previous line what the difference now
the difference is that now we ask asking explicitly also for
the president is at the end of the chain so for their ancestors
for the grand grandfather of
of x because we are not asking for expert for the pair x y three
let's see what we get now is an answer
OK we don't get and the answer the number fifty properties zero so if we
ask explicitly
there the individual it here then the system is not able any more to exploit
the information in ontology because it doesn't have sufficient information
this is the information is not sufficient to say that anyone
o has sought to extract some
that are related to multiple chaining of the hasfather relations
we can
this is an issue but i mean this this is the sum of the game
the one place one if one wants the name
so if one is interested in the name
put the variability it means he is interested in and that's why i asked for
the name if you are not interested in the name that he would about the
first query
well you know that you will i mean this person will have some chain of
ancestors but you're not interested in buddhism has that and so you don't return because
i mean return invented name returning no name is not to there's not much of
a difference to some degree so it's actually just to queries reflect different information needs
that persons
all users may have when they deposed these queries here they are interested in the
name of the twenty ask for it
and the system may or may not have enough information to
provides answer here they not interested in the name and that's why i did not
know that so the messages you can take it from here is not whether that's
too much i mean if you ask only the information that you really need because
if you ask too much then you may not get also what you want to
compare and we had in concrete examples we had this experience where
i mean users west session posing queries which are all too much information in this
didn't allow the system to infer information that could actually provide would have been useful
for users
now let's look at the final example
in which which is a bit more complicated so how much time do i have
fifty minutes
fifteen OK
so i guess i might keep this example also
this example shows a case where
you have to all the system in order to provide an answer has to do
with what is called reasoning by cases so it has to analyse various possibilities that
depend on the data and this
complex thing to do and the fact that this comes
along is because here in our ontology reuse essentially disjunctive information we say that professors
are partitioned into st professor and full professors and this leads to this problematic issue
of reasoning by cases again
i keep this for time reasons
now a
so just to summarise what we were saying
now in this in this setting where we want to answer queries on large amount
of data in the presence of incomplete information we want to take into account at
runtime the constraints the reason at runtime
and we want to answer complex database like queries
also should is this is what happens if we want to deal with multiple information
sources used you in the context of information integration
this situation typically arises
just to connect with same before when i was talking about answering queries we want
to reason so the technically the notion that you are interested in what's interesting is
the so-called certain answers to a query which i intuitively the answers over all possible
interpretations that are models of our
ontology can
this is similar to the kind of reasoning that we did for
when where and when we are asking instances of classes
except that now we have is
but it's the same notion so we want or copies of constance that
in the answer to the query for every possible interpretation is a model of our
and these are called the certain answers
and what we want to do is want to get the certain answers by process
of inference so in general this process of instance required to take to create a
t-bone steak our data a box
do some inference all this information and produced set the certain answers
but the point is that if you want to deal with data efficiently
then we especially need in this largely inference process need to separate the contribution comes
from the data from the contribution that comes from the korean from the tee box
so what we're interested in is in the process of query answering by rewriting what
does this mean that look at this so
separating the contribution means you satiated for for some computational
over the query
and the box and produce essentially new query that incorporate the information coming from the
tee box this is called
perfect rewriting of our initial increase the perfect rewriting cooperate the information in the books
in the new query
you take this nuclear and and say over our a box by viewing the able
to just it was database few as if it was complete data
we want this to produce than the certain answers which are defined in the larger
this is the first thing that i that that i need
the other thing is that there must be a deterministic relation
my belief in a certain proposition
and i believe in its negation
so if i sort of say
sort of running out of examples here
imagine that k
OK let me just be vague so
if i if i think that if i sort of if i'm convinced that a
proposition is false this is false then there must be a mathematical way for me
to know what my belief is indeed being true OK and this relation must be
deterministic OK
so the third one
the first one one is a bit complicated i really don't know where to go
i need to be able to
if i want to know how much i believe i want to be the joint
like earlier we had this joint distribution p of x come out why OK
how much do i simultaneously believe into given propositions
and today being sunny and me being one eighty OK
i must be
there must be way
that that i can
we construct this information from these two quantities here roughly so
from the conditional beliefs so i see sunny and now how much do i believe
in my heart could be
but then i need to also use
actually what my belief in the in
in the something being out is
the consequence of these reactions if you satisfy them all if you if you need
to satisfy the more
then basically this is another book has anyone read james book
not that many people but it's
it's a beautiful book really
he is
a viral and bayesian his his is there already
he died old
but his left a lot of followers shall we say so so that the big
thing is that if these belief functions have to satisfy all of this then they
must satisfy the rules of probability theory including bayes rule
so how could we
how can we apply this to
two modelling situation
so imagine the following imagine we had a certain dataset
imagine we had some models to choose from
and then given the model i also have to choose some values for the parameters
OK so there's quite a few uncertain quantities laying around
all right now the interesting thing is that
the two quantities that come to mind one of them is
the prior beliefs so what the mean is before i see the data before even
see the data
how all
you know
what's my prior belief among complexity with the user neural network with ten billion hidden
o or one with three OK internally in my mind i have some sort of
a predisposition
you know it might be very vague prior distribution over over the complexity but i
certainly would probably not use one with with ten billion
very differently
but there was a function
so we should just one minus
that's what it
so the the axiom was a lot more abstract just said that that necessarily if
i if i have is basically because
proposition and it being falls must cover all the space of hypotheses and therefore there
must be a deterministic relation between the two
OK i want to have a model one said was of picked my neural net
a thousand hidden units let's say
now i have to select also some values for the weights right
and from my experience i know that
if the values get too large and stuff like that you know
i may overfit some gonna
i'm going to sort of i i suppose you know all of us
do that in one way or another right you can either add a sort of
squared norm penalty to the weight spread due to your cost function you have you
know the sum of squared weights or anything that sort of pushes away to be
small and to get sort of smooth functions and stuff like that we all have
our assumptions about smoothness regularity and so on
and then the third
the third quantity is
i want to have a model
and once you have picked value for the parameters
what kind of what kind of data can be small
all right and i can also express that
so you might say oh wait a moment if i have my neural net and
i have chosen the values of the parameters and everything is fixed
there's no uncertainty here right well no i mean there is still some uncertainty that
the trivial one is just noise right you might assume that there is some observation
so you might you might think that
even if a choice of model and the choice of parameters already gives you sort
of the the the the underlying function
you know that if you were to observed data
you know chances are they will come with a bit of noise
right so you still have some uncertainty here and you will be able to express
this as as a distribution
as well
so what can i do now with all these distributions
isabelle mentioned earlier that i i d
this is a thing of the past now we're we're over that
it's it's sort of true so
very often you see this use of this thing here is called the likelihood so
here x has been transformed into a d for for for the data OK
if they were independent you could sort of
you can sort of factorizes but there is no
there's no compelling reason there's absolutely no reason why why you need
the the i i d
on this slide OK
one interesting quantity in in sort of interest in the sort of the bayesian setting
what happens is the following and i'll show you show you later a couple of
figures try to illustrate his let's take let's take the the neural network example again
i have some sort of idea of what my
values of all the values of my weights should be
so what i can do is i can give them a probability distribution and that's
have five equals two
so if you just want to not
and you can also measure there are now two of them to get h squared
another exponent here
so obviously smaller we make smash size
so close to the point j two together to better we have
get to get to the continuous solution
it's also a lot of adaptive strategy which can automatically
choose how far we have to refine the grid if you this adaptive grid cells
not of code alzey how to
where to put the grid points and had two two
get to a good solution
these two dimensional results in similar results in higher dimensions but most of the series
for the five months of this
two and three dimensions because no way really
could do them in high dimensions before
OK so
a bit of new movies so that you can see what people are doing was
this is just the ball which dropped into water
and difficult thing here is to
to actually be able to
things that were there was that they have little splash is coming out and this
can kind of this holds that's in america very difficult to track set
what else do we have
the same when we have
stops this one
don't ever
so here we have adjustable
coming into the water and is the difficulty is that we have to do this
affix subject
fixed objects
and be able to track
as easy conditions on the boundary and it's all moving that's difficult to tracks
two of nowadays
and some people working with hollywood for this kind of things to make better movies
and we have i
you to
we can have some fluid looking over boundaries and finding the thing up a little
bit of fluid goes down here and this is just move it just for that
and one last time and
and one is more
not one of my more
sick of fluid
that's how it starts moving
we you can kind of see second of
so that's was very short course on finite element have you have a basic understanding
what what's going on
at some some names no driven what is notable for its
the set of being done in three dimensions two and three dimensions that are not
sparse grids which is one way
two years
go into
one way to extend this grid kind of approaches into higher dimensions
re one of the basic ideas has to do with the what kind of pages
using so before i read this
the basis functions as we won
we too
and we three
and obviously can
represents function so the combination of these functions these functions can represent commission six from
so we want to include between one and be week
there's a different approach called direct basis
i was already first discovered in nineteen nine by problem
but some picked up demonstrators
and there we have
it's similar to what it's the same as the wavelet decomposition method you heard so
we have now this space with three the same space as before but we can
write it as this w three plus w two
we know that
so i
is less than or equal to five
this article to cite as well
so this the last prop that sorry the third property just tells us that one
of the one of the two opposite inclusions also
and i'll tell you what i mean what effect that has
OK the last two properties just tell us fairly explicitly that
non beliefs minimally entrenched
and so anything that's not in case mainly entrenched in the last one tells us
that the tautologies max trench
OK now what this gives us structure
which is often called the total preorder
so essentially what is the rank
sort of levels or a series of works
so these are the beliefs he
and most importantly ranked then these ones in these ones and this is about the
sort of separate ranks form
now you can prove some nice properties of this form is probably the most important
one is the following
that if you take this rank at any level
and you can't
and you look at all the formulas that are in here
let's suppose this form is
gathered together in the same game
and that's it
is deductively closed
so if cannot anyway all of the consequences of those beliefs are also in that
OK now the two properties i want to have a a look at just before
the ones at the bottom six and seven
that number three property essentially tells us that if we look at the conjunction of
phi psi
so if we have two formulas
so if i here
then a conjunction is at the same level as the minimum of the two
so find sites
the last one just says that with the destruction of the two
is either going to be here
or it's going to be he e
it's going to be some with
we don't know what
OK so that's what is your
a similar picture to the one given on board
the any questions open to us is where this disjunction is an that has a
very important function is change
let's look at this in conditions c-minus condition is perhaps the most important condition
it tells you how to construct the function k minus five
from this ordering
and it says well some formula size is going to be in k minus five
exactly under the following conditions firstly site has to be believed it has to be
in my
belief that someone
then either one of two conditions hold
i mean if i was the tautology in which case i can do anything i
can give anything up country firewire so in that case i do not
that's the sort of trivial case
in other cases they use this condition with the five is less than five or
signed to determine whether
i should give up some
OK so let's see what happens what
what this guy condition is doing
here i've got to form find site
i want to give up fight and size less important five
so if i took my rationality criteria said look i should give up less important
stuff i've more important stuff
that's ownership indicates that
i'm going to get rid of size well
does that seem like a rational thing to do
would you give us if i told you about five and there's something less important
here which always giving
you know what if i you know what if site has nothing to do with
five so i talked about sure talks about cheese
you know there's no real reason to
always give up side just because i happen to believe
in less
you know when i was outside before believed it was sunny
but hearing in this sort rumblings outside you want to contract beliefs
you know
perhaps i have a strong belief about like much weaker belief about my car still
being in the car park when i get back
should i give my belief in the car park just because i want to give
up my belief in the fact that some else
now the key comes down to the hat how this condition is used and that's
two freeways sparsity
that we draw the dictionary elements for action now which is the basis on base
moment can which can be a normal distribution
and we associate each dictionary element which is a pi k indicating the probability for
this dictionary to be selected in the data
and with pike k draw from data
so we would rather pay to acquire coefficients the ikea which case into the i
i d from below deepika
so by construction of rotation would be sparse
however assume that the interoperability which means they have by no binomial coefficient is how
to restrict so end up with a another reputation that the choice of the weights
associate with the from the normal so actually is
actual weights is the element wise product between the binary indicators e i understood as
i we and we have always the model exercise equal to be w plus most
these dictionary that i is the coefficient which
has real when you also imposed that many of these questions can be exactly zero
based on this
the condition we can compute hierarchical model only it
here i'm not going to discuss in detail this hara model but i want to
i want to mention that we only put long informative priors on on this on
this parameters and we we can get we can have the data itself to you
for what's the properties sparsity level of
and the laws will rise
i mean the data
and in case that the use cases we only observe a subset of the
data which means such an image we only observe a subset of pixels
and all only have a project to compress the moment they instead of directly observing
data we are observing y equals two sigma XI where sigma is someone in matrix
we end we a full likelihood model
the first term here is the likelihood and all the rest of the priors we
cannot directly calculate the posterior which parameter so we you can use but we can
use gibbs sampling or variational bayes one the first most the two can calculate the
conditional posterior experiment
the detail i'm not going to discuss the detail which can be found the decision
one mentions i'll all give some first show with our compost coordinates and that has
no computational complexity
and was always the dictionary was based both process priors
has a different perspective compared to
member the case with addiction investors however you free capital look as this updating equations
we can find the actually closely related however the have have the difference in the
level exporting
prisoner but any information and we can show that our dictionary elements that has the
highest level exploiting prison input information
and is also natural to use all
model two two sequential learning
since we
i mean we really nonparametric bayesian framework and so you instead of directly of calculating
the post your dictionary conditional on the whole dataset we can partition the
how dataset integer partitions and we first calculate the posterior dictionary on the first to
be partitioned you are and then use this post as the prior
to calculate the posterior dictionary based on the first
they pageant you on the second part indeed to do distinguish only until we're taking
into all the data into consideration
so in summary of noise around
the model relies arrangements bosnian not know
and the dictionary size is automatically inferred the training data lot required l model which
we can directly below the dictionary and the construction data based on noisy and incomplete
o it's some works i can has its own unique sparse representation which renders much
more flexibility than enforcing the saying it's possible for all the
the conditions and a single model here can be applied
four moments grayscale RGB or hyperspectral imaging denied any painting
first i was sure that image denoising result
here there
we can show that if
last level
and the july slowly the saying that case really perform our borders however if this
is the last level
is the higher than the true lower than the two possible cases really would tend
to either always moves in the image or not giving
you know
nice reduction is also interesting to look at a dictionary
in the right column because see the high loss level smaller size the the dictionary
would be inferred which makes sense because the highest possible level some there's less information
we can extract from image
and here we give inpainting results on RGB image on the first of all we
have is when you take eighty percent pixels this obviously image based on this cropped
image only with reconstructed images is
and we take a fifty percent because of
and the reconstructed image region which looks almost the same
and here is another example for to me
RGB image inpainting we have eighty percent pixels missing
this is our restored image this the original image and this is probably image and
can see the coverage in the past
this one point six a corresponding one iteration
and we can also do text remove this in your learning image this television image
that's the state sequence rule
and you would say
you know basically like this in the temporal lobe
city of linear temporal logic in
OK and what you want to bring his right up until the temporal logic axioms
and your progression plan now actually
looking at it is generating the proposition three it's looking at its library
i linear temporal logic formulas and seeing if any of these branches of violating any
of these rules
to do that again interesting thing ones have been keeping backup incremental satisfaction of all
search control the state sequence words and any time one of the rules is violated
you know you can that match
again this a nice that the technical achievement in terms of writing that algorithm is
how to do incrementally evaluation of LTL formula just the same a inmates dn
that's networks how to keep track of incremental passes phd
now how the language itself what look
and you think that you know blocks my question is can you unite these for
OK this is essentially says good of those that do not violate the conditions
OK this is simply a simple some problem
it says that
as you can see
and then
keep growing would tell us a white that
this reminds me of woody allen's speech to my speech to graduate students with c
is to do all the good things that were all the bad things and come
almost six o'clock you know that's the general idea so this is essentially a new
in blocks one this
is what you really trying to do
you do
come up with the best plan
the question is how many of you very smart people here could write
not necessarily right now go home and look at these and without cheating by to
see if you can like is really silly can but you know seems like that
so the heart of the so these are the whole that
you know the guy that humans
who wrote the knowledge was able to fight so my heart is completely of two
barker's by as with things like this apparently and the guy must have been hard
to deal with other kids dealing with lots were but anyway he was able to
write this stuff
and and of course that actually interesting part of the land program itself is to
incrementally and effectively devalued the truth often want to solve the problem of your learning
what you want to do is learn these things
these are some of the most effective ones now if you don't like as good
one as this relates somewhat less interesting ones it will still work is just not
you're not going to be able to to be working in blocks world
gets us to the interesting
question and know sort of pixels to learning aspects of this one thing which is
in the KB planning there were actually two competitions knowledge base planner and you know
what also separately kept an international planning competition
two years i think the thousand and two thousand two they had knowledge base planning
and in fact the two best planners which has been in the first and second
second first shop which is the one i showed you tonight high-level language planning for
the the and the plan which are right beside the main knowledge about the sequences
of blocks
so now the question of course is it's really hard to figure out i mean
one great lesson from KB planning is it's really what the learning distance
it's really what learning this stuff because if you can learn it you can do
just as well as the
but if you don't get into this learning angle then the lessons of
like you you know i mean how you was for him back plan my version
of using biomarkers planet is you know click the planet is planning multiplication instance of
for him because there's no way i can write the kind of knowledge that you
can and similarly shop lots of applications
the instance of being in now
so that you can write these things for me the point i'm trying to make
i mean you know deported kill me if you this but the thing to make
it is the really comparing the campaigning for him to in one type of knowledge
to the type of knowledge
and what is the right thing that you're comparing if you're doing you want them
merged with i been all that all of these guys can be defeated by somebody
will write a c program you know spent six six months of his life i'd
like to see program for that particular domain and that's the only thing they do
is they have no other interest in it
OK so i think in some sense
planning as a separate track fell by the way because people didn't know what to
make out of the
results but for this come here it's a great opportunity
you can learn
makes for him like these kinds of things is studying psychoanalysis of them we could
just learn this kind of knowledge and that's radically
OK so the question is that maybe we should just learn
it's finally get systems
the customisation part
you but i started by saying don't have time and customization done research can be
given by the humans and we look at what they're doing and then of the
i'm going to look at
how it is on a mission again
so this is my view
that area
in two different pieces of learning these kinds of knowledge
looks complicated network explain to you what do so first at this point remember that
in the very beginning i said for planning you can learn such control you can
learn domain physics you can learn
OK now we're are only talking about such control so we are the big ones
in the big one
now i'm going to be i'm saying if i want to learn such control what
sorts of approaches have been taken what the what
had i could accomplish gets
so there no at the top level you would say you could improve on existing
it seems like it is a little thing especially planning people rebuilding of planets and
you would be very sad somebody just this your community is not needed we can
just learn everything
here it is it's
italian heavy metals arsenic
the aircraft
OK questions
all right so we've described the system
with these properties now these properties come in two flavours have extensive properties
and intensive property
extensive properties of the ones that scale with the size of the system double the
system there
double and in there
numerical number
for instance
to double the alignment
double for that's of use
the mass
if you double the amount of stuff the will double
o intensive properties don't care about the scale of the system
two double
everything in the system
the temperature is not change not double
temperature stays the same
the temperature is an intensive and you can make intensive properties out of the extensive
properties by dividing by
the number of moles and this
so i can make a quantity that are called bar
which is the molar volume
the volume of one more of the component my sister
and that becomes an intensive quantity
volume which is an intensified
finds from all
of of the stuff
so as i mentioned termite dynamics is the science of equilibrium systems
so we need a new meaning it is also describes the evolution of one equilibrium
to another equally how to go from one to the other
and so the set of properties that describes the system
in equilibrium and doesn't change
so these
on changing properties that describe the state of colorado instead of the system
markov state variables
state variables
this crime
equilibrium is state
and they don't care about how the the states got to words
they don't care about the history
of the state just
i know that if you have water
zero degrees celsius with
i it
that you can define it as the heterogeneous system with a certain
certain density for the water certain density for the highest etcetera etcetera
doesn't care how you got there
we're going to find other properties that do care about the history of the system
like work
you put a system or he put in the system some other variables
but you can use those to define the equilibrium state
no use if a very independent of history
and it turns out that for one component system one twenty meaning one kind of
molecule the system
all that you need to know
to describe the system
is the number of moles
one performance system
and to describe one phase in that system one component
homogeneous systems need
and two variables
for instance the pressure and the temperature
for the volume and pressure
we have the number of moles into
intensive variables
then you know everything there is to know about the
by the cliff instead of that system
hundreds of
quantities that you can
calculate and measure that are interesting and important properties
and all you need is just a few variables to get everything out
and that's really the power thermodynamics is that it takes so little information
to get so much
information out
so little data
to get a lot of
predictive information
and a function that has small energy on this graph with a function that's constructed
from lambda one and lambda two or
the corresponding phi one phi two along
OK so
remember that's only part of the great we want small graph energy but we also
want your function to fit your labelled training data well
so this will happen if
your function
it is constructed using only those two
bases and then if you're label happens to be such that
for example positive
labels happens on this side and negative labels is that part of the graph
then you will have
in objective function that's extremely small
it's the minimizer
remember the assumption assumption really is
you are
target function the truth
said the data fit to defeat the graph where it's smooth on the graph
let's look at the example when this assumption is not true
so you have seen many times the two moons dataset i believe where the data
points are distributed kind of like this where you have to
and there connected with each room but disconnected and if you have positive on what
they want one the negative labels on the other one it's very much like the
change there
but let me now turn this two moons into inclining one so they actually overlap
and i draw samples from it then
the the circles are going to be some samples if not you create
a graph that's how people typically created nearest neighbour graph or absent graph
we will have trouble because now the two
parts will be strongly connected here
OK and if you
i have
two labelled points
here and here and you do any of this stuff well then not surprisingly
it's not going to do very well
so this is the case where the graph assumption is wrong
later on we will see one way to
help create a better crop
so i'm going to stop here and see if there are questions
not let's move on to
the final
family of algorithms called s three VM stands for semi supervised
support vector machines
now a brief review of support vector machines
this is only with labelled data
so if you have three positive three negative labels points and you want to find
the decision boundary SVM finds a linear decision boundary that separates the two classes with
the largest margin that means i defined the cart with the largest gap in the
gap is represented by dashed lines
OK so this is the
now if you also have unlabelled data points
it's the same labelled data point
but the green dots are unlabelled
then the previous cut
you may not be good
this decision boundary which cuts through this unlabelled data
why not good well if you believe that this
a whole lot looks like a whole lot is very dense and probably should
come from the same class then you want to avoid cutting through
that's labeled region
instead now the
the largest
margin linear
foundry is perhaps this
notice it still separates
the labelled data point but on the unlabelled data points
you're going to have a gap of this size
and that's the idea behind s three VM
you just want to separate
classes but as well as the unlabelled data somehow so you get the largest margin
OK so how do we do with this
now we need to review a little bit what is behind SPM
and this is the soft margin SVM
let me explain that
you have
classifier which i didn't right here as
which is HX plus b so edges some
so there's the
the bias term but
that's tracks plus b is a linear function of x
you have a linear function here and
you want to say that
this linear function is going to produce
this is the correct sign for my label y
i want
i hx
plus b
to be positive if y is
in the positive class and i want this to be negative if y is in
the negative class
i want
y times this to be always possible
that's my hope
and and furthermore not only do i want them to be on
to make the correct
classification i want to make
the classification with a very strong confidence
so instead of requiring this could be bigger than zero i wanted to be bigger
than one
so they have to be are sort of on the
so far away from the decision boundary
so that's what i wanted
but i also want to
take into consideration that some data points may not be separable in my case
it's it may not be possible for every data point to satisfy
without without this term
so i may not be able to separate every data points
four enough
so i need to relax it the way i relax it is by saying that
i'm going to introduce the slack variables because i
such that now i make this
so concise positive so i make this
inequality easier to satisfy right i can make the site
big so that this term is close to zero or you might even make it
bigger than one so that i will allow
this point to be on the wrong side of the decision boundary
i want to also
if we knew something about the probability we should be able to
use this information and that's exactly what prizes for
the problem is here
only if we sample many times get the problem is right
a good rule of thumb
this is in general actually quite handy
you need unless you do some symmetry
about ten times as many observations as you have to mention
you might say about the microarrays you know you've got maybe a hundred thousand
measurements and you've got only
two hundred three patients well this is very i see you have to do something
really fancy
but in general
if you've got ten times
as many observations as you've got parameters
yes a
what can you do
well one way of introducing processes what's called conjugate priors
and i'm not going to explain in a lot of detail here but what they
correspond to it
it's like assuming that they have additional fake stuff
so for instance if i
well some game of monopoly or
but even with the frame and it's also dies right
so usually i would not assume that my friend will cheat on me so i
don't assume that the
by state
so it's like assuming that one in addition to all the time so they passed
my dies in that game and might have maybe
played another
ten games with the guy before
and know he hasn't read them in the past so i can essentially atmospheric extra
so what i was basically do is i would take
the actual occurrences of an event i
and that my fake accounts to it
and the normalized by the number of trials plus all the extra fake counts the
this is something that in natural language processing people have actually done
it's called the possible
what they do here do there is a just and i want to it
it's called the possible because the going came up with a course without of course
the notion of conjugate priors but
none the less
well done fifty years ago
the very special case of just anyone
now what happens if we do this
look at that
here by the way there is
error here that b
o point one five
so what i do
these are my six different outcomes these are the actual
right like to estimate will give me
the probability is that
max estimate
when my total number of occurrences six
i will give my point one five point seven and so on here
so what you can see is it moves things more towards the uniform distribution
of everywhere one six
if i have one hundred additional pseudocount
it's actually very close to one sixth of
absolutely and i'll be showing you some pictures on exactly that after so what you
immediately covered is the downside of this approach
so the upside is we managed to get away with the local started in the
in the likely case with advice OK
in the unlikely case whether sustained it'll take us a lot longer to pick things
so what you describe is a little bit like the situation we're really golgi
goes to some gambling den where they're going to cheat on him
and then he will lose a lot of money until he realizes what had their
cheating on me and not just unlucky
so what you should be doing therefore you know if you may be
go to some
officially sanctioned co because you know well you can assume
i everything fair
like improv is a large prior like this
fact some somewhat any place they should be pro using something like this think because
they cannot trust it very much
so what it really means is
that's a strong prior well in this case brings us closer to
in this case the uniform distribution but in general
well the rest is most likely
if we have a problem for instance what do you want to recognise only the
numbers that were said to form you have only the numbers so you don't need
to go through four you will directly model the words
which only numbers
but in the general case you will pass true phoneme so we're going to define
the phoneme model so in hmm
that is going to be too we hope to be able to generate all the
the sequences
a rather data corresponding to
to the corresponding phonemes
and this is my HMM and look at the
it has the particle are
relation is what we call it
left to right model
basically saying that well this time going by
and where you're here you can either stay given the amount of time of goal
eventually go out
and because we
we make this assumption after twenty years of modelling that the fourteen goes through a
chunk of small
steps which follow the same distribution
so now
if i want to
to model a given some words
let's suppose the word is cat
if i have the phoneme c
defining a infinity
let's suppose i decided that my language to have these phonemes well before the word
count simple concatenation
of the very phonemes
and that creates a new HMM which is the concatenation of three hmm
where i just need to find these values these connectors which is quite easy to
and i now have the word
and then i can do that for sentences so is if you have a given
sentence you tell me the sentences cats don't like dogs
this is a sequence of words and hence the sequence of words on a sequence
of full of of sequence of phonemes so it's a sequence of phonemes and for
each one you have an HMM so i can create
sequence of nature which is going to be one single HMM and that's hmm
represents one sentence
cats don't like dogs
now what i want is to find the parameters of these these combine hmm that
maximize the likelihood of having generated that sentence
and i can do that for all sentences
and that's only the training part now
when a new sentence arrive i want to know what was pronounced and that's where
the viterbi algorithm
becomes important because now what i want to know is what was used to a
sequence of
for me that was pronounced
for given to sentence
so what i will do is that
to simplify we supposed to exemplify will have created a very big hmn
of all the possible words so
this is the following
a sequence of phoneme corresponding to one word
then you have a sequence of phoneme corresponding to another word and all the words
here of my language
but remember that there is copies so the number of parameters is not so big
because you may have
well you may have an a here in a year in a here all the
same it's just that you join them but the number of parameters is related to
the number of twenty on the number of workers project
you create a very very big HMM which has a number of words by the
number of warnings
there were times number of states performing times the number of parameters state
and you are going to search for a given set that's the best buy that
would go a long that you seem to connect back so
this sentence is a sequence of words or your question post to that here
generate the word
go back
generate in other words the back
narrative work until if you're going to search for the best part wrong this
connected graph
with loops
it doesn't matter
because all these loops can be
unfolded in time
and you're going to use this viterbi algorithm to find out of course this is
not really efficient so we have
lots of more efficient going to do that but i'm not going to talk about
the this is the main
i d
of how you do speech recognition
so that's very
of course
doing being able to do that is one thing when you do research you like
to know how good is your model
so you need to have a kind of loss function
and and in speech recognition what most people use is what they call the word
error rate so the you have model the
if view this is sequence of words
and if you want to compare that sequence of words with the correct sequence of
words but the correct sequence of words may have more
or less words
and it's not so simple to compute the
the distance between two sequences of words so they use the technique based on
on something which is used to compare two sequences of strings the strings of various
which is called the edit distance has also many other names
in the end with that technique you can compete with the the word error rate
which is going to be the number of
of words that you have inserted that we're not in the original sequence
plus the number of words that you forgot to say
plus the number of words that you
substitute with another
all the possible errors that you may have
divided by the true number of words which were expected that's going to give you
there were direct which you have to be careful it's not
nine nice measure because it it doesn't it's the bounded
it is bounded more than one in fact so
you have to be careful with that
we're now in the last part of the talk
which is now we can talk about with similar process
at least at
we talked about the germans and in moved in so it remains are very handy
to model
one single sequence of information
on the other hand in multimodal processing you often have several sequences of information going
true at the same time for instance you may have the device
in the image of someone talking like now
you may want to model these two streams jointly may have more than two you