and it's relatively elementary
i was hoping that maybe also some other parts we can do together are you do do some things
when i weight here and then we saw them together on the whiteboard
so let's see how it goes
this is
so let me see if i think
so uh
i think this two
cases are relatively simple and maybe we can start
with these two so i'm going to
show you the
definition again maybe you have them you have it on the slides if you don't
know them is not recommend that you briefly write it down so a positive definite
kernel is a kernel
it's symmetric and that has this property that
x i x and
in x and for all real numbers
this quantity here is non-negative
so if you want to if you don't have it already maybe briefly write this down
and dr
could not gonna need this one down here now
so i
move to
this thing here
and now i would like you to try to prove because usually when one sees definition one rated but maybe
one doesn't understand the details before one has worked with it a bit so i
wanted to work a bit with this definition
and end
and want do first to these two things
one is
if we define a function of two arguments
like this
where we
assume that five is a mapping
from some nonempty sets carry graphic x into a dot product space age
so we define a mapping like this
we don't claim is a positive definite kernel
then from this definition is already follows
that this kernel is positive definite
so i wanted to prove that this thing here satisfies the equation is required
he inequality required for a positive definite kernel that's the first thing
and the second thing is
i would like to
also show that this thing here
is a positive definite kernel
so what is this thing
it's a kernel defined on sets
and in be of finite arbitrary finite subsets of x
and the value of case defined to be the sum of all
uh in the metric could also
the queen we now assume that case is that positive definite kernel
so we take the sum over all these positive definite kernels
over the sets in being
and it turns out that this is again a positive definite kernel
this time on this finite subsets
so in the first one we don't assume anything about kay we just assume
that phi such a mapping and the second one we assume
that this small kay
there is a positive definite kernel
so i'll give you a few minutes and try to play around
we didn't i'm not gonna force anyone to do it but
i will ask for volunteers that in
if you want
how many have solved the problem
okay so i'm not going to ask you to get up so you can you can be
open in assessment
so i give you a bit more time
and i think we we should actually do the second one later because if we have the
prove it
based on what you know already is a bit complicated and later on it would be much easier
so just to the first one hour take optional if you want you contrite
uh i give you a bit more time to do the first one
these half done it
so how many of you have so the first one
they are quite common denotes different concept from mark twain
this analysis
quite those to the right but anyway this is what's included in the list
it just depends on
might have different sections daniel
the first single concept
people might have different beliefs
but from the comments and they have the mark twain
this is why we
that means you to something conceptually more concepts
OK great so namestring
there's namestring but are
a whole lot of other predicates that relates strings to concepts directly into these
all these over here can relate to people
i don't have the hip-hop moniker but if i did it with p
listed in the cave with the predicate hip-hop moniker
and then these are for
sort of inanimate objects
so named files
the atomic symbol of an element that serve to predicate
like mainstreaming in the sense that relates the concept history
cwm head injury CCW in KB that means conceptual work this lot of interesting
work done by philosophers on conceptual works
i recommend browsing around in that area
a conceptual work is
like a novel
their predicates for
talking about the content of the novel
OK will be
self-explanatory OK so this just shows that it's not all namestring there are other namestring
like predicates
but the
you know
with the life of
these are all specs
string indexing
specs of string indexing slot
the collection
of binary
i could on string indexing slot
OK so here's an example of generative and acyclic
it's asserted
my family name is
my given name is also the
we should do this with the
yes KB
what's to this was to keep it
o but i might not be in and out
and then it's derived
my name string is elizabeth coppock through
a rule that can can it's the family name
given names in language like hungarian where the
given names follows the
family names
the rule for deriving the full name
would be different so this would be an english specific rules for generating forming
the well actually it should hold
it should hold in the hungarian and
perhaps the
the name string
it was discovered
couple course the best
it it's only the only have rules in english team
if that rule were asserted in the hungarian MT then it would show up here
among the
right from the phd in
two thousand nine it generates
it was discovered come up phd
using the fact that
i got my ph d in two thousand nine
also this
so if you click on this assertion was the phd
and then
click on arguments
it'll tell you the rules and the fact that we're used to describe to derive
the search
it is this rule
the first is phd level that the collection of people with phds
given me
a the person's given name
which given the
if you could have a given name
family name
carlos space
ph d
and get question mark name plus this predicate is defined in code
the namestring persons
concatenated string
and it knows
these things called because they were asserted
call opaque indicates that it was
not computed
using regular secretions
all right so
the next kind of predicate is
the kind that relates so word two concepts
denotation is the prototypical example of that
it takes four arguments actually
part of speech for the word
integer indicating the word sense
don't get me started about
that i i will mostly ignore it
and then
there are four is the concept that the word
so let's look at some examples
alright this is
all the things you can use
as a part of speech argument
there are all the parts of speech
in the KB
point is six i think
ring theword
it's asserted to be an english word
in the english MT it asserted that its singular form is writing
and it's definitive form ring because ring can be either a noun or verb
so now in
he gave me a ring
the verbal end
the bell will ring
as a verb
the first sentence
it means
emitting sound the collection of
sound emitting events
according to this assertion
as account now
the first sentence which is the same as
per cent
it means a sound
and novels
the collection of audible sound
as another set has as it can
is a ring shaped object
there's something has
if you
they there there's seemingly infinite can i stay way
this is my chance to mention the name
the two names winner hot
so we hop was about to that should be mentioned too
we are half is about matrices that
that's a start
and go on forever singly infinite
but not dublin doubly infinite is the one where for we could call the fourier
matrices we want
as for it
this is perfect
where singly infinite we would have had to have a smart idea
this this factors well into you times l
that this is here's here's you want to know that we half idea
we remark these are constant diagonal right
we are half idea was that i can factor into
upper time lower
not i winner harbor
ah so upper
and lower
and these will be constant diag
that's the thing that's the thing that this
the that multiplying that times that
to give this
will be no different from find that second row times the second column to give
the two
two two and
you see that the is at least you can hope that
the winner of factorizations preserves this constant diagonal which is what everybody is living in
the fourier domain
but it gives an upper times slower
whereas when we did when we took that matrix so what what what if you
try for the lower times up
actually that's what we did
we did the factorisation you remember the factorisation of the matrix k is not going
remove this
devilish problem
and the q are idea
square root filter idea
just just to complete this book because i think maybe it's worth completing its it's
a mantis evading here for a stuff but probably
this is a good time to say what what happened you remember factorisation two of
our favorite
into LDA you what these numbers look like
what did the pivots look like and what these things look like
remember there was a
well when the pivots for this thing
three have four thirds crewmember
the pivots were approaching one
and what was the l l had ones on the diagonal and had minus
half minus two thirds minus three four
so on
because it was symmetric you was the transport
so these are approaching one
minus one
what i'm saying here is that
l times you which is sort of the wrong order is not the perfect order
but it's approaching
it converges
the perfect one the
as i go down the list
i get
minus one one
in in the limit in l
and in the u i get minus one
i get that this is sort of what i'm
what i'm converging to of a minus ones and ones and ones and minus one
those are
the the
here is that
this was the l in the u
only in the limit
whereas if i switch put in the right order
in the other order
which is the right one for winter harbor
there there are correct from the all the way along
you see that because actually we sell that factorisation that
so that
it was red it one one one one one
minus one minus one minus one minus one song
one one one one one minus one minus one minus one OK so do that
publication in the in the order you times l
what do you get you get two
yet i minus one you get k
so i should have shown you that example from the start
that if making gold forever
so that was the winner have applied
and actually now on the amount of having got this far unintentionally on we hop
we're dysphoria come in
why don't we see it it never hurts like see an idea a month
so we're dysphoria coming of fourier a would say OK what's
what's the
the polynomial
get into the frequency domain
so when i look at that in the or we we're looks at in the
frequency domain he'd say OK we have one minus one times
each the
minus i omega
and two for the constant term
and i minus one is the
plus i omega
that would be
are whatever i want to call it the frequency response function or transfer function symbol
everybody is that it's the right thing
to look at for for that kind of matrix
and what is and what what i have here
following the same reliable one for the constant however minus either omega
and what i have here
everyone from the diagonal and i minus e to the minus sign maker from
lower diagonal and what is suppose
a product of it so we never ended up factoring polynomials
that's the point
is that
that you take the polynomial for k
that's of what
in other words you go into the frequency domain
in the frequency domain you have some simple little polynomials of infinite matrix
the factor that polynomial into
you know into a series of positive power series going one way
and then a power series in the inverse going the other way
and that tells you well in your
and of course
the whole thing depends on this constant diag
so common could
and come would lose the structure the simplicity of the structure
the flooding through the state space
time domain
but of course he gained enormously by having a much much more general
is there a question or discussion i i hadn't intended to
speak about this but it so highly we're kind of in between
having seen the very first lectures these this k
now seeing
much more general stuff
but then see in the future are returning to this
constant diagonal we're probably winner of mentioned again but
it's kind of fun to see here as
having mentioned this
factorisation UL in the reverse order in that crazy problems
just popped into my mind is exactly the factorisation that we are
it's only again
that that's winter harbor
we are half deals with
one boundary
matrix comes up and it stops at zero
so we are half operates on a half
four a operates on the whole no boundary at all
or on a periodic one were repeats and repeats and repeats of the boundary is
and again you cannot use a function that is one when the mean is in
the box and zero otherwise the average that's function
and the the posterior distribution over hypotheses
questions that you have
can usually be expressed as expectations
questions of or what should i believe about this variable
given the data
gentleman what element that someone gives you a nasty distribution they give you some functions whose average values that what
so that's the set up
and now we can forget about clustering because motivated to want to solve these two problems
just in case you don't care about clustering gonna give you one more problem that
can be expressed in this way
well that's why i was right
you you know the problem
so this
the problem of understanding nanomagnets
nanotechnology is really cool
so let's say the magnet
and you've got
area will be energy america
energy depends on the state's oldest remains and unanimous
so let's call x the state-of-the-art nanomagnets
and this is a tiny little minus
made after ten by ten by ten thousand so only
thousands in that tiny
or maybe it's a
plane objective made at that time to use it as a
one thousand students
we've got ourselves
the energy function
is the energy of those things that are in state
what might that look like
well maybe it's a nice simple and
in energy
and all couplings between pairs
it these acts
x is it takes on the value minus one plus one
so at least in space minus one
and binary variables
given the couplings between spins andy
inverse temperature beta
it's a minus beta
divided by normalizing constant which depends on it
the couplings where
these couplings
you all
couplings jay determine energy
in the following so i have a sum over all spins
so some so and things so
so end
the coupling data
prime x and
so that's a fairly standard expression before
the energy of a man with
second order coupling expense
what sort of things that someone wants to know about the nanomagnets
you might want to know what's the average energy
of the things under the distribution take the overall distribution in red
this is red
he is relevant
it's not that's just the sum
got fairly high standards
read this
but is nasty because actually if i tell you okay his the coupling matrix and
say what is the average energy
you'll struggle to answer questions you could try to do a complete enumeration
if you wanted to do like you actually have some overall value
that's referred
the average energy
on but we also we're working
in the same feature space
actually corresponds to the our probabilistic models corresponds to exactly two lin lin model
living instead of in input space living in the feature space
which is
which is which corresponds to this kind
these things are
i extremely close to each other
OK sorry about that so the question is why do i sometimes right
p of star
and sometimes i don't write your star
so this is just sloppy
this is the only ever write down things are probabilities i let p
i apologize for anything that looks as though it could be a probability is the
OK so that was the was the
i mean function
it's a little bit at the at the at the peak of the covariance function
of the
other covariance function
the other term here
then the
the covariance function evaluated at x star and actor itself
minus this this this term here which is the quadratic terms
depending on the
this the vector of covariances between has been put in the training
and the inverse matrix in the middle and this
better again
what this thing that question the brain about what do you mean by a of
text documents are
this is this is just the priors
the variance of the function
this is the variance of the function at x star this is what we what
so if it is invariant because the covariance between identical argument that the variance of
the function without any reference to the training set the prior variance
and then we have the posterior variance
it's going to be the prior variance minus positive for
that means we always if we if we get observations that always reduce the variance
how much will reduce the variance that depends on this term
so it's it's a quadratic form
it depends on the
on the inverse of the covariance matrix evaluated at
all the training input come on the twenty with of all the all pairs of
writing input
this is the noise level
and that the matrix unit this matrix and then
it's depends on the vector of covariances between x starring x
let's say that we have to test input which happens to be very far away
from the training input
the covariance function of the talk about so far the covariance function words e to
the minus distance where between input
so that if the if if they have a large distance between each other and
the grants will be almost zero
i mean is that these terms we always zero these terms will be able to
i mean the whole thing would be almost zero
what does that mean what that means that the posterior variance is almost the same
as the five
it means that the training data didn't tell you very much about what's going on
conversely if you think the largely large covariance between a start next
then this thing can be a sizeable
a sizable contribution and the posterior variance can be much smaller than the prior variance
in the data to a lot of what's going on
and this thing will always remain positive visual words about
OK so that means that we can sort of we can sort of we can
look at this expression and we can sort of understand the they seem to have
a reasonable
up until now i just focused on the on the predictions what about the marginal
likelihood what about it and we and we can compute
what is the
but the probability of the of the of the model and we can try out
different things also matter now of course i want to show you examples with a
particular covariance function
it has a very small properties
so we should worry about what could be my model
interesting function
but now the the the marginal likelihood
is again just the has a thousand four
remember it's the interval of the
the prior times the likelihood people have gotten pawned although
some of the infinite dimensional gaussians come there but then the the all the people
in many variables are marginalized out when you do the modernization
the marginal likelihood
so the so they actually expression you get when you when you do that goes
into the
as the form written not that consists of a are in the log domain of
because it looks pretty
three terms
the first time
i call the data for term
the reason i call that the term is the only term that depend on the
and i can think of the data as being the observations of the of the
function value not the existence of the axes are
consider the
of course
k matrix itself
depends on the on the input
recall that the benefits
and then as the second term here is called complexity penalty
and i had just you
the minute why called the complexity penalty
and then there is a large and that was very boring
the marginal
likelihood that that should somehow tell us something about how to select a different model
essentially consists of these two terms
something to do with how where we're getting the data and one with
it has to do with with the complexity
OK so now
when we want to do learning in processes then
the learning
corresponds to or or involves finding out what the property should be of the underlying
function but if learning amounts to trying to find a good covariance functions
we can talk about you i want to show you one particular variant
but you have to put the covariance function somehow encodes the the properties of the
so this is the situation that we're not really says it is large and we
also use kernels
so that you can also get very huge matrix the first technique you want to
do or you don't
china is of course a subset of this is very simple and often effective just
like clear consensus on when they're going to do you want to try k nearest
founded in classification
but if you have a very large data sets
very large as it
if you find out the training is going to be
very low subsampling is what you wanted to find just try smaller subset in the
so is
and the starting from this we can do all kinds of
more sophisticated techniques but i'm going to show some
this is just one of the
one extension so we use the that you want to go straight find version that
is always more complicated to be useful for your application if you're a citizen that's
the as it is only doing subsampling is that we can we will more
all kinds of approximation techniques but this one is
it's quite simple to increase the with so we say all we can source
we can solve very
that still problem
so why don't we separate the two different parts
for example
he said that they had to ten parts
which for the first part
OK this is only one has already so suppose training is short because the training
training is the reason is that the new company the complexity is not
this usually a hundred
or more
so so training only what is that they actually like
i you only a very small amount of ten of time compared the training hope
so each in the first part
and we obtain a set of support vectors right
but there's property saying that support vectors may be only a small subset
the only a small subset y will we hope that the situation so we collect
support vectors then
we try another which the second part class
the support vectors from the training the first
so this is slightly more
so more but
still only a a little bit more than one test data so from these
we get a set of support vectors
we we call it has to be it all seems to certain part
so it is and you all ten past action
well this is an approximation
it is also quite simple
the problem is you don't know what it is always faced solving
hold your problem you know even for this still problems
the total number of support vectors is so small that you have something to do
is OK there is don't need to use such technique
then there are also some ways of doing this is OK if the number of
days is is so
it is so large
instead of doing the stuff simply by the title a little bit more is to
select some good points
so i only the only each training set of good points
four on the other hand you can say that you are trying to remove some
necessary points
so you get a smaller smaller said please use how can you say him because
kenya is as simple is a list right is first
then you can always use of any other heuristics as selecting these
this is the so-called good points
there are also many papers
i think that's the method
just two
so i think
that is also the question so you can have these classes were members of themselves
and that is where begins to really hurt lot it's not so that if you
have instances
classes class of level one can be instances of classes level two and was able
to convince class level three
and so on this vertical stratification which you could not cross the borders that way
so this is also known three to get clean
and there is a paper by you and you can insist on the stratified first
of all so that is going somewhere in the middle here it's more out
but less than of fools
the more stuff
o three
these are all
but it would be
somewhere in between
so just to give you OK a
this is important comment this has been engineering the proper way so this is really
syntactically layered that if you have a legal
OWL lite statement it's also allow the statements also legal full statement not to around
and it's also semantically probably
so any valid OWL conclusion from the set of light axioms is alive actions also
said about the elections and then conclusion is also valid OWL DL conclusion
and the same level i
so you can in no way so we are great
you can start with a simple language
later on decide you need ritual language or you do you could save you can
also use tools in the same way
so i'll
the tools will do the right thing even if it's only a light expressions
so this is probably the layering is really well done and there is this is
the first WTC
spec with a theorem in the theory says that
is there in really
OK now let's quickly look at these awards in these languages or in these layers
let's do them all three at the same time so this is what we already
seen from ISP subclasses hierarchy individuals domain and range of properties in conjunction conjunction is
just saying that you're a member of two classes at the same time
if is OK i'm human and physical objects or in special cases of of
i'm an academic and father member of two classes
therefore member of
academics who are father the intersection of the two
but that's all you have schema in OWL lite you can
talk about
equality and inequality that's a very big step
various people have said to me well if only i like this idea schema plus
this we would have been during this cardinality restrictions are so saying that something is
at most two were at least forty two property values is restricted to the case
of zero one which is enough to talk about required optional properties as single valued
multivalued properties
so the vocabulary is expressible in just over zero and values you could talk about
inverse transitive symmetric properties stargate example being the author these are domain restrictions
in the sense of of values from a particular domain for a particular property has
to come from this
this particular class if not you have consistency
so that was allvaluesfrom value saying that you have a particular
so that
now you as it is basically a tool for linear algebra
so the negation which is called the class disjunctions junior class you could about arbitrary
not just about zero and one five four two
of forty two
in practice i've seen ontologies for the number two appears right like parents but i
haven't seen any
ontology with the number seven appears very often
and you can define times but enumeration was see example it sometimes it's important it's
impossible to define the clusters by properties how do you define the seven days a
you can only defined by just listing
have such low air
the reason they have such low weight
is because they were correctly classified on the first two rounds of boosting
so we don't really care so much about them
so it makes sense that
they should have low weight and that we should be effectively ignoring them
on the third round of boosting
OK so now we run boosting for three rounds
and the final step
it is to take those three weak classifiers and combine them
and to the final combine classifiers
so here's a to one
h two
and h three
and we wait them by alpha one
alpha two and alpha three
we add them together we think the weighted sum of those weak classifiers
we take the sign with the result is
and that gives us our final combined classifier which turns out to be
this function here which classifies everything in this
upside down l shape
as positive
and everything in the pink region as
so we started out with these three weak classifiers
and each one of them missed three out of the ten examples so each one
hundred thirty percent area
with respect to the original data
but we ended up
in only three rounds with something correctly classifies all ten examples
four questions
what is the u
the point
well because we're missing
it would be classified as negative here negative here
so these two negative for that upper right corner
outweigh the positive for the upper right corner there
that is the half plane take into account the weights
what we're trying to do on each round of boosting is we're trying to
minimize the weighted error rate
OK so
so for instance by the best example of the last last round
where these three examples
i have very low weight
and so were motivated to choose this week classifier because it has very low error
rate because
it's only missing these three examples which have really low error
you would not for instance one to choose
h one again
on this round because if you did
we would be missing these three points which have fairly higher
three using the waiting to guide the selection of the weak classifiers
right right that certainly could happen they could have
high weight
one of the examples and so one of the classifiers can have very high weight
and that could lead to bad
decisions so in principle that could happen is that you're asking
yes in principle that could happen so
it doesn't happen on this contrived example but
the bigger question is what can we say about it in general right
so we want to argue that it doesn't that tends not to happen
right so so the formula so that formula for alpha t is giving more weight
to that classifiers weak classifiers which have low error rate
which is true
but even so a priori it seems like a lot of bad things can happen
with this algorithm so what i want to try to argue next to that
that there are some interesting things we can say about the algorithm
well in this case so we don't really know what
but the question so where in the world of these weak classifiers coming from
so we're leaving that deliberately as a black box so they can take this method
and combined it with any
method that you sitting around for doing that in this particular example
i was always finding the weak classifier of this particular form
which has the lowest weighted area
OK with searching over all of them there are many
and finding the best one
if you keep updating the weights because going the the biggest point example would you
know sometimes chasing out
yes that's the problem so let me come back to that question was about outliers
and does does and this time cause is now a lot of problems with outliers
in this asylum come back to that point
OK good
OK yes o
clearly this is a contrived example we have ten examples in three rounds of boosting
works great on this contrived example
likely say in general
the first natural question is
what can we say about how well it does on the training set itself
so here's what we can prove about this
OK this is the theorem we can prove
so suppose we run the algorithm that i just described to you
and we get these ar plenty on every round of boosting
and then we just rewrite that air raid in a slightly different form
try this thing out
so let me write that area as one-half minus gamma t
remember you just randomly you'll be right exactly half the time
so gamma t is just how much better than random guessing we're dealing with thinking
of gamma t is a small the positive number one percent five percent ten percent
something like that
this is what we can prove
we can prove that the training year
of the final combined classifier
is that most
this kind of airy formula in terms of the one season
which can be re written as this slightly nicer formula in terms of the gamma
in which
using a standard approximation
can be upper bounded by this form which is the former like the best for
in terms of motivating
which says that the training areas that most
e to the minus two times the sum of the squares of the gamma t
OK so how how can we think about that last found
so you popular these high energy and then it would get either here or here
so you can populate these
for example the first spectrum that i showed you on the first day twenty one
so you have this but it very difficult it is to be able to form
so this correspondence between sixty
to spin twenty six
so this has been up to in military one ninety three
concerning fission isomers many predictions have been made in actinides so
fission isomers it appearing i so all the three kv system that are going
the fish and the one
so what is calculated here the energy of the state respect my respect this one
is in in here
you have experimental data the open
compare these experiments the black dots
so first will see these global decrease
of these isomers so this is decreasing
and here you have three to spatial nuclei
where you have
the states which is below this one
so what does it mean
it means that
with this picture
we have predicted that we have to go from ground states of grants the nuclear
which have very huge deformation
but in fact you have to be careful and you have to calculate the lifetime
of the states
and this has been done in fact they don't
very few lifetime
so that's why we cannot say that they states that there
smaller like reason and so they may not survive
as bound states
but that presented that because it's very controversial question has been much discussed
in the community
because superdeformed ground states has been predicted behavior in elements
and in fact in the last ten seems that is not the case
but it's very important because
the superheavy elements they are detected by the flood gates
so i tried to get has no small amount time that fish
but imagine that you have the superdeformed superheavy elements
so then it means that it we've got to feature very easy so then you
have to find something else to detect it
on friday there will not be
a good way to detect it
and also
if you want to produce it
you have to take care of these
so that's why
i think it's an important question now it's concerning the deformation
the superheavy elements
these isomers do also have a role
in vision
what we call resonant transmission
when you have different states in different well if you look at the prose sections
so this is the section
depending on the neutron energy energy
of this here consider the energy of the state here
used in different
and structure
this structure there really are when you have two states
in the different ways of the seminar
it's something resonant tunnelling through a barrier
and the structure are very important when you are
when you want to have a precision for different
now shape coexistence so
it's also related to push
shape isomers but now it's
it's also related to shape so there are many nuclei where
different european states have been observed
they have been observed almost the same energy
so this is the schematic view here where you have zero place here to request
always the same energy
there are associated with two different bands
and you see that they are predicted to be blatant trolling
so the reason for that that you get different gaps for it and already formations
they are in competition
so a situation very complicated where we don't know
if it's spherical prolate coordinates so very precise calculations should be performed
and the experiments so experiments have been done for example here i have been using
spare and so radioactive beams of krypton
they have used call on the citation so that populated many benefits
and then after calculated
the quadrupole moment and they have seen that they have opposite signs so
that means that they have different information
of you who are have some dynamical systems background their applications of these in a
new area in the control community called how systems in which one has a mixture
of dynamical models that which among time and one wants identify
a model for each one of them
let me get back on two
well the mathematics is and try to
describes a little bit what the problem is
one is given a set of points
but in multiple subspaces
the number of subspaces for most of the time is actually going to be known
but it actually can be can be known as well
the dimensions of the subspaces are unknown
the basis for every subspaces and no and the segmentation of the data points is
so this is given the data points in one has to solve for
all these things
this is
and at least this has been considered traditionally chicken and egg problem
if you just think about the
the two lines example that i given here
the venue which point belongs to which line
i could easily defeat one nine
for every
if i knew the equations of the lines
i could easily
cluster the data point by assigning every point to the closest line
the big challenge was that
i don't know the
equations of the line
i don't know the segmentation of the day
so what should i do first
so naturally
this has motivated
a wide variety of iterative algorithms
that's a i don't know which to first so let's say i have some segmentation
that somebody is given to me
given that segmentation
i could solve for the basis for the subspace
given the basis i could resolve the segmentation
and then i could just a back and forth
until it converges
and one can prove that is that it converges and essentially be the ideas behind
these are essentially the same ideas and the k means algorithm for standard classrooms
can also be
done using probabilistic approaches such as the expectation maximisation
which essentially that's exactly the same thing except that there is
a probability underlying probability distribution for each other
group in this case for the noise distribution orthogonal to the subspace
but essentially the idea is the same one starts with a certain prior
of what the segmentation is like
given the prior one solves for the parameters meaning one solves for the basis for
the subspace in an optimal fashion and that's called the maximisation step n given the
parameters one can go back and we compute with the membership of what's the probability
that eight point belongs to one of the groups
and by iterating this procedure again one obtains an optimal solution
the main challenges that
one of these approaches
either optimization based or statistically basically correct and one can prove convergence first the convergence
is very slow
and second and most importantly
although segmentation problems our optimisation problems with
a lot of local minima
so this thing that you're minimizing is not convex and therefore it matters quite a
lot where you start
if you start in the wrong place you may hit the wrong solution
many of these techniques for them to work you have to really do multiple restarts
you start with some random initialisation you iterate you convert and you repeat many many
times until you happy with the final
it is precisely this issue of initilisation what is the main motivation for looking for
alternative approaches there are
more geometric
in a sense if just look at the picture
at least with not a lot of nice
it is rather apparent that
there should be a way of fitting to align to the set of points
i mean i had to do from high school how to ft
aligned to the set of points but how do i fit to simultaneously without knowing
the membership
and just in a purely algebraic way
in nineteen ninety one one
motivated by the computer vision problem of motion segmentation
the first direct solution was introduced in that it was for the case of two
planes in r three
and it was shown that
it can be solved with some
polynomial algebra type techniques
the second technique
and this has been very popular over the past few years in computer vision
is what is called factory station approaches
by factorisation approaches it's meant essentially say the same thing to remember that the solution
to PCA is essentially factoriza matrix
using the value the composition to get
the basis
maybe what we could think
how they have multiple subspaces maybe there is some sort of generalisation of the singular
value decomposition that will allow me to do this
and unfortunately the answer or at least until today
the answer is no
two groups you get tense rather than matrix and so how do you do the
factory station becomes a big problem but in one particular case and this was the
beauty of this approach that was also proposing ninety one in popularizing ninety eight
is that in the particular case which is when the subspaces have equal dimensions
number one
number two there are perpendicular to each other
and number three the intersection is only the origin meaning and this is what i
call here independent subspaces in that particular case
you can solve the segmentation problem using the singular value decomposition of the
but that's not the general case
that's not the case i mean
subspace is not to be able to begin with
they may clearly be intersections
for instance two planes in r three they intersect in a line
they will not just intersecting the origin
and it's a r
the dimensions may be different this one
what i will talk today is precisely
how do you solve this problem analytically
if it receives no destined for
for b
it's going to say OK this is it is going to compute with it's going
presumably wants to send it along whatever the shortest happiness and we'll talk about how
the next step routing is actually deciding which things should be there but for example
it might have helped to the next point towards the center c
it might have one is the next slide so a to b is using it
using l two
and a to see it's using l one
now node
is going to civil wars to throughout the
it's going to have to root through either b or c
and so for now it's just a around one and then it's going to around
to see
it's going to allow c to go in for the pattern the
directed e well we can again you can either have b or c but let's
say maybe wants to round b because has a shorter path so right l two
so this is just a very simple example and you can see that any time
a wants to send a packet it has the next top introduce for every destination
so this is a very simple and this is sort of
a high level the way before works
of course there are some other details associated with
getting forwarding
to work properly in order to talk about how forwarding actually works at the interaction
between these lay in the in the
interaction between these layers what i wanna do is just give you some examples of
what the packet headers look like four different kinds of particles are used in the
real world so
we're talking about here this is the ITV for headers remember i p
is a protocol that runs at the network layer
and this header has the following information so
what i've shown here down the left side is the sequence of
words so these are thirty two bit thirty thirty two bit words that i just
broken up the bit by number along the top so
the first sort of word has some so has information about the version of the
protocol the running and so in this case the version to be
four because this ITV for there's new
IP protocol that is being in the in the process of being deployed called IP
six which is sometimes you referenced
there's a header link field
it specifies the length header there's TOS field is called this type of service is
typically not used in most packets
and then there's a packet length which is the entire length of the whole package
not just like the header so this is fairly should be fairly straightforward except for
the type of service field which you don't need to
paying attention to
so the next field is the there's this
so next to the idea is this identification the next
by the next word has identification
flags and fragment offset let's this look at the next one and the next one
has time to live and intra college texts
important field lighting on what the identification field contains which is why i stalling but
basically the so identification field
so there's flight so let's just talk about the other fields will come back to
the addition of our members of the
the flags field is the flags field simply contains some information about whether this package
has been
has been fragmented or should be fragmented so fragmentation something that the package this this
package can be split into multiples of packets you need to worry about it too
and the fragment offset says if this has been split into these packets these fragments
then this is the number of fragments being transmitted
so they interesting ones that come in the next row so we have the time
to live flag the end-to-end and protocol checks so that time to live flag is
the time to live field is sometimes abbreviated ttl
and this is it's time to live with a little bit of a strange name
for basically what this says is as the packet is being forwarded to the network
we're going to decrement the time to live by one
and every step forward into the network and at the time delivery to zero for
going to stop for this so the reason we care about i believe is that
there can sometimes be out there that can sometimes be loops in our foreign graphs
suppose that we have set this up so they sent messages destined for
say e to c eighty thousand messages destined three forty per se
and see also that c sent messages destined through e for a that would be
a loop that would be a problem so we were trying to avoid forming these
loops when we run when we do our routing protocol that they're going to be
certain situations when nodes fail for example the loops can occasionally occur we use the
time to live field to eliminate those
the next thing is the and the and particles we and and particles specification of
next is specification of which and and protocol
we should forward this message on two
so i'll talk about that more second and then there's the checksum field which can
it is the which which can be used to determine whether the message was fully-formed
although it turns out that in most cases an IP this field probably is used
so and then there's the source address and destination address so these are IP addresses
the and identify the end point of the PAC
and finally there are some additional optional information which
you can specify a a huge range of different things that can be up to
forty four bytes in this case
you don't need to worry about it and then finally there's the payload which is
the actual message was sent from the and then later into the IP layer
so what you see happening here if we look at a diagram of
with the interface between the
with the interface between the end and layer and the web the interface between the
network layer the link layer is
so we have
are let's just look at our three layer and layer
we have our network layer
we have really clear
and one of the things that we can pick out here is that knows that
this we have this and the empirical that's actually in our IP packets what this
means is that if i have a network protocols like IP this running here
very low-tech
very high tech
and i will start
with myself which is very low-tech
and that is this
i was sitting in my office and i said to myself she would like to
so i took a pencil and i just get
very roughly
the sinusoidal
right here
and i know according to the solutions you accept
that these beats these
particles must lie on that
and c one is that the choice of the amplitude of the sinusoid
in the second mode
you pick another value for forty amplitude stacey two
then he beats have to rely on that
sinusoid and so on
what you will see however
is that these beats i connected with straight wires
so you will not see those nice arcs
what you'll see
of course this
the red lines
are the actual strings
so for instance if you go to the second
we call that the second
monic if you like
notice that this point you on this point here
never reached the amplitude c two
sinusoid does
and this is true that equation does
but those points will never reach that because their location
as such
but they never make it to the point here
this what standstill then it was intuitive
we had that year
and if you go to higher
particularly the very highest one
it's always out of phase which is so you see that
up down up down up
and again this little
article will never reach the amplitude c five
this one does
this one does not
this one does not this one does not this one but this one does
so as i'm going to show you the simulation we will keep this going
it will be great
this debate
what we may be seeing
so the first thing and going going to show you
one complete oscillation in the normal mode number one
which i have said to be fifteen
second which they help
you're just model all
has guided me greatly
in this
so let me
first of all
give was the right
light conditions
and you know i will start
the last fifteen seconds
i have given the amplitude
two which is very large and of course it's unrealistic these high and it but
i wanted to see
the relative position of these particles
there we go
you all seem to make one complete oscillation
that of course is no surprise
i think only one will stop now and will be exactly twice will start thank
you don't want
i'm going to show you the second one
and i give the same amplitude so c two i give it to
and i want you to count
how many oscillations it makes before it comes to stop
well can be exactly fifteen seconds
so we'll have to agree
that the number of oscillations that makes is now one point nine
missus the two you will not get back to the
the complete also
so you're going to look at
this mode
so these two particles will never reach the value two
two is marked here
it will go down
down and
stop just short of two also
so that no
make sure
the first one zero
now we get the features
the two
i mean the two
that we will not count
one also relation
well just short of two you can tell that of course
because you don't have that resolution chop stop just short of two
now we go into this one
amplitude of two
and now we're going to come
and you will definitely be able to see
it just missus two point seven five because two point seven five
it's something that you can ibl
so we're going to number
three now
number three
it already has
two interesting points which don't move at all
this point one move
that point one
never reach the plus still in the plus two
and the other two
there we go
this one
it's too
two half
and that's the point seven three just short of two point seven five
there's this number
now we're going to number four
number before this one will stand still
many others
do not have the maximum amplitude of two
we go
three point three five
the last one
before we go into cocktail the
this one
again this point will be close to
this one will never reach that
this will lead to cluster
it doesn't make it to get high
three and a half
it's not
just on the three point five watts
lovely to see you all back again
i'm sorry about missing the sunshine
but you know serious things to be done
the last time we were talking about
how to make
active contour filters that statistical filters working in a space of curves
and we had a bit of digression
in two
filtering with points just
people who haven't come across kalman filters before to see
basic things go on in the kalman filter but now
we want to go back to that space of curves again and see how filtering
works back in the space of curves
you may remember when
what you remember when we were doing the recursive algorithm for fitting curves there was
a regularisation matrix s north terrace bar i think it was called
and i said the the time of that looks a little bit like
the term in a prior distribution over curves so now we want to go back
to that
so now we want to really think explicitly that
in this shape space parameterized by catholics that we have gas distribution
let's say
better began as in otherwise we we start with the kalman filter
over the curves with min x by
and covariance p not
actually this
so i i could sort of set up such a distribution and i could sample
around random from the distribution let's say in the euclidean similarity space which was to
run the full degree of freedom space with the translations rotations and scalings and phi
sample random from this template shape
for distribution with this mean shape and i get
sample bottles like this at different orientations and scales and positions and so on
actually this
it's probably worth mentioning
that given what you've been doing during the week that this is a guassian process
it implies a guassian process over
over curves in some ways it's a bit of
a crude way to do
guassian process
so actually what we have is
if i only neglect the mean of this
and then what we got is
covariance over you know across two points on the curve if you like which has
the form
this is
an exciting experiment from the net
i heard that little cool people do this
this is this is
more interesting than ever
it's pretty isn't it i think
i was a practising this last night and this didn't happen but you read the
dark blue on black writing
very excited
so anyway the point is we implied a marriage
is this what happens when people do this
well the least i won't send a message to microsoft
miss out on that
i got some very exciting new technology over here
i technology
i can't actually see whether ten is
this is an
this is this is a valid and
OK yes so what i actually was attempting to write and who knows what will
ever get a powerpoint presentation back again
was that we've implied
forgetting about the means setting the mean zero something moment just sort of oil mess
we can apply to guassian process of this kind this is the the covariance function
that this parametric
guassian implies and actually
if we were free to to
design covariance functions that in some ways would be more appealing and maybe you guys
really know how to do this now i'm not sure if the whole thing
will carry through because the
only a function of the difference between those two arguments so that's that's that's often
green tea i'm honesty jay
or just just just kate cave tau
and you can see that here in the squared exponential
so in in a picture
what is a stationary kernel
essentially you'll notice at
it doesn't really matter where i am over time the prior looks the same no
matter where i am in time the only thing that matters is is is that
the difference between time points how much how much how much variance there's between time
there are also plenty of nonstationary kernel so
one one on one of my favorite ones that a using example is is that
we process is a standard brownian motion
we remember has
this infinite limit of eighty of a random walk
so that's
has the following that's a jeep
and has the following kernel function
which is the the the mean of other two time points and so you can
see this can be written in stationary way
as the difference between these two time points
this is still a jeep e
and so
here's the pryr
here's the prior in winter process so you can see what's happening
is there these variances growing linearly over time
again this is standard deviation so that's what looks like a square root
variance grows linearly over time and so this is this is nonstationary because what's happening
at time zero war small time the space that you can explorer that you expect
to be exploring is quite a bit smaller than when you further out here
so again in the same way we can just take draws from this nonstationarity
and this looks like familiar draws
a f of other particle diffusing or something like this which is all which is
all very familiar from brownian motion
another interesting non stationary kernel which i think is important connected because if i
because evolve e
all familiar with linear linear kernels
so now
let's say that
let's say that were saying that are regression function fifty
a linear function of tea
with some random random weight w
then there will evaluate out if you evaluate this kernel you've after university i then evaluates out the following
and there is this
growing variance
variance on envelope and you can see then when we take draws from this kernel
you just get you just get straight lines
okay so
building our own kernels
so we've seen
a handful of examples
and there are a number of operations that we can use that will be helpful
in building a kernel why would you want a billion kernel
because in your particular application area you collect this this specific type of data and you say
i really like
i really like some of this feature in some this feature and i'd like to
be able to design my own kernel that's model appropriate
so the first thing is that kernels are linear we saw this when we took
one which are latent
half an hour noise and we add them together
we add those two gy piece together and again got a teepee with covariance with
the kernel function as the sum of these two
it is linear in other words you can add you can add in scale these
two as long as you respect positive scale cause
you can add to kernels together to get another valid kernel
what is interesting is that here
we're talking about adding kernels on on on time
but if we look at a multi dimensional case
we've got
you know latitude longitude we can add kernels better we can we can compose
a multidimensional kernel by adding kernels on each dimension individually so we can have a single kernel latitude
i think we should be you know just on x one this single-dimensional single dimensional
kernel on launched to we can add those two together and i will give us
a multidimensional kernel
the products of kernels are again kernels
integration gives you a kernel for filtering context so if you have here is a cheap e
and we've got some fixed function gene duty
and we integrate across it again this is just this is just a linear operation
then set of tea
that gives us so
that's also a cheapy and has the following kernel
this is just the standard result from
b filtering or signal processing
differentiation again later operation and so this again gives us this again gives the cheap so effort a cheap e
if we take the derivative at over time called at z eighty
then kesey if ti i ti jay
is again
sorry as it is again
the jeep e with the following kernel
one thing is not discussed has as much
is is warping and this comes up in again in geostatistics or the court spatial spatial defamation
but we've talked a lot about
regression in time or this this fixed input space to u x
you can also impose a function in between there are two two two toward your input space
such that if you've got some cheapy half
which is usually if you know fonte
you can make it for age fifty as well and i will again be a jeep
something nice about this is that
because you've
because you have a fixed kernel the kernel is
the kernel is
positive semi definite
in it doesn't care about what the inputs are and so you can you can
mess around quite a bit more with what the input warping
in the periodic kernel that we looked at before r
you could look it that's almost as a squared exponential kernel where we've done some
warping input space on to on a periodic basis
one thing is cool about this i want to point out is that many of these operations preserve joint gaussianity
what i mean say instead let's look at this linear case where we took why
equals at f
plus noise
the respects to a joint gaussianity between all these
so that is why and at and why in an effort and they all remain
jointly guassian that's true linearity that's not true of products but that's true love
all of these other features so differentiation is is an interesting example
so let's take a cheapy on at
end we we see we have this this this this cheapy on the derivative at which recalling see
well it's an interesting fact and that these are still jointly guassian with one another
then for still jointly guassian one another and so that gives us this nice opportunity to
for example if we measure
both the function and its derivative we can still use energy to modeling context
another way to build your own kernel is via the frequency domain
we talk about stationary kernels
so stationary kernel
is positive semi definite
if i have categories
the generic category of paper i have journal papers conference papers and workshop papers
then potentially what i can do
i can go through and say
i can have the different
conditional probability distribution for the acceptance of the workshop paper
rather than
the acceptance
conference paper
are so generic paper so
for these
i would come along and
find the lowest level
and this
where there is distribution defined
and be able to use that for
the conditional probability of whether the papers accepted
now four
learning the class hierarchies the
issue is we
potentially have
first really observable data
and the approach
again too
build the decision tree
the training set
we have
attributes which
flip on
class attribute
and again we can split on
attributes of
entities second but on
papers authors fame
and get out these classes
this is the hidden variable they're going to be
need to be inferred potentially
when i apply this model
at least here what we did was defined over the attributes observed in the training
set which are the attributes
entities and attributes
other entities you could also do something worrying doing more for clustering
approach that's not what we did here
this is the way to
we're fine
kind of
more abstract heterogeneous classes into
potentially more coherent subclasses
and refine the probabilistic model along the path
we can start off with something that very abstract
and refine it
and potentially in the places where we need to go
two level
of instances
OK so
that was a whirlwind tour of directed frame based approaches
i hope that you could see
in many cases can the parallel
ideas involved
the rule base directed approaches and the frame based on approaches and get a flavor
for the inference and learning algorithms and potentially the types of objects are
take the task you would want to solve with these
questions here about the directed approaches
everybody structures of that we get that
i can here
OK so
the question was you are curious about the other approaches based on
my probably misnomer the programming languages approaches of first i am going to go over
the undirected approaches which is another major category and then they say something about the
programming approaches to programming approach is what i'm capturing under the problem
which i don't know anybody works on them and is wincing an idea and i
are both kind
proof based methods the stochastic context free grammar method
and things like eyeball which is something that i be that for
works on
to some extent
prism as well
so there
they don't categorize quite neatly
this is in the standard language that exist today but
it's easy to simulate this is a picture of our simulator if your traffic models
and what not so just a couple of motivating examples so what is monte carlo
planning and i should say if you do have questions you can raise your hand
in interrupt me cut you off it's if i think it should be dealt with
later but
feel free to ask questions
so what is monte carlo planning
roughly defined as we want to compute a good policy for an MDP
by interacting with an MDP simulator
as opposed to
taking into compact representation of the model in planning with that source about
computing good policies by interacting with a simulator and will
formally define what we mean by simulator moment but now we have average here he's
going to world simulator instead and
every step is going to use the simulator play around to figure out what to
and get some feedback from the world and is going to use the simulator to
figure out what to do and take another action
so good question so so if we define the simulator that now mention that difference
you can look at this on your own basically there's a whole list of domains
there's simulators and i should mention these slides will be on
in fact if you wait a couple of days are going to be updated with
references and what these are very fresh from fifteen minutes ago in fact
so so
so let's define what we want from our simulation based representation of an MDP there's
still some states and actions but our instead of being given probability distributions in some
language we're going to be given r and c are is simply a stochastic function
to see program also a that returns a reward when you pass in stay in
action to think of it as a function that you right and see the returns
to random reward according to the distribution of our underlying MDP
and the same thing where t is the transition function you pass it to stay
in action
and it's going to spit out the next day
so these are simply stochastic functions that we don't care about their implementation you could
use c java whatever language you like
you could encoded in planning languages simulate that if you care to so so that's
what we mean when we say a simulation based representation now coming back to reinforcement
learning so
again in reinforcement learning we don't have a compact description of the environment in fact
we start off with no knowledge of the environment whatsoever was allowed to take actions
in the environment
here we start off with a simulator of the environment in our head
so the so the the key distinction is
sometimes users we're using a strong simulator here and a strong simulator simulator is basically
you can teleport to any state at any moment and take any action that you
want in reinforcement learning we sort of in a week simulator model where you you're
you are where you are you cannot teleport to any state that you want if
you want to get to stay state you have to figure out how to get
possibly in some cases you could ever reset the resets to an initial state so
that sort of the key distinction weak simulators reinforcement learning
we're in the strong simulator case of and that there are some
theoretical relations between these two so
so let's move on so that's our our simulation based MDP representation now we're going
to talk about the basic monte carlo algorithms
now i
i said our motivation is to scale to very large state spaces but on the
start out by talking about how do we use monte carlo techniques for single state
so that's not exciting by itself but we're going to try to build on that
and then create things that can be applied to large mdps so going to start
with a single say state case
this turns out to be
identical to what's called the multi armed bandit problem some of you might have heard
of it so i
suppose we have a single state MDP sources are only state we have these actions
we have k actions OK
what happens when we take one of these actions well you get a random reward
by calling this reward function
and you can view this is pulling the arm of a slot machine in getting
what do you have is this cases child alexander mackenzie
you can kind of be
proceeding of the old is that it is
and the judiciary
archives he said well he was an apprentice and used to leaving castle street
while on the other that the public record office was not john alexander mackenzie was
alexander mackenzie spent in a different way
he said was an apprentice but you to to leave on old across street and
in one case in the old bailey the guy was
condemned to that
couple penalty
in the other guy
he was
actually don't another one was sent to australia deported to australia is this the same
person one
this is all the reason that you have to do it implies some form of
imprecise reasoning is typically not supported by
the current tools
there are ways of doing this is one of the
sources of a of information the UK so sorry to see you can use this
is about three metrics is uses the names of objects like john alexander mackenzie alexander
mckenzie and this also applies to record
and tries to tell you which one is which
and this is something you can download from the web
but now we have just caption
information what we have to do the next step is to share
to let people finding it so when we talk about sharing views
now we have all this database this knowledge base of facts of instances
it is there
and we want to search we want to make the information available at the right
to the right people
now the
task is incredibly complex i can speak for four hours on this so we simplify
the view
exactly ten minutes so i simplified if you to searching
so what is ontology based annotation enables you to the two things is is to
collect information across documents and reasoning talk just searching two types of things that you
can search
one is the document
you can search documents especially collections not necessarily on the web
on the world wide web unless you really have large coverage
but you can also search for knowledge i said before you can you remember the
hamster examples you can use the information to
find the page
you can use
the information just to say this guy says force expanses knowledge
well or information according to how you define
there are
but if you look at the
possibilities for search you will have keyword based search and that is what we do
with google or any other search engines or whatever
you typically have two problems one is the one of ambiguity
he was can be police and so they can have multiple meanings
so you receive losses for these documents
and synonymity an object can be identified by
multiple terms
so you don't find documents because you're using c nineteen eighty and people have seen
only be in the in the text of low recorded what he said now
you tend not to notice that with google
on the way because they do some normalisation and also because you have such an
amount of documents that even if you have low recall you would still find documents
you will find something relevant and then you navigate but especially that power is the
interlinking interlinking gives you the most popular pages and this is quite useful
because people tend to be interested in the most popular pages but when you work
within the company on the organizational memory that is not linking on if there is
a hyperlink is not good enough
well actually the most important resources so
this is where you really find that people search doesn't work
semantic search if you just use the information that is in your knowledge base quite
i suppose knowledge search suppose document search
the problem is
if you look at the lead there whether different methods of doing that one going
to be used
you can use keywords and he was into concepts you can use the graph based
methods to create queries using the ontology you can use natural language approach is that
your query natural language query into an ontology can form based approaches the problem with
ontology based approaches is their metadata
can cover only part of the information
and the page about the hamsters
we can say anything about the address with the markup the rest of the show
but actually it turns out it's quite useful isn't but it was not in your
apology no one marketed that
so what do you do when
that happens and can be quite dramatic
well we did an experiment in jet engines
someone had developed an ontology and we were analysing
the typical topics of research there some
engineers data voice and we discovered that the ontology that was designed carefully
actually didn't call fourteen of out of twenty one topics
they were looking for just because they had so many things that were interested in
not everything was annotated
so the solution is that we have proposed to c was
well why do you want to do that well
you know you can't index everything you content think everything is two times spent time
consuming and it is impossible to foresee all the users and also automated means there
are pieces of information you can extract another simply you can't
because the system is not good enough because information is still in place
so what you are proposing cyprus search
enables you to combine
semantic semantic search and he was within the same query
basically it's three types of complex combination of three types of
of that's one is
pure semantic
so use
your eyes
he was based in which you match
the whole documents like good
but also you can add keywords in context in which much keywords within the annotations
when hamsters is annotated
you have
the concept hamster and the term memes
and you can use well within the
whatever is this as pet
find me
combine the semantic information that is on the web
like using watson is like using the semantic web or not and what you want
to put stop basically so
he was supposed to have an online demos i will talk about
basically it looks like in terms of interface it looks for space looks pretty much
like semantic web search search engine normal search engine you put keywords you obtain a
list of ontology is only stuff semantic documents that talked about you keywords you can
i want my keywords to correspond to class all i one i two as much
on is the idea of the entity i want to match to be exact meaning
that you can formulate ways like
i one semantic documents that contain
by its ideal stable researcher let's say and then you obtain all the semantic document
on the web that talks about research the class
and you get not only
the documents you entities you get a rid list of all the classes research that
has been described anywhere on the web
and then you can explore its you can click on the entity see that your
research a subclass of working person of that it does surprise which is research in
academia then you can click on research in academia i see that is the subject
of academic you can do graphene you can get metadata about
about the ontology containing your research being meaning that you can know
what is
the description logics underlying it you can know how it is
i mean the classes contain what also ontologies import what's what ontology that imported and
you can finally
the sparql query to it and gets with that
so this is what the interface that
basically it allows you to explore all
the same is the semantic information that is currently present on the web
now this is not what is interesting again
i mean this talk is about
building application and using it as the so
watson provides a set of API
which allows you to do whatever i do we use these interface within your application
in that you can find
semantic information you can explore it you can
find relations between entities and you can find anything
that is in the documents and trying to apply sparql queries and
in that case you know i i
how hard time trying to choose which application i'll show as an example
because there are many very
the watson plugin for ontology engineering for example for ontology reuse which some talked a
bit about
basically allows you to find
whatever is in your whatever and you have your ontology to find corresponding of entity
ontologies and to integrate any of the statements that is out there into your own
trading links between
the ontology and if you ever use we have an application for questions sharing
meaning that you can actually as natural language questions to the semantic web through watson
the semantic roles of dynamically annotate whatever you are browsing ontoweb
we have scarlet a nice application given two terms it tells you what is the
relation between the two terms by
going through ontologies on the web
moreover it is an adaptation feeding some other people are doing well since simulation
some people are doing folksonomy enrichment finding semantic information to put into tags synonym discovery
only sort of things
so with all application what i thought i would do
these are the show you want
which is not particularly impressive actually it's a very simple one
but it's a nice demonstrator of what you can do in today's two hundred lines
of javascript
and that actually provide a future but actually at semantics into something
without you having to collect semantics without you having to get to in the ontology
and two billion that set to put into other
he very simple
demonstrators caldwell who because it's
watson and yahoo
this user yahoo API to get
simple web search normal web search but what it does in addition is
it is part
which to you for each of the keywords you entered into the query follows the
search engine one of the keyword you could use to generalise the query
in the case of research can use working person you can use that
you can use academic staff
what keywords you could use
to specify your query in that case you could use scientists senior research fellow in
academia is a good one computer science researcher
does not four or
you're keywords
then every click
in other words korean you can run it when you click here it replaced the
keyword by your feet so i really this is not
particularly impressive is the big thing but the thing is that it is fully simple
to do
again i was supposed to do an on line demo
it's actually working
well i want to show
is that these application
the reason a bit
just a tiny bit of development can be done very easily any that can be
done very easily
what i mean you can imagine what you can do in one week two weeks
one month or year
so i we do actually see
using the watson API you can for example search for all the ontology is on
the web that contains a class researcher
this is one simple call
this one
to this particular USA we want semantic content
corresponding to the keywords
now this is not exactly
what you want
you want to tiny bit better
if you want something
you want to all
the ontology that contains
class researcher and that any thing that is research
which would be exactly researcher not research in academia not research computer science researcher
and that full content research and not in anything but in its ideal it's labelled
so and we will see why why this is useful in the second case
so we have a lower bound
that's palmer tries by these q functions so if we for different choices of q
we get different lower bound on the likelihood
all right so what we do now is
that's the wrong way we now take this lower bound
and we
optimize the lower bound for given parameters theta and pi we optimize with respect to
the variational distributions specific with respect to these q functions
OK so
actually we maximize it it's a lower bound it turns out we want to maximize
that we want to maximize the log likelihood function ultimately but you know we have
this lower bound so we basically maximize the lower bound and in this in this
step here what we do is we actually find
we can think of it that way we find the best lower bound in this
family that we've defined so it's the tightest bound at the current estimate of our
the parameters
so so we can look at you know what if we vary
you know and look at the end an extremal point well we see then you
know that just by performing that
we get the following equation namely that this q are fuzzy
equals for what's written on the right hand side here
so it's p of w given times of the given d and then
normalized well that is simply the posterior probability
d common w
right so
so so this is basically what we do in the east right so we can
we can think of the e step as as
basically finding as the tightest lower bound among this family of lower bounds that we've
OK once we have a particular lower bound what we can do then is optimise
or parameters maximise lower bound with respect to all parameters
and and this will then result in the m step equations case if we look
at the gradient of that with respect to fade as they are the derivatives with
respect to participate to zero respectively we get these two equations that are exactly the
same as the m step equations
and of course we just have these q functions in here but but the way
they been determined before is just to be the posteriors right
so this is slightly more general way of
you know motivating
these types of you know that that also applies to slightly more general class of
problems than does the model of them but
so this is basically the derivation
there's also there questions of
problems of over fitting in such models became what
what we have done
in our early work is used a trick called temperate TMN
we're basically if we look at these lower bounds again
right you can actually write them like this you have two contributions maybe i can
go back to show that here you know if you look at this what you
what you have here is
if you look at this part right is just
the expectation
so it is just the expectation of that block here
right and then also you get an entropy part if you get the you know
q r log
qr xe or one of accuracy so he pulled out with a minus sign so
basically you have one part that has to do in physics is called the average
energy and the other part it has to do with the
entropy actually of these variational distribution so we want that to be
and we want
this to be
large and that means we want the q functions to have high entropy now what
one can do
and this isn't just a heuristic approach
as i motivated here at least is increase
this entropy part OK you can
usually this is just the one here OK there
you know it's just this minus this but we can
amplify this entropy part
and forest that you know we're not actually computing posterior probabilities but that we smoothing
out posterior probabilities in some way and if you do that you can actually see
the following look at these graphs here OK so what's shown here is number of
and what's shown the y axis here is the
perplexity so this is the basically the test the likelihood on some
test data set of all the datasets
i mean basically scaled you know e to the minus test look like this anyway
so you know the the lower the better and you can see is train models
for instance here would be to equal one this would be the standard model of
OK the quality of the model gets better and better and better but then it
after about twenty five or iterations in this particular case here
it actually
deteriorates so the performance get worse and worse and worse again this is the typical
overfitting phenomenon OK
now as you
use this trick here we
maybe it's right translation and scale from one to five with five being perfect one
being completely terrible
and then
let people judge people don't even agree on that by the way
so that
the history of automatic metrics is that we take what works in speech recognition is
actually general model and machine translation
take what works this feature so we look at our right so we still do
the same thing where we have human translation we have all machine translation and just
look how many words match the error rate implies how many words match the same
but often things get kind of fundamentally order and you don't want to get completely
punished for that so there some adaptations for that way you allow some reordering
the metric is use
right now
pretty popular section of the old blue was suggested in two thousand two
and it's based the same idea you reference translation you have the system output and
the only trigger setting not only look at how many words get right
which would completely ignore reordering
we also look at how many pairs of birds and
triple suffered some four grams of words to get right and if you get forward
to write comparison to the reference sensation it is deemed to be a good thing
OK how does this work that say this is the reference translation here
slightly violent the gunman was shot to death by the police
and he system translations of human translations so whatever they are possible
candidate translation so you want to judge them
by michael how what they are so we we use
n gram overlap with the reference translation
so i have a little bit colour coded so they can afford can write kind
of the whole thing green fagin
by right
it's blue and
and if i get nothing to help produced the wrong word put in red
so you can kind of see that really terrible translations like the one that have
on subject larger than zero symbols
of course a lot of words that are at so these
just very lonely
but of course the perfect station has all matching programs
it doesn't work perfectly so the last sentence
police killed the gunman
missus elizabeth information that there was shooting involved so it that instead money thing
but is actually good translation but
we have
a single word arrived in the by grand
and the period in the right here
so that there wouldn't be just very highly
so it's very easy with this metric to always come with an example of a
perfectly nice to station
but it doesn't match the source matches you reference at all
and it would be judged fairly lowly
the argument is that you don't do that for one sentence you do that for
safe house sentences
and if you look in the decision corpus of a thousand sentences you have much
more matches with human reference you probably better
a system that doesn't have that much patches
OK so that's intuitive argument you might believe it to believe it or not
so what made this argument convincing that this is a good metric to evaluate machine
translation graphs like this
there you have
automatic scores
on the one hand axes and human discourse we make human society that what i
said earlier you give us a better person say
actually here yesterday for questions one is is the meaning preserved its called adequacy and
question is not fluent output in this confluence e
and because influence correlate a lot
but the main point is here
that also the automatic scores
so here's in this causes slight variant of the score
also correlate very very well with their
with the human judgments of the system on the top right it was judged
best by humans is also just best by the automatic metrics
and on the bottom left
the very system according to both humans and
automatic metric
so you can
draw a nice line here and say you know everything kind of is on that
and we can also compute the correlation
and say well the correlation i think what we have here
you can read the number
and when the eighties nineties that's a very strong correlation
and you say well OK that's one metric maybe have a different metric and it's
very nice game to play so once you have a corpus annotated with human judgments