always cheat when they think that when they play with dice
promise it in zero to be team
so basically like the point when he would usually at some point get frustrated and
say well you cheating
said but
yes getting the right getting the prior right is not quite so easy
but out of
they were
in exactly
and while there is only really one way to address this
you just measure more
that's the end of the day what you have to do what you can do
so is
you can get uniform convergence statement saying well
actually with high probability the likelihood that getting cannot be too too far off from
what it should be
you can get back up statements reasonably easily
and this might influence the choice of prior
i think that when you might want to really really small that you say
in this case
was the expression can change the law
if i get the general of it wrong
i mean
this is essentially problem that he will not be able to
so exactly
so for instance if you measuring wind speed
and you know that in a certain area usually have wind speed of ten kilometres
per hour
then you should of course that the prime people serve many times before you would
probably because rather
strong prior
one way of addressing to some extent is
by doing something like cross validation but that
kind of defeats the purpose of prime
people have done
and and then
you have to question how do you say hyperprior
you can then have a heart-to-heart prior make it more and more and more
OK so
this was
the first unit
and i know what looks like a run out of time
i think l
just briefly mention what can do
in the afternoon
so that that's
the partition
we shall prove the maximum entropy
you what to stay on rather than half of the after
so that was
that is
can estimate of this so all i done to the morning now was really classical
statistical estimation theory
there wasn't much nonparametric to it except for the fact that we have this fix
lurking around which
i didn't we say whether it's finite dimensional not in fact if you want to
do nice things you have to pick for fixed to be really complicated sophisticated and
quite often
infinite dimensional
but other than that
i mean this is really basic statistics it's quite powerful and quite often you might
want to use that
the first k
we want to again
and i'll be just explaining a little bit i get the maximum entropy estimate
subject to
the integral
of course
p of x
we have maximize with distribution
he calls
going to pick an equality constraint is that the math turns out to be slightly
otherwise we'll have to take which constraints are active or not and all that
now how can we solve this
one way is first is to set up lagrange function
so l
of p
and lambda
this is the constrained optimization problem
so i get
while the integral
of minus
log of p of x
and your x
and here we have
of forth ics
p x
OK that one is me
but we have a whole bunch of other constraints
we also know
that the integral
of p of x
equals one
so we get
it's called astronomer energy for reason
g times
g here
of p of x
x minus one
and furthermore we know that the density is nonnegative
here x
is critical in sierra rawlings
and now this
actually will lead to a lagrange multiplier which is
the function
so we get
plus the integral
and for r the sum of the squared the match
you have something
it be different so you have the camera case to ground metric symmetrical again in
metric which is
so we take the function side will be replaced
o also known
and also function phi f
corresponds terms of this problem
and maybe you know the kind of problems
it's like that people
the problem of a picture
so you have
this is called a factor the
highly coefficient and if you want to find a solution of this
you will have you will have
two sons aching vector problem
so if you don't trust me
just think about the following thing texas formula
it took six days gradient
and make it a new
and you will find that the solution
that are able the solution for the table two and you have to make new
to gradient satisfying
this kind of equation
so the eighth it again vectors of the matrix k
OK so we are happy because we
it's another way
to come back to what we know about principal component analysis
and of course was that
as you as you see
if i take
and you can then also came in
all work
what they describe these
it is always OK can i can use it
so this method is called cannot PCA
and you will use it
i said he was data which i just described by by proximity based similarity so
you will try to check that your proximity assuming is really you can and then
you have you cannot PCA
all eyes are if you think that
you have some doubt
about the fact that the about the fact that your cloud is really a
risation of caution viable and you will know that principal component classic the company
well one
these two cases to try to go forward canard PC
notice also that so when you were structured object when you have a graph or
when you have if an object in the sense of
object oriented language you will be able to
two began then and then you will be able to
to visualize in fact two projects into this is the first principal directions
the object and it would be a nice way to visualize complex objects
he then you equations
to two battle
of the course
is to keep
you seem
OK so we have
question that
OK so
in these short course as you see
there are a lot of things i didn't talk about
so first
i talked about the way how to formulate problem of
machine learning algorithm and i i d i the
optimisation formulation
but they didn't gave its accredited program for instance
in the two cases support vector regression and support the commission show you an implementation
of the programs we use in this case so in fact you can you can
that was pretty much quite programming tools
to get the tools because there
a variety of tools are so i didn't
talk about the fact that you need
to define you can
even if you have defined can and usually you have some parameter
two to tune
and you have several ways to to do that
the first way ways to use
things like cross validation of obstruct in order to select parameters so this is more
model selection
or in some cases not seen in support vector machine
you have some some researchers who have proposed away
of learning both
the parameters of q is the whole USPS but also with us in the parameters
you can
usually they did gradient in g instead of using a classical quadratic programs they use
gradient all the combined
three examples for M is two where we have two v variables X one and X two
and the vector Y on the ri on the vertical axis if alpha is one
one one-half  one-half then this is just a geometric mean of these two
inequalities and you see that this is actually the same as the second-order cone but
rotated to be in the horizontal plane so you can show that if you take
this power cone with alpha is one half alpha all the alphas are one half then you
get the second order cone but just rotate it   we can also consider other types of alpha
and then you get some cones that are not equivalent to the semi-definite cone or
the second order cone this is for alpha is two-thirds one third for example three quarters
one quarter and so on so those are some examples of convex cones that are useful
in applications are there questions about this so then let's say a few things about modeling
tools so software for modeling I think many of you are familiar
with packages like CVX or YALMIP and MATLAB and there are also some  similar packages
in Python they are less well developed but they're also developed for Python
so modeling system is a software that will translate a convex problem in the natural format in which
you would normally specify an optimization problem and then would translate it into a canonical
form required by a solver and then it solves it and returns the solution back or translates it
back to your notation in your problem so to give an example suppose you want to
solve this simple problem in MATLAB you know from yesterday how to write this
as an LP but  you could also just use CVX this is a modeling system
for MATLAB and then solve this problem by this MATLAB code so everything
between these two key words cvx begin and cvx end is CVX code so you first declare a variable you say X
is a variable of length three for example then you say what the objective is
in the normal notation you would use a MATLAB you say minimize I want to minimize the one
norm of A X minus B you give the constraints you say subject to X greater or equal
to zero less than or equal to one so these will be componentwise interpreted as componentwise
inequalities and then when you finish CVX will pass this it'll recognize that this
objective can be written or trans transformed into a linear programming objective so it'll do
this transformation call an an interior point solver to solve that LP and then return the
answer so after finishing X will be a standard MATLAB variable with the result
of the optimal X right so in this cope X is a CVX optimizational
variable so it's not determined after finishing  it's the optimal value so that's
modeling software so this is a very basic problem but CVX will recognize actually most
of the constraints that we saw yesterday because it knows all these  tricks and
equivalences that allow you to translate convex problems into LPs but also second-order cone
problems or semi-definite programming problems  so it's very convenient because otherwise the translation of
a problem even fairly simple problem in a canonical form required by a solver
can be very tedious and so this does it automatically and so there's others so
that's CVX YALMIP is a similar package for also MATLAB does more or less similar things
and then there is also some older general-purpose modeling packages in optimization and the best
known ones are AMPL and GAMS so these packages use conic optimization solvers so
in this case CVX will translate it into a linear programming problem but depending on the
problem it might also convert it into a second-order cone problem or a semi-definite optimization problem
so it translates everything into conic linear programming problems with these three types of cones so
nonactive orthant the second-order cone and the positive semidefinite cone so that's a little
bit of a limitation so for example the exponential cone included the power cone
is also not included so there's some a few constraints that cannot be directly written as
conic inequalities with these three cones and that need to be approximated but  one of the
reasons why the restriction of the restriction to these cones is that the solvers interior point
solvers for conic optimization are actually also limited to these three cones and you see later
why has to do with the algorithms the classes of interior point methods that people use in these solvers
are restricted to these three cones in practice that's not much of a restriction because actually
surprisingly these three cones the nonactive orthant second-order cone semi-definite cone cover actually most of
the convex constraints you encounter in practice so this is a list of some
constraints that can be written as second-order cone constraints and we saw them already
yesterday so for example if you have a function in the objective like this or
an upper bound on a f this quadratic-over linear function then you can write
it as a second-order cone constraint yesterday also we mentioned the powers of X
so if you have X to positive power greater than one or a negative
power beta for positive X then you can write it as a second-order cone constraint
if alpha and beta are rational and of course if it's not rational you can
easily approximate it by a rational function it also allows you to by using this
trick to minimize P norms  for general P as long as P is rational you
can also write this as a second-order cone program although it's not obvious at first sight
these are some  functions or constraints that can be converted into semi-definite inequalities
and we saw them some of them yesterday for example the maximum eigenvalue of
a symmetric matrix  is something you can directly enter in CVX or YALMIP
you can say I want to minimize the maximum eigenvalue of this matrix variable and it'll
the answer to that is that it did
i just didn't mention it
that's what we all explain so suppose i'd stuck in the minus sign here
OK i would have gotten
with the difference so with an extra minus sign
but then when i compared to what was over there i would have had to
have another different minus sign over here
so actually both places we get an extra minus sign
and they would still coincide so actually the implicit method is little better doesn't even
notice the difference between the branches it does the job both on both
the top and bottom
another way of saying that is that you're calculating the slopes here so let's look
at this picture
here's the slopes
let's just take a look at the positive value of x and just check sites
to see what's happening
if you take a positive value of x over here
x is positive the denominator is positive the slope is negative you can see that
it's tilting down
so it's OK now
on the bottom side
it's going to be tilting up
and similarly what's happening here is that both x and y are positive
and this sexiness this wire positive and the slope is negative on the other hand
on the bottom side exit still positive but y is negative and it's tilting up
because the
the denominator is negative positive in mind positive slope
so it it matches perfectly in every
this the this is
complicated however and it's easier just to keep track of one branch of the time
even in advanced
so we only do have one branch of time
other questions
OK so now i want to give you a slightly more complicated example here and
indeed some of the
so here's
here's a little more complicated example it's not going to be the most complicated example
but you know
would be a little bit
so this example
ah i'm going to give you a fourth order equations so why did the four
what's x y square
minus two is equal to zero
it just so happens
that there's the trick
to solving this equation
so actually you can all you can do both the explicit method and the not
OK so the explicit
i would say OK well i want to solve for this so i'm going to
use the quadratic formula but on on y square this is quadratic in y square
because there's a fourth power in the second pair in the first and those in
the third powers are missing
so this is why square is equal to
minor axis plus or minus the square root
x squared
nine four times minus two
divided by two
so this axis the b
this minus two is the sea
and is equal to one
in the quadratic form
and so the formula for y
it is
plus or minus the square root
of minor axis was minus the square root x squared plus eight
divided by two
so now you can see this problem of branches this happens actually a lot of
cases coming up
in an elaborate where you have two choices for the sign you you have two
choices for the sign here conceivably there's many is four routes to this equation because
it's the fourth
degree equation
it's quite a mess you should have to check each branch separately
and this is really is that level of complexity and in general it's very difficult
to figure out
the formulas for quartic equations
but fortunately we're never going to use them
that is we're never going to need those formulas
so the act the implicit method
it's far easier
so the implicit method
just says OK
i'll leave the equation in its simplest form
and now differentiate
so i differentiate i get four
why cubed why prime
here i have to apply the product rule
so i differentiate the x and
the y squared
alright so what we're going to do today
and that i'm going to start talking about the development of atomic theory
in the next few minutes i'm going to win is through the observations that led
to the
belief that adams
what are the most basic constituent
and then what we're going to be
is there
i can actually be
the animal is not the most basic constituents of matter
there's it lists an electron and the nucleus
we're going to start talking about
what are the fundamental principles
there are to obtain in order for the electron to the nucleus came together to
remain an entity
and what we're going to see is that we're going to have to
understand the new kind of mechanics to understand how the electron and nucleus hang together
and then further on in the course we're going to see be we're going to
need a new kind of mechanics wall also understood how to adults came together how
to atoms bind to form molecules
all right but today i'll lecture for the first two-thirds or three three quarters of
course and announced that now why introduced the rest of our teaching team and we'll
talk about the mechanics of course we'll talk about the expectations of course and some
details like
OK so
let's get going here
and now we turn the lights down because and going to use the
here in the right
the ancient greek philosophers
they certainly were known to have pondered whether matter
can be divided endlessly into smaller and smaller pieces
or whether there was appointed which you couldn't divide matter any further
and in that year he was one of those philosophers who
i argue that matter
could be divided into smaller and smaller particles chopped up into smaller and smaller pieces
and in nineteen and was visible
this is called the continuum theory of matter continue
because you don't have nice discrete point of the continuum no boundaries
but there was a contrary philosophy contrary philosophy heralded by democritus who actually was about
one hundred years older than aristotle
and he held
that matter indeed was composed of individual discrete particles
these discrete particles he called animals
for now
almost four divisible
the origin of our world of course is that
now in the fourth century BC there wasn't much evidence one way or the other
for these kinds of either one of these philosophies i call the plot
because it was the search for understanding reality by speculative as opposed to a
investigation or observation mean
but for whatever reason
it was the aristotle here his continuum theory of matter prevailed all the way to
the seventeenth century
and here he is depicted by rap eleanor fresco
and now on the walls of the vatican holding court
continuum theory man
but just about at the same time in which rafael painted this picture
there were observations set of observations being made
that began to point out that there wasn't really behaving
like eight continue
there was a
behaving more like that i have some discrete nature to it
so what are the observation well
one of them was by this gentleman here robert boyle
and that yes what is moral occupation was
constraint that the good by his former occupation was the theologian both scientists were at
the time
and you of course know him
the empirical observation that the pressure times volume is of constant along the temperature is
but he actually advanced the
one of the first ideas of an element
and that is
he called
a certain primitive
i mangled body
and that somehow you can take these primitive on mangled bodies and put them together
to form a perfectly mixed body
again if everything if all of these probabilities are gaussian
everything is going to be alright
annual and up with nice convex functions and convex functions to minimize
in any case
there are
there are ways of choosing the prize
which i did not described here
prior to that might be might either be obvious from the setting that you have
in in your problem but if not then there are ways of treating noninformative prior
or jeffreys priors
that i won't go into now but you may want to look into that
now i have to all sides about
a few months size about probabilities which are
the first one here is about concepts
that stem from the information series that information theory is a theory that in that
aims at measuring the amount of information you have in your random variables in your
the basic thing in information theory is the entropy the entropy of
a random viable is
nine the integral of x log px of x
you can show that it's actually negative
actually no
so i think it may be may be due to the entropy is positive when
you have the discrete survival but if if you have a continuous horrible that it's
it's not necessarily positive anyways i don't remember and if we if someone knows that
better than it now
what is true is that the kullback leibler divergence
is always positive OK
the biggest
and it
contract thank you
so for a discrete distribution on the
on the set exercise that takes values x one to x and
then the distribution that minimizes the entropy is different the function is in in one
of the the excited so basically if you're
random viable takes values in x one to x and x one x two to
then the probability as the minimum entropy if it's
the problem if it's the poverty
the random bible it takes only one value
with probability one
and values was probably his u
that's what the function is
and the entropy is maximal
if all
of the exercise of exactly the same probability which is one of
so if
the discrete probability the uniform discrete probability the the one having the most
the largest entropy
on the set of probabilities of exercise
all right
the kullback leibler divergence is the way of comparing comparing the
mountains of information in in the two variables x and y
it's in particular its way
it's a way of comparing them
two probability team there to probabilities px and py y it's always but even it's
it equal to zero if and only if
the probabilities are equal
and the mutual information i of x and y
it is the only one type of information that is shared between the two of
the two random variables x and y it's actually the kullback divergence the kullback leibler
between the two
so in probability
and the product of the probabilities
the two marginal probability so it's the distance between the joint probability and what would
and x x and y
it would be independent
so there is no information shared between x and y if and only if x
and y are independent
he two s three
now there's an ocean called city which is a measure of the complexity of the
complexity of the distribution
unfortunately finish and is due to the entropy of x
and it's used in evaluating language is a language model
so i don't know much about this but i think you see it in the
maybe a few more musically
you can you should think about en tropy as matter that can tell you
is stationary or of
one that's right
stationarity so
we want to view the world as we want to view the
there are the objects of study is static now i'm not as concerned about stationary
since the world is a stationary dynamical system because it's
because that's still dynamic
it's just if they don't have source streams of inputs and outputs at all
OK so the let's let's move on to second idea in the second idea is
perhaps most obvious of all
is one of the kind more carefully reward
rewards values verification
the awards are very simple
and general formulation che both both short and long term goals and
that's a key point in
because of that enables the agent to tell for itself whether it's right or wrong
so we can verify its own thoughts its own understanding
or you know i'm just talking about the elementary things like you know the backgammon
player can know if it's one the game
OK so bill rewards and values short and long term goals i think this is
people are talking about
obviously this is this has to do with with the reward system in the brain
and the relationship between short-term things the reward signal and a long-term things the value
thing so i theory of long term goal is just to the prediction of some
of the structure goals
OK that's that's the theory that the computational theory
that's reinforcement learning computational theory of what it means to have a goal
and for the purpose of the mind
very very simple
and that i think is where the power comes from so it's it's simple but
it's also very
and it actually is more
it's not more complex but it's more powerful than what is often considered like he
might consider goal states or
desired trajectories and so
a reward measure instantaneous measure over time is more sophisticated than that
even though it's OK so it's been stated ball is we can so i wrote
up this this this attempt to do that and a strong way in which i
call this hypothesis because because i'm not brave enough to stand up and say it's
but i think this is in a major the stent which is chosen major reason
for power reinforcement so you say all all of what we mean by goals and
purposes can be well thought of as maximizing the expected value
the cumulative sum
the scalar signal that comes from outside recall reward
so ruling out lot
this this this is sort of a really general but it's not
it's not true in general its ruling like and that's
that can be good to tap the simplicity we're just going to have a single
criterion that che that should be sufficient for the expectation this ruling out issues of
sensitivity to risk
we're going to deal with additive sums
not interactions between things and finally
the goal is received its external to the system is not internally generated goal so
all these are make this a substantial to hypothesis could be wrong you could disagree
with it but i really think these are just making simple and not real limitations
for example you idea of risking can easily encode the risk as a different kind
of reward
doesn't really change it if you don't want to deal with things being additive just
this is me the fuel additive you can and you can see the goal
the final reward including everything to come at the end
and the goal
you could something is a huge difference is if you want it
go to the
makes it is that it is these
right so big
it's a big deal i think i'm trying to present positively that that that the
reason we can cross across fields have very simple
theory there can be no that we can analyse mathematicians and psychologist can make sense
of it it's just like a theory of sums signal going on in the brains
of communicating
you what
well of course obviously on excommunicate people and i realized that when i say these
so he had this connection between the property of the base learner and the margin
of the combined forces OK if the base learner has this property that always returns
to certain
weighted error why i mean they are which is more than half minus half coming
then we have this property
and therefore the margin of the combined forces
is the least common when we find the optimal of k
OK so what the model which is actually see but it was to sort of
what i was talking about was the optimal case here so we maximize all of
so the question is what is article was actually cheating
so it can be shown that it is actually finding a solution which has a
large margin but not the maximum margin it can be shown that the
margin which is achieved by the most is at least half of the maximum margin
OK so that's why i mean it's it's some it's fine hypothesis which has a
large margin is good so it's good for these margin bounds
for the more modern but it doesn't really matter too much about the margins half
what just what the maximum
it can be shown that i was might not be
converging what they can or cannot examples of articles is definitely not maximising the margin
was open problem for a long time but it was actually maximizing the margin and
so it has been shown like two years ago i think that but it was
not maximizing the margin for i mean they're called example
OK proves it was only known it finds combined forces with which has least to
half of the maximum margin
OK so then we came up with ideas of changing articles such that actually maximize
the margin so the first one was actually little prime and i think he to
design the new algorithm which is called opportunity
asymptotically maximizes the margin so he changed something such that really maximize the margin but
only in the very limit
so he didn't have any convergence rate
then month and and i worked on adaboost star so that's
what application and total was very recently
and then we were able to show that it requires
we can be changed the algorithm and the algorithm needs only to look and over
x squared iterations in order to achieve margin which is at least roast minus epsom
OK so roast as the maximum margin and epsilon this the accuracy would like to
achieve me need this many iterations
and i'm going to show you how we did that
the last technique is based on linear programming that was some by christian bennett
and that's related to kind of generations and that is usually very fast however there
are no convergence rate so the only on
with convergence rates are these adaboost stein told post
the case is it clear
how the model relates to the edge and any questions for that
please ask now getting more complicated
essentially on the training at a service on training data so that means here that
on the training data we would like to achieve margin so rule starlets a max
margin and then
we would like to achieve margin on the training set which is at least roast
so all which comes now is is empirically that means is on the training set
so this may be
i mean you know it's all yours
i mean
firstly of course i would like to find something which i mean to say i
would like to compute something that we have to run the algorithm and then i
would like to maximize the margin small number of iterations is just cost something to
run and if the number of iterations is ten billion second which kind run some
some tree ten billion times something so it's more like a computational issues
OK it does it says satisfied
OK well is the right so
of course when you have in your functions are very simple for instance of anyone
conscious just one dimension of your of your data
OK so then you might want to have a very small number of features because
then you can actually interpreted
so if you achieve small i mean large margin which is with a small number
of iterations but small number of features then this is good for you practice for
the solution of practical problem because then you can actually look at what these features
on can try to understand what's going on there
so what i want to say so the minmax theorem that's really the the most
important thing
i mean
so make make note in your notes and this this really relates the it's
with the margin
OK so
that is so let me try to drive a little bit how this new algorithms
this article star and also called forced work so
i start with a small modification of post
so it's called adaboost role it's made by first proposed by prime in ninety seven
it is essentially just about which articles are so we have everything which was another
post if just one wanting thing so and that's something which we call the target
marginal role
so and only goes in
to the
computation of poverty so this role simply constant which is subtracted from the
it's only modifications
everything else is just the same
OK so
what does it mean
so you might ask
and there is some
there's some theory so maybe maybe let me first explained you so the idea of
this target margin is that OK adaboost madaboost this rule is here
OK so then this term is just here
and to give the sequence
i think i think it's important to see that there is a difference between
these kind of fixed continuation i would say like when you look at the numbers
as they are given in the this
and you try to find out how you can add them up
to get that in the next sequence
and here you try to look for other type of properties not additive properties but
i don't know how to go about but i don't know
but and properties like you look for patterns in the binary expansion
well OK there are some other funny things that you can think of actually this
one is not in the
encyclopedia but because it's not exactly correct there should be as free
to make its correct because i i just
so it's OK if you look at
the by the expansion of pi and
and you can interleave them so i would be three
one four one five nine
and e two seven one eight
what they were
so when not i mean
it's also corrects it starts with one two four seven so why not
and can you can invent all sorts of things
in general in these IQ tests there is one
kind of
natural answer
one is that looks
simpler than the other ones although all the other ones are correct
there is one that seems more reasonable
and and and again usually is to just two
try to
i guess
what's the
this exam minor
the sinking actually but but there is no there is no reason why i i
would prefer this version to this version because
so maybe my brain is naturally inclined to looking at numbers in binary form rather
than looking at numbers in this form is just a convention like we have been
trained to look at numbers
like this and make additions
i mean if you show
these two two two-year-old baby you probably would see the patterns but you will not
see the additive structure
so it's just a matter of
what you
how are you know what you think about
another one which is also funny i think this example from marcus later again if
you start with this the
OK this is the prime numbers so you write the prime numbers until fifty nine
you enter the sequence
in the
on the web and you you would seen that
there is only one way to continue this sequences to put
prime numbers but actually it's not the case there is another sequence that's exactly the
same way
and which has sixty instead of sixty one
which is
the the least of the order of the
simple group
OK i i will not tell you what simple groups are
just to show you that i mean if you are a mathematician working on group
theory maybe you would mean that you immediately notice looking at the sequence that this
is the sequence of orders of simple groups you say sixty whereas if you are
number theorist
he was a sixty one
OK so it's it's also depends on your culture you know way
OK yet another example
in the same flavour
you have a sequence of numbers again
and the goal is to extend the sequence of numbers
if you have ever
looked at the
this is this email expansion of by you will notice that it's actually the first
numbers in the decimal expansion of pi
but if you have not seen that
like if if i have put u
if i put here some
other people maybe he or square root of two you would probably have not noticed
so the question is
when do you not is the structure and when do you not not just the
you could say
let's just count how many times i have one i mean sometimes i have two
and so on and you will notice
at least if you continue the sequence
long enough that actually all this the frequencies converge to one over one pence
this is the
funny properties of
pi and e and some numbers like this that
actually every
in figure appears
take some ten years ago
usually the data recording was quite expensive so people really care about what they measured
so they
really measured only relevant things and what
the out come was the outcome of this was that the datasets for the
really well defined
very good for the state of minas because we were quite sure not really should
but but
consider a sure that all variables all attributes of the data points are really relevant
to the talks about talks
so that is usually was quite low dimensional analysis or
even if we have a higher dimensional data usually all attributes are relevant
if all attributes irrelevant even you can have thousands of of attributes you don't have
crisp dimensionality because
if all
actually are relevant then
there's nothing
to be cursed by much OK but nowadays the situation is different
data causing it's very easy very cheap so everyone measures everything
maybe you know it's myself so
attributes are no longer have evaluated before measurement measurement if they are relevant or not
just measure
because it's so cheap so easy
and we end up in datasets that usually contain a large number of features
and a large number of these features are irrelevant
for the task of data mining
we have it in and we don't know
which other elements once and which are not
so for example here's some
very few examples in molecular biology mir gene expression data with more than a thousand
dimensions for object
quite a lot of them are irrelevant
how to do that
customer recommendations but we have ratings for products again tends to
thousands of sorry to hundreds of
dimensions for
corruption and there are many more
whatever text
highdimensional data is is really
a big challenge nowadays
so what is the challenge
again the curse of dimensionality so if you have a lot of irrelevant attributes
usually data is really because by
this is the fact that the relative contrast between
simply increase with
increasing dimensionality we had this in the
which is great
picture we
the cheese credit distribution of
to the to the to the mean
when we increase the degrees of freedom and the distances converged to economy
so the distances get
the higher the dimensions are
so the relative contrast between the distances
consequences they don't very sparse almost all points and noise or outliers what kind of
i mean all points of
at least in the full dimensional space
and many
models that we heard
here rely on the concept of neighborhoods to to define outliers in the concept of
does not apply it becomes meaningless in high dimensional spaces cannot say
what is the one of the k nearest neighbours of the absentee
if we if the concept of distances is no longer
meaningful in high dimensional space so is the concept of
so solutions for this is to use more robust distance functions and find for the
full dimensional outliers cosine
measurements or whatever
or to find outliers in projections
of the original feature space
that means only a subset of the features are relevant and we try not only
to find the outliers but also the features
that specify the lines that are relevant to this line
the guys did intensional knowledge with the distance based on
so i think these are the most important challenge is here
so here's one
the idea for the first
the idea of solution using more robust distance function or distance measure and find full
dimensional outliers which is called a but angle based outlier degree
so the idea here is
and angle based distance measure is
potentially more stable in high dimensional spaces for example you may be you know that
text data which is really high dimensional this term frequency
it's very popular to use cosine
similarity measure
because and that's a more stable than distances dimensions space
so this is that you use angle sensor instead of of distances
and the idea is that
an object could be an outlier if most other objects are located in similar directions
or take this
object here
you see that most of the objects are
in a similar direction
tation from from o
they are all in this direction
on the other hand if you take
o point in here
all other points are most of the points are in various this similar
so this is the
the idea
how is this formalized
so well first of all the basic assumptions again here outliers are at the border
of the of the data distribution because all other points are interested in a similar
direction and normal points are in the centre of the data fusion because
most of the points are similar
and the idea is now implemented in the following models so you just consider
for a given point p
the angle
yeah sorry for a given point p you take two other points x and y
from the database
and consider the angle between
the line
p x p y so take this one you
x and y and you just consider the angles between
this line OK
perhaps change system accordingly so that adapts system that interfaces all that sort of thing
to do
it's a step further
i organised a workshop in the modelling two years ago and had been fight with
they actually convinced me i was wrong because we're saying you know we do machine
learning and clearly machine learning and so we got these wonderful system can actually help
you to do this we all doing these systems they finish off by
then predicting what the user is going to do
so we are very happy to come up with system model
which will predict the next clue to use these two to
so i think that is no way
the next operation person is going to do is to actually that direction all of
this is what he likes because this is what see
and they said no we do not want that all because we know that you
should use the money is used in context
being used in context means that as soon as you install user modeling system are
also using
the adaptation
of the system to model which then means that the user himself going change what
does not correspond to this model to predict so coming out in machine learning just
as capable of coming out the system with its
that's not good for us because it's a bit like when are talking about the
the distribution of probabilities relaxing the distribution is not change between the training and testing
whether it's clearly something they don't want distribution is going to change because the machine
learning is going to actually do so
and getting this example just to show that all truths in machine learning which are
then people go further thanks to this sort of discussion available in machine learning that
then into account how to measure the annotation system although there will be nice theories
but if we do want to
of interest
groups want to hire is very capable of saying you know i don't arrive with
my true this is what what has always existed they all work in different ways
to get the data we think sampling is pressing to about naming them sampling might
take four years to see how the child may develop and language so you can't
always just say right and i disagree i saying we need to know twenty thousand
examples to
so i was my last message which is machine learning there's lots of perspective in
pure machine learning i'm not sure also means is a machine learning and something else
and a huge keep open-minded towards towards the sun
this is
yet so
a follow-on from but
you think that OK so first of all
my own careers is i'm coming academic
professor university but actually started out
as an engineer with IBM and stay the same for ten years solving problems designing
systems and so forth and then i went into to accademia and so although my
probably would be called applied statistics rather than machine learning problem solved because
a lot of people would argue that machine learning is
applied statistics and in many ways some people will disagree with me i actually agree
with fully but it certainly are a viewpoint that an awful lot of very senior
people within the machine learning community take
push forward
machine learning i would say is is very much an applied
subject and takes all of his motivation from the problems that are being considered
for example one of the really hot is at the moment
is computational biology and we were talking about earlier on so very area because it
is largely a data driven
subject biologists and experimentalists they have these hypotheses there is no
underlying c
o which describes the systems that we are studying
the one to understand that they want to develop the in the only way they
can do that is by observing the systems usually have a in that minor
generating observations generating data and then going by contesting for these hypotheses
and consequently there is a huge amount of data there is a huge amount of
uncertainty in the data is well and so that there is
a lot of opportunity for people machine learning background applied statistics by background to engage
with biologists in trying to understand some of the most complex
around mean user modeling is extremely complex because of the interaction and the other activity
it is converted to heat
and to give you
some feeling for the incredible power of neutron star
if you make
this little
as little as ten grams
think of it as a
thirteen full-size marshmallow
and you throw marshmallow from a large distance on two neutron star the energy that's
released is comparable to the atomic bomb that was used the russian
ten gram objects thrown onto a neutron star the reason being that this velocity becomes
enormously high
if you put in
for the neutron star
a mass of about
ten two to three times ten to the thirty kilograms
and you take for the radius of the neutron stars
about ten kilometres
you'll find that that velocity becomes about
times ten to eight meters per second which is about seventy percent
of the
speed of light
because of this enormous speed one half the square is horrendously high is the conversion
of gravitational potential energy to kinetic energy and then ultimately
two weeks
no nature
transferring mass
at extraordinarily high rate
many of these binary systems there are at least
hundred and so did we know
in our own galaxy
the mass transfer rates
which i call the MDT
so is transfected from the donor onto the neutron star
that transfer rate
it is roughly
ten two to fourteen
a second
there's no ran this mass transfer rates
you can calculate
by multiplying it with
one half the square
how many joules per second are released in the form of kinetic energy that means
in the form of the form of heat and i call that the power of
the neutron star and that then for this mass
transfer rate that's about two times ten to the thirty
joules per second
which is what
and that is about five thousand times larger than the power of our own sun
but the temperature of these neutron star because of this enormous amount of energy released
the temperature will reach values of about ten million degrees kelvin and at that high
the neutron star would emit almost exclusively x-rays
you and i am very cold bodies only three hundred degrees kelvin we radiate electromagnetic
radiation in the infrared part of the spectrum we have warm bodies we also someone
in your arms you can feel that
if i
what need to update
two three thousand degrees kelvin you become red hot
you actually we could turn the light off and i would see you you just
remaining red light
if i would need to up to three million degrees you would start to begin
two radiates in x-rays you may not like it but that's the detail of course
so i wanted to appreciate the fact that the
the kind of radiation that you get
depends strongly on the temperature
and that ten million degrees you're dealing almost exclusively
so these binary system very potent sources of x-rays
the neutron stars rotate around we discover that we discussed earlier
conservation of angular momentum
and they have strong magnetic fields
matter that falls onto the neutron star already heats up doing in full
because the gravitational potential energy released and so the matter is so hot that in
general it's highly ionized
and highly ionized material can cannot reach
the magnetic
neutron star and all
locations that it prefers to do so a o two you will learn why that's
the case
however the matter can reach
the neutron star at the magnetic poles
so what you're going to see now is you're going have a neutron star
with magnetic poles
so the matter streams in on to the magnetic pole to give you two hot
and if the axis of rotation doesn't coincide
was the mind forty two hotspots if the neutron star rotates
you're going to see x-ray politicians
when the hotspot is here
or not
and the way it's going to do that is is in a random way
it's random but it's depends on its neighbors this node is going to decide whether
to flip is going to look at its four nearest neighbours
and what is going to do is
you've got value zeros and ones that these neighbours
and you can compute a certain kind of logistic function
is a very specific reason this function arises but i won't go into details if
it comes is the conditional probability from this
but what you want to take aways that all this node does a very simple
local update
just like message passing its local in diameter says
depending on this number on this sample uniform random variable
and based on that all decide whether flip or not
just going around the graph and you're just doing single site updates just flipping variables
and what's interesting is you can show that if you do this and you wait
long enough
the second part is key if you wait long enough
eventually you get a sample that's that's essentially a random sample that looks like an
image that's been drawn from this model
but in general you might have to wait a very long time
so these methods are always practical but but they're interesting methods
so the reason i mention this is because it it sort of gives nice parallel
to the class of methods that i'd like to talk about which
i called variational methods
we're going to see the
the message passing algorithms that we've already seen the ones that are exact
we're going to see those can be understood as variational methods that were also to
see that there are other algorithms actually ones that were understood before that look very
much like sampling there are also variational methods
and the motivation here's these algorithms for instance of discussing here the mean field algorithm
these algorithms are not exact anymore
that is going to give you approximations to the exact quantities
but i will see is that in certain cases they can give you very good
approximations to the exact quantities
and what's key is very cheap they're not exponential you're not doing things with the
tree with the graph you're doing dumb and local things
so this algorithm this mean field algorithm a special case of it it looks very
much like the gibbs sampler
except that there's is
everything that's been passed all the messages that are being passed just numbers there is
no sort of deciding to i flip or not there's just numbers going along edges
and this is very easy to implement
it's even simpler than belief propagation
the way it works is
you pick another random
that node looks its neighbors
each of its neighbors has some real numbers this is a real number between zero
and one
it just take these numbers inputs into this logistic function and updates itself in this
so what you sort of want to see here's there's a strong parallel between this
algorithm in gibbs sampling this this function here is basically the same function in the
structure of
picking a node and then looking at neighbours that's the same structure it's again purely
local it's just obeying the local graph structure
so it's something that can be done in parallel can be done very cheaply
but the question here is now
where did this come from it looks like i just took it out of the
what is this over them do doesn't converge
does it give reasonable answers
i mean it's nice because it's very cheap you could just implement this and maybe
three or four lines of matlab
cheap algorithms are interesting unless they do something reasonable
so c in certain cases this this kind of algorithm slide extensions of perhaps do
things that are reasonable
the second sort of motivation here is is coming back to what i spoke about
in the beginning part
we spoke about these message passing algorithms on trees
there we derive them from the elimination perspective we saw that they were exact algorithms
guys are just again doing dumb local computations but everything converges
and at the end of the day everybody is happy
so again just like the HMM these algorithms are real work courses in practice people
use these terms all the time for chains and for trees
but what i'd like to move on to to here is the interesting question well
you know not everything is the tree like we've discussed someone may well have graph
that has cycles
what's actually been done this seems like an incredibly stupid thing to do
well not stupid but naive
that's something that has turned out to work much better than i think anybody would
have expected people will have to take the same the exact same algorithm
the exact same message passing updates
and i just run the monograph that has cycles
right here i was running on the tree and here everything we discussed everything's nice
converges everything makes sense
there's nothing to stop me from just doing it when i have cycles
right the algorithm doesn't know
this node is just computing is taking messages is just some meaning sending things along
what he doesn't even know there a cycle cycle in this graph that he has
no idea that it's there
there's nothing to stop you from from implementing the algorithm for a general graph
but you might have some concerns about this
you know it's again no longer an exact algorithm
what does this mean to do this
it doesn't mean anything
before we did it you know the messages meant something they were
we're eliminating things in the messages were things we're sending to give partial information here
it's really not at all clear what's going on
so lots of questions i mean this to begin what does this mean what is
it doing questions doesn't converge
does it good good answers
if so when if not one behave badly there are all sorts of questions and
the only reason these questions are interesting is because people are using this all the
time in both communication theory and in computer vision
as two particular examples
sort of one way to understand why the algorithms approximate is
well there are many ways to understand it
maybe the simplest intuition is is the following
i i think this is a reasonable example
so i'd like to say this because
none of my colleagues from berklee are here in the audience began sort of think
graphical models
actually some people use graphical models whole area they use them to model social networks
right you think about sort of the nodes being people and edges are for instance
which people are friends which people are enemies
who talks to whom
people model things like gossip behaviour
gossip protocols
would be to actually have no activation function so i've linear
neuron just means that the activation function on my pre-activation
is just pre-activation itself that's not very interesting
we often have sigmoid units have you seen that in
on stock this morning so this sigmoid function has the property
that is essentially squashes pre-activation between zero and one
as you can see here so this is this axes pre-activation that's the
activation of the neuron you can see the squash between zero and
one it's always positive it is bounded and it's strictly increasing
so the hired pre-activation higher the activation
and the actual mathematical formula for the sigmoid is this here
it's one over one plus the exponential
of the negative pre-activation another popular choice is the tange
or hyperbolic tangent function in this case
mainly what changes it's it's it's quite similar to a sigmoid function
but instead it it's activation ranges between minus one and one
and so you have this somewhat more complicated formula which is
the exponential of pre-activation minus
exponential of minus pre-activation
divided by exponential the pre-activation plus the exponential
of the negative pre-activation this is one way of computing it
you could multiply the numerator and denominator by the
exponential of the activation exponential ok and then you get this
formula which is slightly more interesting just because
here we only have to compute one exponential exponential twice
pre-activation and exponential is more are
actually expensive to compute that can be a
more convenient more form compassionately
and filey probably right now the most popular activation function
is the rectifier a linear activation you are function
we often refer to those as a rare this is painful re l
move ok for rectified linear unit
as if you see this in papers is refer to the usage of this activation
function rectified linear activation function
it is bounded below by zero but it is not upper bounded
it's also increasing not strictly though because here it's
not it's actually flat it's a stake and then
it in practice it will tend to give when you train neural net with
a rather units will tend to give you a sparse activities which
is property we observe empirically and the function itself
is simply the maximum between zero and pre-activation so the pre-activation
is larger zero you get a linear function
but if it's below zero you get a flat zero output zero activation
right question on that ok so what is the cap as capacity of single
neuron what kind of things can we achieve
and represent using a single neuron so we've seen this
picture already and you can just looking at this already see
that at it seems we are able to represent a linear decision boundaries
so perform linear classification so indeed
if we think of single neuron and we use the sigmoid activation
function one thing we could do for want to take the probabilistic
approach of classifiers that are going to describe this to think
of the activation of that neuron as representing what is the
probability that for some given input x
the label associated with my input is one
so think of in mind tation a assume sometimes a binary classification
problem which case the positive class is one
and the negative class going to be zero
so this actually corresponds to the model behind logistic regression
that are going represented and so if you want to make a prediction
that is assigned the label to some given input
we would just compute are activation of the neuron linear transformation
followed by a sigmoid and with threshold zero point five weibull
if that represents the models predictive distribution over the
label y if it's if it's values are the zero point five it means
it thinks it's more likely that belong to the class one in class
zero and that's how you would get a classifier performing a classification
using sing neuron is one can easily see that you would essentially
be drawing a line in your input space between the positives and negatives
so what's kind of function you represent i'm going to use a very
simple example of boolean functions which is a classic example
for explaining why we want more than just a single artificial neuron
so it's also those even though it's simple it's kind of interesting
in a sense that you know if we would like to use neural nets to
perform some kind of logical reasoning
we would probably want such functions of neural nets to be able
to represent sort and simply simple move and operations
to representing three different boolean operations so here are true
represented by one and falls by zero so we have the or function
the or function would output true one
if any of its input x one and x to
z at is equal to one so in this case so the triangles would be the
positive class so we can see if at either
this dimension that dimension is equal to one we are in the positive
class and output of one f and otherwise both zero we get a zero
so we can see that in this case it is easy to draw a line that separates
all the positives from the negatives so we can represent that
with a single neuron and other function is the and function i'm
here i'm showing the and function on the negative of the first
argument and the second argument so in this case
and will be equal one or true only if both arguments are one so
that means that x one x one since i'm taking it's negative needs
to be zero and then x to needs to be one that's why i have a
positive example here and all the others either one is going to
be zero so i get the negative class and again in this situation
i can easily chop the space using a line into the positive and
negative and same thing for and where applied
negative on another argument so all these function that can represent
with a single neuron however right take a slightly more complicated
really not that complicated function the x or function which
is equal to one output true if either one
is equal to true the other false or vice versa
so this case in this case this would be positive examples zero one
and one zero the other with an output of one
and any other combinations to ones or to zeros would be
the one on the right to the one on the left
in fact
they're not superimpose we're looking at here is essentially
a pair of gloves
this is considered the left hand and this is the right hand and you can
close the gloves you can make them fit one against the other
they will here
one another
across mirror planes
but they are not superimposed upon
you know as opposed to something like say propane if i take propane which is
also carbon sp three hybridized
propane in contrast has
math all above
and below
and that clearly
perfectly symmetric and
doesn't have such a glove like
feature such molecules that have we say a handedness
are called chiral
chiral from the greek word for here
so chirality is the property of
having handedness
nine super impose upon
we call these another term for these is stereo isomers
we can consider
chiral molecules stereo isomers
stereo listeners
and the different che hands if you will the different hands are called in and
and and tumours
we don't refer to one stereo lies somewhere in the other story my so we
refer to the and and humor coming from the greek word for mirror and uses
the greek word from here so these are
mirror images
the other thing about this is that they are optically active
and what they will do is they will take polarized light
rotated through
a degree
of polarisation here just to give you another example of the difference between something that's
chiral and i see the box at the top with no distinguishing features they can
be twisted and turned and made
superimposed over one another by putting these little features in the bottom corner we render
these boxes chiral
no matter how you twist and turn this box you will be able to superimpose
on top the other box
here's more complicated molecule that can come chemically identical
he has
a right-handed version are left-handed version
so let's talk about optical activity
the only reason i refer to this is that it gives the labels
that are used in referring to one
versus the other so if you have a light source that just gives
like that randomly polarized that is to say it's not polarized and then you put
it through a polarizing prism so that the light is polarized in a certain direction
others electric vector is only in one direction
now now the polarized light here it's indicating that
there is polarized vertically
this is the optically active substance which could include an aqueous solution of alani
and if the aqueous solution of alamein consists of only one and here are only
one and tumour
then when the polarized light passes through that solution
the plane of polarization will be rotated
a certain amount by interaction of the light with the electrons in the orbitals in
this particular molecule and
what you see here is
angle of rotation alpha
where alpha is proportional to the concentration of the chiral species and also the path
length through the
the solution
so if we put in both
and and tumors we expect no change if we put in one and actually
we will have
one direction
and so
it turns out that
the different and humorous will cause different directions of rotation and this is how they
are labeled so the one that i've shown here on the right
it will cause
a clockwise rotation of the light
and so it is termed
as indexed wrote tree from the latin word for word
dex wrote
the to tory
this the dexter for rotary form
and one here on the left will cause
the light the right age new here it's the it's the it's the plane of
polarization of the light it's a right so the plane of polarization
if it went through a solution that consist of only the and and humor
depicted on the left it would move in the left direction and even though the
latin word for left sinister they didn't call it sinister auditory the college level
wrote to tree
because they had slavic languages together
a report so level rotary is this one dexter rotary some will cause
we call this the positive
and and more
on the left when the negative
and and humor but in most of the reading the you'll encounter it will be
the the d
and the l
it turns out that only
the l four
only the l form of amino acids are found in proteins
in and humor
of amino acids
good afternoon everybody
it's my pleasure to introduce the fifth called the lecture series speakers today
and we are introducing professor neil james is university distinguished professor
your science and engineering at michigan state
it is also a member of the electrical faculty
doctor changes in species diversity in nineteen seventy three
something like this
distinguished researchers here the pattern recognition computer vision
and biometrics
if you look at his
can online you
quickly come across some rather impressive numbers five hundred ninety seven papers
eighty thousand citations
h-index and one hundred thirty three which in computer science second
thirty six species students advised in his career eighteen those since the year two thousand
i happen
one of them
better for the experience
you see
thirty books
six patterns
fell i hear are actually
it in
the recipe he
that's for sciences so without further ado
history professor jane to speak about large scale data clustering
i'd like
to a little bit about
there are some problems in science is known it
become more interesting
at the time
so far
data clustering is one such problem
i was first introduced the last thing i'd like
in nineteen seventy
at the time was
to not published
right now
draft a copy of the book
and the
it's very easy to describe the problem
the problem is very simple for people
in this room
can be partitioned into
so the number of rules based on some
that's all
that's what that's what clustering is
and that's why has fascinated scientists
every discipline information from biology to
computer science to marketing psychology
anyway these data
has to deal with
two ways about it
and the reason why it's getting more interest now
because all the data we see the web
the text images
all of the new
you know you've
hundreds of millions of
on you
you have to somehow organised state
data clustering is a convenient way
so in this organization
it had over fifty years of history
and let me also w
simplest clustering algorithm
it's called kings
some of
you can write the keys at time
one in ten lines of
and it is still the most widely used
even though
all the
the problem is that it was published
no good
can you
so so this problem
it's really exciting
and now that
i did the title of my talk for large data data with document
it doesn't
so i know it doesn't give you some labelled data
and then the
introduction to clustering
and then
some of the
my keys to the
likely contd
large scale clustering and all that
cluster one billion points
thousands of features into
tens of thousands of clusters
so this is a city of london
the reason we are doing is basically
an approximation in
so some statistics about the
the following
forty years ago
started doing clustering the points where
large one of the was
last time
link is not on the
but now not going to be killed by the way
it's not to
you know
the power
only one
so now know the new
when we see the lights
the data was created
and the estimated by thousand fifteen
will be
for some reason idea
introduced nature
that's not just me
one data
it's also velocities is
the world
aspect to it
the nineteen eighties heterogeneous data is not all numbers
edition of the
so heterogeneous
it's also
structured data and unstructured
so you
some statistics on on
information is on the on
so these
i'm sure numbers exceeded
nine hundred million million o
two one five billion
five hundred divided by data
have to
one million years old
have to do with you
well i was smart
the interesting statistics
but in the house
be many more like was both
it is also in the
one hundred twenty five million users rating it
tweets per
this is mind-boggling amount
that is being generated somewhat
statistics from
one five million
every day
to forty thousand
more than one trillion euros
so the idea that all the data you need to extract information from it so that
you can make it lies
so that's what this is what to do with it
next generation to make decisions
even companies like walmart
and similar result for another example
OK pretty much finished actually just wanted to draw
attention to
an important area that i haven't covered in detail yet that's the combination of MCMC
with particle filters and there are two principal schemes that that i'm aware of there
are other of other things with different flavours particle the so-called particle MCMC which is
an iterative algorithm for batch parameter estimation but here i'm talking about sequential schemes that
use MCMC
so back it should be there about that so the idea
in the first game is very simple
it says that after resampling importance sampling filter you've got some particle trajectories that are
drawn at least approximately from the smoothing density up to time t
since those already
nominally at least drawn from the correct entity
if i simply applied an MCMC kernel with this thing as its target density
for example you common thing to do would be to apply fixed like gives
gives within a metropolis hastings
sample on the
on on a lack of data points going some way into the past
conditional upon everything else
then the intuition is that as the MCMC converges the particle representation is going to
get closer to the true target density so we can actually just improve performance by
applying a few iterations of our chosen favor
mcmc scheme or particles
because we are nominally already converged we don't have to diagnose really the convergence of
the chains
we just know will likely to improve things a little bit by running these a
few steps of these MCMC is and this is the the well-known resample move scheme
berzuini in-jokes from nineteen ninety eight some related work on similar scheme down a little
bit about quetion clyde and you very effective schemes
because it doesn't remove the importance sampling element you still waiting in then resampling before
you go into your MCMC so i think this is an add-on it's just basically
the particle filter then run some MCMC on a limited part of the state space
and improve the situation
but slightly more
it was not really a more recent idea but a perhaps more fundamental idea
it's simply get rid of the importance sampling altogether but still stay
within the sequential
and you'll recall
that the SMC scheme
can be thought of this is the first thing i revised started this talk SMC
scheme is simply approximating the updated filtering density
in terms of the previous particle representation from not t time some other terms the
state transition density the observation density of constant
or equivalently so that's represented on the joint space of the path we can integrate
out x not through t and just look at the marginal t plus one then
you have the formation of a state transition kernels overall centered on all the particles
nothing to say
what see seeing what monte carlo algorithm you have to use here so the
the point is why not simply run MCMC on this or this or combinations of
the two
so this one has some benefits of being marginalized spaces reduced dimensional space but very
heavy computational at evaluating this likelihood function in the MCMC because you've got salvation over
and is this
joint space that doesn't apply because this these is direct functions so you don't end
up having to evaluate all and these reach likelihood
evaluation in the MCMC so that this one might be statistically better but very expensive
to to compute in practice we would prefer this one
and you can run MCMC directly on this target
using whatever your favourite scheme is there gibbs sampler you can apply to regenerate the
the initial state sequence from its point mass representation run metropolis hastings on elements of
the state vector and that's the important point actually is you can spread the state
vector ron gibbs sampling type steps on bits of it conditional on the other you
not start with the importance sampling paradigm that says you have to generate the whole
that in one go and if it has a long way to go about fit
to the density tough
you've lost the game so you've got the possibility of converging refining your sampling representation
so i don't really goes back right back to some some work in nineteen ninety
seven by one jokes and can they operated sample from the joint space a recently
more easily the computer vision people have done things on this
the marginal space with reversible jump samples but they are very effective schemes and quite
promising we've some papers in in just about to go to print at the moment
developed these schemes further show how how effective they can be also very difficult structured
state space models violating learning hierarchical model sequentially over time effectively
but i really have run out of time more than run out of time i
hope i've
it the particle filters are very interesting thing to pursue for hard problems powerful computationally
colour most of the basics i couldn't get through everything by any means in in
in the three hours in particular are not covered very much about parameter estimation so
brief example of that with our estimation of alpha and they are stable noise i
didn't get a chance to to talk about SMC samplers and population monte carlo which
is quite a hot topic at the moment in the area
seventy exist in all different levels
so for for example when we use sensors to detect the presence of animals
but when reports is a movement of animals you might not be correct
he made mistake other phenomenon as a movement of the animals
so in this level and uncertainty because it's seeing whether this event happens or not
so it's because the existence uncertainty
so this is the up
up to
go figure something so this is because the term couple level of certainty
so in this example and opted to take a probability to appear
in the table
but the examples for example the the the the example
we know that there is one record of posthumous
the thing that we were not sure about is the social security number of miss
you might be one eighty five or seven eighty five
so in this example the uncertainty only lies in one attribute
we just don't know is correct
and that of this attribute
it's called the output level of uncertainty
so in this actually level uncertainty and that to build an object takes a few
possible values
and then we may have a probability density function over the possible values
i will introduce the two different uncertainty one by one
so first of all the publicity that this model is always
after used to fly up to the top level of uncertainty
in this example this is are table all the speed of car detected by radar
because the radio radar and they may be interfered by
high voltage lines or the close by car interference so the problem may not be
one hundred percent correct
for example for t one contains the time relocation car make plate number and speed
of the a car
but due to the uncertainty we we may associate with a confidence value with this
it means that this temple only takes the probability of zero point four
to be existing in that table
and in addition to that the plate number of cars are identified by human operators
this may also introduce uncertainty
for example
t two and t three there the
o records about the same card the plate number fame
but the passion time quite close
with the addition can quite close by the relocation are far away
and also the reading of speed are quite different
so between these two titles we know that only one could be true
we use a generation rule
to specify this explosiveness between the two temples
the same situation of also happens to t four and t five
so in summary in probabilistic database you can test a lot a set of probabilistic
and each table the values of each table are sorted
but each table carries existing or membership probability
in addition we may have generation rules to specify the constraints among those couples
then we can make another example in the survey data we have records about smith
and the wrong when we create an uncertain table to describe in this case
in this uncertain table we have
four records
OK so for this last bit going to talk about the sierra called belief
change article believe change what people call belief revision
and as i say the basic idea again this is another application of logic in
this case we're just going to look at the
propositional case there's a lot of work on the first order case and so on
again people to tackle this problem using different logics modal logics and so on in
but as we can look at a fairly simple
propositional model get an application of logic
as an application to the following problems
you want to sort of figure out how
some reason who is maintaining beliefs about their environment
firstly how they maintain their police and secondly how those beliefs
should change
the reason to obtain new information about the
so that's state that sort of simple statement of the problem
anyway the beginning never wants to go forward
OK now
as i say now what we're going to look at a particular price are quite
of few approach to this problem but just to try and introduce the area going
to take
perhaps the approach that's the most commonly encountered one in literature
now what will see is that at the end of the day this approach that
sits at one end of the spectrum which is probably the more idealized in the
spectrum in terms of belief change approaches
but when you leave reading literature billy change this is invariably approach the people mentioned
and measure the
they're approaching its
OK so let's take an example suppose you have the following believes these ones are
and if they say that the word caught in this trap is this one
secondly the but according to track comes from sweden
sweden is part of europe and all europeans wonder so these are ablaze
now from the six possibilities in
consequences so one of the consequences that the bird caught in the trap is white
why is that the case well we know that all europeans once alliance sweden this
part of your according to track conditions within
should be sufficient to prevent calls
OK now suppose we're told that the boy caught in the trap is black
now that
contradicts the belief that we currently have so obviously there's something wrong
in our in this set of beliefs that we hold
so the question to you is which
a sentence or sentences
of the initial belief said
would you give up
OK great why
so you think it's like the last one you take before you make consequence
right OK
again the exile that's great
so one great
one for the has any other guesses as to what you might throw away
good beginning there while the second one
right good
good so it sort of sounds a bit dodgy right you might be able to
figure that out just by looking at this
but you know what got apologies to go out there and actually take the DNA
and it just happened that swedish d
could be
i didn't know that the birds were in this way
anyone else want to hazard
when only one or maybe something else
all europeans wonder why why is that
because you probably need a lot of to
figure that out right in a lot of europe efficiently was once you need to
figure out where the european and then way
what about the third one
you're all pretty happy with the way
so it's not part of the european union i decided to call to the
OK now my claim is that if you take it these are expressed in logical
logic which is what we want to do it then there's no reason was released
at this point
claiming that any of these forms is better than any other
so as far as i'm concerned any of these funds could be removed
any of them is a good choice
the only reason
we sort of triumph a
so performers
so the pre leaf for emotional factors or perhaps maybe we know a little bit
more than i explicitly written down on the
on the slide here maybe some you might claim that was not just a matter
whether believe something i don't believe something is allowed to shades of gray here and
really strongly believe that you know europe a source which this part of europe
but i less strongly believe that you know one
that all europeans wonder why something like
in this slide here are just illustrated one example is the same as far as
i'm concerned you can remove any of those sentences
what i've done is i've done another sort of trivial thing and that is taken
one of the sentences
that all your spain's wonder why have we can slightly
and a sense what i've done is i've taken it sensorimotor but i've replaced its
energy from moving and throwing it away which is sort of what i was originally
it is a taking the sentence i removed it i've replaced by
one of its consequences
and this consequences that
all europeans ones except for some of the swedish ones away
but as i say this point if we will have to transcend the problem into
logic propositional formulas then there's no
the reason to favour one over the
OK so the lesson at this point is the logical considerations alone not sufficient to
answer this question is going to need to have something more
large enough to assign
degrees of belief maybe probabilities and to do something to these formulas to help me
answer this question to make this choice
i think this is going to have a look at the general idea belief change
and then i'm going to focus on this AGM account of belief change which is
the most common one literature
h images the initials of the people that came up with the initial idea
OK so
so the diagrammatic form this is what
the problem looks like
you've got your reason in there are some in some belief state
o epistemic state in computing tend to like abuse all the words in the english
the stomach is more about knowledge belief but anyway just take it to be some
be the number of common friends to people have and this is the probability that
they will send email to each other and again the whole reason for this pot
here is that again we see the diminishing returns type of curve where first few having
a few friends adds a lot to the curve and then less and less
this is exactly if you remember from before we had this submodularity property right
and it seems that properties is good right because we observe this diminishing returns
so this is now let's take a step back and see what we are really doing
right for example for viral marketing for the study I will go into more
detail about it later all we see is that some node received the i-th recommendation
and then purchases a product or doesn't do anything for communities again what we see
is that that some time T
they they decided we see behavior of their friends and then we see that the particularly
node decided to join the community so there are there are there are questions like when
did this node become aware of the recommendations of of a friend right so when when when
when did they became aware of I know that their friends adopted how did this translate
into their decision to act right I mean we only have like one
trace of of of what was going on right we don't know whether they
were watching television or not what what newspapers they read and so on and also we don't know
what was the lag between the the decision to buy and the act right so these are all questions
one can ask here and go exploi explore them here's there are also more subtleties to
everything so for example here here's one one thing that you can you can ask right so
if this is if this is some predefined some community of people and now we have
two candidates to to join right they all have like three friends in the
group but the friends of Y are all connected among themselves while X has like
friends that don't know each other and the question is who is more likely to
join right and there are two competing theories or two possible explanations for this so first
first one is called the information argument and the information argument says that unconnected friends
give you the independent support so this would mean that having independent friends is better because they sort of
each one gives you a independent opinion and having more independent opinions is better so
this theory would say that X is more likely to join the social capital arguments on the
other hand says that trust in having friends who know each other is what we really
value right so we want to have we don't we want to have people that
we want to have a set of friends who are all friends among themselves so
that we can hang hang out with them once we join the group right so this would mean that you
get independent support while here you have you have a highly connected set of friends in
there and that gives you a lot of social capital because you can hang out with them
so  for the livejournal data set we can go and measure this so we can ask how
does the community joining probability increase with the number of connections between the friends and
what turns out that is actually that the and the connectedness of these friends
if you want to if if you if you define these as a
as a prediction task where you want to be able to predict whether a node
will join the network join the group or not and I don't know train a decision tree
then number and connectedness of these friends is the most important feature so this is the
first split in the decision so now so basically what this is means is
that the more so the more the friends are connected the better so what
what the experiment says is that this is if if this is the case you
are more likely to join the group then this but then one can go
on and ask a different question so if connectedness among friends promotes joining
then do highly connected groups right groups that have high clustering coefficient so groups where a lot of
friends are friends among themselves are they growing more quickly right because if if people join to
them with higher probability because they are highly connected are they are they also growing quicker right
so we define clustering as the number of triangles in the network over the number
of open triads or land to paths and now we ask we
look at the growth as a function of clustering and here's here's the plot right
this clearly shows that as as the clustering increases the growth sort
of sort of decreases right so groups that have large clustering grow slower
and this is not just because the groups would have fewer fewer nodes so this
could maybe be explained by saying that all older groups sort of saturated and they
and they don't grow for that reason there are more subtleties when thinking about
this is an example from viral marketing so one easy question to
ask is does sending more recommendations influence more purchases right so here would be the
total number of recommendations somebody sent and this is the number of people that
would buy that product okay and the reason we can we can get get this curve because
we have this total record of what was going on because the recommendations were sent
through email people would get discounts so they were incentivized to really go and buy something
okay and what you can see here is that again we have a increase
up to I know around thirty forty recommendations right it's a superlinear growth and then it sort of stabilizes sort of slows down
and this is this is also something that one would want to want this is even more
surprising here so if you say what is the effectiveness of subsequent recommendations between two