not optimal solution to a problem
contains optimal solutions
two some
we're trying to
so here for example
OK if
this is the longest common subsequence of x and y
is a
one is common subsequence
the prefix
so this is basically
the problem i can see that there is optimal substructure going on
in this case
and the idea is that almost always this means that there a cut-and-paste argument you
can do to demonstrate
it is the
some structure were not optimal
and you be able to find
eight their solutions to the overall
using cut-and-paste
his as a strategy for being able to compute the longest common subsequence
so ignore these cases
basically just implementing
is there
so it's either
the longest common subsequence if
if the match
one common subsequence of one
the prefix that we drop that character
both strings one
that's the matching one
drop a character from
in fact since longest common subsequence of
you draw a character from y
which everyone knows is one
it ends up being
longest common subsequence
which is what's the worst case
this program was going to happen in the worst case
which of these two clauses
causes more havoc
the second one second
during two LCS calculus up calculations here only do when i to decrement
this is here
basically go
you only get decrement one indexing i calculate two of the that's can generate
the tree on the worst case
x y
it is not equal to j e
and j
let's draw a recursion tree
this program
circuit understanding as to what's going on
i mean do we have an equal say and
and it also six
most of the time with my two indices being seven six
and then the worst case we have to execute these
so this is going to end up being
six six
and seven five
during this is after
first call
in this guise because we're is going to be
produced by six here
first index i
i keep going down here in
four six
you guys
standing here i get
six five
six four
OK over here
the first index six five
these guys
here i get more
they get sixty four
just getting what costa photocopying by thing in and eric and i are just you
know roman and so so it's probably cheap enough right
you can you can finally get one more general one without being too much obsolete
that said people i think in general find course reader to be an asset we
do not require reading it does have a lot of material with very
useful and can understand the cause there are people who don't make is as big
a use of that but there are some sections i think there is really very
very valuable and the ones that may be more or less depending on the kind
of your learning style whether you you appreciate more chance to be background material more
examples and there's also a lot of good sample problems in an interview questions that
helped texture understanding
you know it's tricky
right because the the universe in general discouraged from giving alternate exams
because of of you can imagine the issues of having a example actually has been
seen by some members to before some numbers since take it even though we're all
bound by the honor code it does can create situation where there is some temptation
it so it's possible to to be a little bit earlier without logging that but
i think we have to make a lot of help is the truth rate we
can talk about it that but the point is is is not i would say
so if if there's something really important about that you know that you definitely know
your enemy around the exam week that's going to be a problem you need to
talk to me
and then what about compilers that we
you see both pos and we also use some custom libraries which limits us to
us to determine a certain number of platforms we've had a good chance to test
on and work with so the compilers that we have support for a is x
connect ajax code is apple's free developer tools so anybody with mac OS ten can
freely download that source libraries were using microsoft visual studio version two thousand five on
windows and we have arranged with microsoft where they have distributed the software free of
charge to students so on
if you would like to install and run windows computer which gives some handouts on
friday that tell you
what you need to do to kind of go get the comparison get installed on
two system so thank you to make sure that and are cluster computers in the
dorms in libraries and
the layer
are you have both of our the maximum pcs have compilers and libraries installed issues
working clustering do anything special it just walk up and it's got the stuff ready
to go
well i can ask me that is televised high and that person and that person
forever so i can get over the fact that you go to the start menu
to shut the machine down that makes when is impossible for radius so that i
was in the campus wide you know this big people probably there is far more
windows machines and max on campus so if you
i want to take a popular vote you do that but if you want to
be on the side of the mac big you can can be with me that's
good i get to the rest of the visual studio also seems perfectly serviceable
well look this i got ten minutes more
to the people
because that is the next journey right we're going to go on together
but also like the which i think is why are we doing this do you
like i i just java and now you tell me to throw in my job
and start over OK so let's let's look
in general below for the c plus plus OK
but the advantages of early multilingualism so i have two small children
two and four and the lot about bilingualism and stuff to raise your children chemical
world and there's not very clear evidence for natural language is right that when you
acquiring language you know at the young age is right that that the best time
to introduce the second or third language we're kind of building all the pathways in
honor of this really training research there and so the same thing that in terms
of programming languages as well that when you're learning a programming language right there are
certain kind of of rocks your mind gets into about the way language is that
it is based on your experiences early on and if you spend a very long
time working only in one language the wreckage deeper and you have a certain way
of thinking where you are stuck in that paradigm and its approach what's easy to
do in that language was hard to do in that language right now tends to
make a stronger impression on you know it makes it harder as you as you
grow and explore the languages to get out right to kind of shake itself that
it so there's been some pretty good evidence that actually that about one-quarter between one
and two is a really good time actually think about branch and a little bit
and starting to think about different ways of doing that and seeing some different interactions
some different ideas to help cannot just create building the flexibility from an early age
in your career to kind of by u
some strength later so that's what we're doing some of part it is actually a
lot of the upper division courses right rely on knowledge of c and c plus
plus the family of languages and the longer we postpone the kind of more painful
it becomes because the
in the later courses right we learn about compilers are graphics or networking they don't
have the
time of process stop and teachers seriously plus possible they need no simple fast to
get the work done in sort of where we going make sure you get the
foundation and to remove you get an improvement classes to make the most sense in
the context of our curriculum so we we do switch over here the good news
is right is that it's not is big changes it might sound first one seven
going from a totally different language which job actually highly derivative c possible superstar writer
for a fixed now
we consider
this is
essentially conditioned on a fixed
double sample
and then we take expectation that over the choice of the double samples
so we fix the double sample
we consider permuting the elements what is the probability that when we permit
by random choice from the sense that we have zero error on the right on
the left-hand side only on the training sample and epsilon o two error
on the ghost sample
essentially know independently we can think of independently swapping these guys
and how many of those what can we do
in such away
but we end up with all of the errors on the right-hand side OK so
the overall in the whole double sample their exon
and over two this is an error rates because they're in the second sample the
actual number of barrels is epsilon over two
or at least that many
so epsilon m over two
errors in this double sample
in order for this property to be true
in other words for this
this quantity this
being here to hold we need all of those areas to be on the right-hand
i can say OK
and because of the way we've chosen to problem the the set of sigma we
have essentially
independently the probability is one half of swapping those
OK so that particular error on the site and its corresponding point on the other
side could be swapped
but we're not allowed to do that's what if we're going to keep this property
that all of the errors on the right-hand side
so very effectively that reduces the number of permutations that we can apply by half
each time for each error
the probability
over this random choices to to the minus epsilon over two
essentially half
times to the power of the number of errors
but we have on the right-hand side
so for each of those i mean you can do just accounting argument is another
way of thinking of it counts the permutations
but actually leave those guys on the right-hand side but it's all permutations that do
anything to the other pairs but don't change
the set of points so as to to the
you know and minus on and two and then divided by two to the end
because that's the total number of permutations of that is that the ratio of the
number that keep it happy with those that
and that these two the minus epsilon two and the expectation that this is not
independent of the
of the actual set of sample points so
the expectation is bounded the for every set of samples
double samples
it's bounded by two the mindset from end two then certain expectations bounded by two
concepts on two
any questions
OK so the question was
thank you right was that
how do limitations affect the ghost sample of choice because some effectively
OK so i think
at the point where we start applying these
limitations here
at this point here
we've effectively forgotten in a way that there was a sample of ghost sample
and what we're thinking of doing is randomly mixing points with the ghost and between
the ghost and the true sample
so sort interchanging
and was saying OK
because of the way the probability stack up it shouldn't make any difference if we
those two
and but we find out that this is significant number we aren't allowed to swap
because if we did it would actually make invalidate conclusions that we would join
and so
we're working out the fraction of those which invalidates and saying OK
the probability then is bounded by that fraction
OK effectively what we're saying is that the the errors if there are a lot
it's weird that they're on the right-hand side
that's weird it's unlikely you know it because you know this is an even training
set this it shouldn't be there although there is on the right hand side
and that we're bounding the unlike unlikely
likelihood of that event
this is just a technical way symmetrisation technical way of sort of
making that intuition sort of
the other
questions is OK
so the trick again is just too
to consider this probability that the event holds under these random permutations where we swap
corresponding elements
and we know that
in order to have this whole all of the error elements have to stay in
and that's actually quite useful because many of the best algorithms things like plan shows
methods or conjugate gradient for computing eigen values are actually what they're actually doing is
trying to solve this problem there are actually optimisation algorithms
so we're going to see is the max product and the sum product algorithms are
also optimisation algorithms
and didn't even talk about lagrange multipliers in
OK so what we're going to see is that the messages
right these kind of mysterious things here that are being updated that i just sort
of pulled out of the hat we're going to see is if you take the
logarithm of these messages those are going to be the lagrange multipliers for certain constraints
right so whenever constrained optimisation problem and the messages are going to be away via
lagrange multipliers are trying to enforce the constraints that's that's the variational interpretation
OK so let me
that was my review so if you're fast you so i was going to say
let's let me work through it on this like so i think it's better for
me and for you
OK so let's
let me do a simple reformulation let's again go back to a maximisation problem
and let's
the sort of think about a different way
a different perspective we could take on that problem
right so we do have a simple example will do just three notes that that
sort of toy example but the ideas are general
so it's me who's making the paper
it doesn't take a rocket scientist to figure out why is that why am i
so dirty
OK so let's do px one x two x three
that's what we're doing is we're maximizing
this is the concrete let's do an example where everything is binary it is to
get the intuition
so what you're doing is you're trying to maximize this over
overall binary configurations
let me put the logarithm here too
it doesn't matter if i maximize p or i maximise log of p
let's think about a distribution factorizes let me do it
up there on the slide i have overwritten the compatibility is in the form e
to the data three
exponential theta two three let me use those just because when i take logarithms and
i'll get the fate is that will come down
so if i use that form that i have up there this would be something
like max
of x one x two x three
again binary and then i would get some
i get some over as equals one to three
they state as x of s
and then i will get some over the edges in my graph whatever they are
of the pairwise functions
there might be a constant here too but we don't care about that someone trying
to be constant from the normalisation
OK so everything geometrically this is why i like this small example this is not
a graphical model this this is that the space over which were searching
the space over which searching is just binary hypercube
it was searching over all configurations like zero zero zero here in one one one
and zero one zero and so on
right what makes the problem hard of course is that in high dimensions of a
hypercube has many different vertices has exponentially many
so what we're going to do is instead of searching over that space
what i do this and introduce
some other distribution
it's called the distribution q
so it's going to be
a probability distribution over all binary vectors
and i'm going to maximize
the expectation
so let me call this whole cost function
it's called c
x of data it's
the cost function that depends on experts parameterized by data i could instead let's call
it el maybe because you see the article l x of theta
the claim is that
i could instead solve this problem
so we need to think about why this is the same thing to do
so by the probability simplex in this case i just mean eight dimensional vectors
nonnegative entries because that the probabilities and the sum to one
right and what i'm doing is i maximizing over those vectors in any one of
those vectors i can use it to take an expectation of my cost function
so why are these two problems the same that's the question
right so he said that your optimal solution what you would do is say one
one one was optimal configuration you can always recover that by making q put mass
one on
that configuration and zeros everywhere else
so that
it's not clear to just sort of think about a little bit in one direction
this direction is certainly clear
because by doing this unjust just enlarging the space
and i'm taking the convex hull somehow instead of just the vertices of to bigger
because of the special structure of the objective function because the objective function is linear
then in fact equality does hold here
OK so it seems like OK fine but that doesn't really help us yet because
i started with an exponentially large discrete space and now i have an exponentially large
continuous space the set of all probability distributions
right so it sort of seems like OK playing games but you haven't made the
problem any easier
but now we can do is expectations are linear
and your cost function is linear and has terms that break up into turns on
nodes in terms of edges
so what i can do is i can move
this is an expectation all use the shorthand
e for expectation under q
of l
right that's the shorthand i can
i can use that push the expectation inside the subterms
so what will happen is that this will be equal to the maximum
what i'm going to get here is a sum
over my notes
of expectation under q of
the node terms
expectation under q of an edge terms
that's using linearity of expectation
OK so that looks a bit more hopeful because somehow there's some amusing that i'm
two true known motif in this example so it has biological meaning
and the red guy which is actually slightly more stable
biologists a reasonable one but i don't want to make more claims to others good
additional supportive evidence
but is
stop there but nevertheless by one of the true ones and an interesting one which
is stable
so what can we learn from these examples
using the is haslam that just from las
four is serialised said before this is very questionable it
from a theoretical point of view many things can go wrong as i explained before
if you even would get something out here
the issues you have not sign any measure of somehow uncertainty
or stability or something like that
and this is no way what i would like to
so this is what we call stability selection which is exactly this idea
it's based on subsampling or bootstrapping is not the big deal here
and so let's begin worked first for the linear model international you also things for
africa so here's my linear model
i want to have the set of active variables
now i have a
variable selection procedure your favourite one the last a prime example just you know it
but it's hard land land some sort of regularisation parameter but you can use boosting
or you can use whatever your favourite feature selection algorithm
this is the setting
now what you do is what i just explained
you draw a subsample of sydenham
without replacement denoted by i started subsample run the selection algorithm on this i start
on these random subsample i do it many times and at the end of the
i just count the relative selection frequencies which you can write you down with the
peace dollar i have the probability that the j th covariate
it's actually selected
among these subsampling runs OK
this is nothing else in the relative selection frequencies if you do it on the
OK you could use bootstrap sampling gives you empirically and theoretically almost the same result
OK then what are you doing this this now you just have
this thing here
and then you want to say OK now
what is it good variable while a hundred percent
stability great ninety six percent is pretty good
but what about eighty percent is stable or not should we have this variable or
and i will come to this point
but just
define now the set of stably selected variables these are just the covariance between relatives
selection frequency is bigger than a certain threshold because the percent between nineteen percent
don't pick your ninety five percent from confidence interval this is quite a different story
OK now the thing will be the choice of this threshold and i will come
to that in a so
so there's also the issue
people look at the regularisation path and you can do that here as well
is modified finish never stable variable
you say i'm mean here i have relative selection frequencies
as a function of my regularisation parameter here was for the land and then i
just see which of the variable
pops up a lot which not
and that just brought racial line defined
to the set of state variables as the one where the relative selection frequencies just
show this line that some of these land k so whenever a line goes above
whenever curve goes above a fixed threshold variable is in my statement
OK so this is a bit exploratory but it's quite interesting to see what's happening
so this is again my riboflavin my by the production example i've shown to the
very beginning
so why is the riboflavin production rate exceeds high dimensional covariance
and now i do this but i just briefly mention to break into the senior
artificial semen synthetic data
what i do is i have six
variables six covariates
which are important also from the biological point of view i leave them
that permute all other variables
so by doing that i know all these permuted variables they have to be noise
variables if it
this is noise i know about the noise and not a hundred percent sure about
through but i think the six variables or through real variables
now you have here the last so regularisation of solution path as a function of
this is quite common that you look at the regularisation path and the path
the lines the red line to correspond to the six non permuted variables supposedly the
true variables
and the black lines correspond to attributed the noise variables
and here is the stability selection scale here is the relative selection frequencies again the
red one the non permuted black then always able bodied to see exploratory from these
fifty four or up to six through variables
the red line here they stick out much more clearly from the noise covariance
and here in your original as to just by looking at this picture i hope
i can convince you that the stability selection scale so to speak have a much
better chance such that the true signal can be distinguished from noise
OK clearly i mean the stability selection is not just the issue using the land
the right it just provides the fundamentally
different solution path and this one is from the last of these outer subset exercise
OK an interesting question is really there should be put the threshold right how should
you choose to traditional
and he was an answer which is kind of based on some
theoretical or guiding principle
it's a very general theorem which i tried to
and what we have here is just consider any
selection procedure and make things a bit simpler to explain the theorems just take a
selection procedure b which selects q variables to topic you variables for example if the
loss of
the variables which have larger estimated coefficients are the ones which come first in the
regularisation or forward selection just the first fifty variables
your favourite procedure takes the qprop variables
and then you you know by the
the number of false positives so this is kind of the non active sedentary is
the stably selected said that have been said before
and here is the theory
it has the main assumption which i will explain on the next slide
the mean squared error that is proportional to the information content of the object i
wish we cover so for example if xs s nonzero components is it possible to
i mean squared error that will scale
was the complexity of the output of the object that is is the object gets
sparser and sparser the mean squared error comes down and down and down
and so
to think about these problems i always find it useful to think about it
as having the help of an oracle
and i recall
we do the following things suppose that our calls
is going to
big essentially giveaways the problem is going to say many i've seen your genes
i know which genes are responsible for you disease i've seen them
i i'm going to give them to you
and you know know you want to make estimate x but the article tells you
well i see x and i can tell you that x seventeen is not zero
i can tell you that a hundred and forty three is nonzero and i can
tell you that the two seventeenth
two seven gene is now use this region out everybody else's
and of course that would be giving out the problem in let's say we have
such a genie that comes around and says i have seen many tell you which
ones are zero and which were not
now the problem is underdetermined anymore because it's another gene is more than the number
of observations is not underdetermined so i would say
but look at all these genes don't contribute so i'm going to remove them
and i'm going to create the submatrix
that essentially only takes the columns corresponding to the locations of the genes
so column seventeen columns one hundred forty three and columns to seven
so everybody else is irrelevant
thank you very much you give me a very precise information now let me delete
everything that is relevant me just fit the data to what i know is relevant
so how do i do this well by least square what i would say that
i'm going to remove the relevant variables learning for
on the complement of TT beings
index set corresponding to the
columns where x is non-zero
one issue impose that xt complement zero and otherwise i'm just going to do squares
now it's not underdetermined fact after many observations and all of us
and i call this an idealist squares estimate because of course the g comes in
and gives away the problem telling me exactly ahead of time which genes
telling me exactly which is a significant and which ones are not
OK and then i go back now it's becoming very classical ideally square and so
i would just regress to use statistical
language we regressive observed response y onto the variables that i know are in my
that would be my
and outside i would foresee estimator be
and when i do this
it's a very simple calculation i have squares estimator
it's bias is zero here
and it's variance
it's essentially the trace
one of the hat matrix will be
so the trace of
they start t eighty
very simple things can also calculate the mean squared error
and then you have the trees and now if you have this kind of restricted
isometry property this submatrices of a well they have can values between point five and
one point five
that's all the igon values of
they start t eighty are between about one
roughly between point five and two let's say is it all about one
and so when you calculate this
you say well
if all the eigen values are between about one i mean do i
how many do i have well the size of t that's as sparsity
so the mean squared error is about this time sigma square and what we discover
is with the help of an are
i can get
and which is much smaller than enhancing must for example there are three genes
you know the previous results so the the air is about the number of patients
time sigma square this would say
o point three six
it's just proportional to the true number of components as the true number of things
that need to estimate and not anything else
and of course i would never be able to get such rules mean squared error
because i get to se to get there
i need to have access to
information that of course i don't
and so the question is can we just do as well as our bodies can
we have an mean squared that is adaptive in the sense that it really depends
on the complexity
of what is it that we're trying to estimate
OK so to do this
one way to do this
is to kind of by semantic selection
which is
and the estimators that i propose with terence tao
and so we have model
now we can again use and l one criterion except that now serves as a
data fitting term is slightly different
i'm going to say is well i'm going to it data by getting minimizing the
l one norm
and imposing their will look at the residual vector there is a mismatch between the
data and my eight times my guess
my predictions if you will the residuals lectures
then when i correlated this residual ways
the columns of a that is when i look at the vector is star times
the residual
and all the components of these vectors are small
so what it says it's minimized in one norm
as usual announcer data fitting term as the the residual not be not correlated
where is the columns of
so it says
now when i look at a star are
it's as if
if they are use the ice
variable or the ice column of the matrix
it's a is the vector AI times are
is small
it must be within the noise level sigma the standard deviation
OK so i'm asking that the signal the residuals cannot be well aligned with the
predictor variables because if they were actually probably as include them in my mind
so it's convex optimisation programme it's actually a linear programming disguise that's why called the
dantzig selector
in honor of
of george then six father of linear programming and so it's a something that is
easy to solve
all right so
the result that we have when we try to get to see is more subtle
i configurator quote unquote
by such
we got all we have to do we have to tell for instance for this
this sort of here
test points
three and four
so that would be circled the
but if you look
more carefully you see that this is not
the configuration that i was talking about because now we have two
it lies
for instance
this article that meets
different point
one axiom of configurations of points and lines
it's not satisfied
but these structures can be studied in the past and there are also interesting
let's go back
let's take this configuration table
that living graph to this configuration
so now i have green and yellow points not black and white
and four points correspond
the four vertices correspond to points one to up to four and four let's say
of vertices corresponds to a b c
so let's look what we have here
for instance
if we
this is a
then a
consists of
o point one
o point two
o point four
so what now
one could go and try to
write down everything
but if you read this
then you get this
nice graph which looks like it you
of this is just this graph drawing the different way
in this configuration here or in this this
you have in fact
all the information needed
to get
the graph of a few
let's keep this because we have too much
motivation so
let me give you another example
this comes also from geometry is called mechanical calculation
you have
again points in circles
these two are considered as degenerate circles
let me give you an example
this one here
if you take an arbitrary graph
it may be considered as an incidence structure
so we need to the types of objects
we need the types of objects
but this is
one two three four
and edges a b c d e
and what is the as well as the if
vertex one
it is it this with the edge a then that would these
relations so
if i say p
equals one two
three four
equals a b
the the then i
it will be the set of
let's say
a and so on all flanks so flags here in this case in this case
just hours
but we talk about that later when you get to graphs which we're not
about it
and there are other examples but this is
and you can see why this is
imagine i took rotation matrix
are OK so it's going to have the property that are transpose is is the
i know i have multiplied by lambda as by are OK i so lambda is
not equal to lambda times are
you can see that lambda times than the transpose doesn't change
all right
so what this is saying is that
you know
if i
if i if i do PCA and i sort of have you know strong idea
of how the dimensions are like we're directions of maximum variance are then i'm always
going to get the same representation in in my in my two d space right
if i were to run factor analysis many times it's possible that i'm going to
get this representation but you know rotated so the relation between
the the means is going to be always saying is just i think my sheet
of paper sort of
can rotate around OK
the other thing just to keep the just to keep the bayes in hide alive
the proper thing to do would be to
to actually specify priors on on land and on
on the noise right and just
compute posteriors and turned
marginalisation sort of go crazy
but i'm not going to talk about
that's correct yes so the way the way you treat it is used up here
you take you take the
likelihood so just as
as a reminder
this is a gaussian distribution rights of these actually that all the
is actually the matrix of all the
otherwise would be
and times the matrix of otherwise it's interesting because you use and for the number
of data points and attend and and for the that mentions and i tend to
use and for the number of data points and the for the dimensions but i
guess one has to get used
the fact that this
many many ways of
using this notation so this is the gas and has zero mean and he has
covariance matrix
lambda lambda transpose plus the noise diagonal OK and then i could do exactly the
same thing as we did when we maximised
the likelihood of the normal girls of the double the standard multivariate gaussians take the
log on i think derivatives
and maybe you should just right
it's it's nice derivatives come out it's a lot of fun
OK so
what we've seen is a specific case of of the so called latent variable model
because we had this
we invented some variables that they weren't related to anything we could see OK
and the important thing is we didn't try to learn their value either
we just use them
to generate our model to generate all distribution OK
we don't
bear in mind we do not maximize anything with respect to x right
we take x the sources
we invent some prior on them
and then we sort of say
they're gonna generate the data using the land matrices
but i'm not interested in the axis so let's just integrate them out right so
that's how we obtained actually all prior distribution otherwise we did by saying we have
y is equal to lambda explores noise
and now i been myself p of y given x
and now what i do is i integrate this out using the prior over x
i'm not interested in x
i just using it conceptually to build model OK so that's the kind of
that's the kind of stuff we've done right so we had the
a a prior over the hidden sources
we knew how to relate that to to whatever we were gonna
we could be the joint distribution by
multiplying two and then
integrate out marginalise of the axes
and the typical example for you is
you know if you're if you worked with the dimensionality reduction
who's who's on any dimensionality reduction
what what what have you used
besides PCA
so SVD is is very similar to PCA right
it is the same spirit really so what gets used
OK that's interesting
so that was four
you also had targets he was supervised learning problem
what is
feature selection absolutely
has anyone use the elderly
OK those are nonlinear techniques
has anyone use the
back constrained
latent variable
get back constraints i don't even remember the name
got process latent variable models
as the band OK anyway
so if we were to learn if we want to know to learn
the parameters of this model that lambda and the matrix of noise we would take
the logarithm of the gaussians
and if we want to minimize because we just have coded does minimisation is maximisation
we just change the sign and then we get this objective function and
if you want to have some fun as i say you just take gradients of
this thing with respect to london with respect to the to the noise
it's actually not that hard once once you've taken that this kind of gradients in
you know forever
so tomorrow
actually will not be here so we will not be studying the EMI grid tomorrow
but we will be starting today
so before we take a break
i'm going to try and
relate factor analysis two
so this one now
one model that is extremely similar to
factor analysis
is probabilistic PCA
and he was
proposed by
mike tipping who used to work at
microsoft research in cambridge
and by my boss chris bishop
the idea that the difference
the difference here too
factor analysis is that
instead of having
one noise term for each of the variables in in data space
we now say that the noise has the same variance for all of them
it's not a very big differences
so that's essentially
that's essentially the only variation
and now the interesting thing is that if you do that little change
now you can prove
OK so let's get back to the the
a little-known field of financial astrology
and if you come common that you can find some software which
provides tool
predict things like share prices based on the positions of the planets that kind of
stuff and if you look on the web page not going to say
which packets is scared of libel laws and what not but google the powerful tool
anyway if you look at the screenshot you find you know there's all this stuff
to do with math models you can kind of like different planets the thing might
have a bearing on europe which on this is ue looking at and there's various
claims about the performance of this other software on historical data so looking at they
claim we
we looked at the last couple of years of some particular
indices and we found we could predict them with an extremely high rates of accuracy
the implication being by this model is going to continue predicting with the same accuracy
you're investments can repair itself many times over
OK so maybe you could
so i started to feel the something not quite not quite right about this
clearly put finger like what the
what potential
issues might here the before you break show your cash on this
on the software
any niggling doubt in your mind
what does that mean that does not mention at all in the middle of automated
stock trading and like it's a lot of financial trading companies to use automated trading
of some solid so the answer is not knowing this
sure sure might be the minimum monkey whatever you exactly right
OK so that might be the objection that perhaps there no structure in the space
whatsoever patches like the lottery and it's completely random
you get the same thing for lottery scheme predict next week lottery numbers and there
you know there's clearly an objection that this thing should surely that's independent you know
like it doesn't involve the history or any other environmental factors
so even if there was structure
you know they tested this on previous data like three years data and it's got
the right thing almost all the time
how could i could be wrong that sounds ten great
it's all fancy math of planets their brilliant in our time
i would like to my credit card details
all right well there's a couple problems here one is
this data has all
past so you know one thing we can do is memorize the price on each
when someone asked to predict predict surprise
we just say
OK what they is that i look at my database
i give you the price and that predicts a hundred percent
and all attorneys memorize each day
and it's not going to tell me anything about the future
right that's kind of an extreme case where
in extreme case where we get
zero learning and a hundred percent prediction on past data
because that's kind of one warning about testing on your training data
let's just think about a few reasons to believe something is true here's here's some
things i propose are reasons that should make you believe that the system some kind
of learning machines doing the right thing
OK one thing is successful predictions of the future
predictions on unseen data if
if this software which will remain nameless if we tried it out and we
we gave it a go for the next six months
and i got the right data
all the time
then i would start to believe that something was was going on i would be
a hundred percent convinced it may just be that does
those random noise and i just got lucky every time the some non-zero probability that
it just it just kind of got lucky but the more i see
the doing the right thing
on data which could possibly have been available
when the thing was being developed
then i started to think or maybe this may be something
OK another reason remember we talked about inductive bias right at the start and
there were particular kinds of things that we were
we felt were
what properties of
believable models
and one of them was simplicity
and if we can find
some model or some learning system which takes data in the past and give a
simple explanation of the data
maybe there's very few parameters which accurately describe large quantity of data
then that's another reason i might have to to believe to believe that model
so if we had something like
you know some
particle physics experiments in some simple property like you called t squared
to simple thing it fits the data very well
and that's one point one which i might
i might choose to find out more credible
OK so whether you think simple models
there are more
there are more reliable than complicated models
at some stage that's up for debate but we cannot handle the start going to
make some assumptions which enable us to move forward that was one of them that
we prefer simplicity over complexity given that and here's the consequence of that assumption
OK there may be things specific to
applications which
which make it plausible if you've got some
maybe a bit difficult to
explain this with our example but
if you have some model then you may be able to find some consequence of
that model which you can which you can text in the data
i'm kind of going and wait from the river i can give you
examples if you like
three and you should
not believe the model is because it has high likelihood of the data you've already
tested so when you're building model usually trying to optimize something
and that thing you've optimized
after you've carried out process you already know it's as good as its
as it can be it's like you use that statistic and then you have to
find something else to test it on to the need new data
or you need
some other way of evaluating
the model
other than what you've already used to train the model
so the problem here is
the models being
with respect to accuracy on
so i
excellent scientific data side effects if you don't have
you know anyone who takes medication in this day and age it doesn't look as
side effects
what taken is taking the chance
so that's a really important scientific data
that you know in the the most experimental fields as pharmaceutical companies
operate under
so similar to compute doesn't get it either quotation by mars humans to p one
side to the other
you end up debate all the time and not doing the research
some new standard here
except external reality but detected objective viewpoints we talked about talk about
being abductive
and values play an important role just like it does in qualitative research
we try to combine form informal techniques
and started writing
we think that you could look for causation
you can pin down exactly
and we research is influenced by theory hypotheses and so forth but also by of
observations facts evidence
so how is supposed to get there
how however some slides i'm this gonna get going hit the high points and tries
which have underlined boat
how is it you know very big name in the US
published large
he is on record as saying that mixed methods on this development which really concern
me when said that
so let's look at some of the names of a lot of these are from
the US but
you may have heard of them before like giving lincoln who played a big role
in the qualitative movement issued landmark book in nineteen eighty five
and mean just see over the years what some of the people
some critics of mixed methods have said
for example both quantum quarter-on-quarter methods may be used to populate a new research paradigm
ninety four
nineteen eighty nine they stated information may be quantitative or qualitative
eighty five and in my book
they said that
there are many opportunities for naturalistic investigator utilize qualitative data
probably more than appreciated
and then
they also
paradise commercial
and they said it was cautious yes that's in two thousand five
that's the whole reason
and this one should like questions such a distinction between quantitative and qualitative
so she really get rid of that those terms and i argue that point later
the slides
there are many definitions that is are the can
myself and lisa
when we see it so it's effect is a powerful third paradigm
the company quantitative and qualitative again
we really respect quantitative research you know is that while we expect quite a research
is that well
so i'm not saying it replaces we say this complements this at supplements
the philosophy pragmatism
civil for the languages are less likely to win more medals
it's appreciative increase local and
again you have access to messages access to articles has this definition taking the continuous
time afterwards
office an important approach to generate an important question that's really important thing that we
think mixed methods
allows you to generate the questions
the same is a better than b the that we could we could do better
than that
what's exciting forces at the loss of jobs when i first started off
like that mixed methods about fifteen years ago it was so difficult to get anything
i was known in the field
as a about that's why you see some slides of their
controversial people come up and say are you so controversial
o station makes quantitative qualitative
i would like to tell the story of when i was doing a presentation about
nineteen years ago
there is no impact on either this side and the woman sitting because the fact
the person and i was talking just gets angry with me
you can kind of stoking the pencil and next thing that is not enough
and i started i thought that was my neck you know
i will be here today itself
it's really amazing and maybe
it has been such debates have been so
in europe in straight in other places africa about
can certainly say the US has been really is that is that it's not as
bad now
so people get really angry when you mention one of the major mixed methods
these are several journals that so you may have heard of
and i'm sure there's some political science not familiar with political science journals so i'm
sure there
if few the public scrutiny
mixed methods according to
for those looking for a job with that publishes mixed methods research
john mixed methods research
came out in two thousand seven was tajik calling creswell with editors
outgoing now the decision up a few manuscripts
and you have to sit mountains
and men's max bergmann
so she is on their
so as an outlet you have there
this action video that's come called multiple research approaches and that's
that's also very new
so that's not second
jill that routinely publishes
expected research
a lot of special issues have been published or planned publication like the ones that
and this is one that's come in that you study about international journal of
what research approaches
and nancy my colleagues and myself
yes it is thomas in percent
these are some of the more recent books and mixed method still not that many
books compared to quantitative qualitative
slowly growing and
chaco intently
and now working on the second-hand book you'll see some
so as we speak was to work in other chapters are you going to get
a preview of some of some of those thing or two from that chapter that
still ongoing that's such kind of this is that you
things are still
this presentation
this is the same that we use
two when i teach i i want to do research this for step process for
mixed methods research
i what looks like a legal over baby featured those stats
i would i will guarantee you follow
the steps
that there is a very good chance you're going to have a good study good
rigorous study
it's actually an article which go for those who take the class
that we follow the steps to the termites
you know its publisher american educational research journal and
the goal is to make sure you're know it's going to go in this direction
and intensity
should the magnitude of the control
so do the integration get particle trajectories
and that is either flow maps your
you've seen several times
and so the
our main duty behind this is pretty simple and this relates to the minimisation of
dynamical system
so we have the location of the particle x y t x y and then
the optical flow is you which sort of change the particles and we have to
find this a
fixed point of this system can
we know that is
this fixed points which is accessed online store and then
we can
do this you is given by this and these going about that then we do
that kind of substitution of new coordinates with x minus sixty because even
last week of the two and we do some manipulation and at the end of
the show that he
the optical flow fields even easy to
is expressed basically
the the
david you test x and i don't you suspect why
and similarly these experts but data
the petersburg x y which is essentially the jacobian matrix so this is the system
that is you really want to that the jacobian gives you the rate of change
if you really want to see a doctor
jacobian is going to play a part in analyzing his behavior which is you nice
so so what we can do is look at the eigen values of the jacobian
matrix this two by two matrix so has two i can use and then the
interesting thing is that if you look at the things
the case where the highway continues
both of them are negative and then that essentially to bottleneck
and then the
both positive and
then that gives you the departure from band
when have one of the eigen values you then that as it essentially the same
which is very nice elegant way to find behavior that set point
is one of the two and one is positive and it becomes blocking OK
and finally the centre
if these ideas are kind of complex then that gives you
or just
so it's pretty interesting very simple idea but you know it's very powerful and it's
going to work
our idea approach is that they can provide you compute optical flow
and they first thing is want to find out what the regions of interest
and for that reason that should get flow maps and you look at the accumulation
of these particles we can do something called denstream et cetera look can you know
that how many particles each of pixels are going through a new cluster those two
identify these regions of interest
and those players we want to look at these behaviors of present OK so these
regions of interest gives us the can points and then you to take go the
optical flow games and computers i can really met OK
and the jacobian lighting and so on
then using those we have to
decide which behavior is
so so given the sequence like this which is as you see it debauchery
optical flow again column order the direction of some kind of
intensity as the magnitude
and these are the particle trajectories and this is the density schema
so then semantics is that how many particles are going to excel
and sequence
optical flow
and decrease
and they don't seem ok
so we have to
look at this image new find regions so this is potentially to and for that
our article does it
the train through that
pixel and they look at the history of itself these trajectories
and that to provide this information dense in the second example here
and these are the the particle trajectories
and this is the story of these languages
and this is the second these systems histogram so
simple criterion is that is a high variance
these are the attendance for the
what if there is no evidence that i cannot spot
lindsay arches of things
so once we get these candidates then look at optical flow again and compute the
the jacobian
and look at the science of these ideas values and then you have for fatherly
the these four cases as i've shown you before
on the the naked to israel positive zero and one z
in one of them is use blue
and so on green is you know one positive and negative and then
for the complex conjugate can use cases
so far in this example we get the idea make like this
and these three ones are the
when both of them and get
quickly walked right into whether energy by just try to say what type thing what
about Bellizzi change joined I mean can you say I don't mean any norm was
that publicist exchange that at how would you actually say by the way Thomas Taggart
that was beach I don't agree with that I think it should it's not about
the each obviously not tag of X . arm and then then that biggest thing
at the ultimately because product was that is equivalent to what we do in history
of Europe in ontology matching her son till years when they stop the goes and
the other converts them that same problem syntactical tight spaces so still community flicker has
as text-based marauding delicious travel and they actually legitimately have slipped you know their folk
songs so the sets of words wrote to the community Club with but how do
you intact talk about the text-based themselves as entities that you can reason about them
otherwise you couldn't do these processes that translates so these are these questions are real
and their posed to you can actually say if the answer goes this way we
seen so the other was the so that's and is in that the mathematics of
the formalism did any work it was the humans were forced to be clear about
I think that's a real contribution at the semantic Web we forget that we bring
its methodology thing
and now the status of this thing I'm afraid to say I let the ball
drop on this is busier and anything armor and those those issues came out the
1st week it wasn't hard cover the issues on the re-signed and that if is
because it's real work to solve the issues is not reward technically headed done by
now is work socially politically so we we need to come up with the idea
now I have a thing contact comments as a clever word that that the domain
registered etc. were all ready to go on the political process with that because of
posting contributed I guess you don't have to be boring working on it but if
you guys wonna participate what I need 1st and foremost is folks to volunteer reference
applications that would do something with this because of the something worse than a budget
like myself run around same like says the go really why searching the diamond line
but you say Oh by the way if this happens then this is called which
machinery for translating we can come into play was machinery for information extraction or whatever
and not in a surgical that occasions you could look up to the stuff fantastic
and then of course if you actually have machines that create Tiger applications respect and
finally isn't enough knowledge engineers now but they have to learn how to write I
mean I know this is hard skills in running open-source project they were that's that
neural tube playoff Hasek example is about that pretty negative structure
now the thing is interesting here this is about my musical travels my example but
apply any place and any knowledge of collective knowledge system to have this property that
it gives better as more people use it tested do a couple of things 1st
of has to motivate people to come out and do something with it contributed that's
really the harder part Bessler learned from enterprise suffer work interest that we had a
collective we added to the collective mind for enterprises but almost 4 focus in the
source of the problem which is missing the point that the real problem was collecting
people's actual work products online so could searched and that's the problem solving and from
that knowledge and collective memory emerged the same thing is here that the technology can
actually helped motivate people to come will 1 of the waste and the 2nd here
to the cost to make it so that the more people coming contributed the more
value to everyone who's using it into the network that these things growing stable it
turns out that we have some tools are toolbox for using the structure part of
this mix of structure and function that secondhand have those properties they can solve problems
so I think it's as with blue words set so the the problem is this
value traded values grow sort shot and solution or the approach of solution really is
welcome to lecture five
in the last lecture we defined symbol codes we ask theoretical
and practical questions about symbol codes
that's gave us even more evidence for these claims which we've now proved sufficiently i'm
going take them as true so the claim was the right way to measure information
content is with long
base to of one over pe of an outcome
that's not only sensible measure of information content it is how many bits you should
expect to be able to encode the outcome into if you're using a good compression
the entropy is the average information content
hand the source coding theorem says
if you've got a source with entropy age you can compress
and comes in an age bits
we looked a symbol codes where
without punctuation you give binary strings strings of zeros and ones to each letter in your alphabet
hand we established
some theoretical results about the some of them without proof
so we
came to an understanding of how
unique decodability constrains the length you comical length really short you have to make some
length shorter you have to make up the length of your code words
introduce notion a prefix code which are easy to decode codes that are associated with binary trees
and we noticed that's
if you've had code length equal to the information content then you got the best
possible compression and the average length per symbol was the entropy
hand we stated without proof that would be optimal symbol code you can get within one bit of the entropy
and finally
so the huffman algorithm which is an algorithm is extremely simple for making optimal
symbol codes
so let's just recap at with these examples and
so probabilities are
if if they
huffman algorithm says combine the two smaller with smallest probability you can take your pick
give to fifty
combine that with small probability
and then combine the two is
probability again take your pick
and then combine these got one
and then by putting it zeros and ones on edges
we can we can define codes this one is zero zero this
one coming down the tree
this is one there's error
this one zero one
and this one is
one one
one what i've done wrong such as they one
any questions
so let's do another example the probability is proportional to one two three four
and ten
half one says
combine these
these statistics and combine these nine
and take to
get twelve
then seventy eight
and then what
carefully we take two nines
get eighteen
then who does ten go with ten goals with twelve
twenty two
and then the two smallest articulating
looking at the history
and the
his this fifty five
now we slap on zeros and ones anyway you want and we've got ourselves the optimal symbol code
the ensemble why
any questions
yes the question was does the huffman algorithm ensures that we've got a prefix code
and the answer is yes because when we put the labels on when making a
binary tree
well defined in the code words from the root of the tree at words what
we'll get is a prefix code there is no way that one codeword can be
a prefix or another if defined in terms of a binary tree
so the have algorithm always gives you a prefix code
hand it's awful
you can't make a better symbol code
and you might think that that's then wraps up
one thing
you might ask in addition about prefix codes is
it is it sufficient to make a prefix code if someone said i've got a
really coming idea i'm gonna make a code that is not a prefix code and
it's going to be better can we prove
that that's is untrue
and the answer is
yes we can prove it's untrue
by the following fairly simple argument imagine that someone has made a symbol code
which they claim is wonderful and it's not a prefix code you say okay please
tell me the lengths of all of your symbol codes
starting with the shortest lengths
up to the longest length give me them sorted by length
then i'm going to go to the symbol code supermarket which we introduced last time
and i will walk across it from one side to the other and i will
buy the shortest code words first and then having bought some short ones move across
to the next while
by some the next length and so forth in accordance with the shopping list that you've given me
happened as long as you have given me a shopping list that doesn't exceed the budget
the crack budget and one
then i will be able to buy your lengths of
and because i stepped across
from one mile to the next assignment across should
make clear what i mean so let's say i had to buy
link to
and then you wanted one of length three
like this one
and then sum the rest length four by all these
as an example
and because i'm moving across and never overlapping with myself i'll end up with a prefix code
the only way you would violate the prefix property if you but to the from the same
the vertical coordinate
in the supermarket
all right
they huffman algorithm is already optimal makes prefix codes so we didn't need to worry
about this but it just in case someone is claiming i want to do something
clever not using prefix codes well whatever expected length they could've got with non prefix
code we can match it we can just replace the code by a prefix code
and the code i showed you before
was indeed
they could maybe the huffman algorithm and did say prefix code
so how we wrapped up
compression by saying his had made simple codes and here's how to make optimal symbol codes
well for the rest of today i want to argue that we are not done with compression
and the reason we're not done is because this lurking plus one
in these inequality
are we done
let me give you one really simple example
justify this
and it's example we started with the bent coin
let's imagine we have been calling and two faces are called an be let's say have probabilities point nine nine
o point zero one
and now they i will compress it using
i have an algorithm because they make optimal symbol codes and you carefully find the
two symbols the smallest probability you combine them into one
stop words the force would be the birds which have from this non-existing you don't
carry information and we usually just remove them that they have just dysfunctional also listed
for english this would be a about above across and so on and usually we
just remove these words and algorithms
work better
after that this and similar lists and if similar but different lists we have for
other languages
what's also interesting to mention which
usually people don't talk about this but this can be quite
annoying so
the characters
i'm not necessarily even the characters are not necessarily written in the same way that
especially if we use unicode let's this
a circle above it so it has two representations in unicode and if we want
the normalisation of words we need to be aware of this and so this means
that usually be we need to use some some
proper effects of the packages for this kind of normalisation
i think which we need to be aware of
when dealing with words is stemming so
stemming is
is a procedure which
four different forms of the same words into its smallest normally
normalized form so we can have stemming which usually just takes the root of the
word or lemmatisation which really tags that generates the
normalized proper normalized word
just store scheme is it as i can just
fashion show you the most often used stammer which is also public domain from this
website so this is the set of rules for english
these are the rules which we apply one after another
we tried to transformation rules on the suffix of the word this rule would apply
in such cases of relational would be
would get transformed into relates
could the second one conditional condition and so on and by applying this rule then
most likely not often but not always but most often some of the get normalized
but but that's occasionally get also areas like universe university i think they would get
normalized into the same into the same which is not correct
but this porterstemmer some others as well as the fact standard for english-language other other
languages have
there are sets of rules occasionally you'll have even the rules which are learned by
machine learning techniques especially for smaller languages and this
this can be quite quite efficient action
OK the next level
which is sort of similar to words but still different are phrases
so instead of just having single words we can have sequences of words we have
two types of phrases so one would be this frequent contiguous word sequences are
possibilities also to have frequent non contiguous perfect for sequences which
the location because of proximity
features both type of features can be identified with a relatively simple dynamic programming algorithm
so this is not a big science and
but it so that often this is not being done on this preprocessing clever when
dealing with text
do we need this just by
having dealing with phrases means that we can more precise precisely identify sense and you
can get rid of we can get rid of
some of these annoying properties which i mentioned before
like synonymy and so on
what we're saying here is that google released last year
the biggest ingram corpus so we can get it on this
link i think which
if you order this get twenty four gigawatts of compressed text files basically
in the dataset because thirteen million unigram so single words
thirty three hundred fourteen millions of bi grams of double double words it goes up
to five grams which is over one billion so if you have an effect
DVD then you would get such
ingrams and so as the frequency of ingram so i guess on will corpus
so this is i think quite quite available corpus place
the next level of textual representation would be part of speech
this is already
step away from
two words are small category of words are now
by introducing this part of speech tags somehow we
try to
and they have different work functions why do do we need this so
most often in text mining can be would use these for information extraction techniques which
we will see a little bit afterwards in one other possible uses just to perform
sort feature selection so that we reduce the vocabulary of all words which we do
it so
that's a
it's quite well known that the most information is carried by nouns and so we
can easily extract just is by
preprocessing of the text with its part of speech tagger part of speech tagging he's
usually are taggers are learned by hidden markov model algorithms
one of the first cover corpus which is manually annotated and then if it's hidden
markov model we learned model and then we apply this
also to unseen
previously unseen texts
these are the most typical categories when we try to annotate documents all of
these are categories which we used to annotate words
works words of verbs nouns adjectives adverbs pronouns prepositions conjunctions and interjections and when you
probably know what was the function of each of the word so works would be
like action or state
now this would be things and so on
so these are categories and now if you look at one example
the feature elements would be identifiability within spilling out features will actually reveal the relevance
of the future
there the problem with this method
the reliability to samples information gain is dependent upon the node composition
obviously got smaller nodes and unless stated splitting then
you can actually split it purely by chance
then larger and more data actually the more reliable measures information gain
and also irrelevant features will still non-zero measure relevance
because in the worst case for example the information gain
museo so the average information gain is always going to be the mean
the non negative sample
we still don't have some some non-zero
many of these relevance for relevant
OK now complexity compensation
chris anderson nodes reason to split
we're taking average information in situ by feature what we want to do is is
where each sample so we have a weighted average
and weighted by some
measure of the reliability of these nodes
all the complexity
so what we do is
we project the states down to the one dimensional space
is given by the feature
we're using a binary classification problem here with
and examples and i positive examples
we have in mind side negative examples
and the number of possible arrangements when you project mistakes down to the one dimensional
space is given by the combinatorial functions
the next thing to consider is that some of these arrangements when projected onto the
space is actually can be non unique
so such is here where we have
the notice two examples one each class
weak acid is reflected
we have two possible arrangements but basically the same
and if you to optimize information to optimize that maximize information gain
you actually achieve the same value for both
but also those of other arrangements is symmetric about the center returns unique
and these were given
during unique value the optimized information gain
they yourself consider
although these are the same arrangement the probability of the current is doubled because there
are two ways
this arrangement aka
the way we work out
the number of unique arrangements are given by these functions here
which is dependent upon whether and there i odd or even
you have an even number examples of number of positive examples of conformal
an arrangement which is symmetric about its center
so therefore there are no unique arrangements in that case
and then using information theory what we can do is say the probability
of a unique arrangement is given by one over the total number of possible arrangements
and probability the non unique arrangements is two over the total number of
possible arrangements
and i would say the
negative base two logarithm that give us information then we wait them by the proportions
you need in nineteen eight
and then because supplies down the kernel function here which is a measure of of
OK i want to
test to see how well this measure actually works
and what we want to do is look at the information gain density functions for
each feature
so if you imagine you
sampling information for each feature in different areas and different nodes
and if should give us some sort of distribution
these information games for each of these features
so we did built
the random forest using five trees
on an artificial dataset
and we recorded
e to the information given by features
and then
use that to construct
a density functions
we use the one way using unit weights for example
and another way we actually weighted by some measure of complexity
there is a pairwise comparison and then you choose the one which you think is
and then there was
recently before propose modifications
or combination of those this approach with cross validation
which is based on this agreement on test examples
of the model of the two approaches and their
the the the the higher disagreement means lower trust to cross validation
and the combination is the way in the way
of waiting weighting the
waiting in some way combining in some way one or choosing one or the other
OK so that was about represent similar
the third group embedded
it's very simple there is no preprocessing the whole feature selection happens in the loop
in the machine learning algorithm
and then
you use the algorithm is it is so there is
no additional work to select the features
and one simple example of that is all decision tree
there is some inherited feature selection that happens in decision tree induction
and it's a so-called embedded approach
and of course some other
approaches to feature selection these which is this in that idea
one is
at each iteration of the incremental optimisation
of the more the use of fast gradient
basically stick to find the most promising future
so while we induce the model we already do feature selection
and the other one the idea that
features that are relevant
four ford
concept we are learning should affect the generalisation error bound of the nonlinear SVM more
than irrelevant features
and the idea is in use
when evaluating the feature subset and
here they use backward elimination
there was also this
the idea that i already mentioned using
features that occur in decision trees
as the selected feature subset
is it is a kind of using embedded in approach
four instead of optimisation in the filtering approach
this proposal was
around decision tree induction on the data
take a look in the induced decision tree
take the features that occur in the decision tree and that is your feature subset
and and then run whatever algorithm you want on the feature subset
and in this case they run the nearest neighbour great
and simple filters
there that
the first group of the approaches
it's basically the same as filters
but assuming future independence
in this that instead of evaluating the the whole feature subset
we evaluate just individual feature
it's about
usually evaluated all the features one by one
you collect the features score
or they're all the features by the score and then select the top
some features
so how many of the features is
people decide for different numbers or just you know in the research papers observe how
the number of selected features influences the performance of the system
so what is happening in
domains with many features is
usually this involves entering approach
and that's also what use on text data
and then the methods differ in
the way how to evaluate individual feature now so we have different feature scoring measures
that they use
so here i organise them in
kind of three groups
one group is
supervised feature matches that
take into account the class value
like information gain
a variant of information cross entropy for text
hotel information for text
then there is a group of
feature of feature scoring measures
but actually they class into account and moreover they work for binary class
which is not a problem but what's ratio also
takes into account that one of the class values is the target class value
which is not uncommon for text data
for instance if you
if you do user profiling and you want to find all the documents that interesting
for your user you know that this is the target class value and the whole
universe is negative
so it's good that you're classifier
that year feature scoring measure knows that it should be kind of concentrate on positive
examples finding them because it's like
zero point one percent of positive and everything else is negative
and the normal separation that actually
so far
is the only measure i have seen in combination with it
the inner SVM on document categorisation that is improving
the performance of
because there is a feature subsets selected
and then there are surprised measures reaching grow or to the class value like
just taking frequency of the word in the document and
no selecting the most frequent
which also surprisingly
performed surprisingly well i'm not better than the other but surprisingly well
and i'll show you some results of comparison on the next slides
and there's is another approach
actually also based on the simple filtering approach
but using this idea of
using embedded approach in order to select the feature subset
and here it's not embedded in approach to select the whole feature subset that assigns
score scores to the features
so instead of calculating information gain or cross entropy or something like that
actually the
i mean i SVM is trained on the whole data on all the features
and then
there are weights in the normal to the hyperplane SVM model
and these weights are used as scores
four individual features
so the higher the weight you know the feature is more important for the models
just take that value
and this feature selection they also show some experimental comparison
how this performance compared to
the other feature selection measures and also
in combination with different
learning algorithms
so just a little bit of insights what is happening in this scoring measures
which actually can help us to understand
what we see in the next slides how they a
perform differently
so for information gain
it goes over class values
but also the feature values
so it ignores this difference between word occurring or not occurring in the document just
it's zero one
these are two values of my feature so
it's a real and symmetric and i just can't click information going over that
in the in the next slide two will see
at least in the on the data on the yahoo data that was tried it
didn't perform well at all
so there is cross entropy for text
which performs
significantly better than information gain
so each of those things can be a little computer the sensor network
and then
well you send messages and when they want on their you do that and all
the nodes
and in here all the message that you need to get probabilities
really nice simple idea
the questions here
who can tell me if i run this imperiled
there is a node does this at the same time
how long it will take
until i get the correct message here
and i'll tell you what requires initialisation if you've got the right message from the
other banality it
you just invent something
and assume that the system
this will be the right message
now how long would it take
to get the correct probabilities here
you want to use
i don't think about it for a moment
in order for this message here to be correct
this is no need to send the message here
that you need to do something in in the message on
so in order to get that message create any two states
with this one
also need to six one two
in this case you
one two
so after three iterations of the spiral now
this message clear
i can compute this probability exactly
how long
would it take for this note
es ist
its heart
i said
so it's really easy to you look at the graph just count with along this
path is
and that's what it takes until everything is converged
so these out
well because basically
all the messages until you get the right one
i mean
so don't really matter i mean you might as well not sending great message in
that case so if you were to implement that
on a single node
you would not implemented in parallel
what you would do doing
this the following
i will first so in that case they would just
first look at well we can actually or is in the message to you would
start at the leaves of this tree
so i can see all the messages from the leaves can do this one that
one that one
that one that one i
well whatever nobody other two during that time doesn't really matter
now all the seventies this now realise
i got a message from here message from there
so i can at least in the message on here
OK so therefore this
this note here
let's i received an incoming messages from here and i can forward their
like the right now
the next step fifty will be doing
all others can actually do anything with haven't received any other message
now things start getting interesting
this known here
the case received the message from here to seek permission from there
the second single message
you can also send the message down here
so by the time already this right now then this clean
i will or will know exactly what the probabilities are
now what's the queen of has received incoming message
dresses up a message from here from their second centered on
likewise the message from here and from here i consider up there
so this is how you would implement it sequential
this considerably less wasteful
but if
the other nodes to something
stupid while
in the meantime well OK these are
we're we're
if you have a single computer on which implement all this you're absolutely right
what i suggested is stupid
if you have say
the really big graphical models
in each of those nodes the computer
he might not even know how big the network is
and so it would be a good idea just ignoring it started running
the other thing is and this is quite curious phenomenon
sometimes really
so far away
now may not have
much of an effect on what you're going to do local
so even though you started with the wrong message
eventually as he passes through lots and lots and lots and lots of nodes which
are reduced to do the right thing to make a wrong thing right
what's the point if you have a network of computers something might go down something
you might be running
and you might not really no
before and which ones
are up and which ones are that
you wouldn't want to just send around the message along if you
i don't have any other
i don't have an incoming message
so a really good idea is
to take some pride
seeing the right message that looks most similar to what you what you would have
two neighbours
a very nice paper by colours christian and mark asking
from you i
will square these to compensate
before it
and then
so we have
the map
so this is
the answer and
and this is
by s
and we are very very
so we have this square of the difference becomes it's one of the first describe
the second life first place and second here is the same as one the first
described the second place the product
and and here i have my linearity of expectation with expectation of this minus these
processes is expectation of these mines this practitioner face but this is a constant
so we had system this
the speculation of the expectation expectation is a constant
i mean
here i am looking at that it was because then here i have one expectations
squared i have another once you have to
but i have minus two here of the same thing expectations square
so all these
concepts of
so what i mean
what's left
the square
this presentation of the square of the estimator
minus prices product plus the square of the value to be predicted
and here
i am
taking expectations again
is a constant tensions partition i come with the corresponding and this is a constant
is expectation is the same cost
here i have now three is uncomfortable them out by linearity and i get expectations
of this quantity and this quantity sounds like the square of the difference not
the first square
energy committee
is one of symmetry office
the real value you want to predict y
squared error is that the square the others part of the research partition of one
and what you saying here
is that you can move
that they
square error
equals the sum
of the ninety s plus the square of the bias
this is a list of what is what happens now
do you o four
the a b
at each
hypothesis class of which
you can is very much
you're biased
but what's going to happen to the variance if you're sure which do have so
many possibilities you can approximate very well anything
you know attacking the knowledge that is in your sample
only on their feet adjusting so what do you have some
during car
latin dictionary because of the high
on the other hand
if you have a very robust they very boring passes class either this or this
well maybe you commit to matter because of the bias but you will be
must i mean if i need the height in metres
they take
the is of different centers
and it has to be or one that and something
my answer is going to be one that i will be pretty independent of the
if i miss to the mean
well i just change one based in the sample and the whole thing i
what is the best there is no reason no best
you have to be careful if both sources of
and this will show up very briefly in the next few slides
a bit faster now
so you're making a prediction on the basis of the given data
is it true that the data determine your religion only that you don't know which
this is actually the
you have all the data you would like to
and the extra factor there
that you don't have a way of accounting for
many people call this a lot and i was some there are variables that influence
your outcome but do have access to to the this problem
and the HMM switch up this
later on
or they may not repeat exactly the and you have a small amusement centre
for instance
aviation frogs
but how how do do you how do you
how do you manage do know the conditional probability of class is given the values
of the
parameters but are not from not to flowers that the exactly the same number of
many of weight of with of of the
o well
as soon as you are
using some sort of
this is what in problem but be aware you have one x bias or you
have one more
externally this is you to
prediction process
as an aside
if you write this
if you look at this
you recognise this exactly
the probability
that you that this vector
in gaussian with mean and variance
but just as a function of n and and observation come back to the other
you can assume that m and the feature or you can assume that they
feature is the same
in one case they call it
reliability and in other cases they call likelihood
if you're some people here is a computer scientist this is
we're doing this sort of
o thing
all of the
ten two are parameters into data they to parameters and
so what is behind these as assumption that similar observations lead to similar to what
you said and it was so much about the extreme case
of this assumption you work it out is is nearest neighbors is where you
eight of your prediction by looking at the cases that are most similar
the ones that you have around a probably so yesterday that it depends very much
for how to choose the distance
and there are a number of issues
me and computationally an issue because in high dimensions finding out the k nearest neighbors
through topic e
the reason
but now imagine you're working for
bank and was just asking you to some data-mining
and you come up with the naive bayes predictors
you showed us tables full of real numbers to your boss
it's going to like it
you managed to to
okay so that's all nice and there's also a lot of hype
there are some real research there remains to be done and that
some interesting challenges
so this
the trail
it's about these challenges also introducing you to some of the concepts
behind deep learning
end i'll try to tell u about
what i consider the major challenge which is
how to move the successes we've had with supervised learning most of these applications are being using supervised learning
unsupervised or semi supervised learning we have tons of unlabeled or weakly labeled data
and structured outputs which is
tightly connected to the unsupervised learning question
be off-putting the system is not just a category
a few numbers
but it's something that's very high dimensional like a sentence in image war some complicated data structure
the thing with these
both supervised both of these
structured outputs and unsupervised learning scenarios is
probabilistic models quickly become intractable
both from a computational point of view and from a statistical point of view
we use deepening in these areas could have a fairly important impact
all tell you about
the challenge of scaling up from a computational point of view because what we've seen
in recent years is the better models are the bigger ones
and we limited
just by our ability to try data models
and related to this will tell you about some of the challenges arising in
deep nets
so there's a numerical optimization issue
even the techniques we are using are
doing amazingly well
we have some indication that
we're not doing as well as we could end all tell you about and some ideas to get around these
and if we can
if we can face these challenges than our
it can be a much
more impressive impact on only i think
with computers i can see here understand natural language understanding humans
and provide better service to to humans
i've course maybe even understand help us understand how humans and animals
managed to solve difficult learning problems
all right
now let's
go a bit more technical slowly
how do we
build intelligent machines well on
you need knowledge in order to
take intelligent decisions
and you need doesn't always to come from somewhere in part of it could be that we
feedback knowledge directly machines but
what we learned in the last few decades is not a large part of it has to be
directly acquired by the machine and that's what machine learning is about
and if u
learn about machine learning and try to figure out what corps elements
that you find in machine learning well
one core element is priors that there no
there is no general purpose machine learning algorithm
you need some priors and price can be very specialized to your application or they can be very broad
and in the i was trying to get very broad priors
both both could be interesting
then there is always an element of optimization or search were searching forward a good
solution to problem in a large family of solution or in the case of inference
we're looking forward searching for a good explanation to particular input
like when you are doing
machine translation or speech recognition
there are many explanations for things we see and we're looking for the best one
so there's search query optimization comes up
and these are the times
practically from a computer science perspective there is also an issue efficiency of computation
we've seen
what programs in recent years due to
do you use that can paralyze a lot of the computations so thinking about that aspect is also important
the more fundamental
question behind machine learning is generalization how do we get
are learned here to
provide the right answers for new cases
the take that i'm
trying to put forward on this generalization question is eight geometrical one so
during the presentation you'll see this come back
well i'm thinking about generalization is
how we take the probability mass
that's we know should be
on the training examples in and spreading it in the right way
i'm guessing where it should concentrate
you'll see this notion come back
unfortunately in high dimensional spaces
guessing where to put a probability mass is
seems intractable because there's eight
exponentially large large number of configurations
of places where you could put protein mass
so that's the curse dimensionality
and how do we get around at
something i've been pushing the last few years
this idea in mind
we can get around the curse of dimensionality
if we are learning systems
and disentangle separate out
these underlying
factors that explain the data underlying causes
basically making sense of the data
so it may seem like a hard thing to do and of course it is
i i've been trying to
pushed as the agenda four
making really serious progress towards there
all right so now let's go back to
but i'm also proud of my alumni in this course who
are not in the world of finance
i think this course is go beyond
it's not just for people who are planning careers in finance
finance is a very important technology
and it's very important to know finance to understand what happens
in the real world
just about any human endeavor
it involves finance
you might say
i could be a poet
and what does that have to do with finances
well it probably ends up having something to do with finance because as a poet
you probably want to publish your poetry writing
and you're going to be talking to publishers and before you know it they're going
to be talking about their financial situation and how you fit into it so i
believe its fundamental and important and so
i think you
will find this course has not
a vocational course not
primarily of occasional vocational course but the intellectual course
about how things work really work
i see finances the underpinning of so much that happens it's a powerful force that
goes behind the scenes and i hope we can draw that in this course
there is another course in that we have two basic courses in finance for undergraduates
the other one is economics two fifty one
financial theory this financial markets that one is financial theory
last year i was taught by rafael romo
that was because john john accomplice who usually teaches the course
i was on the
and so
so we had to find someone else but i assume that next fall
john john accomplished will be again teaching two fifty one
so what happened why do we have these two courses well it was something like
eight years ago
that we really reach the present
the situation with to finance courses and john an accomplice and i
had a meeting and we tried to divide up the subject matter of finance in
the two courses and so we thought of financial theory in financial markets would be
the two
but the the problem was that both john and i are interested both in theory
and other applications
john john accomplice
is actually chief economist for large
investment company called ellington capital in greenwich connecticut which you see a lot of the
news has been very successful
and so he is very much interested in the real world
and so my interested in financial theory and so we find it
we decided after talking about that we really can't
divide up the subject matter of finance
into separate courses on theory
in practice
the either one if you try to do one alone it would not work
so what we decided to do was to divide it up
imperfectly and there may be some repetition between our two courses
both of them
self-contained courses so you could take either two fifty one or two fifty two or
you could take both
and i think maybe the best option is to take both if you're really interested
in the subject matter
it is true though that his cause is more
turned into
theoretical detail than mine
and john is a mathematical economist
and and we both love mathematics but may be done
is going to do more of it than than i am this course
actually we will not use a heavy amount of
try to keep it so that
people who are not comfortable with a lot of math would take this course
and so
but i
so i want to emphasise that this is
i i've said that i think this course is
vocational preparation in a sense
i pride myself on the fact that people who have taken this course find it
in a subsequent lives
but on the other hand i think that it's
really interested in how this i find it really interesting and so i hope that
you will too
now i don't know i may be different than other people
i think organic chemistry is really interesting how many of you have that feeling
show of hands who is interested in organic chemistry
are not getting along with cancer hayes unfortunately i've never taken a course in it
but accelerating lately out of just like a broad intellectual interests
that is of course that has a bad reputation doesn't because people say i've got
take that if i want to be in medical pre-med
you know to me
there's a lot of detail in organic chemistry to me
when you read the details you're getting into
something deep and important
about the way everything works
and so i start to find it interesting
so i don't know how people feel about taking turning off by saying that there's
going to be a lot of detail in this course
but i may be made a big mistake by likening it to an organic chemistry
course so i don't mean to turn you on
the idea in this course
is that
it being in financial markets course is you have to know how the world works
we're going to be thinking about that in connection with financial theory
but we we have to get into the details
and so
we are going to be
we are going to be learning about
in fact
so let me
let me start by talking about the the textbooks
principal textbook
rec posi
the other authors are modigliani jones and very
foundations of financial markets and institutions
this textbook
very detailed
it may be some p i had some reaction to students is more than i
wanted to know