that was my
the pattern in the past you can see that
i branch for
a release
it took three years so
you know we don't want that to happen again
so it's available sources are available of course binary packages available this turns out to
be really important because more people use binary packages and stores
people these days they're like what i do with this you know they download from
the FTP site and they say
i double clicked on it but it didn't do anything it's just the jesus park
right so they they know they think it's supposed to install itself
they don't even understand what this sort what source
binary understand binary meets they say what we mean binary
in addition active itself there's
there's another or companion project that was started by paul cancer when he was at
this time not sure if still there are not
it is the collection of contributed functions initially was just intended as the players are
the doctor four was hosted on sourceforge net was intended as a place where people
could collaborate to write additional functions rocket that maybe didn't belong in active core
domain specific packages
now we actually have a package system so there's a little bit more organisation to
this and
there are seventy domain specific packages there
and i think it's growing and i don't know when i made that counts for
a few months so that could be
that could be even bigger now
but especially
people companies always want to know
how many people are using octave how how many people
i have no idea
you know i can count them because
people are downloading and getting from places like controller distribution
so my guess is hundreds of thousands and how do i guess that we have
a little evidence and that's that
there there were twenty nine thousand downloads of the octave
three source code
four months
and that's a lot from the previous stable
but that source code right now many people use source could i don't even know
what if i'm installing activize so computers for people i don't installed from source i
get the debian package
why i installed from source when i can just download
and install quickly
now the doctor foresight distance binary for windows this this numbers even more interesting to
me sixty five thousand downloads of same
version of active in four months
that's just the windows users and i think we have a lot more
in linux users
i don't know about so much about the
mac OS ten users but certainly
there's a lot of a lot of people using active
unix systems and they
so these numbers these these numbers of you know
sixty five thousand i think that's probably
small compared to the number of
now mailing list subscribers are you know there's seven hundred seventy five subscribers to the
help list
partition participation is increasing
overall traffic approximately doubled in the last two years i
i don't know about you but i don't subscribe to the mailing list of every
software package i use so i don't know the multiplayer you would use for this
mailing list subscription number but it's going to be fairly large
posted the list over this is all the time
i started it i started mailing list
almost at the same time i started
writing software
i guess actually right around the time released it to the web for the for
was was an
for the first time
it really took off around two thousand two or three
started really getting increasing participation and i think that happen
around the same time that
a particular contributor sort of arrived on the scene his name is david bateman anywhere
paris and
he did a lot of things he worked on sparse matrix
functions and some of the multidimensional array functions
incredibly active i don't think he sleeps
how serious he again now for almost twenty four hours a day
when he was working the unfortunately his job motorola which allowed him to work on
active life
i ended and now he's working for start-up company which is consuming all this time
twenty four hours a day along with a small children so
he's going to do quite as much work on
also this depth but the end
so for any
vertices u and v
in the ground for any two vertices
all patterns
from u to v
i have the same weight
as they did before well not quite they have the same freeway
so if you look at all the different patterns
and you see well what's the difference between VH
sorry this let's say
delta which is the alternative sparse
and all this of h which is shortest path weights according to this new weight
then that difference is the same
so all these pairs are reweighted by the same amount
it is actually statement about all has not just shortest paths
there we go
how many people is obvious already
if you're here it is
one word
OK maybe not that obvious
i checked out the word when you figure it out
i mean already this
rather verbose
is one word per
still waiting
so let's just take one of these patterns starts at you and we
the very
it is going to see what's new weight is relative to to its old ways
so this is really out w seven age of the past
which we define usual way as the sum over all edges
the weights
of the
the new ways
the edge
from the eye to the i plus one
in other words
it's possible OK
so the best definition of the the weight of path
and then we know this thing is just w
yeah i
the first one
right plus the weight of the first vertex classes
the reweighting of the i
minus the rewriting of the one
this is all in parentheses
it's all summed over i
now i need the magic word
telescopes now it's obvious these telescopes with an extra previous except the very beginning in
the very and so this is
some of these weights of edges
but then
outside the sum
we have a plus
HIV one
and minus
h v
because those guys don't quite council weren't looking at the cycle just passed
and this thing is just
the past
as the
normal way to the past and so the change in the difference between w h
p and WP is this thing
which is just a you
minus HIV
and the point is that the same as long as you fix the endpoints u
and v
the short
you're changing the shortest this pathway
by the same thing
for all passes for any path from u to v
and that person so the one word here with telescopes
and it starts moving
with a certain velocity
let's say this velocity v
and this angle is estate
so this component of the velocity in our direction
cosine theta called the radial component
and one the stars moved to us
we to to star makes no difference
if the velocity of this star is much much smaller than c
f prime one that you will receive
because at times one class
he overseas
the the cosine of the
this equation is only your exam
she is three
i'm standing
cosine theta is positive
the object is approaching
you observe the higher frequencies
cosine figures negative
object is going away radial component is away from us
and the frequency is low
in optical astronomy we cannot measure frequencies we can only measure the wavelength
and the connection between
wavelength and frequency
equals the speed of light divided by
so we can substitute in that equation
f equals
he divided by land
and prime
will see divided by lambda
when we do that
and we also make use of this approximation
one divided by one plus access
it is approximately one minus x
as long as axis much much more than one
this is the first order term in the taylor expansion
you can find that now let the prime
becomes lambda
one minus
minus sign the plus changes to minus sign
for that reason
times the divided by c
i'm schools to think
notice here
you have the radial velocity
you have that you
eleven the prime
is larger than life
the object is going away from us
we call that
red shift
object is receding
lambda prime
less than wavelength
one of the last the land that recall the solution
because the wavelength becomes shorter in this time
move towards the blue end of the spectrum becomes larger
fifty ret part of speech
roche it means the object is approaching
during the accident we discussed this we took an example and the prime of lambda
there's one point zero zero
if your
substitute that into this equation
you'll find that we
cosine theta
equals minus one hundred
what it means
all you know is the radial velocity you never get any information about the angle
that the radial velocities hundred kilometres seconds away from us
we are moving on the club's second away from the star
that's the same thing
if we apply this to sound
then we get
very similar equations
suppose you sit still
twenty six one hundred
and i move sound source to you
you don't move
you get a similar equation that francis crick residual here
he calls f
and one was
POV the sound
the cosine
of the
is about three hundred forty metres a second
at room temperature
in other words
if i trolled something around in a circle
u i
in the plane of that circle you are here
when the object comes to you
the maximum
frequency of prime is larger than that
when it goes away from you
we decrease in frequency
more than half
many objects here
and when is here
when the angle is ninety degrees the cosine say zero
you'll find a prime equals f
the primary process
twelve something around
let's suppose i truly the around was a
orbital velocity if i call the orbital velocity
three point four meters per second just to get some nice numbers
and this is
o point o one
so if it comes to you and increase to one percent in the frequency when
it goes away from you
you hear decrease
one percent
i have here
sound source which produces roughly fifteen hundred hertz
i could turn it around
i can do it once the second around with you twice
so you would here
two percent increase when it comes to you
two percent decrease when it goes away from you
you the doppler shift
it's always difficult intellectual because you get reflections from the wall
you know it when it comes to you the pitch is higher
this parabolic containment function
so that's how these getting units behave in the negative log prob domain if you
think of them in terms of native approach costs the parabolic containment and then linear
facts coming from the hidden units
this is just one example of something in the exponential family
the paper by welling
that shows how
you can apply this kind of idea anything the exponential family most combinations work some
combinations like gas in use
guess visible units engaged in this will blow up on you if you're not careful
they can go improper they can get weights that are big enough
because both sets against him that as you increase the activities of the visible units
and the hidden units together
if the weights is there's been a value value your weight matrix they can block
faster than the quadratic containment function
and that was it is and i evaluate matrix is bigger than the coefficient in
front of this
then think can explode and you can get in from the negative energy so it's
not appropriate proper distribution anymore
so this problems in using getting invisible units engaged in units
but it's fine to use cases visible units in binary or binary visible and goes
and that's because one of these two numbers complex
and here this complex quadratically if this between zero and one
they're both consumers that this can blow quadratically
this is trying to keep it under control automatically is these weights are big enough
it won't standard
i just want show nice example
of another graduate student alex krizhevsky learning a big model with binary hidden units
case in visible units
and you can only we know regularizer there's nothing saying the hidden activity should be sparse
they just turn out to be extremely sparse
it just that's what he wants to do
and what he did was he learned on a few million thirty two by thirty
two colour images were got by taking photos and downsampling and searching for the photos
using the names of fifty three thousand different kinds of things so it
it's a collection of images from the web is very representative
and what influences something really interesting
it has each image is represented by RGB chances thirty two by thirty two
for the red green and blue
just the naive encoding
and when i show you what filters learned like this one
it's got three thousand weights
and i'm showing the three thousand weights by for each pixel showing you the RGB
for pixel so showing the three different weights learned as an RGB value
and what you see is that almost all of them almost learn to be almost
exactly black and white
and this is clearly just property what real images alike
we know the visual the human visual system does this it learns is high figures
a black things in this low frequency kind colour wash
and that's what kind of watercolour pictures work
it's interesting to see a little restricted boltzmann machines a bigger story boards machine it's
got ten thousand to three it's got thirty million websites
and actually took him like several days to learn this on the cluster
you can and probably like in a day on a GPU
and these kind of filters almost exactly balance intensity
and the colour is very wrong in this printer but it has roughly two different
colour contrasts it has that kind of blue yellow and red green many
and the colour filters almost always low frequency fact they're all low frequency and high
frequency the few low frequency black-and-white terms
anyway it does the right thing
one reason i'm pointing this out is the paper from MIT and these tiny images
saying they tried to apply builds machines using getting visible units binary hidden units and
it didn't work
there's also a paper from the cambridge research lab tries to play but machines like
that gets not very good filters
it turns out you have to try quite hard
in a GPU
and they needed several weeks of
actually a couple of months me tell graduate student no try harder
and that's the role of the device
and filling around so is not trivial to get these things to work but they
can produce very nice solutions
now i want to talk about some work by ruslan salakhutdinov me
getting processes with deep belief nets so getting press a really good not finding structuring
that's important thing to be really good at
so if you have just a few labels
they're very good things to use but you have to decide on your kind of
metric and
one way to do it is to build deep belief net
entirely unsupervised and then
say that two images are similar if the the final vectors produced by the deep
belief nets in
maybe that's better measure similarity there
and the
it's sign of the critical angle
which i write c are
is and two
divided by and one that there is a condition and the condition is that and
one must be larger than n two
that's not the case
then there is not
in total reflection
it's actually very interesting
it has practical applications which i will discuss with you shortly
but i first want to do demonstration in which i want to show this to
i have here
and here is air
and i have a laser beam which i can shine in
and i can change angle theta one and slowly increase it and you will see
that when i approached fifty degrees
first of all you will see that they data to increases increases increases and then
when i approached the critical angle and exceeded then we have a hundred percent
let me first on the laser sort of this a little bit of light
and i'm going to show it to you there for those of you
who are not
sitting very close
and that means i have to set the light situation
OK so there you see
the lights
coming in just the way we had on the blackboard
this is the way it comes in in water
this is the reflective part
and this is the one that is refracted into the air
that this one here
and i'm going to increase the angle
when i touch the table the water will start to wiggle a little
you will probably see that
so i'm going to say OK i decree i'm going to increase the angle
come increasing the that they had to
getting larger is going to
approach to ninety degrees
increasing one
increase in one look at data two
almost ninety degrees and very close to the critical angle now
almost at right now
and now all the light is being reflected
o percent
remarkable phenomenon
and this has practical applications
and we're going to show you some of these practical applications two
the most important practical applications fibre optics
if i have a fibre this properly designed
so this is the a fiver
and some light comes in here
and if here so this is some plastic or glass and this is an area
if this angle of incidence is larger than the critical angle
hundred percent reflected
so nothing comes out in the air
on the percent reflected
again the critical angle is exceeded
so hundred percent is reflected
you can go through this whole thing for miles on and you can put even
not in there as long as you never exceeds the critical angle
that light
will propagate
and they will never be any loss
all flights that's why people are very much interested in it you can transport
images as i will show you
through fiber optics
i have here fibre optics
which has four thousand five was
it's fifty microns in diameter each
and we have a laser beam here
and the laser light will come out
i will sorry laser light shortly there and it doesn't matter what i do is
the fibres i can even go on eighty degrees in china there as long as
inside the fibre
i always
exceeds the
critical angle
i don't want the
television anymore so we can turn this off
and let's hear have the
laser lights
it is
see laser light
OK now look at this
this bundle that i have here
and turn it into an absurd snake
almost like an s
all light still comes out
so it goes all the way through
i'm going to
one hundred eighty degrees around two hundred
there is
is an amazing phenomenon
at this light
doesn't get out in the air
stays inside the fibre
and that's the idea behind
fibre optics
i have another
application of fiber optics
right here which is very similar
you can send an image through fiber optics this is my
fibre optics now thousands of
small fibres
and i send the message in here this site an image could be a person
could be text
and here we have the TV camera
and we can watch
that image
on this side of the fibre appears that image
this television camera
will be able
to see that image
let's see whether we can
show you that message
OK i have
do something here again
i think is going on there is
so we actually can see individual five how interesting
each one the individual fibres
the monte carlo estimate is not the only one there's other estimators
and tomorrow article mentions some of them because
i mean maybe alittle provide introduction to them
if you just
from what it would be
very briefly if there's other ways of doing this like some people put it distribution
on this for example and
through that they managed to summon analytical
but this is sort of the sheep easy way
of doing all this stuff
not the best of a certain cheap
and it's
it's an average it's an ergodic averages the laws of large numbers apply
you can get central limit theorem
we know the cell culture
and this is the problem
we don't know how to sample
how to generate some
if you knew how to generate samples there would be no curse of dimensionality there
would be no problem
one the carla has no curse of dimensionality in
mainly because of the thing you know how to generate samples evening
and because the young dimensions if you put the samples in the right place you
can do it
we don't know how to get the samples
i guess this is just somebody that you can read again
this is the sort of delta measure the histogram
and this is just what we do now
four recaps
i forgot and i had this slide
again it's a question of taking this guy replacing it here
and like child is that
now the thing
now if you had one sample
positioned at the mean
in high dimensions
and i will give you the minister that's what i'm saying so its positioning the
samples that is
so i have to have just kind of washed
the problem into another problem
but i haven't solved you correct
and so now we're going to try to solve the problem
keep them on the cover
OK so that's pretty much did it replaced at histogram estimator and just so that
you have it in your notes
then you end up
f of x
and this becomes an approximation now
f of x times one of and
some from michael want to and
delta x
you get the estimator will be chosen
one of the
hi a call one g and f of x i
and this is sometimes referred
sometimes referred to the
the estimator based on in sample for the function
so i was
monte carlo can also be used for optimisation
so sometimes
well if you have lots of samples
if you draw a thousand samples from a distribution then you can look at their
their heights and you pick the highest
that's one of the optimisation
a better way is that to make sure that when you draw the samples that
the samples concentrate the peaks
and we're going to see several ways of doing that one of them that's very
popular simulated annealing
where the samples try to concentrate at the peak of the distribution because what you
care there's about optimisation about finding the peak you don't care about integration
just care about
finding the max
so now let's look at the first basic technique for generating samples and it's called
rejection sampling
the algorithm is very simple
and it works as follows
you iterate steps
what we're going to do
is we can construct another distribution
q effects
so q facsism nice distribution think of it this account
we know how to draw samples from agustin distribution
OK matlab is just around them and you can generate a sample from constant revision
so q of of friendly distribution
again i'm washing out a moving the problem somewhere else and moving the problem to
one of choosing could kill effects let's assume we have a good cure effects for
the time being
and i'm going to try number uniformly between zero and one
in matlab just ex aequo around
one common one
or something in python
i'm going to use maps for this
how many people know matlab
OK good you're moving
pythons the way
i still have everything on my was in matlab unfortunately
OK and so what we're going to do then
if we're going to generate
we generate x i
we generate you and what we excise of the samples that we care so we
generate them from q and then we're can await them in the way
so that their actions samples from p
that's the trick
generate something that's easy
weights in some sort of way
so that they become samples of p
because once they have samples of b then you can solve all the expectations
so first we need to
almost all the expectations
the technique we're going to do
it is we're going to come up with a big number and
and now mention with send this later
that's going and we're going to accept a sample exercise it's going to be only
valid sample
if p is sort of a much larger
mq effects so let me kind of give you
an illustration of this
we try to come up with the distribution q of x
we multiplied by a number
to ensure that this q facts will sort of
dominate facts
so that it provides a good cover
in particular when necessary condition is
but i can't have
q effectively zero
in the region with few facts is not zero
because that would make sense because then you will never generate samples there were vectors
here so you will never get a good estimate of q p of x
MR justice scalia
three eight if
it's there
it's apparently actually once to this one is that the the coin has a
fifty percent probability of coming up heads
the other is that the three flips are independent of each other
that has no memory
in that case because it could be that the help that you could have a
magic coin comes up tails tells tells how the time and heads heads heads half
the time that have had to have tails right
but it's not the case the
two then two hundred would have probability zero
the probability three
so we're making some assumptions here
for most places this option
it's just another example
yes i don't have to beat over the head
and and or
and of course the example when we ask
for the probability the probability that the second letter is o
the rest of the total probability of all events
all sentences whose second
so there's an infinite number of is actually
as you know you can have an infinite sum the infinite summations whose sum is
fine one half plus one core plus one as sentences longer
what happens to their probabilities
you're multiplying more dice together right
the the probability of the die coming up in a particular way is less than
or equal to one so the probabilities will tend to go down
as these things get longer so it's like a geometric sequence
one half plus one color plus one and you do end up something
all strings to one when the sum over all strings second letters
you'll get something less than one
that is going to be
the probability
the second of so that's all it means
OK so let's go back to this program here
i want to suggest that we have a couple alternatives
here's the difference
so what i'm trying to buy you know emphasizing general back over here is say
what you got different choices here when you build model about how you divide the
how what you picture variables to be
how do you decide to
or things in the factor things and what you just what conditional independence assumptions you
try to make so i want to point out something that's kind of wrong about
it doesn't have a dictionary
forces is becoming a very
and while i was missing the forces common more
is more common than the driver that would would predict
because the trichromatic predicts all kinds of words that are not in the dictionary
in which are really rare
it's when we try to model does it stealing probability mass that should rightfully belonged
to horses
i mean i don't know why we take courses much forces
it's forces of
probably going well it's courses
now first one torso is
we could have picked ources instead of course is a dry ground model with like
that just as well
maybe even more
but what happens to affect horses and all
only knows that you know hl are as far as support
are likely
OK so how can we learn from the corpus
the first is the common word one we do
it is instead of talking about random variables like as one of the first letter
we could talk about random variables like w one of the first four
so we can divide you know as long as we have some function which given
the sequence is able to split a sequence of characters able was split white space
we can compute w one given that
so we can talk about the probability that w one is forces and if we
run our white space weather on the brown corpus then we can find the number
of sentences use first water sources
that's this
as expected
so i back to just how which is forces in
and we get
seven point two times ten to the minus
actually is a lot
higher i think than what we got
was on the previous
so was five point four times ten to the minus seven
here we have
more than one hundred times more likely than the driver model for
so this is just really signal
the tribunal model
it's getting something wrong the driver about things that forces us to be
more than one hundred times less frequent than it actually was in the brain
and that's because it just doesn't know that in what happened to pick the workhorses
rather than forces
he gives them both of them
people in probability
that was
OK so
one advantage to using a model based on words
it is that
you know it gets gets the probabilities were writing knows what the dictionary
a disadvantage is what happens if the word shows up like savage which is not
in the brain called
well the triangular would still give some probability because all those sequences of three letters
are still probably the brown corpus somewhere but that word that polish names nor in
the brown corpus so the brown corpus could estimate
probability zero without backing
OK so the advantage is that we focus more probability mass stuff that we've actually
in some ways this is like a six model or something right because you know
it's looking at longer sequences to know whether whether the thing is likely but at
the same disadvantage that any of these higher order models have like six kramer seventeen
he was you know this is you found with respect to each other the field
published this information after
now of course you know this
it's really you know when i was twelve
it's actually original jumbled picture but now we know to time
good photograph
now points you
find just as these zakri run people down and DNA but that's
two hundred
first of all why
we really need to find out
like can to be made this
after creation of graph
you know what is going to look like
and also
is finding subgraphs in large graphs with people
from that he seems like an issue but
well shows small graphs like the unique
and efficiently findable
and in particular in graph theory and you simply connected pairs
your new account simulation probably
in first one trace of he said found itself
now fold in order to three
and i learned relations
which wanted to
that is
the first one to spend maybe
three or four minutes going to
a few specific
so we have roughly shown roughly two like this and
this system know
three two one
we swear
in fact not three squared
experiments again taking our model systems formerly known large graph which part of the problem
in fact i said
and therefore the
twenty four hundred relations between the
four power amplification square ten square from so seven
new accounts for twenty four
were intended to see
first begin breaching privacy with
small work and so forth
notion of a has
one to understand what's going on the space of so what
many of you you can do for this
even advance preparation
i mean the probability that the USA six your friends to
we can be so people can actually be encouraged to ten users just because the
you say is actually
you need to find all the way to hotel
the french relations so reactions leave the four fortress
each of the sort
so it's going to scared when he was
one one hundred mapping rap because interesting here is that understand why small random graphs
actually working understanding the notion of space fuzzy graphs so huge that also is from
this last commentary school
ramsey theory
which has a a very extreme and it's really much from that it's
the idea is to use
this one one calculation here
which essentially shows you were too long and so
all things come through the twentieth century that exists in france
which has no sleep and no one set size two times
number two one
we want to honestly connected by seven points nodes all mutually connected with the decision
related all
is there which essentially said one of the other class
as in any graph
of science about the
it was
in fact we need not be one two times one
and the this population when is false
so this profession exists in this problem you need reference and only
just waiting
so i'm going to take
he said well i could actually working set
well it's OK
it might be more
and to the
well any of those
so we
there are species two possible relation
and the
so to the stage
we're all
that's too much
so that's why it for
so far too much space to any these later and
from a huge number time there is a huge number of things that might be
considered to be but the problem is
it's actually trying to
so competition between two terms and problem
this probably just below ones can get three models students
in this
this happens
well case the
three but was forced
it turns out that in china
the social work
the random
roughly same population works
when we got want to be unique
other things that could be a
we want to get the probability that two myspace
i don't in graph is like driving
right like drop in the ocean number possible graphs so huge it's very unlikely any
that's really what
and in this confusing and
reflections on
and i think it is
so the
there also even in
well it's i completely
graph data no individuals and that's it but they were
no just
when the world is not a social network of mars for any comments whatsoever such
that the world we live
times that say the that goes to new new would be binomially distributed variables
and the parameters p
corresponds to the branching ratio
for that particular mode
so we use that all the time for for analysing
in the case of the particle to some specific final state
OK now this i think we'll get a generalization of the binomial distribution to the
case where you don't have
two possible outcomes but n possible outcomes that's called the multinomial distribution and i'll let
you look at that neuron
i want to belong to the same distribution
which is i think probably one of the most important distributions in
particle physics and
if you consider the binomial distribution
in the limit where the number of trials the number of bernoulli trials becomes very
and the number the probability of success
per trial
becomes very small
but the product of those two factors remains
equal to some finite constants which are called new greek letter mu
that's the expectation value of the number of successes so in that limiting case
the binomial distribution
becomes what is called the posterior distribution
and the number and then can range anywhere from zero up to
any integer from zero up to infinity
and that's the formula which is is almost important enough you should just memorize it
would you should remember that the expectation value then is able to new that somehow
had to emerge from the
the limit of the binomial that we consider
and furthermore the balance of the past so n is equal to its means
so those are two very important problem properties of the posterior distribution
now an example
of the price of distribution is that if we
well the accelerator for
a certain amount of time with the same certain integrated luminosity we can count the
number of
events of some type that occur in that number will follow apart some distribution
right so
that means that a
what's the distribution will be given by the integrated luminosity times the cross section
for the event that we're considering
and you might wonder why is that while
i mean if you think about it if you run accelerator for a certain length
of time to get a certain number of events
thirty seven if you repeat the experiment with the exact same integrated luminosity you've got
to get thirty seven events were you probably won't get thirty seven events again you
may get thirty nine or thirty five and if you were to consider repeating the
entire experiment
under identical conditions this many times you get some sort of distribution and that's the
poisson distribution the
thank you
cross section times the luminosity of course doesn't give you that integer number of events
that you realize on any specific experiment that gives you the mean number of events
but now why should russia should the number of distribution and if you think about
when we collide together particles in a accelerator you have for example a bunch with
ten to eleven protons and another bunch with ten to the eleven protons and you
will allow them to pass through each other and the probability that any specific proton
here is going to collide with
a specific proton there introduced the event is extremely small
on the other hand the number of potential collisions is extremely large because i have
ten to the eleven protons here in ten of the eleven protons there
and they're going to pass through each other and so that exactly satisfies the condition
that i said the number of
trials is actually extremely large and the probability of getting
an event of the kind you're looking for
per trial is is very small but the product of the two
gives you whatever the mean number of events
so we almost always model number of
of course
events that we see
it's very basic to the very formulation of classical mechanics and was the great achievement
of descartes galileo
and newton to realize the importance of introducing this primary concept of mass
as an example
central equation of classical mechanics ethical zalmay which relates
on the left-hand side of the dynamical concept of force that you
computer make rules for
based on the properties of particles
their intrinsic properties
the motion through space and time that their kinematic quantity of acceleration
and to relate those two you need some kind of conversion factor and that's the
role of mass plays something that didn't have mass
something that could giving origin to mass wouldn't know which way to move
it would be senseless object
siemens similarly
if you
think about newton's law of gravity
the gravitational force exerted by conglomeration of matter is proportional to its total mass
if you try to build up that of things that had no mass you be
trying to build up the gravitational force out of the sons of some of things
all of which were zero
so in newtonian mechanics
and in the following development of physics really right up to the beginning of the
twentieth century the question of the origin of mass just didn't arise
mass was the primary concept that could be reduced to anything else
this all changed
at the beginning of the twentieth century
when einstein introduced his second law
m equals a divided by c squared
you may think this is a curious thing to be calling the second law
it's called the second law because there's familiar first law equals MC squared
it's actually inspired
army's instructional manual for radio engineers
which has as in its first chapter owns three laws
which are
holmes first love equals i r
on second law i be over r
and the third law which i'll leave it as an exercise due to
in this case however
and for that matter in that case it's not entirely a joke
because the way you write equation suggest different things
this way of life of writing
einstein's laws
of the conversion of mass into energy
perhaps it's possible to explain mass in terms of the different things that could be
primary that is energy
in fact i einstein's original paper on the subject
has this form of the equation
not equals MC squared
and the title of the that paper
was does the inertia of the body depend on its energy content
right from the very beginning
einstein was thinking about the question of whether he could
get rid of the concept of mass
in favour of the concept of energy
and the theory of special relativity energy plays a much more important and
irreducible role than mass
for instance photons or
he was also think about photons at that time photons or maxwell's equations have the
concept of energy
but not the content of the mass and them
so i einstein from the very beginning i was thinking about the origin of mass
not the origin of bombs which is what equals MC squared HS
so then so now the the the big starting with that the cons the question
of the origin of mass began to make sense
and let's refine it
to the question i promise to address namely the origin of the mass of ordinary
ordinary matter has mass which is mostly overwhelmingly concentrated inside atomic nuclei
well over ninety nine percent of the mass of ordinary matter is concentrated in atomic
and as you learn in high school
are made from protons and neutrons
and as you should learn in high school
but i'm not sure that
everyone that has
by now it's established just as well
that protons and neutrons are in turn made from quarks and gluons
and that's good
if we want to address the origin of mass matter
because we have marvellous theory for quarks and gluons
quantum chromodynamics QCD
it's a theory that's marvellous in many ways
it's a theory that has a tremendous
amount of symmetry
it's based on symmetry really
it's a theory that's very mathematically precise and has few
very few parameters
very few disposable parameters that's the consequence of its high degree of symmetry
finally grand generalizations
of quantum electrodynamics another great theory of nature
best of all though
is not
that's pure that we think it's beautiful appears beautiful is consistent in fact it's the
only really consistent theory that combines special relativity and quantum mechanics that we have
but the best thing about it
is that it's true
how do we know
taken from an experiment of a dominated by MIT l three experiment the web
it shows the body and soul of QCD
in a very tangible form
the body
well first let me the body are the quarks and gluons
so let me explain what's going on here
this is a picture of an event where electrons and positrons travel down
well that's this red can read thing here
they collide and the collision results in three sprays of particles which we call jets
coming out
and i want to argue that these jets are actually quarks and gluons
properly interpreted
how do we come to a conclusion like that
well let's put this in context
when one collides electrons and positrons at these high energies
different things can happen
roughly half the time what happens
a kind of process is governed by quantum electrodynamics
where you see the electron and positron colliding and out comes another electron positron pair
in a different direction
all the twenty two w
c by all those the the quantity that point it is that you can find
and i use the linearity of the inner product i do the computations
and i get
OK let's let's let's go through through the computation so
if you take the inner product between w and x minus c
so if you take this you just use the linearity of the inner product gives
you is
w is just this guy
so we replace w by c plus minus minus
and use the linearity of the inner product again and you get this
for his part
you just take again
the definition of w
the definition of c and you had is that
i think there is a missing one hundred something somewhere three
i i still again i place symbolized by its definition
on the top on the top of the slide c-minus by definition
and i get these
i use again the linearity of the inner product and i get that
x x is computed as
and the second very important message here is that
the decision function
it's just computed as
something like that
so you first
some of
in know product between the training patterns
and the test points
and that constant
and that is all there is to it if you have a linear algorithm usually
you end up with something like this it is very important to see that the
only thing that you need to know is to compute you know how to compute
the inner product between two
pairs of points
and once you you know how to do that you're good
the fact that the sort of thing that is very important to see that
here is the real business kind and it's very easy to compute is just set
c plus this
some of inappropriate of you know products
it just
it depends
on the change training data so
if you can compute the inner product between the training data
which you you know how to do
then you good because computer b is computing these very easy
and and the rest of it is just easy so
i intentionally used these these writing here
with some of the
and the product plus
b because is this is what is going going to be a very crucial points
of of the rest of the talk
and here
very simple very
handy thing
which is that the out for ice can be computed
the reason why i say that is a very simple classifiers
here if
i is the positive points that are far is
one divided by n plus
i is and negative point
it is this label is minus one then alpha i is equal to
minus one divided by
n minus so this only
these here
here sorry is a compact way
to write these here with
i phi
defined as as
so b
is computed like that
so if you place c
by definition
it is a little bit of a for a
calculations then you end up with this
so to summarize the important thing is
once you're able to compute dot products you're happy there's nothing more than that
because you know precisely how to compute i for i and you know precisely how
to compute p
and in order to
to anticipate on what i'm going to to say for SVM for for instance
learning phase is just intended to two
assign values to alfie and b
here is very simple here you can do it analytically if you can program it
you can do it in just just five five minutes you can do everything i
told you about
but for SVM
these are what we're going to do in the practical tomorrow's practical sessions
we're going to program are
an SVM so if you're already done that then don't come but otherwise you can
and the question that is very important that and that we are going to have
to address
for the these these talk is
if the data set at hand is not linearly separable
which is the case here you can try to
they design
but it here or here or here or
whatever you want
wherever you want you won't be able to separate the the the the train set
train sets so
i can see
that's one
step one
in one
one more
and the goal
all how to one
that is
of course
it doesn't
the how
you are
so in this case
so if i go slide back
you know what nodewise more likely to join because they have different squad were more
tightly connected inside him OK
so basically number connectedness of france's what it turns out this if your formalise this
as a an kind of prediction task as machine learning problem and you're to train
your decision tree what you find is that the number of connectedness of friends that
are already members of the community is like the most
the most important feature that determines whether a particular knowledge or joined the network
here's another question so if connectedness among friends promotes joint so
the highly clustered groups and groups that are highly connected
do they grow
right so if i'm more likely to join
the network the group the group all that people are already well connected then
what we should means that the groups that are more connected to grow fast
and what clustering is just the number of closed triads in the network over the
number of open triads and i want to look all to grow from p one
to p two
as a function of the number of closed triads in the group
and the question is how do you do more cluster groups grow growl
here's a plot i hope you can see it
i have the clustering so this would be in low clustering with friends people are
for people are not connected to each other or prime doesn't close and on the
on the right the right side is heavily clustered groups and this would be the
and what you can see is that
the growth rate decreases so we are sort of
having gone
the sort of thing contradiction right
no this is this is already
so so i hope i hope you are able to follow right so first what
we saw is that people do if you can if you have the same number
of friends in the network then you're more likely to join with your friends and
so what this means that now
node y joins the network and this continues so the
the the groups that are more connected should grow faster
so i can go who
so the way the way the study was done
is that i don't you go you're going to grow your network every week for
forty four years ago and now
now you can see
from between two particular times people to join the people did not join
right so
and we take a snapshot of your network every week
and i can say i will look for months worth of time
and see which people in this month joined the groups in which people
could jointly
so you have this information is the
so this is just a bus
but there are more
subterfuge is also going so for example via marketing one could say
the sending more recommendations influence more purchases right
this is this is this is what's going on right so i have a number
recommendations that a particular person sense in the number of purchases
the number of people
that purchase after receiving recommendations of this is becoming purchases a particular person in influence
and you can see that the first the thing grows superlinearly and then sort of
slows down
which is also something that
our models that can capture then a second thing that you can
investigate this morning asking what is this effect in the subset subsequent recommendations right so
if if two people exchange more and more recommendations what's going on with the probability
of buying
so here i'm here i'm blocking the number of exchanged recommendations between the pair of
and the probability of buying OK and what is basically says it's best if you
just command one product
two of particular friends so as you start sending
two particular products
more and more and more recommendations so you're basically spamming the purpose the
the probability drops and then flattens out
some basic
and this is all done over this data set the of sixteen million recommendations was
in fact
you may have no penalty whatsoever because you may have to distributions that share
the same huffman code
and that way you see that there is really
not necessarily any asymptotic penalty
you have IID distributions when n goes to infinity and the huffman codes are
sufficiently far apart that indeed
you incur in
in the penalty
now here's another one that has to do with reliable communication
back in shannon's original formulation
channel capacity
is the number of bits to push through the channel divided by the time the
time it takes to push the bits
through the channel now here imagine that instead of
instead of paying by the time you pay
by the lateral by the euro
so some symbols
cost you one one unit
and some symbols are free
right so
now what happens is that the output develops you what to send you only see
some distribution
induced by the chance
so so that the maximum number of bits per unit cost than that's going to
the relative entropy between p and q
so in essence
when new normalized by cost rather than time
in one of the symbols has zero cost that's important then
rather than having to maximize mutual information like we do in the
and the formula for total capacity you maximize or relative entropy
OK so here's is the connection with
that i alluded to before
so you so that there is this
this interpretation of relative entropy as mismatch data compression well there's also
according to this formula and is actually a very recent formula would take i got
i published earlier this year you can ride is relative entropy for arbitrary distributions p
and q
and integration of the difference between two mean score was
and then this integration is over signal to noise ratio
actually i think i have
and others line here that
this is in a little bit more
detail although i'm running out of time
so here we have the mean square error of course you all know it attained
by the conditional mean
right so if the noise is gaussian if i observe sex in gaussian noise then
i can write that conditional mean
as the ratio of
two integrals
but now imagine
i have in mind the wrong distribution for x
so i have
mismatch in my MMSE estimator
so this would be the case this would be the case where x is gaussian
in which case what you have is of course a linear estimator
that would be the case when x is equal then you have hyperbolic tangent
i'm going to denote the MMSE
a particular signal to noise ratio
this notation MMSE
now mismatches timation is when
and this and this is up q
tells us that the distribution and thinking is through is q
but in fact the x is distributed according to pt
in fact this q actually also depends on p because p is the truth and
q is what i think it is
all right so the MMSE would be
dmc one i think
these are two one and it is indeed the true one
all right so then
ireland during this is joint work between me
jiang and gentleman a so talks creating was decision trees on hadoop
i've had the luxury to work well if do for a couple years down
or sometimes it's a pain but this is kind of more of talk about the
process of how we got to a relatively useful implementation GBDT on
and i do
so the gender is
i'm going first described what GBDT is
globo like the different implementations that we tried and the two different ones like native
mapreduce one as well as one in MPI on top of hadoop
and i go into my reasons why we tried different versions later
and finally the results
so great was the decision trees is a machine learning algorithm that constructs
a ensemble of weak learners with was weak learners are decision trees
and still a process called boosting where the target of the tree is
it's based on the gradient of
the error in the
ensemble before training at tree
so it was first introduced by jerome friedman nineteen ninety nine
at stanford and it process that favors many trees but more shallow ones so typical
numbers they were fleeing power
a couple hundred trees six node tree
one of the reasons why you would have many trees is that
you actually we start with data set at the top of each tree so
your entire dataset starts again i mean you look into the dataset the root of
each tree so you don't lose any dataset as you continue
splitting nodes like correctly decision tree
and there's numerous applications of this within yahoo in terms of regression
the classification so
in terms of ranking we've had quite a bit of success with this with different
learners as you rank which says
pairwise is the pairwise loss function smoothly seaview which is like a listwise loss function
and recently it was used as the blender in and of course solution to the
netflix prize so that like how he combined different
and recommendation
so some advantages of GBDT is that feature normalisation is generally not required unlike some
other learning algorithms such as SVM
feature selection is also an inherent part of the algorithm it is the features present
in the tree
i mean it was useful and it wasn't it
there might have been like in near-identical future something that's also thing is not prone
to collinear down tentacle features
the models are relatively easy to interpret you can just follow the path
the the giving tree that might be arguable is you start having thousands of trees
and it's relatively easy to different loss functions
so some disadvantages that it's boosting right so that inherently not parallelizable if you want
exact solutions
and this extremely compute intensive
for every single feature every feature value we actually have the computer game to find
optimal split point
and it might perform poorly on high dimensional sparse data sets so that the amount
of data that you can
i mean how model the structure model is
it is based on
how many nodes you have an entry so if you have
like six no trees you have a thousand of them you only have about three
thousand split point to it so you have six million sparse
the features are not going to be able to model it
so some known implementations early commercially available treanor from suffered implementation in our planet from
google which is recent papers one and the actual implementation we built on top of
it is limited by time general use at YRL
and there's actually a couple of other implementations here at this workshop
so that the algorithm overview freeman's paper is as described
the first lies basically to initialize the
there you response initial response to
minimize loss function so if you're using something like least squares loss function the mindset
that to the mean of your target
and for every single tree you would want to
for every tree you would look at every sample and compute the gradient of the
function so between the
the target and the current score so far
and for this set of new targets you which had decision tree into
l terminal l terminal node decision tree where each of the responses from each of
the terminal nodes
minimizes the loss function
your score is
essentially the
every tree
plus learning rate which is new and the response to the sample and so on
CSO training especially for you just find our sample propagates in some of the scores
so the
learning process to break it down is essentially to
splitting node right so you compute with
for every given feature
the can split points what's the best split for this feature than for
amongst other features what is the best overall
split point given symmetric as well
information gain a
and what you have to split point you're partition data
into the left and right side and
then you update residuals of how close you to the target you repeat that process
and to construct tree
what you have done territory then you do gradient boosting and update target for the
next race
so for example is a free here
it's a like you
and actually put alpha and beta here found it
that that's what a linear function of x
so now consider one sort of a particular sort of linear function which is the
evaluation function was that what it does is it takes a function
and simply evaluated at the point x
the evaluation function of
six of
evaluated at x
you can see that linear because if i take f let gn evaluated at x
and i'll just get fx gx
we can of course
evaluation of light left less evaluation applied to g
OK so this is the linear function
and i would like this to be bounded
that means
that if i take the
supremum over all functions that the more or less like the maximum over all functions
all of this
divided by the norm of so every f is a member of my hilbert space
so it has an on
and evaluation s is the number
so take the absolute value of this number
divided by the norm of a function f
this whole thing is the number
and i think the supremum of this over all possible functions
and i want this to be finite
that will guarantee that if fixed point x
for any two functions h and g in my head but
if h and g are close in the norm
h evaluated xng evaluated x will be small
in other words
if this holds uniformly actually you can show this
that if d one x minus seventy two x
without two functions f one and f two
this is evaluated indexed the supreme over all x that means the max the the
thing on the left is actually
trying to say that
if you take fifty one x and f two x and measured its prediction of
the point x
this is the prediction of the fd one of the point x is the prediction
of fifty two of the point x this prediction of these two predictions are not
very far from each other
the functions are near each other in the hilbert space norm
that's basically
the intuition that we one
we would like this to hold uniformly overall f because i don't know what f
of the one is going to be
f of the one is going to depend upon the one and i have no
control over the ones
given an arbitrary data set d one i get f of the one arbitrator said
to have a for the two and then i want to make sure that this
distance is not one
is not too large
so this is the property that we would like additional property that we would like
to find both space that evaluation functionals are going to be bounded
and then there's the basic theorem which says that any hilbert space
the evaluation function is unbounded
is essentially a reproducing kernel hilbert space
so now
i have to tell you what a reproducing kernel hilbert spaces
so the development as follows that we started with linear function
and this all kinds of nice things we could do with linear functions
and now we would like to to introduce a class of nonlinear functions
which class of functions
and we asked somehow minimum properties of this rich class of functions
but if you have a linear structure have a hilbert space structure and then the
the evaluation functionals should be bounded
he wanted to maximize with respect to theta you
i wanted to push this bound
the likelihood as much as possible
given a fixed q
by manipulating data
OK so
this likelihood that appears really in the first term of f and doesn't appear in
the second term here this is the standard rewriting of f is an expected
energy here
this entropy term
you can see that the system only
i just think that the only time we can effect is this term in other
words the parameters given a fixed distribution over the latent variables
affect the free energy
through this term expected complete likelihood
and so the the first term is the expected complete log likelihood of the expected
energy if you want to think of log likelihood as energy and the second term
doesn't depend on theta it's just the entropy of q so in order to maximize
with respect to the need to do is to maximize this term with respect to
data and that turns to just be maximizing the linear combination of fully observed models
this expression you
it is the expression most often associated with the algorithm because it's the business part
of the m step
but then leads to some confusion
because it looks like the algorithm is all about maximizing this expected complete log likelihood
no the name is about maximizing this thing
sometimes i suspect and sometimes with respect to q and it just so happens that
when you maximizing with respect to it reduces to this form so don't confuse this
with the actual function which he m is guaranteed to maximize this is the function
which m is guaranteed to monotonically maximize and this is just a piece of that
which we actually manipulate during the m step but the good news here is if
you have here then this is just the problem we already know how to solve
this is of fully observed
model and we want to take the derivative of the log likelihood with respect to
to its maximum likelihood learning in fully observed models
the m step in the algorithm is just like the maximum likelihood learning in a
fully observed models where the model is the sort of a linear combination
of some of the models given by this distribution q
and we're now going
go and look at the e step to see how should we think that distribution
so the the e
it takes advantage of this claim and they're going to do something in the style
of mathematical proof
which is the style i don't like
but all tell you what the style the style is identical to the answer to
and that i will give you proof which convinces you that the answer is right
that gives you no idea how you would have gotten the answer if you didn't
already know it
OK so
my claim is that the optimum setting of humans e step is to post variables
given the current parameters in the data
and i can prove to you that the optimal setting by showing that setting that
choice of q actually saturates the bound it makes at equal to the likelihood and
since we know that that has to be strictly less than or equal to likelihood
there's obviously no better q than the one which saturates the bound
this is kind of an illuminating it may be convinced that this is right but
it doesn't show you why this is so
the real figure out that this would be the answer would be to use some
kind of variational calculus or
to rewrite these in terms of cross entropy is KL divergence is this is really
boltzmann distribution from statistical physics
so you ask yourself
why doesn't
this latter
which is sitting here at the table
why doesn't it go into the lowest energy state which would just be a crystal
isn't there are some rules that
physical systems should minimize energy
well of course that's not the rule the rule of the physical system should minimize
free energy and the reason it doesn't go into crystal state at room temperature is
because there's many many many many more configurations of the water in the liquid state
then there are viewed in a crystal state and so get a huge win on
the entropy term
it's true that the expected energy of this configuration of the water is much higher
than expected energy in the crystal state but there's only a few crystal configurations and
there is a massive number of liquid configurations and so the x two
cash you get back on the entropy term more than makes up for what you
lose energy
OK that's the same thing here in the algorithm right so he says it is
you going to put your money on low-energy configurations but it's good to have some
entropy in the latent variables
so this q the kind of trade-off between those two things is exactly what the
boltzmann distribution from physics would be
so so
after all that talk you need to know is that this is the choice of
q should make in the e step if you want the EM algorithm to work
this choice here is nothing more than inferring the posterior over the latent variables given
the data and your current parameters
that's the that's the main idea
now that we have all these pieces i can try and to convince you of
that link i made between the iraq intuition of the what's the right intuition well
guess what you think the hidden variables should be like and then some values that
gas to make the learning problem into the learning problem that's more likely observe learning
OK mean specified exactly what does it mean guess guess means compute the posterior and
what does it mean somehow use that distribution it means compute the expected complete log
likelihood in the step and optimize that and those two together are guaranteed to increase
the function f which is the lower bound on likelihood so here's a picture which
i hope you have enough information understand this picture in which the abstractly represents the
parameter space that we're trying to search through giving particular datasets is well conditioned on
some dataset you have something on your to desk this is the likelihood of the
and the likelihood function is now some complicated
multimodal page
and we're trying to maximize it so what do we just need to compute you
know start here or wherever compute the gradient and follow the gradient and get here
and we show that just computing the gradient involves summing over all
the configurations of z n you actually have to do inference now one
look at what is he doing in this picture of what he is doing it's
constructing sequential
convex lower bounds this function
well conditioned on a particular q
becomes convex function of data
that's the reason we were able to maximise its so easily in the amsterdam system
right because it's a linear combination of fully observed models
what it does is add a particular set of parameters theta that your current guess
at the parameters it constructs a distribution q over the latent variables that distribution q
induces a convex function
f of theta given that you q
which is guaranteed to be little bit more likely
well if you think that this is concave we can call concave
that's fine
can do this
in general
there's so
right you can
you can take this further and you can actually move to
reproducing kernel hilbert space you
don't necessarily just limit yourself to like finite dimensional representations and if you do that
just to sketch that here
basically you could
so ended up in the following way that you have hilbert space of functions f
and these functions are defined basically as
linear combinations over some sample set of points that's and these points are actually is
the sample of input output pairs OK so point here is that is really an
input output pair
and and then you have these coefficients offers it right so
so this is a way that you can think of
you know you have generating kernel
and basically all the things that you too
with end is a reproducing kernel hilbert space you can also do by just basically
treating of the input output pair
really is your input and sort of the kernel then just instead of just dependent
on on on the single
said here it just depends on this cross product so this is not
this is not too deep and of course
you know you can think of these kernels as a special case that they are
defined as we define it before basically as as inner products of some feature representation
that you extract
and and again you know i said this we already said this before if you
think it in the criminal world again right for the tensor product kernels for instance
you basically just get factorisation over kernels that are just defined over input pairs and
kind of functions that just defined over pairs
for something like this tensor product
OK so they have two purposes here really so one is what you already know
you know in general from kind machines that you know they are flexible and efficient
featureextraction they often help you to avoid the limit yourself to
you know finite dimensional feature representations they might help in longer much faster learning by
implicitly using the kernel functions instead of explicitly computing inner product in this context here
you also have always the problem of combining things on the input and output sides
which might be a problem in terms of the common the combinatorics of the combinations
that you actually want to look at so like in this case here right so
then kernels by if you have a conferences that factorizes nicely like this
right then that's also an advantage on the computational side that
a kernel approach would give you
OK so then
let me move to the story and the
slower than i thought let me move to
talk a little bit about statistical inference problems for structured prediction
in general
if you look at it without committing to a particular learning algorithm or particular formulation
even of the learning problem you can look at it in the most general setting
as follows you have a training sample s
your training sample these are now input output pairs right x y i and you
have some
cost function
our functional that takes
as input let's say a function from the
from RKHS
and he basically measures the goodness of fit of f right we will look at
different possibilities for that
and then we have some regularizer in there
typically we would use basically something that depends
there's a simple function of the hilbert space norm of our function f if we
have something like that and we want to minimize such regularized objective function with
func function here that depends on the training sample and this ondition stabilizer
then we get the following representer theorem and there's basically one thing that you need
to understand here that's different from the general case so basically you can show that
the minimiser of that have had
for a given sample
is it is the function that will can be written as the sum over all
your training example OK that's usual but now you have a sum over all possible
outputs y of in your output space and then you have to wait a better
i y for this depends on the training in x here i and on the
actual some output y
note that this is not just why i it's it you know you need
all of the otherwise basically show up in the some you need to consider and
then it's the kernel function
basically this is the argument you going to apply this to write an input output
pair and the second argument is basically the pair x i y
OK so
so what is
if you just do this in the without you output learning in the in the
case that you've probably seen this it'll just be a summary of training points then
there will be a bit i and then it will be k a blank comics
yes yes so row I tells you what
which cluster data item I belongs to and row backslash I tells you the clustering
of all the other data items except the Ith one is basically the same as
that yeah the only difference between Z and row is that zet also
includes not just a partition but also a labelling of each cluster of the partition
yeah yeah this is basically an unlabelled clustering yeah so I guess there was a question
just now about how do we set alpha okay we also saw that you know
we can derive the expectation and the variance of the number of clusters as as
a function of alpha and N and they kind of look both look like this and we can
see that so I think this is for restaurant with one hundred customers or a data
set with a hundred data items when alpha equals to one this distribution over the
number of clusters tells us that the the Chinese restaurant prior Chinese restaurant process prior
gives a very strong assumption about the number of clusters that are used to model
one hundred eight items right in this case when alpha equals to one basically this is about
I don't know six or seven so what is says is that it believes the prior says
that it believes very strongly that the number of clusters exhibited in a data set
of size hundred should be on the order zero to ten there should be
at most ten clusters okay when alpha equals to a ten then the number of clusters ranges between
twenty and forty and when alpha is a hundred then the number of clusters ranges
between sixty and eighty okay and basically this Chinese restaurant prior Chinese restaurant process
prior it's a very strong prior it tells even without seeing the
the data it is kind of saying that it knows the number of clusters
that is in the data set yes yes in fact in fact it will approach a
Gaussian in fact if will approach a Poisson which does approach a Gaussian as N goes
to infinity yeah so how do we set alpha we kind of have to set alpha
such that the number of clusters under the Chinese restaurant process reflects the number
of clusters we believe should be in in our data set right so if
we believe that there should be fifteen clusters in our data set of a size hundred
then we should set alpha such that it has a mean about fifteen yes
that's true in fact under a Dirichlet process there will be actually not
that many clusters which are small-sized basically up to the if you knew the
number of clusters it's basically kind of a gives a uniform distribution over the mixing portions among
that number of clusters more or less so that's kind of not as much of an effect
so yes yes that's right so if you do
believe that there's like at most ten clusters in the dataset even though you have
ten million data points then you shouldn't use a Dirichlet process Dirichlet model then you should
do something else okay in that case you do believe that it's a parametric model
in a sense at most ten clusters yes yes
yes that's right because if you really have no idea that the number
of clusters then you cannot set alpha to any fixed value because once you
fix alpha then it has a very small variance around its mean right so what
you could do is actually could give a prior on alpha that has
a kind of a wide range over all possible values of alpha so that basically
you remix a different values of alpha together we're gonna get a distribution over
a number of clusters that's a lot broader and in fact that's kind of what
I do in practice I kind of think about what is the minimum number of
clusters kind of and what's the maximum number of clusters that I expect to
see and then with that range I could set a range for alpha that would have high probability
over that range of the number of clusters yes
yeah so it is quite similar in the
sense that you have this hyper parameter which in the case of a finite mixture
model you have the number of clusters and in this case you have alpha okay the
difference is that it is and this it seems to be easier to to
learn about alpha in one single model than it is to learn about the
number of clusters in a mixture model where basically the number of clusters is this
discrete quantity and is a bit hard to optimize it ought to compute posterior distribution of it
of course there are approaches did Peter Green talk about reversible CMC no
okay so yes there are ways around it but it's a lot more complex than this
so the nice thing with this approach is that you know one model and that
model will tell you the number of clusters in your data while in the other
approach you cannot say that there are lots of different models each of which has
a different number of clusters and then you have to decide which which of
the models is best explains the data and that's kind of a more
complex processing it kind of has to be a double looped type of algorithm where you do learning
of your models in the inner loop and then determining which model to use in the
outer loop and that's kind of a lot more expensive to do yes
in this case in this kind of power-law but it's kind of a bit of
a degenerate power-law yeah I'll come to that actually a bit later when we talk about Pitman
Yor processes because those are actually give you much richer power-laws okay so that's the
CRP representation right actually any other questions about the this clustering CRPs
okay so another representation is this degrading construction and in the case of the
stick breaking construction the nice thing is that we can basically dissect our Dirichlet
and so on
all right
so here's the problem
and now
let me show you the solution
well let's graph function
so would say here's the graph
here's some points
maybe i should write lower so that i don't
so here's the point he
maybe it
about point zero
x zero by the way
this was supposed to be an auxiliary that was the some fixed place
on the x axis
and now
in order to perform this this
might be
i will
here's another color charge
so here it is
there's the potential
i went straight to no
i did it
all right that's the and that's the geometric problem i achieved
what i wanted to do
it's kind of an interesting question which unfortunately i can't
solve for you in this class which is how can i do that
that's how physically did i managed to know
what to do
to draw the tangent line but that's what geometric problems are like
we visualize that we can figure it out somewhere in our brains it happens
and the test that we have now
is to figure out how to do it analytically
to do it in a way
machine could do just as well as i did in drawing attention
so what do we learn in high school about
what the tangent line is well the tangent line has an equation
anyone who point out the equation y mynydd y zero
people to
and slovak tech
so here's the
equation for that line
and now
there are two
pieces of information that we're going to need to work out
what the line is
the first one is the point at that point he
there and to specify p
given x we need to know
the the the the level of y which is of course just like
it's not a calculus problem but anyway that's a very important part
the process
so that's the first thing we need to know
and the second thing we need to know
it is
this led
and that's the number and
and in calculus we have another name for we call it
after prime that zero
the derivative
of so that's the calculus for that's the tricky part and that's the part that
we have to discuss
so just to make that clear
explicit here i'm going to make a definition
which is the prime suspect zero
which is known as the derivative
of f
at zero
this slow
y equals back
the point
let's just call it
all right
so that's what it is
but still i haven't made any progress in figuring out any better how i drew
that line
so i have to
say something that's more concrete because i want to be able to cook up what
these numbers are i have to figure out what this
number and is
in one way of thinking about that and just
so i certainly am taking for granted and sort of non calculus part that i
know what line through point is
so i know this equation
another possibility might be
you know this line here how do i know unfortunately i don't quite straight there
it is
how do i know that this orange line is not
the tangent line
but this other line
its attention
it's actually not so obvious
but i'm going to
describe it a little bit it's not really the fact