what do these CSP patterns look like so
these three classes left foot right foot sorry left hand right hand foot
the nose
and you see all these crosses correspond to sensors
so as i said if you move or imagine your left hand then on the
right hemisphere
there's some activity
and in is essentially what what we're always trying to do is to create a
spatial filter that reflects this
we would the most discriminative is so to say to to see it to have
the filter that that takes into into account its physiology so
discriminating left activity and write activity and in the obvious thing for for CSP filters
just to have be very active in this region respectively in this region that
so this is just a few is so that this you convolve this
this thing so this is a positive and this is negative it's like
it's like you
of the motor cortex on the on the right and left side and on the
right side and you convolve this with EEG signal
over time
so typically and so is maybe one more remark maybe you want to ask this
question but maybe not one more remark markers is
so what i haven't said so far is that typically we
two bandpass filtering before doing this year's p
would before computing
it is because so we are
looking at certain frequencies c
twelve months also
and we're looking in this frequency band for some very discriminating filters
this is CSP is
now your question
most obvious these are these
this is just a very simple case so you
compute the very structure
of the single
down to the sea
bandpass filter
and then you have all these very
for the
i j
what about
and then you
so addition whitening solve the problem that you get
like for two classes you get what you get these
protect the p and the protector are and you concatenate them
and that's your project w that you can to the sea
let me just i go
forward a little bit step further
and maybe it will be clearer
this is just this side of
i have been showing my videos information transfer rates and this is just the the
formula how we measure
so if we have
p is the classification performance of or classifier that distinguish between left and right say
and we have and the number of classes then
can we can define the information rate precision as this so this essentially shannon
of course there are smarter and better ways of doing that
and for example
he did on his thesis has some
good insights on that if you want to
look it up
but this is the typical definition of the information transfer rate by the community
of course if you think about it and in particular if you think about my
brain pong game
we i do some continuous control
so you know
this only considers some some discrete classification
so it's it's actually for continuous control this is not the right measure for information
transfer rate
OK images OK so your question comes here just as the previous peer review OK
but then
shine this picture
i showed you before the plot how much we can gain
by combining
and now i showed you the definition of the information transfer rate so you can
actually to saying you can know what is on this axis
that's the the shannon information formula as you sort of the last slide these are
some subjects
and the question of this study is the underlying question is is OK should we
actually just
you know ramp up the number of classes and they get another high information rate
so if you know can we take
hundred classes and then we get in a thousand bits per minute or something like
that and of course this is not possible
why because
if we
distinguish between different classes of all classification performance will go down a little bit because
there's more crosstalk between the class
a difficult problem the end and so if we go from from two classes so
from two classes to three classes between three four classes five plus six plus is
you see that the
of the
this is the information transfer rate
thirty percent from this one i have to have these are called the mixing proportions
and we're going to see them OK
you can think about how we would be if you were to actually sample from
a mixture of gaussians would first have to decide which goes into sample from with
a certain probability and then sample from the right so you would need is mixing
so now if you want
if want to force mixture of gaussians to be the same as k means we
need to take the mixing proportions to be the same for all OK equally likely
that i take
because because k means
it doesn't say that one cluster is going to be bigger than the others it
doesn't say anything about the right
just among
actually becomes a bit later
sorry about that i thought i thought that
the next slide was different one and is OK so before i tell you how
to how to
how to
c k means as a mixture of gaussians
let briefly skim through the
through the limitations of of k means
if you use k means you have noticed that there are initialisation problems that you
get different solutions for different initializations
so now here's a question to you what do you do about that in practice
OK repeat the experiment and and then what you do which one do you keep
OK the best one in which sense
what you exactly so you say you want to minimize the average distortion and and
you just we initialize and you keep the one that's what i do was well
OK the OK another thing is
distances are computed
i in an isotropic way right so if i had my data was this
so what would be the what would be the k means solution here
i can make this longer
and long
so k means here
it's actually going to decide that this is one cluster and this is one class
and the reason is
it doesn't know about learning how to compute distances right so it just
just compute distances
in the same way in in all directions right
so if we could learn a scaling then you could very easily
have actually
done this right if learned
how to compute this is good but it really doesn't
how to find k and they're going to say much about that because when i
talk about mixtures of gaussians i'm not going to tell you either how to find
k so it's it's a tough one actually how to find k
the other thing is so remember this responsibility variables that we talked about these are
i is
for k means there either zero or one
there there far OK we're going to see the mixtures of gaussians they become soft
there's also variants of k means where you can actually make himself
that's a bit of a hack
so this is what i was trying to two two to say before i forgot
that i had a slide in between
so this would be if you had a mixture of gaussians you can sort of
say well each cluster i'm going to think of its cluster as it goes in
distribution really write some good i'm going to imagine that when the data was generated
it was actually generated as i said earlier by
having a mixture of gaussians
which are located at different places and i have certain prior probabilities of drawing from
the OK and they have the mean and covariance function and that's how the data
was generated and now
i get given the data
and i try to sort of guess
where discussions were OK
if we were to take goes instead that they just have no variance and they
have just a unit variance
and i was to take equal mixing proportions
my model would be indeed this sort of a mixture of gaussians here despite k
should be replaced by one over k OK right now
let's conditioned on the fact that we're looking at one specific
so there's little o notation mistake in this line actually
note here
where it says j
it issues a case OK should be equal to j should be little agreement between
the two
so if we if we condition for a moment
on the fact that we're we're computing the likelihood for fixed cluster for fixed gaussian
we have to decide we go through all the points and we have to decide
whether this points belong yes or no to that goes OK
and we can do that by raising
the the
sort of the gods in evaluation of of each point to the power of the
of the indicator variables right because if it's zero is going to be one and
it doesn't contribute to the to the product right
so basically what this is doing it says all only only compute the gaussian likelihood
here for the points that do belong to this class OK and remember j is
k and we're looking at classic
so what happens if we work out the whole thing and if we work out
if we work out the likelihood for the small right given given the responsibilities
well if we were to do that if you look at this equation here what
we would end up with indiana is would end up with having to
a very similar expression to what we had in
k means actually right
so now you can ask yourselves
OK so what was this all about why we need to
look at k means is a mixture of gaussians are trying to sort of make
a smooth introduction of mixtures of gaussians OK
constraining mixtures of gaussians a lot to make them similar to k means and now
what we can do is simply relax assumptions and
OK so
mixtures of gaussians
as we said
we have
number of capital k
garson distributions OK
and we have some indicator variables so s
there's one is i for each data point so if we have n data points
we have an such indicator variables
and this indicator variables what they say
if you know this intersection rule then it's actually immediately obvious that it's convex
because if you look at this definition
for a fixed fxt
and they say that this
for a fixed fee
polynomial has value
absolute value less than one
that basically means it's great and minus one less than one
so get two linear inequalities in the coefficient of x
if you think it is just on
and as a condition of x you get two linear inequality to take the
so for fixed that defines two parallel hyperplanes tool but i ask for example in
you might have for some
this is hyperplane on says that polynomial has a value less than one other is
the value has to be great and minus one
you get two parallel hyperplanes
everything in between is and that that's why the commission and any very t
and as you very peaked at an intersection of many different hyperplanes infinitely many
since all these sets are convex defined
here we do is put these lines correspond to
so i think this polynomial equal to one minus one
for some fixed and then we say the
and your thing that that's not fully political
it's obviously convex
that's this intersection property
that's not very useful
it allows you to immediately see that this is convex without actually
writing an informative
another two more obvious book called property is that if you
take the image of a convex set and they're are not find information
general something defined by this is a linear combination of experts constant
then your opinion you context
for example the projection of a convex set is always convex
and also if you take say anything preimage
and there and find information we look at all
points that are mapped to the set s and it is i find information also
so for example we've seen that the positive semidefinite cone is convex
and from this it immediately follows that this
so is convex the solution set of linear matrix inequality
here we take this is called a linear matrix inequality
we take in symmetry
i mathematics b
and the condition is that this linear combination of those made a i
the coefficients x
is this article to be in the matrix inequality be minus the right left hand
side of the same
and it follows from that just the fact that the of
that the set of semi with convex
and then this property
this is actually the
preimage of the positive semidefinite cone and a linear transformation
b-minus the left hand side
this also is convex
as another example take a positive semidefinite matrix b
and then you say the accessible both the axis based on the square of the
transport act
and also see as both on a
so that's actually an indefinite quadratic inequalities to bring the second term here the left
and you get a quadratic inequality but indefinite positive semidefinite
and then the negative sign on the screen
it's not immediately obvious that context an indefinite quadratic inequality
but there's actually follows from
again this property and the fact that this
second order
because we define the second order cone like this
four are who
and then this is actually kind of USB
again the preimage of the second order cone and the a linear transformation
the tea party becomes is that there equal to t
it but i think that the
if they can ask semantic code of the CP one half that of the ten
the second part of the second order cone
and then this is that does this linear function of x has to be in
second order
and the last one is actually
interesting this is not that important
we've seen that the linear image and i find transformations preserve convexity
i have
query variable
accepted p one
and i looked to see
in my knowledge base
what are the rules that i have not talked about
papers being accepted
it turned out that
i have
this depends on
the quality of the paper
and now the quality
are there except it depends on the quality
i can
can construct
local probability model
given the information that i have
backward chaining on high quality
if you go back and look at the rules
it turns out that there's two different grounding for this
whether there
authors our
or the author
and i actually do put both of these groundings into
the constructed
put in
and i put in
and now i need to create CPT
for this
i'm going to
make it and noisy or
but i have to
can define
how i construct the CPD
you can see that there's is an arbitrary number of potential
what is that these things could be in
injuries i have to specify how this is done
and then if i looked
now it turns out none of them
have any
matching rules in the knowledge base so i can conclude
now i go i
and i do a search
what evidence i have so i
five is far
i go through
and you
variable elimination that i showed earlier
for computing the probability of the paper being accepted everything else is well defined here
and i guess i never did that
actually get
so that's the idea here
right and actually i'll talk a little bit about some of the
kind subtleties
i choose the nice example
it doesn't have
any subtleties it worked out
very well but
six problems come up
well let me
first talk about some of the ways to handle
and then get back to that question
as said at
i think the
the best way to potentially deal with negation will be the context variables and i'm
going to talk about sex
good question
so you guys are anticipating i think and number of the
the things that
first stuff
an even simpler one
i was brought up the issue of
i may well have backward chaining
to the point that
i get things that employ
both the query and evidence
and you need to
be able to reason about the
because it is possible
in business for the
query and evidence have common ancestor and
i need to make sure to include that correctly on the basis that i
and that may get a little bit here because i'm
reasoning about the different possible
instantiations of all the different roles and i have to look at the combinations and
so on
the nice thing is that actually is sufficient because
using kind of the bayes that
i was
you can say that
they descended the things that are separated
are irrelevant i don't need to include them into the business and this is something
that does
so the huge amount
in terms of
the possible construction
is not
it often is the case that
there's some kind of deterministic knowledge that you want to make use of
rather than kind of
taking that into the bay is that we want our approach is to introduce these
the importance weight at time n minus one
time the same quantity x one
over gamma minus one x one n minus one
o basically qn xn
one minus one
OK so before
well i wasn't using the resampling step i was going to impose time in politics
for time and minus one time this
so when you have an for doing this recursion you that essentially doing importance weight
was appalled at basically an increasing number of ten
typically basically it violence that increases exponentially fast with at the time index no basically
when you do resampling time and minus one
at each time step on particle at time n minus one of the new importance
when considering he's basically
by this expression on was the washing or for that when the washington for that
is very simple
once you basically was so important part called according to their own particular solution time
and that's what they're approximately distributed according to pi minus one
after the sampling step
the past x one two x one x two xn minus one xn as the
distribution after the resampling step which is
approximately necessary approximately
the target distribution at time
ten minus one
because you've been resampling particle at time n minus one to the approximated according target
this the
the conditional distribution so this is why once you've basically introduced something that basically the
importance so it is normal basically report from the problems with the time minus one
in one of these guys
basically it simply given by question
once you've got the new parliament something weight at time n OK
what you do yourself or to be the time from the associated with the empirical
measures to obtain w new particles approximately distributed according to certain
no you don't need to you mean for four
in or something
well if you just you you like to like to put more less
you could you could you don't have to have basically and which is constant over
time if you're so you could basically was on call
the number m of them where i could be large large and small shop you
he began people on that but it's possible show
so in particular so you in france instead baseball or
you have to kind of big of light coming out so the weights are really
kind of don't be very well
actually like you i then basically you could include at this stage more particles special
you could do
so these are stories
OK which is like a scene for twenty or modification of the original importance sampling
basically the reason why this is two approximation of the time solution of the approximation
before there are some things that are basically the approximation after sampling all remember here
that have been been abusing notation that essentially part the particle are the result of
all articles on i just susceptibilities get
also what does it give us well remember i was interested in approximating the normalizing
this is in
it's easy to check that if you look at the explosion
of the importance weight at time n which is basically the ratio of successive target
divided by the conditional distribution of xn given x one x two x minus one
if you take the expectation
o basically these normalized importance weights with respect to pi minus one two and then
this thing is simply equal to the ratio of the successive target distribution
OK new approximate destroys two
well after
the resampling step i n minus one my father caught up ultimately decided to go
according to pi minus one they on polar component xn iconic this conditional distribution so
basically you have some balls at time n
before there are some things that which are approximately distributed according to this target
so basically you can use the to basically approximates the ratio of successive normalizing constant
by the symbol on particle average so that very simple errors
if you're interested in the the successive rise to a normalizing constant but basically the
normalizing constant time and you just multiply all of estimate gaza only we go you
have basically the normalizing constant estimate of the target distribution
so i'm a bit funny
this is going to be a bit in poland have time is that is essentially
user sampling scheme which is unbiased that is like essentially all the or something sky
using in pakistan so
basically that is is essentially the expectation of the number of offspring of particle like
is simply proportional to its weight
w and i then you can show
that as in the second country pollen something case the ex chairman of the normalizing
constant astigmatism by action
that's quite a remarkable property despite all this interaction taking place into the algorithm used
to live basically by the system in the normalizing constant
OK so let's basically to kind of better products understand what's going on let's see
what's going on when you apply to newmarket for the time as placement model OK
so in the state space model remember what you're interested in you
the dynamic model
where x one is distributed
according to new then you have a markov process
of transition
on you have acceleration which are approximately distributed
i call which are distributed sort according to g OK so that define the target
was the distribution of the first and later volleyball and the enforce of salvation which
is simply portion the one
that involves the data
the data being the part of the data that we modelling otherwise of course k
itself depends on the axis
i call this the benefit terms
i call this term here
the complexity penalty
to you probably know about the fact that when you fitting models to data you
should worry about where the model
is perhaps
too complex to fit the data and you have to worry about things like overfitting
not in the case against the process
in the case against processes this thing taken care of by itself
and you see that by actually observing that the marginal likelihood exactly has the trade
a data fit term and complexity
penalty term
so also a third term here was very boring
so now
so how would we actually
how do you actually
go about using this thing in practice
what you could do in practice is that
often you have a
covariance functions that involve
the promise of
we would want to try to find out what are good values of those parameters
show you an example of that
here's an example with the same shape of covariance function as before
but have introduced to process here
one parameter is is the squared here
and one parameter is elsewhere here
because the
the the distribution you get over functions depend on exactly
this is the
the form of this this covariance function
for example
notice that i told you that if the axes are far apart
then the
covariance of the corresponding output values will be small
if the is are close together then they have higher commands
but i didn't tell you exactly what is meant by
and what is meant by far apart
this notion can be parameterized right so now down here measures
gives you a scale to measure when is x prime deemed to be close to
be close to each other so if l is large
then even if they are quite far apart though still be deemed as being course
if l is very small
then they have to be really close before the various time
and similarly the square just gives you the variance of the overall process
so now let's try to fit
again using a very simple data so let's try to fit
i guess the process with different values of n not just focus on the values
of the
in general there are the parameters there is also the noise parameter
and the overall skill from let's just focus on a on this case
have a data set with twenty points
and i try to fit in with three different girls and processes had three different
values of the of the length scale parameter
so in red
i've chosen very short lengthscale problem
in green are chosen immediately intermediate length scale l two very long lengthscale
x notice in the the the bluefin here is not a very good fit to
the data
it the model says that even if the axes are quite far apart
they still deemed to have high variance high
the only way you can achieve that is by having a very small function
of course is very small function doesn't do an incredible job of fitting the data
so it's not clear that if the lengthscale too long
then the the mall doesn't really fit the data very well it's it's sort of
under fitting
so what happens if the if the if the data is the length scale very
that's what the the red curve here you see the red curve actually fits the
data points almost exactly
so if the length scale is very short you can also see that the that
the function is able to june two new stuff so in between datapoints right
the characteristic length scale
maybe on the order of the link between two data points here
so they so the
the function can do something significant in between two data points
you get in an almost perfect fit to the data
and in green have the
the value that i get if i just optimise the marginal likelihood
notice that the the green fit is not as good as the right fit
in terms of actually fits the training data
but it does seem to us to be more reasonable fit but it seems that
it's probably more reasonable to expect that a little bit of noise here
some of w
so this thing is is
cohen and otherwise you can just scale up
everything and have the better gamma
so we make this right and it's usual kind of SVM thing we eliminate gamma
and translate that into minimising the norm of w square
president substitution
so it looks very much
like in SVM right now assume without outside variables except these constraints now you have
three example and for each
all ultimate for example
you have some kind of constraint essentially constrains the truth beats out
this alternate this runner-up
order of the margin
in the case where we can do this we need to add slacks the same
way as we did SVM we add slack
for each example
OK so
so i and they're essentially in allow us to violate this constraint that the penalty
if c
so OK so now we have this problem with this we've sort of road down
exactly what we want
and we could senses do brute force enumeration
all these constraints and try to solve it
o ou u this doesn't scale of course and we try we try to do
instead is actually
do this thing
exactly the same problems through what's called so called min max formulation
it's going to be
it turns out was some algebra is going to turn out to be on also
polynomial in
all the things you care about number of wise
number of parts in india
in the input
two years ago from this kind of exponential
enumeration into something that's
that's a much nicer and we do this is by doing the following trick it's
simple trick
essentially what we're seeing here is that the truth beats out everybody else
by this amount everybody else for example so it must beat the max
and then we're going to do is take this max foster now we have something
we agree with the minimisation over continuous space and then embedded in this thing
is the discrete maximisation over y
and then the second trick is to take this
embedded max
and take you know you go from a discrete optimization into continuous one
if we can do that without loss we can essentially just take that
continues decision plug it in and have a joint continues measurable
and that's exactly what we do
the question is whether
so the
this assumption is to make this work are this structure looks like a set having
lost that
it decomposes in the same way
as the model so i summer parts and compare whether i got the part right
so this could be zero one basically but it doesn't one it could be something
weighted as well in certain part making a mistake in a certain part might be
more costly than another part
so it's something decompose into parts
so it's kind of a weighted hamming distance a
so that's t
and then our get decomposes again into this thing into parts this is part of
the score
and this is the part of the
we're going to do then is this mapping from discrete to continuous so what we
do is basically
have some variables e roughly correspond to
OK there are continuous relaxations of y and then
q is going to be
we're all of us are coefficients of the fact that so
i'm going to explain what you is but
this is going write down this this this
descriptions a something which usually would solve the there was a weighted matching organic program
to determine or passing things that said
we write it down as a linear programme
this is not to say this is how we can do prediction right this is
the a tool to to do the learning art and kind of get the reductions
the way you do
your prediction and the run time is still up to you right to this is
just a tool to actually know be able to to map these problems into something
and then you know once we we can kind of
see these guys are
equivalent value in long as they return the same value this in this for now
what dependency when w and l
as long as it is in the same value things like this thing in end
go that
OK so now if this going to sort of take a step back and explain
to do this
argmax using linear programming for a few years problems
and then we can come back and plug it in and see what happens
OK so o
the plan is to take our whatever we're going to do with the dynamic program
and now write it down into more actually declarative way that program you usually is
is thought to
so what do we do that is to take a y fronts in this case
is the thing with sequences right we take the y
and it's still five cience five sequence and we get
encode that
with five variables great
well fire exits kind of vector variables these variables
question so these variables correspond to just going to have what i really want to
be is a binary variable for each of these
for it is it's possibilities again
this corresponds to the first character this correspond to the second character that so
was is less than thirty or years
and those are really the students almost exclusively who have less than forty five
for example two or approximately four
so this is the danger zone doesn't mean
that you will fail
the cause is just a matter of probability says hi
and those of you who are dying to know what are they going to get
all i can say is that if you leave now is more than forty five
so that you've taken all exams
then you will probably end up with an a
really you end up with a i don't know
it's all a matter of probability chances i mean
that's as far as i can go
regarding the
dividing lines
course grade
i will continue to ideas of interference
which has very far reaching consequences
and i will turn to what we call thin films
and i will cover
little incident
doesn't change very much changed two different angles
concept is the same
i mean field
i have here a
thin film of oil
and we will shortly see what i mean by that
this is a air
so we have plane waves of light coming in this way
normal instead
this is an one which is an that's about why
this is and two
it's for oil
it is about one point four five let's make one point five
so we run of
this is an three
which is again air
in this case so that make one doesn't have to be and i will make
and that the separation
order thickness this i should say of or we the
and i call this surface
eight and the service three or air
call that the
so that the lights
in a normal incidence comes in from above
over a large surface
i just put in one area here
and that that intensity BIC
now i'm going to calculate how much
is reflected back into the air
and i put zero here
so offset
just for the purpose of marriage
so some of it is reflected
and some of it goes straight through
all of you are more than capable of calculating how much is reflected
at that point eight
are reflective of effect
is and one-liners and
defined by and one class and two
that mind is o point two
the minus sign tells you that that is the front period effect
five hundred eighty degrees
the intensity of the light that is reflected is then for
this graph not
and he four percent is reflected
and clearly ninety six percent go through
so if this is one hundred
and this is four point zero
and this is ninety six
this slide here
it's the surface b
the boundary between all the air
and some of that light go through
is i'm not interested in
and some of it comes back
so i can calculate
again the are value for that
surface in the
it is now and two
and three divided by and two cross and
this is an three so that plus o point two
so there's no flip e vector as it
and the
the fraction of the light that is reflected is again for percent
however it is four percent of the nineteen six or nineteen six percent and four
percent of ninety six percent
three point eight four
which is this surface again four percent will be reflected in ninety six percent will
but on the final advance next topic let me check with questions
the same thing
choose how
they made
yes absolutely yes the regression
can run into the lookup in which action is not the panacea for the problem
of overfitting on the underfitting on the it can still runs the same problems the
way to regression on which she just said on about
and so some some of these things that he does discover for yourself in a
whole you actually see what you just mentioned
it also like even though we all
o point
so the question is this is what is almost as you know building model because
you need the entire dataset and
the other saying that is that this is a nonparametric so this is an on
i want i want to debate whether you are we really building model on on
its own
this is a perfectly fine
so i think
when you write code implementing
locally weighted linear regression on on
on the day said i think that cold as a whole as building your model
well actually uses
well actually use quite successfully to model the dynamics autonomous helicopter
this was the last of which is the
the what weights of the weights w i
the the
the yes so no
if you can do one thing that is quite common is on how to choose
the bandwith parameter tau
as as using the data which is all about the later we talk what model
a lot of
the see
the weights are not random variables and it's not for the purposes algorithm is not
useful to endow it with probabilistic semantics so you could choose to define things is
calcium but doesn't lead anywhere on in fact
of course it turns out that i happened to choose the bell shape function
four to define my ways is actually find which is a function that doesn't even
greater london address infinity c c weighting function so that sense
you could you could force the definition of the gaussians this or not useful
special use other functions that the integrated and it's done right
last question
one project
so should
so it is very common
because of the way to regression is on was is nonparametric our
every time a prediction you need to fit data to the entire training set to
get on so you have the right but if you have a very large training
set that this is somewhat expensive alpha continues because every time you want to make
predictions you need to fit
you know a straight line two
two huge datasets
turns out there are algorithms that are
so the way to make this much more efficient for large datasets as well as
the little pages it look at the work of andrew more on the trees
the figure out ways to fifty small is much more efficient dispersants
and then mean once the questions later on
so those the way to regression on
remember the
o liner had because at the beginning of this lecture what i want to do
now is on
talk about the probabilistic interpretation of linear regression
and in particular of the this probabilistic interpretation that says move on to on
talk about the just regression which would be a first classification
the other side of the way to regression for how we just talk about ordinary
you know unweighted linear regression
eighteen months
it's the only thing
or something
we do
read the whole
to draw right
we'll see
o general
all square
with with you know
i mean you don't really get
what i
two these
so we see that we can
we growing
then you get
i mean you
it is you
problem is
right from the start
it's a huge
these things
the distribution
so so
in this some way all one
this is
in the UK
you might be able to see what you want
the distribution
what is it
so my
the space
we define the
to see
this was
so you just
you know this is the right
the idea that
this should be addressed these
we use it
he well
we can't
well three
you know
this is one the
to actually implement this this policy
so that's why we're not saying that but obviously eventually would for him in the
improvement is pretty striking i think that's what your
pointing out from this domain so that was a fairly surprising
but it's expensive i've got some work we can try to get rid of this
time by using machine learning or not going to talk about that here
you have to read the policy or
so there's not really learning that were the hours coming from is
we're doing multiple stages of rollout
so if we do two stages the complexity the number of simulator calls goes to
hw square we do five stages this too turned into a five
that's sort of the problem here is so that's why you can't do too many
oh no no you never actually use the theoretical constance never ever so
just pick it take it empirically so
to the
i don't know if they talked about that the papers pretty
i memory
i usually pick ten
well don't know why this is not too much but
but you
so this result really there's only the one parameter
w and basically are time complexity is going to scale quite dramatically with w if
you have a lot of stages so so there's not a lot of tweaking you
you just you know
pick w star with ten
increase it if you don't like that
right so
in these games the horizon is sort of naturally
defined but usually if the game could go on forever you could just have arising
cut off and
so that's going to require domain knowledge so you sort of look at the domain
and you say roughly
i mean you can run your policy for example in c roughly how long does
it typically takes two terms and then you choose the value like that
so in the game of go it's going to be larger than in some other
it simply a
the baseline
the doing search you get you can view this as a search process to some
degree is so weird type of
trying to visualize the
space based space for these multi stage rollout is pretty hard i find but
but i usually just think of it as it's doing multiple iterations of policy iteration
that so i try to understand it be a you're you're adding search just like
if you have a basic heuristic against the baseline performance you could do minimax searcher
or just heuristic search process
we generalize
so so sort of sort of alluding to you can use machine learning to sort
get rid of this cost and try to learn
the original version of the rollout for policy rollout one hundred policy as the technique
called well there are different variants but approximate policy iteration
i've got a paper on that they basically that tries to do this so if
if you search for if you're my web page and look for a paper with
approximate policy iteration title you'll see
a qualification
one of them
and so it is in way the
you don't need to go
that's what we are looking at
i have
so so that the the API approximate policy iteration sort of
i will first learn this in only
the version that generalizes to
generate cheap oil
i mean you could you could
i suppose you can remember whatever you want it so you can define a new
algorithm that tries to remember states you've been to but the basic the basic idea
here is instead of there's no generalization and the basic rule out just
you can instead of doing policy iteration across all states are just doing it for
one state and it takes you time to do that
the set of memory
all right so as here basically trading of time memory for time writes sparse sampling
that's the only way to
see that section before so we went to see core because of so far all
the u
now we are going to see if you are
so these are the use property when we have seen query before you have a
single question to ask you if you want to ask question about the marginal because
people live
and they use this elimination
i mean will be more
i'm just giving example if you have a single query
what the joint distribution px one xn
it's all of them can be seen as
successive elimination and that's why has the name initial will not investigate how this works
so let's start with a graph of the light field because
because what because it doesn't edges
he is already
and our goal is to compute p of x y
with the following elimination on
six five four three
what is the elimination or
order of summation of my body
because here is the expression
p of x y
is the some comic book six of the joint distribution right
so the joint distribution factorizes
system is a markov random field
the joint distribution factorizes in terms of one
in terms of the maximal cliques
so we have factories here corresponding to the maximal cliques of the graph
we have one and two
correspond to this clique
one in three corresponding to this click
three and five for this clearly
two five and six
corresponding to these click
and two and four corresponding to these
is maximal cliques
by him sickly for theorem
remember the expression of the joint distribution
it is the product of
i've tried
one negative function over the maximal cliques
divided by the minimisation of course
it can all different
so yes thanks for pointing that this specific functions can be the same function but
they can be different so
technically there should be some subscription
one two one three each of these c
thanks for that
in general there can be different
and then
we just use the distributive law
right so essentially
you can
think of distributive law is just pushing this summation as far as the
which contains
the index
you can push through
x except here because since we decide on the elimination order six five four three
went to push x six first until it reaches
then this factor and then push x five into which is for that x four
x three two
remember that what we're doing is simply put in evidence
if you have a b was a AC we're seeing what
happens a here
the have a was
eight people
that's exactly what we are doing is just that we have more
we need to use the symbols
just using
OK so basically we go through this that here by using distributive law and here
we actually perform the song
we performed this song is some of the function of
over one of those five
so the results of this competition will be a functionof what
it will be a function of x two and x y because i'm summing x
so this is the function of the columns six
of x two and x one
i just called in six
because this function is obtained by marginalizing
over the body
six but this is just the x
is a function of x two and x y
now i can compute the sum here
and look that in order to compute the sum is the reason is simple
for all the values of x two five and six
so could make computation
because of table is to damaged
i have some more x five
and also more about that but assuming it doesn't learned the identity for some reason
because we put some constraint on that code then
actually does something interesting and if you use the same greedy layerwise trick just showed
to initialize a deep neural network
it works not as well as the stacks
RBN's but substantially better than training a regular deep neural network or even shallow neural
so what you do is you trying one autoencoder
then you
forget about the decoder weights here you just use the encoder weights here to find
our a new representation for the data then you can train another quarter-on-quarter
and then again once you've trained it you can forget about that that decoder part
here and you get an unsupervised transformation that's a bit more nonlinear and an abstract
and you can go with as many layers you want the end you can add
a layer that's equivalent to logistic regression and finally do this supervised fine tuning in
the same way that we've done for deep belief networks
you can even do the same
o thing in a purely supervised way so instead of training an autoencoder
you can train i one hidden layer neural network to predict
the the clusters of interest
and then throw away those weights
just use
the first hidden layer as a new representation and then train another one hidden layer
neural network
and so on and so on and in the end you get a deeper network
and you can fine-tune all the parameters with respect to the target
classes so
this actually
better than training from the beginning of a supervised neural network but it's always worse
than using unsupervised learning methods that i just mentioned
it is in
in experiments we we did
one thing that we found which
isn't something that geoff hinton likes but
is what happens
and i don't like it either
it's not enough to do this provides training and get these nice features somehow you
need to find you do those features for the task of of interest otherwise you
don't get as good performance
and this is what this graph shows we train
one of these stacks
RBN's or auto autoencoders and this is training time up here we only do unsupervised
learning and we look at the top
layer unsupervised layer as features and we use them with a logistic regression to predict
the class and so
the features get better and better and now if you continue doing unsupervised learning it
you know
it's still some improvement but it doesn't help so much if at this point now
use you decide to
fine tune in a purely supervised we all the parameters then the air drops significantly
the test error dropped significantly and ends up in a better place
and we try to understand what is going on there
o to one quarter
o to associate her
start with
because we didn't think about doing these experiments
as far as i know
are you
one that
not that i know of
i realize work
so we experimented with a variant of the autoencoder that is
working much better than the two input in fact works as well or better than
rbms for getting these deep networks and it's called the denoising autoencoder and the idea
is instead of reconstructing
trying to reconstruct the
input we can take the input we get corrupted by sending say by setting some
of these values in the input to zero
and so
the network sees
partial information about the actual input but we can ask it to reconstruct the original
so that's why it's called the denoising autoencoders trying to and do some stochastic corruption
that we're going to insert in the input
it's very similar to pseudolikelihood in the sense that we're trying to predict
we're trying to reconstruct the whole input so it's like an encoder but we're also
trying to predict the missing things that had been corrupted
it turns out that
it turns out that you can connected to it
gender model and the training criterion minimizes the variational lower bound on the generative model
so it
of the model is similar to an RBM but not quite the same
and you can also interpret what is going on is learning vector fields
that sense examples that are unlikely
two examples are more likely
so what you do is you you take it so your data lies near manifold
you take an example you corrupted
randomly that's the encoder points that i've been called that's just across option and then
the encoder and decoder together
try to map the corrupted input input back to
places where it like to see examples and so you this vector field that pushes
that points towards high
density regions
you can stack these and get pretty good results in here
we show results on
what's it's called infinite and this which is an mnist digits with
and i really large number of transport translations rotations so so we have a huge
dataset is as big as you want and
and here we see different experiments with one or three layers using denoising autoencoders or
IBM's two stack are deep architectures
and in this particular case the the best results
is online
test error
the best results are obtained with this using it one quarter with three layers
and the
rbm here
and then this is the curve you get with purely supervised training and you can
see that the slopes are different suggesting that there really going on this on the
log scale here
all right so
welcome to the last hour of monte carlo
so in the last hour the introduction is now done
and think the marrow
what people are doing these days
OK ninety five to for whatever we
we got to the twenty first century of monte carlo
so i'm going to go quickly
go quickly over here and then you talking to me afterwards
i need to go quickly because i would rather get you to know what exists
out there even if you don't understand it so is you know what is out
there there which can be delicately done
and for any part where you want the details were you know where to find
a bunch of people here in all this stuff
i haven't thought of
here it is
we need to answer the question how the clever q
and i'm going to go on and how they deal with towers question correlations
here's one way of doing this
the technical mixtures
the idea of mixtures this suppose you have to kernel t one and t two
that are both valid
and it's very easy to do that
because you take the metropolis hastings new play different cues
and because of the construction it's a valid kernel
so you can actually have an infinite number of different
kernels that are valid kernels that will have the same invariant distribution pi
the question is which one is best which one converges faster the solution because all
these things are valid asymptotically but you don't have an infinite amount of time
the the european
want to converge
here is the good news
you have won kernel to one another two
and what i do is multiply the topic question by
the bottom equation by an
and if you have the more you get this
why because of high plus one minus y is just gives you high
so you get five plus one month of fighting two
that means that if you choose
they have common factor
and if you choose then with probability alpha you choose one
with probability one minus obvious another algorithm
you still have to some invariant distribution
the great news is now you can construct is
algorithms when you have more than one heuristic and how to solve the problem
you can actually take a portfolio of them
and you start randomizing you choose between these
and then if you want to go one step further you try to control the
markov chain
with some
the maximum likelihood estimate of office you sample
so you construct adaptive change that allows you to select between these kernels
and you can do that that's actually a lot of work
in general is the gulf by
try them and see what worse than
that's true
but the important thing is you can have these mixtures which is very very
so here's an example of this is actually based on
a consulting job for the
for the french atomic energy
so they have a specific signal by affects the distribution
who is familiar with the FFT
what we're trying to get good
so sometimes you want to compute fifty of the signal
and the problem the of fifty
is it is not very good at resolving
peaks nearby
OK in the frequency domain
so they wanted something that would work better
thank you for t
we think that signal in the frequency domain we interpret it as the probability distribution
we come up with two proposal
one proposal is
we compute FFT
and the fifty just picks one peak doesn't pick the two peaks
we use the FFT
two more or less tells us
well the big peaks are
so it's a proposal distribution we computed fifty and then we put a little cussin
around the peaks of f t
we can try to make sure that some of first q
and this is a good q because this ql
makers is like an importance sampling makers jump to what is important
two of
this big stuff
the next year that we choose is a random walk
because the
you jump here
and then you to local exploration and then you jump here the local exploration then
the flow limiting a lot of details
the service profile is all about advertising and matchmaking services so it's used to characterize
so about one summary level
so that if you can think of yellow pages style of description that that's designed
you a quick look up and and identification of services most useful for a particular
need so the idea of the discrete of these profiles is that they can be
used to populate service registry such as UDDI registries which were
we've seen a lot of tension a few years ago
it should be noted that the profile can be used both for construction of the
advertisment for the request that can be used to match against those advertisments should also
be mentioned service can have many different profiles is not just one right way to
describe the services might be described in different ways
three different communities of possible users
this is an ontology bubble diagrams the simple really really ovals or classes and the
arrows are properties and this is just
basically a lot of what's in the profile
really breaks down into what is known as the functional
or capabilities descriptions on the left side and non functional descriptions it's on the right
side which is things like provenance associated with the service policies associated with the service
quality of service aspects those are probably the errors are used that are expressed most
commonly in terms of nonfunctional properties this functional properties
inputs outputs preconditions and effects are actually so recap or summary of functional description which
comes in the process model so i'll come back to that later in just a
moment or two and i talk about the process model
but you can see this is actually quite simple
so of properties in classes here this is just the basics here the core profile
but is really critical to know
if is designed for extensibility in various directions so for example there's nothing here in
the core profile
about quality of service
properties and classes but that has been provided by different groups various research teams in
various extensions of the profile
probably the most prevalent using the pro was profiles is to construct a class hierarchy
of services again for for discovery and matchmaking purposes and this is
this is the style of his own makes you takes advantage of
reasoning capabilities in most natural to and description logics OWL DL in particular so classifying
services depending on their properties and constructing a class hierarchy or you you know additional
properties as you come down to
two greater detail greater specialization
and this is this can be
tied in with existing standards which predated semantic web searches UNSPSC another such product and
service standards and some people have actually we express these these kind of standards using
similar things so i think i've already mentioned that you can have multiple profiles you
can even multiple
different kinds of hierarchies in which service profiles for the same service might be situated
for different purposes
four different classes of users
so i think i mentioned it
profile is typically used to subset of the class hierarchical yellow pages although of course
there is a great deal more expressiveness then you can go with just the bare-bones
taxonomy and as we can take advantage of the reasoning capabilities of OWL two
to do much more precise matching and what you could do with just the taxonomic
categorizations the profiles also been used for planning purposes
in which case the focus is on the functional properties inputs outputs preconditions and effects
as i said focus on a little bit more
in just a moment
so we are coming to the process models
process is really the heart of OWL s where you have all the details about
how the service works you can spell out the steps
that the service will follow his wherever workflows style of representation and
with the degree of detail and description of the preconditions and effects there's lots of
different kinds of reasoning that can be done to support automated invocation planning composition automated
enactment interoperation interoperation monitoring service progress and so forth and so on
this is zero processes of inputs outputs preconditions and effects and also a bit more
about these categories of processes the next slide
so the
this is a very minor detail
in the process model that just a high level
based on the
so i listed are very fast
and it
and a broke already
so this is peter is very important
and faraday they
made this discovery
he was asked by a news reporter
whether this would ever be of any practical use
and he answer
someday you will tax it
he had that vision
now indeed what you have seen here looked in the nineteenth century
as a very
in this and demonstration
however this simple
from normal
what i'm going to tell you know is no exaggeration
this simple phenomenon
runs our entire economy
it runs or
the common
without this phenomenon we would still live more or less like our ancestors in the
seventeenth and eighteenth century
we would have candlelight
for light
no radio no television no telephone no computer no internet
no laptop
imagine how miserable you live food
without the thing
without computer games
without video games without your ipod
why don't you admit
you spend a lot of time right before of the two
like this
for electricity is produced
electric generators
by power stations
and all they do is they move copper corals
through magnetic fields
if you want to move copper coil
you have to do work
that means
you have to put in tennessee
i put in the energy when i move in and out
but if you want to do that on a big scale
you need energy sources
to do that for you need for instance called which is very common source of
or nuclear energy they drive termites
and those turbines rotate
coral through a magnetic field
of course you can also
generating electricity
these waterfalls like the niagara falls and in some cases was wins
but it takes energy to produce
like bolts and all kinds of electric appliances consumer
and this energy consumption
is expressed
in terms of what's
named after james watt's
who did a lot of research in this area
in the eighteenth and nineteenth century
you have light bulb
at home
four mark forty w that means forty watts
you've got to
that makes a hundred what they do is more like
it means that this one if you run it for one hour
uses two-and-a-half times more energy
and this one
this is the energy
i have here
of electric generator
you can rotate
i want to find the best the point you were sort of the features in
f one and f two
and the candidates but points are really be between one and two
two and three and you would pick the one with the highest game
and in this case is if one is less than point five
using this you would split you petitioner datasets on the left to right
and you repeat the process of the tree and once again the boosting part
you can have several different gradients in this case it so
as i mentioned earlier
primary use least squares regression and for some ranking specific ones they're like be rank
so an example
this tree in this case you have you have you can see like this the
future might actually be split multiple
time break even within the same tree
so i would discuss likes the two different types of implementation so we tried
so an obvious motivations are really in larger datasets and we want to get a
speedup but one of the additional constraint that we had as well as that our
datasets that we're working on was still relatively small so
it was editorial data for ranking and the the good overall goes for maximum speed
secondly for scalability in terms of data sets size
but the first thing we did try this is
pretty early on july two thousand nine we just started in two thousand seven we
first started playing with the do and GBDT and
the will we
figure was how can we get a frame this problem into something that's exactly like
the canonical map reduce type of problem and it seemed natural that you want to
partition data set amongst this samples so
a set of machines get the set of samples taken this
the set and you can easily see how that would scale with the number of
so the the implementation we do that in the in the map or what we
had was that for each
for each map we would look through all the features their values each
and we in that a feature value as the key
and the residual and the weight of the sample as the as the value
and the reduce to aggregate this so
for every single
a unique feature value you would have aggregate of usage losing weight so in our
in our loss function of least squares loss
i mean for the squares improving this causes more metric for gain in this case
we were able to
just given the sort of lists of the feature value residual
and the weights to compute with the optimal gain was in a single pass
what we do with this is we were able to determine the gain in one
then given this you would partition the data
and there was another mapreduce jobs so given this key and the data again you
over data look for the future value for the sample and in this case you
output to DFS is well if file for left side far from right side
and you will repeat this process for the next tree or the next node
you can see is already multiple mapreduce jobs and there is actually another message
mapreduce job for computing the
the gradient so it's three mapreduce jobs in total
first look like this works pretty well so it scales as you add more machines
but if you look closely
it is actually pretty
so for a dataset with
roughly one point two million samples and five hundred features
it took about five minutes to train a single node
this was with
because hundred machines
so for a sixty three node tree would take a little bit over two hours
and they are and what we realized was was the problem of HDFS so
on the graph over here in the lower right
this was the example just copy the relatively small for a couple of megabytes amongst
one hundred machines we just copy this file almost finished with like five seconds
there's is usually one or two stragglers that took about one to two minutes
and so
if you have like three minutes per job i mean per node overhead new training
lee multiple
no poetry in this a couple of thousand these now this is very prohibitive process
so next we looked at how can we
communication cost so if writing HDFS was the problem this try to minimize so
another mapreduce implementation we tried was partitioning this time by partitioning the data amongst the
features so that
one machine gets set of features and is another that then you can see that
you can just use single pass through
characterizes the colours inside colours outside and then iterating on all of those hidden variables
i have you know you've learned a lot of things this week you might feel
something you've learned that you could do better than this is important problem and you
that would be good if you
learn something that was only are better ways of doing it
OK and then
back to that a test database again
and evaluating over the whole
database we can see what's the effect of this looser kind of interaction you simply
drag directed around so much easier than the greasy pan and what you see is
the error rate goes up a bit from one point four two two point one
percent of error but still small in these these are all still rather small areas
it's a very effective way of interacting in you saw
you so much for
how often does it work well you the kind of examples that are easy for
this for graph cut by the way an alternative that sort of intermediate difficulty is
you can draw
a curve but there's no longer has to straddle the boundaries so can always could
very quickly that's a lot easier
manipulating the greasy pencil but not quite as much work but not as easy i
mean is dragging rectangle and anyway you see in these
and these problems all you have to do is these these preliminary interactions and they
get very beautiful
answers but then hey the colours are well contrasted these examples here are some other
examples is the camouflage kind of example i will come out in greek sometimes happens
hands up the first one given a translation of this
so you drag a rectangle around this
this fish and despite the fact that its camouflage come out pretty well i think
there's a bit of coral here stuck to the fish and
so you'd like to go in and provide more information to correct that
you know here's something where it's really not going to work well because the prior
that prefers short separating boundaries is really not going to work for this
it's almost fractals
kind of boundary effects be hard to say with boundary is in fact the notion
of the boundary is not really very helpful with this segmentation problem so you know
we can probably expect not going and integrated this this is much more like that
the problem of segmenting the teddy bear where really you'd like to think of many
of the pixels as having fractional foreground membership and not the same as the foreground
probability by the way this is an actual mixing fraction between foreground and background
the actual linear mixture of light
and then finally
you know his just very complex scenes and
you know no telepathy i've said meaning that how on earth did you expect computers
no which will get you thinking of maybe one perhaps maybe one of the tracks
maybe you you could have wanted to many different things and so it's is not
going to do
completely magic four you but i don't know if i have it here
it's all the same problem now the tighter curves and it all works much better
because you provided a bit more information
another way of providing information which i guess i haven't got in the slide here
and i actually didn't get around demo yesterday although i could have done is that
you can also have some brushes so
foreground background brushes so you
do an initial segmentation is almost perfect and then you go into little brushes and
i want that it as well but you don't have to do with any precision
you just sort of
make a mark approximately on that you want really solve the
maximisation of this posterior probability
it's all can be done very fast
the whole thing is very fast anyway you saw that the fact that you've already
done it once and now you just solving a modification of the problem rather than
the whole problem benicio in fact the way of even capitalizing on that to make
the solution fast and i may get to that if i have time
OK so how are we going to solve these problems that's what i want to
talk about now the rest of the time
so generally minimizing
energy is of this form
on on the graph is NP hard although there are some interesting special cases but
you know if you if you were to accept well doesn't seem likely to be
how you can find it useful
exact algorithm then you know you start looking at approximate algorithms and has a long
history of approximate algorithms including MCMC like algorithms the first two which i guess you've
been talking about earlier in the week and some
relatively naive algorithms like well let's ignore the fact that this energy function this is
a complex non convex function and just optimized anyway by local
local gradient descent
you know we get away with that
and there are various other solutions one from under the child involves kind of taking
the approximating the problem with one that is in defined in the continuous domain that
continuous space and continuous values so it's like a variational problem rather than a combinatorial
problem then it turns out there is a need approximation to the variational problem just
involves solving a differential equation so you then you come back to the discrete domain
and solve the differential equation is finite elements of finite difference what have you
and then there's a graph cuts which is the the kind of thing i'm going
to talk about which actually was it was known about that you could solve certain
kinds of markov random field optimisations exactly with graph cuts but amazing you know the
right there is a subclass of problems here which can be solved exactly even though
they look so so complex and however
when that was done back in eighty nine it was so slow
that it was used only as a sort of laboratory benchmark for the exact algorithm
so that you know was a great insight that nobody thought of it as being
an algorithm actually using some software that we compute in reasonable time
then there is no you talked about belief propagation and if you have to talk
about belief propagation
so there is the belief propagation and that that's also
a candidate for solving this
this kind of problems so that is doing belief propagation as if the if these
functions are defined over tree
but you and i know it's not defined over tree and so you can have
cavalierly ignore the fact that it's not over retrieval do what you would have done
anyway and see what happens but it's clearly not going to be an exact algorithm
what does happen and then finally there's the modern
former graph cut which is what i'm going to talk about mostly which is just
like before except the algorithms have got so much better there really was sort of
revolution in computer science in combinatorics on how to solve these graph cut problems efficiently
computer vision discipline kind of exploited that and adapted it to work particularly well with
it is
the first thing
well my
we're all in of
all of a
the old
from north
there are
well from
one of
what this is
one where
expand this to bigger number of these
so this is a good reason because every moment you need to keep in memory
only one number
you need to keep only this figure number that you get from enemies and you
also need to keep pointing to have released
you can read this
by far
because we scanning them from the beginning to the end during this rigorous
this scanning them in one direction
and recently come numbers and getting results
it's usually pretty fast
the problem is that if you are trying to estimate the complexity of this
the complexity of this algorithm is simply multiplication of numbers
of course things in all these lists
you can understand that usually this is a huge number
another advantage this error is that if you just keeping in one of these
these keeping a lot of usually
because is stuff this is usually this bridge far
therefore like college is also called so we're looking in one these usually as keeping
a lot of numbers not a lot of species between
between the plates
but still
it's not usually so fast so this approach you can look into
many open source search engines and you can see this rigorous
how we can improve
the first
counts two of mind that
sometimes we can do is keep
if they have some pointers for
we can jump over some numbers if you don't know if you are not interested
in that
this not
this numbers
and and this is the place
the idea of people this
pretty simple
what we're going to do
we're going to know decompress parts of index
so it in
the same example imagine that going five
we can
on the second we see that
there's some point four
that's how the channel or one two three four to say
somewhere in this area
so what is possibly is
we skip skip list means that
we are in searching for something
o point in all
and using this point as we can judge or
parts of this list
what we get
this structure
we get better speed and you can do theoretical estimation
how many
o point as you need to to
to keep the speed and size of this game
you can compress still compress these these pretty well
not not maybe maybe only a small percent difference in percentage
compression ratio for this list
so you see this list of the top imagine that this is a piece of
these documents
at the beginning we have some
this situation you have number one hundred sixty five it's not not just now but
i will show you what the difference and we have a point
some way forward in this league
one point is that even if we have a fixed number of
keep so we always keep fixed number of
there is some of these is
it that we are using compression
and that means that every number
can have different number of white feet
therefore we cannot predict in advance how long you been this part of course list
and we need to point we need to
in court somewhere how many of you the
should ski
to jumper here
when the scanning through lists
risk skip b
fourteen to some memory to some temporary
this one hundred seventy five and point to this place where this one hundred thirty
five years
then we are taking numbers from this list five six eight nine seventy eight
and then we are coming to offset in the least
equal to said that wasn't
one thirty five
and in this case what we're doing
we are not put so of course is that the coordinates the
in this case we don't need to port
so we know that we need to put this previous number we put in one
hundred seventy five
and we are put into our temporary sixty six and next point
and and then accounting
four three nine thirty eight previous now and then we
come to that
next place where we have point to really got number from this place and so
it's comprehensive because except two first numbers of numbers are actually there
it's results step from previous and next note
and here we go
you can imagine it's like
two release of alpha cuts
one the are all numbers that are included another of pointers keep the numbers of
point of this skip list