so let's start
what we're going to do we are going to follow part of the
configurations from graph theoretical viewpoint
that is being prepared by my me my myself by big disadvantages and can sort
of answers
the book
five chapters
actually six
and today we're going to cover introduction
next chapter one graphs
chapter two
groups and symmetry
chapter three
surfaces and maps
chapter four incidence geometries and combinatorial configurations chapter five geometric configurations
we designed two courses
two one semester courses out of this
the first course
let's say
algebraic and topological graph theory or introduction to algebraic and topological graph theory that it
covers the first three chapters of the book
so introduction graphs and symmetry surface maps and this is what we are in
and then the next semester
if everything goes OK
the river the second course
and geometric configurations
composed of these two
chapters but we're going to talk about that
next semester so
let's focus on the first course algebraic and topological graph
as you see
delivering this course in english
and there is more
on our
he which in
the lecture on
and here is the
how to get to this
you have to register their
but more information how to do that
you will be given by alan or manage is the system for this cause
and if you have any questions please ask him and he
give you
information about the
i would like you to
for this course as soon as possible
if possible today
definitely within a week because
much much more difficult to
to follow the course if you're not registered for the course and if you do
not have access to this
web page
the web page will be protected
this means that only you
those of you who are registered
will be able to
view the contents of this page
but that doesn't mean that
you must be present here
maybe some people will register from the united states or from some other
countries and they may register but we know exactly who they are
and we welcome everybody who could register for this course
so as i said the first
we're going to do
very broad introduction to algebraic and topological graph theory
and it is possible
it's pretty much torture he's going to
basically the
the the lectures
what is new
to this type of of course is
will have as i say exercises and homework and alan alan or manage is going
to take care of that
everybody is going to do
to have to solve some problems
that will be given
and during the election period and they will appear
on the web
and you have about
one week
to solve them
and then you will
upload your solutions
to the web page
maybe the first we can be a little tricky but alan is here to help
you how to do that
but you have to have access to the
to the computer to the internet in order to do so
the other feature is that we are trying to get as many
guest lecturers as possible
so we try to get
and they will give lectures
i know one lectures already taped
so the lecture is not going to be performed here
but we just want lecture
on the screen
and then comment on it
the last features that we are going to use
very much these
lecture room
so that would be the first advanced use of e lecture this means that this
that tape
and as soon as possible
the tapes
will be available
in there
so in case you catch a cold or something like that
you may watch later lecture
on the internet
any questions
what the objective of this course
as i said earlier it's bread introduction to the subject
and we try to get some selected deep
how likely you are
so you draw new candidate text
from you put it through the dynamics
for example if the dynamics is just not regressive process then what you do is
you just say that xt
until that is sixty minus one plus some noise
in that case the text is still there
you have an expression for the model the likelihood is evaluated
normalized importance weights because we don't know the normalisation constants we had to do this
and then we do this black box resampling routines
we looked at it yesterday
i think
so let's look at an example
actually of this
so this is a very simple model
kind of illustrates this
basically have the dynamical system with the new state depends on the previous state
for some linear transformations the some nonstationarity embedded in it
and then there are some noise process which is scouts
the observations are generated
depending on the state and also according to some noise gas
now first you would think of as discussed in the last but it's not because
the posterior because of this
square would be by month
you try to convert x from y and y for all x squared up two
possible answers
what with the code look for the this
we just get the right of
all right so
that's what the code is going to look for
particle filter to to solve the problem just some parameters
i'm just going to generate the data synthetically and this is the particle falls
OK first i'm going to generate some particles
i'm going to use two names x particle spread is the extent the particle production
x part english x
and initially draw them from lagos in distribution
which has
covariance sigma chi square
and now wants
capital t the number of time samples
and so on
some just initializing these guys matlab
and then the algorithm
recursively goes like this
i can get rid of the different french they fought
so first we need to do prediction
that's that's w zero from the transition prior
and in this case i would transition prior was just
if you recall was half the previous particle that nonlinearity
but the venture for the terms that go went that way
and that these are the new particles at time t
so you start with the when the time t minus one
article lifetimes minus one and that gives dx still the antiparticle particle and that's it
and the noise that you have to it is just gas in noise which was
the noise of the model
once you do that
we moved down to
evaluate importance weights
so your computer why predictions according to the particle
and he basically just compute the likelihood which is that counts
e to the minus zero point five with covariance and this is why
x squared over twenty
and you do that for each article you compute the likelihood for each particle and
the new normalise the weights
and that's it and then
actually we only need one line of code just was trying to make sense here
so that idea
different people with use different kind of sampling resampling schemes and you can play with
them but basically what it does just calls wonder sampling schemes they receive sampling
you pass in in this is outcome the new industries
that's a black box routine you never need to change the is of course
all you need to change over to implement this thing
using matlab or unicode byte order
is you need to change the expression for the weights and you need to change
the expression for the model
it's a very simple algorithm and actually know i think that's the main reason for
actually in the interest of time
i actually slide
so does exactly that
here is the same algorithm but not in life generate and samples from the prior
but each of the samples you look at the transition model
evaluate importance weights normalized weights and result
and if you do that then you get this
you look at the distribution that evolves over time
and yes you are able to capture the multimodality
if you run a suboptimal filter like an extended focus on here what happens
the fourth chooses one of the most states with one of the most and then
it diverges
because when one of the most disappears
like if you choose this route
and this guy kind of disappears
then this guy is caught
you can get lost
i'm going to try to so that's sort of basic algorithm and
with that knowledge you can go into one of the particle filter for a lot
of these problems
now when try to like this
presented some sort of more advanced ideas
at this stage i hope you have first i would like to know
who would be able to now go home and implement the particle filter for those
equations that showed
on the board
in my copy
if you feel they can't
you know what to find ways or
and the evening in malaysia
i be very happy to help you could one by one
now more generally i'm going to discuss some more advanced ideas and i'm going to
increase the pace of election
because some people here to know this stuff before
and more
my intention i will be more to give you a taste of the things you
two graph kernels
and they are based on the idea to link graph comes
with other fields
of machine learning
the first one
by by
combines graph comes with graphical models it's
quite similar
two days
colors using saab three like patterns
and those using box but they use especially this specific factorized form for the local
economy between subtrees
user factorizations similar to
those used in graphical models to compute across com
and that's
definitely an interesting area
this combination of graph kernels and graphical models
and i i'm sure see further work in that area
and this is the second idea is to combine graph comes with group theory
you do have a new set of feature vectors for graphs
by representing a graph is the function over the symmetric group over the group of
permutations of the nodes in the graph
and then you derive invariants followed function
called discuss spectrum
this comes spectrum of features
it includes
as it of features
there are computable in cubic runtime use this these
it's invariant
as features to represent your graphs
as the feature vector so that somehow it
a graph a crude theory
inspired way of deriving
the feature vector representation
of graphs etc
also an intermediate thing between graph comes in these topological descriptors
but as mentioned twice before
so these other recent trends in
i similar to those night
before concluding i want to give you
three examples of rare people have applied these different
graph kernels one
paper from
two thousand five
rather like bowler
by the end of
uses graph comments compare chemical compounds to each other the final three newcomers
the trains
inspired by similarity measures defined in the game chemoinformatics community
based on the idea of molecular fingerprints
which which in turn
are based on counting labour costs of that's up to the
using a depth first search
from each
no in your given
graphs so basically
these accounts based on graphs
of depth up to based on powers of that
up to deep
contiki for chemoinformatics tada for applications
in chemoinformatics obviously that because they exploit this small size and low average degree of
these molecular graphs if you do a depth first search in graph that has a
really large
average degree then you might run into serious runtime problems but
as to use it on a small chemical compounds here they don't encounter
this problem
another paper that studied chemical compound classification using colors which is very interesting is that
by rail from ICDM two thousand six
the final
a new type of colour well
basins are called graph recommends these subgraphs
the maximum of l edges so that somehow the counterpart to the graph let's i
mentioned before you would call it is the actual it's
so subgraphs that contain up to l
and what they observe
is that these
fragment based comments
and outperforms
in their experimental evaluation
that use frequent subgraphs as features to compare two graphs and
comment sort of talked about here
which boxed compared to to each other
so that's really interesting findings
i think we'll see also more work in this area of
comparing these different
ideas of how to
the final graph cut using different
types of
features such as
fragments graphlets
five inside as
all walks
and they also
talk about
four interesting choices that you have to make in common design for chemical compounds with
which i want to quickly cover here
learning theory you show you consider like the class of all quantum states as a
hypothesis class news quantum information ideas again based on quantum mechanical linearity the show to
upper bound the fat shattering dimension of quantum states you know and this could have
some actual applications in
quantum state demography because this gives you another is characterizing an unknown quantum state given
a lot of independent copies of it because this is if you only care about
predicting the outcomes of most measurements then you can reduce the amount of sample data
that you need from exponential to linear
you know this was just you know
theorem that a few years ago i had to work with the student yelled actors
here end he actually implemented this quantum state you know learning process in matlab and
we tried it out on various simulated examples and you know the result of these
numerical experiments is my theorem appears to be true so
they you know indeed the sample complexity only grows linearly with the e the not with this they
number of qubits and very the constants are perfectly reasonable as well
okay one last dimension is the no cloning theorem this is the principle that says
that there is no physical procedure to copy an unknown quantum state and the reason
for that is simply that if you write out algebraically what cloning of a quantum
state would mean you find that acts quadratically in the amplitude go but that's not
allowed unitary transformations have to be linear
okay end on
so this makes quantum information hugely different from classical information you know you've heard that information wants to be free
but quantum information wants to be private and so that's okay
you know it's closely related to the uncertainty principle says you know you can simultaneously
measure about the position and the momentum of a particle to unlimited precision you know
that to imply eachother actually you know there's been some amazing applications over no-cloning theorem
to quantum information a we one is quantum key distribution so alice and bob can
do cryptography by sending photons you know sending qubits down a fiber-optic cable and if
eavesdroppers if you know tries to measure the qubits housing bubble actually be able to
detect thattheir qubits had been tampered with and therefore aboard the protocol this is already
practical you can buy devices now
that will implement quantum key distribution and how much market but you know
so so you know more speculative thing is quantum money where you would have some
qubits attached to each dollar bill let's say
you know such that you know they are
the bank the printed be bills could authenticate state as genuine by measuring the qubits
okay by someone who didn't know how the qubits were prepared would be physically unable
to copy a bill
okay because you know again because the no cloning theorem very recently with paul cristiano
we show that under some cryptographic assumptions you can even get quantum money that can
be verified by anyone not only the bank
okay and then one another thing that cristiano and i are now working on its
quantum copy protected software quantum theorem so you would get some states sorry sorry so
state about the you know but you know is not good are not gonna be
practical for a long time
stateside about what to evaluate the function f on inputs x if your choice but
that you wouldn't be able to efficiently use to learn the function f or indeed
to prepare any more states with which have to be evaluated and we actually think
that this can be done in general now
okay so i only asking my remaining few minutes is quantum mechanics relevant to biology
okay well at small enough scale you know we now know the answer is certainly
yes right that should be such a surprise because you had a small enough scale
everything is quantum mechanical
okay but there's been some really you know call recent papers saying that for example
green plant photosynthesis right the reason why it's able to be as efficient as it
is at harvesting photons you know fundamentally has to do with a coherent quantum optical
effect and people are now working on reverse engineering that's so that you know maybe
they could eventually designs solar cells that would have similar efficiencies
the european robins and various other birds have this amazing you know ability to navigate
by internal compass is okay and it's you know we over the last decade has
been discovered that you know the way that the internal compasses work is by measuring
now the problem seems to be
as i say we've got us
we've got this set k of formulas it's closer the action and the original idea
was you trying take away
so it's possible he
so that we just eliminated five
and we said there are many possibilities here we're going to choose one
but if we just choose one we end up with this problem
you know suddenly become opinion
OK so the giving up as little as possible idea seems to be a bad
leads to opinion and revision
so we're going to try and do something else
and something else is let's go to the opposite end of the spectrum
instead of just taking one of these possible sets we're going to look at all
and we'll take what's coming toward them
and that's called the formerly contraction where you just take watkins
what's in all the possible maximal
not implying subset
now it turns out if you do the same thing in the case of formerly
then you end up with the following also equally bad property
after you do this all the belief that you have in case stuff i just
the consequences of five so
so if you did have beliefs about other things that had nothing to do with
you've lost all of those beliefs now and the only thing you have an opinion
on is just stuff about five
necessarily lost too much
OK that's probably not so surprising you know the fact that if you look take
what's coming toward them again
throw away too much
OK so the compromise just to take a few of days and you have to
select the mouse and again i delayed this choice by just assuming this abstract selection
function take account can take a couple of the
max implying subset somewhere between one and the whole
and if i do that then i get exact
a function that exactly characterizes
those properties now it's fairly obvious that i could have many
such functions because you got me choices here in each different choice will give me
a different one of these functions
so there is no unique contraction function like there was an expansion there are many
so if you want to go into the detail of like trying to provide more
you know trying to make more concrete what this selection function might look like in
properties hayes
then you can start to get a reason for getting this supplementary possible
again i'll just leave it for
the benefit
OK let's just take a little bit of a look at the recovery property because
as i said before it's ten tends to be the contentious one
so the following example comes from
and since this is the following so as i said
from k minus one k minus four you get the
the opposite inclusion to the k minus five properties so when we put all that
we end up with this property which is called the recovery properties
and it says that if i is in k
then if you want to find that back you get what you started again as
i said what it's trying to capture the side dish this idea sorry of minimal
change giving up as little as possible
so this was a counterexample
i offered by hanson
so suppose the proposition m stands for george's murder
the that
you know george's law right
and g is the tax evasion so we see that if
you know george's murder the george lawbreaker in georgia tech savannah more georgia the
suppose initially that we believe that
george is both the murderer
and a
a little break
now suddenly someone tells me all the current to show the so you want to
give up the fact that you know george's so i suppose you want to give
up the fact that george is a little break
and as i say you're forced to give up the fact that george's murderer because
george bingham murderer means that he is also lawbreaker so you got give us the
fact that some
now for the more you know by the partial as we know that you know
this contraction of
OK i want to give up the fact that george's
a lawbreaker
that's more than k
so we also know that
you know that
george stopping attacks break is not
tax evaders nineteen years well
just by the fact that it wasn't mentioned in
initially so we
you also we can not
express that takes
OK now let's suppose what happens when we start adding the back you
if i try and add
so let's look at the situation where we want to
into this set
it consists consistent for me and t this set because it so we can conclude
that not to in this because it
wasn't mentioned in the first set and when i contract something it's more than what
i started
so it's only consistent for me to add to this case
so far and
the fact that joy is now tax evader into my beliefs after having removed that
the fact that he was a lawbreaker
well that
tax evasion implies is lawbreaker solo break it has to be added back to
so this is certainly going to be a set of just adding
the fact that
george was
it was a little break
but from the love you know the recovery property for and back the fact that
george was
a little break
that means i get back what i started with one i started what we did
was that george was murdered so that means i'm going to have to and also
the fact that he was murdered
so suddenly when i j
start adding back the law that you know changed my mind i'm giving up his
then i added that he was the tax evaders somebody forces me not only to
add that george was lawbreaker but also means i have to add that he was
motor recovery properties forcing them back
so i mean that with the fact that if i now want to and expand
this contract and stayed with the fact that george is a tax evader got also
believe it but the tax evaders murdering
and that seems a little bit counterintuitive so perhaps recovery properties of little bit strong
so you see a lot of people sort of argue for the forms of belief
revision don't include this recovery properties
other properties tend to be fairly sort of accepted widely accepted but this is perhaps
the property that's mostly the most contentious
OK now
let's look at all the functions
then that satisfy the AGM postulates k minus one
to k minus six so the basic policies that we have not came under and
came on
but don't satisfy
this recovery properties given that we think the recovery is a contentious properties
so these functions that satisfy k minus one to k minus four
then came under six we usually turn withdrawal functions
so i can already said this so we need a similarity function and we will
put the value the similarity value between the data points in the matrix which is
called capital s so that similarity matrix
then we need to know what the degree of vertex is
so in a graph the degree of a vertex is just
the some of the traits of the edges which are attached to the vertex which
simply shows you see some similarities of all the data points which are used to
vertex which are attached to the vertex
that's the degree of vertex
and then we will put those into the matrix which require degree matrix it's a
diagonal matrix and we just put the different degrees on the diagonal
OK then also need later is we need to measure
how large different parts of the of
of graph so we say later on for example we would assume this
guy should be closer we need to know how large the clusters
there are two different generally two different ways so you or tool
i don't think about how you would measure the size of the cluster there are
two ways could come up with so i simply can't how many vertices and the
that's what i been not by the absolute value of a
so is this is the absolute value is just five
or we can do
which is called the volume of a instead of counting the vertices we simply can't
the edges so what we do is fall that vertices which are in the subset
we sum up the weights of all edges which are capable to vertices
you know it makes it means well OK
it means that the similarity zero essential
so in the end i will i will tell letter later on how we achieve
that the similarities are so is essentially what plot here is sparse similarity matrix so
you know that certain points for example what you can do is
take it just computer calls comments on your data
but then only connect points in the similarity is higher than zero point nine
and the other one set to zero
so it's so essentially if there's no it's we really assume that there similarities zero
however which is that to
any more questions so far about the notation
OK so you need to you need intuition what this means because if you don't
know it then you will get lost from the next slide
OK one more thing which
you probably can't because it's just on the bottom of the screen
so assume that such a graph and let only one i mean clustering in the
end will be we want to give labels to data points within the cluster one
cluster two cluster five so we want to attach vertices to those data points more
less in each vertex get the
gets the label of its
corresponding cluster
and the way you can express is now is you can just write the vertices
is a vector
so if you meaning that the clustering the
index of the clustering of these data points
and we will often write so that's where in my notation often called because essentially
the function values so if we have a vector
of n data points in this setting we usually mean this vector contains entries which
but show you which cluster the data point t
the standard object
we would always use inspector accessories the graph laplacian
actually i just think
two so the graph facets matrix and
it is the so
given across can define this matrix which is called the graph laplacian
and it is simply the difference between the degree matrix in the similarity matrix
OK just taken as the definition for now we will see why why this makes
sense later on
and the most important property of this matrix is the one which i have on
the slide so everything else is so what we will do is the consequence of
and property that the properties
if you take some vector in rn
and you
multiplied from the left and right to your matrix
what you get
this expression you see down here
it is essentially
the sum over all data points
so all pairs of data points the sum runs over i and j
so for all pairs of data points is some the similarity times the difference of
the function square
it's a
what's the question
you may varied over this this should be here
that's the type i then when so forget about this
so maybe write definitions again that was it so the
this the matrix
which contains the degrees
on the diagonal otherwise zero
this is just the similarity matrix which contains entries of similarity functions
OK i again the degree to which you have from this matrix d i
is some more
our kernels may the main kernel equality so we went product to be such that
the kernel represents taking the dot product in that space
because the at the end we can get away without mapping into that space we
can just formulate everything in terms of dot products and computer products in terms of
so we want to come to represent the dot product in that space and by
definition of ahmed that means the kernel has to have this so called reproducing property
all the dot product together with the kernel has had this problem this property so
we'll have to be constructed dot products such that it satisfies the quality here
and there's only one way to do it and we have to define that the
dot product takes this value here for
two such elements but that space contains also other functions because we're just taking the
linear completion so we also have to have to say what's the value of the
dot product if we take linear combinations of such kind of functions
and since the products have to be by linear functions there's only one way of
doing it we have to do the linear extension of this definition and that's that
this equation here so you just imagine substituting linear combinations back here
we already know
the individual kernels the product gives us something like this and sums in the coefficients
we have to move out to make sure that this becomes by linear
so then this becomes our definition for the dot product
and then we we prove that this is the product in the proof was kind
of nice because it was proceeding by first consul showing that it's a positive definite
kernel and then we use the properties of the positive definite kernels to show that
this is strictly positive definite by linear form
in other words a dot product
so now we have a way of thinking about our feature space of feature space
contains functions that look like the kernel function together with a special kind of the
product and maybe i'm sure i would say a little bit more about this today
during the lecture to give you a bit more of an idea
what's going on
now we've seen we can in no way
yes if we map each point two
so we said the kernel represents similarity measure we now map points to the kernel
since centered on that point so that's all representation of some of the feature space
so we can also think of this as a representation of data which is more
convenient all representation in which we will construct i wouldn't know if this nothing takes
the point that into the kernel function it actually means we represent each data point
by its similarity to all other possible points because the kernel function is not this
thing here is nothing else but a function which given some other point tells us
how similar it is to x so we x is represented by its similarities to
all possible points
and then with a suitable product
so that's one way to think about it and some of also makes it plausible
that one can do
some kind of empirical approximation of this if one wants to
by robert rather than representing each point by similarity to all other points we might
want to represent it's just by its similarity to a sample of points but sometimes
and so
again map point to the kernel function but not this and we restrict the kernel
function to a set of points
evaluation points so that's like
so then the point is mapped o input point is not actually to effect because
the function evaluated at a finite set of points is the vector of this is
all vector here
and we can not think about well if if the original kernel such that
the kernel trick holds true for original mapping phi
so we we can't compute the dot product after taking the mapping phi how about
if we take the mapping phi and then just use the standard m dimensional dot
product we get the same or we get something different
so it turns out we get something slightly different but we can make it the
and we can make the same exactly if we substitute
the kernel matrix to the power of one minus one over two
in here
it's some kind of whitening procedure
and i'm not going to go
please infer the algebra but basically if you if you look at this thing here
and i imagine taking the product of this with itself
then you can imagine you've function twice and the then the dot product matrix of
this thing itself actually ends up being case square
and to make sure that we get k which is what we wanted to we
have to put in this whitening procedure so that sometimes convenient if we want to
kernelize migrants so we have some grim you want to do it in the feature
space but somehow find to complicated you don't manage to write it terms of the
product then you can do something like this which effectively means you are doing things
in accordance you are choosing some basis of a subspace of your feature space that
you're interested in the subspace spanned by the kernel functions centered on those points x
one through x and then you can work on a subspace so if you don't
like infinite dimensional space that something sometimes
so before i move on to a kernel i agree that i just want to
say a few more things about kernels that are nice library for
constructing similarity measures because they have certain closure properties you can multiply kernels by nonnegative
numbers you can and then you can take the product of kernels that
without telling you that that distribution
but just to me
but if i ten years some p
then by optimizing the beta
i can recover q
they can recover distribution where everything came from
and this is not problem
it's convex
it has a unique solution
well as i said the suffixes is q of pixel appear fix
just achieves the minimum value
there's really nicely behaved
now here's the catch
this is all in terms of expectation
and obviously we don't have access the distribution but we just have an empirical average
so what would you do in this case
what you suggest
but as a suggestion
come one
i cannot compute expectation but i have some data
what would i do
i just
take empirical averages over my father and try solving the same problem
so i just
take some average
over the training data reweighted
and the average over the test starter unweighted
now somehow will try to make that distance small
and ensure that
well the ratings prob
that's the problem
exactly what i had in the previous slide
so here i've replaced
average body parker mean
same here
and i only need to estimate m of those coefficients beta i
and for convenience of also
required that those beta is bounded by some
upper bound b
then you just have to be optimized away
so at the moment this looks like a hack
like why should this work at all
as it turns out you can actually prove that this is
the this gives you a consistent estimator
but if what you care about is algorithms or you do now is you can
not fall asleep and just remember that problem you feed into QP solver
and you'll get some weights use them
used for his support vector machine and you'll get very good results
actually what we can show is and i'm going to stay in the theory is
that this reweighted set of observations will behave like one which is drawn from the
correct distribution but you pay a little bit
if a basically by m over the squared norm of those coefficients
so they
effective sample size will be a little bit smaller
not too bad
of course you pay
and then
you have a little bit of bias in it
and that's just like how well you will manage to approximate
this from here
if that term is zero then the box disappears
but that might cost you rather deal in the beat
now you actually well actually want to be close to n because you want your
writing to be such that it corresponds to a proper probability distribution again
actually what you would really like to have is that
in minus the sum is less equal in uppsala
we're going to be a bit sloppy interested in this epsilon to sierra because it
doesn't really matter very much
and all the theory goes through regardless
and the other thing is
imposing this constraint
actually led to make a very nice connection to single class SVM
that's not published yet
so you have to
well stay put until this goes online time
but the nice thing is this is just the standard quadratic problem
you can use we could tweak to chance code a little bit
and you could just happily it
how do we prove such results
basically what you do is you argue that for smooth functions with the loss doesn't
change much applications
the empirical
the two losses are reasonably close if i just take care of my min operators
the new show that the empirical loss is close to the expected loss
so basically have to work
for the approximation term
we trust try to map different distributions and then you have to worry about the
fact that well
actually don't have
the right expectation but you just have an empirical observation of the labels
so the first statement essentially is concerned with the x depend in part
and that's like the the y dependence part we condition on x
but the tools are very standard
let's have a look at some actual but i mean that that's the reason why
does it
so this is actually from a paper by shimodaira
and the blue surface in the right ones are
the dot is drawn from
the solent blue line
one would assume that the blue dots
are what is drawn from the training data
and the red dots are the ones drawn from the test
sorry the other way around
that's the training data
and that's it is
and then
the idea is well you would like to find some linear model which fits the
started fairly well
so if you don't do any rewriting
this is pretty much what you're gonna get it
if you
well the proper
importance sampling
that's what you're looking
well this is what you will get if you use shimodaira method which does the
importance sampling then if you act on top of that
this is what you get
if you use
re weighting method that just six days before
and that would be the optimal answer
you can see that actually works fairly well
and if you look at the very
what is this thing doing
so this is what you get three importance sampling
this is get this is what you get to the moment matching we what explain
that's what she our method with two
so these are all
this mysterious
and this is of course what you do if you just do it if you
train and test it
the variance is lower
and the mean is also considerably lower
i mean but obviously that's just toy example
let's look at some real data
that's on
the breast cancer dataset and well unfortunately it's really hard to find such five starters
it's where you can
effective taste
so we constructed in
and the what we did is basically took
dataset which was all the same
and the bias our training set
he wanted to do we can therefore the classifier because it's just so equal just
had about seven events for
failures and thousands of thousands
normal operation we can let's build a model of you know all
and then detect hopefully any divergence from norm normality
there's actually two things ways to approach the problem is the same as in there
one approach is to model was called the support of the distribution
which is actually what i do here
and the idea is you something i want to know where the data is located
OK then have boundary around and outside the country is assumed to be novel
the alternative which is suggested here which is also
two triumph it's some sort of a mixture of gaussians or some sort of distribution
function of your data
and do it that way OK
so that's alternative which might do
here i'm just going to do the support of the distribution
and as say the more subject and giving him
so if just wanted to model support of the distribution then this is a binary
valued function which is positive in the region beams put space weather data lies and
negative elsewhere
you can do this using linear programming and the method i give is with christine
better just to illustrate the idea but i think about this book it tends to
do his own quadratic programming type things subjective is defined as a surface in input
space which wraps around the data
and as i say anything outside is abnormal
what you do is use a gaussian kernel
the reason for the choice get kind
comes about from just have a quick look at
i introduced last lecture six months ex-prime square
o two sigma square led to actually quite ex-prime words just considering the point itself
and what i see
is that this is going to be easier to just one OK
now with the gas kernel therefore
all the data points must lie
on a hypersphere
of unit radius in feature space for this reason OK
and indeed there full-time using a gas kernel
my domain data
lies like this in in this feature space
now the idea that get a give you now christine invent is that we saw
a hyperplane in the feature space on the data
OK provided the data points became negative then i just stopped it on the data
doing that is a simple
linear programming talk problem case alpha here
you can do it using quadratic programming as well
OK again we're seeing this linear programming quadratic programming choice
so that's the objective function subject to constraints these with the constraints and you can
also do using soft margins and the bias and
you got various choices just given the basic idea is to cleanse the data and
and it's not the the best way of running but it's boundary around the data
OK and so something like here
will be viewed as normal
whereas here would be viewed as normal
OK so it's just means of estimating the support we can elaborate it uses soft
these guys here i really like the boundary
so i can use the soft margin variant
and drop them out OK
after all
if i got data which i i said just now my unable detect tries to
get a function which covers the data
and then detect abnormal events unfortunately in my trace and they also have normal events
OK there outliers have to account for the possibility so that's why you can do
this all this with the soft margin with not modify kernel is my data
it was an nature only data like so
you'll notice some data points set right on the edge that doesn't look too good
you can do a variant on its way you introduce virtual data or various other
variants which pushes the boundary as you wish OK so you have various on the
same story but it's sort of greasy c
it's actually
estimating the support of the distribution and
i have here very special
violin string or yarn or string whatever you want to call this
and we can generate
these resonance frequencies by
searching for them and i would need assistance from
student which you be willing to help me
so your hand and one
hold one end of the
piano string in your hand
don't let it go please don't let go
i promise you i will let it go either
OK so i put a certain tension on it
and i started to shake at very low frequencies
the columns
and look are happy this string is nothing
just last me ignores me
it doesn't like me
now i going increase the frequency
hitting the first coming up
and is
that's exactly the shape that you see on the blackboard
very clear
shake it here
have exactly the resonance
f one
let me know try to
it's the
second harmonic
if i got a little over the
f one then
nothing much happens
apart from e to c is this
this is the second one was already the third
so very difficult
the this year i can get the second
i think i got it now
OK so you see the second harmonic
he needed no that point standing still
the amplitude is you know
that's the characteristic for
resonance frequency we call it also normal mode frequency or natural frequencies all the same
let me know try to generate one that is very high as high as i
possibly can
you tell me which
monarch it is
all you have to do is count how many nodes there are not counting my
hand on his hand
you add one
and that is the
monica that generates
the system is not too happy to you feel it sort of when it comes
i see no i'm of residents
very hard for me to add resonance but i will get it
comes the first question
residents now look it
william resonance
so how many to come
six harmonic
twelve to me but OK you can better than i can
OK thank you very much so you see here
our was system response
two driver
and complicated system like this
has many many
of these resonance frequencies
which we call the normal modes
so when you have a
four strings
they all have the same like their musical instruments like the piano by links is
finally for strings all the same length
you can
set b
tensions so you have something to play with
tension is change normally when you tony instrument before you start playing
but these four strings all have different mass
that gives them a very different frequencies
now to played the violin you cannot change the tension of course during the play
that would be a little difficult although the instruments exist
we're actually
the playing depends on the tension of the strings
the violin that's not the case with violin
the only option value playing it
is to make the
string length shorter
you do that by moving you finger along the string
by making it shorter
the frequency goes up and by making it longer
the frequency
goes down
now how do you excite
musical instrument like a piano string or violin string
there's nothing that is driving it exactly at the resonance frequencies if you want to
get to four hundred forty
words out of the violin string
then you know not driving it exactly the four hundred forty it's like we are
well that's true
but if you take a bow
and you registering with the ball
that in a way which you're doing is you're exposing that string
to a lot of possible frequencies not just one
it is a running action
i could also robert was my finger i could market what i could kick it
and what does it
it ignores all the frequencies which are not resonance but it picks out the ones
which i addressed
so striking it was the bow is effectively exposing it to to a whole art
spectrum of frequencies and it picks out the ones that likes
in fact if you strike a violin string with the ball
you may excited simultaneously in the first harmonic and in the second even in the
third harmonic or even higher harmonics
and that makes
the difference between the various in some that gives special
don't quality
depends upon the cocktail the combination
of the various
harmonix that you excite
now if you go to a woodwind instruments
the situation
quite different
i have here
some cavity
it has length l
and there's an inside you
and i want to see whether this
system has resonance frequencies
so i put it here on the loudspeaker
generate sound different frequencies and search for residences
and there are
the residences of this system however a different from this string in that sense it's
not the box that will resonate here
this is the area itself starts to resonate area x like which way
in fact in that sense it is very parallel to or spring system
it is also a longitudinal
oscillation was that is the transverse oscillations so you make pressure waves inside
and if you do that the right frequency
air acts like a spring and then you get
strong reactions which i
the residences
in this case
and smote
and harmonic
is given by
times the velocity of sound
divided by two l
and v
it's about three hundred forty meters per second
the temperature
so it sounds
nor is it again the inherent
in other words if an instrument
but uses a certain
let's say that l
because twenty five centimetres
OK i'm going to explain think being and a this strategy so we include like
a huge number of people
let me show you how we do
the general idea has been proposed by leslie in two thousand twelve
other questions
the general idea has been proposed by christina leslie the two
and the idea is that we consider
OK now OK could be like for something i i mean some or some small
number of nucleotides or amino acids which are like in sequence
so like next to each other
we consider came in and for every possible came which is a bit size to
the power of k
for every possible came out we have one feature
so it essentially created feature that every example every second week we record came appears
the sequence
this is what is defined here to the indicate spectral
at the time this one
this is defined as either one when the
heyman s
it's appearing in the sequence x
what's your what's actually actually counting all the sequence x appearing in the
and we have no effect on where the sprawl this information called him
the dimensionality of x the exponential in k to be about the they are thing
the spectrum kernel to be discovered product of these two features
so this might be very inefficient but there are actually ways of people eating the
so and maybe just to give you an example
the second point is to the protein sequence if you put a b
and now you look at all
what when you looking at one man
just let
you can identify all the
one man all the letters PN sequences quite efficient
you don't need to compute exponential exponentially dimensional feature vectors and the kind of product
you just need to see which led us to here and here and here
the l p c
the same kind of the tumor with three minutes
and you know this and the number of they appear then you can compute this
kind of product without really
computing the kind of the city
without computing the to the text
it is important
i choose which
OK premiered a new rituals
typically depending on the alphabet so like in nucleotide you're looking at six million eighty
six proteins usually but left the
but you really i twenty two the par five already item
so but
so you have choose to this k just by
what you can do you can already look at
a different case at the same time
it's actually a good idea so you look at one man who may be on
you have to that if you usually one
at that point no i
are better than others
OK so it may be the best thing that could be just period any position
so it's not important that they appear
come to kernel which are position dependent
but for now i just want to do
can you know when you have several kernels you take the sum of kernels
it's just going to nuclear
if you you think of what what it means in feature space you have to
search maybe one can we take this kind of product in one subspace
and now you adding to kernel means essentially that you take the two pictures basis
and augment the i mean concatenated each other
OK because then it kind of a product
taken independently of each other
i mean this kind of product
so that's
considering one man to man be this independently and then
OK so important part of this
i have x only had very few
non zero element
only those payments which appear in sequence
they will be non-zero
and this allows very efficient computation what about the later
i think one
so the fact that this is an example of
so called substring
and idea is that the count common substrings in two strings
and i think that are deemed to be more similar than they have more up
walk on that subject
so now there are variations and this one will allow
and then in the card
allow mismatches and only to look at the motives of what you have wait
i'm only going to get old
OK so let me explain the so-called gettering so
the idea is that if we
look at this spectral sequences which are
like its sequence select and then we look at all different letter combinations which are
in the middle so points all too many which are
for all combinations two letters which are within the man
so there was no need to be next to each
the problem is designed in such a way that
it can be a scan can just go find or
sit there just keep eating one
is the inexhaustible supply one
or you can do much more challenging thing you can go to war
pick it up
the men were not needed
because hungry
what all the fish
you get one fish it now has one
it has to go back to the war
the couple are remember
much more challenging to learn to fish
that just need to work
so what is the fitness level is just witness increments by one for each fish
and points for for each
for each data sets case
i just define an arbitrary notion of of
OK so now what do i basically defined
his experience some experimental results
the x axis
possible lifetimes of an agent
so each point on the x axis is a completely different age
here the list for ten thousand time steps here is in the list eleven thousand
time steps here is a journalist for told that so what changes is the lifetime
of the nation
and basically searching
o were
internal reward functions
which are functions of internal states
what features of internal states the amount of hungary let's remember something it is hungry
or is it
not hungry for eating fish
or its medium revisiting the war
the internal reward function can decide how much reward
internal rewards ascribed to each of these two situations
and searching the what three-dimensional reward function space
so for each agent i search for the best reward function
internal reward and ask how much to that agent actually
the red line
it is the
thickness of paint by the best internal reward
and the blue line is the thickness obtained by the best by the
confounded reward where the fitness function is used in war
no search just little is the fitness
so the first thing to observe is that it does not surprisingly because the fitness
award is is in the search space of internal rewards they don't reward always better
you can see the difference between the lifetime of twenty five thousand because the difference
three as much more much more late so
let's keep going here somebody noticed this is about the life about twenty five thousand
steps is a lifetime
beyond which
it and this is going to live longer than that it can learn to fish
and exploit that explains the biggest slow
it was lifetimes shorter than that
the best thing you can do is just eight one
never just
not bothered about eating fish
it would get confounded reward it takes much longer
to learn to eat fish the media is about forty
OK let's keep punishment state many many things about this so let's
if i can go on
so the phi let's just do this this
so the point is the best internal reward can help
because mitigation value y mitigation a few minutes and then there's much
for horizon for a lifetime that short enough that you can't learn to eat fish
we can't learn to eat fish so
you know that don't know what to better
it is but i much
this is mid-life it's really interesting because of course the best internal reward is much
better teaching to fish short enough
it is long enough live long enough that both
and efficiency of the
the best internal reward agent can get get there much faster
so now here again different view in which we're looking at the proportion of fitness
that comes from eating
in the war
and again this is saying what i said before the for lifetime of twenty five
thousand it's all this comes from from eating not
one thing to keep in in mind is the learning curve for each agent is
completely separate
bayes classifier is this without the data
so the bayes classifier is
minimize expected loss under the true distribution of the labels given the input assuming you
knew everything about the world
so the bayes classifier is the best possible classifier that you could possibly do if
you knew everything
so it's sort of theoretical objects that people compared to analysis
it has no practical application because you can never know everything
bayesian inference
doesn't assume you know the truth there is uncertainty and conditions from the data set
and this this is the predictive distribution given the data rather than given knowing everything
OK that was on the site
this is what we're trying to do
we need to now know how and how we come up with this distribution how
do we predict new labels given a new input given the data set
and if you've done lots of manipulations probabilities you would write down immediately the surface
integral if you have and then maybe after tomorrow you will
this probability is just equal to the integral the idea is
it's the average of the predictions we make for each possible weight vector
average by
their posterior plausibility
you make predictions using whole bunch of different weight vectors
and you wait those predictions by how probable work those parameters are
OK so
here's a picture that
might make this a bit more concrete the logistic regressions so we have a classifier
in weight space
so there were two products for the class of the classifier
there is some history distribution is the probability distribution list in that space the parameters
of the distribution and we came up with after seeing the data
metal has the maximum somewhere
now one thing we could do is we could maximize
that probability of way
that would give a single weight vector that we could use the prediction
so we could do that
that might look like a regularizer fit that we did before
we would come up with a particular class they the decision boundary and is dotted
line shows some sort of confidence interval that's where
b and they started lines are actually pretty certain what the classes
but of course we don't know
what the weight vector is
we've seen only a limited amount of data and that's not enough to pin down
what the true underlying decision boundary is
what we should do is what was on the slide we average over possible decision
boundaries may be the decision boundary points out like this
maybe point over like this we're not really sure
and if you average the predictions under all of those possibilities you end up with
this decision
the decision boundary is in a similar place
now when you draw
contour showing sort of where that region is beyond which you certain
they can because
it's averaging a whole bunch of lines
like that you end up with kit kat decisions
so the result of this is
near where you've seen data end up
pretty certain
these confidence bands are quite married
but it turns out that because the plane can vary a lot more out here
we have a decision boundary that
and very like this
you end up very uncertain away from the data
so now
i'm reading the check
i see some really weekly handwriting that sort of not really like anything that i
saw my training set
maybe the model notices that that input in x the representation of this wiki handwriting
isn't near anything else
and so
although i think that this might be in nine actually have no idea and i
should make a decision so this formalism gives you a natural way of dealing with
uncertainty and it uses the fact that you don't know these parameters to tell you
that you are not certain predictions you can make either
once you come up with this
the formalism you can then sort of look back in
my college connections with things that we've already seen
so a
that has to use this one is too
i tell you that this is a sensible thing to do and the other is
that it can tell you how you might do better and make better method
say same
i apologize for people on videolectures
companies like terms
we're solving
this problem we optimizing liveliness integral here
over the way
we don't know what the correct parameter vector so averaging
under the posterior distribution over the parameters
and that can be hard to do so may be something we could do is
well that maximizes thing
let's find the most probable way
that was one in the centre of the posterior that gave reasonable decision boundary
and just use that so if the averaging predictions of distribution will find the best
way and then predict using just the best
setting of the parameters
now if we do that
what we end up doing is we maximize the posterior distribution of the weights given
data and so we really maximize the log probability of the weights because again
probabilities get very small
a variety of reasons dealing with log probabilities numerically is a lot better
so the log probability of the way
it turns out to be
the log likelihood log probability of the data given the way
plus the logprior plus constant that you often do they need to work out
so now we have a log likelihood and the time
and so noise
four between those two options we have two which is somewhere between these things and
i guess that makes the science of engineering but you you have an expressive enough
b not too expensive to to to allow you to prove optimal inference
two of them in my area
people come up with a good models
but no runs
numerical optimisation
now some numerical optimisation problems to more in the most for the local minima
but i wanted to happen we want something it doesn't
probably doesn't fall into my comment
but that's what i mean by exact inference
obviously its relative to how much change
on the approximation
and that's what i call inside come inside of
getting the best of both worlds
so the graph matching
we show that the problem is equivalent to another problem which should not in be
this actually shows the front of the guys that it is it
they completely missus its exponential
thank you for coming to the point
we want to use graphical models to try and make it more tractable
well i think you know i'm talking about its
you same many examples i tried to give you earlier
you have the template trying to find the complex scenes
was the pattern
the problem is to find an optimal match
now words we're trying to find this
this matching function
that will
points in the main point in the range
and as
we are
typically in this talk today focusing particularly all measures pairwise
although we out out extensions to set particularly because we're interested in certain types of
geometric invariant matching
we have
higher order points like cost ratios points things this of course the whole points missus
four points and of course it's complexity
well first
good thing
about playing geometrically with graphs graphs embedded in some way
a metric space
that you can reduce
the matrix representations
of the data if you like
he calls
if we couldn't would have many more satellites in the sky wouldn't
and to the national try the notion of triangulations
is it enables us to have satellite communication
without having the full satellites
guys satellites because we know
if you have for example in the plane
if we have just the distance around here the distance around here
the sorry the distance from this point is uniquely defined by its distance from these
reports for all very point in the distance
to uniquely localized more
so that means that we move to encode
distance from every other point in the game
i can triangular kind of
so that we can increase the sparsity
the because it can make the graph much more sparse
so for example
here's is a graph on one two three four five six seven eight points
r men desert and this really is to one
one is that it has connections to fully to fully now everything
so this is very important very important result
we really only need
on the plane
triangular reference if you like to define everything
so we use is built on that
this in the sense that embeddable in image
metric space with distance metric many years is that
in the interest in the individual
when you get to be attributed graph matching and hidden markov random field stuff
not so much jigsaw accepted to pre-empt we're going to have to make a graph
is chordal
and you're right i
invited to be done to ensure
and that's all we don't
in the context of the points that i have
p so far
so it is not just by itself but in the context of the points i
have big so far
this in importance measured is characterised like like every sample distribution is characterized by by
the centre and with
and and so let's let's look into what that means
so again
the the little white one-dimensional problem that we have this is the function that we're
trying to integrate this is the
a PS space where we are drawing point four and so picture this sampling distribution
that a
most of the points here have
see already low importance and of course
star which is the
the single point
that that will minimize risk in the context of finding the best single tree of
the best single that that's what appears to be will mean
and so this template is usually centre around p star
and in this case we have a broad distribution so this is OK you you
are allowed to pick
poems from everywhere but mostly but if you pick points from the center those are
more important to get a good approximation to this function
and so if our sampling distribution is narrow like this narrow centred around the star
which is the best single
then you have
what is going on in sample of
many a strong base learners then we do you have an error
close to that of the best
on the other hand
if we have a wide distribution what like this we're going to have a diverse
and symbols the predictions are not highly correlated with each other
so here
in the narrow distribution case again they the friend that if talking about recent different
trees which gene similar highly correlated predictions so when to take that combination and you
know don't necessarily get an unexceptional improvement
on the other hand if we have a very simple with many weak
so again means the risk of of that particular
it's much higher than than the release of the single optimum one then we have
good performance and this is this is the
so there
the empirical
observe trade-off between this trend
all the
individual base learners and the correlation some of them can be understood here in the
context of their with of the sampling distribution
of course they optimally
the optimal sampling distribution depends on the unknown target functions so so far is a
little bit of theoretical thing
right so we can not really
get like analytical form from the sampling distribution but but what we're going to do
is to come up with on are packed
which is an artistic approximation to the process of sampling from that
the importance distribution
they do is take is based on a technique that is called perturbation samples which
is unknown three using monte carlo integration to simulate the process of growing from from
now on
they down on sampling distribution and what it is is so we're gonna
so let's see how perturbations sampling goes in the in the algorithm so remember we
we're going to build a simple in enough for what stagewise manner adding one symbol
at a time to the
problem right
this expression here if for a moment you ignore there were perturbed
it's your saying give me the best tree
one of the best known their work at this time right
so that that is
just with this expression is aimed at minimizing the expected loss which is the risk
of the
now so perturbation sample says
simulate the process of growing this point from the sampling distribution by perturbing an aspect
of the problem
and so in the context of an symbols perturb is a random modification so all
let's see what what can we perturb in in our situation we can perturb the
distribution here
so again whenever we drop point we can
somehow alter the data distribution for instance by re weighting the observations and that happens
to be what enables us
we can
mess around with the loss function
we can perturb the loss function and for instance by modifying doing something to eat
argument either randomly or deterministically
and so we can see that that as much as we for what goes on
in gradient boosting later does
and we'll talk about that
later on in the week
so one thing we could use for example is could look at a very very
simple cubic polynomial
our function x
is just a polynomial expansions
of of our
a lot of time
so now we have four parameters
to think about and more generally speaking we could use the case or the
results as far as least squares are concerned still hold
for the simple polynomial expansions matrixx
still of course consist of a column of ones and then each other column will
correspond to the
the polynomial ten that we've used up too
whatever case order
so no
our data matrix
the design matrix will be an n by t plus one dimensional matrix work is
obviously the
or death
all of the polynomial that we're using
so that means that the least squares
machinery still holds
well now
w hat
rather than being in the simple case to by one is not going to be
a t plus one
column vector
so i well let let's
let's look at
very highly nonlinear model of order k equals nine
and here is what we get
now it's
this model
nine sort of polynomials
but still captures the ongoing trend but also seems to capture these oscillations
the question is
is this a better model and not
the linear model
would you be prepared to go to the
the book is the diffusion the keys that's not european
i put some money on any predictions this ninth order polynomial
model would use
is this a better model
so much shaking their heads on what basis the
make that judgement
what we're going to do is we're not going to
but i'm going to do well potentially finish
ten fifty three OK so we could planet thing
to answer that question we need to look at the whole notion of generalizations
and i have one lecture
looking at how the
the loss function can be decomposed into bias and sort of residual
eight of terror
but what i'm not going to do is move on
and what time
this whole problem of creating models like this
from october probabilistic basis
so this has been rather
well one could argue it's been rather arbitrary
that we have used
OK so
we we started off
and we should we can identify a linear model
using this squared error loss empirical squared error loss
but that so that we can really do it because we cannot really judge
how good the model as a whole confident should be in the estimates that we've
what we're not going to do
is look at this problem of modelling
linear linear models
within a probabilistic framework
and you've all been exposed to that and the number of times that were raised
when you were asked if he knew about hidden markov models suggest that probabilistic view
is something which a lot of you are familiar with
so we're going to
look specifically the likelihood principle
and maximizing the likelihood
as a method of parameter estimation
but we also obtain by employing this
probabilistic perspective is we know
can i say this
the levels of certainty of confidence that we can place and our estimates and in
our subsequent productions
there's no moves is much more forward anyway that allows us to rationally consider the
validity of our models and the
the validity of the predictions that our model will make
so basically what we've done is we have
define the very simple model
potentially some linear some non linear function
over attributes
some set of parameters associated with this function
which maps two are are actual target values
and there's also some
and of ten and associated with this
some noise ten
the model is based on a deterministic function
all that outputs
so about
and that deterministic function
it is then
contaminated in some way
you can view this
the shapes
the problem is that large point clouds
we would like somehow how
to compare
so something much more compact
so the main problem i give you points and the point i want to know
just to point
how much overlap there
i don't want to look at all the point
OK take it on the sample well if you just take random samples from the
the blue you might not be consistently
i think it's hard to be consistently point from that the blue set
and this is a you like
call me actually
introduced by bruno
document similarity
which is to say we invoke especially around the next round of expertise nothing but
one of the
or you take up space in the blocks
he began to occasionally brought space
and you simply according to your preference for each
o point for that point according
the ordering of this voxels
so maybe this experts
fair the self
it yourself
the best and there's nothing there and fairness
the ones that it's not in their preferred to select how that point there fifty
seven that blue point and so on
so here is the best point according to the best
o point according to the fact that
he is best report according to sex
what about
and expert different underpin
the notion of voxels
and for the fact
the law
you know
this point here
he is best
before the blue
yes according to
how many of the random experts
the first choice
the same or not
part is the same or not
and it turns out
you it
estimate of how many of you have said
at the close by back
the ocean
so the line here is can
broken up into shingles
the computer signatures for signals
from that moment on compact descriptor and then
this idea
we were really very very compact we used a hundred random experts was selected the
descriptors of favourite actions in that sense they are missing
and here is some
so the results using based on comparing partial scans of his
using geometry
on the black
and this a fingerprint
on the right
this comparing large point clouds comparing
you know
a few sites k it's very close enough
the same but quite close
in one can use is also find a market features got together
aligning multiple times without ever going to get decide for example a discount
four the holes just by looking at this
and again
standard databases
clustering of shapes and so on
or based on this
they compact disc
so to wrap this up
he was that
decided not to look for
so the human significant features of shape
but let's think of the children at random
because if two shapes overlap enough
the probability of finding some randomly chosen feature that appears in what that is high
in the future
it's a very simple method the parameters you have
for the last
my last
i think that
the bottoms
this game
not so much for but actually
and the structure of the human themselves that is said to be
there are we
if if have windows so much
but if you you look at the task involved in this election
therefore the above
so for first of the building
like for me to be good
the question is can we detect the structure without knowing
what the problem is
well what the elements
and you
the but quickly and algorithm based on the stages again this is an will show
the aggregation state
so if stages we take the input
we analyse the contrast show you how
then based on that we estimate what be the bottom and then we go back
in time that
the human
like before start going on in the spatial domain
it's going on in the main body
close couple
in this work we discover
he said structure based on
the community guided subgroup consisting of
rotations translations scaling
show here is actually the only possible
that you see here
then the function value
is always less than the
the same linear combination applied to the function values of x y so the core
defined by these two points on the graph of the function
is above the graph of the
and that has to be true for all points x y in the
all possible points x and y
is actually another condition that sometimes important of the domain of the function of the
meaning it's defines the
a set of values of x for which is defined as a convex set and
if you pick two points on the domain then it satisfies
and concave means minors
so these are some simple examples of one variable we have a linear or affine
function exponential
is convex
powers are convex if for positive x if all size greater than one negative
for example one over x is convex for positive
or power of an absolute value
convex on all of are if he is greater than one
negative entropy is convex
the logarithm is concave
then i will also look at function
functions of obviously and functions of made
again any find function is convex
you can see from the definition
and general expression for the function of the fact that this
four matrix we use this station x is an m by n matrix
then the trace of the product it's politics
b is the channel
the station of anaphora
basically it is a complicated or compact notation
the just in the product of the next face if you look at the face
of it will take
then it just some of the products AIJ XIT overall change it's like taking the
inner product of factors over all the elements of
and we write it like this phase of a perfect because that's all
more compact but it basically means the same thing as the inner product of those
nor is always convex
i mean if if you know this is context on this property
and that's also true for matrix norms obviously so for example if you take the
maximum singular value norm of a matrix
then because norms always convex you know this is convex
although from this mission for example it's not obvious that the square root of the
maximise value of examples x
that's a convex function of the elements in x
it has to be a convex function because it is used as an normal
but it's not that easy to show it directly
from the definition
now it's very non-standard
if you have to start optimizing it's very non symmetrical
the same so maximizing we'll talk about minimizing convex functions
and that's easy
and that's a good to maximizing
minimizing concave functions actually extremely hard
that's the current maximizing
but then you switch quality of the minimize and maximize
so you can get actually very problems that look very similar and actually have a
completely different complexion on this very easy on
like finding closest point sets or in its order followed point that can be very
therefore differentiable functions you can actually so many convex functions that you can impact is
not differentiable
but did eventually gets a little more have occurred conditions are
actually better and especially this one it's function is twice differentiable
then the passion matrix is non negative semidefinite for all x in that the best
the true definition of convex function
it's always the easiest one to apply to show the physical
first find the derivative and prove that is positive semi here are often easier ways
to function is called
if the function is
there's also a condition that in terms of the first derivative it's also interesting
it says that if f is differentiable so the gradient is o point x the
gradient vector of first
and you always have this inequality
for any y and x in the domain
basically this means if you look at the right hand side here
and this is the first order taylor series expansion of f
around the point x
to be valid in f of x
if elevator gradients
of project and i give you a local linear approximation to the graph of the
function of y that's true in general for any
but for convex functions we actually have the property that the approximation
is always less than the function of lower bound on the function value everywhere
it's not just local
linear or local
good approximation to the function value around x it's also less than this for quite
a few lower bound on every
and that's not true for non convex functions that are convex functions potential through
it's actually one of the basic reasons why convex
usually really often in which we want to to organize the data saying
someway for applying then although kind of algorithms
so here i have an example of it's really
traditional example of a geyser
who is very popular because he the shots real from
we want to to understand if they're correlation putting
the time the eruptions last and the time between two
two eruptions
from doing density estimation we see that there is a
kind of to two patterns so if we here we have i think
time between two eruptions and he not here is how how long th eruption
last and here is the time between two eruptions
so a frenzy we see that there's two kind of of patterns in here
which i don't know can be used for modelizing this data
ok so what wants to show by this example is that most problems
in machine learning that the one i have shown
and the reformulating into curve or surface to be discovered
and that's it's usually modelize as system of equation
with unknowns to be solved which it's really easily don with
much as metrics much relation so that's that's what's is in larger
useful in machine the second thing that comes out from example
is that there's diverse sources of uncertainty
one comes from the fact that we have a limited amount of of data
and others can come from the noise in the misery muntz
and also of course of the randomness inherent to the observed
phenomena what is really a can be something run from happening there
so that's the second which i'm going to talk about tomorrow which
is probability theory we we again really
a basic step from a introduction to to probability
ok let's go to you are algebra so as has been already discussed
today there is a different kind of data vector we
most often or least what have been done moston machine learning
it's data are represented as vectors
so vectors which m features of course i think i didn't take the
same convention of is a bit because we didn't
so for me i have but n vectors of n components so the f
and so
de inner product toro which is in some condition don't in some cases
called look for the doors carpet that it's more is the same
the finance that so line time column
that's important then for matrix multiplication not that
two vectors are say to be orthogonal if there's carpet that
is zero and as calling was saying just a few minutes ago
it's as often interesting to to have a metric so in in a usual
he genspace like where matrix and vectors like
most of and it's we have norm which is
the square root of the sky are for two of the vector by itself
and usually the distance is defined with these norm as
or the norm of the difference of two vectors
and as you can see here in the definition of the distance in fact
there's scarpa looked of the two vectors
which is included and that's why
also we can see these there's carpet that the similarity or
dipole moment and you have to have to spend articles
some of these very general out one electron
good habits
dipole moment this direction and the in this direction and vectorial sum is zero
the net result is that most atoms and molecules
i have a dipole moments
which are either one bohr magneton
or two were making that is very common
and that's what i will need today
to discuss the issue
how strong
field we can create
if we align all those
the magnetic field that is produced
the material when i exposed to in
external field
magnetic field b
o is the vacuum field
that i can create a solenoid we will discuss the further today
the film which i will call b prime
which is that the magnetic field that is the result of the fact that we're
going to align
these dipoles
external field wants to align
these dipoles and the degree of success depends on the strength of the external field
and of course on the temperature of the temperature is low
it's easier to align them because there's less thermal
and that's a big if
they you will see why it's a big if
if b prime
is linearly proportional
to be vacuum
if that case
there you will see that there situation where that's not the case
then i can write down the b prime
the equals sign of and we call that
last lecture the magnetic susceptibility
time the vacuum
the linear proportionality constant if i can do that then of course be is also
proportional to be vacuous
because now i can write down the b is one class
and the vacuum
and that core that we write
and in fact
which is the equation that i started out with today
and so that only meaningful equation
the some of the alignment of all the dipoles
can be written
as being linearly proportional with the external field and this is is what i want
to explore today
more detail
paramagnetic materials
there is never any worry
the linearity doesn't hold
but with ferromagnetic material that is not the case
because the ferromagnetic material
it is relatively easy to align the dipoles because they
already group in domains as we discussed last time in domain split
in unison
it's always ferromagnetic materials
as you will see today
we can actually go into what we call saturation that all
the dipoles are
the lines in the same direction
now the question is
how strong
would that field b
but to make a rough calculation
but if you have a pretty good feeling
for the numbers
it depends on what material you have
using material
well by the magnetic dipole moment is two
so this is
i told you to one two or three i think one
for which it is too
i have them all lines
so i think the situation that all aligned
so here
the current going around
the nucleus is another one
here's another one
here's another one this is solid material
so these atoms and molecules
nicely packed
you see all these currents going around and all these magnetic dipole moment
nicely aligned
so the magnetic fields supporting each other
and the question now
is one of the magnetic field inside here
well that's an easy calculation
because this really looks like a solenoid like you have windings
you have occurred going around
you remember or should remember
if we have the solenoid
and we run a current through the solenoid