in fact if you look at his three students gets better than the teachers
so in the theory something is completely wrong
and it's completely aware of that and very annoyed by this fact
so inductive inference
and you start with the pattern recognition problem
that draws the fruit fly the simplest problem that contains the learning
four were just slows the point
so you are facts observations about this but then exit
and class is the one that became minus one plus one just two clusters
it's really the simplest problem you can think
and you want to find the classification will find y as a function of x
which is not always possible
but you want to find the function that works best
although the first part of letting this work was concerned about the complexity problem
and it has been known for long time
that the complexity
the solution to find
determines how
credibility are much interest
and the something like in the twentieth century there was all kinds result
entities are not be multiplied beyond necessity that support
it was written that way in latin
and entity means the thing
and then you see things
is a viable
and it's going to show this is not exactly the right formulation
and beyond necessity means that
i don't need to multiply these entities beyond what we need to explain
the observed facts
so that was the complexity concept in the twelfth century
if you apply the to physical sciences
and as i told before learning is very interested in the way
i fields theory
physics is very example of successful science in fact a lot of the world in
which we live as been
produced by our understanding of the physical world
and so we take some quotes the first quote is a quote from understand i
stand said when the solution is simple god is answering
but you also say to to explain this when the number of fractals coming into
is too large
thank you for
the same thing has been said by land are
it was the most version is this
with four free parameters one can draw an elephant
we five
one can do on the front of the thing is there
and that means that if you multiply the parameters in physics well the
the prosody of physics of the physical sciences
do not work so well
but the commission deals with the complex well because we we know how to do
but and commissioned with a lot more common and
well in for the tall second show examples where we have used the parameters and
we can do it
so there is some discrepancy there between the way we build our understanding of physics
and what we are able to do
in pattern recognition
and why is it so
so then they about nature and the series the back from the sixties
in the sixties and the there was no
showing or show there was no real computers where you could actually experiment so when
you start thinking about learning
while computers were distant possibility
i was really interested in the fundamental phenomenon of learning
in machines may be
in humans for
so for any algorithm that selects one function from the set of functions which was
up really
there are two and only two fractals
pick standardisation
the first one is empirical laws that is the number of training are also made
by the functions number also training set
and the second one is the complexity measure now several people with the VC dimension
VC entropy is much better than
and if the complexity of the set of functions
i mean is not the complexity of the solution
it's not because you find the solution and you look at the solution states complicated
like was just a all kinds result
is the complexity of the set of functions from which you search
the right answer
i'm going to go over the
capacity the notion of capacity of learning defined it in the sixties
so you have these patterns x and you have set
of indicator function the function that next
as going to say same minus one plus one depending on which class you believe
x belongs to
and x one xn is supposed to be in the
identically distributed samples of independent examples from the certain distribution that you don't know about
so there is and it's very important that the cause and
which is the number of separations can do about this
but you at them
with function from that city
and this number is of course more than two to the l which is the
total number of separation could think of
basically there are some partitions of these examples but you cannot represent with the function
from that
so it's going to be less
and there is the quantity
it's called VC entropy
which is the logo even of the expectation of that number
the possible drawing office and
so that's the important quantity
there is the quantity that because the growth function
well you're plays the expectation by maximum
so this is an upper bound of
and i think the breakthrough was this
automatic relevance determination anybody one
when you have
all right
maybe i'll do this and then you know
we can take it
break in the die-hard people consider around kind more
in feature selection
so the standard method for doing feature selection in a bayesian setting is called automatic
relevance determination and the reason is nice is that it avoids this
combinatorial search over to the possible subsets
of features instead of that it attaches continuous
number to each dimension
which is the relevance of the dimension and then tries to
infer optimise that continuous number and is usually much easier to optimize one continues d
dimensional vector
ten two
search the corners of a d dimensional hypercube because there two the the corners
this was developed in the context of bayesian neural networks
you have it doesn't matter can apply to lots of other things he has some
inputs and outputs as they were doing regression
because what we could do classification or anything else we want
parameters theta which are the weights and your neural network weights
from inputs to hidden variables and from the very beginning stu outputs
then we define a prior on your parameters posterior under parameters
is a
o point guard from bayes rule all these things come from the basic statistics of
what you define the prior then everything else
i don't need to go into the details
the important thing is the prior the the prior
has a vector
of hyperparameters
and there is an alpha
element for each input dimension OK so here we have three input dimensions and one
output dimensions so would alpha one alpha two alpha three
and what these
hyperparameters do
they essentially determines the relevance of this input
in the whole prediction problem
let's try to understand how
so actually what they do is
they control the the variance of the weights
coming out of each one of these input
and it's OK so
that means
input unit xd
there are some weights coming out of this
w dj is the weight from units input units the
two hidden unit j
OK so this this way here
y alpha d does
is it controls the variance the prior variance of this way
so the prior assumption is that the distribution of wtj given alpha d is normal
with zero mean and variance one property
let's think about this
when alpha d goes to infinity
variance here goes to zero because one over infinity
the weights coming out of input
all of the weights coming out of the deal have zero mean and zero variance
in other words all the weights coming out of the d going to zero
therefore no matter what input is
it has no effect on the hidden variables and therefore no effect on the output
when alpha d
is infinity
it would be is irrelevant
when alpha d is finite
then the weights coming out any finite meaning not in or close to infinity six
like some reasonable small number
then the weight here
can vary
which means that this input x d can have an impact on the output
alpha d continuously controls the relevant
input xt
so the idea behind automatic relevance determination is simply to infer the relevance alpha
from the data it is you're trying to learn
this alpha vector from the data and using the same idea of marginal likelihood and
so on to do that so often what we can do is we can just
optimise of
as a function
we can optimize
probability of all of the observed the outputs given the inputs
as a function of alpha
and then when we do that optimisation what we find in practice is that a
so should start or ten minutes or
so which just left by this very and saying that he five gonna contraction and
we have seen that those properties some previous slides for pretty handy in compete in
here in
why is the unique fixed point if you buy
it iteration is converging to be of and that matrix is invertible the rate of
convergence is is exponentially
so all
why is this case so this would turn out to be
important for
for some reasons so that they are given that we require that you can have
any policy of interest of you
but other than that this doesn't seem to be directly useful for our purposes right
now so what's next is how do we really compute an optimal
you are to do this so we are just one step of a doing that
so we define this
operator that's called after ban on the battle of canonical operator
so this is pretty much the same thing as the operator that we used before
so the difference is that
there is is no policy here since enough
having a policy iran
what we have
we have the maximum overreactions
so if we didn't have maximum body actions were chosen by some policy this would
be just the police abolition operator here by
so why is this change so remember that we are looking for something some policy
that maximizes the reward
it's sort of
i can understand it makes sense to
specific action choice
choosing the action that gives you is this good our lives factors
and so what happens is
but if you define this policy
OK you need one more definition before
i think the next proof
so we say
that policy pi
his greedy respect some function
the director b
fifty five because you have to be
so what is the meaning of this this this is very very compact notation of
saying something very simple
so that simple saying is that
policy is greatest respect to some value function v
if it works in such a way
that maximizes
the sum of the parts
some of the immediate reward for the first time step
plus it matches that from that step on
the put that expected return is going to be defined by p
so if you imagine this and you still have the the action that just
it maximizes this site
you get that policy that's previous respectively
so let's
the definition of greedy policy
and then it turns out that these are gonna contraction so why do we know
that these are coming attractions
the game so
you start by
by decomposing it or looking at the
component defining this operator
and again you see that you have a matrix
vector multiplication so that you see is some of the advice
the have a vector matrix multiplication
and that's this respect probability transition matrix so that's anon expansion and then you multiply
grandmaster that
makes the contraction
and and then you should have
the whole saying by this immediate reward
and that still makes it
contraction OK because it's expansion shifting something
and then you take the max with respectively and we have seen that
so before taking the max what you had that you started this function that was
defined over the state
and you end up with the functions
what are the free variables if if i don't have
max over a here
so the free variables are
x a set of function
over state action pair so we started with the space of
functions so
states and we ended up in the space of functions
the state action pairs
and then we take the maximum we suspected the actions
this brings us back to the space of functions
it is defined just over the state space
the course of
the struggle is
you start this
now you've got to be f
x time a survivor access time is just the product space
and you go back to the facts and this was the operator
and so in the previous slide two slides before we have seen that that operator
is anon expansion so all together the whole operator is is gonna contraction
because every
so it appears someone side
OK so maybe i should spread out
so that definition states
this this is this so by is the greatest respectively
the following happens if you take
this thing here
at some
actually this is the by
applied to the
and a weighted MAX
so keep by visa backer we can take a look at one of its components
so the components are indexed by state variables so that's big axe
so this is
at the
the left hand side
a that
and the right hand side
is what
you have
almost the same exact almost the same expression
except that he's denied having five
in patient
you have the maximum actions
so what they say is
it is
that the policy
which basically says you just going to do
the pass greedy algorithm right to get the solution when we optimize the
benefit cost ratio
and then we get a separate solution that we just tend not considered cost
and then take the best of the two solutions
then the thing works
so then you can prove that again the year optimal meaning we are we get
a constant factor approximation
and the other thing that i would like to know is
how far from optimal right we know we can go and find optimal solution because
that requires the enumeration of all possible subsets in that sense so
the question is
how far in the traditional by this constant factor about that you can define how
how bad so even before looking at the data before running the algorithm you know
how far from optimal you right it says that was you will be at sixty
three percent so you don't even need to look at the data and you know
how how how far how far you could be
in which case so
what we also have is is tighter bound
which basically tells us
how far from optimal worst-case time and the idea is that since this marginal gains
are decreasing
you can go
and get the better
so i was
and the at finish early
so we have two case studies and i just show you want
one is on
on blog network the same that i was talking about before we have this one
blogs for one year and we asked which blogs should one read to detect information
as quickly as possible and the other one is the water distribution network have a
city water distribution network
and we have a realistic simulator simulates how the water is then caught over time
and we would like to find locations for sensors to detect this things skip this
as effectively as possible and i will show the the water network example so we
have looked network has ten to one thousand nodes or houses and we have twenty
five thousand bikes connecting them
so here's a picture of one of these networks
and then we simulated three point six million epidemic scenarios
o what is that
so for any time of the day for for every house
you you pretend you there was an outbreak started to the polls and then you
how how the how the poisonous water would spread over the net
and that gives you a decent amount of data
and then if you're smart you can by exploiting sparsity we we can get down
to sixteen eggs and fitted into the main memory
and then we can run our optimisation
and on
the first question is how far is our solution from the optimal solution
and the
the previous result would tell you that the optimal solution
it lies somewhere between what we have
and this so we know that in worst-case optimally
is of there
the new bound to realize that looks so that they can looks at the algorithm
is much tighter so this is what is basically tells us is in worst case
this is the margin this is how far from optimal so instead of being fifty
seven percent away from of tomorrow we are ten percent from just gives us a
better estimate of
how far is our solution from unknown optimal solution
then what you can also going to ask is what
what if forget about how viruses spread over the network can do these optimizations but
let's just say
let's just heuristic just the locations so for example what i'm showing here is the
the quality of the solution as more sensors are added to the to the to
the network
more than monitoring stations
and these are the other curves are
how good to be would get if you would point for example the sensors randomly
in the network that the black one or even if we were to put it
within based on the population so that's a moot point
the more people do with the sense of the locations where there are more people
or for example you could say i put it put them on the on the
main pipes the pipes when the flow is highest or whether they are not of
the pipes is high but you can see that
if you really going to know how the virus propagates over the network and optimize
then you can do much much better than using any other heuristic selection
any other criteria that does not
we consider the virus
and what they also want to show is that given different different different objective functions
of different criteria
you get different placements so for example
this is the
the water distribution network the dots side of the sensor placements the decided to be
found in human
trying to optimize population affected so the idea here is to have a placement that
would detect
the outbreak of so that the least number of people with the the poisonous one
and you know it
but also this particular presentation was given by michael
is one
copied with languor chunk of text
but we do is
i mean it
that's because it for
so will tell
this is all these things through this follows
and what has to be true so all this
it has to
if this
this is a presentation i don't is the story
the place is given
this tutorial is actually given
this particular presentation
the tories make
and the tutorial is
subgroup of
this one actually working here
so the this topic
who was done
here presenter
so we need there's a person
and who is presentation so this is what this
it assertions he hated tells so
being given a presentation by person
then this person
experts in this field
and also
four medically applied to all the
it for
materialize this rule
let's see how this works
OK so now we sort of this thing in the knowledge base this
what do we know about michael work
and we see that he's expert in the
this if you know we should have the article was under the some of the
point because of
sort of it
we can try to contract
you assert that
i am a person
but this
but does it no it also
so this this
and think it
you can use to
i think second this should automatically
so it's
four so
in fact my probably person was be
this is because
there must be a person
maybe sort apparently attempting if you do this
here we the markers person and the next
it was checking to see that for this is for medical presenter
the constraints are the
the second argument has to be a partner from this it automatically
OK so this is
your cities
so because full of for those of you who basically
we don't know anything on the calorimeters are we really very briefly
in the first like twenty minutes from now the multicolour principles OK
then we move on
basically by discussing introducing the class of markov chain monte carlo methods on their i
will reduce the such as sampling of mental processing factories on that i will discuss
more sophisticated techniques such as slice sampling hamiltonian MCMC
all part of the empirical so that you take this one on off OK so
we will lose all place anytime
during basically this morning after that after the boy we really start discussing the class
of sequential monte carlo methods which is the so-called essentially a large class of multicolored
methods also known in the literature time as particle filters because so i do
OK first i first are one of MCMC sigma
as smc on that's basically to
once you have understood all those techniques with MCMC on SMC then we will describe
essentially mother calorimeters which is essentially a combination of both MCMC on sentiment on this
will include actually
very recent material that have been published actually last year or even as it we
should be published actually very significant so for those of you are really especially some
of the calorimeters i'm afraid you're not going to let me much things this morning
OK but definitely to more like this you should basically get lonely few new nutrients
in this field so
let's start with a little bit of motivation why am i interesting mccallum elements were
essentially means coming from my interest in bayesian statistics OK so essentially a lot of
prior and likelihood of use the bayes rule only we go you have the posterior
distribution of the data given the observation first type or this very nice for slide
define the type of this is why this is notable style OK this is this
is was the distribution of essentially as soon as you have basically model which are
little bit complex you don't have a closed form expression for the posterior distribution so
you need to approximate it on the tools of shows in the states community on
increasingly in the machine learning community consists of using multicolour methods OK
that's why we will be interested in that similarly when you don't want to do
so some kind of model selection in a bayesian framework you have essentially to compute
the marginal likelihood of the salvation which once more so i'm unsure integral typically more
OK so everything you show you interesting computing estimates for complete data bayesian models say
you want to compute the posterior distribution
the probability to find a posteriori was televised one more you i mentioned in schools
so basically multicolour meant that what you need to use this issue as you know
like complex models
OK so
i'm not going to go
like to give much more detail about that you will ever caused by peter noreen
basically tool
on bayesian modeling each time you doing essentially bayesian modelling value adding nonsense non slgnol
model or you're going to have to deal
and we the element to it so as to compute marginal distribution or if you're
interested say in computing center predictive distribution over new acceleration even the call observation one
small this is an idea want in order to go once more you have to
use the kalman you have to use demonstrated sold
that's essentially
my motivation
bayesian statistics i want to approximate
like i i'm unsure percent distribution all over
all the remaining the rest of this talk i will not put any of is
bayesian statistics i will just assume that i'm interested in a given target distribution poisson
distribution to result from the application point of view it's typically we're still distribution but
all it was obvious describing can be generally use uses can be used in the
much much wider context
i say for those of you who have never seen a mccallum i'm just you
know we you essentially very briefly the main idea behind multicolour so
let's start with the kind of silly to example the sea like simplest you can
think so we we can see that we have essentially a circle inscribed in a
rectangle OK
basically i'm supposing
OK so that's really silly example that basically going to utilize the rain that falls
on the square
the blue square here
i'm interested basically
in computing the probability
forward waterfall in a given region a
so which is proportional obviously to the our you have a because i assume that
the drops falls uniformly basically on the square
basically in this case you don't need to do
to do anything basically you know that you should be fine as the the on
the that represent the location of the drug
on a region of interest status article in my case in the previous slide OK
In the thank
I've been talking and then multiplying matrices already but certainly time for me to discuss
the rules for matrix multiplication and
them into
the body of the many ways you can do it and they all give the
same so as and all-important
the matrix multiplication and a
come in Delaware and we mentioned the inverse of a matrix but there is that
than what do about inverses and how to find
OK so not beginning with multiplying 2 matrices birth OK so suppose I have a
a multiplying the matrices B
and giving me a result well I following the anytime me OK and so that
be just review of
rules for the for this
at the entry into rule i and column j so that the ICA anything right
there is the idea we always write the row numbers
and then the columns so I might my might maybe I take it the 3
just make it set so instead of by Jeremy use numbers the the word that
comes from the 3
it comes from both 3
row 3 and column for
as you know
problem and then I just write down the can we write down the formula for
3 4
if we look at the whole role in the whole whole column the quick way
for me to say it is rolled 3 of I could use that . 4
. product often use that actually done column for
of the
and but this gives us a chance that just like you a little matrix notation
what are the entries what this 1st entry in 3
the 1st the 1st that number that's sitting right there is a need so it's
got to indices and what are really want other than any
3 1 there now what's the 1st guy at the top of a column for
so what was sitting up there will be 1 4 right
so that this not a product starts with an a 3 1 times the 1
and then went on to the next so this is like I'm accumulating the sun
then comes the next guy 3
2nd column times be tuned for 2nd row
so as to be anything really new
the 2 more and stuff
just practice within this all let let me practice with a summation forms
so this is an
most of the costs use
all vectors and very seldom not getting down to the details of the particular entries
but here
we better do so I'm in some kind of some right of names in rows
column k of times things it
I wrote a column for using that
that's what we're seeing here this is same 1
here claim to follow along so well
so that's not
all the way along the row and down the columns say 1 that in so
that's what the agent
the C. 3 4 and 3 like a son of a free trade be paid
this takes a little practice that
OK and
all well maybe I should say when are we allowed to multiply the matrices 1
of the shape of this thing
the shapes the if we allow them to be not necessarily square mesh
if there for the the same stuff if the rectangular they're not the same so
if the rectangle this might be well I always think of a and my aunt
and roles and so that growth and now what's the point commonly rose B
and on the number of rows in and be the number of guys that will
be coming down estimates the number 1 of the product that we will have to
reduces the number a twenty two derivatives
and and or some here
this result
would say is that when i take the derivative
i lose the power of t
in the end i don't want any powers of t
very clear i got to start with
function that looks like the square
this we want to take two derivatives
the naughty left
unfortunately we know this is not the right answer because if you take the first
derivative i get to t
the second derivative i get to
i want to get a
and not too
and it's very clear
you find
that's it up
it's you multiplied by this constant
now we are all set
this function will have the right second it
the certainly describes the particle
whose activation is it
it is not dependent on time
but the question is is this the most
general answer
this is just one answer
i think you all know that this is not the most general and so this
one answer
but i can add to this some number like ninety six
still have the property that if you take two derivatives you're going to get the
same acceleration
so ninety six now is the typical
constance i'm going to give the name c
everyone knows calculus that if you if i find a function
what would you know only the derivative you can always add a constant to
one person answer without changing anything
but i think here you know you can do more
you can add something else to be answered
without invalidating
and that is
with one power of p
because if you take one derivative it'll survive but if you take two derivatives
it you begin to get wiped out
now it's not obvious but it is true that you cannot add to this anymore
the basic idea
solving these equations in integrating is you find one answer
the many taking derivatives the function does what it's supposed to do
but then having found one and so you can add to with anything
that gets killed by the act of taking derivatives
the only one that is can have a constant
taking to that you can constant and something linear in t
if you knew only the third derivative the function you can have something quadratic without
changing the outcome
so this is the
was general
position for particle of constant acceleration
you must remember that
this describes the particle going side-to-side
i can also describe particle going up and down
if i do that
i was i would like to call that coordinate y
and i would the same thing
you've got to realize that in calculus
the symbols that you call
x and y are completely arbitrary
if you know the second derivative y
to be a and the answer looks like this if you know the second it
directs the absolutely
now we have asked
what these numbers
b and c
so let me go back now
this expression
x t
it is where over two
let's see
let's pt
it's true mathematical mathematically you can add two numbers you gotta ask yourself what am
i doing as a physicist
when i add these two numbers what am i supposed to do with a and
b with this BNC
what value should i think
the answer is that simply knowing the particle has that acceleration is not enough to
tell you
when the particle will be
for example
let's take the case where
the particles falling under gravity
then you guys know just me
acceleration is minus
nine point eight
twenty nine point because minus because it's actually writing down
and up was taken to be the positive direction
in that case why the
will be minus one half the square
let's see
let's be
the point is every object falling under gravity
is given by the same formula but there are many many objects that can have
many histories of falling under gravity
and what's different from one object the other object is
when was it drop from what i can with what need speak
that that's what these numbers are going to tell us and we can verify that
as follows
you want to know what the number c is
you say let's before time t equal to zero
in fact let me go back to this equation if
what time t equal to zero
x zero
it doesn't have the strength doesn't have this term
and c
so i realize that the constancy
o is the initial location of the object
and it's very common
they're not that by
x not
so the meaning of the constant is
where was the object at the initial time
it could have been anywhere
so knowing the acceleration is starting enough to tell you
but it was initial you get the big but it was the initial
then define the meaning of b
we take one derivative of this
that's the last is a function of time
if the derivative this guy
i find it t
plus b
if the velocity of the object
and you can then understand
that we have zero
is what these
which we write as
OK so the final answer
is that except t
looks like
x not
let b not the
it is my impression is that the second movement towards HDP based URI as the
can also make
l is ID's you reference above
over http just the technical question like
there's a identification she might down
on one level and the dereferencing
the text
on another level missing people are moving towards making this idea is also the difference
the idea of linked data is
keep it simple simple
you just have to three technologies and uses regional colleges you can solve most of
your problems with histories technologies like http RDF and links
if people want to do is build proprietary data space for puppetry standards sure and
this idea is also have since URI is the library communities which require specific infrastructure
to do exactly the same thing
just declined wants to get some data that's not nothing
you have been
i would say everything dies and this move what the reference http wise
and from my impression maybe people should have
this is due to the same impression
you notice
this is not too low special thing is
plain HTTP
meaning that apache does most of the time
as you busy just take part like that to the talk about more details
what does but basically
it's http they can use any http server and the thing is you just
when you do your friends URI
you asked
all content type rdf not for content type x amount
so it builds on
paul over classic infrastructure
it's going to
so what happens
you are
also nice because you can
we use of the technologies like access control and stuff that
have proven useful
four ATP four years now and the people can we use that knowledge to already
have about these technologies and
as ideas
scoring from a scientific point of view but i think pretty compelling from a practical
point of view just don't build new in new infrastructure for stuff that already works
used in the world
the thing
the other others
the new
know this is that you know the topic it's coming later in this tutorial
the kind of the tricks of the whole thing like
s on the that explicitly have to set links
so what people usually do is say
you know about some data sources they look the status of clouds that we also
have list the on the in the wiki about all the data sources they select
some noticing interesting
and then they usually
the data sets a big like the data set was
o records about
it was
twenty so bands
hundreds of thousands of albums
usually use an automatic interlinking charisma some similarity matching i reason to figure out your
could just means you have to talk about this in detail later
this is because of the
much of
but strongly being done is people don't care too much about ontologies
so now you see
hopefully connected to this notion of
if how we control function from
from a jeep e
so the step so this should be clear that is the only
this is the only code snippet i will give you throughout the course but it's
but it's but it's only it's only one line and dual one packed more
okay so how do i get how to actually get the straw
so to do that's i take a whole bunch of index points
a finite number
so here i took
the integer index points between zero and five hundred
i evaluate the kernel function just like we do with those three index points
i evaluate the kernel function building the sum in the sum
five hundred by five hundred matrix can
and then i can take a draw
from the guassian with zero mean and the covariance
so how that's actually done right and this this would be here matlab code
how that's actually done is is according to this
so they will give u
this this procedure will give you this nice
will give you this nice strong
okay so there is one drawing green now taking four draws at end and belaboring
this point just so just that we remind ourselves that draw from guassian process gives
you a function so four draws from now give is nice for functions
before when we are evaluating the kernel matrix
we we messed around with the hyperparameters a little bit and see how that changed
to see how the change the covariance matrix
let's do that here in pictures
so here is
sigma alpha ten
and the lengthscale fifty
if i change and leave the lengthscale fifty
but not change the power the envelope about from ten down before r and you
see what's happened is that the
the onlooker shrunk and the draws a strong
not surprising
if i change
if i change the lengthscale fifty to a length scale of ten
right so what this is saying is
has two points get further apart
they fall off the their correlation falls off more quickly
so accordingly you get more weakly draws
one final point on this is this
we should feel a whole lot like when we are evaluating those those covariance matrices
in other words this is easy
is it so is that
closer to the identity matrix the covariance matrix is closely and stand for example this which has much longer-range correlations
okay so i mentioned that's what we've been looking at regression in time and taking draws that are nice
temporal functions as easy to look at and familiar to us are you can also have a dimensional input
i wanna be
one of the the histories the application areas where gas process even used a lot is in geostatistics andtheir
there are often interested in
since spatial guassian processes so for example latitude longitude instead of regression and time you
want regress on latitude longitude so do that we can make
we can make each input
instead of instead of a single real a real valued number a pair of numbers
so now
we've got some guassian process here for the same gene he
and the kernel is almost exactly the same except here is just an extra term
there's there's there's there's a squared term for each dimension about casting process
so what might a draw from not look like instead of one single function
what you get now is a field over over latitude longitude so that a random
function is drawn over the field
i suppose
shameless plug if you are staying free cystatin you wanna see a multidimensional cheapy in action
we've got a we've got a paper on the and i'm sure there will be
other papers which appears as well
okay so
we've got the same model
there we just been dealing with
and now let's let's gather some data
so this is that this is this is our model the jeep model
we've got a prior
and we can go and take we can go and take a data point so
on so i say i gathered data point in time
two hundred four r
so what i know
is there i can evaluate wife two hundred four r
and i know that this is according to the model
this is calcium distributed according to mean zero and came why
evaluated to afford four coming to the fore that's a simple univariate gassing
this is all just pulling this right out of right out the definition of f
of what other jeep peay
and i'm just evaluating the kernel matrix
then we can use conditioning to update the posterior r so here i still got the prior there
but not got this data observation so i can use
i can use the inference rule that we talked about
and evaluate why to
so i take this data point why to afor
and run this equation
and what is this give me
well now this is refined
my posterior estimate of so there is no longer flat mean function
but i think the mean function comes down here and goes to ask
furthermore because there are choice
f of noise parameters you can see that what's happened here is right around two afor i'm awfully short
my my my my
covariance outlook has collapsed and of assure that that the measurement is around there
but as soon as i get further away
well i forget because because i don't think that what happens in four hundred is
particularly related to what happened to the fore so by the time i get over
here and basically back to the prior
a small change is there
here we are looking at the posterior this this i think is important it is
important a hang on just for a second because often when you look at
geeky work it's not clear whether people are talking about whether whether showing that the
posterior or they are showing a predictive model so
this on the poster and this here is the predictive the predictive distribution so you're
just know this is a very small change here but this this this very simple
it has just increased slightly ever-so-slightly because we think that on top of their
and thank you again to the person loaned me
laser pointer and so excited
so in the second part of the tutorial
i'm going to focus on
other ways of understanding adaboost so
so far i've described
talk about boosting in terms of
as a boosting algorithm in this pack sense and i talked about the margins theory
as a way of understanding
why adaboost often does not overfit and let me say i don't think i said
it so far but of course adaboost sometimes does overfit certainly
but in many cases often does not
it turns out that there are many other ways of thinking about adaboost
and in the second part of the talk i want to talk about three of
the first one is a game theoretic perspective on
boosting in general the second one is viewing
boosting has lost minimisation algorithm so in other words in terms of optimisation
and then the final view
which is closely related to the loss minimisation is a view based on information geometry
so let me start with the first of these
we can think about boosting has a game that is as of formal interaction
between the two
in this setting the two players are the boosting algorithm are the booster
and the weak learning algorithm or the weak learner
so on each round t
each of these players is making the move
so the booster chooses distribution dt that's the move that the booster makes and the
weak learner responds by choosing a weak classifier ht
so we can think of this as the game booster makes move and the weak
learner makes move and that repeats
so we're going to study this in terms of game theory or think about in
terms of game theory so game theory
is the field of mathematics that studies ordinary games things like you know checkers tic-tac-toe
and so on
but it also studies all kinds of interactions between all sorts of players between people
and corporations and animals
computer agents
and here we're going to be thinking about
boosting as a game between these two players the booster and a weak learner
and this is going to lead has will see this is going to lead to
many insights about boosting we're going to see that
the boosting problem itself is very closely connected to game theory
two key notions of game theory
OK so
to get started let me give a little background on game theory
for our purposes the game is defined by a matrix m
so here's the game matrix for the game rock paper scissors which hopefully everybody
nose in principle
any game can be
any zero sum game can be put into this form as matrix although in general
the matrix might be
extremely large
but in this case the game matrix is just three by three
so in this game there are two players the row player in the column player
to play the game the row player chooses one of these rows and the columns
player chooses one of these columns
and the resulting loss
to the row player is just whatever entry is chosen up here
so for instance if the row player chooses
and the column player chooses scissors
scissors beats paper
and so the loss to the row player is one of his were always going
to be taking the view of the row player you can think of the column
wanting to maximize
the loss suffered by the row player so in that sense the game is set
to be zero sum
meaning whatever one player wins the other player loses
OK so
so usually we allow the players to make randomized choices in their play
up until now is in the row player chooses a single row and column player
chooses a single column
but instead we could allow the row player to choose the distribution over rows and
the columns player to choose the distribution over columns with the understanding that the actual
choice of rho
will be selected at random according to p
and likewise the actual choice of column will be chosen according
the distribution q
and then we can compute the
row player's expected loss which would just be the sum over rows and columns of
the probability of choosing their own column times the actual loss that would be suffered
by j
we can rewrite that in this nice matrix form
or i'm going to be using this notation pq
i to mean the loss suffered if the row player chooses p on the column
player chooses
OK so this is really an expectation
but i'm going to forget the expectation part and we're just going to think of
this as the actual
loss suffered by the row player OK
i'm also going to write things like m p j
when q is just concentrated on a single column j
OK so
the fundamental theorem
zero sum games is called the minimax theorem it's divine ointment
and in symbols it says that if you take the men over distributions p
over rows
of the max over column distributions q of the loss that would result
that's equal to the maximum
so you can just take the minimax in reverse get the maximum
and this common value is called the value of the game and i'm going to
write it as be OK so this is just a lot of mathematical symbols what
does it actually mean
well the fact that the minimax is equal to v
that means that the row player has what's called the minmax strategy p star
so that no matter how the column player plays the matter what strategy distribution q
is chosen by the column player the loss
will be at most the
that's what meant minimax equals b means
and the fact that max equals maximum in the fact that the maximum is also
equal to the value v
it means that p star
it is optimal
its optimal in the sense that the column player has its own strategy q star
called the maximum strategy
so that no no matter how the row player plays its loss will be at
debating what what exactly what function for use on this of exponential decay function is
this happens there is a common one that seems reasonable choice
you can actually pick another functions as well
the image and the second is that for those who are familiar with the sum
of the
normal distribution of the gaussians distribution say this what this form written out here you
know it cosmetically lots of the gaussians distribution but this is that actually does actually
has absolutely nothing to do with gauss distribution on this is not
it's not that you probably excised calcium whatever is no no such interpretation this is
just a convenient function that happens to be bell-shaped function and elders of any calcium
as the fact
if you're the familiar bell-shaped calcium on again just
the way to the end of associating with these points is that some
if you may imagine
but the sort the bell shape by centred around the position of where you want
to value hypothesis it then this is saying this point here i'll give
a weight is proportional
so the height the gaussians used to the height of the bell shape function
evaluated at this point
and the way to get to this point to this training example will be proportional
to that right
and so on
so the training examples are really far away
a very small way
one last small generalisation to this is that normally is one of the parameter that
is out of
this which i don't know how
on again this looks suspiciously like variance of the gaussians but this is not is
convenient form of function this parameter tau
it's called the bandwidth
and so
if only it controls how fast the weights for with distance so
my diagram from
the one
so on towers very small category x
you end up choosing very narrow calcium using a very narrow bell-shaped so that's on
the way point far we are rapidly
whereas if fun
tau is large
if tau is largely that using
a weighting function to falls relatively slowly with distance from the aquarium
i hope you can therefore see that
if you apply locally weighted linear regression today the second outside this
then two
ask what you hypothesis is output is in the point like this can be in
a straight line
making that prediction
on the last week classes output is that value in a straight line there
you think that value
and since every time you are you trying to value hypothesis every time you are
going out to make a prediction before you know how much the new health path
whatever you need to fit
you need to run new fitting procedure and then about
on this line defects
just at the position of
on the value of x is the position of the query where you tried
but if you do this you have every point along the exact is then you
find that not everyone regression is is able to treat all the full very non
linear kernel
it is said that
in the problem that western that you hear rumor is our from so i won't
say too much more about it here
this visualization
techniques and pretty should depending on the application people may do different things
so this is a software tool that is applied for
cell phone calls
and in this
and this is o
for detecting go
telecommunications fraud and people try to
data using
different different graphs
phone calls that
from camp
because actually every not crisp on the cellphone actually
lines correspond to which
phone call you made so basically if you have the line here and here that
means this for some medical this person so they use the colors
represent different anomaly in this case i think
below correspond to quite normal behavior and then red green and red correspond to anomalous
and then use also the kind of the histograms to represent what can be
number so
again this visualization techniques mostly depend on the application mostly depend on the
the problem so
people end up using different visualization tools different approaches to visualizing the data in multi
so now we will talk briefly about all this approach is here contextual anomaly collect
collect detection online and distributed anomaly detection
so as i mentioned earlier
in contextual anomaly detection you have to put the context in into the game so
the key assumption that
if you don't do this
all data records made of the same only managed to do this concept
the context then you will be able to see
what is normal and what is not
so the general approach in this kind of techniques is to identify the context first
using a set of contextual attributes this can be like spatial domain or temporal domain
to put them into place
and then you have to to determine if the test data record is anomalous the
thing that specific on
o thing to provide some
four inside
so obvious
but of course they can detect anomalies that are hard to see the new
ignoring this
contextual information
but some of the challenges included sometimes identifying a good set of compassion for the
features may not be trivial task
how to determine the parts of the context then you find this conversion activities also
very challenging task
as i said i set confessional debate attributes usually defined neighborhood for each data record
so they may include spatial context for example
we you the latitude longitude certain data records
the graph context they include edges and waits for sequential position in time
four profile use some kind of demographics and so on
so usually what you're trying to do
you first try to use this had to identify these
contextual attributes and to reduce the problem to point anomaly detection
one of the first step is to segment to cluster the data using only this
contextual information
and then
you can of
apply this traditional anomaly detection techniques
within each context using other types attributes we call them behavioral attributes
again the problem is sometimes
this context like this cannot be saying that and easily that maybe the problem so
in this case usually you're trying to
exploit some
the models
the well-known in contextual domain for example for dealing with temporal data you trying to
use for example time series for the sake arima moving average out regression models
to do something with this can actually did to segment them to buy some more
and then you can try to do this point anomaly detection
and and also
you're trying to optimise using that one elegant writer and automatically analyse
data instances with respect to the context
OK this is one of the approaches
proposed by sundaram come from is to florida
so they're trying basically to do this conditional
anomaly detection this term they introduce incentive contextual using word conditional anomaly detection
basically they represent everyday to record as a pair of attributes x and y x
denotes the contextual attributes
and y denotes the behavioral attributes
so a
right now they are trying to do
mixture of
and you go the model then basically model correspond to contextual data
very similar to a mixture and the
of course models correspond to behavioral data so basically they're trying to learn mixture of
course among for both
contextual attributes and for here
so i know that second the mapping
is basically learned that indicates the probability of the care about to be part to
be generated by component vj
when the contextual part is generated by component u j what that actually
we're are trying to see basically
how likely is the contextual part to be the component
of URI basically that's
what we have here so this is the parameters used in all the actions this
is used
as anomaly detection score
so first
here this space basically trying to compute
as a so-called likely
this data could only the contextual part to be generated by
this is a distribution
you i here
so the next step
what is probability
the behavioral part to be generated by the distribution of the j
and finally
given this fact
the data records from contextual q i
what is the probability that it is the most likely component vj
that will generate the behavioral part so basically it was first tried to
estimated distribution for contextual part
and then to learn from the history
what kind of behavior can correspond to this confessional part
then you go to the test data
you identify contextual part
and and if the pitcher paul does not fit this piece
then you will treat this as an online so that's like some kind of tool
step approach when you're taking this kind of anomalies that's probably
the only
actually one of the rare papers that deal with this kind of contextual in conditional
anomaly detection
they also mentioned earlier this collective anomaly detection techniques
and in this approach is
is you exploit the relationship among data instances in order to detect this data records
and as i said this is mostly applicable to
two spatial domains
and some graph anomaly detection
of course
if you have the time series data also sequence a sequence of symbols
with the same frequency in that in that sequence and it even every subsequence appears
with the same frequency in that sequence
this way if you look at how many times thirty five orcas in this
expansion you would have exactly one
over hundreds
so you could say well it's just randomly like if i if i sample one
in figures
independently so if i just put numbers i strode dies with ten faces
and i write down
which are the numbers that come out i could ever sequence that looks like this
at least in terms of frequencies
so why would this sequence b not random
different difficult thing to say it's not random because here we see a simple way
to continue the sequence and this and simple in the sense that we can express
an algorithm
that would
produces a sequence and continue
this algorithm would be the algorithm that computes the this man expansion of can maybe
it's not a single organism but at least it's an aneurysm
and it's not just a random phenomenon
that shows you that
in this process when we try to
observe something and continuing to predict what comes next
usually we look for but turns off for good reasons or for something that we
can express
in simple and operated terms
that would produce the sequence
and continued
the question naturally is
is there some kind of unique way of doing this and i think i have
convinced you i hope i have convinced you that it's not the case
and there can be
many answers to such questions
for example
if you think in terms of algorithms if you have a programming language that
that is some pretty primitive that allows you to naturally make
o multiplications i ditions and so on may be expressing the algorithm that computes the
this is expansion of by simple and you can try the short program that does
it but if you don't have these primitives in your language i don't know if
you have a
maybe approach prolog programming language or something new language that doesn't have arithmetic primitives then
you might have a much harder time expressing this
and maybe you would try to create a program that expense or continues the sequence
in a different way than computing the decimal expansion of pi
because it's all it's all a matter of what are the things that you think
are simple and what you are the things that you think are complicated
like this example of group series versus number theorists so number theorists see primes everywhere
group series c c
groups everywhere right so it's just
yeah its simplicity is not an objective notion that's the key point
unfortunately this is
i i would say that main
the main thing to
about this is that
there is no principle four
induction unfortunately
i could just of the lecture now but they continually of it
reasoning that you might think of to justify induction based on simplicity
cannot so can just failed because
simplicity cannot be defined in an objective way
what can we do this
so now i want to
talk a little bit about probability because probability is often used in this context to
justify induction or two
derive algorithm for induction
and i want to tell you
a few things about probability just two
two have a common understanding of this
so probability is
the nice theoretical tool mathematical tools for dealing with reasoning with and under uncertainty
it allows you to formulate
imprecise statements knowing
at the heart
of the probability are the core there are these actions
so probably you you can deduce more less
all the rest
all the all the other properties of probabilities
but the question is
how do you relate these abstract mathematical objects that are the probability is too
the real work how do you measure these quantities do the probabilities
actually exists
what do they mean in the real world
there are several answers to this question actually it again
a somewhat philosophical question and there
at least three different points of view on how to answer this question
one very classical one is too
i don't the frequentist point of view
and in this point of view frequent sorry probabilities are
just taken as needs
the observed frequencies so you just throw dice a certain number of times you count
how many times it's ends up on one or two or three and then you
do that enough times
the the the
frequency that you have converges to some value
and you would say the probability that my dies
lens on the one
is this frequency
and then there's is the objectivist point of view
that's a
the case of trees we have to estimate the accuracy evaluation
when we the
this is the ultimate value and then the corresponding model has one two three four
nonzero coefficients and one two or three
that still see what the point
and so
reference here and so in our
it is also the the score something called the largest package in r and so
you can get
this that said i believe it might even be included with the large package and
you can't really do this picture and and even compare the
this solution has
four coefficients versus the ordinary linear regression solution with the cerenkov aphasia and and and
show in this particular case that there are right i solution has a later lower
case ever
so to summarize
two two is light summaries on on
globalization so what is the decision what we've been talking or i got this quote
from these cases this recent phd thesis is that this is so any part of
model building which takes into account implicitly or explicitly the finiteness and imperfection of the
and the limited information in it which we can term but instead an abstract sense
so that's where decision
how do we know that i swear to they win or lose of three different
ways of regularized the
one is
having explicit constraints which is what we do with the lasso
we can do all
implicitly through incremental model building so that is and if they
epsilon stagewise for work that were built in the modernist slowly little by little daddy
some form of regularisation and that's going to play a key
in today's understanding of how boasting work
you can add to regularize the rule
a choice of they are was loss function in so doing it is my somewhere
like what does the lost interest
decision well so one of the sources of finance has to be with outliers right
so to the extent that you have
loss function that is less sensitive to outliers URI using body and and so you
are doing meditation
and then let's let's look at the picture that we had before
and in the realization side to it
so this is what we had before
and which is great so now what we don't is we have restricted already know
more space so so when increasing the bias
that's that's increasing bias that we took
so this is the motor bias and this
now it's what it called estimation by this
and so the closest to the truth
in the restricted model is this one right so so that's that's what i mean
that we have think remain
increase the value and so they
regularized feed the f had lasso
so remember where we were there will arise in these have had so it's going
to be the closest in this restricted model space to that guy
the right hands is going to be a lot smaller and that's that that's what
that's the intuition and so
when the increasing by us
or where there shown body and so we went from these by audiences what when
the reduction in body and it it's larger than the increasing by yes we need
something useful and we have a lot of water
OK so now
switch topics
two perhaps what you're he
and so
in the abstract we said that
one one of the things that we're going to talk about his importance sampling that
goes by the acronym years elite distance or importance sampling learning ensembles this is reason
worked on
from donut
by professor friedman stand for which as we say in the have of the allow
us to view the traditional and simply methods of bagging random forests balls on march
as special cases of
a single organism not only that it it does suggest ways of improving
each of these organisms so if you are currently using bagging you you you will
find ways to provide you know you use random forests and so on so
they approach it is so we're going to come from the top assume you don't
know anything about and symbols and you're you're going to be described is generic and
simple generation algorithm and then will
but that template next to the template the of
they they
previously existing methods and see how each of them fit is generic template
so there
the model that we have so let's start with what is the model that we're
so optimal
was the paper from two thousand two
sort of pretty
well cited paper now on that analyse this regret minimisation problem for the multi armed
i'm just going to tell you the algorithm is extremely simple so every moment in
we're going to have some statistics we've collected so we've pulled a bunch of arms
q way
is going to be the average payoff that we observe for army
right so we pulled arm a some number of times QA is the payoff that
we've observed on average
and a is the number of times we pulled arm
so we we can store these things easily
and now the question is what are reliable next
UCB for upper confidence bound is going to pull
this army a star
that maximizes this quantity
but about this quantity in the moment and this assumes that the payoff an zero
there and zero to be be square there are but this is the quantity that
is going to maximize going to pull that are
the basic theorem is that
the expected regret so the difference between the sum of rewards that we get if
we pull the over the the optimal arm
and the sum of rewards we get according to strategy that's the expected regret the
difference in the sums up expectations
is going to be bounded by
log and the number of our polls
this is a pretty pretty good bound in in fact is actually a lower bound
that matches this
so says that the sum of our poles that i get for my strategy compared
to some of our pulls if i always pulled the optimal arm is going to
be bounded by this particular
formerly over time it's not an asymptotic result
so if you think about what is the average
regret right you're going to divide this by and
and so on average
your your regret your payoff
it's going to be raag again divided by and away from optimal
so that's pretty good that goes to zero quite quickly
so that's the issue pretty famous result this problem was to find in the sixties
and it's just two thousand two that this result
came around to score in
so so those results so
so the original scoring rules require quite a bit of computation the the indices the
this requires practically no computation has simple statistics they had some later work so they
could prove bounds of log for those but they were asymptotic as an gets goes
to infinity that they had some
easier to compute versions and also the bounds for asymptotic this was the first found
that was not that this actually every single and it satisfies the property that none
of these are
i don't know about that
i think they have to think about that so i forget about this system animation
problems so let's look at this this
rule this is our algorithm our decision rule
so what it is is a value term
so is that have high value
or we're going to be more inclined to pull because the some will be larger
armies that have looked really bad in the past will be less inclined
but remember we always have to make sure we explore a summary because maybe get
unlucky with the optimal arm in the beginning you know a fourteen forever so we
have this exploration term
the in what this is going to do is to notice that lol again is
in the numerator of this term
remember n is the total number of poles
so is the total number of poles increases
and i say we don't pull this are so in a stays the same this
term is going to keep getting larger and larger and larger and eventually you're going
to pull that are again
now when you pull it again
this is going to increase by one it doesn't take too many samples for
this to sort of dominate the log and and if you pull amalie this basically
goes to zero so as alarms that pulled lot are basically dominated by this term
answer to pull the little dominated by this term in the only pull them
a little bit
now of
sort of the the fundamental result of that paper the following
the expected number of times that we're going to paul
the sub optimal arm
so so there are now going to find it in the case of the expected
number of times we poland a sub optimal arm after and total poles is going
to be bounded by this
so so notice first it's log n so if an arm is suboptimal
asymptotically and actually in every moment
is dominated by bloggers who are not going to pull it very much because logan
is a lot smaller than
what is this
is the difference between the expected value of the optimal arm
and our a
and notice if our a is really bad compared to the optimal arm
this term is going to be very small
whereas if are may is very close to optimal
this concert will be large
in some sense that's OK because it's close to optimal
we're happy to pull in more than an arm that is really bad and so
this is the fundamental result in
basically if you multiply this quantity by
this difference to get the expected regret of time
and so on
so you just get one of these and in the denominator
all right so
so that's so it doesn't waste time on bad arms sort of fundamental result from
the theory of multi armed
bandits so so now how can we apply this result
we have about twenty minutes
here because it's
it's the sound standard normal mean easier
this is the kind of processes that may represent some
stock markets areas like this i am IBM
statistical review what what's
interesting is trying to estimate
the parameters of this model here we have three parameters beta
and sigma
and observations
well we have about five hundred observations
OK so we have the whiteys from one
two five hundred and one to produce
the posterior distribution on beta
and sigma
we cannot really look directly at this posterior distribution
because the likelihood is this five hundred dimensional integral we need to integrate out
OK because of the y t
so the whiteys of the marginal of the joint whiteys and xt
so the distribution of x of y t
she going from one to five hundred is into world of the joint distribution of
y t xt
she going from one to five hundred so we need to integrate five hundred sixty
and we can do it
in closed form therefore what we want to do is is
to approximate not only the dispatcher distribution of
and sigma
but the joint posterior distribution of beta
phi sigma and vxt so we just plug txt is into the unknown
and in terms of of distributions to get the same treatment as parameters because there
are no
so now we have a distribution
joint commission on the expertise and why it is that that look like that this
is like the likelihood if you had observed also
next season
so this is usually one to cement for given the parameters
and we have a distribution for the distribution of the parameter so this makes the
distribution to simulate in dimension five hundred and three
that is the probability dimensional problem because we simulate loss
the exterior of course links
together so it's not like simply a five hundred points independently
and the shape of the distribution is not exactly standards
get something that is really
no more like but here
we have an exponential growth and exponential
that's not
and we need to deal with this
what to do to simulate this drug distribution and beta phi sigma NTXT this to
replace these difficulties since distribution
we have a simpler distribution
and why is usually to get
rate of the exponential by linear transform like this kind of terror expansion
and therefore we have a huge gaussian distribution of dimension five hundred to simulate
the xt
OK with some
mean environs that
we can compute
now we have a gaussian we can do it one term at the time
and we get an importance weight which is the ratio of the truth all over
the wrong
well the importance distribution
we have
because the size of the problem
most of the weights will be very very small because it is ground
we normalised of the mapping
the way you can see that
the bill
that correspond to the highest weight
it is very similar to young get something that is very nice and climbing up
no it's and centred at some value and you have difference of
of two magnitudes in log of ten ten images in logs
number one you take the highest
the sequence with the highest weight you don't necessarily get something that is very very
close to the troops in
you can see something and is the blue line is the true volatility the true
sequence of is and the red dotted line
on the simulation
the sequence and that got the highest weight
because the degeneracy of the weights
i have to wait doesn't necessarily mean
simulation close to the troops
OK and here is another example of the same thing
except that includes the range of all
the consequences of of simulated and you can maybe see that it this is true
the range
well if you made can be very very different from the truth
so this is the sampling and
i tried to come back
to this method after
after about MCMC methods because there is kind of
convergence of both methods in in more
the techniques that we call population monte carlo
which is up
synonym of particle filter method
just before
going to to markov chains i want to talk about a few points
monte carlo method
improving the monte-carlo methods
it's trying to reduce the violence that few tricks that can help with reducing the
and one of these traces is whenever you can produce negative correlations in your simulation
or rather in the age of x are
you're edges of our
OK this seems
so to impose correlation but actually
if instead
after producing two
independent samples
are of x i and y j
and using this to sample
cumulatively to approximate the integral i
if you can produce
correlated samples
so that the covariance
i once had and i two had is negative then you get of course is
more violent than using and i i d
now it is not
always obvious to realize that they should trick that if the function is symmetric
you can
use the symmetry of the symmetry
in function if you know for group action
the space you're working on
no no this one more thing perhaps about PCA
so peace is really good for presenting presenting this
this kind of distributions as we have here
which are characterized by the fact that well for example by many facts actually well
but basically have something like an edit for something like an ellipse that the data
from the club is something similar to with then some points here and there
so let's think of many different kinds of data sets
for example something like something that's a bit like a band shape
so you have
data points
like this
now if you do PC this kind of data
you get into trouble
well because i mean what is the PCA uses this kind of the coordinates well
let's make it even more weird the PCA doesn't work
so what PCA would do
well let's face it would give you one
component one linear
beginning from the being so let's suppose the means here
so then
the principal component might be i don't know maybe something like this
well the
certainly this single called analogous to describe your data so well not in the same
way as the singing composing component in in that case
i think
this may not be the best example possible but in case you see is that
this kind of thing is very natural for that kind of ellipse shape stuff because
if you have an ellipse than how to represent you can easily represented by this
and these
these two continents but for this kind of data what you actually want to do
is to use some kind of feeling sorry some kind of nonlinear coordinates some kind
of nonlinear manifolds well i mean the idea way of representing this kind of data
would be that you have one coordinate that goes something like this
actually you don't really need another coordinate because there's you have only very little noise
in this in the orthogonal to this one you just this one coordinate one accordance
with very well described it so this is the case where people would like to
use some kind of non linear PCM
this is not a case where you would like to use ICA ICA addresses completely
different problems as we will see later probably tomorrow
but this is
this is this is related to the linearity of BBC
OK maybe that's enough but PCA for the
and let's go
so short reminder of how
you estimate statistical models
in particular what is the maximum likelihood estimation
so what is the dimension means we have basically three different words which sound very
much the same but which have slightly different meanings which is
one the fundamental thing is destination
estimation can be defined in an extremely boring and abstract way in in mathematical statistics
but here we define it in a more intuitive manner which means that we have
some kind of parameters
something which correspond to usually one sponsor something into like for example the mean value
of all of the population of perhaps the standard deviation of the variance of the
population and now estimation means finding an approximate value for
that parameter when we have a random sample of of the population
so this the idea of of in statistical estimation is always there's some kind of
theoretical population
and we only have access to a random so it's my small sample of the
so this is very different from things like data miners from some some aspects of
data mining of some approaches to data mining where you just have you know a
and that's all people don't assume that it's a sample of something
well some people do but some people not in statistical we always have an underlying
population which is actually model is represented by statistical distribution of random variable are random
now we estimate is the concrete function or in computer science terms it might be
an algorithm that really gives you computes this absolute value given this sample
so you might also uses the floor of the sample
which is to be kind of signal processing terminology in in statistics when we have
a number of measurements that's one sample
but as in signal processing you would perhaps there is some people will say that
each of those measurements is one sample which is again a bit confusing
but in any case so in statistical problems so we have a sample from which
we compute this approximation and estimates now is the numerical value given by the estimator
for one particular sample so here my cause set of samples but in statistics we
would say that the value given by a single source
so basically you know like the population could be like all
to be represented as a very sparse long binary vector
if we give the query two of our favorite people alex smola virtual can't remember
these are newspapers eighty seven ninety nine
things may have changed
by the party members that there are the following people including you know more paper
people like and are
and the top words associated with that that are the words back to support colonel
have no idea what pages here
maybe there are lots of pages
machine quadratic of regularisation minimizing
so if we give a large following from the accolade we're you probabilistic models around
the same time
here's the list of people that we get other people working on probabilistic model
and the top words are log likelihood models mixture conditional
and during in red button we're working on a lot of reinforcement learning and decision
making models
we get other people report learning and decision making and these are the top words
here's here's something i would actually find really useful if somebody provided this service based
on the
we haven't done it but you know the next if somebody did
often we we're doing the literature search
we may have a couple of examples of papers we know are on the topic
we're interested in
and what we really want to do is we want to find other papers
that are somehow on the same topic so instead of typing in keywords which is
what we had to do
which seems incredibly stupid if i have to incredibly
big rich document
why would i have to come up with keyword to try to represent what can
i give my two documents as the query
so here's what we did we had a system for searching literature where
our query
it was not just the
title here we have the title
and the authors of the
in this paper but query whether fact a representation of the whole document in terms
of the
in this case the bag of words representation of the document in terms of words
OK but we binarize the bag of words so that represents each document by overabundance
of certain words
and then the results are other documents
the interesting thing is that both of these documents were are about gas prices are
both papers about casting process these all these papers are about casting processes
including for example this one computing with infinite network
which if you just look at the title the
you know mentioned but if you look at the actual at the cutting process is
at the top words are
yes the process related work
chris williams
OK i have to take a look at that the second thing except
and it's not in the light of that but you have to take a look
at that
and query times are very fast and this is just running on the left
you know different have that with
you know matrices there are thirty thousand by two thousand doing the really naive matlab
implementation each query takes about the second process or less if you didn't mark level
clever implementation
i am sure it it can be sped up by in fact we know how
to speed up by even more than that
so we can use this to be content based image retrieval let me show you
how to based image retrieval and that
and try to wrap up and we can take a little break
in our content based image retrieval
we have a we have the following scenario
we want to search a large collection of unlabeled images
we imagine entering the word
we can also hear subset of images
and the basic idea of entering the word is that we have some small set
of labeled images
so when we enter the word penguins what we can do is we can
find the labelled images that are labeled penguins
and present that as a query set q this is the
that's going to retrieve
unlabeled images
the query set is the set of images
all of which have the label penguins
and we're going into the data set of unlabeled images
and finding other images that match the
purely content based visual features
so we have here
label that ten thousand images from unlabelled set of twenty two thousand images and about
two thousand different keywords that this can
can run on this many keywords you have but we have about two thousand
so the features that we use are incredibly simple and stupid there's things like
texture features
i like for texture features these things are more features and just global color histogram
saturation value we we
this implies that we represent the probability that a feature
and we binarize our data by three feature we
take a continuous feature we compute the cube that feature we take the
the heavier tail that every giver one value with some of the heavier tail and
zero value otherwise
so we end up with the two hundred forty binary features very different
yeah it's pretty stupid but you'll see it a can actually work quite well
the texture features are a little more clever clever in that we take the image
it's still pretty embarrassingly
so we get divided into quadrants we compute texture features and each of the
o actually nine
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses visit
MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
again welcome to eighteen o one
we're getting started today
what we're calling
unit one
highly imaginative
topic i highly imaginative titles
so let me first tell you briefly
what's in store in the next couple of weeks
the main topic today
what is
a derivative
we're going to
look at this from several different points of view
and the first one is the geometric interpretation
and that's what will spend most of today on
we'll also talk about physical
i what derivative is
there's going to be something else which
i guess is maybe the reason why calculus is so fundamental and why we always
start with it
in most science and engineering schools which is the important
of derivatives
the of this too
all measurements
so that means pretty much every place that means in science
in engineering
in economics
in political science
federer polling
lots of commercial applications just just about everything
so that's what we'll be getting started with
and then
there's another
o thing that we're going to do
in this unit
which is
we're going to explain how
to differentiate any
so how to differentiate any function you know
and that's kind of tall order
but let me just give you an example
if you want to take the derivative this will see today is the notation for
the derivative something
of some messy function like e to the x arctan
i will work this out
by the
and of this unit
right so anything you can think of anything you can write down
we can differentiate
right so that's what we're going to do
as i said
we're going to spend most of our time
on this
geometric interpretation
so let's let's begin with that
so here we go with the geometric
what we're going to do
is just as the geometric problems finding
the tangent line
graph of some function
at some point
which i think you're right
that's the problem
they were addressing here
the station