distribution seems to the store for the distributed to the ship every this kind of
distribution is
but key distribution means you are not just you want to do so many things
the whole track you may go down there so
with this
what about instead of thinking there
one so the idea is if the ship at the same time what we
but we think they are just one idea and that idea we
actually say instead of thinking there are so many things we have to register
we're thinking we invent one we called generalised i've been using this IP actually compact
loss of our bodies inside because they move together so we get the human to
generalize i
then a reasoning you may have tensile record if they move together we just need
that's why this generosity becomes quite useful
then you also have to think in this way
actually things and not moving in one way this keep splitting
actually in many cases they
keep merging and split in many different ways you think about this supposed in the
real case you think about this one suppose is the producer somewhere suppose in china
OK this one supposes big port like in shanghai so there are many many things
produce here different factories produce different things the ship bound to this bigger pause the
bigger pillars financing ship to the biggest seaport
a lot of these different things packed into this ocean liner this alternative down to
here suppose loss and is in this list and then they keep distributing to different
OK you have march and then split
OK you may merge and split in many ways
for the RFID
how could you compress
OK what our claim is for example this ocean line you shipped millions or you
can even say i should hundreds of thousands of kinds of items from here here
how many ideas i need
actually what we do
her you is what you only need is what you just need one idea
go to register here shipping this ocean liner from the show had los and you
don't need that many things
and we also carry you you don't lose any information
another thing of course you can have
generalization this generalisation we call is lossy compression and if you have a particular features
because it is our shores OK
this is called the children for women for men to find shirt sure just go
to our our school to close it if you do this
you still can do a lot of reasoning but this kind of thing do this
reasoning the the interesting level of reasoning it is lossy compression basically you
well this it our you don't know whether it's jacket is sure
and another way to the lossy compression actually is
compress in the pattern along the perhaps
if you think about this case
if people
suppose manager or be only interest in this part
into the storm entering only interest in this part
you can compress all the transportation no matter from which distribution centre to which try
and finally getting to store that part can be compressed
but for transportation they can compare this part the can only watching this so of
course this is lossy compression if you trace particular jagger of milk how they go
wrong OK so there you have two
the campus
our model is this
you get into
the other part is similar to your typical data warehouse
you have to those different products different information different manufacturers of these is very similar
to the typical data warehouse
but the interesting thing you can see is
many things can be compressed as long as they
stay on well together if they stay on all together they can be compressed into
one GID
the only thing is your GID
may have hierarchies
what used your your whole movement or state
this one record if they share the same locations or one rec
for example you sinking those ocean liner OK this ocean liners may store millions of
things to find use one GID because the more exactly the same way
OK then here
you have hierarchy of your GI these
OK with this hierarchy of jedi you do not lose any piece of information because
this one jedi made many many such these of subject is finally getting to the
are five
so with this structure you actually can do most of data warehousing using much more
compress they but you do not lose information
so you can see
what you need for the for your schema our data warehouse design the only thing
is you can see
this is a very new part because you haven't yet these factors
otherwise all the others using his more or less like
no not too much data
you can play with it
but how do you get this you
OK are our was basically you scan data only once for your whole body scan
data once
you actually can construct all these map paper and you the state people
in a very systematic way
how to do it you can see this is your EPC called RFID
this is a tiny and time out this is your location or something this is
no information
and with this information what can once again this you can see if they share
the same location same time in time out this would become president one so that's
the reason you actually can go so they want to get all the jedi sort
it out
so that's the part we can say is very fast you can get this one
and with this
banned use your GID comparing two EPC this size is far far smaller
so the
you're you're you're dataset you try to play
it would be much smaller thing you can place
so another thing is you came name
your CID because the IP is under your control you actually can put a lot
of information into the IDE for example you can you can put your past information
tied they'll have to go back to track past you actually come in colonial past
into your GID
then a lot of information can do reasoning just grab idea and allow reasoning already
so that's why it's very efficient and it's quite possible
the essentially you can see that you is your apparent ninety plus you're unique IP
you use the structure you can check all the next to structures and checks over
the past as well
then there are many other ways to generalize for example you can generalize based on
the modular hierarchical structure and you can generalize with within the past
and that's the
paper what you need needed just information tables
which register
the jedi with different attributes like whether this is the shared with others for four
woman with the size of a witch who is producing it
the information is your information table but you have to stay table justice
two new g end there is a hollow almost a all the book
the map favoritism nested structure what you really need to just these three major papers
you can construct a data warehouse to do the money in very systematic way
but anyway
but i'm going to do now is
stop that one you could quite easily write it yourself
i mean if they just
using all the framework that we introduced in the previous section
and now find
i guess one of the key points departure from
what you would find it useful to take care
but there are people are usually referred to estimate the proper function
there are interested in estimating p of its franchise on the
and they want to make something
that is fairly well established in local
and the
key difficulty in this context what compute the function g
twelve songs
fourteen collection
all my
all the
with the
specific some measure
maybe some of the go
o thing
how much statistical physics book
this function is referred to as they
are actually love this
there are one hundred one different ways how you would actually going to compute this
useful things with it
seems a little bit of what you can
first of all trying to do with
consider the light into so effectively
i will take a slightly two
this is well known well studied
well we can actually also have the following thing we can try to estimate conditional
if you want to get
parameterized by theta
well to write this
in the same way as in
politics and why would they want
do you think now
and where the
do they
given by the integral of my otherwise
on why
so that's the way we depart from
standard statistics textbooks
and what's the reason why you might want to do this
well this domain can be really nasty to integrate over
can be expensive
he might not want to do this
is that the main can be considerably smaller
for for binary classification
why will just take on values one minus one so apples and oranges say
for regression while
you might have why being on the real line
however it could be that well this distribution he has a particularly nice form like
it's normal distribution and so on
so we get
so all this in more detail as we go along
i just want to give you a little bit of an idea of where this
is going to go to
so depending on how we set this up will recover a lot of
what people typically recall supervised learning problems
or sometimes people talk about as discriminative learning
and i mean it's actually pretty simple reason why this might be a good idea
so if you want to
distinguish between cats and dogs i mean
i imagine that each of us in the room will be able to to look
at apart from the dog
if i wanted to ask who of us can actually draw cats and dogs in
such a way that they look like cats and dogs while i
what at least that i don't know how to do it really well
and for most of you and other
building a generative model of cats and dogs
it's really hard
building a discriminative model of cats and dogs can actually be pretty easy
for instance we don't need to know the entire distribution of those axis which might
be pictures of cats and dogs but just look at some discriminative features of it
for instance one discriminative feature will be the whiskers
the beast has whiskers probably a cat otherwise it's all
so of course just that by itself doesn't make a good model of a cat
or dog but it's a pretty good discriminative one
so you can already see that you may have to estimate may need to estimate
only something considerably simpler
and that you know why want out to do
if the wise
plus minus one
and we get binary classification
if the wise
and the set from one
we get multiclass
if the wiser say
in our
the market regulation
of some sort
the wise for instance
in theory
we have have to measure one or
why factorial the negative class or regression
there's another thing that i could have namely that the y sample of structure
this was what little lead us to graphical models
that's actually quite the powerful connection
good will allow us to
find reasonably nonparametric
representations of a graphical model quite easily
so in this case the whites could be
going from sequences of plus minus ones to the in
but with the structure
and i'll talk about dependence independence and all that a little bit later
but that's a little bit the program of what we're going to look at
and probably since my commitment is still stuck in a snowstorm
also on wednesday
OK so little depend on how bad the snowstorm in north america is how much
you'll see if the grafted models
OK good
they get are
all right my
you can't
what is about
a lot
o five
how does one
number here
his last
then what it would be
if i let those two hydrogen atom wavefunctions destructively interfere
and they have the key
in this chemical plant
is this right here in this term
that makes all the difference this is our constructive interference causes the
extra density
because those two wavefunctions constructively interfere
what is this pile up of what lecture
electron density right in the centre
it is the cool in this chemical bonds
they make sense
all right
we are now a molecular weight function
by the linear combination of atomic weight function
now what happens to the energy when we do that
i i mean what happens to the energy the energy goes down
we're going to form a new molecular state
let's draw an energy level diagram
all right so energy going up here
and let me represented here by these two lines energy levels
these separated hydrogen atoms
so i'm going to call this one as the enemy
the one st and and the
the the same energy
i can tell them apart
and each one of them has an electron
once we
those two wavefunctions to constructively interfere
we're going to produce a new state
we're going to call their state
sigma one as
and that state is going to be lower in energy here
the and
that's too
from the individual hydrogen
and that's good because it's lowering energy we got a hydrogen atom stuck together
right we want chemical bonds two hydrogen atoms are why are want do
thank you
and therefore do two electrons here
one from each hydrogen atom are sitting down the molecular state
we are calling sigma one
the weight function then that describes the electron mass
sigma one molecular weight function
that's right
everything looks school
these away
so not only in ways
destructively interfere
they destructively interfere too
right think here there is now
the case of the structure of atoms
well what's the
right in this case
what's going to happen well
everyone has a weight function
and i want
the weight function
and now
what i'm going to bring these two together
the equilibrium
but i'm going to be
what's going to happen is in destructive interference
this weight function
it's going to cancel this part of the wave function
when these overlap
and i take the minus sign here
or i'm superimposing two wave functions with different sign
it had destructive interference and the result is
at the molecular weight function
that kind of look like
like this
right in the centre here hey there's going to be you know
there's no old
this part of the weight function exactly cancel this part of the wave function they
there's no way function right here
right we have destructive interference
powergen label this function
well we're all going to call it a signal wave function and sigma that symmetry
cylindrically symmetric around the bond axis
but because
it is a
linear combination
is a consequence of these structures here i'm going to call this big star
i think most are one and
and i'm going to call that sigma star what has happened and tight bonding orbital
four antibonding
how do i know there well
let's also calculate the probability density
here for sigma one at a time you that's going to be to be interesting
so we got the probability density sigma one garden
OK so i am
now one as a minus one as
times one as a minus
one as
multiply that out
so i get one as a
one these square plus one SB
twenty square minus two times one
times one as he he
now going by
in my career here think
this is what i wanted write on my
graph of the probability density
when i do that well OK
way out here
right on one end of the molecule probability is pretty low
probability density goes to maximum right at the nucleus
and then sure deployment right and right at the centre here
right at the centre here the probability density is zero because the function zero
because we had destructive interference
OK i want you to notice something
probability density here is zero
it is even lower
then in this case
in this case
which is just
on new data so this is what we would think of as a generalization
so the first point here is just that example i gave
if it was classifications of this loss function is one of the two outputs disagree
and zero otherwise
well for regression it could be the square of the difference between
the application of the function to the input and the true
you know if it's regression we can't say
you know a lot of one event article
because they're always going to be some error but is no need to measure the
difference between the two
so this
random variable
defined appropriately for whatever task we're trying to solve is a measure of generalisation of
the learner
and that's what we'd like to understand and control
well i'm just going to go into
this talk is trying to give you a sort of feel for these things and
you know intuition behind what's going on
so i'm not going to go into details of the kind of analysis at all
but in the case of classification the critical method for doing controlling generalisation
is to force a large margin on the training data so here's your positive the
negative margin is if you want to hear somehow got lost in the transcription sure
they went to but anyway
when you pick a line that separates these two
there are many lines you could pick up line like this like this
now the large margin
criterion says pick the line that has the furthest distance
between the line and the nearest points on either side so here's the two negative
points and here's the positive point nearest to the hyperplane
this hyperplanes been chosen so that this these distances are maximal
so that's the sort of method know why
why is that going to work well
these are intuitive explanations that you can
and they're all different but they all say the same thing so you could say
that the
in fact we kept the hyperplane away from the examples makes classification robust to uncertainties
in the inputs you mentioned we call the inputs of some sort of distribution of
things that might happen around those points they're still going to be correctly classified because
this nice but
so that's sort of intuitive
o thing you can do is another way of thinking about it which is two
randomly project into low dimensional spaces and if you do random projections things don't actually
change their inner products that much
so if you've got this nice margin even after you've done this random projection they're
still going to be
with high probability but separation
you you've effectively got separation in the low dimensional space
is random projection space
and so
we know that a low dimensional space there is low capacity by the previous theorem
that i mentioned so you know although you high dimensional space the fact that you've
got a large margin means you actually
effectively work in a low dimensional space
and again you can apply rigorous statistical analysis shows effective dimension
it is one of the gamma squared when gamma
is this margin quantity
so you know here is exactly what i was alluding to before when i said
you know you want this neither
but you can
control your capacity with
OK the lever is the marginal OK so what we're saying is if we can
keep the margin big
they're effectively controlling
the capacity
although we working on this very high dimensional space
capacity potentially at our disposal was very high
like sort of cranking up the sleeve we're keeping it under control
this is you know sort of
a different way of controlling capacity than just specifying the space
we see entropy
OK so
so if we had an example in the function
you can work out what's the loss function on the examples of the same quantity
that we used to call that we also called XII
the other cases this quantity can be zero one
likewise if you have a whole sample of points
you get a whole set of of loss vectors which are zero one vectors of
the corners of the hypercube m dimensional hypercube
a fixed set of functions one
a set of training points
we get some numbers
of such output vectors
the VC entropy is then defined as the expectation of the logarithm of the twenty
news expectation taking over
drawing many
training sets so you can for typical training set how many possible predictors can generate
how many possible
the logarithm of the vectors cannot generate so over the number of was not vectors
this quantity is called the VC entropy
and it turns out
one can
so i said before the uniform convergence of risk is what we are interested in
terms of the uniform convergence of risk takes place if and only if
the VC entropy
some the states sublinearly with number of
training observations
so this is this is something that depends on the underlying distribution
we have this expectation of the distribution here which is nice takes into account the
problem but is that since we don't know the distribution
we want to we don't know the distribution and that's why i want to be
keywords with is dimension which is possible for all which is south of on possible
distributions in this sense worst case theory
but this was case because we don't know beforehand
we can see because could imagine things in between
any more
this is a
this is
so the question is to assume that the data distribution is the same training and
test sets the answer is emphatically yes
if the data distribution is different between training and test set
things can go up the the tree right
so now it's interesting question to think of the interesting cases in between
four in a
what if they did this because i'm not saying but they have something in common
from the point is what the
distribution over x
is different but the distribution of y given x the conditional distribution is the same
one would be tempted to think
in this case
we should still be fine but actually it's it's more complicated even in this case
a lot of things can go wrong so let's call could very cheap so it
so the answer if there's a general change have some p of x and y
in the twenty k some of p of x and y in test case can
go up the tree wrong but it's interesting problem to think about
how much change in the law and can we still say something and this very
little research that almost none so
it's interesting topic
and so there are two questions here i don't know was first
so actually it's a little bit more complicated i was glossing over some details and
it's even
so it took if you want to get the equivalence between uniform convergence and consistency
so if you want uniform convergence as the replacement of consistency then you have to
use some
slightly strange notion of consistency with the dominican school nontrivial consistency in which
it took them
twenty years to come up with this is this part of the learning theories was
only published in the late eighties
efficiency should say maybe not not everybody is happy with this definition of nontrivial consistency
you could you could even say sensitive it's definition which is
made such that these two quantities of these two things become equivalent
it's something like that
you have to remove
those functions from the class
then you have some from the class which are uniformly better than all the rest
then this can screw up so if you had one function which is so clearly
better than everything else that you can already be identified from the first training point
that you see
then becomes
this is a second get this equivalence anymore so is this a little bit difficult
to answer but i just want to point out
it's interesting to to look into the same thing to look at this notion of
nontrivial consistency which requires that even after removing the best functions
this fraction of functions in this has to work both fractions you still want to
be consistent afterwards letters from the condition than the usual consistency
over here
OK so the question is why we're symmetrisation
important in the proof so the symmetrisation
i was replacing
symmetrisation was replacing
this difference
this one or upper bounding in terms of something like this one
the nice thing about the right hand side is
here we have in here so this refers to m points in training points you
want this is another set of training points of function class
o functions take values outputs plus or minus one
so if we only have twelve points
and the outputs of plus or minus one there only two to the two m
possible output vector is that the functions can generate
so even if we have infinitely many functions
it's enough
if we instead
consider sets of functions that have size at most two to the pol two
everything that happens way
these two sets of points that
going to hear it doesn't matter for us so it's kind of factorisation of an
infinite class of functions
into equivalence classes
and only two to the path to an equivalence classes and it's a good question
because in the sense that the the central idea of all of learning theory
i want to do is use that data to tell
weighted sum of basis functions or
other estimator
how to behave
in between
sample points
we do this through a method which is generally known as regularisation
statisticians tend to refer to as penalisation
OK but they both mean the same thing
what we do is place the penalty cost on the roughness of use the
quotation marks because
the number ways of
defining what we mean by
so if we place a penalty on that typically will just simply add it
the cost function that we're trying to work with in the first place
as an example if we look at some squares are so we're looking doing the
least squares fit
the first term there just the the ordinary selves squares and we seek to minimize
by choosing a set of weights
by some method
and we have to that rose just some
nonnegative constant
times q
o where q is a
it's something stands in for how rough the function is
and then instead of minimizing just the mean squared error of the sum of squares
error we minimize that entire thing
and that gives a bit of control
what about when q is for the
because rho than if it is zero
basically brings us back to original problem and says OK just minimize the sum of
squares can be the basically square solution
if i make row
very large it says
give me
very very smooth
fit to the data
so basically it you're you're making the smoothness of the problem that is
try to minimize the roughness
the major component of your optimisation
as of course
again a good engineer what i'm looking for is the trade-off
which tells me
i get an acceptable level of fit to the data
with the smoothest
a function that i can get away with
so the strategy i take a very flexible
structure a lot of
radial basis functions with
quite narrow
which is for instance
nasty rough thing that is capable of doing all sorts of weird things
and then
rho here to choose
how flexible i let the final
so what we want is something that is very
simple here
and nice
to deal with
a good measure of roughness or something very strongly associated with roughness of the
one of the function is it's second derivative with respect to the
so the argument to the x's
because that's the curvature
the functions areas of high curvature
are areas which are doing this kind of
that's a nice thing to use and you can use it formally it's what ultimately
leads to
pspline fits
OK that's where it all comes from
the optimal choice
to minimize
sum of squares error and
a measure of curvature
penalize curvature
they just to explain it but i'm going to talk about that
what happens then is you get rather complex
the solution to the optimisation problem
there are number of other possibilities but one choice which is very very nice and
leads to a very very simple solution
is this one we like you just equal to the sum of the squares of
all the weights
in our estimator
i've used the double
index because
sometimes we have multiple layers of things to come after that
anyway just think about the sum of the squares of all the weights in the
the estimator we
do that it turns out in this linear in the parameters case
OK that we just have very simple modifications to
OK we have w hat
now the estimated set the weight is equal to phi transpose phi
plus times the identity matrix was phi transposed times that
pretty much the same as we had before
and when rho is equal to zero of course we get
the same answer i should say inverse there sorry
sorry is an inverse missing
so what we are doing what is the advantage the the advantage is that we
are reducing the number of the compositions
and number of times when become aware of
ideas ideas of documents
OK so we can use this list
so we
we discussed in this construction yesterday about
this structure
seems to be
october so how we can be because
there are some pointers and it's not clear
when we talked about compression everything seems very straightforward we are taking one number next
number in it and
in the end encoding sigma delta between this numbers repeating this separation is
a more complex structure
so the same
what do you have put into some key way the temporary very well and we
need to keep in memory so her
four out input information
so at the beginning of asking for a zero we don't know what you of
and they put into temporary buffer
is that
but this possible
when this buffer
for the next number to keep for while
four to skip way and output it to the hour
five or what what what what they're going to be
this place
fourteen of of course posting list
then after this is right temporary buffer
clean repeat this separation
so it's is pretty simple
to create a a portal is keep
there's only one problem that the during according need this temporary buffer ski way
i want to
one hundred percent it also in use such structure
and you can see it
not a lot of some number of research papers
this structure called two
two of this keep harmonies keeps in a
but usually it is also the simplest approach is to
for this particular posting lists
the size of these temporary buffer because size of these jumps around school where root
from the length of the postings lists and usually it works pretty well
another approach toward
ski please
it is
is very simple we talked about block compression and i said that block compression could
extremely effective
and football competitions can
but we can
look at the block compression
and as an implementation of its key players
because we have blocked what we can do remember interpolated
according to its always number and delta
so imagine that you are looking for i don't know what thing number
two hundred
so without looking at first block
and we're looking that his block stars from five
and delta length of this block the
the difference between smallest IDM biggest estate is one hundred thirty four
so it means that the last posting in this in this block
is one hundred fifty six thirty nine so it's less than two hundred
we don't need to incorporate something from his blog
they can simply jump over this block start looking at the next block
and for an example of feel stupid be
one thirty nine plus eleven so it
current sixty and we we can see that
is supposed to be somewhere in this block and begin to compress it and look
these two on a
block according
it's automatic skip lists
and also it
very high
compression ratio as i said
only one disadvantage that is pretty small
if we need to decompress we always take it always takes a lot of time
therefore it's not very and also it's very complex
therefore it is not very common algorithmic implementation of inverted file
another another situation is really is implementation of inverted index over the tree
the is very good
structure was keeping
we all the also dividing our policies listening to number of blocks
and more than that in
the treaty
we can do not simply keep or one block
b because their order it and we can do so much
one assertion this knowledge
we can do
much faster much faster because we can keep and also told
from from the root note start positions in every in every node
and and we can do along this keeps
there is
not that article
conference three w from to solve all
three i believe that people implemented
so much of our the trees and they call this very simple and they keep
not do during marriage ended airing during
building of results they called it exact choice because this keeping doing this
john's in the tree
to plants and bacteria
leaves of this tree
so this is an example of another automatic skip lists
and if you
are good programmer and the creator good implementations
of these
o thing
you can achieve pretty good performance
but the stu
very unlikely
in this situation where you have
query this every is
a very popular before
you cannot keep anything
because all you need in a case you need to comparable to position
imagine that we also like that we have query
for example zero one five
and a lot of documents can contain such
number far
and all of these numbers
this huge force base
how we can improve speed
in this case
it can be improved using some skip police or something else
because we need to check relative position
the only one solution is to a
help us during
building of the index
we can
do this intersection of post lists in advance
now basically
and the such interesting bayesian stats and as such a model
although on the bottom interested basically
the failure rate on that one too long that ten on the additional
i feel parameter beta
for the bayesian point of view it means that what i'm interested in interest in
the posterior distribution on on that one too long that ten
beattie given basically the observation time on the number of fellows
so it's very simple or is proportional simply
two disperse percent solution is proportional to the point
on the playoff for all
gamma distribution for each parameter
even beta
OK so this is why those terms coming from the gamma pi all these things
coming basically
the apply on the top on this is essentially the like to tell corresponding to
my question assumption so i'm interested in is the solution OK is six really simple
models on still have no clue essentially to approximate
in doing like deterministic approximation you would really accelerometer with the pain
OK when you try to do addiction something you need to come up with a
kind of like probability distribution on what to do about them is too high dimensional
to kind of the public distribution
it's appeal because essentially these bodies but this essentially this column seems to have a
lot of structure
in particular
o xo the joint distribution of lambda beta units allegations quite complicated
the some expose some conditional distribution of a much simpler form so if you look
at the conditional
distribution of the parliament along that given south asia
well by using element articulation and you see that this thing factorizes according of gamma
distribution is quite simple
similarly if you look at the conditional distribution
peter argue end up salvation on the parliament along this thing is seen before
gamma distribution well so the joint distribution is the nightmare
but the conditional distribution of the get along that you beta beta you quite simple
what you propose going to try to look get the is which is called actually
a gibbs sampler we try to justify later on so and so what i'm proposing
so as to approximate the posterior distribution of blonde on beta given the salvation is
the following iterative algorithm
on is known in the literature the gibbs sampler so that the algorithm is to
be like rejection sampling OK i'm not going to go until late on to have
sample exactly is going to percent
it's an iterative algorithm repositories follows so similar iteration i
you have a set of parliament
these are the current value of the parliament along the on the current value of
on what you're proposing to do at iteration i plus one of your iterative algorithm
is that conditional upon the current value of beta
use on paul
the parameter lambda according to the conditional distribution
this is the part of the gamma distribution OK
on once you basically
when you realize values for the parameters
you data basically
beta apartment to be done by sampling it for according to its conditional distribution given
the current value of lambda on the observation OK so that i know because the
conditional distribution of mary's
so that's good so i this kind of algorithms
we basically instead of going to knowledge in this area and emotional space i just
need to solve for c paul essentially is won the valuable distributed according to start
gamma i can do that using matlab say OK
so you can do that
OK on you could also they thing formerly on this question is basically where
you do have to sample from this conditional distribution
i think is going to give you basically sold for approximately distributed according to the
joint distribution of interest it seems like it's a computer stick for the time being
on the fifth basically the chase you basically is iterative algorithm converged in some sense
conditioning on an impossibilities less the technical
condition here
also x is independent of y given v if the probability of x and y
given the
factors into the probability of x given b
and the probability of y given p
so in general we can think of conditional independence between sets of variables
so users are currently notation for sex sets
x is independent of y given v
it is the sort of factorizations
marginal independence the sort of
usual for independence that
you know we first learn about is just independence with conditioning on the empty set
OK so x is independent of y
it the same as conditional independence given nothing and that just means that the joint
distribution of x and y factors vision of x times the distribution of y
OK so why conditional independence important why is marginal independence important well it tells us
what things depend on what other things and what things we can ignore
and part of doing things efficiently is being able to ignore as many things as
so conditional independence
happens in all sorts of
nice intuitive places and i want to highlight
conditional independence
as opposed to marginal independence
so let's look at some of these examples
so the amount of speeding fine
is conditionally independent from the type of car that you're driving given the speed that
you're caught driving OK
so if you're driving if there are any at fifty six miles per hour you
should get the same speeding fine as if you're driving a fiat fifty six miles
per hour
of course
this is a good example thinking about marginal independence if you just randomly went out
and measured speeding fines
and you
measured types of cars the people were driving you would not find these things are
independent right ferrari drivers will get bigger speeding fines than feel drivers
again a classic example is for example smoking
tends to make people's teeth yellow and is associated with lung cancer but
lung cancer and yellow teeth are conditionally independent given y
if you know whether somebody is a smoker or not
now these are sort of classic things but you can imagine conditional independence being used
in all sorts of other settings where maybe you're sort of doing something like robotics
or tracking OK so it's you're modelling the dynamics of the system and you measure
the position and velocity and acceleration of the system over time
and you draw out model
and then you could say well the state of the system the position and velocity
at time t plus one is actually independent of the position and velocity at t
minus one given the state the position and velocity at time t and the acceleration
at time t
you could be doing
genetic pedigree analysis and looking at children's genes
parents genes their grandparents genes and then you would want to use the conditional independence
structure to be able to infer you know the genotype of a particular individual given
their ancestry
and in the nice example the chris showed
if we have two teams of players playing against each other
maybe have three or priority
their abilities are independent but conditioned on the outcome of the game a versus b
the ability of team and the ability of team b become
conditionally dependent so knowledge of the outcome informs us of
both of these things in there
depend on each other
any questions about that yet
what we condition and what they want stay in
o belief five was
but but but the question is it amount of speeding car
doesn't depend on the type of of sorry amount of speeding fine doesn't depend on
type of car
you when you say that you have to say under what assumptions
OK so what you know about
what you know about the situation if you know that
if you know the speed it doesn't depend but if you just go and measure
these things
then there is the dependency you can plot the dependencies between the two
so all
notions of dependence and independence are really conditioned on the state of knowledge
in some ways of these are representations of state of knowledge not representations of necessarily
physical things out there OK and
things can become dependent once you know something else
so let me start talking about factor graphs again you've heard about this from chris
i'm going to go pretty quickly hopefully
you have two types of nodes
in a factor graph
the circles in a factor graph represent random variables the squares are filled dots represent
factors in the joint distribution
so here are two different factor graphs over five variables a b c d and
e and factor graph eighty represents
this factorisation of the joint distribution
so for example g one is the factor
that relates a and c
g two relates b c and d in g three relate c d and e
this thing at the beginning here is just a normalizing constant
what we have here is the probability distribution over these five quantities if we sum
or integrate over all the variables it has two summer integrate to one so we
need a normalising constant to make sure that when we multiply the factors together and
we some out some to one as well
what are the factors the factors are functions of their arguments OK
so if ANC are binary variables
this factor is a two by two tables
so two by two table
with nonnegative entries
we don't want negative probabilities otherwise nothing makes much sense k but we can allow
the factors to have any nonnegative number in because then we have a normalizing constant
that ensures the thing sum to one
this factor graph represents this factorizations
the factor graph b represents this factorizations
and i think i've said all of these things
has a roof you just need to move around so that is the right
place so that's what i call energy-based learning and and
yeah ok probably sick a this this emission is kind of
so special case of this if you want you can sort of the formulated
in those terms but but those this technique includes things are
not probabilistic in nature and general
tso can seven different methods to
strategies to shape the energy function
in the right way in such a way that data points lower energy than
things outside the manifold of high this tendency to essentially
the first one is to build machines such a way that the volume
of low energy stuff is constant so basically the same normalized
distribution ok so the energy function did negative log
probabilities synonymized distribution this finite fixed volume
of stuff they can have low energy because the distribution is
normalized but there are other non obviously models have this property
pch or k-means or yes mixture models or square here stuff that
the second strategy is to push down the energy of data points push
up everywhere else so that's basically what maximum-likelihood
does when your function has an explicit normalised are when when
you're so you probably just vision if you density estimation
as an explicit normalization
and that doesn't quite work all the time because it's possible that
the the this normalization on the partition function would be intractable
or gradient with the intractable and so
a lot of situations we can really do this is a lot papers in
machine learning community increase by people in this room
that have to do with how do you kind of make approximations of this
that it's to works by some approximations something whatever
for method push on the energy of data points push up on chosen
locations sometimes close to the point so you know living outside
so things like contrastive divergence ratio matching noise contrastive
estimation you know every time as this this slide people to pictures
of it and you know i should probably this paper some point
so as other other methods this site so protest divergence is you
take a point and then you would be away from it preferentially in
directions where the energy goes down
and then you push up on that point and what does that creates
local groove in the energy surface it doesn't trying to shape
the energy surface far away from data but you know
as problem number for our you might gradient maximize the curvature
around data point this what's called score matching
that's actually pretty much practical complex models
fifth method you train a dynamical system so that danny's
goes the manifold this you know you know you could was very popular
around 'trial but
you know and beyond
but talk much about this this much everyone so if we use regular
as and this is your everyone to by the way
for most of you least even if you don't know
which is to use regular as that limits the volume of space that has
low energy and that includes things like dictionary learning for
sparse coding so dictionary for costs sparse coding essentially
you could think of the sparsity term as when you do dictionary learning
as a way of limiting the volume of space that can be properly constructed
ok and if you use the reconstruction error as the energy
function then that means you can create the move that with the
volume around data points that manifold or through the
training one to talk that ok so pc ok so if you which are points
drawn from this spiral to pc with one dimension you get this is
a terrible approximation but if you have some you know the energy
function is zero on the black and sort of increases increases with
intensity here to easy you'll k-means if you train
with little quadratic welds are all around this the surface
seems that it's great except doesn't scalar in high dimension
and so this this is just getting sparse coding
sparse modeling india a when you when you learn dictionary learning
is you have an energy function this type where you have the square
reconstruction error where y is observation
then you is dictionary matrix z is sparse vector
which by when you multiply but dictionary matrix is meant to reconstruct
the input or his approximately with a square penalty function and
then you have this sparsity term so elector represent this as
kind of funny type factor graph where those are variables or this
one is observed this one is latent has to be inferred
and then you have deterministic functions that those symbols those
factors which are kind of times in the energy function or enter additively
in the energy function or multiplicatively in the likelihood
function if you take exponentials so the problem with
sparse coding is that even once you've learned
dictionary inference is relatively expensive
is also efficient algorithms we heard about one this morning in the
first talk cht is is fista whatever according to descend is
all kinds of efficient algorithms for this but this just
so if you want to do sparse coding with four thousand dimension
on a window in images going to take a few seconds
and tricks autres and you have with to do this approximately as
fast but but you know it's it's going expensive
now sparse coding essentially makes assumption that data is sort
of union of planes for the energy function really has
a kind of linear grooves of rule relatively low dimension and
then you can add them up and you get this sort of
approximation of the of the data so so one thing that we cannot
with back two thousand eight or seven well as to
learn quick approximations of sparse coding inference so instead
of learning ista our d you see here i ratio whatever our
we're going to train yeah what amounts to no net essentially to
produce a good approximation of the
ultimate solution sparse coding inference problem
and so that these are what's called sparse but encoder so you
have the top is just getting are the same
the same as i to originally this thing at the bottom here which
is a non not parameterised function
which predicts try to predict what the optimal code is for particular
why ok so you can white you find z that
x one x is zero you find the potential to zero
and when x is
one centimeter
you find the potential to be thousand volts
and that then
goes together with the electric field
equals minus
and the this
in this direction
it is extremely physical
this is something that you would have whenever we deal
with parallel plates
as long as
there is no charge moving
and we're dealing with
solid conductors
so we have static
electric fields
charges are not heavily moving
in the field inside the a conductor
is always zero
not the case
in non conducted only in the conductor because conductors have free electrons move
and if these free electrons seeing electric fields inside which they
they start to move until they
experience no longer force thereby they kill the electric field inside
so the charge the conductor always rearranges itself
so that the electric field becomes zero
if the field is static field not rapidly changing
so now
i want to evaluate with you
the situation
that i'm going to charge a solid
and i asked myself the question where the charge
in honor of
valentine's day
let's take a solid hard
it's all all the way throughout
this is a solid conductor
and i bring on this conductor chart from the outside
the bottom line is not just a plus for now
so the question that i'm asking you know
this is the conductor this is not an insulated the story for insulators is totally
it has three moving electrons inside
i'm asking you know if i touch this
conducting hard
by the way you are very good conductors
if you touch this conducting hard where with discharge
and up
where we go to
and i leave you with three choices
i have vote on that
the first choices that the charges were uniformly distributed for throughout
the possibility
the second possibility
slightly i think
that all the charge go to one place there
i don't know which place that would be maybe
and then the third possibility is that maybe the charge
uniformly distributed itself
only on the outer surface
and then the fourth possibilities
none of the above
all the suggestions i made were wrong
i i think that the charge
might uniformly distributed throughout the conductor
i see one two hands
that's good don't feel ashamed
raise your hands in the worst case you're wrong i have been so many times
wrong when it comes
don't feel bad about that
who thinks that the charge will go to one point in the hard
you have the courage to think about one point charge repel it's alright that doesn't
seem likely with things that will uniformly distributed itself on the outer surface
o things none of the above
very good well
those who suggested that it might be uniform on the outside i would still give
them abu
but is not uniform as you will see
but i will go
to the outside and i will prove that now to you
the first
look for that ridiculous possibility that the charge would somehow end up
in the conductive itself
i think here
gulshan surface which is a closed surface
i know inside the conductor we electrostatic fields
not fast moving charges but it's static field i know that field everywhere must be
zero on the surface
this is closed surface so the integral of adopt a
equation one is zero that means the charge inside my
sphere is zero
and so there cannot be in charge
so gauss law immediately kills the possibility that there would be any charge
this conductor so that's out of the question
at least you only was one choice that is on at the surface
charge must be
at the surface
and later in the later lecture i will
discuss with you
the details
why that charge is not uniformly distributed it would be uniformly distributed the surface it
is more here
if it has this funny shape but it will at the surface
i'm going to make this heart
very special heart
more like a real hard
is open here
one of the solid here
this is a conducting heart muscle
and here open there's nothing you
and again i'm going to charge
bring charges on the outside
it's obvious that we don't expect that there is any chance it will be
inside the conductor that clear the same argument holds with the gauss law argument
but now
is it perhaps possible
that some of the positive charge
will go on the inside
of the surface and some on the outside
o things that maybe some will now
go on the inside because now the situation is different right there is no
now the whole conduct
anyone in favor of some of the charge maybe
going on the inside
one hand two hands
who says no it's not possible montgomery inside the building outside
for most of you are very careful now you don't vote anymore
it cannot go to the inside why can not go to the inside
let this be my girl so
closed surface think of the three-dimensional
everywhere on that line the electric field is zero because you're inside the conductor
so the surface integral is also zero
gauss law says there cannot be any charge inside
that box
again the charge has to go
to the outer surface and nothing will go
to the
in a surface
and so the conclusion then is
that the electric field is zero in the conductor with the electric field is also
zero in his opening there's never any charges there
and so the whole heart including the cavity
is a potential there's never any electric field anywhere the only electric fields outside
the heart
and there are field lines
and these field lines
are perpendicular to the surface of the heart
because the heart
the equipotential
you get very funny field lines
go like this
have to be perpendicular locally where
this is it's kind of like magic but it's it's pretty cool so
let's go back to the old equations that we that we that we had before
so here with the lucas kanade i had this forward additive idea so i've got
my source image my delta p is where of following want to be this is
this is like where the actual line image is going to be
of course got the actual
my current guess
o vary in size from the open sea face detector not really sure
and then i apply the chain to get this to protein drug
but with the forward compositional
what i instead of
i want to essentially
it's like this
and this image and this image should be exactly the same thing but how why
estimate the what a different my delta p here
will be different for delta b here because i am essentially of got my coordinates
what by delta p and then those coordinates i award by
so it's actually composed
what i what i then do is about the original source image and this is
the magic pot so this is why i was so
i was pointing out that the nominator here about the gradient so here
what we're doing is we're estimating gradients from the source image
and and then we'll warping the x and y gradients
to get this so we so we have to estimate the gradients in the source
image first and then will be to the to get this these image gradients
here what i did because i'm actually doing this with respect to
not p one to p has been removed
i will
p of what the source image for p tackling the gradients on that will damage
and this is this is what this is indicated here
that i'm not doing it from p of doing it what he has been removed
because because this is zero this anymore and then apply the exact same will
to be completely correct the jacobian differently but because the
my what constraints typically linear
it doesn't matter what my peers here
this this is essentially a matrix in ways that the society but this point before
we calculate the delta p
this is just the kind of like this is kind of a MAP here about
just the kind of explaining what's going on
this image on doing the exact same approximation this image and this image should be
exactly the same
my delta p here delta p
now this is just the forward so
computationally not getting any benefit here at all
this and again the actual operation of and i always always keeping so this is
that this is the paper put forward by harry shum image with the last thing
and what around the show was essentially you've before compositional output
you again the hessian but this is the forward compose hessian the jacobian which is
the four composed jacobian and the only difference is that i'm taking the gradients one
siemens has been what from p instead of taking the gradient at p then
and then of got the image differences i get my current delta p update and
because i'm working at the delta p for composers wall rather than an added what
i have to oppose
so i have that IP not by adding delta p
composing p with this delta p
and this is my car
and i keep on applying these steps until p convergence again
this is so
can see j ford compositional
is taken with respect to zero not p
and looks at all but it's really important
and so
in this composition this is this is called the core
so four compositions still essentially have really boring thing here it's got it's kind of
nice in the sense that i might be able to save some slight computations on
if gradients cost me more than tackling the gradient across the entire image cost more
than k great small area
excuse me i might be able to buy mister something but i still going to
do some extra walls as opposed to the other one way i you have to
do the one more
has only brought me anything computationally
if we assume the template is not static we can invert our problem using approximation
so let's now invert so let's say that all i want to actually approximate my
car poorly positioned image so so so so the image that badly position that are
there are no
of the template which is which is the image which is the temple trying to
match with and lines instead take gradients
of the tenth not of the source image
and because the implied i know is in the ground truth that always with respect
this zero to so there's no p there at all
and of course to cope
and so basically this the inverse compositional approach the big advantage here
it's essentially i only have to like this
and this
and i can actually precomputed
i don't have to compute at runtime
so the big advantage is that instead of having two i image gradients b
immediately hard
apparent why should be hard to say
there are here two reasons why you might be interested normalising constants
one is
the probability of data
given the model is that the marginal likelihood of the evidence for the model
this is an integral it's an expectation you average parameters of your models drawn from
the prior you average under that distribution
and you just a each those parameters drawn from my prior how probable if the
data to happen
so it looks as though there is an obvious simple
monte carlo solution to it you just draw parameters from your prior and you evaluate
how probable that data was under each of those in your average
and that's actually a terrible algorithm for most data modeling applications because
you've just written down a bit complicated probabilistic model and you often quite vague priors
on lots of things that you don't know
and as soon as you see a bit of data you some learn an awful
lot about the parameters
i mean if you doing something as simple as regression as soon as you see
about three points you know there's whole
load possible slopes if your line pretty invisible and if you have more flexible model
and that then
different bits of your data we'll pin down different parameters in different ways but the
result is that if you just draw random model
and draw data not gonna look anything like the data that you actually have a
what's going to happen if you do the simple monte carlo algorithm is that almost
all of the parameters you draw will be complete junk this will be about zero
and then if eventually my draw sensible fitting the parameters and that one sample would
completely dominate your estimate for the bad algorithm for estimating the article
another reason you might want normalizing constant is to find the normalizing constant of an
undirected graphical model
so a johansen next week we'll talk a lot about various undirected graphical models
even explained you have some
function you can evaluate that the product potentials and then there's the normalizing constant which
is the sum of all the unnormalized probabilities now
z the normalising constant can sometimes be very useful for model comparison and various other
tasks but it's a very large sum
the unnormalized functions defined by an undirected graph
now if you fitted this graph to data
you've made it so that
along the finns skinny weird manifold that looks like a reasonable dataset in your world
the probability the high and everywhere else in the exponentially huge state space where
things just look like junk and like reasonable data the probability is very likely so
this something is completely dominated by the skin the manifold which can be quite hard
to find a new not confined by very simple sample
personally i'm actually more interested in
the bayesian application i'm going to use this undirected graphical model
example is the running example for computing that because i can draw i can very
easily draw some pretty pictures for again
talk about just computing this one scalar
that will normalize the distribution is you've defined up to a constant
say a
to motivate his a benchmark application of why you'd want to compute that i've got
a probabilistic model which is the boltzmann machine which is the model of binary images
so the toy vision applications at this stage and
restricted boltzmann machine defines the probability that images up to constant and i don't know
and what i want to do is compare this probabilistic model to other models i
want to say is this model here actually better than something standard like a simple
mixture model which looks worse but maybe this model is just a fitted
it's actually better probabilistic models so i want to evaluate probabilities on the test and
actually this
evaluated things better on the test and say
if i have got complicated training procedures and i want to evaluate whether model is
a good idea
i want to be able to evaluate the probability to say yes this hasn't it's
actually about better probabilistic model
so how many going to
do this when
p started only going to be large the very small number of binary images that
look like digits and most of them
it's going to be very small
i certainly don't want to do it by importance sampling
from a simple distribution
if i sample
uniformly random binary images
they look like this
OK i get away to very very long time and for one of these looks
like integer
and so if i'm going to
evaluate the probability of each of these images under my model of digit and then
average all its probabilities together that's not going to
tell me anything meaningful about
some attempts actually matter because i'm never going to see any of the terms of
you might think that the the obvious thing to do is to just sample from
a different distribution one way you get the chance we know one of the things
we could sample from the model itself
now we can sample directly from the model because we only know it up to
a constant but we could run MCMC
you could imagine
let's sample
using gibbs sampling
from this probabilistic model of images and generate random images and this these are genuine
sample drawn from the model and they all look like this and they all have
high probability under this model
but this does actually help either
they might not z is the sum of the unnormalized probabilities over all images
and here i got some images that we know have high probability
so i can evaluate p start x these particular images
but what i need to know to know how big the sum is
is how many images like this
not i need to know
how how probable the problem images but i need to know how many of them
to approximate the sub and the samples don't tell me that
you think l but you you just important or something redistribution if you write down
the importance sampling estimator turns out to tell you actually need to know that say
it it doesn't actually help you with that that is approximately equal to z so
i'm just write that down and you're done which is useful
so a
don't kind textbook has a really nice discussion of
what's going on in these algorithms and why findings at its heart it says
imagine that was the volume of the lake so now you state space you're wandering
around the area of the lake in your unnormalized functions is that the like and
obviously the volume of the integral of the unnormalized functions over here
like the base
sales around
so is something from the prior
this is the lake with very spiky canyons because we want to model only put
extreme values of the function on very skinny canyons look like they
so as you sail around most of the time you're not about the canyon they
sample from the prior would just be solar around random ignoring how do like it
and occasionally look at how they like
that's the bad algorithm because you're not going to spend any time over the canyon
sampling from the posterior
swim around the lake
and sample uniformly from
the volume and the like and then see how deep you optimize the volume within
these massive deep canyons they'll be in these and you can see how deep they
but in order to know the volume of the like you know you need to
know how deep
the can table you need to know that sort of cross sectional area of hyperbolic
is very difficult to estimate hyperbolic instance breakpoint
so neither of these algorithms give you the information you need
so this is an example of a problem where
just doing MCMC isn't the answer to the question like it is an expectation that
is not
usefully obvious expectation that we know
how what sensible distribution to sample from
and there are several ways around this problem and i have
several references i've got a section references at the end of the slide switch on
real generative processes out there in the world
we should assume that they come from something simple because then will definitely be wrong
essentially we are not to limit the complexity of our model a priori
since we don't believe that the real data was actually generated from a statistical model
with a small number of parameters right
so therefore regardless of how much training data we have we should consider models with
as many parameters as we can handle computationally
we all have to do the selecting of model order we don't have to say
all rights use five gaussians are six gaussians and my mixture model
in fact we can have infinitely many of you know the parameters if we want
and the key thing is that we can have infinitely many parameters as long as
we don't optimize them
we optimize the
we're going to
overfit the data
the kinds of models that i'm going to to talk about these nonparametric models including
gassing processes is shown about talk about our models with an infinite number of parameters
there are two ways of understanding guassian process
so the first way starts from a multivariate gaussians
and the second we start from linear regression so then we try to explain
let's start from
dallas in the solution OK so this is it's the univariate gas in this mission
was zero mean right
this is the multivariate gaussians density
it's t is the vector with elements t one t and
OK with zero mean again
now let's look at this expression for multivariate gaussians density
look in particular at this matrix sigma
so sigma
and n by n covariance matrix
imagine the following imagine it
sigma i j
depended on
on i and j
so imagine that
if i and j are close to each other
then sigma i j is large
these areas
a lot of covariance between
t i
i pos one let's say
there's less imagine if there's less covariance between t i and t i was ten
if we were to do this
uh no better
this is probably not going to work
OK with high probability this is not going to work so don't care of
what happens
forget it does not work
very sorry about this
show picture i think that picture on it
slide later on day
so here's
imagine that t i
t one through t one hundred
we're were lined along here
so i imagine that the index one three hundred was line along here and the
values plotted here where t one
thirty one hundred now if there
these four samples from that multivariate gaussians distribution
what you see is that nearby samples are very close to each other
nearby samples are very close to each other
nearby points t in input space are are very similar to each other but far
away points
are less correlated
in the gaussianprocess what you assume is that the covariance
sigma depends on some say the covariance between t and t j
depends on some
input variables
which here we're calling i and j but in general could be
indexed by space for example
so two points that are close to each other in space have the same value
of t
a similar values of t
two points that are far away and have quite different values of t
essentially it's infinite dimensional generalization of the multivariate gaussians where instead of this finite index
of integers one two and i now
indexed this by space
call it acts OK
and instead of the covariance function which is the so instead of the covariance matrix
need is a domain
it must be a nonempty domain otherwise it doesn't make much sense we call this
delta delta four domain and it is associated with a particular interpretation i and then
we need a function that draws the diagrams a function that gives us the set
associated with the
names always the
concept descriptions that we might come up with using some nice syntax and so this
is usually written as this take something here and interpreted so we write it
this way
and as we said our intention is to
map the names to some subset of the domain i think you remember the diagrams
take the domains
the name so a subset of this domain
and four
role descriptions we are not talking about single object but pairs of objects
considering plans in the works for
if we
i want to draw one to draw the diagram actually it's the a set of
pairs i don't i didn't
daud here but i think it's obvious so it's easy to understand that a particle
role description should be a subset of the cross product of the domain with itself
pairs of a set of pairs of objects that's pretty easy to understand now let
me just summarised
the idea about the
operators here so the
conjunction operator
it is then
the semantics of the conjunction operator is defined with respect to set intersection
the disjunction is defined with respect to union this is exactly what we have seen
in the drawings before complement is an interesting thing if i have the
the main here and
these are the set
this is
these are the students a then the complement of the student is all the rest
and if we have a very complex concept descriptions then
we can apply the same modelling
this is very
interesting there are restricted languages that don't allow you to do this
then you sacrifice modeling power for the same computational properties
turnout inference problem to be less complex
this looks a little bit strange for instance we discussed some
works for
organization this can be an arbitrary complex concept descriptions it could write down using your
favourite language this is the schema here then a set of domain objects for which
there exists something on the right-hand side and this thing on the right hand side
must satisfy certain restrictions
and this was the same for all very different different different
any question about the
i mean
it's not really necessary to
really understand all this mafia i i think i have drawn diagrams and you got
the idea
four four in some
cases you want to say
that a particular professor
must not teach two courses or
some professor usually a younger professor must teach at least three courses otherwise something is
wrong by research prof or know the professor can teach at most one cause obviously
right so
clear that one probably wants to restrict the set of all objects that one might
find for one particular object on the right hand side so students must work at
at least four four companies in these days
o five was one company if one has strict
the government
it's obvious that there is the need to introduce new concept forming operators that
we can use them to describe these sets in this of secure language
we can do this using these
access these at least restrictions and this is the qualification you could say
works for at least
o for at most one
this is the number
operators long
known in description logics
but has only recently been added to the old two standard
but it's now it's very very nice that this was also adopted
i talked about interpretations i talked about this relational structures that we might want to
define now we can have a look at the particle or structure
we can
take some particular object
of a domain let's take
object that i call p one
let's take object p two
p three
p four maybe
and then
we might want to talk about courses there's the description logic course database course maybe
a semantic web course so these are objects of the domain
i gave them the name but you can think of these circles here is representing
objects of the domain and we can see that those objects into relation to one
another so
we say
the relation takescourse consists of this
o p one
p two p l
p two d p three seven
as you see i write down
the variance
on our dependent variable is pretty large
there are other values
so here
but the variance
it's pretty small
this is annoying as well
another issue
let's take this area here for the
independent variable
and this look at this data
and others assume the difference between cone
it is zero and forty percent should be that large
but as have been sitting in this room heating up before we came
you may remember that normally you talked about
he CA
there's notion of fuzzy sets
in fuzzy sets terms
talk about replacing rate we could argue in place and rate
which is that low point four
if you got only forty percent of former salary
you're probably quite eager to get the job in this area
in this sector
we could argue is the differences here are that large
music playing over here
where it it makes a difference whether you're
above or below
alternative wage
and if we take this
one part of
of a replacement rates across countries
and we see something that we call the wedge
has this form
so should thing here
which shape form
would be something like this
so variations here
this area is much larger
on the dependent variable
then variation in this area
which shape
another alarming signals
it tells us
at least
we cannot answer for our
significance tests
and at worst it tells us
the model specification is utterly wrong
so the straight line here
a nice summary
with artfully painted it into data about are standard for us
it summarizes something indeed if you look at the big picture
then we can say
for low rates of the replacement rate indeed on average
employment seems to be lower
for higher
levels of
the replacement rate
employment in the private sector consumer services
is low
in general
the association that we expect it
can be seen
but there are lots of
it's about that
we'll talk during the next two weeks
because this is simple
you will be able to draw this picture
by the end of tomorrow
most people go home or good party
but i will recommend to stay on the wow
and two
also look into those bits that sketched
to make
better use of what you're doing
the data
so let's go back to the art of summarizing relationships
this is
what you will be able to run in our tomorrow
we have a relationship
it's related
to x
these are vectors
so we have here
a set of values for
a dependent variable
in our case it was employment private consumer services
and here this is a matrix
which means
a set of vectors
each representing
the independent variable
the previous picture
i've had one independent variable the replacement rate
things get nasty as soon as more than one
independent variable to draw
however this is nice representation
so here it is
o thing you must consider as a data matrix with parables
the columns
the names of the
unit of analysis
in the rows
here we have a vector
of coefficients
telling us
but how many steps
the dependent variable will change
and also to what direction
we move one step on our independent variable
got the residual term
in which all the noise nuisance is hidden
all the rest
and the assumption
otherwise we can not
calculate these coefficients
this is all well behaved i'll tell you what will be a means in a
few minutes
now with some algebraic
you get after a while
this expression
of the two
divided by design
of the of two
now i square
i have will greatly increase
so what you see now is
that's little d
it is always larger than rapidly
you're going to see that the maxima
o which comes from this
equation i being modulated by this one
and so
if this were
by capital the was the opening each individual group
and if the grading one-fifth of course is zero or maximum always here
and if the first or maximum of the degrading fall here
and the second order one full year and the third here
and this is the price you pay
before the fact
that these groups have an opening so you see and modulation in the strength
of your
first second third fourth order and so on
so when you look carefully at the grading
lights and our
demonstrate that the you they are not all
sixteen times i zero if you have any calls for and if you have any
equal thousand not all a million times
i zero
but they have this
overall envelope
which modulated and that's the result
of the opening finite opening of the growth
they could to make sure that you understand the difference between the
and the two days
this is my great
and this is the open area
this is
when the light can not go through
and the definition
of these this
and the definition of this the
that the shows up in here
and this capital these shows up
so this is the
a single slit diffraction
this is the most puzzling interference
there you see again
we make the distinction in water
but that has no
meaning because it's all the fraction of course
somehow be
were approximately divided by five and it just so happens we have grading
for with that is the case
the first
order maximum of the great
it's going to be
because that is
when this function becomes zero
so you will see that
zero order one two three four five will be killed here and then they would
build up a little again and then ultimately of course they will peter out
so if i show you is
a spectrum of great
you can actually roughly estimate what the ratio capital be of little these by seeing
sure that modulation
and so that's what i want you to see now
it's not so exciting
many of you were observed may have seen any
because it was every time there even when i showed my own
so we're going to make it
quite dark for this
i know this is the wrong wrongs which
so many switches here there we go
this is a great thing that i purposely offset
i purposely offset sort of here is the
zero order
make sure
this is the zero order i think that well actually
test when my zero it was
this is the zero order
we aim exactly here
and so this is the first order
second order third or fourth order
look at this soccer almost gone
that is the result of the fact the single slip into
and then it comes up again and the reason why it comes up again
because now you enter this little many
in the singles that's so you see here quite well sometimes
grading you can see remarkably well
all the time
it is hard to see it depends of course on
how many
maximize you have
you seem quite well the modulation
see comes up here again in this little point here
would then be somewhere here in this axis
so this is then the complete equation that combines single slit diffraction
with multiple
slit interference
if we change
the single opening
from a senate
there was circles
circle you policies circle
then very little changes except of course if you have a circular opening
everything is now actual symmetry
so you get circle
the thing become circles
and then
which is not so obvious
that is that
this minimum doesn't for of land over two in terms of angular dimensions with one
point two times level to
and if you want to use one two
for an approximation that is fine enough so it's a little larger
for all perpetrates but this very rigid model
one of two alternatives does not hold either
so let's take a look at the real data
the data comes from thomas hunt morgan
a developmental biologist to be eventually became one of the great geneticists of the century
columbia university studying fruit flies and he studied for flies rather than peas
there many good reasons why makes sense the flies than p is
as four chromosomes is the seven
o four seven
anybody been to columbia university
i mean it's really
also what else is wrong with studying these
they take too long how many generations piece you can get a year and half
so many
from flies how long did it take
a couple weeks ago get a generation every couple weeks
if you actually want to write some papers i mean if you have a day
job is among you can you can do these p things that take a long
but for example if you're trying to get tenure at columbia
you might want to actually do something that you could get a couple generations every
month or something like that so the fruit fly was much better they also you
know they don't take feels and things you grow them in little files
with some
food at the bottom these are medium at the bottom and little cotton stopper at
the top and very quickly you can grow zillions and zillions of fruit flies to
the the
the flight was chosen easy short generation time et cetera et cetera and there are
a lot of natural variations other geneticists love to choose organisms that is easy to
work with you can do a lot of work
so and provide four chromosomes but i do so any calls for that four pairs
of chromosomes
so he said across
the have zero cross was between a normal flight and the way we see norman
genetics is wild type
wild type that is the type in the wild it actually doesn't mean that it
is the type in the wild it means it's whatever type the geneticist was chosen
as his or reference train but it's called wild type and he said across
between the wild type fly by flight had two interesting properties its body
was black
and its wings
were in bad shape and they were called vestigial the funny little when things that
weren't warned that didn't work and grown outright et cetera so instead of the normal
flight body color which is kind ten around the middle it was black all around
its middle and its wings were very short the hypothesis is that there genes controlling
in fact by demonstrating mendelian inheritance black was the single mendelian trait which was recessive
to the normal body color as the gill was the single mendelian trait which is
recessive to the normal body shape and the genotype of wild type was homozygous
normal which already possible plus now geneticists actually prefer plus terms rather than big or
small plus over plus and will also a female
and we'll cross her to a male
who homozygous
for the gene that controls the body color there and this gene that controls wing
and we'll look at the offspring so
makes f one f one have what genotype there plus over black class over this
the jail
f one
so that
what he does is he takes
say these males
and he crosses them
these flies here that have the doubly recessive phenotype doing what we call a test
now the name of conclusion is more is known as a test cross when you
cross back to the home of zygote
for the recessive phenotype and
when he gets out the same exact picture i drew before but we're just getting
used the nomenclature and getting used to a slightly different nomenclatures here he could either
you always get blacklisted URL blacklisted job black stage or
black the job
parent on the right and here you can get plus plus
could get blacklisted joel he could get
black plus
or you could get plus stage all and
as we said over there
that as then doing this random changes i want to get better and better models
so one way to think of this is sort of like doing the simulated annealing
over all these things
you can think of it this way
and then you know with some probability of course you also accept sort of changes
that lead us to bend towards more in some sense
so that's the way how we can estimate the model
and what do the authors use this model for link prediction for three very small
networks where what what is shown here is the probability that the fraction of things
that i removed from the network so basically and
so basically or it is the
one minus the size of my training or it's the it's mind one minus that
is the size of my training data set where
here for example i'm pretty much removing almost all the links from the network and
i then i try to to predict them
and the red curve is this hierarchical method and then the other curves are sort
of competing methods this is the random
or chance
the evaluation is done by area under the curve measures so not comparing to random
and you can see
that this works toward this tends to work well for small terrorist network so i
think this is like nine eleven terrorist network also about it for example for the
metabolic network
what tends to work better is for example short spats so predict
link based on the on the distance of the shortest span between the nodes or
by the product of their degrees so this would be like a preferential attachment hypothesis
that this is the food web from some grassland echoes ecosystem where again this sort
of this hierarchical model tends to work really well
a different way to model graphs and also sort of to reason about links comes
more from the social sciences and this is called exponential random graphs are based on
and the idea is
somehow describes
the graph by r
by some kind of statistics or some kind of numerical somebody measures and then throw
throat a log linear model over that
and that's very nice for very useful for hypothesis testing
so what i mean by by that is the following a probability of missing graph
y is just some big nasty normalizing constant and these are my and then
the my linear building combination of my summary measures like this is my summary measures
times the parameters and what they want to learn is this but on this that
i OK
i can be a bit more concrete how can i designed this
summary measures this statistics you know i can say the the number of nodes the
number of edges
the number of open triads number of closed triads and so on so these are
these are the kind of kinds of summary statistics i can use
and yet the nice thing here is that i can condition this summary statistics based
on some kind of know that if see the like activity or individual's characteristics
so in this way then i can do hypothesis testing consumer whether certain types of
nodes are more likely you know to participate in such structures was as structures where
the edges are reciprocated or you know a particular sets of nodes more likely to
cause two to participating triangles or you know in open in open i
so that's basically the idea
so the first such models so here's an example is called the one and it's
on edge of diet independence model and what it says is the probability of of
seeing the graph is simply this is done
this so i have like four different parameters
the first parameter rho
is basically telling me what was the tendency to reciprocate edge right so i have
multiplied by j and j j i element of adjacency matrix so whenever they here
and counting how many times a french is mutual goes both ways then i'm asking
how many edges so there so phi is the density parameter
and then i have a sort of
the out out degree parameter in the parameters so
in social sciences they were called is called a separate activity of and also how
many edges it creates and attractiveness of an old how how likely is the node
to this evening
and i can go to feed this
using maximum MCMC
the reason for that is that
calculating the normalizing constant here according to coppola's policy is basically a sum over all
possible graphs times the probability of the graph right and for this little network this
is the number of graphs i would have to some some of so it some
it's somewhat too many so people do MCMC and since i'm running short on time
i want to explain how to do that
but here is example what you can do so one of sort of again very
very used networks in social networks analysis is this florentine families
this is the network these are the sixteen florentine families and i think every edge
that means that means that families are somehow related either by business relation or marriage
or something like that and you know miniature something i think this node and so
on OK so what you can do then is here community network