so the more you know
the the seventh
so the the
you should be
it's just that
it's just because
this one class of algorithms that we have been working on which of is many
many whole at which is based on sparse coding which is a very old idea
due to also has the field as an idea for learning these of i guess
feature hierarchies
so this
unsupervised learning
o which we start by taking natural images like like that you can actually check
x shown on the left and we learn to decompose these images into a linear
combination of a the small set the dictionary basis functions so on the right hand
side of three examples of dictionary basis functions by sparse coding on what this is
done has learned to decompose you know this natural image patch that is the combination
of a small number of this dictionary races
if you're on sparse coding on a large set of unlabeled images this is also
basis functions you can correspond roughly to age detectors was he lost to texas but
is not that exciting but when i think this was coding is that the hypothesized
is that it's like patches of the called basic elements of the scene
and those resident images in terms of the edges appear
and therefore it gives us a higher level or most the same or abstract representation
of an image that the raw pixel intensity values because now have a representation of
an image in terms of the edges appear in a rather in terms of pixel
intensity values and does unsurprisingly they can use large amounts of unlabeled data
so more interestingly is of course if you can you also go from governor input
image to detect edges one just things this idea is repeated in deep architecture so
what we did was implement a sparse version of the deep belief network is given
how at least where we go have information to detect edges it's even more higher
commonly more high-level representations of combinations of edges
one of the challenge is that and if you do this thing started the interesting
feature hierarchies
one of the challenges that we face in this work and i think community faces
and scale these algorithms so turns out to be you know papers and this you
a lot of people work on forty by forty images we work fourteen fourteen images
some of us bite the bullet we really scale up to thirty two but the
two images
and you know
if you learned from data about the two images there is really no there's some
stuff but it's really not that much interesting things going on in those thirty about
these two images
only when you
can scale up to large real size and more realistic sized images that is much
more interesting structure to be learned
so the main conference hall at present the papers of one method for scaling up
which is using convolutional deviance and since he gave it to the main conferences someone
to go over this in the two slides three slides so motivation is to
use ideas from convolutional neural learning the scale up to larger
unsurprisingly models
measures a yorkshire
school has to work on related conditional models as well
o so
the sea is is very quickly i guess given an input image we don't have
feature detectors in the first layer of the out of the woods highways so these
are convolved feature detector over the input image i intersect features clear and then select
convolutional neural networks we don't have the pooling layer that compresses representation by factor two
whereas a convolutional neural nets
young and gives you which is very old algorithms there is this idea of max
pooling which she would take
four feature detectors and just compute the max
right in a DBN we're not working these real numbers in the DBN working with
these binary valued random variables
and so rather than taking for real numbers we instead the max for binary valued
random variables
and in addition to make our more scalable where actually do we call probabilistic max
pooling which is where we enforce constraint that the low-level features in this DBN are
mutually exclusive so that only one of them can be turned on all the time
and the fact that is that rather than these variables having two n possible combinations
collapses into n possible configurations and so this makes learning inference much more efficient
these are some of the
do you think that'll work
so here i think
i have a hard right in the current implementation it doesn't overlap but that be
a beach thing to do
so when we created our one natural images these are the sorts representations you were
the first there like everyone else we get edge detectors and the second there on
the our river which now has the largest receptive fields well start to put together
a short edges in order to form colonies in final on contours and so on
more interestingly
if you the sea in these experiments the first there was trained on natural images
so the first there
yes detectors and the second and third in areas where the and trains on objects
of one specific object class in the leftmost column the second third is which trains
on images of faces i see the second there so there are parts of faces
by putting together edges and the third there then put together it is possible basis
the more complete models of faces and if you do this with of you know
other objects as well
then again you see this pattern of learning object passes second air and that there
are more complete objects of
a more complete models of offerings is i think this is so this example of
when these sort of object parts hierarchies emerge for completely unsupervised learning algorithm and the
OK show will use this thing here given its early in the morning and
voice is not quite up to speed
OK so this is going to talk about two topics
i've been working on
so one is the question
the thomas already been hinting at the question how
we sample neural topographies using multivariate analysis using pattern analysis and the other question is
how we can compare the information we extract using classifiers to any information we extract
from cognitive paradigms for example social paradigms for the ideas that we directly relates the
accuracy that we measure to the behaviour
here a sampling of high-resolution neural maps with voxels
it's going to be the first part of the talk
so idea is we can actually
virtually increase the resolution of fmri or we can actually use the right structure that
much higher resolution than we might have thought previously
and this is the second section comparing cognitive neural information i'll show you a number
of paradigms just as examples where we directly compared the accuracy with cognitive accuracy
i'll start looking in a very
difficult case for from our research
so this is orientation processing in the ones three fundamental
aspect of neural processing visual processing is orientation processing one of the basic features of
visual stimuli and so we've got orientation selectivity of single cells in the visual cortex
and in one
all o
because has better so single cells have orientation selectivity which means that they respond preferentially
to specific orientations but not to others and if we look at the orientation selectivity
is distributed across the cortex you can see that here this is an optical imaging
map obtained from monkey visual cortex
you get such topography word is very fine scale topography where different colours indicate regions
of different orientations selectivity and i'll show you problem
if we sample the brain using these larger fmri voxels the problem we get run
into is that this voxel is far too large to actually resolve these individual regions
of different orientations selectivity so so for example want to zoom in on horizontal orientations
we can't do that because if we is if you want to get the horizontal
we also get all the other orientations same time so this is basically what people
knew from right to study orientation processing
and sir thomas already shown so work that originated primarily not just for us but
mainly from you can italian in front on so if you go into visual cortex
is just the sketch
and you acquire pattern was a small set of voxels the responses a small set
of voxels what you find is that they actually distinguish between different orientations although the
spatial scale is quite different
and the reason that happens is this is one of the possible models is that
in fact that if the if you see the this this topographic map with regions
of different orientations selectivity here with sampling with these voxels although the map is rather
random we will still get slight fluctuations in the density of cells of different types
and that will create a subtle bias in the measurement of these molecules and will
allow us to record for each waffle has a subtle small
information for example the top left the voxel about the orientation of the stimulus and
the ideas of the pattern analysis allows us to accumulate this information across a large
number of voxels that's the that's the idea
so just show you just one representative voxel we can actually see that this orientation
preference actually occurs at a single voxel level
so this is basically the the angle shows the orientation of the stimulus and the
eccentricity shows you responsible for example this box response stronger two left older than to
write tilted similar so
and single voxel if you do find these biases we can cross between microscopic topographic
maps and voxels
and these orientation biases of individual voxels their measured here using the t value for
the difference between the response of each works between the two conditions so ultimately is
t value captures whether the voxel responds strongly to one orientation astronomy to the other
orientations and what you get is you get this distribution of these orientation selectivity is
are not random and the easiest way to see that is if you split data
set into two halves you can see the orientation preference in the first of the
and the second half of the data highly correlated so basically these small preferences of
individual voxels are quite reliable
and that creates pattern so if we look at this on the cortical surface and
the way we do that is we segment the cortical surface shown here in green
so this lecture will be about what my plans
this will be
well as part of this thing will be logic much that users is not really
what to this will be connected to some of the other three
what planning
most cases about is about
deciding which is actually a
so as to some
even objective and
yeah think it works in the order autonomous robots
the same source
thank you input from the same source
and it was that these since the sequence of actions x
well no normally there would also like to knowledge base is updated
twenty states
sensory input and then well
is that knowledge is lost since they will fall
the robot its knowledge base and with
and the planning area
the on
general purpose methods for planning something
input language planning system like PDDL is explicitly not for describing almost any kind of
planning problems
well understood
of course
and the idea is used to use this to a problem the
the purpose out planning forestalling any instance in planning problem that che
so this is
a different school
specialized on for solving particles
so the idea is that of this language which problems and
some of the are following
examples of
like problems people have been targeting planning research complex
control of any kind of
complex system
examples would be like a NASA autonomous spacecraft they have some experiments where they have
been using
there are plenty for controlling the
the complex systems currently sits on
planning what actions to take control of the electricity distribution network when the out
so the great makers we is have to be closed or open
supply that as many people as possible
they have been
and in the manufacturing systems hull cool what actions to take manufacturer sort of
in the little robots is all uppercase automated planning
and all kinds of problem solving for example
one user games like it you can be described in
the input language planning systems
and now lots of
related problems like more narrowly on the planet and some respect so
like just getting timetabling these are also
problems about deciding
when the they given that this all as efficiently as possible
i'll have a couple of examples
later multiple planning that and this is sort of simpler
one of the most simple
problem scenarios that can use for demonstrating planning this is a lot of
blocks consists of this table and the number of blocks
and we will be
the idea is that lot can be stacked in different ways
they don't use any geometric information about like beats according to four
and the only thing that matters is whether
so the block is on top of another
of this matter
and we also don't allow
more than one block
on top of of the one directly on top of another block so
each block can be
the only
directly under
i did
below and director of all the works of the
thirty years and is not loading blocks
the variance of blogs have different number of blocks this
example of what's wrong with three
works and
in these blocks are they are these thirteen
it is possible states of the world
so all the
possible ways of backing those three blocks on the table
one or more on on top of another block
with the world
considering because he had earlier so we need to look inside the book does not
matter and only of what can be only one one another block the other way
the planning problem in
normally have been interested in
is given in
the initial state of the world
let's say this that characterised by this
it's like looks on the lower
left-hand corner
what are the actions that be taken at the some of the best also
the other thing is that the world would be flexible the one on the on
right most the world with with the
block on top and then the red we
in this book world the act different actors correspond to different woman so more so
one action is because this
look from one location and with
some of of the fish and of course from this graph is c
what is actually said was that people from the united nations so it simply follow
arrows in the graph and these are of course one action and
that's also planned
this pretty simple
why why why why is this the research problem and why why don't we just
dard shortest allegory like doctor algorithm
the great
that would be the case that would be
well as you can obviously be very happy
they are
they were pretty very happy about
we're talking about the guy
first we have see all the
so you can use long-range in
unfortunately what this immediately leads to a tractable comes in fact
come the begin to make
this is what you want to use of
so it became very much on the specific application
now what be very nice if you could just take some time
tell you what don't want the right across the wall
and to some extent people do that
so a lot of
bayesian networks
well people are very very active working in this area
the others were very well in practice
there is
just like very
this it's very hard to point
to prove optimality examples
so you need to find good heuristics for
and then the question is what is used to be one
you can prove that is
but that is something that
i would like to mention that this is the information that was
you don't have to
also collection
to model the log
well this is what i previously
mainly what we have is that
what if i have some all year round one thing
henri e
they not all the
one the things
we also know know that it has to be
decomposition property of graphical model
can one of the
overall they
on the
it follows from that
due to both along the place that idea
the problem of the
it c
what they see
and then
he that
one of the
now you might think that this completely option made by
it's actually what
i mean first of all you
he had the position including one but one can always assume that some facts fig
and we have should
and there's a universal approximation result
those certain sufficient statistic
it shares
that is
can be well approximated with a financial and small
at the moment for that is not
so in the exponential family of the year fixed term in front so you can
just look the anything that will approximate the exactly right now it's not that way
that the
so that
i mean
the bottom line is
you have
well just like the fact that
contrast that to the mean producing spaces
things in
these easier zero cost
a continuous functions
on the right
you have
are you
correspondingly that
some part of
by will be essentially the same despite all these
what some constraints may
so prove that in the television
the hard for me in terms of the
the distance is rather easy
at the moment there are only problem or
proves anything that's all you can really consider them constructive
finding good right despite all this this will be wonderful
at the moment nobody's
so that it is not known
the paper
tracks song
the back
sort of the back
so in one one of the things that you would be seeing here
this is after all a summer school so you sort of interest in learning about
all sorts of machine learning algorithms and so
in terms of the coverage you would wind up saying that is more of knowledge
based learning algorithms that we talked about in this picture then let's say a couple
of hours of a you start totally backtracking
the other thing that sort of interesting in terms of machine learning algorithms have been
used in planning learning intersection is most of them have been relational
it turns out that you will see as you see in planning most of the
time the background the domain knowledge itself is given as actions can which has which
are very easily understood in some of this relation languages and so much of the
learning in plan it much of the learning algorithms have been relational OK so that's
the other aspects of in terms of coverage you learn a bit more about relational
learning algorithms and a bit more about knowledge based on meaning algorithms
so i also i mean i guess should say a little about my background i
already told you my large number of ICML publications i want to tell you a
few more things basically my primary interest is in automated planning and i do a
lot of work on plants and this is improving the speed at which you can
not be generated plan given the problem and in the scaling of the performance of
this planets
i have for quite a long time in the past i have looked that actually
speed of learning in the context of learning and i do have talk about it
a bit but you know i have a lot of interest in
speeding up learning performance
and i'll show you did later that there is an interesting
they at which this work has been done at one time planning algorithms was really
really really really really slow
and when you slow you want to see if there's any way can improve performance
by learning so learning you was pretty much required crutch for planning programs at one
point of time that would be like pre nineteen ninety four ninety five frame and
there's a lot of work in speed up learning i'm planning that was done during
that time when i was also very much into that over the period of time
intervening period of time we lost interest and some of that because planners is just
out of the box of much much faster this is much faster and i'll tell
you exactly why they became pastor and one of the things so we sort of
lost interest at least in the speed of part i mean it's not that you
learning itself is going on the body it's no longer necessary crutch just to be
able to do this of planet but then
i am currently freshly interested like many other people in actually
in the intersection of planning and learning for two different reasons one as i will
tell you is that a new crop of learning algorithm that in the of his
research efforts to basically shown that has
impressive as the scale up in planning has been you can still improve
you know which much more to get them to even faster speed ups and part
of it has been as early as we can see that in the part of
it has been because we have this competition for planning performance garnered international planning competition
and there was there are two two tracks one track with essentially domain independent all
tell the planet is
your actions
and then it's given the problem and the goal just supposed to sequence actions of
actions to get the plan there was another track knowledge based planning which was held
at least forty two competitions and real people
what LOD to right on top of the
the main action descriptions anything else they want to tell the plan such as you
take these branches when you're doing search do the planning in the following way a
lot of extra control knowledge could be given now the interesting thing is this was
being done by humans
so humans would write his knowledge and what's interesting of course is we saw that
these sorts of knowledge based planners were significantly faster
then the domain
independent plants
and so that again opened up an entire interest in
learning that knowledge that people are writing by hand let's try to learn that automatically
so that would be another reason why people got quite interested in
and learning right now and tell you some of the work that's going on that
i think is pretty neat
and then i'm also interested like many other people of late in actually learning not
know that much of the work in the speed of learning has happened with this
right on
definition here
so we just
this is true here
OK so now let's try to prove these four
different properties and i'll i'll give it some time for this but maybe i'll give
you a couple of minutes before
and how to proceed so there
once you've seen the film afterwards you're probably say they trivial but if you have
never seen this definition of a positive definite kernel before then it would be non-trivial
to think about it and write them down even though
each one of them is maybe just two lines so
so the first one is we have to prove that this is a positive definite
to prove that this is a positive definite kernel we just have to verify that
this condition he holds true
for a kernel which is defined like that
so that's the direct verification
have to use things like linearity of the dot product and so on
the next one
this may be slightly more tricky even though it turns out this very simple if
so in this next one we have to prove that effectively the
if the kernel is positive definite
so here in
if the kernel is positive definite then its diagonal elements are positive or negative so
diamonds scale xmax or if you think of the kernel matrix is the diagonal elements
of the kernel matrix
so here in all these three cases we assume is positive definite little incomplete so
i should have written here so here
this is a complete statement but the statement should also a if k
is positive definite then
this holds true this of this so here
there is
a simple proof but maybe i won't tell you know because it's hard to give
him without giving away the whole idea is very simple but you think about it
a a little bit
the second one
i have given you a hint here
it's with this hint it should reasonably simple but still requires some thinking
and this is the general generalized cushy schwartz inequality
and you can be seen from here
and the last one
is this property that if a kernel is zero on the diagonal
for all possible many then it's actually zero everywhere
so it's
the last properties of leave these up on the screen and again try to remember
whether i can separate myself and give you some time to to the process mean
and then we'll be together
as you seem to be you and spare this
in that time
could then
i have to draw brought
thank you
the output the room in the knowledge sources into thinking he on wednesday
the only one
one the book
PTFE teflon minus 60
a 1st thing to notice is to look at the range and if you look
at the range in the periodic table of the range of something like density so
you have lithium scattered density . 5 3 and you got osmium that's around 22
so a range of about 40 per but this 10 to the 7th 10 to
the minus 16 a range of 10 to the 20 3rd
10 to the 23rd
what we know about the compounds we've seen so far ionic compounds
conductors are insulated we know the they got tightly bound electrons in a stable octet
configurations so that's not going to help us covalent compounds
well that work ones like diamonds very very good insulators
on compounds let's look at that a argon they got the answer would be a
good conductors of electrons know why extended gas configuration those of the 3 types of
primary bonding and I can explain how three-quarters of periodic table has this abnormally high
value of electrical conductivity sounds to me like we need to come up with yet
another form of bonding
and the answer is metallic bonding wiser metallic bonding because it's practiced in metals so
let's look at metallic bonding the need for metallic bonding was brought on by the
observation of electrical conductivity so if you're going to be true to form a 3
0 9 1 we have to look at the electronic structure
and the 1st model the 1st model that
attempted to account for the highly highly observed value of the electrical conductivity was enunciated
in 1900 by German physicist by the name of Paul
pultruded in 1900
what he said was that party could model metal
a mixture model the metal has a mixture of
positive nuclei
plus the inner shell electrons for the inner shell electrons which he called this whole
mix of the positive nuclei all the inner shell electrons he called that the atomic
core and then the valence electrons he said were separate so you get the atomic
or plus valence electrons which he assumed were free
were free that is to say they could move about the material number words they
were not associated with any single
so we call them the localiza The Glass they're used the term the localized
we'll come back to that in a bit so this is in essence of modeling
the metal as
I solid
consisting of course and the electrons freely moving much the same way as a gas
so this was a tournament argued that turned the free electron gas model number gas
of free electron free electron gas what and what this they had some success they
were able to account for such things as the heat capacity of solids so he
capacities of solids they could they could model
that was good and I think there's something else you're able to do
but by and large but this didn't stand up because it wasn't quantitative
so there's not quantitative what's happening right off the bat
Nobel Prize you get no Nobel Prize reported no quantitative Nobel Prize will just put
this year knows
those shown in the bottom of the maybe be no causal relationship
you know actions the kind of leader one can cause the other
so looks grown right and i've been bragging about learning causes announcements this example really
can't learn any causes all
let's look at this more complex examples what i said the beginning of the talk
is that we can learn something about classes when we have data
and at least four variables
you need for
suppose these are four variables
and x and y are independent then w
is independent of x and y
given c
this was again an example we looked at before
p is embedded faithfully in the DAG in a and in b
this is that we learned before
right x because y like this is because w
this can be hidden cost
the same independencies
as this one
and why are independent given by the argument i gave before
they still for the independent owing to the separation and when i condition and the
that strict state of the markov condition w is independent of its non descendants which
included x and y
given c
right so all these dags
these conditional independencies
so these two
causal inferences are not necessarily causal influences could be hidden because just like before
but p is not embedded faithfully
in the i can see
this kind of tricky that entails the w is independent of x and y
just like i said before
land and sea
these two variables are independent right
it's like the earthquake
burglar h one and h three are independent
and since there are independent given by d separation w
and x are independent
so say i can't
take this one can replace it by hidden cause
even if i go with this zero that i know what you too many dags
that went directly there would still say
the same thing because that's what what
i would say x and h three are independent
and then by d separation w was also independent of x
the bottom line is
this page has to go and here
whether it's true causing now
it has to be an arrow into
from the top
if i replace
the COI policy
i know into to the which is called the head to head meeting
i'm going to make xnw independent
so i can take this
arrow and make it go up
the hidden cost just like i can make it go up without having because they
can make it go up with the hidden cost because and up with this head-to-head
we can still conclude
the causes w
this is a causal relationship can be learned
these two can that but again now if i had long linguistic variables here all
of them would be good
it's just these initial ones at the top that are not good
and that's
the argument i gave before that we can learn something if we had at least
four variables
here it is
i mean if i have a hidden causes in the chain here b
these two
eight if thousand an error from h one h two
you wouldn't have
these independencies
well if we have these independencies assuming it can be hidden causes present but
they couldn't be ones like this because you wouldn't observe those independencies
so we're assuming whatever they are the such a nature that this is what we
well making no assumption about the causes of oxygen might be present but whatever they
are they have to be present in such a way that
these are the observed dependencies
this example is entirely with time
this is this is what i had before
what i learned
you know it wasn't there i think now we realize that means there is a
hidden common cause
once we make the causal embedded faithfulness assumption we i simply observe independencies means c
and w have a hidden common causes the the only explanation
in my example was
as one can see
and i'm going to get some some
quote real life examples this is not really a real life example but the next
two are
this is an example may not just illustrate how you could learn that smoking causes
lung cancer
well it's just assume that
but things that made this example i i saw something in particular but likely more
there's an actual study very similar variables indicating smoking causes lung cancer but made this
up because it easy to track
let's say you have these for variables
our which is the parents smoking history
a which is alcohol consumption
individual smoking-related lung cancer
and suppose we learn from data that these are independent
whether person
carrying small is independent of whether the individual
the child
as opposed
right so those are independent and we have and will end up learning that one
cancer is independent of both of these
conditional on smoking
the along cancer is not independent of whether the
current small one cancer is also not independent of whether person
but these two are independent once we know the person smokes
right so just like there is an actual real life example that is very similar
to this but let's just
and this is just say this is true
we will learn the graph on the right
this is very similar to what i was just like the example i had on
the previous slide i replace x y c and w
they are a
why did why is this graph look different
because now i'm using
notation that i use when i'm actually learning causal influences
by one hundred year-old
what i mean is
that the causal DAG could be that causes as
or it could be a hidden common cause
that's the notation are used for the for the the fact that i don't know
what's going on right i don't know what causes us
well there is a hidden common cause but i know one of them is true
places that look good but also explore places that has looked at much
what is the value of this essay is the average
the different things
right so
so it works out
theoretically believed to say for now that
you destroy the average of what you say you can do different types of backups
if you want to UCT does this
basically the tree policy might say well i guess i'll go down here because it's
looked more promising and it selects node
and now we're the state where we have it's like that all the actions so
it's going to just generate this
and run the default policy right
there are trees bigger we update our values and perhaps now at the root
and know maybe it would select this again
and now maybe based on the same maybe it would explore this path and so
on so there's always two distinct phases the tree policy that will sort of find
the first leaf and the default policy that once you find all run to the
and the values we store the averages
so that the critical question is what is the appropriate role of policy and what
is an appropriate tree policy and UCT is a particular choice of those two things
so the basic UCT algorithm is basically just going to use a random rollout policy
that's theoretically what what what uses you you typically use something that's informed
the tree policy is based on UCB
so remember every state we encounter we can keep count of how many times we've
been there
that is what we're going to store here so state as we've been there at
this time we can also keep to count on how many times we tried each
action that's an essay and we can keep counts on the average reward we've seen
we've got to that state that's qs a
and the UCT
o tree policy is simply the
except theoretically you have to have a constant here
theoretically these these these payoffs you get when you pull the arms are not independent
from one another and they are also not stationary so so theoretically the main contribution
is to show that the same form works as long as you have a constant
the theoretical constant is the horizon
typically this is something you too
for a particular application domain just try bunch of values is this the best value
for go for example
so let's
UCT and so just to show you one more view of this
so i suppose that this is our current tree we've already generating
the city now wants to do another policy
it starts at the root has all the statistics
you have the bandit problem here
to choose the summer this are and
basically use this rule
it will choose one of the arms
and similarly the bandit problem there
and will choose one of the arms and then it will distill random rollout from
the area where we need to
the theoretical result is for the the constant is the horizon time so that you
but in practice you don't use that because it ends up exploring too much basically
so so they don't don't actually have a theory
the city result but basically it's in terms of
so so you might think that maybe should do sort of store
the maximum of the q values of these
you might be able to improve doing that people play with the stuff theoretically what
happens is
remember what you see be does
if an arm is suboptimal
it's only going to be pulled sort of log n times
so the average sort of is dominated by the best arm that's actually the key
insight behind these algorithms you have to do and max you can do an average
as long as you don't pull the bad arms too often so
so that's the that's actually the the key insight behind the two thousand five paper
in fact and then this sort of built on that
so as the theoretically the the results are in terms of number of trajectories
basically as you know there a polynomial relation between the number of trajectories and
close you're going to be to the optimal value here and is independent of the
state space size
the balance to sparse sampling the sort of equivalent you can also bound the probability
of selecting the the
optimal action
so in terms of the number of trajectories and that's the polynomial bound in
one over t where t is the number of trajectories so so as you pull
the arm more and more
the probability selects suboptimal arm goes down
fairly quickly with with the number of trajectories you generate
but but don't the key thing here is
you can stop pretty much at any time it doesn't take much time to generate
trajectory so you generate
ten thousand one hundred thousand trajectories you can stop and you have something nontrivial to
to work with the root and it just so happens that it's non-trivial enough so
you get state-of-the-art performance go so this is sort of a recap not gonna go
through here
computer go
the here just some quotes
that indicate how hard people think it is a it is a hard problem we're
not even close to master level performance yes even with UCT but this is what
i think is chinese origins is played lot in asia
so in nineteen by nineteen borini by nine board and you're basically trying to surround
your opponents with these black and white stones
minimax tree search is very bad nobody's ever got to work very well
primarily i guess because we don't have good heuristics and also the branching factor is
a lot larger than chess for example in the branching factor is basically all the
places you could put a stop that's enormous and heuristics
i mean this is very visual game we don't really know
how to compute good heuristics for go released
i was put this animations screwed up but two thousand five i mean basically
goes impossible there there's ago conference but mean for years and years is just a
which sit in my equivalence classes fourteen dimensions variable xj
and that's summarised this thing in the thing
capt data
and this is identifiable objects which you can identify from p
so from data it should be possible to get a handle on this data
his picture is an oracle
this is the probability of the data generating probability distribution
there is an algorithm used the PC algorithm
we can estimate the equivalence class
and then in principle in numerator all that members in the class
then you do the do intervention calculus you get all the intervention effects story
in this cat feeder
so let me just say this is a disaster in high dimensions
we don't want to enumerate all
these members is computationally intractable
you need to do something
but let me first say what can you do not have to model is a
set of all potential intervention effects and i claim but we can get the bound
on causal effect very trivial
so what you do is
you take just for example absolute value of your intervention effects
and go over all
the members an equivalence class of all the hours
and for a certain variable very two dimension j
so these alpha j
three only a lower bound for the true information of the true one is one
of the state s
so trivially the alpha j lower bound
the issue is here and there are many issues and i have no time to
go into that
you need to somehow sorted out more practically
and the point is
if you true underlying graph is sparse
you can actually
have an algorithm which is polynomial kind of the degree of sparsity index of the
and you can go through that and get that multiset without enumerating all that members
you can go directly from class to all potential effects and the number of effects
q is typically much much smaller than the number of members equivalence class
and this is particularly true if the true underlying graph bars
OK so this is kind of maybe more some sort of
the future
directions that you can do something in this area we need based on this is
what the experts
we rely on the PC algorithm this is again fully experts i don't know about
any convex relaxation algorithm so far too more equivalence class that
but you can for example use PC algorithm it has been invented by peter spirtes
and claude
climber and that's why it's called PC
peter and clark algorithms
that gives you
in a statement of the equivalence class of that's
and then you can also
get to the slower by
the three key areas
local computations only try and maybe to finish here
mister last says that everything was convex optimization
that was fast i didn't show you actually our interest is extremely fast extremely efficient
now he learning that's an equivalence classes of that
i don't know how to do it in the convex relaxation manner
but you can work on local computations on graphs which is not as fast as
a convex optimization but it's still feasible and reasonably efficient
i think i should things right
i mean i just want to i isolate it is one example on the east
and i just want to finish another example we really
employed this causal technique
in arabidopsis so the response variable was
here are plans and you want to my experiment is as follows you have plans
and you want to create a fast-growing plants because it only fast growing rice or
maize and so the first desirable jobs to make principle experiment and ask about the
response of interest the phenotype is how many days does it take the the flower
the plant is flowering
two days to flowering of the plant
and the aim is to have a kind of
low values and by just a few days is school
and you have extreme expression profile plants observational data
forty seven
morning twenty thousand
if in collaboration with by going being and increase in the tree
so what we do is the
cannot infer the causal effects but can go through this machinery giving the bounds of
causal effects this is my scoring scheme
look at this here the last line
i really encourage you to put some bootstrapping or subsampling on top of of it
i can apply my stability selection machinery to this problem as well
might help
one hundred variables these discourse bounds scoring let's just apply stability selection let's use that
formula which i showed you before i don't know whether exchangeability holes condition holds or
but i just using a more practical way
and then
you can come up with this list
here are the top twenty
jean interventions
experiments suggest that what you should do
and the plant guy said that he knows the three genes
and he was willing and that i find kind of interesting he was willing to
go forty others exactly according to this scale
i don't no other biological know how well this is better than that justice involve
those three and so i don't want to do these experiments but i do the
remaining seventeen and interstate twenty is enough if want to do more OK
so what do seventeen gene intervention experiments while unfortunately could do to seventeen could only
note also that every pure
other linear decision but that doesn't have any anything linear decisions such as for example
cutting plane
it is equivalent to some pure in a linear decision method such as
which of the composition
do the equivalent in the mathematical sense
so much
so so let me talk about special cases
OK because the class classical cutting plane method maps into the framework
the equivalent
for this problem here
the equivalent is too
the indicator function of the
of the constraints that has a second function
and to introduce
a constraint that x one and x two must be equal so this is the
subspace constraints k
so just two functions
two components
and the substrate right
in the classical cutting plane algorithm we are dealing arises f
and we have this unchanged
the approximating in p has this form where f has been replaced by its
and capitalize a finite set of subgradients
of f that have been obtained so far
so it's the method that i showed earlier
i have a
i the linear eyes just f i keep c and changed have finite set of
subgradients minimize get extract value of new
subgradient and keep going like this
so that's the special case
that corresponds to cutting plane
the special case correspond to simplicity compositions for the same problem is a little different
again the equivalent is like this
this is the indicator function of the constraints that the second component
but here we are in the linear eyes the constraints
in p f and change
and then the approximating problem has this form was see bars
is a finite point convex hull was in that approximates
and the enlargements step is
is is is involves using
after news of the primal approximating problem you have to solve the dual
well if you you're about
the dual optimal solutions are of this form here
four white had a subgradient
white is that is a subgradient of f at x
they had such that minus white heart is in the normal cone
of this polyhedral approximation
now in the classical case
f is differentiable
and why patterns very simple playing by
this condition
in the non differential case which is new actually
you have to do some computation here to find not just any subgradient but also
one that belongs to to the normal component of this
in fact
many high it's more complicated than just differentiated
and now after you obtain an extreme point of the constraint set
or after obtained after you solve this problem then you
finding new extreme points by
by this
minimisation here
which in the case was useful here is the linear programming problem
the point i want to make here is that the classical methods are special cases
involving this problem here
and either in the linear
minimisation of this or other minimisation of the
OK so complicated thing this way took so long to learn OK shows simplicity composition
for the case of a differentiable function i explained
you obtain extreme points by going in the direction the negative gradient
this is a depiction of simplicity compositions for nondifferentiable cost function that has this level
sets here
given this inner approximation you find a sub gradient of the cost function at this
point that's also in the normal comes to mind is that in the normal course
of the
of the convex hull
now you have this white can't
you go
as far as you can see in the direction of mine why had to obtain
an extreme point
and that's the
x still there that large this
this current approximation
yet a new
subgradient that's in the normal component of the approximation
go in the direction of a
mine is that you pay optimal point here
the reason being that both f
and c are polyhedra
and this is a generic property if everything is fully hero there yet
convergence in a finite number of steps
the reason being that you have expand the polyhedral approximation eventually you're going to be
adding more and more points and get the original
let me skip this slide because we're running out of time
this is the case where you have the minimum of two functions
with a common
from one
dependence on on x
and this
the figure
to show the duality between in the linear decision in a linear is one corresponds
to the linear rising the other in the door
this is an insightful figure if you have some time to study then unfortunately we
don't have time to do that
so let me say a few things about converges
comment is a little tricky is not as simple as you might think in fact
i'm still working
let's distinguish between the polygonal case
we're all out the linear is functions are finite he
finite meaning real
all in the linear eyes functions are called finite when he meaning that conjugate is
is finite
and let's also require that
he knew refinement points that you have to the point he the approximations
language but i want you to start thinking that we don't think of it as
a specific box into which were putting things think of it as a link to
evaluate i could have for example
simon statement
that creates a binding
from y
into that same
one of the things the concept i can do is i could have a statement
the z
the bound to the value of x y said it deliberately that way that statement
says get the value of x which is this link
and gives ia pointer
to the same place
the the value
not to x
OK now what is plant that idea when come back to later on as we
as we carry on
OK so if we have variables
the questions we can ask is what's the time
the variable
and the answer is it inherited from its value
so somewhere in my code
i have that statement that assignment statement x now is the variable whose value is
an integer
unfortunately at least in my mind implies on these variable bindings
or dynamic
the type brothers dynamics
it changes depending on what
the current value is
four set to different way of somewhere later on in the program i do this
x now has changed its title
from and
to strengthen
now why should you care
my view is
and like
especially in the presence of operator overloading
because i might have wrote written some code in which i'm expecting a particular variable
to have an integer value if some more later on in the code it shifts
to string
i might not be manipulating that getting actual values out but not what i wanted
him to be really hard for me to chase back
so one of the things i would like to suggest is that you develop some
good style here in particular
don't change types
our central can
meaning sometimes you need to do this but in general this at least in my
view on a drama degree you just don't want to do this you don't want
to make those changes this leads to trouble down the road
now let's think about variables and i'm going to start pushing on this is work
the answer is
a user variable
anywhere you can use the value
any place it's legal to use the value
this is just sort of bringing us back up to speed and adding a few
more details in what we really want to do not do now we start using
this stuff
let's take expressions get values out
we can store them away in places but ultimately we want to do something with
them so we need to now start talking about what are the things we can
do inside or any programming language to manipulate them
and for that we're going to have statements
when i think about it legal possible to use the word expression except misuse that
elsewhere so legal
python can enter
you've already seen a couple of them
two obvious statements commands to do something assignment is binding and name to value printed
saying put it back out on the screen obviously of princes away putting things that
we expect to have ways of getting input and we can see an example that
the second and if you go through the next two lectures run adding more and
more these statements but let's look at what we could do with this
and to do this i'm going to use some code have already typed in
so i'm hoping you can read that is also in your hand out this is
a little file i created
right and i'm going to start with
the sequence of these things and walking along again i invite you to put comments
on that handle so that you can follow it's going to do
so let's look at the first part of this right now this is just the
text file
OK and highlighted in blue up there sort of the pieces are going to start
with what i have a sequence of commands got an assignment statement
another assignment statement out of print statements about an input statement which will come back
to the second
and i want to be is basically trying to use these things to do something
with them
the second thing i want to note is the little hash mark the pound sign
OK so
in the first half i talked about how you would learn multiple is the feature
vectors in an unsupervised way
once you've done that
you can then fine tuning for discrimination
there's way fine tuning them
that is non discriminative that i've sort of suppression and talked about i'm talking about
how you can fine-tune them
and why you think get much better models
that is classification regression models than if you try and use only just go into
so it's been a long history of people saying that you should use discriminative training
rather than generative training if you wanted discrimination
and i give you some reasons of data and the tutorial why i think that's
completely wrong as soon as you have interesting data data with a lot of structure
and it is really pays to do
generative training rather than just going to training to begin with
one reason why it works better
to train a multilayer network generatively
and then discrimination
is the greedy layer by layer learning scales really well
you can learn one layer at a time you don't have to worry about going
backwards through many many many layers and is getting very small which is always worrying
so you don't actually start doing your fine tuning until
you've got a deep net with sensible weights that because each layer is quite good
reconstructing what's going on in before
and that means the derivatives are going to be quite good when you back propagate
they're not going to be tiny not going to be huge
you end up getting much better local optima
if you think about it
it's silly to use the local search great being non-linear space
by studying the origin hoping that it's you could by going downhill
you can find a good region that space to be
well you do it does unsupervised learning is going to a region of this great
big space and non linear functions
and you're doing that without using up any of the information in the labels and
then in that region you can do local fine tuning where you have to improve
things a lot
this is sort of
generalisation view of it
so you get better after
it's also much better way to use the information in the labels
images contain more information than labels usually
and often only some of them are labeled
so if you can design your feature detectors without using any labels
even if you have some labels then you got a very good start and you
only have to fine-tune them using the labels that just change the discrimination boundaries slightly
so your much better dealing with that there is much information about two labels
people in you should avengers group have done a lot of empirical research showing the
what i just claimed is true i'm just going to show you one of our
nation examples
the kind of digit recognition network at all about the other day was trained at
the top
to to learn a joint density
a sort of pure cases just to train it purely unsupervised so in the joint
density here is pure unsupervised then we stick ten labels on the top
we treat we only consider the forward connections now just back propagate through to train
these full connections more
and it turns out that helps a lot
so if you take the best you can do with backprop if you start from
random weights is like that
if you
first learn this model purely unsupervised then you have the labels and then you won't
forget you do this
more recently i've tried doing things like
when you add the labels
you make a lot of them wrong
and you still do very well this technique
we can handle lots of errors in the labels
shows you what happens when you do the fine tuning
these are the feature is the first layer feature vectors
and before you do any fine tuning
so here's the feature vector like this little piece struck with
but and most road nearby
he is the same thing after fine tuning and basically nothing changed
there's almost no change if you look at the coast of anglesey cheaper few degrees
of the most
so the fine tuning didn't have to learn the features
features sort of or what kind of feature that be it just made very slight
difference to a large number of features
and caused by doing that you can move discrimination boundary quite significantly
so what stories just relocating the boundaries right to get the right answers
but not really learning features
and that's where the wing comes from
those who is that this is same it's going to be in the region of
the space that you find with the pre training and then it's going to dig
a deep hole just and it's not going to consider all the rest of the
and to show that's much better than starting at the origin and wandering around
by gradient stochastic gradient descent
this is the test error a whole bunch of nets
these are ones
without pre training these ones with pre training
this was on
a data set made from the mnist digits by introducing lots of translations and rotations
and scalings so an almost infinite amount of data
it does much better when you the pre training
so the
topic for today
today we're going to talk and post linear equations the next time
instead of i think it's a good idea since
in real life most of the differential equations are solved by numerical methods
to introduce you to those right away
even when you see the computer we use all
the computer screen
the solution is being drawn
of course there
what really was happening is that the computer was calculating the solutions numerically and plotting
the points
this is the main way
numerically is in a way differential equations are actually solve
the any complexity at all now so the problem is an initial value problem let's
write a first order problem the way we talked about it on wednesday
and now all specifically add to that the starting point that you use when you
did the computer experiments and i'll write the starting point this way
the y of x zero should be
y zero
so this is the initial condition
and this is the first order differential equation
and as you know the two of them together
are called
and i vp
an initial value problem which means two things
the differential equation and the initial value
that you are
i want to start the solution that
the math
we're going to talk about
the basic
method of which many others are merely refinements in one way or another
is called alleles methods
did of course everything analysis
i didn't
as far as i know didn't actually use it to compute solutions of differential equations
is addressed was theoretical
he used it as a method of proving the existence theorem proving that solutions exist
but nowadays is used
to calculate the solutions numerically
and the method
it is very simple to describe it so naive
you probably think that if you have been living three hundred years ago you would
have discovered it and covered yourself with glory for all eternity
here is so here's our starting point
x zero
y zero
what information do we have at that point all we have is the little line
elements whose slope is given by f of x y
if i start the solution
the only way this solution could possibly go would be to start off in that
direction since i have no other information
at least it's career has the correct direction eg zero y zero but of course
it's not likely to have the correct direction anywhere else
now what you do then is
choose the step size all draw just a few
two steps to method
that's i think good enough
choose the steps size uniform step size which is usually called a change ge
and you continue that solution
until you get to the next point which will be at zero plus age as
i draw on the picture so we get to hear
we stop at that point and now
you read calculate what the line element is here
suppose here the line element now
through this point goes like that well then that's the new direction that you should
start out with going from here and so the the next step of the process
will carry here
that's two steps of oil is meant that notice it produces a broken line approximation
to the solution
but in fact you only see the broken line
if you're a computer
if you're looking at the computer visual for example which is whose purpose is to
well it's great for you while is not there
in actual practice what you see is
the computer simply calculating the point that point that point and the succession of points
and many programs will just automatically connect those points by smooth looking care
if that's what you prefer to see
that's that's all there is to the method of what we have to do now
to derive the equations for the method
we can do that well the essence of it is how to get from the
m step
to the employees first so i'm going to draw the picture just to illustrate that
so now we're not x zero but let's say we've already got into x and
y and
how do i take the next step well if i take the line element and
it goes up
that let's say because the slope is
this i'm going to call that slope
and so
of course a savannah is the value of the right hand side of the point
x and y and it will need an equation
but i think it will be a little clearer by just give it a capital
letter at this point
how this is the new point and all i want to know is what are
its coordinates well the axon plus one is there
the y n plus one is here
clearly i should rather trying to complete the triangle
this side of the triangle this the of news has slope a and
this side of the triangle has length h h is the step size perhaps i
better indicate that actually put that up so that you know the words
step size
it means health it's the step size on the x axis of far you have
to go to get from the x to the next one
what this well
if that slope
as this is the slope and this is a then this must be a times
link to that site
in order that the ratio of the height
so this with should be a
and that gives us the method
what's the
how do i get from the clearly to get from x and two x n
plus y simply at age that's the trivial part of it the interesting thing is
how do i get the new y n plus one and so the best way
to write it as that y n plus one
minus y and
divided by
well why and site why n
plus one minus y and is
is this line
the same as the line h times and so that's the way to write
since the computer is interested in calculating y n plus one itself
so on
it's insulting terrible
let's simply assume that our choice for given y
what is way to long enough is to advance to the next cycle
so we will have to the size of the green destruction green
in order action OK so really have to state the light
let me
we do this
so with sixty four states
OK so the action is just do i see any current lights data i switch
assume that all the issues with the time delays are taking care of
so what's my action space
so how how how how many
actions do have
four right good OK because for each flight
i can
or change
so the action of four actions
OK what my observation
set here
this is the question
my sense really tell me everything that everything that i can know about
the world
so what i could have done i could have instead
put the
sensors the the inductive loops
into the
observations that
first try that
is really
i observe inductive loops but those are way the observation what's actually going on
OK so instead listing my observation space
the standard inductive loops
now what's higher fidelity way of modelling stage
i just want the course price or not but i start to use observations
about cars cassie reductive groups over time
to start estimated
q length maybe
you know if you have five
like screen and you have twenty cars passing over that not while green
OK you can start estimate whether it's ten costcutter twenty professor how long q might
so in the noisy observation on the stage
OK so i
what stated me let me relaxed you links to b
real numbers
so you really cannot happen car
but it makes things a bit easier
so i'm going to say
for every q we have a real numbers see how long that q is now
expanded and so on which is
for simplicity was a through real number and we have four so there are four
so now how many
states do we have
the distinct states
infinity right
so your point six
today after this example on the talk about discrete states OK discrete is clearly the
simplest case or with its finite
i realize the real problems might have
elements the of the state space
now there are solution methods to deal with that i can't cause days
big big big at the time but there are methods to deal with
six this
this is a where have any questions about what my states actions observations are here
OK i observed
cars passing relieves every time step
whether or not use that to determine
estimates of the killing everyone
i also know inherently what the state of each
light is
and the actions i can take reach layers stay change
but as a no
we've got a few more things to do
so were function as
the observation function
the maps
observations and states two
so really activation function is the probability of a state
give an
what you observed a conditional probability
this model the complex
OK my one is kalman filter
something to try to model gal queue length
the on this course
as there was going going going to be
tel aviv probability so we we needed additional constraints that summer of his career observation
is some sums to one
assume that given observations i have the weight featuring this probability
are there any probability course will tell you ways to model that
transition function maps states actions to next states
with some probability
if we make markov assumption we can model this probability of as
so if i take a state action
we just think about
euzenat along that
bigger than little element like out then the probability of making an infected wound
the tiny
in a long time and you don't need to worry about real life
i think that in the short time intervals
and the chance thing on the pancake is tiny
it's gonna be
the volume of the banque de
in it in subspace the
thank you
we got at length write down the number of dimensions
well thank you
and then you divide by the volume that that there is a growing problem
this is
the probability of making that
and is
ratio of
tell that length over here that i want to raise possibly quite a big number down the number one the
we could easily be about
this is a disaster
make one
in fact if make it bigger than a little help
essentially the constrained
you can't
go there
at one greater than health
the bad news
because of
even though
you wanted to in order reduce you random what properties
he wanted to go there
you what we end up with saying that still make local
except for
very very small chance finally making a proposal
makes the night before
thank you so much what it happens so rarely
you don't want to be there
in practice
be feasible
values that's long
there are less
obviously don't want to make small so
it is where you want me
what somehow know what the smallest like nobody's business
and that's roughly what you want know i want to be
you're using in the problem with something simple proposal distribution like
are there
so in practice people using those all
the problem is that that
will then find
the optimal at all
is roughly
the smallest length scale
then when they run them properly with with the smallest lengthscale that prize
they will find
that they're expecting roughly fifty percent of the total be
the resulting optimal
although it
is roughly half
probably a little bit bigger than
but not a million miles from
so i went
eight years later and what
and now we want to do is revealed way that getting rid these random walk on
was shown here is not to which one is that we have a random walk behavior like counting methods
don't get around by random what that has said that in going in a particular direction
in some way
that's that's
you still at involved in growing like going in the right direction
you keep going on short time scales and in incident direction
so that's golden ball goal number two it's a pain in the neck
have carefully tune the side if you don't know what we should something a little problem is
it will really pay all we find out that uses like big
will likely be running a simulation that will be nothing left behind
to make it small you're wasting time order badly
it would be really have methods that didn't require this special events that have a
tuning that we now have a robot that self-tuning automatically chooses
the right that's
in a way that is valid or not using any sort of attack
so let's now
address but those
it is
so we have the through all these years there
we are now
five point one eight meters
quite impressive
so we have a pendulum with l
five point one was minus point o five metres we cannot measure it any better
by sending because it has to be on the stretch when we naturally
and now you have to go all the way to the ceiling and all the
way down
markus does that the risking his life
and he claims that the best you can do is five said we had thirty
one pounds hanging on the
we try during the summer believe me
we tried with technicians of MIT
have that kind of you
and then one day it looks good but finally said no we can do it
you can install it here's the safety issue
we don't have the money
of all patterns here
in twenty six one hundred twenty lecture
newtonian mechanics
i demonstrated
that the period that this pendulum produces
it's really close within the error of measurement which will predict
in other words the mass of the stream is indeed negligible is small
compared to the mass of the object we even though we really
string ones i remember i don't remember what it was but it was such a
small fraction
of and that indeed
could be ignored
and sort of prediction then is
if you simply put is alan there
he predicted
purely on the basis of that simple equation
equals four point five seven
plus or minus o point o two seconds
and this is o point o two is the result of this point of five
is one percent every in
right five out of five hundred eighteen
is one percent
and so aren half percent because description
so you get a half percent and i rounded off
so that's the prediction
and then the two measurements
one five degree angle
and one ten degree angle an idea that ten times
so ten t
five degrees
and ten t
ten degrees
but it was in nineteen ninety nine those were my good days
well my good times right that is always
the good
and so on
i then
claims that i could do this to an accuracy of o point one second
and a lot of current in those days and i met at the five degree
and what did i find
truly unbelievable
if you're really lucky
i found
exactly that number which of course is an accident because my accuracy was no better
than o point one seconds and then i did a ten degree angle
and then i found this
so i demonstrated
that indeed five to ten degrees i still considered small angles
four that approximation
and it is within the uncertainty of my measurement
what you
i wanted to demonstrate
which is not so intuitive
that the period is independent of mass
which is not the case for spring
so now if you change the mass
you don't change l
you expect
no change in period
and that's what i really wanted
to show you here
but i can
therefore i cited
show you what i did in nineteen ninety nine
if you can show is that two minutes
version of my
you can judge for yourself to what extent
the mass
does not influence
one of the most remarkable things i just mentioned to you
is that the
period of the oscillations is independent of the mass
of the object
that would mean
if i joined the bald
and i think that was the ball
that you should get that same period
we should do not
i'm asking you a question before we do this
awful experiments
what the period come out to be the same or not
some of you think it's the same
have you thought about it
i'm a little bit
following these objects
and that therefore
maybe effectively the
the length of the string has become a little less
if i set up like this
and if the length of the spring is a little less
the period would be a little shorter
be prepared for that
on the other hand i'm also pretty well i'm not quite prepared
i'll try
to hold my body is horizontal as i possibly can
in order to
b at the same level as the ball
so again here is restricted isometry property and if every presentable condition is somewhere in
the middle
and the restricted one i can condition i told you this way more on the
right and
in my view i would really claim europe presentable condition for the variable selection problem
is way more restrictive
then the compatibility condition or the restricted l one i can condition so
if you're interested in doing practical stuff
you should be very about preventable condition
OK so i think it's in a way not very realistic and so
all we can still run it i did run it i select twenty six variables
in my example so what can i expect from this
and he was kind of a nice story which i think is important to bring
our that in my view this one restrict restrict that what i'm about to condition
or ortiz compatibility condition is kind of reasonable in practice
so i
i told you before under these conditions we get this bound on the estimation error
and i think this is kind of reasonable impact
OK so i had this one
northbound bound
if this kind of more technical
four million here
but now this is really a trivial thought
now you say OK the hope is maybe to get at least as strong variables
so suppose some of the variables has huge quite regression coefficients can we get them
so i define not this is not the issue this is not the set of
active variables these are the variables which is have sufficiently strong sufficiently large coefficients to
s relevant rd
one which have sufficiently large coefficients and is actually just copied from this formula just
the larger in this bound
and i just say here then clearly and i mean this is really trivial suppose
you have one of these variables and suppose to estimate will be zero
and this is an immediate contradiction that you have to say one norm bound
again suppose he would say
they had to a zero
but in fact is larger than this cannot happen because you have this bound here
that has a very interesting interpretation so clearly i know
with high probability from this stuff with high probability the exact contains all the relevant
and that's great news in way
i mean this is only one side of the story but in a way i
don't miss them i get them and a couple of other stuff
so what i'm saying is screening for detecting the relevant variables is quite
likely to be possible in practice
OK i selected twenty six variables in my example it kind of means that through
stuff is hopefully among the twenty six
so now you can move on if you say OK you
a zero
i mean this is the active they actually all the nonzero coefficients are sufficiently large
then you have screening forty active
but that may be questionable assumption but if you're willing to say OK either zero
or their large enough then you know DS had from lots of real actually contain
two active variables
so i didn't say it was last stands for so tibshirani in this great paper
i mean coined the term lasts only stands for least absolute shrinkage and selection operator
and here is my new
translation of this i think it should be rated at least absolute shrinkage and screening
it's really screens in the sense of
you catch it but the couple of other stuff
you don't select really for a field
from a practical perspective
if you want to do that is still the land around right
and i decided know well and come up later to this issue from another perspective
but it's hard to get good land for selection
well maybe some BIC would do the job but at least nobody has proved that
is what i've seen something like that
you just trying to cross validation but the relevant variables or for the through so
in practice is kind of nice
you have maybe too small and they just get too many variables
now why is this interesting
the other issue which i should mention is what is the size of this is
hacked of course if you have this just all the variables you always have the
screen property that had an interesting screening operations it's hacked for any kind of london
in absolute value cardinality is less or equal than meaning p this is
trivial to show easy to show so the lasso selects at most meaning the variables
if p is in the ten thousand during the millions and then it into dozens
or hundreds you reduce two thousand one hundred variables
that's great
and so
this is really the screening is a huge dimensionality reduction for your problem i mean
in original called covariance are not doing some sort of PCE
linear combination are so it's just a huge dimensionality reduction in the original covariates and
it is a huge gain very useful machine
kind of in my experience
OK so once you have it once we have done this reduction
you're down to a couple variables so to speak
i mean if ten is not too large and then i just say no you
just apply your favorite method of choice it's not
very high dimensional anymore
OK people have done some things but typically what do some sort of reestimation
for example you choose water really squares reestimation you're smaller set from a zero
and you apply some sort of BIC penalty there
or you thresholding of the coefficients and all reestimation
or if you apply adaptive lasso
and so on all fours so the thing is really you cannot
do it in one stage
you do the first stage for screening and in the second or even third stage
you need to do something else to get rid of the false positive
OK summary two for the last
variable selection
so if you really want to infer is zero the two activities are very ambitious
goal and it requires necessarily
it is rather restrictive assumptions theory presentable condition and that the non-zero regression coefficients are
sufficiently large
both of them are restrictive but as a kind of indicated variable screening
is much more realistic it works with the much weaker restricted their one i can
condition and and then you get the results like this
if you
how many small
non-zero regression coefficient in the truth it would still get i mean the ones which
are real the large coefficients you get
and if you assume the truth is such that it's either zero or the coefficients
are sufficiently large actually screen for the true underlying it
again mainly focused on the lasso in linear models many extensions have been worked out
group lasso fused lasso so and so on and so forth some people but is
concave penalties they argue to have better selection properties scavenge seed class and so on
matching pursuit boosting
again on the rough scale
i would say it's kind of a similar story i'm of i mean the details
one of these
given the
so we can all
you will find a way to make them
so what
what about
call four
i wouldn't say what
we are one
what have
you have
the car is
what i'm going to
suffering from
sure there
so the
we need to focus on
you might
to that
march most
would be great
it's not like the
you know what
as a lot more
the boolean model
no they
the from
i'm sure
i have one of
so so
so o
so this seems to
you know you can which we can or
one class of people
now the one we are going to post
one of them
hi drawn on the left
but we're not
when i say
well we don't have
one with a lot of things that
you know
i do
i have had
what they did
there is a primary goal
what mean
or no
well what good thing
well what about these questions
so we have to
because you want
you know
we are one
are they a each
what what
well what is a
you can
we try to go
i e
can do
or that
with your
it is
we want
really hard
o thing
what you
there are no
and what
i mean
you have
she she
estimating it on
trick something
the next thing is that we can
remove that
expectation here
through the same
and we will only actually increase
the value
the reason for that is
OK we're still going to randomly trying to these expectations together on the outside it
so the reason we can move through the city
is there
if we have the
expectation inside the
we don't have the option of optimizing h with respect to a particular
and still
it's sort of h has to be optimized to the average of the still
but if the answer to the outside h has the option of not only optimizing
with respect to s but also with respect to us till
so we can do better you can actually get bigger
and therefore the actual expectation
will increase
can increase
so we actually get the
this is now
that was what we started with is less than or equal to
the expectation of the
with respect to the sample and the expectation with respect to the
go sample all of this
which was what was left inside
which is this summer
where we had the average of the
ghost sample and the average of the true sample and i just put the two
sons together make into single some
so now
we're at the point where we can do symmetrisation so things sort of go very
smoothly in this in this view of the world you know sort of
so what these things in as you go
symmetrisation will now correspond
to just
again with the same thing exchanging corresponding elements remember we took the first element of
the sample and the first element to the ghost sample and swap or didn't and
the first element second the second self
now if we do that that corresponds to just swapping these two
guys write z one until the and z one here
and said to till the and z two
what happens if we did what those two
all that would happen would be that the sign of this
some of this entry in this some somewhat change
OK instead of being a hz z i
so one till the minus eighty percent one it will be hz one minus hz
one till
if we made this one
so we can make this wall by just multiplying by
a minus one
so that's the next
sorry control night
you know that's right so that's the trick
it is to just put in a sigma i here
which is going to be variable which can be plus or minus one with equal
and that sigma into the expectation here
so that now is an expectation over sigma
and because of the fact that
the two samples are generated according to the same distribution
there is nothing special about
you know
as an as still there
the equivalent swapping will not change the value
of the
of the probability of the expectation
so exactly the same argument we had before
he was saying OK if you choose the sample and then apply a random permutation
it won't change the probability of that particular set of examples being generated
if we swap those two
it won't change the probability
it's just as likely under that
choice of sigma s under any other choice of sigma
so adding in those are not change the probability
so you know
things go very smoothly
and now on this point
what we're going to do is to
split apart this sum now
the two some something my age that i tell them
and something that minus some sigma z i
sorry seem i hz i
and then that the difference of two
things are going
band that by the sum of the absolute values of the two
individual sums but they're both the the same some effectively
that's something my agent said i expectation with respect to some
sample and we're going to also
take the suit into both of which again is just going to increase the value
because we can take this on either
so we just get twice
this value here
so it's quite a few steps in that stage from here to here
maybe it's a little
condensed but hopefully
you can see the basically
some here
and will be if you separate that will have exactly the same sum is the
sum will occur twice once was until the once was that i and effectively
we can take the issue to be super bowl
and separate them into two
and will only increase the resulting values
and so that just then to just comes outside and get this presentation is that
it's not okay i can write up some steps on the slide if you prefer
these people walking the plank