with this guy and I get a factor e to the minus 6 times in
from the exponential loss
but that has nothing to do with the integral is a constant as far as
the integrals concern because it doesn't involve T 1 and therefore I can pull it
outside of the integral sign and right that e to the minus finds a right
times the integral of 1 well e to the negative
you T 1
at 15 1 the
still integrated from minus the including affinity and now the final step this U of
T 1 is year-old for negative values of T
and therefore
it's equal to 1
for positive values of T is equal to zero for negative values of T which
means I can forget about the part of the integral that goes from negative 8
is 0
I better rewrite this efficiently than in other words this is equal to unity a
minus A times the integral from 0 to infinity of even the minus
OK let me do the shifty part
so I that we can do that
but that's since you of T 1 is equal to 0 4
negative values for is equal to 0 for less that that's why I can replace
this with 0 because from negative 8 is 0 nothing is happening the integrand is
0 and why can I get rid of it after that will because as 1
after that
and what's
this is will plus transform
now is not all plus transform they said because you had T when they're not
to error
it's all plus transform because this a dummy variability when I and is integrated out
to W variable it doesn't matter what you call it is still plus transform make
that we delete T or T star or
where you've psychical anything want and it's still global plus transform
so what's the answer therefore it so that's e to the negative AS times all
plus transform of function
that's what I promised uniform
now how about the other formula well let's look at that quickly but that's as
they say is a sleight of hand
of but since that's the formula you'll be using at least half the time you
better learn
but this little sleight of hand is also reproduce no 1 page of notes that
I give you but maybe you'll find it easier to understand if by talking allowed
so the problem now is for the 2nd formula what is
I need to know what the
look at the battery copy of the first one in order to make the argument
the form which you'll understand
so this goes to you the minus a after that
except I'm now going to write that not in effervescence I will not be able
to write the 2nd formula using events and that going to write it right the
1st formula we all alright as will plus transform the now formally
somebody said OK calculate all plus transform of this thing
I say put down this will has no t it it doesn't have the affinity
they're just then right this what formal I did I do I looked at that
you can figure out well you the better metric
and you can then the better metric you can then compute the score for the
and then you can see doesn't correlate better with human judgments are not so actually
machine translation evaluation
it's a very well-defined tasks
we have no several corpora annotated with human judgments of sentences
how what they are available since
they all these competitions and mt
you can download one of these different corpora
and you can come up with your own metric see correlate better than
the official metrics that are use
OK let me say a few more things to the blue so that the two
i want to point out where
thanks don't correlate well at all
so this is an example from two thousand five
so you this versus the nist evaluation of arabic english this kind of the most
popular contests
americans we love to translate arabic is very fond of arabic and the
they have every you know competition where
i want people to translate arabic and people both statistical MT machine systems basically sort
of different groups participating in that and you have the blue one and
and you have human gesture on the other hand and you see that one outlier
actually correlates pretty well except for the one of finding outliers
so that was that point
a graduate student at the university of edinburgh
who read the rules and said
well it doesn't actually say anywhere in the rules that humans can take the output
of the two system to fix it up
it's definitely not in the spirit of the game and he was very
explicit about and he admitted offers some people called cheating
but what happened the one system is just humans looking at the output
you know
english speakers in a number the nothing about arabic but they know what makes sense
in english
so it's not surprisingly that that these systems could very high fluency ranking before the
perfect because there's always someone is about better
judge of what is good english and what is a good translation and next
and i also got a very high edit pursuing
because sometimes you just
you know what the text is about can fill in the missing gaps
and you can put things until
you know things which are much more sense
it's also true that if humans reading flow in sentence so much more convinced that
it has the right meaning
even if it actually has some states
so that that's interesting outlier so this is
system that humans be like a lot
but the blues but doesn't like
OK that's a bit of things
he became across another example
and that's when we want to compare our cities counties systems for the best thing
out there which is commercial software model is that we thought so
the most popular system more commercially successful system machine translation
from any language pairs sister
company in france california
we translated text on the european parliament so we have a huge corpus course
the european parliament text we can learn machine translation systems
and people to define machine translation systems one good one
and one bad one it's very easy to build that he system so the trick
is to just use percent of the training data and of course you can do
and if you look at the two in SMT systems that kind of one that
diagonal that you want so the court systems is judged better by humans and by
the automatic metrics
but there
rule based system here this
gets just really harshly worse than all of that and he system by the automatic
but such
highly almost as high as opposed to the system by humans
so that's that's of course are concerned
so we have completely figure out why that is we noticed one thing that this
the rule based system of strong outliers
much more if you test in domain if you have a certain corpus and you
system runs all the right jargon and all the right words while the rule based
system might
say the same thing but uses different words
and of course that gets
punished them by the automatic metrics because you don't match exactly the right thing so
some mistakes that system makes sense of the european parliament
real mistakes so when you're for the enlargement of the european union
the system always has the widening of the european union
that does sound funny
but many of the things that the perfectly good words and good translations
so we think part of the answer is that
the automaton that is a little bit too literal you have to get their the
jargon right not just the word the
meaning right
and it's bit too sensitive to that
but it's actually still
so all of the main that that
problem shows up as well
so that's not all of the answer but that's interesting question but the nice thing
about this is a very well defined problem now so a few several corporal who
based on statistical systems are judged by humans have the automatic scores you can come
up with the metric that doesn't have these problems
and other that's definitely humans are very sensitive to
things being produced
things being very fluid and that that that does not only
in fact influence adjustment also biases that expresses just more or
yeah not really enough if you actually want people this question to the idea and
people say well the different version of the blues causing the some versions are much
more biased towards the so arguably if you just look at how many were said
to get right
that's more biased with adequacy but if you look for fourgrams
the new more biased towards fluency because you can produce fluent grams
so that was
so this is not a single reference translation he had four stations
well sort of
smaller or more
so so we often driven by necessity
so very often we only have one reference translation available so for certain been involved
in organizing
you know european language translation competitions
and what you do you take part of the training data sets test set don't
use for training and then you only have one reference sensation for the next revelation
there was produced for reference translation
please go to the third one from these other and
you get it on this
where w are you get to the point that of one
and it
all right
many it your way around
if you were
why don't directly
morning unless you gone
this is something that we don't have any real valued
and it
correct and valid and in practice the value eight
might be something like twenty o five
and additional work to get twenty drawn from this distribution
is quite helpful and not much work for example use adaptive rejection sampling
you if you're using a rejection rule
the first points in green
of an adaptive rejection sampling has the property that you get another minus one point
at almost no cost or all the work with
consumed in getting the on any other one week
is very very cheap and it may well
improve your random walk behavior
up guarantee that it is work on
and the basis of their local blogs
the whole inference using sampling
and but it's been around for about fifteen or twenty years now
way layer implemented sampling of all
these are different models used by the model
using a simple declarative language
and then it figured out how to run
and i'm pretty sure that the the but right now all the ordered pair
ordered overrelaxation built into them
so you can get this
speedup for three point in that that's it
using bugs
we've been going for an hour
so we just carry on with these advanced methods showed only the right
but what's going
start new
and now like to move on to the question about dependence on parameters
the vanilla
the trouble is that we talking about
use a gas in distribution somewhere and the with which were crucially important we want it to be
as big as possible and no bigger
when we use hamiltonian monte carlo there are similar but rather
gibbs sampling doesn't have any parameters which means that maybe like it
but if sampling only works if you've got a problem where you know how to draw
from the conditional distribution
and it may be that you are in a world where you just have a
clue how do the energy function is too complicated you can evaluate it you can't
draw from this distribution
it would be nice to have a automatically discovers result right the size
and that's what like sampling
we all know that
why something
slice sampling was invented by two people
rapid now
and it's very
amazingly simple looking way of the problem that simply can imagine schoolchild
and then in the end you might say
put up work
so let me show you
by sampling
all the first order
this little red one dimensional distribution idea quite something
if you can do it in many dimensions by doing one moment in time just like you have
but it's not like you pick a single by mentioned working
or a single direction be any direction you want in your or you can use
a new
you the math that i'm going to describe in one dimension
and then repeat in other dimensions
so his ideas
we have
and that's the red region
and we have a current location
it will collect it
and i'm not going to describe to you how we get the next location with
the first one
and it can be quite
a few steps so
that all you read
at the current location
we evaluate each stock
this a graph is not
then we
we draw a point uniformly between here
you start at x
and we can invent
o point on the telegraph or
we create
are the whole
where w is going to be at byproduct of the slice something that
value we don't care about very much because whole thing can be robust to it
that gets what the site might be
make a little bit like this
and there's a green thing
its i is determined by the i want
and it's all there
is chosen randomly uniformly from or what role
the two little
and that we all
you aligned why
this way or that way uniformly with the
thank you
so if it
the uniform price of this little horizontal
going up out of all
all right
the three is
check to see
the places
what value he said there
and what value if you are
the value star is about
the green line it is all works
that's not far
let's make an additional there
by w
and then check
he was checking out until when you check
i call our
although there
major advantage by
when the world
in this stage
that is wrong
they you have more than
they are
there is also a
the of
two of the dual problem is
weight that the there
even without help
which is more in the area
of the network
none of them match prior to the
two of a
so one
the other
we don't
and also
i do with my money
you are important for to
it was shown that some of the world there
we know about that so
maybe it will have to work
some of us
the can
the problem
it's here that the that
he should buy it now
i would have thought it was
showing that there
so the
there are going to want to realize what is what is to
well i e
it should be able to use that
so you
there are usually
the ship
i would love preservation that allowed
then you to two
it is using
so what
he was funded
so what we
i suspect
so far
so i
o for
he is more
you do
one way run the media is a strong
you can find it at all
because it is also possible to define the one
and as you can see
you know way you are in for you
all them the
it is used by more senior management
we should
if there is a little bit more and more actually
which leads
sound is
and there is a
is a
the station by
my sort of thing that would be
the the importance of the
our heroes so
i've been in
it's also all of these
is the wife or b
with i
five or only
the war not that are
i don't know
we need to be aware
we have
so agent
and then we
and they
the real
do that
on the day
little bit computer support them then you can finally come up with this with this
and it's it's from this because your computer scientist it's clear that you can encode
destroying here
with just a few bits of information with a racial program
there are of course many many other regular patterns
you don't have to use these for example most of my slides also because they
are constructed by recursive applications of the harmonic proportion the golden ratio
which some
his claims is preferred over other ratios
you know before i came here i thought this is going to be just another
ECML PKDD conference and there won't be much of an audience but you are actually
aligned audience by my standards
the other day i gave a talk and that was just a single person in
the audience
a young lady i said young lady it's very embarrassing
but apparently today i'm i'm going to give this talk just feel
and she said
OK but please hurry
i got to clean up here
so what is that about jokes how does all of this have to do what
does this have to do with jokes and humour and and the answer again it's
very simple every child has the punchline the punchline is designed to be unexpected to
those who don't already know the if you're all the jokes is totally boring but
if you don't know the jobs and there some
you need extra bits to predict the thing so you predict something but it's not
what you predicted so you need extra bits to store the stuff that you can
couldn't predict well however all the jokes that he signed to
two have regularity that relates the punchline back to the previous story in the way
human learning algorithms
easily pick out
and so immediately the learning algorithm kicks in
and recognise that the punchline is related to the rest of the story in a
way that allows you to
save bits because all you need to insert there's a point to previous part of
the story so i showed you can again get rid of these extra bits added
that said you didn't expect and not safe bits
that's the fun that the number of bits that you're saying the first derivative of
the compressibility
that is your interns
that's what you're trying to maximize the actual CD the action selected
the actors selected
just as the usual thing that all reinforcement learning algorithms still namely trying to
generate more data which also has property that its
and so for example one possible action could be just stay seated and and wait
whether this comedian has another interesting thing to say
so learning from previous experience to predict which other things in the future it might
adding something to repertoire of novel patterns
which then so none of novel anymore
here we are in spain and the recently
i had the great honour and pleasure to
to give the scientific talk very much like this one to the king of spain
at least he said that he was the king of spain
in fact what he said was if if you are scientist and i'm the king
of spain
if you want to build an artificial scientists and artists
we have two questions what kind of compression algorithm prediction algorithm to use and what
kind of learning algorithm for this method and the other one is what kind of
reinforcement learning algorithm to be used to maximize the intrinsic reward signals that we are
getting as the other guys improving so
the reward
maximize has to be smart enough to deal with the situation where the intrinsic rewards
coming from the system
and influenced by the limitations of the learning algorithm of the other system vanish over
they vanished because obviously as the compressor predictors learning about what's going on in the
the high order markov chains was true
because if you had a second order markov chains
is of the next
depend on the past from the last two states take the was
of states
state space which is pairs of states markov chain so i always thought it's just
markov chain theory
that's true
chemists were very consistent but want to keep things reversible the subject of
higher order markov chains doesn't exist as far as i know so now it does
but that's something to say
say it at great length but it exists to define things so
markov chains
the chance of the next given past depends on the last or states
stochastic process in school
the tragic to be reversible with different the reverse i said before if
the graph is the same as the of backward to the
the x that's one of x should be the same messages in stationarity should be
the same as the change
those xmxn minus one of x not for being so
that is reversible and
physics sense of
time runs backwards is the same this time and forwards and so there is the
space the space of
second order for example markov chains you could ask how priors on that
could be factors to test if your processes markov was the second order markov and
so forth in the same group ten
but instead of having to work out of the
works going to
one thing you need to know about the brain graph and that's familiar object in
both combinatorics and other parts of the world now because of the small pins people
use familiar that in the graph is a graph
in which the vertices or this one companies
connect to this one examples
couple which starts
the first time minus one topic
the second one minus one table i should have a picture but i i don't
if you so that's from the complete graph but if you have restrictions on the
edges you can see see that what we found is that
so if you
this is
are indexed by
sapir was
this is from BBC to scene simply because that would be ceasing begins with a
scene with c c
OK if you do a random walk with reinforcement of the brain
of course during the kansas state each time and it is so without without
going to work
the that but don't partially exchangeable mixture of conjugate priors in the theory goes through
so high
reversible markov chains in pretty good shape for this i never
in fact the technical papers they think about the message
second order markov chains which or
so this the kind of markov chains with many of you can go in the
direction we want to keep going in that direction
that's useful important just as position
and the
ingredients and mechanics
i mentioned the markov chain theory and it's quite useful radford neal in his own
way has been
put it in china has been stumbling around in the same
and is something that is very interesting
corner space it's it's quite different from from
reversibility is you'll see if you just think about second order reversibility because if you
go to pillars is not the case that reverse trajectory reversible second order markov chain
has its per process
reversible it's different different subjects and OK can have the next transparency
one of the the things to do is to
both math scientific problems out of the river
the problem of
of understanding the priors so if it is going to be pretty big spaces like
prior on the right
well i don't know if people don't seem to ask that question so often but
i'm asking and so is the start at the kinds of things that you could
about what properties of these priors
so suppose i
in the simplest case just to start with namely me
by the transition matrix and each of the rows
independent and if so uniform vector on the simplex uniform vector the simplex independently that's
probability distribution on transition matrices
what's the distribution of the stationary distribution we're not enforcing that
it's a problem not the distribution of the three three french to french and italian
showed up and it's sort of large
you know the it's sort sort of one of the brain which that the stationary
it converges to a point mass one over and over and when n is large
one of the
that seems like it's all the same setting
i wouldn't mind
going on
how we have to
i would like to go on place so the proof is there if you want
to see
again is approved there
wind w
so the lemma is
if box find is in w exactly when for all v and w
WRC flies five it's a it's is the box flies in w
exactly when the area there you go
using your reachability relation
five w
it's just by the definition
the other direction is something that you have to prove all of this
stuff about local deducibility
and this is this is where it's absolutely essential to use local deduced in it
doesn't go through
this thing here
is an infinite formula k
so what you need is you need the local deduction says no no it's not
that i'm interested in
there some finite subpart part of which gives me the deduction that i want that's
absolutely essential for the process to go through
so what's the truth lemma states kids now where
getting to the end of the day is that
this lemma says that we can lift the membership from at formula
a particular phi
is w
particular finding that w then u k
phys true that w
we've lifted development
and this one it induction on the length of the four
so the base cases
why does it the way we define the evaluation
i assume it's true for all formulae of length
i assume that you have the formula of length n
in this case it's the
pushed induction through
maybe maybe i'll do this one so we have
so we want to claim
is equal to true
OK what is it it's
he is
c and w that definition of the information
in your class of world
when have
it is in one step as successor of w and
the valuation thanks
so the the
i called the truth
that's the definition of when
box formula is true it
i've just written definitions
now you say well
there is some
the which is related to w
we have to show
the c
maxiter what does that mean lies inside the
so what have we got we got exactly that picture
we've got the here
bauxite is true in other words it's a if and only if
five xtri here five smaller formula hypothesis applies
everything goes back to that definition of the reachability relation
how does the actual completeness
so we started with
wanting to show
from this to this
we had no handle
the opposite if we assume that there is no
these deviations from the status
this status consistent if the gene the generative bayesian deviation is has the same sign
the status of b so this means that if a is evaluating someone with the
heart with the positive status meaning higher status than himself should be positively surprised you
should be more like to generate minus any if a evaluate someone with the negatives
that the source that is smaller than you should be more negative than what he
usually so he's baseline is sort of deviation based negative and then for the conceptual
basis for the set apart from the viewpoint of this is that the opposite right
so so the action is status consistent when when somebody of high-status evaluates mission gives
me minus right so so this the sign of evaluation has to be different than
the that the status of course evaluating me and similarly if somebody of negative status
evaluates me
then perhaps most should be plus OK so this is how now established this predictions
and as i said before sort of for the deviation to be consistent with balance
it is just whether it completes a balanced rider so here are a few examples
so this is now exact results for epinions dataset so what i have here is
sixteen prior
this is the count of how often does each of these triads appear some appear
like three hundred thousand times the
less frequent plants appear only of two thousand one times here is the probability of
that prior being closed by plus right so one was friend of a friend
and this one is closest plus ninety seven percent of the times
and then what you have here is also the deviation in the in the baseline
so what is the way you should understand somebody that up person who is who
appears itself in a friend of a friend relationship there ninety five standard deviations more
likely to give up less than what we usually and the person that is assuming
that is two hundred standard deviations more likely to receive applause than what they usually
get right so what i mean by this this is
like everything bigger than here is is significant so this is like super significant right
on this one for example would be negative edges and again when you have enemy
of the enemy
you you you tend to close that stupid things like the the random worked closely
with eighty percent probability right to close you close to plus fifty percent which is
sort of a seven hundred standard deviations more negative than what usually
and then what they show here
it is whether the behavior is consistent with balance and the behavior is consistent with
standards and for example here is that here is one of the cases where i
stand this makes correct predictions but balance makes wrong prediction so this is a prime
number nine that's the example that i have x positively evaluating a and b
for example balance in one case would say that
then the edge should be should be negative while the status correctly makes a prediction
that a will be positive the deviation of a positive but deviation of the will
negative right and then there is another example for example the eleven where now i
have positive edges pointing downwards so again balance would say
put the glass here what we see is that actually people tend to give one
minus so even though there it's a friend of a friend but in the wrong
direction people given negative evaluation which is again consistent that this so overall what we
see is the balance
correctly predicts about seven eight of these triangles and status correctly predicts fourteen or fifteen
out of sixteen trying so it provides a much better explanation too happy people create
these pages
another thing that that another sort of more more global level of analysis you can
start asking what is the probability of an edge how does it depend on how
embedded is how many common friends and and what you see from here is that
the more he invented the edge the more likely it is positive and this is
like the the baseline there would be no effect so basically what is so that
means that networks are globally threatened supply stand to according to in places where the
network is there's connection there are many common friends and then minuses are where there
are few human friends in common which means like we like strategies is no friends
in common very likely to be minus many friends in common much more likely to
be different so this is another type of information can have about these networks
the reason why i was sort of showing this because this is what i would
like to do i would like to go and be able to predict whether a
pair of people with friends or enemies right so my my my my second is
the following i'm having this sign signed network pluses and minuses on you know on
the edges and now
given the network and when all the signs but sign one edge predict what is
the sign on the so what want to give you want to predict what is
the sign up on that that's so basically whether you're going to be friends or
this is a very simple like having formulated simply as possible so i want to
predict the sign of jury i have a binary classification problem
so the positive class is that this is the friendship negative class means this is
not the friendship my my prediction methods be very simple logistic regression i will do
this on a data set where we stop writing subsample positive edges so that the
random guessing would be fifty percent accuracy
my my evaluation metric here in this talk will be classification accuracy another question is
what are the features that place-kicking duties logistic regression and here are different types of
features so the first set of features is simply lost
is to generate the vector of sixteen numbers that just count if is that i'm
interested in predicting in what kind of does this edge appeared right so for every
possible try and i have a feeling i come across and i just count in
common triads like this is this
embedding comment i think that it is that you can give me account of sixteen
that's the for the sort of the first set
just says how is this edge locally embedded in the network and then the second
part is a sort of more summary statistics like what is the size of the
sign in and out degree of node u and really what is the total degree
what's the total number of triads or embeddedness of this what is the number of
common friends between you and me
here are sort of the results of the the thing is
use that idea and our narrates like this between twenty two six two to six
percent so this means that one we on epinions we can predict whether people trust
one another with the ninety three ninety four percent accuracy we can do the same
on slashdot and wikipedia the prediction of the prediction results around eighty percent so so
if random guessing due fifty percent accuracy
this very simple feature vector of sixteen c sixteen items gives you ninety three percent
accuracy on two datasets eighty percent accuracy on the other data and sort of this
this this corresponds to a compares favourably sort of previous work that was published about
two thousand four by all
the red where they were really doing some kind of trust propagation through the network
and the error rates there
much higher what also comes from here is is that slashdot and opinions seem to
be very easy to to model and predict while wikipedia seems to be much harder
to predict
another interesting question you can ask is that because we have this very different datasets
how how so you know the people use do people create positive and negative edges
differently in these different datasets so what i will do is a very simple experiment
i will ask how generalizable i'm not my results or my models across the data
sets so what i do is i will bring my model i'm showing knowledgable where
i will bring my model in the real world datasets and i make the prediction
on the column dataset OK so here is here is what i mean by so
for example the edit here means that i bring my model and opinions but i
evaluate it on slashdot today
you i have some entity
to a page that describes the entity then feel free is the appropriate coatings
so this is this
so called hash sorry is the so-called slash approach because the u i has basically
at the last step special character
then there's the other approaches to hash approach
we would end up with something
so basically we take the generic document URI brand telescope about
and then we append hash
something that's a hash it's for example
this gives us a different URI
so the page one URI the generic document has one URI
and the brand of whisky has different URI
but if we look up to see why
initially p lookups
offer you are with the ash something at the the end they have something to
be ignored and the HDP interaction so this means
if we make an actually if you look upon this URI then that's part will
just be ignored and we end up again with the generic document
so no no it's just whatever whatever you want
it's personal preference properties whatever
the about what's the generic
document where get the HTML document or the RDF human
well you
that's right
so in this case he was the has URI we don't work
so you're talking just about the history like it or
right i see you
you mean like OK so in this case here
we could actually
it would be OK to just kind of you know this part doesn't really have
the same if we say we do this we do this has URI approach
you know this is one of the then we could just say you know this
about party it doesn't really matter
because like telescope we have used this URI for anything yet so we could just
say this is a generative we could just append the
the the the hash it
it's the different i again the requirements are fulfilled
sure should i mean that the words in the u i don't matter at all
the important thing is
it needs to be like
o and don't use the same but i four two different things
like for the page and the entity
and then the new
so we need one for age and the different one for the entity for the
for for the brand
no no because
no you
if you do the first three
but the way
the way i describe it like the way you
the first redirect from
alaska talisker slash about the history of
but then
you don't need to do any further redirect but you can surf whatever variant you
want from that URI the generic document URI i
so you don't need a redirect from
from about to about HTML to about the end of each image you don't need
to do redirects there
just directly to
the english version of the at
right at the generic document your
note is basically
could probably do with that you could do it with with with
you are we writing but that's again
depend on whatsoever using and it's kind of an implementation detail at the same time
you could
you know if this is like a php script that processing the request
the description could just look at the except error
you could just call the
appropriate function in the framework that produces the HTML or the order of
so what
but the
key point
for implementing continuity if you don't need to do any redirects you can
you can be turned to serve you can set up to serve in the way
that we experience the appropriate content
just depending on the except without the redirect
to put this on the location header into the response
so the client knows oh by the way if i want to that particular area
five and twelve month one together and the likelihood function has a nice speak
we can
i think a bit more about what this function actually is how does the function depend on the data
well this particular function depends on the data in this way
it's got z
lambda and be
and it's got e to the minus let's take this right
so socket upstairs even minus some
on lambda
is all you need to know in fact
i am rewriting the likelihood
so the brilliant intuition that said why don't you just compute the mean of the data
it is exactly right if all you're trying to do is inferred lambda assuming there's
one exponential then the only thing you need to know
it is the sum accent
andrew then you can work out the likelihood function so you don't actually need to
know all the data points the twentieth places you just need for some of
the cost of this particular form
of the probability density
if model that look like this it would be in the mean that is the thing you need to know
but the general lessons drawn from this is not ok so now i need to
compute the mean my data i can solve any problem
what you need to do
his work at the likelihood function and the likelihood function will tell you what you
want to do with your data and in this case the answer is to find
the mean
and then
what the likelihood function and on the screen we have a likelihood function there
i can
re-create these because we're just looking at
here are
just repeat the sequence it
there are three probability densities over data space
o x three different values of lambda
you can imagine getting data at point such as three or five or twelve
the predictions are these different models for different values of lambda are simple exponential that
something you can notice about them
is there are places for example the left hand blue line
where the red is about the orange is above the yellow
so the red wings it predicted better
there are places where the yellow is about the orange above the red
and there are places where
the orange is thought
so there are
such that any of those three can be the winner in terms of having predicted better
and the other two
and that's another way of saying
when we put the likelihood function there may well be at peak as a function of lambda
so now we do that's we plot the likelihood function
hand this is the likelihood multiplying together those three
and i've shown in red orange and yellow here
the three values lambda that we were considering above we look lambda as two five and ten
this is when you get data
at least three
the three points
i mentioned before
you could
stable time scale
rule can
so just going through these sequence again
his three places you could get data
left endpoint points to
the red hypothesis being the most probable
data point five
prefers the hypothesis that lambda is something like five
and data points at the right hand side preferred hypothesis that lambda might be ten also
to the hypothesis that lambda is to a five
so this is what the likelihoods look like if you get just one data point
that is respectively at three or five twelve
andy this is the product of
so that's based thereon
finding a single parameter lambda
and it wasn't easy because all you have to do
was right
three lines
the new plot to define the function and now we've got this one tells us
the answer
thank you very much be before we start
and we start to look at the material and we've we've got some great stuff
i'd like to ask you to help me out with what is one of the
most important parts of today's presentation
i'm going to ask you to do do something for me to worry it's not
very difficult and and then
the rest of the time i didn't work so if you would please stand up
put your hand on your heart
so on this side is turned to face the back of the room
now very carefully because of the the furniture take one step forward
and so as to thank you very much please sit down again please sit down
that's wonderful thank you
i said that was the most important part of the presentation not for you
that's the most important part of the presentation for me i work for this gentleman
here a gentleman called but he
he is the founder of our company
and he has what he likes to call
a hands on
approach to the business
we like to say he tends to interfere in everything and
sometime in the next week or ten days
but will calls that standard
and you say tell me first and what did derek do for your audience in
now i like this job
i get paid for doing this job
and i get paid very well just for doing what i like which is talking
that's what irish people like to do so i want to protect that so
now she can say in all honesty all o
he got them on their feet
he touched our hearts
he turned them around and he got the moving forward so for three months job
security and now in your that now i o u and i need to give
you some good information this morning the rest of the work is mine
from this point forward
in slovenia
as elsewhere
and coming from ireland i can appreciate exactly the challenge that every leader in every
economy has today very simple
if in this room you have leader
or manager
or group lead or anything like that in your title
this is the only thing that matters
in the last two years particularly i guess
we've all been under pressure to make sure that the bottom line stays
so when when things got started to get even tighter we cut down the costs
is as much as we can that's that's what you do
and that in fact
in bad times teachers anything
they teachers that in good times we get lazy
and sometimes we have costs there we didn't really need
but i would say it's safe to say
at this stage
we have trimmed down costs pretty much in every organization everywhere as low as they
can go
we engineered processes
we looked at any way that we could do business
that would make things more effective more efficient more productive what we did that too
and now we're at the stage in twenty eleven
where the but he needs of your world
what the shareholders the company owners of whom every reporter says hey you did a
great job
but i need another twenty percent this year i know of no twenty five percent
this year january one is always
the time when you both celebrate
and commiserate because in my company does a great job derek around thirty five percent
we need forty five percent this year and that's the same in organisations
over the next while
the only way
we can actually achieve
that additional productivity
running the very lean operations that we have now
is if we can make each
and every one of our people more productive
if we can get more from each and every one of our people
now the extent to which we can do that is really the extent to which
they want to give us
that extra productivity is the extent to which they are engaged
a dazed is a i really want to do this job to the best of
my ability
i am so interested in this organization and what i do and what we're trying
to achieve that i'm even going to give you some of my time to get
this thing
and in
just about every country worldwide
we have about twenty percent of people
four engaged
twenty percent of people who are positively disengaged that is
if i can break this company i will
and then the floating sixty percent middle who are
one of the day i'm engaging on a bad day and disengaging is i give
you an average
why is important
because basically there's an enormous difference
between the results that engaged are organisations with high engagement get
it did this one study
by the towers parents you can see one of the larger ones
about eighty thousand watts at eighty thousand ninety thousand people
eighteen countries worldwide
and i found very simply
hi engagement companies
dramatically outperforms low engagement companies that makes sense
if the people that are working for you are genuinely dedicated
getting the results you want to get of course you're going to get fifty one
percent greater operating income than the average and of course you're going to get greater
earnings per share
in twenty eleven
twenty twelve
twenty thirteen
engagement is going to be
really one of those
those issues that is going to become the primary concern of anybody
was the manager later
currently of course
were tied up in in dreadful economic challenges
but hidden behind those economic challenges
is an issue that hasn't gone away
and that is the demographic issues the fact that
in ten years time
i will be more sought after
and customers are
so engaging the people we have one
so they get the results we need today
and two
so that when things start to look better they stay around
that's what it's all about
and they are
thank you
talk about
it is
thank you would
basically it
the main
we can try to
two but
this all
you will be in the image
and it is
it is
because the
he was
we know other
how can
the college
the one
this collection
find that
and people who you are or what the need of
what they assume that
which is
actually are relevant to each
hello my
so we have a u
because of it's oil was the first of all i always trust
for people
and so on but again and again because of the way
that's just a little bit more than just the words
that is true
combined with
so i
and by the
read to us
another way to use image grouping and the most popular way in medical college
is the same idea still images have really just so we have support
which is which belongs to one
but you that these groups are called by way
so medical images
these sometimes doctors
b is not actually a lot
images are just like think that this is the same
it is some kind of mind
it's a good way
compare the collection using these girls but it is very time-consuming
two such groups
another the way
quite likely to
researchers tried to make
this is
exactly like but
so to their similarity to the might
because they are
well no
actually the US
so idea is that
one way that
so called legal
we all want and what they are in the end we
built up
and also that
it is that we can define a
the one was the
the problem with a
that's right
if this is the most relevant to the
right now
we can
on the right
usually one
subject object
the fact that the government
most of
does all this mean
the first
the beach is the class
here is
this image is query and this is the same
and the results of the system
can you tell me which one is better
which one is right
one of the main
assumes the
this is
actually i can and i don't think that i would like to use this image
close one aquarium here on the second place so on this that one is better
does we can do this and i were forced to
one is that the also to see system some action
you can select query registered works quite well
and you can put on your user page
the square and say
it's just not my
the best
because the image is the the most
and they
there's an article in another query which doesn't work
and the you use compilers
again the only
i'm charging to that
calculation of i and j
that calculation one j
so you can view it in terms of
analysis of bookkeeping argument
just as well the charge
in to
not to calculate my own to do all my own local things close enough to
the value in the next one
get returned
OK and then it has go calculate well that's OK that's all been charged
i j one
for every cell only cost me constant time where mn cells
the water and then
four per entry
and you can start using advertised analysis story
how much space does it take
if you're just start looking at space
it turns out for some of these out really important
based on
storage space
also in times and
historically CIJ table
the restoring x and y
that's just
plus and so that's
negligible but mostly i need the
memoisation five algorithm is is a really good strategy and programming
for many things
when you have the same parameters and you get the same results it doesn't work
in programs where you have the side effect
it's certainly is when you're
when you're the calculation for given set of parameters might be different on each call
four was something which is essentially like functional programming type of environment
and you can calculate once you can look it up
so this is very helpful
it takes a fair amount of space
it also doesn't proceed in in very orderly way
so another strategy for doing exactly the same calculation
in a bottom-up way
that's what we call dynamic approach
the idea
just use
this board
so here's what we do is look at the CIJ table
i realize is actually an orderly way
of filling in the table
top down
OK but there's actually way we can do it
here's the
the idea
let's make table
so is x
here's why
and initialize
these cases
four CIJ
but c is zero meaning are prefixed with no
elements in it
critics that with anything else link is zero
OK so that's basically how
i found the supporters here
now what i can do is just use my formula which are raised there
to compute
what is the longest common subsequence link the longest common sense subsequence
from this character
and why in this character next to this character
here for example they don't match
the maximum of these two values
here they do match
it says it's one plus
and the the original nineteen this is not entity extraction the practical problem here is
hard to find
people who are experts in this area who are not maybe specified of being experts
in this area in the skills database because
they might have just use different
different names you could say i'm an expert in search information retrieval and i might
not find you or they have just not updated their skills so
and the way how this process goes is that what we did is very simple
approach and so if searching expert in large interactive displays
all the aquarium my enterprise search solution we are here using an SP solution and
i'll get a bunch of documents now from the documents we can extract entities this
doesn't have to be done on the fly it can be done beforehand and this
means people
who appear in these documents so what and that is just a list of the
four hundred five hundred entities that are relevant to my topic
OK so now i wanted to brand this because we wanna find the best experts
in this area and to do this very simple so we took each of the
entities and and the to the initial inquiry so new query would be large interactive
displays plus the first entity kelly and we get about a set of documents for
each combination of original query and entity and now what we do is simple cosine
similarity between the to both sets of documents
so what we wanna find is the closest closest sets of documents
all for a query and and fifty two do or to the set of documents
corresponds to the original
a topic and what get in this way is the rank of entities this we
get who's the best experts in the area
now this seems like a simple approach we tried to do this with the text
from the documents but the results were not is this actually using them at the
metadata and the parts i mentioned in the previous slides
so people are very simple so in order evaluate we actually
deployed it in our enterprise search solution and i'll actually show how it looks like
i think that so this is how erm sable like search and browsing of large
because most of the documents in their repository not but i think around one-third is
powerpoints and there's a lot of graphs inside including in office documents that's where there's
a lot of graphs there is a need for visually seeing
well what is inside so here the was for as i can sort of browse
through the case something
companies do ask for
so what
OK so i can browse through the content of the document descended from wanna downloaded
instead of actually just
if of actually just downloading and finding out that in this one hundred page document
is not what they need when we first introduced this people were really impressed because
what they had before is just the box and google type of center books with
a list of snippets of
text snippets and they didn't know what was the document was about and this is
how we actually got our use of these people were really interested so here you
can actually go from documents which on documents OK so here in the filters correspond
to some of them
metadata fields it's we have
the automatically so sensitive search
but what's my interest is the experts i mentioned so for instance i can search
for help
the data mining code
so i did should get list experts
and here there should be for some reason i mean if it can just be
their profiles pulled pulled from the
official central positive saying could they are way of what is it belong to what
has been by
the day by the office times they dealing with they works time-consuming finally can filter
based on their levels and
based on locations and different thinks OK so
i'll talk about
OK so we
tried the same experiment
but we had this interactive bot which i is now accounts baby here was we
give the solution to our users that they can search for some topic and a
list of users of the online will appear and then what happens here is there
was a lot of vanity searches so the users were not finding themselves to the
top they believed they were experts they really unhappy so we had to some to
somehow compensate for these vanity searches but making sure that your name appears in the
first ten experts you can't kind of bumped up to be the first one and
then all sort of happiness OK the system sort of works that's bad and this
present believe about this is that is used as much as the expert search there
because i think people have to go to another IM client and search for something
them more willing to search within the our sable application but interesting
and the the IM bot also had support for time zones people connected to the
people which are online the an interesting thing is once we found out we believe
the two an expert in in this area we send out emails of asking them
to to confirm if their experts in this area as and actually got can quite
nice responses people i would go and they can look and say yes i AM
so the others and was performing of very low it very well in an applied
deployed environment
OK so
reusable information about quickly these that we thought we were to uses graphics and why
because as you've seen sable there are lots of new information and power powerpoints made
make more than one third of documents in a repository so we thought we developed
this enterprise taxonomy which was things like architecture diagrams it's not very easy to that
they had to achieve diagrams but that's might be what i'm actually looking for might
be looking for an picture bagram for active project so if it's a powerpoint is
the one hundred slide document i would have to download and find it so it's
not very easy to find those what we did this is sort of relatively simple
so in this sense you can say
your characterising how many support vectors like it in the solution or how many points
do i to i trust how many points do i want to satisfy the margin
condition is how many points but i allowed to be margin errors
six i
because of the course i should have been more explicit about this
so size is the variable of the optimisation problems and i so i will
along fault lines to violate
the street
inequality constraints
and if they violated then discs i will grow but because i will be penalized
in the objective function so in some therapy optimisation problem just like w and a
and b
so initially we just we're looking for wnb this where the parameters governing the position
of the hyperplane but now we're saying we will optimize not only the position of
the hyperplane but also
how many points are allowed to violate
the separation conditions and by how far they allowed to violate it so now XII
is also one of the primal variables of the optimisation problem
and if you know compute the
derivatives of this
to offer new levels in which i haven't written down with respect to w signed
now you get three conditions people we had to
if you substitute these three conditions into the kind of you can get to a
problem but the dual problem doesn't depend on i
just like didn't depend on w b before
so you don't have to worry about twenty at the two dual
more questions
so at the end of the of the optimisation
all margin errors
we have enough i so in this case
all margin errors will happen i find that c remember the model there is a
subset of the support vectors
and all the other support vectors will have the value of five that somewhere between
zero see but it could also be zero or it could also be seen we
cannot say anything about this we can only guarantee that the margin errors will happen
five which is c or in this case in the new SVM would have enough
i which is one of them
so far the modern errors with the upper boundary
here the new optimizer will the show crash i will not give you results if
the problem is not solvable you don't allow for this
it is solvable
he is actually starting to ask this question me
go back to this live skit
so it turns out you can interpret the fires as some kind of forces that
you want you want to think of it in terms of mechanics
in this analogy you assume that each support vector exerts a force
of size of i
and direction why i'm on some kind of sheet which is lying along the hyperplane
so you have to support the one class the pushing the one that support vectors
of the other class pushing in the other direction and the size of the size
of the forces
and i remember we had this constraint here on the
derived by taking the
derivative of the
derivatives of the
primal problem with respect to these
the primal variables so the derivatives of the log on june sorry so the first
one was this equation here
now i remember said that i five i think this is the force and y
is the direction of course this means
all the forces sum to zero
which is one of the conditions for mechanical stability
but in addition
this thing here implies that the torques sum to zero chance of a second
so the second condition which is true at the optimal
implies that the torques sum to zero because we compute the talk so i have
to take the the cross product between the points where the forces exerted and the
size of the force times the direction of the force of this is just a
unit vector along the
normal hyperplane so this is the talk
if you're an engineer offices you probably
know all this but after another this cross product this is by linear i can
move over these alpha i y i
the left side
and then i see OK this is w again so i have actually w across
divided by something and
the cross product between two vectors that are parallel vanishes
so mechanically
the hyperplane lives such that the solution of the optimisation problem is mechanically stable in
the sense of the forces summing to zero and talk summing to zero
does that answer your question
OK so the mathematical argument is
i guess i mean it's hard to give
mathematical argument is that people have proven that by minimizing this with respect to w
and b and maximizing with respect to the dual variables you do get the solution
of the problem and so
it's difficult to say something precise
without going through a lot of algebra here so what i was trying to give
an intuition that these five can take various values there is no upper bound phi
will increase
and WP will work against it at some point w left change such that the
point is classified correctly and at that point i would have a certain value which
is then the force
so maybe more questions
it's this is sort
more or to say i would say
we can be the same to be a little bit more precise as to make
the kernel morning non-linear are easier to separate the problems
and in that case the
the difference between training error and test will increase
so the difference between training error and generalisation error
will increase but of course you might have a problem which is not linearly separable
to begin with
in that case the linear separation
with slack variables so with a lot of training hours will not do well on
this problem because if the problem is not linearly separable then linear separation were not
generalize well even though it will probably have the property that the difference between training
and test error small but if the training error is already very large then this
is this isn't isn't going to help you so
but basically you intuition is correct
and more questions
that's what
his next
so actually then the next thing is something slightly different and maybe
maybe out before the pink
actually no i'll do the
to give you a cluster views logically speaking you could believe some of these things
are not all of them a set of views that many of you probably believe
and i imagine most if you believe that lists some of these things so here's
the set of common views
first of all that we have also that is to say
we're not just bodies were not just lumps of bone and flesh but there's is
the part of us perhaps the essential part of us that is something more than
the physical to spiritual immaterial part of us which as i say in this class
will call so also
most of us most of you probably believe in souls certainly most people in america
believe in some sort of immaterial soul and given the existence of the immaterial soul
it's a possibility indeed fear likelihood that we will
survivor deaths
the death will be there in the destruction of my body but my soul is
immaterial and so my soul can continue to exist after my death and whether or
not you actually believe in
so all you
i hope that there is a soul
so that they will be this serious possibility of surviving your death because death is
not only bad but so horrible that what we would like to have happen is
we would like to live forever so armed with the soul as it were there's
always the possibility of immortality
immortality would be wonderful that's what we hope is the case whether or not we
know that it's the case
immortality would be wonderful that's why death so that robs us of immortality
and if it if there is no soul of death is the and if if
is no immortality this is such an if is no immortality this is such an
the bad thing that the only the obvious reaction the natural reaction universal reaction is
to face the prospect of death with fear
o and despair
as i mentioned earlier than death is so horrible like is so wonderful that it
could never make sense to
throw it away
so suicide is both immoral on the one hand and never make sense is always
irrational as well in addition
so that they say is i think a common set of views about the nature
of death
and what i'm going to be doing what we are doing in this class is
that that set of users pretty much mistaken from beginning to end
and so i'm going to try to convince you that there is no soul immortality
would not be a good thing fear of death isn't actually an appropriate response to
death suicide under certain circumstances might be rationally morally justified and say the common picture
is pretty much mistaken from start to end that's at least my goal that's not
my name that's what i'm going to be doing now since of course i believe
the views i believe and i hope at the end of the semester you'll
i agree with me because i think the true and i hope you want believe
in the truth but i should say that the crucial point is for you to
agree with me
the crucial point is for you to think
for yourself and so i really doing is inviting you
to take a good look
hard look
and they sit and think about it in a way that most of us don't
if you look at the end of the semester haven't agreed with me about this
particular claim with that particular claim so be it out the content i will be
completely consent but i really is largely content as long as you have
i really thought through the arguments on each side of these various issues
can it be good time to pass around the
the syllabus
next introductory remarks like today's talk is going to be devoted to business i get
if time permits some philosophy the end
what about making one more remark about what i'll be doing in terms of this
license classes of philosophy class will basically be sitting here thinking about what we we
can know or make sense of with regard to death
using our our reasoning capacity will be trying to think about death the rational standpoint
one kind of evidence or one kind of argument
that we won't be making use of here is appeal to to religious authority
so some of you may believe in for example the existence of an afterlife may
believe going to survive death you may believe in immortality because that's what you're church
teachers you and and that's fine
it's not my
purpose or intention here to try to argue you out of your religious beliefs or
to argue against your religious beliefs all i'm going to ask is that we not
appeal to such religious arguments appeal to revelation or the authority of the bible what
have you in the course of this argument course in this class
if you want to you can think of this class as one big hypothetical what
conclusions what we come to
about the nature of death
if we had to think about it from a secular perspective making use of only
our own reasoning as opposed to
whatever answers we might be given by divine revealed authority those of you who believe
in divine revealed authority that the debate for another day it's not a debate that
as high as the steady state value so I can take that dataset and plot
the flux at up
x equals x 1 I'm sitting here watching the video profile evolve with time initially
at 0 because there's nothing in the in the
membrane and then slowly rising
and reaches the steady state value so this is this is jay at steady state
here jails steady state and thus
but could be a T 1
23 so you can see that coming off the soul
so clearly when we're moving through this time period J
is very much a function of time because if you close your eyes and wait
you'll see that the profile was changes the profile was changed it means that the
instant value of fluxes changes of what's a function of time so this is not
a steady state this is not a instead it is transient where in the transient
regime and transient regime in so far as
is always the case we can draw these curves they start a high value the
attenuated 0 what's the magical question what is the shape and what is the shape
that's only reason mass
to tell me the shape of those
is is is this an exponential decay is this half of the sign only what
is the shape of the curves I want to know vs. x at all
time at all times because it is changing as a function of time that means
I need to know C as a function of X and T of to solve
this and fit give us the solution of this as well
the solution of this is the solution to an equation
known as fixed 2nd loss so let's look at fixed 2nd
6 seconds and underwriting the special case when Dean is independent of the composition of
of the has compositions really do I do next and is a pretty good assumption
in many industrial settings and soldiers the right it's a it's a partial differential equation
and so what is telling you is that the partial with respect to time is
equal to the product of the diffusion coefficient times the partial all of
the gradient in concentration and so clearly this is a partial differential equation and that's
that's that you can't solve this was not yet OK but the good news is
it's a linear partial differential equations and that's good because I can show you a
solution that applies for a given and then you can play with the boundary conditions
and use the same solution so that's the good news it's linear alright so
but the solution of this is to both in x and the
on the solution looks like the best solution looks like this
but say we have an initial concentration seen
see is a function of X so I have an initial nonzero concentrations and I
have a surface concentration fixed C S and this is the system that we're trying
to model and the general solution
the general solution to fix 2nd largest city complexity is some constant it was a
constant b times a function which we're defined for the 2nd the error function dousing
function of X divided by the square root of d t so these are both
constants to be determined this is the Gaussian error function the error function X is
tedious time and D is the diffusion coefficient and this is nothing but a transcendental
functions that varies from 0 to 1 and here I could have said sign if
I said it signed x over but 2 routes of DT you know that the
definition of science it's got some weird integral and blah-blah-blah nobody pays any attention to
it in August 0 1 it's linear at low values of the so what somewhere
along the properties of the star
but I can tell you something right off the bat we think the shape of
the error function what's the shape of the error function that's the shape that's the
OK that's what methods Matthias
finding the shape
otherwise it doesn't make any sense and 1 of these these scale factors here you've
done this on a computer where you take some imagine you pull it you stretch
it and so on and you can lock the aspect ratio pride
lock the aspect ratio that's all you're doing mathematically where Paul that's why we got
call because at a later time it looks like this but the relationship between all
these points is the same
so that matter does it doesn't
no matter works for you you know work for
so let's put this thing work lazy so what we do we have to solve
for the now
you know that when you when you differentiate you throw away information right so every
time we throw away information we need to add some so we need to have
1 time based boundary conditions and we need to have 2 spatially based boundary conditions
because we threw a 3 bits of information so do and if we go ahead
and do that so here's what the uh and B will solve this works for
all cases minus the surface concentration divided by the initial concentration minus the surface concentration
equals error function of X over 2 routes of DT so C is that what
you're looking for this seen as a function of X and T C a surface
concentration of C O is the
the initial concentration and let's take a look at what the function of class so
to be someone graph z of efficiency as a function of z it varies from
0 to 1
and it starts off like so many functions as linear for low values of z
errf z equals z and in fact up to about 0 . 6 and you're
good to within 1 % errf z equals z within 1 % and they want
not to be sufficient right so we could say well certainly is good many pages
point to a page that seems to indicate is an important page so we could
just use the in degree but not that of course is is very vulnerable to
spamming right so i might just create some take sides and they all point to
my home page and suddenly have very high indegree and does that now make my
homepage more important and it should not be so easy to artificially inflate a score
so and the answer seems to be somehow
the that not every in length in link should matter in particular these artificially created
in these but rather what we care about is that the page gets innings from
other documents that also
are important right and then we inherit some of his important so if i just
create arbitrary new
pages that point to my home page i should gain much from that because these
pages will have a very very small score and so they can not post my
score a lot
OK now in the
the pagerank algorithm is really very simple to understand i mean maybe many of you
have actually looked at that but i would like you to go anyway here so
one way is to think of a random so far right so
you know you're in front of your computer you start at some random randomly chosen
page let's say and then at every step what you do is
if you look at the available outlinks all of of your page with prob some
probability of
do that that's in ninety percent of the cases you look at the available out
links and then you pick one of those random
right let's say there for links on the page and currently at cyclic on one
of them with so first with ninety percent of the time it's a look at
the out links and then if there the for
with probability point two five five pick any one of them and then follow that
to the next page then i repeat with some probability one minus it's a probability
point one
ten percent i randomly chosen new web page where that might be a little bit
hard to simulate a new machine how do you randomly pick a web page but
you know but if you have access to the whole web you could say simply
say you know give me no random page and then you move to the random
page and the you surface little bit moved to random page seven little bit and
so on and so forth and the question now is if we do that right
we can ask what is the probability that this surfer
is at the particular page five
as time goes to infinity right or we could also say you know once once
we reach the stationary kind of you know once this this random walk is people
see kind of has makes what is the
probably what is the the the the fraction of time that say that we spend
at a particular page i mean the surface sensitivity to particular page
OK and that
number that we can get here it's a the probability that is what we call
the pagerank so it is parametrized by this parameter for we can choose somehow
and we call the patron and the idea is that you know the
the important pages
i mean they have a lot of in links so there are many ways to
get there and then also
if if they are well connected by other pages that are important right side meaning
that it's also easy to get to them the basically this
simulation really will that that the random surfer will spend more time on
pages that are kind of well connected
on the web that have a lot of connections going in there and it's not
just kind of artificially created links but it's really main roads that lead their that
connect important pages so anyway that's that's of course is an assumption
but seems to be a good starting point so
formally we can also
like this so
you know what we really do here what we have here is an markovian random
walk or simple markov chain if you like that we start with you know we
know it's a little
so so we we say we denote by q
zero the initial distribution that was
used to select the initial node and if we then denoted by q t
vector with probabilities every probability indicating the probability to be at a particular page at
time step t right so i think of
q t and q zero as say on the web if we have let's say
ten billion pages this will be a vector with ten billion numbers right for every
page there will be a number
that at that point in time we will be at that page
and then if we if we would know that vector at time step t
we could compute it for time step t plus one
by looking at the
transition matrix probabilities right so this is a matrix where the entries denote the probability
we will go to node i went before we need to know j
right so how do i get to a particular node i well i can look
at all nodes j look at the transition probability p of i j
get two are right and then i just add this up so i look at
all possible nodes what's the transition probability to get to me right and i just
add up the probability of being there are times this transition probability and that's exactly
what you can write in this matrix notation here
so you see that so you take that right let's say we looking at that
page one here you take this whole vector the probability to be at page one
times the probability to go from one to one the probability of being page to
the probability of going from two to one and so on and you have
and of course if you just look at that by induction
you can go back all the way to the initial state and then the state
of the state of this probability vectors here at t plus one is just the
initial one multiplied by
the teapot
once power of that transition matrix p
and so what we would look for ultimately
is the stationary distribution that is we would like to find a distribution that reproduces
itself if we multiply with this transition matrix so that p times q is equal
to q
and so
so that would characterize
let's say there's only one such distribution than that
you know hopefully the kind of the the random surfer model it wouldn't matter how
we would start and we would end up in that stationary distribution at some point
so note that this school q vectors basically is and i can vector of this
p matrix
in the i can value happens to be one here
now in the case of pagerank right how do exactly define this transition probabilities well
it's just basically what we said before it's just this random surfer model so
so we have here the probability
to the page i
at the next step
is this
so far
which means
that we follow to an actual link and then we look at all pages that
have edges going from j to i k that point two i
that is essentially carry influence between out so if i have x
and c
so in this case everything is marginally independent model independent challenge
in this case everything is
well marginally dependent meaning but we have something like what we have
is independent of z
given y
so it is the semantics we want from this thing right so what why does
is is block the kind of the active passive influence from ecstasy think about some
causal chain one say no
with the value of this thing is for example i know that one ring
it doesn't matter whether earthquake
i mean it happened or
very what matters rang and that's why i called
OK so
there are basically past like that and and so the path of the sword right
you have long been doesn't have to be a chain of three longest chains of
of course the evidence they can be blocked right so
x amount here
after two y
actually is easily asking about x
you for you give
given y k having something observed here changes in
blocks this influence
the same thing happens in the other direction
right so these are two common cases a directed path between x and z directed
by the way is the next another kind of
the question
just get to
we have something like
like this saying you know we have x and
right so
we can assume that that the here is what causes in x and y causes
zero maybe this is the the alarm rate and this is mary and johnk
given the alarm these things are independent not given a large their dependent right so
now consider this kind of path were sort of
goes against the direction gets somewhere some kind of elbow and then goes again in
the direction of the aristocrats this kind of
centre in in this way so now we ask what is this kind of pattern
influence blocked what you know
obviously when this is observed
OK but then the situation slightly more complex
x and z
anything here if this is observed or this is observed anything want
one is a blog this completely independent of so so far this notion is very
much like me under the notion
because it's just it just you know for every path in some
observed variable in order to kind of bring the influence of one variable on the
he gets you get
i can hear is this
he gets interesting when we get to call the structure
so as the name suggests it
the structure of this article
because e
and why
so you can map these mentally to burglary earthquake alarm
right and so
is x and z
marginally independent
the next question x independent of these churn
yes but this is true now
what about x
given y
how many will say i think yes
i mean think now
OK the sales you'll notice that OK go so
they are not independent why because there is what's called explaining way that could happen
right so you know you might think that so if captains
this is more likely to happen if very happens the alarm is more likely to
once i know
alarm off
and i asked myself the question so suppose somebody can tell me what
the earthquake happened or not i can listen to the airport in radio
with mean knowing the earthquake happened change my belief about burglary
and yes support because
if i knew the earthquake happened i would explain away the alarm
by the earthquake and the probability of burglary
go down that the kind the kind of common sense reasoning that could happen so
this common sense reasoning
actually depends on the parameters of the of the
one of the model i mean what i'm assuming is that this kind of
you know positive influence if this is true is more likely to be true this
is true
this more likely to be true in this case
explaining away
occurs and so once you know this these guys become dependent
more generally if you have know some
a another idea which will come back to eliminate is do we really have to
be satisfied with sampling from the prior is there some other way of generating samples
that would be
better and so the idea of the proposal distribution
captures this we that we could kind of many cup a prior in some way
by choosing some other distribution q if only we knew some way of making the
q that mimics the posterior better than the prior itself did
anyway there are very many variations have arisen on particle filtering sequential sampling many of
which are trying to
improve estimator variance by
increasing this effective sample size and i don't have
time to go into all of these
but i will
straight one or two
so this
importance sampling idea
where you invent a proposal distribution q
that proxies for the
is is is an effective thing
so in the in the old
system we simply samples from the prediction distribution but now instead we draw samples from
this proxy for the prediction distribution
trickle q
and now correction has to be made in the computation of the weights so
the weights previously we just evaluate the likelihood by now we have to also bring
in a ratio that puts back the influence of the of the true
posterior which is derived from this prediction distribution and discounts the biasing effect if you
like of the proposal distribution so we divide by that
and in visual tracking this can be used in a number of creative ways so
the beauty of it is that it allows you to bring in extraneous information for
which we don't have a precise probabilistic distribution
you use it simply to improve efficiency but not actually to old
o introduce bias into the field so in this case for example we can measure
skin colour blobs in various locations in the image and we're trying to do and
tracking so it seems reasonable to concentrate efficiency in the areas where there's
skin colour but i don't have an nice probabilistic model for how skin cover
the position of the hand perhaps i could get one but the point is with
a proposal distribution mechanism i don't have to bother so now
what you see is a track
fired off proposals generated in the region of this these colour blobs actually there's a
mixture going on the proposal generated from the colour blobs proposals generated from predictions in
the in the old way
you see that for some reason the skin colour detectors firing a little bit on
the bottom of this coffee cup so it must be the particles being generated there
but they don't ever received any support from the likelihood model so they don't do
any damage except just a slight lowering efficiency but the point is we managed to
concentrate efficiency so well
compared with the show this video before and explain the
the importance the importance sampling aspects
and here's another use the same idea
this is tracking using motion and colour cues combining the motion and colour together
detection of motion in images is actually quite cheap so
we can afford to do that over an entire image whereas characterizing colour especially with
reasonably subtle colour model is more expensive so
if we tried to
track based on emotional only aims to track the face again and the person moving
through this
the CD apostles of moving stuff the body of the person is moving so that
actually the TV screen is moving so that since proposal the proposal generation here is
done in response to motion we get particles generated on top of the moving screen
but the other particles the ones that get high support so
this was wasting
samples may not actually doing any damage the estimate the posterior
we try to
filter based on colour cues alone while we
you know there isn't time to explore the whole image and so the posterior
sample generation hangs around uselessly in the corner of the image waiting for something that
matches the model two
to come in and then locks onto the model but if we put together a
motion driven proposal generation
and but the added
evidence from the colour likelihood model then we get something which is more powerful than
you see it's tracking efficiently
picking up on the person rapidly as they come into the room because proposals generated
from that motion
tracking efficiently the face as the person moves the room
same idea used to fuse
sound and colour again the two things are complementary because sound with the stereo microphones
is something where you can explore the whole range of directions from which the sound
like come very efficiently in
in the video frame in the video frame time but you can't explore
as i said before the fit of the colour model to all of the possible
locations in the image in one frame time so we could filter using sound proposals
and sound likelihood on the basis of the sound alone
and you see it's
picking up the speaker
as they talk about the distribution is rather broad and of course