to do
his so this objective reasoning so we know the conclusion we know some premises to
this conclusion i would like to add this is in the premises
which would lead from
known facts to the known conclusion
and this is
who has a motive so this would be
for the translation of this kind of query
so you see that
answers are supported by
effects from some of the public sources like CNN
and so on
i is you would be this hierarchy
now we can also ask for justification while a way of fado
had market for
four such
the killing
and then we get
sort of
pretty much says so that he could is an advocate of living on lebanese economic
OK that opposes lebanon lebanese economic reform
and if you ask for
so therefore OK that has a motive for the assassination of now if you ask
for a slightly more detailed justification we would get
down to very
common sense type of rules so which we can reach
so if some intelligent is really generic i mean would hold even for us so
if some intelligent agent opposes some policy
the reason is that
for instance a good example
and some other
intelligent agents which by some
kind of
tim berners-lee victor skulking victim is an advocate of that policy
monthly OK
and some other intelligence agent about their
this is responsible for
four according to the policy OK
and it is adopted by doctor in some of
any some about five
and some act prevents victim from playing the role key participant in any about part
that's intelligent agent had the motive for act
is the generic tool
and pretty much what cyc found to get some so
there are some more reasoning going behind the this is the key role which really
find the answer
and since this is about the reasoning far cyc
i found that some of these facts i think the one right
in the blue
the blue of facts are true then
this rule can be applied and therefore
well we can connect some premises which we know from public sources
and we know the conclusion that
the not
exactly and so therefore are
so why are we so then pretty much we can connect all the bits and
pieces and then cyc as i can provide some kind of well i would say
really interesting and relevant and so this is one
one such example of
a relatively nontrivial
three two real reasoning which as i can perform
i think is the second example which i have
so this is a summary no
so what
so pretty much the this is going to for family of the topics we have
so i could also lecture with an equal infinity
so we want they i one call circulants anymore other column templates because the diagonal
go forever
but if we have
image which caused we do
then there has to be some closure
one way to close it one way to close it is
make it periodic
so this is the
period periodic version of
of a the filter
this is the a filter with wraparound
points coming to mind about that matrix
i guess i do want to ask about one point it starts as usual my
lecture is running a little over
that's a matrix whose i can vectors i am interested in
that's the matrix whose i can vectors are very important
beauty is the eigenvectors of the same for every circle
so there's a little little world of circulant matrices
of a given size
and its eigen vectors
of everybody in the world this is that the world has the same eigen vectors
so that's what i want
so so so what i want to say i can vectors
of of c
of my search
we haven't really understood the the
right now
i introduced circumstances the matrix vector shorthand
to to produce
we see might have been the course actually
whatsoever wasting these matrices are really
almost right
in our in those first lectures
the minus one is
was minus one
well but now that we see it
with minus ones in the corners
maybe in the notes with
the periodic version
one of the eigenvectors
one one one is an i can make good good good
i mean
could be all right
so the idea back to mean
make a list of them
is an organ of one one one
how does everybody every was the i value what if i multiply this matrix by
one one one
let's just say yes sure enough is an organ vector multiply by one one one
and what do i get
so i'm really involving you could say with the one one one vector and what
the eigen value is c zero plus c two c one
times one one one
every row it's the same number
and what is the number well over the so
i just want to ask you to identify what we thought we just discovered
one of the vectors and its eigen value or one
this i can value in this
a column of my free matrix
it's the d term
it's the one one one column
of my f three fourier matrix
and so this is going to be the point
the eigen vectors of c are the columns
are are the
the columns
so as the matrix
contains the eigen vectors
of every circulated it'll diagonalizes circulant matrix
in other words OK
so what's happening now the this is so wonderful taken circa matrix
OK so when using amplifiers you don't really have to worry about the details of
maxwell's equations
OK i'll give you some very simple abstract rules of behavior for an amplifier can
go very interesting systems
really really knowing how maxwell's equations applies applies to that
because you will be working on this abstractly
however since the engineers
and you will buildings system is very important for you to understand how we make
this leap from the laws of physics into some of the very primitive engineering abstractions
so once you try and six double two
but the basic to starts here
you start from the laws of physics and then proceeds all the way out
so once we
talk about amplifiers
with a two pass
on the amplifier
will build the next abstraction called the digital abstraction
OK and the digital abstraction to build a new elements such as inverse and communist
OK so small as to be of the building bigger and bigger things which have
more and more complicated behavior inside of but which is very simple to describe
right so following the digital abstraction
so i propose the combinational logic abstract on top of that and define functional blocks
that look like this some inputs some function
some outputs
the next abstract top of that will be
the clocked digital abstraction
we will have some notion of time introduced into the system
and this will be some
and it would be a clock that introduces time into
so the logic values that functions operate upon
following that
the next level of abstraction that go
it's called instruction set abstraction
OK now you begin to see things that consumers get to look at
can someone give me an example of a instruct or name of the instruction set
so the fraction
x being OK so x eighty six
it is one to abstractions
and in fact in many universities
in many universities
education could start just by saying OK here's an abstraction the x eighty six instructions
some MIT gurus that design is often the microprocessor
OK so you just worry about you take this abstraction the european assembly instructions and
you're going both systems on top of that
because it is an abstraction of the x eighty six layers
the abstraction layers in six double four
you will learn about the ability of
the beta
again is other attractions at this point
so six w six table two
kind of goes on here
six the little dixie from the world of physics all the way the world of
interesting analog and digital systems
o double four
course and computation structures which are notable computers all the way from simple objects all
the way to a big systems
following that you learn about
language abstractions
jealousy in other languages
that is external to
and there set of other courses that cover that
following this
little about surface system abstraction
and so systems to learn about operating system
an example of an operating system abstraction that people are there
what's that
the next
what else
i just wonder how long will left to go to the you know what i
want to hear
so if you want to suffer system
these are nothing but abstractions simply implies a set of system calls
that the programs listed here
windows another set of system calls that's it and so much money they made
OK it's all about abstraction layers all start from nature right but that
fraction of an abstraction upon abstract one abstraction
and not here
o dollars
so so probability that fractions we can then be useful things for human beings we
can build up
you know
useful thing
the game
OK so
OK we can send
the space shuttle up and a whole bunch of other systems but it's based on
these that's traction layers
what's unique about education at MIT
what's unique about six table two and ECS
it is to my knowledge
there are not many other places in the world where you will be educated you
get an education in everything going all the way from nature two hard about very
complicated analog and digital systems can be show you layer upon layer upon layer upon
you know where the onion under you're down the raw nature
OK so maxwell's equations
six o two double for the three three
OK six one seventy and and so on
the whole ECS is about building an abstraction layers one atop the other
so that's one pattern
the and look back at all but to take an amplifier abstraction layer called the
see also the look
the amplifier
the world
and the operational amplifier in the animal or just slightly different ways of looking at
the same same devices
so the bill and lots accessible the operational amplifier
and then you we go and up building
a whole bunch of interesting
system components
OK these components might look like
but look like filters
OK to look like
o supplies
a whole bunch of very interesting abstract component which put together can then give you
the next set of systems and these systems might be
the posters
all right often so for example other analog like you know by various control
there is control systems for power plants and so on and so forth and ultimately
in a fun and dollars
OK so
so sixty two
it's about going from physics
all the way
this point will be build interesting and analog systems and you all the way up
a interesting system components from which double forward take you all the way to building
yeah that's true so
i think in in the psychology literature
it's certainly the case that once you've made the bet
you believe anything much much more than before you made about
is not rational
because the bad actually give you no information
so this is the dutch book theorem
an economic argument fore we use the probability theory through the beliefs
so let's talk about some of the theoretical properties over
bayesian methods
if you are worried about
let's say well let's come back to the royal statistics a little bit
on imagine the following scenario
you have a data set dc and
then data points
and he was generated by some
with some true parameter theta star
now of course from a bayesian point of view
i'm perfectly happy to accept that there is a true parameter out there
bayesianism doesn't mean i believe the parameters random okay that's a really bad way of very incorrect way of describing
i can believe there is a true parameter out there
for example the parameter could be
the number of people in this room that i'm trying to infer there's some true
number of people in this room
but i'm uncertain about their
i'm going to represent
my uncertainty by probability distribution so consider the following statistics kind of scenario where i
a data set dc and consisting of n data points is generated from some true
parameter theta star
under some regularity conditions and that's careful the footnotes as careful with the regularity conditions
these are just sketches of the theoretical results
as long as
i could
to be more formal here i put some
positive probability mass
around theta star
in this i've written it has be density and theta star is greater than zero
but what i really mean is not just the density that stars good here but
there is some probability mass
around theta star
a priority
the limit
has these amount of data goes to infinity over the posterior here
delta function centred around the theta star
so what does this mean
this means there
as long as i put some probability mass around
all reasonable theta stars
in the limit
my posterior will converge to delta function
so what are the young regularity what are the conditions that we need to worry
about i won't go into details but what are the conditions is
for example identifiability of my model i need to be able to
make sure there are multiple different fade that are all equivalent to each other for example
all the status can be uniquely identified
so these are similar to the regularity conditions that you need four r
on consistency of classical estimators as well
so any questions about the
you can read about it i e
i think you can generalize this to
the more general case and non ninety data
but then the
conditions become more complicated
so now
this is a nice this is essentially a case a lot of people worry about
how to choose the prior this says
if you choose your prior so that you put probability mass near all reasonable status that many such priors right
there isn't one right pryr
there's no such thing but if you choose a prior that puts some probability mass near most reasonable fade us
then don't worry
you know
in the limit you'll just
find find out what the right feeders yeah
the rest of the
well if you have too simple a model and let me give you a concrete example
let's take polynomials
if i put my whole
prior mass
on linear polynomials
my data actually came from a quadratic
then it doesn't matter how much data they observe
i put all my mass on linear polynomials our learned the best possible linear polynomial there is
that's exactly what the second point says
so any unrealizable case
where the data was generated by some key
so the next which cannot be modelled by any theta for example
eight quadratic
that can be modeled by any linear here
then the posterior will converge to some theta hat
just two
we like
the problem is that
when new
this change
and you i
change the world
can we
and i
what about what it does
what i probably get lot
but so that was the not
one of the
what should
right so we believe that run by the same role
what about
this is correct
i have no problem with that so he said
the question is if you look
like know not just
all of the you
what we like
that it's very unlikely to be so the are
it's kind of
but not this is
is an issue
he was
say what you may be assuming in the same
but actually
prior to
it's not
that's right in
well i think about it you feel that the number of points on the main
the problem of seeing
he has assuming that you need
you know what i need to make predictions about
i don't know what they are
so that we can only see three
o point
what's happening is that
they can be made into a hundred point
that's why you know that when you can find
but what
we but want to predict
i'd like to do all we know is one of the gas density
the three-dimensional space of the observation that may
so next let's show you some pictures
you should
do not just one
being one in the state of
one two
so there are these
process is the
they a rule by
seven three
thank you very much for the invitation to speak here
it's not my usual activity to talk to machine learning people but with a bit
of luck i learned something about the interface
between probability and statistics and machine learning during the my time here
levy processes well that that's where my research is and the application that i have
looked into a little bit of this in mathematical finance so i'll give this a
little bit of finance flavour when it comes to to the modelling part of the
but i'll first
spend some time
and looking at the structure of the processes so that you get the feeling for
so what the modelling freedom really is and how we are modelling using live processes
so this is going to have to involve some form of the technical
material related to infinite divisibility and the le vy khintchine formula
but then really with a view towards constructing
and assimilating these these levy processes
when doing inference later it it is going to be very useful to have some
parametric families at our disposal so i will review some
some of these parametric families that have been in studied and used for for applications
particularly in finance but there is no no reason why that would be the
the application that that you have in mind
so in one this is this is the main part of the talk
and when i then turned to two modelling and inference out just look
in in
very very briefly about model is more general than the processes where the processes play
a key role as as driving process of of some some other stochastic processes that
can model financial price processes or other quantities
and if this time then i'll talk a little bit about quadratic variation
and the the problem of of estimating
on making inferences on on volatility
and financial
and then
well this this last bit would be some some of the work that i've been
involved in
volatility inference in particular in the in the presence
of jobs
OK so this is true for some
some motivation
our lady processes being studied while there's bottom-up reason that you may want to have
continuous time
analogues are limits of random walks
or indeed generalisations of brownian motion realizing that brownian motion is maybe not the very
best model for the kind of data that you want to fit has also top-down
reason for studying the processes if you're looking at larger classes of stochastic processes is
might markov processes are semimartingales
that that you look at for various reasons such as simple dependence structure or that
you want to do some stochastic calculus with them
then the process of prototypes of these and actually a very good idea
to study them
first and then moving to this more general classes of processes if needed
other than this historically the main applications have been insurance ruin
storage problems
dams in particular
that's been driving the very early research in direction of the processes
the process of being more general context of markov processes as a means of turning
one markov process into another markov process by time change called subordination
and we can study the process is also because they're related to other markov processes
that you may be interested in the test branching processes or self similar markov processes
more recently
the applications
that have driven recent research
and put the process is very much at the forefront of
of visibility and essentially is they come from financial modeling
it's got no normal returns and the black scholes model says that normal
so this leads to to all sorts of undesirable effects such as volatility smiles
and which are in contradiction with the with the model that that's being used solely
the processes are a means of addressing such such problems and you can go further
stochastic volatility is another such keyword from financial modeling and leverage effects so there are
models around based on the processes that can address these
these features that that one would like to model in in financial applications
so i put at the very bottom something that's that's also close to my research
but i'm not going to touch upon this which is that the importance of living
processes in population and phylogenetic models where particularly for for large trees that one one
looks at their
one can find
levy process descriptions or interpretations of the of the results in in the area
so the structure of the processes we should define the processes
as follows
we are looking at a continuous time stochastic processes with three properties stationarity of increments
independence of increments and catalan happens
and what this means is that if we look at an increment
of lag is overly presses then its distribution will only depend on s
and that being true for all t
and this
is what we call stationarity of increments independence of increments is looking at
increments over disjoint time intervals i've chosen to do look at consecutive
and we require these to be independent
random variables
so we really building model
from from rather basic independent random variables
and we
we can then specify a joint distributions based on these two
so thank you for the invitation had to be here and must that well i
didn't do anything really for the summer school this was all
a lot of
organizing committee
you would see that large values of theta are necessary to drive distribution close to
a close to zero
so the probability close to one of first here
so i'm not saying that this is necessary in a very good prior
but if you have no idea is not actually not to be a bad thing
i'll be discussing conjugate priors in the moment
will get back to what this is actually not such a stupid idea
and the research talk
OK so let's see how it works
the blue things
otherwise you get through that selective restoration
so it
it's exactly the same but what is so before
the bias of what get by using maximum posterior estimation
now what you see is well
i did not serve any force you
nonetheless the bayesian procedure
penalize look like procedure
if you want if you want to be pedantic
does something quite useful here so it still gives it the benefit of doubt that
says well maybe it is enough to say that actually applied to this
down these extreme probabilities as well
the think that you should see is as we get more and more data
the the blue and the red curve get very close to each other
actually what you see from this is i probably didn't use the strong enough prior
actually now that this was
fair dice
these are constructed this way
and i would want that this actually ways things even will considerably evenly here
OK but
so this tells you that the bayesian procedure
in this case
is not a magic bullet but it can improve things quite a bit
well there another prime
i'm just going to mention briefly on
two slides
this this thing called conjugate priors
and mentioning it because quite often you would treat some statistics paper and then we'll
talk about say OK here's the binomial distribution and then the use of conjugate distribution
like to do is actually level of lower we estimate the normal distribution and then
use that contradict is charge and so on and so on and so on
it's quite intimidating initially when you read this
single how did they pull this out of the hat
it's actually very very easy procedure hiking at the conjugate distribution if you know its
initial families sufficient to dealing with
that's all have fun funny names and they all come with funny parameterizations
probably the first thing you might want to do it
some paper talks about this just strike back in the standard as exponential families for
minimizing is actually not very scary
so for instance like read of the chinese restaurant process
in this case you have a certain self-reinforcing properties now
to say these et al explain this equation afterwards but basically this is
three close what the chinese restaurant process will do as it sees new observations
and the idea is very simple
so what we actually have michael serious
will look different from the light
this is maybe not such a good idea
because consequences if you go out with your friends and play a lot of
but again with sources then you will just have seen a lot of thought
you might think that it's a good way of
representing your prior knowledge
in the form of a lot of things after that you've seen
like you've played with them before maybe ten times so maybe overall you toss the
dice a hundred times before i play with them again in it also ten times
but actually it's as if he's still remembered those one hundred times you toss the
dice before
that's a convenient way of representing prior knowledge
just an extra
what i want is
that p franchise for x has the similar functional form sp affixed patches by theta
PFC parameters by some coefficients a so
i'm just guessing the solution and i'll show you that this does the trick
just prior to this into the approach between states
and sometimes a
my sincere
i'm still state
which explained the whiteboard what's going on
so really exponential families tradition
here x parameterized by theta
into the inner product between
forty six
and theta
g off
in particular if we had a lot of start
this expression here
will be replaced by
and times new
this will be replaced by
so now i can write this
also as
the difference between the picture
g of theta
m times you had to
now what is this good for
well this looks like the product
well this is not my feature much
so this
looks like
five of satan now
this looks like some other parameter
so what if
i think some distribution
on the scissors
when my five seater looks like this
and have some number here
this is precisely what's happening over there
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
1 draw your attention to the fact that the final exam schedule is out for
about a week and a three-line 1 final will be on Wednesday finals week which
puts that on the morning of the 15th of December of the 3 hours
extravaganza celebration of learning where you all come to show me what you've mastered
and it's going to be a just a grand grand time
and it'll be over the Johnson athletics and 5 so I urge you to take
a look at the final exam schedule and make your travel plans as soon as
you know what you're last obligation because
things are get books and it's going to be harder and harder to get out
of here and certainly get out of a decent price of last day we looked
at Electron Domain theory which allowed us to predict the shapes of molecules and this
is taken from the book The sustainable for 3 highlighted in orange we work through
some of these molecules last day the SF six BR 5 I O 4 minus
and we looked at the series CH 4 s f 4
from ICL 4 minus and we saw how our by counting the number of electrons
domains and then partitioning them into blinding verses nonbinding domains we could proceed in a
systematic manner towards the end of the deduction of what the molecular shape should be
so that was that was a productive day and I urge you to understand what's
going on in Table 4 3 and you can you can expect that to the
testimony at the end of October and you'll have energy so you from probably wanna
know how work through this
this document here
so today I want to continue this this treatment of ionic actually of a covalent
compounds and specifically I wanted to talk broadly about how we determine state of aggregation
number words how do we determine whether something is going to be a solid or
liquid or a gas we've already seen that ionic compounds by their nature because they
have unsaturated bonds they continue to allow more to belong to the initial starting point
results in a larger aggregate larger aggregate tightly bound leads to crystal formation the crystal
is the regularity but definitely solid formation and when when you're trying to answer the
question is something of solid or liquid or gas under certain conditions this is the
you have to compare the cohesive forces versus the disruptive forces so the cohesive forces
are the binding force and the disruptive forces typically are viral in origin so we
have to compare the binding energy of the substance to the general thermal energy
that's shown here so binding energy that gets back to the nature itself it's an
ionic compound this binding energies that Madelon's bearing crystal lattice energy is very negative for
sodium chloride it's about 787 kilojoules per mole where's the thermal energy in this room
is about 40 of an electron volt so that's that's small sodium chloride is a
crystal at that
room temperature so now I wanted a covalent compounds
and ask the same question what's the state of aggregation but there's a fork in
the road here there's 2 types of covalent compounds we saw that as shown appear
on the slide that the results when we have just a single molecules but we
also saw at the end of last lecture it's also possible to talk about covalent
networks we looked at Diamond and we looked at graphite now the case of diamond
and graphite were in a situation that's similar to
called excuse me ionic solids in other words we have large aggregates because the SP
three hybridization allows for carbon a bond a carbon a bonded carbon a bonded carbon
as you end up with a large aggregate in fact it's an it's an ordered
aggregate it's a crystal Diamond is a crystal just sodium chloride is a crystal ball
were larger aggregates and we saw also that the binding energy and diamond is very
very strong very strongly negative and so therefore it trumps the
thermal energy of the system so these are solids at room temperature horrible molecules that's
focus on today what is the nature of the blinding in molecular systems and specifically
let's just take 1 of the molecules we looked at last day we looked at
sulfur hexafluoride and I told you sulfur hexafluoride is a gas at room temperature you
know this thing has a very very of high molecular weight so the question really
we measuring interestingness by the size of of the that saying this as low variance
the average variance so it's not very interesting is less interesting than average that's the
russian so there say a right well people the land is bigger than the average
and discover
and the final method people use this one scree diagram
what's the diagram is building that apply
the eyes a plot of lambda i see against so this is
plot for the
i was data
so the first ones
and that's one less there was point five is so
so the dominant variances in these sort of if you think it is just
so you want to be
yeah well in this diagram so
the the album choose the ones left to available to the components to be
all this three diagrams what this because
the land is are in order that one has to be bigger than the one
that was begin on august one
so in this case i would say well in the first component because it was
such a big difference
the problem of
through this right was just one final thing that people do with present problems on
the always do this if you
the problem with for because a few changes the measurement so if you went from
measuring one thing is that there is another meters it will also the results
so no one was in his ways to fix this so what do is you
take off the average size of the object
then divided by the standard deviation which is just the square of the variance for
each and that it is said is that will be the normalized data and they
put so its analysis on the normalized
what happens if you wanted to people do this this is the sort of starts
to happen if you
mess about with the scale so
in this one
was just
standard is an instance of the data as well as in the middle
drawing on the principal axes
principal component axes that correspond to
this data
and on the if i keep the circle with the same
five athletes to stop early by a factor of five
see the angle
so the direction of these complexes start moving
so the first
flat space
doing it because when you multiply by o point five increasing the variance in this
direction so it starts being pulled into the direction and that's the same effects well
it's not just that is less than the effective going from centimeters to meters on
its enemies and also is quite dramatic if you swat from imperial units against
three pounds to kilograms meters
then you get to some differences but basically just problem was if you do the
normalisation first it doesn't matter
you get the same answer so there is situation where you want to not do
this might be first-innings some analysis that whether it was sort spatial coordinates and matter
that they were in the same scale and had to keep the scale but that's
the same situation i think of what i would do trick
which i want going to get into because of the downturn was when the book
was an explanation
why one is measuring you can look at the ideas values and try and give
an interpretation
all what the principal component directions is measuring
so this is i think is an interpretation is to do with the show you
can work out to
the shape of the petals
this was done on this particular set on
how to actually come to to that conclusion is detailed in the book but that's
the idea is that you can
if you can when gets the and you try to give a real world definition
of what the principal components of measuring of the things where you want to serve
as well organised sample way home is where it survey of the employees about and
that's the different aspects of the job and
what you find some what we find an example of got hold of is managed
to simplify
it from down from about twenty different statements that about three different principal components three
principal components that is being paid job satisfaction ambition if you
try to interpret
what they can have how made up of the original variables so that's the idea
is that we try to work out how which is why one relates to lines
that would settle intersect with other try to say so ones measuring
it is big for long thin ones all
short vowels also love was also looking for
OK so so what real interpretation if we can but we can always get
well was
in this
one of the things that you find is that
later in the book and chapter i was the link between certain types of learning
and principal components it stated the is
well here we go
if you have a neural network
of of the whole by the perceptron is this
sort of model that was developed by paul at it mighty these all feed forward
models there is no feedback connection
and it turns out that having these feedback connections are very useful in particular for disambiguating the input
you can define conditional probabilities in this model
the very straightforward to define
but the thing is you this model just like in deep belief networks computing the
distribution over hidden variables becomes intractable
so that's one of the challenges and for those of you who are not familiar
with a little bit with machine learning you know
people who are working with markov random fields conditional random fields
in particular sometimes people with my markov random fields with hidden variables so those are the classes of models that
that basically similar to the markov random fields with hidden variables latent variables
now how does it compare to are to other kinds of models if you look
at neural nets models neural networks style models
the difference is that neural networks style models inference is just feedforward
given the data
you've feed forward through the neural network and then you have output
now typically neural networks i discriminative models right because they're trying to basically map input
and the output in trying to classify something
forty neural net
models like diebold's machines which generative basically trying to explain the data distribution data as well
compared to model like deep belief networks you know
you can sort of see that
you know they
they look somewhat similar however when you're doing inference in a deep belief network as
i mentioned before inference is just feedforward
so you basically the way the way the entries in a deep belief network was
to train you basically converting it into a neural network
and then you proceed with an inference step is being basically a neural network
so let's see what's happening with deep boltzmann machines
if i wanted to maximum likelihood and these learning in this model
then i basically get the same rule
the rule just matching expected sufficient statistics driven by the data with the expected sufficient statistics driven by the model
right so you have these expectations and these expectations
and remarkably
if you ever deal with undirected graphical models like markov random fields conditional random fields
factor graphs you know they have a lot of different names
the learning algorithm maximum likelihood learning algorithm basically comes down to define these expectations
now the problem is that now both expectations i intractable
and the problem is the reason why the intractable is that given the data
because we introduce dependencies between hidden variables computing the distribution over hidden variables becomes intractable
so it's kind of like one of those things that we made our model much more flexible
but we suffering
not being able to do inference
in the membrane like restricted both machines you have one layer of hidden variables and
there's no dependencies between hidden variables no connections between hidden variables
so conditional on the data
the distribution which variables becomes independently contributed exactly here introducing more flexibility so these models
are much more flexible but inference becomes problematic
so so what can we do
so both express stations are intractable in particular this conditional probability
it is no longer factorial it's no longer easy to compute so we have to
do something else let me give you an intuition behind the warning out what is
really this model trying to do
imagine you have some data
and imagine you get observe these characters these handwritten characters
so what you like to do
is you'd like to put some probability mass on those characters
obviously you want say this is probable this is what i observe this is what the world looks like
and that's what this term the first term is essentially trying to do
this is the term that tries to put little bumps the true data point
or the data points that you observe
but now
imagine that i get and i go and i just finished you know i see
an image like this one here
which is completely you know
it's still a valid image
but i'd like to say well this image should actually have small probability
and this is the rule
of this expectation here
this is the role of the partition function
which essentially says look at these exponential space
and try to sign small probability
to invalid data points or to to to
very improbable data points
right so that's that's roughly the idea behind these running and this is what they're trying to do
now what we're gonna do here's what used different techniques and i'm going to explain
to you a very briefly what they do
we're gonna estimated data-dependent sufficient statistics using variational inference are and we're gonna estimates
the expected sufficient statistics by the model here markov chain monte carlo based approximation
so if you look at the previous work
right there's been a lot of what people trying to figure out how we can do
inference in these models in particular was missions and i'm not doing justice listing all the people
but the problem with a lot of the previous models is that you know if
you look at the real world applications we typically have thousands of latent variables seemed
to design something that works very quickly
and many of you know the previous algorithms when not quite successful
when you're doing learning in these models with latent variables with hidden variables
right so if you look at contrastive divergence if you look at you know a
lot of different methods like score matching composite likelihood piecewise learning
a lot of these models cannot handle latent variables hidden variables
so what what can we do
so let me give you a brief intuition what the algorithm is gonna trying
it's going to
be trying to do
the very first thing we need to do is we need to do inference
right i give you this data point
and i need to figure out what features
high-level features i seen this data
of a certain size
but this is
speedy close as in terms of idea of basic ideas what is that we with
support vector machines you know how to overcome his work you know that the decision
problem solvers support vector machines can be cast the problem of finding the shortest u
the cheese margin
at least one image example
if it takes set of examples in the parable
good OK so we know now that the link to view matters
if it's if we call it with the entrance
and we are now ready to analyse the performance of perceptron this was because
not the kind of a lot of time
thank you
we're going to give a general bound for perception on on january general
on january streams nonseparable streams and then we can because they specialize for separable streams
looking for analysis of perception
so that
basically two ways to analyse this
so we have an extreme
and there be we fix and you
so we're gonna compare the number of mistakes made by
the perceptron
only with the hinge loss
in a lot of you
which is an upper bound on the number of mistakes made by
but you is any guide
any any here
there are two basic ways to to make in this analysis one is looking at
the evolution of this
you over time so looking at the evolution of the squared euclidean
distance between wt
with you
as time goes by
the first one second one ongoing and all i'm going to look at the evolution
of the inner product between u
now i'm dropping dropping the bars because they
the more i look into the evolution of this quantity
for the
the killing by the norm
multiply by the norm of the
the cosine of the angle of about but not
so i'm now showing the pro based this measure here
because it
may be simpler
and simpler so
focus on
the easiest way here is to look at the sequence so
when no mistakes
twenty one
on both that's where there's no mistake nothing happens
but that doesn't change
the state of the art reminds remains the same on both mistakes when we're not
on both that's when no mistake
so we can just focus
on both the
well mistake look like
just because of this
let's take one of those steps and let's look at the people of what how
this is going to change
i'm looking
now in the process of
this is a quote
i'm just using the update rule because they're not a mistake at the steps
so i know
the weight was up things way
now i can
history but the inner product of the summer
so you see i'm i'm looking at aiming at getting kernel
now i can
two very different think again and the and track one
now what i have is what
plus one and then i minus one minus i write this way because they like
like the
you know i don't about
cool i didn't do anything wrong again
and then i can make this
i can make this
i think the bigger by sort of the whole thing is smaller because his mind
by thinking
the class
so the maximum between this is zero
four you remember this provisions the max became this zero so made this thing is
which means that they
so the minus sign i went down
OK so now
this is the hinge loss of u on the example
and this is the indicator function that the mistake happen
and this is the term that is that the
so i keep on going like this
i keep on going like this
and the
we end up with is the following
OK if i
just represents one electron
there are going to be able to available for bonding
so what we going do here bring in some hydrogen here's original
here's ideas hydrogen common and here's the hydrogen
we've got ammonia
what did we do to form these nitrogen hydrogen bonds where we took that as
the three function on nitrogen
and brought in the hydrogen where
one as wavefunctions constructed we destructively interfere with SP three wave function
the result is a sigma bond
it sigma it's composed of the nitrogen
two sp three
and the hydrogen one as we function
the main goal right in years
being all
hydrogen nitrogen hydrogen angle here
what you see there is actually a little smaller
then the ideal tetrahedral angle
no longer a hundred and nine point five to three hundred seventy three
and the reason for that is because of this lone pair out here
this long hair
has very repulsive interaction with the electrons in these nitrogen hydrogen bonds here
bringing an in a little bit more courses
they're are being repelled
so there will generally be the case if you've got a long period electron somewhere
that will tend to repel everything will be repelled from it
the consequence is that the single was binding you're is going to be a little
tetrahedral angle of one hundred nine point five degrees
OK but now here's a really important point
you're on and for what is
the geometry around some and
in this case
you ask for you might be what is the geometry
around nitrogen
when you ask such a question what that
means is to you what is the geometry of the atoms
around the nitrogen
that's the electrons
the distinction is
the geometry of the electrons around the atom is about three draw
but usually
one is interested in there
usually one is interested in
what is the geometry of the other animals around the nitrogen
so in this case here the geometry of the other and this is the trick
and all parameter geometry
right it's not that
so if you ask for the shape of the nitrogen molecule the answer is
a trigonal pyramid
now i had redraw
really important
trips up a lot of people
the lone pairs pointing out here the electron geometry is approximately tetrahedral
that's not what we are usually interested in we're interested in where the atoms are
the geometry is the trick all
here amid
so that's a sp three hybridisation and and ammonia or nitrogen
oxigen k oxygen can also undergo
this as three hybridisation
here's the
the electron configuration for oxygen and
two electrons in the two s two
and four in the two p
what we're going to do here again
is we're going to let he's
i wavefunctions constructively and destructively interfere when we do that again
we're going to get
four new wave functions
sp three hybrid wavefunctions
but in the case of oxygen because we have one more electrons
than that of nitrogen we're going to have two electrons that as the free state
two electrons in the other SP three state
and then one of electronics in the free state
so what is the electron arrangement around oxygen going to look like
well it's going to look like this
we're again each one of these sp three
wave functions
is pointed to
is there a question over here that i can help somebody with
each one of these wavefunctions is pointed
two core
in this chapter he drowned
but again
one of these wavefunctions represents two electrons as long here another one represents
two electrons that long period
and then only these two sp three wavefunctions are going to be available for overlap
are the one that is most similar to this one is regarded as
the important centers and get a higher score than there is query based method
given a query this method can take similarity between the query and each sentence in
the document and that the one with the
it's the summer
two other will be selected to compose a summary
and then you can also add some position feature
like it gave extra weight to sentences that at at the beginning of the document
and this is especially helpful with the news texts
and then there is a new member in
and these this corpus or but this lexrank method is not currently in the middle
package so we didn't try to get
but it's not that difficult to implement the idea is not to compare each sentence
with the pseudo sentence but compared to do pairwise comparison between all the sentences
this sentence pairs with similarity value or certain threshold are regarded as similar to each
other and those
sentences is considered more important if it is
similar to many sentences
and those sentences are also important themselves
this is the idea behind this method
just to give you a quick idea about the package
and then there are also two baselines around the method and the method
included in the system
the random method basically assigned
were high well into two sentences happened at the beginning of the document
and then run the method simply pickups and that is selected randomly
if you have speculated these significant scores for
different sentences
and make can use
you can use reranking facilities
to adjust
the scores
one is the mean cosine reranking it's simply
there are always sentences about certain similarity
threshold with those sentences that are already included in in the summary so that not
all the same
the summary doesn't only come contains sentences that are similar to to each other and
and are here and here is based on CMU so i'm my are of course
and it actually just called the scores so that similar sentences end up receiving a
lower score
and it is actually
four an user it is not actually not very straightforward to use this system may
be for you guys
for more technical that there are many techniques behind this kind of systems
it's not so this still a long way
before this kind of system can be given to an end user to use it
in the real world setting
and even for us to carry out
experiments for research proposal
it takes a lot of time and effort to do like preprocessing work and things
like that
and so we have created
user interface elements and so
we use these
we use this tool to
to to do all our experiments
concerning to be
here here we can
just a load documents
donald documents directly from from the web into our document repository
and then we can
choose different types of play
summarisation methods
here you can find the features to be used and then you can define in
in the classifier and the weight of the features
and then you can also choose what kind of ranking facility would like to use
and you can control the compression rate
the length of the output
you can choose the compression rate based on words or sentences and you can also
choose to
the volvo labelled so
the scale degree of the measurement is
all over the world
so the question is could use all of the thirteen balls since twice thirteen is
twenty six and that's less than twenty seven
i'll leave that as an exercise to think about
another thing to think about is if i give UW weighings how many balls can
you do and how does it scale
that's the fun from and what is the general solution
w weighings if you're given n balls where n is the maximum you can possibly
do w what is the solution and actually super elegant way
to describe the completely full way you can say in advance what when going to
it doesn't actually depend on the outcome of explaining what you do that you can
plan the whole thing out that
the full solution by conway
so in
surprise surprise it has lots of problems
and the solution by john conway
the mathematician which enumerates in advance exactly always you're going to do for any number
of balls is in here
very pretty
good OK so
this is just a piece of evidence is definitely not approved but it's the piece
of evidence for
claim here the shannon information is a good way to measure information and should be
is a sensible thing to think about is not just an arbitrary invention of physicists
so let me now
tell you a little bit more about source coding
so we just tested the shannon information content idea by i
trying out on one of these puzzle i can come up with other puzzle of
the form how do you find the something or other and quite often if you
say well let's just go for maximum entropy strategy you may well find the thing
in the most efficient way possible
and we can come up with other ways of testing this but let's move on
part of source code in some
his fear the proof of which is in the book
it is the case that there exist compression algorithms which if you give them and
i i d samples from the source text you can compress
using that compression algorithm into roughly n times in tribute and p bit so that's
the source coding theorem i'm not going to improve it for you it's in the
book but i'm going to show you some algorithms that do get you in the
first case very close to this will sometimes close to us and in the second
arbitrarily close to to this limit
it is if we were
is our connection of this entropy to the physics entropy yes and there isn't time
for me to talk about it this morning because there's lots of other fun stuff
to do
so let's talk about symbol codes
in the book
simple codes are a particular way of trying to do compression they don't solve the
source coding theorem but sometimes they get you close that of symbol code is we
assume we are compressing something like english maybe the alphabet is a to z and
space and we assume that we've got a probability distribution on those characters that we
know what we believe is the correct probability distribution we're assuming that every character in
the file comes IID from this distribution so here's is the distribution of english using
some limits fact as the source of english
space is very probable so i and t
and the idea of a simple code is given these probabilities we then say i'm
going to compress this into binary
by giving every element in the alphabet
a binary name
the binary name is going to have some link
and this can be bought at the symbol code supermarket which looks like this each
of them could
every one of them can have different lengths so you say i'm going to encode
a with one zero be with one zero one zero i could say with zero
one and so forth
and then the rule is to compress
emma woodhouse bowled one
look what's the code for e
certain configuration
in the case of the magnetic field
it represents the work that i have to do
to get current going
inside pure self-interest
that means the resistance of the cell conductor is zero
and it takes work
because the solenoid will oppose the building up of the current
so i have to do work
so is a parallel between the two
i can make you see
in a quite dramatic way
how strong self inductances can fight
one current
anyway i'm going to do that this was an set up there
by have travelled
car battery
and i have
two labels
i have here an enormous self inductance l
thirty henry we will later in the course how you make such a high
self inductance
and here was the libel
the light as the resistance of six all
this self inductance there's nothing we can do about it happens to have four all
we don't have itself we don't have
superconducting wires
so it also has the resistance of four
forgive me for that but there's nothing i can do about it
i have here
and that the resistance of four
the light bulb which is the same ones that one
also six
and here is my car battery
a switch
and the car batteries twelve
and i'm going to
so to speak
i don't know
you'll see that this libel
comes almost instantaneously there's no self inductance in this little well maybe
few michael henry or even less
but in this little new self-interest and so the self inductances take it easy to
current thinking easy
just wait you will very slowly see that light bulb
come along and we can calculate how long it takes
because we have here
ten all six songs and for all
so l divided by or
thirty divided by ten
so what three seconds
so what that means is
even after six seconds which is twice this time
even then
the current through the light bulb is only
eighty six percent of its maximum
but that means since the light of course is proportional to ice cream or
in the
light bulb that the light is only seventy five percent of maximum and even if
you wait nine seconds
and the light that comes out he was still only ninety percent of its maximum
this one comes on immediately
the reason why we put the for all year
we want this part
to be from an ohmic resistance point of view to be identical is this part
that's why artificially added before
before is always
there the self inductances nothing we can do about it
so you're going to see a remarkable example
this is one light
that's the one
that is here
and this is the light bulb
is there
and the self inductances in this incredible monster here
make the lights change the light setting a little bit so that we can see
the light of the book but only eight were built not very
very strong
very bright bulbs
but the effect will be
very clear so if you're ready for this this is the one that i think
comes on immediately
this is the one
it takes its time
three two one zero
six you see how slowly it still not very bright
still getting brighter
still belongs right is this one
getting there
you can actually do some finding accounting
by the way the values of the resistance and again you are when the light
bulb so hot three
two one zero one
five six seven eight
eleven twelve i'm still seeing getting brighter
what you're seeing here is a remarkable example
that the self inductance
is fighting
that's why the name self inductances so nice
i want to go
one step further
i want to
o in the l our circuit
with a
a c
learning paradigm now
you know you have a bunch of images is a great by two million motorcycles and say well
can you ask me what that's
which is still a challenging problem
but let me
switch gears a little bit and see what we faced with the following problem
suppose i give you millions of unlabeled images so you get to learn something about
the world you get to learn something about how images should look like
know those could be text could be speech signal
different domains and then i give you partially labeled data show you a few
you know dolphins assure you tractors few elephants
now the question is
can you take all of his background knowledge
and then learn new concept from just one example a few examples
and obviously you know it's it's a very interesting question that people in the deep
learning community asking is that whenever you learn these features with high-level features
obviously if you can learn meaningful and useful high-level features
you should be able to start learning new things very quickly
obviously if you can recognize and pass images and intercourse here and semantic meaning
and if i show you a new object you've seen
you should be able to recognise and be able to learn very quickly
right if you can't
then probably the features that you're learning and not very meaningful
right and then start testing what that's so that's
that's the key problem in the visions speech perception in
natural language processing different a little different domains
so here's one particular classes of models that
people have looked at
so what you do is you contributing to kinds of different models
integrating hierarchical bayesian models
which are useful for
for constructing category structure
right so the way you might go around this problem can say well see kind
looks like a funny kind over
he correct
what kind of looks like
maybe some of these things obviously some relationship with integrating these classes
is shared high-level features right like
like wills in end
handles and such and they should low-level features like edges a combination of
right so deep models are very good in terms of unsupervised feature learning and learning features a hierarchy
and the hierarchical bayesian models are very good in terms of constructing the heart is
how different optics are related to each other
and you can basically construct
a hierarchical model where you have dependencies between
classes so you might say well horses and cows
should be grouped together
they carry a lot of high-level parts
cars vans and trucks should be grouped together material a high-level parts
i at the lower level you might have a
distinctive perceptual structure of a specific concept in my head edges and combination edges that get
they get put together
so there is one particular model you you can construct and you can also learn
what that hierarchical organization should be
so the tree hierarchy of relationship between objects is learned
that can be used something that's called nested chinese restaurant process prior
it is a very simple private effectively assigns probabilities for different trees
different tree structures
and you can sample the states of the latent variables from something scale hierarchical dirichlet
process prior again this a simple prior that allows you to share parts
across different objects
and then the distribution of the observed data
is gonna be given by boltzmann machine which effectively will enforce
approximately global consistency by looking at many many local constraints
so both machines are very good in terms of generating data if i tell doubles
machines these features e i'm seeing generate me something coherent
they're very good at doing that
hierarchical bayes models are very good explicitly defining higher it is and how objects relate
to each other how they can be put into groups together
so unlike many standard statistical models here you're trying to infer problems but you're also
trying to infer the category hierarchy of how different objects are related to each other
so for example for these models where low-level features are built in unsupervised fashion high-level
features are built by looking at the labelled examples are fifty thousand images have different
and this is the kind hearted that the model is learning right
so you know it puts fruits together humans animals and then there is
the learned high-level features learned low-level features
right so trying to learn the hard your politics related together as well as low
end high-level features and it terms of the hierarchy itself right the mopix up things
like you know different
the crocodile lizards spiders snakes get grouped together
you know there's different man-boy
girl get put together different trees that get put together right so a of that structure basically involves
by looking
good at the data
and how
transfer learning about one one is not mentioned
and i show you an apple
and these are high-level features that you get
i show your red apple
now is that the shape
get shared together because they have the same shape
and the color features are different
the model basically figures out that the best way to code the data and that's
the best way to go to right
you want get the shape and color
out but let's say i get an image over orange
and again orange sits on the same class and again it sort of captures these shared high-level features
but let's say i wanna classify sunflower
so what is sunflower well south was basically an orange with gotten it right
basically have the same structure and that's what the mos discovering right semantically sunflowers not really related to orange is
the visually always discovering that is basically relates to apples and oranges just
except with these features these couple of features that you see
now all these high-level features are being learned on the background set if i'm looking
at dolphins dolphins will have very different features
so by learning the hierarchy for sharing parameters as well as you know learning these
high-level features and how they relate to each other you can basically learn
a new concept very quickly by sharing high-level features as well as figuring out relationship between objects
right and in terms of doing sort of recognition from one two three ten fifty
examples these kinds of models they do much much better compared to know traditional both
machines only you
and other models you can also do fun things like
generating data from these examples especially three apples
is what it generates
if i show you will treat is what willow trees look like
it looks like because painting but this just based on an example them always seems
will increase
if i show you right it is what it generates figures out there should be something blowing up right
again the beauty of this moses there's nothing specific in this model
with the gauss and charge
how do you understand this
well the third of may be the easiest way to understand the whole
if you have
as you say you have hit distribution this amount of heat
what happens to be quite why do i have this form well tool
think about it let's just think about it at one point so if i have
exactly what point
so i have some fixed amount of heat at one point
but it has to be actually
delta function let's think about a unit amount of heat that the point what happens
to the well it spreads around how does it spread around it spread around according
to the girls and distribution so after time t
become foegaussian like this
OK so
the in the beginning i have
kind of this infinite amount of heat at one point then it becomes very little
goes and the fact that gauss and so on
and it's a sequence of
you know gaussians which grow progressively flat and
fat and flour
that formula follows from this
so if you believe that this is true that the individual amount of key it
becomes gauss then this formula should be
almost immediately actually made it because if what is integral in general is just to
stop so you can think about your initial q distribution having some fixed amount of
heat and every point
what happens to this heat well it's about if you becomes gauss
so now you have a sum of an infinite amount of gaussians coming from which
point well that's exactly what is far below
so that this kind of intuitive
interpretation of
solution to the heat equation
so if you believe that
you can
what can you do
you can say
if you believe that this is the correct heat equation that the plus some of
our enough you fixed is equal to do you over dt
then how would you compute the law applies manually to compute the uprising you can
if you know the function and its in our and you just take the derivative
you some them up
the usual thing but what if i just want to use this heat equation
well i think about this
i want to start this some f of x
i seek propagate at a little bit
and then i take the time derivative
all of
that function
well according to the heat equation
the time derivative
if my efforts the initial heat distribution and i propagated just a little bit the
time derivative of this is nothing else but a lot less
so this suggests a way of approximating the laplace operator well how the approximated i
take my function
i smooth it out using the heat equation
and i take the derivative of that
make sense
if this makes sense then well
what is your phi xt ut of xt is nothing else but this form of
this convolution so i've basically what do i have to do i just have to
differentiate this integral with respect to time and that is the laplace operator
this is it's freedom here so the laplace operator if f is the time derivative
of this convolution
well now we all know what the derivative look like
the derivative looks like
well if you want to differentiator function at the point you takes while of the
point you take a little bit of an incremental you take the difference in new
divided by the size of things right
what does it mean in this case
so what is that function at time zero
at time zero
you can see that actually well at time zero the heat propagation of course is
just the initial state distribution so it's just the function itself
so at time zero it's f of x and i put the mindset change the
order of
it should be integral minus f of x i put my here
so what do i have i have f of x
minor so this is
the at time zero minus at time t
divided by one of the t
so now i have an approximation
the laplace operator OK
so we now know how to compute the laplace operator from
the heat equation
i mean this is very in some sense for elementary
once you should have tried to think down
OK but this actually has implications
well what happens when we have data when the data and when the data is
sampled from
OK i want to say a uniform distribution on around but unfortunately there is no
such thing as a uniform distribution around so i'm just going to pretend that it
right if you
if there is if there is some problem then the best way is just ignore
so i'm just going to ignore it and say well
let's just say this is a uniform distribution
in this is it is a uniform distribution on then this farm home while there
should be actually one the and
the average of this
i guess i'd like to start off by since this is the last eight think
our hosts
at the summer school for those of you who are not organised such events you
find its millions of little details and and i think it's an excellent time for
me and i hope you all
twenty one so thank you very much for discrete
but all a i'm going to talk about the general
topic of speech production models in are automatic speech recognition i guess you could find
a lot of researchers who
have over the last twenty years twenty years investigated how we can build automatic speech
recognition systems that are based on
a models of speech production and you can find
a reasonable pretty good set of researchers will say that we're never going to solve
any of the the basic problems that we have both robustness
and portability to new domains and issues like that unless we
have our systems the more you will be more closely aligned with
four were built on principles that are more closely aligned
with speech production but on the other hand over the last twenty years most of
major developments of the important advances in speech recognition have been in the areas of
statistical formalisms for
we get for learning and modeling that have had some but little to do with
models of speech production
so well
what i'd like to do
is this talk a little bit about why this is a hard problem to begin
with the words what what what are the difficult issues associated with building systems that
are based on speech production models but also what of the potential payoffs what advantages
might we have in building systems that incorporate more of more notions of of the
are human articulatory system
in in making them more
but that spend a big portion of the time talking about how
how we might in hell and existing efforts for exploiting a speech production models in
we'll talk about statistical models for
four logical distinctive feature detection
how we can incorporate this distinctive feature knowledge in ASR model structure
building models articulatory dynamics
and how we can perhaps an easier problem is how we might in integrate these
distinctive features in existing traditional ASR systems and finally to finish up a little bit
of a lighter discussion will talk about some resources that exist some tools some devices
and tools that are used to study some of these issues and
maybe outline some of the projects that have been dedicated to
to this problem
the first part
i'll start out by trying to motivate why this is something interesting
then out just so we have the same terminology i understand that a lot of
you are not necessarily people who you got we've got some
computer scientists and those whose background is in areas of speech translation and natural language
processing so some of the terminology like that i might use might not be too
too familiar and so i'll spend a little bit of time reviewing some of those
fundamentals and i'll talk about
talk about some issues relating to using canonical baseform dictionaries and that's problems with full
nedic phonemic dictionaries not ponemic dictionaries sorry about the the type of their
and then i'll talk about
the some models of
how some models of how speech production
fits into the two models of speech perception so
why would we want to use articulatory representations for speech recognition well i guess our
some of the basic some of the basic data
that has been collected by people of mainly at haskins labs in the united states
how all the articulatory representations are put together we'll talk about speech is the organisation
of articulatory gestures
the notion of critical articulators an acoustic invariant articulatory invariance and evidence for the usefulness
of of articulatory knowledge in existing systems
so this is kind of a very interesting
set up plots here that was obtained that was obtained from parallel acoustic articulatory measurements
and there's some theoretical performance guarantees
on the other hand there are some difficulties it's not really clear how can we
incorporate prior knowledge into into the
posting on how this can be improved maybe the linear programming algorithm as well
and often realizations of essential essential so the best strategy for player but so i've
shown you some some strategies
and of course the best choice of the vehicle is not up to snuff this
is essentially the same problem as in support vector machines where you have to choose
a kernel the same problem you here you have to choose an appropriate set based
on appropriate courses both both ways to find some the the feature space for and
if just feature space is always what matters
people have used boosting with systems and c four point five and they often found
like when they compared
UCI benchmarks they find that points boosting stumps or compared to c four point five
is is better
i mean they one c four point five on the dataset one one point is
the data set k
then this is a transition our and they find that posting stumps they get smaller
the most cases but not all
and if you wish to c four point five that usually leads to an improvement
so there are four four c four point five are usually large
but this only shows essentially the boosting improves i mean many have one base learners
then boosting improves many people i mean
based on boosting then the generalisation becomes but often it's not compared against other based
or against the support vector machines and this engine then you when you do this
comparison the oftentimes that boosted stumps of city four point five well performed with us
this because of the based on c four point five is not really the best
which i found my own experience
so for instance i compared boosting their RBF networks with boosting c four point five
lb posting of it networks all the very often performs much better than c four
point five postings four five and boosting RBF fall off very close to support vector
machines performance with RBF kernels
OK so you some results
there's also a dataset collection which you can download from home page so this is
thirteen datasets thinking and used by a bayes function networks
than adaboost using these radial basis function networks adaboost break this regularized adaboost than linear
programming adaboost maybe just run adaboost twenty iterations and then after afterwards we just optimise
the the weights using soft margin and his QP version and you support vector machines
OK and you find that adaboost drake is very all the best and it's very
competitive with the support machines
so there's some odd results which i quite quite awhile
and you find them together with the
benchmark results so there are some key to results on the side
OK like to mention a few other applications but just very briefly so
boosting has been used for text classification so they forced by ship you anything they
stands with the normalized term frequency and multi class encoding
so there was some application on optical character recognition that the use of multi perceptrons
space and the control the improvement the the performance was quite a bit improved
then also natural language processing image retrieval just to mention a few i've used that
are OK medical diagnosis i've used it also brought detection
in drug discovery some applications and the quantitative structure activity relationship modelling
and also some application electric power monitoring so be applied to posting to RBF networks
and to some this was trying to show
so that's a much fuller list of applications in trapeze review paper and also in
the review paper of and myself say they find someone altercations
OK i'm
essentially at end the early sorry
maybe there are some more questions which can fill the last ten minutes something
OK so
thank you
so the more questions
so maybe
let me give you an overview slide so you remember what to what i talked
i mean i guess the basic issues for really clear always talk about the so
the idea so
are there any questions additional for that matter
OK so then this
this OK then maybe yes
sure this
it is
as many
so the question is about the complexity of the base is right so how how
complex or what the right policies right so i mean OK so there are many
different types of policy so there might be decision trees such completely different class from
matrix or kernel functions like this OK so the time you have to do designed
for your particular problem OK so maybe if you very smooth functions which you would
like to approximate maybe RBF networks are better than the decision trees it's really like
using very few features that may be and it's more tree like the decision then
maybe use decision trees
but then the second question is how complex you should you choose your hypothesis class
thinking about the properties of the network
so there are some technological issues
which have to do with
things like the physical medium over which are transmitting messages
or the properties of the links are which are transmitting the rate at which you
can send data the loss rate the number of percentage of messages that lost by
the link is transmitted so those are the kinds of things we need mean by
technological concerns
there are so one kind of technological concern is this
sort of the different kinds of technology that we might use for transmission and we
we saw this notion of the technology over the technology over dt
before i was just this idea that the technology just like the technology in computer
system has been draw evolving dramatically over time the technology of networks has been evolving
dramatically and we're going to start to study the race some of the range of
different technologies that we have to deal with
so our set of limits
any time technological
physical fundamental limits their are associated with networks of these are things like
the speed of light
we simply cannot over we can't send messages faster than the speed of light grey
with these are these are messages that being transmitted down the wire and propagated some
speed and that's going to be fundamentally bottleneck in in the design of computer systems
i have to send a message from here to california that message isn't going to
get any is there any sooner than the amount of time it takes for light
to travel travel across the country and those numbers sort of the amount of time
it takes to transmit a message of the country is nontrivial in computer time it
might be a couple hundred milliseconds and that's a long time as we saw before
we have a process that can execute billion instructions per second
OK so the other sort of interesting issues it's going to come out about networks
is that networks are shared infrastructure
what that means is that networks there are multiple users who are simultaneously using a
network because of course although this from using the internet and all the networks that
going to study in this class are basically a shared infrastructure we'll talk in a
minute about why sort of the networks are are fundamentally almost always going to be
sort of shared going to have to transmit data from multiple different users at the
same time
and that's going to present a number of challenges about how we ensure that the
network is
fair that everybody is that everybody gets the standard a when they want to send
how we
sort of allow multiple people to access the same physical wire at the same point
in time
OK so
i want to do is sort of talk about the talk about these two things
now in order to start off by talking about technology so
so the first interesting technological problem which i've already mentioned is that these networks are
extremely diverse there are heterogeneous
technology networking technology has evolved a great deal in the past twenty years
for thirty years since networks were first first started being designed and that means that
there is a huge sort of range of devices that we might have to transmit
data over
so let me show you what i mean this is just a graph showing the
rate of transmission these are the number of bits per second the concerned over different
networking protocols
and the thing to take away from this first is to know that on the
y axis here
and this is an exponential scale so
the technology at the very bottom things like that early telephone modems
maybe send data ten ten kilometres sec
whereas the sort of high and router class devices that are
running the running mate
internet or
it's very fast desktop ethernet kinds of connections are coming out today
are concerned more like say in this case we have we have a hundred
we have
terrible sack right so one one ten ten ten for talking about a factor of
ten to the seventh or ten eight
the difference in performance in terms of the number of bits that these different kinds
of devices can actually
that's pretty dramatic and that's gonna make it difficult to design computer systems
and these kinds of variations occur not only
at the sort of thing
number of bits that we can send per second
but also
in terms of the propagation delay
of the links
if i have a local area network connecting two computers to in my office together
i may be able to transmit the message from one computer to the other in
order of microseconds k but as we said before it is sent a message of
across the country by take two hundred milliseconds to send a message across the
across the pacific ocean by way of a satellite in orbit around the united states
might take a second to send a message to mars might take you know
tens of seconds for a minute so there is this huge range in terms of
transmission times that some of these different links have
and fundamentally basically the these sort of two things bit rate and propagation delay
are going to tell us how long it takes it we would expect to see
it to take for message to travel across
the message to travel from one place to the other
for example we can say bit rate the amount of time so we can
think of a communication link if you like
as being a piece of pipe
which has some
that is the bit rate