start with
to prove it
in order to
make prove discovery
in the calculus like this
humanly feasible
computers like this calculate the two but with that
people don't
we need more help
we're not going to try and millions of possible consequences
see if the
goal turns out we don't reason like that
so in order to help
what we need to establish
is the fundamental
theorem about this calculus
let's call the deduction theorem
or deduction equivalents
sometimes called
for any
so gamma
any you only be set of formulae go
any formula nb
and tales
if a then b
if and only if
gamma and a together
until b
notation here
should be simple
when i write gamma i
i mean gamma
right but i write with a comma
to save cluster
just before we prove this what does it say
the implication here is that if a then b
it's supposed to be a kind of inference ticket
or you can cash it for an inference from a to b
if you have a you can use this to get to be
and this says
suppose you have a
you can get to be
but a valid argument may be in the content in the context of some parameters
and so
that holds exactly when the that
the implication that the whole story about
as a connective
so how do we establish this well we argue from left to right and right
to left to to to
two directional bidirectional things like all these proofs in logic one directions is in the
other direction is not
left to right i guess is easy
if from gamma we can derive
the conditional
OK so we've got our derivation
starting with gamma
and we've got a implies b
then from gamma ray well we can throw in a is well because it's one
of the assumptions here
we can get the OK that's it
one step and as just immediate consequence
we allow the a because it's one of the assumptions
so left to right there's nothing to
to do
right to left
is another story
so supposing we've got the derivation here it may have any structure may be of
any length
we don't know what axioms it uses what's inside it
if we have such derivations then there will be a derivation of this
and this is the formula that doesn't occur it also is not completely obvious out
i to do this how how we got to convert this derivation into the derivation
well we prove it
as we prove everything by induction on something or other
and we prove by induction
on the length of
this assumption here is that we have the derivation of the right hand side
so we suppose
the game and a we can derive b
this derivation must be of some length and
and we show by induction on n
that there is a derivation
of the
the base case is
splits into several sub cases base case and equals one
suppose we have a derivation of length one
that doesn't involve notion of immediate consequence at all
then the derivation looks like this
and that's the derivation of b
from gamma and
so everything in there
it is either an axiom of logic
or is
a member of gamma
or is the formula
if b
is an axiom of logic
or if he is a member of gamma
then we appeal to axiom one
of that
OK we take
axiom one
then if a then b that's just interchanging the roles of a and b that
and we have the which is
an axiom of logic or a member of gamma
we derive
if a then b
this is an axiom
this is either an axiom
or is in gamma
and so that's the derivation of this from
i like
that's the case the other base cases where b is actually the formula
because that's allowed as well that the derivation of b from gamma and a
it just indicates that i be the same formula
but in that case
so in the case
equals b
in that case
they are OBE a implies b
is just
a implies that a
and that's derivable from the empty set we just did
so gamma
in that case entails
a implies a for any gummy like
that's a implies b
because it's the same formula
so those are all the base cases
then there's the induction case
suppose that this
after this
deduction theorem holds
for all the derivations
shorter than
for everything is derivable in less than n
that combination i i'm i know log get zero but the
the question is does any other combination gives zero if not
then the vectors are independent if some other combination does give zero vectors are dependent
let's just take examples
i suppose i'm in
say in two dimensional space
i give you i'd like to first take an example let me take an example
where i have a vector
and twice the vector
so that's too
vectors of the an two v
are those dependent or independent
those are dependent for sure right there's a combination one vectors twice the other
one vector is twice as long as the other so if there were dependent means
anything these should be dependent and they are
and in fact i would take
two of the first so here's
is the vector v
and the other guys vector to v
that's my
so there the vector v one
my that my next vector v two is to be one of course those are
dependent because
two of these
first vectors minus the second factor is zero
that's a combination
of these two vectors it gives the zero vector OK that was clear
suppose i have a vector
here's another example
easy example suppose i have a vector
and the other guys the zero vector suppose i have the vector v one
and the two
is the zero vector
then i those vectors
dependent or independent
they're dependent again
you could say well this guy
it is zero times that one
this one is some combination of but let me write it the other way let
me say what combination how many the ones
and how many the tools
well i take to get the zero vector
if v one is like the vector to one
and the two is the zero vector zero zero
i would like to show that some combination of those gives the zero vector what
shall i take
MTV one so i take
zero not taken all the ones but how many vetoes
so six OK
or five
and in other words what the point is if the zero vectors in there
if there is zero if if one of these vectors is the zero vector
independence is that
right if one of those vectors is the zero vector then i can always take
they include that one and none of the others and i would get the zero
answer and i would show
dependence OK
let me let me finally draw example
where they will be independent suppose that v one
and that the two
those are surely independent right
any combination of v one and v two
o will not be zero except the
zero combinations of those would be independent but now let me let me stick and
the third vector v three
independent or dependent now those three vectors so now and three here
i mean two-dimensional space
whatever i mean the plane
i have three vectors
that i didn't draw so carefully i didn't even tell you what exactly they were
but what's this answer on dependent or independent
deep and why
how do i know that those are dependent
how do i know that some combination of the one v two and v three
he was the magnet
this is the north pole of the magnet
this is the south pole
i don't remember it's written by frank you
so the magnetic field around like so
and i have here
current y y and ones the current through it
why is perpendicular to the blackboard
when i turn the current on if the current is coming out of the blackboard
five fifty percent chance because i really don't remember whether this is north out
but let's assume that this is the configuration
the current is coming out of the blackberry
you will see
this wire
experience force
this is an experimental fact
the force
on the wire
is always
in that direction
of i
crosby is a unit vectors
and since i was coming out of the blackboard
if i cross i would be
i get the force in this area
so if i reversed now to current
the current
goes like this
then of course the y i want to go down so you both
but i don't know which one will come first
because i didn't like the poles
so you see it now
slightly different from the way i on it
i draw magnet looking this way
it is of course much nicer for you to see this picture so you see
the wire
and there's the magnet
and now
i'm going to run a few hundred and wire
and then
you will jump up
or it will go down and they have a reverse current
and the opposite thing will happen
we're ready for this
three two one zero
notice there was this thing for that
the forcible so high
and even paul van
this supports
so now i can predict
the very first occurrence
in this experiment
that now
the wire will jump up
there we go i know not exactly because i switch
this way so now switch to this way
the wire jump up
that's the first row you three two one zero
very clear
so it come out
take this down
if i had
so it's ironic current
let's say i run the current i one
the wire
it will produce a magnetic field
right hand corkscrew
right here
the magnetic fields
will be
in the blackboards
call it the one
right here will be on the blackboard
but that's irrelevant right now
is out of the back record years in the record
i have another wire
when you're on the current i two
there will be enforced now
on this wire
in the direction i crosby
thank you and i cross
that forces up
this wire
will experience a force up
but of course
this why experience force up
this is actually my reaction
this is why will experience a force that
so there you go towards each other
they will be attracted by show
you can independently confirmed
that the force here is down
this is the force
probably will be enough to say actually was minus reaction
the third law
but if you want to put here
the magnetic field
which is the result of this current
which is of course out of the blackboard and the the right hand corkscrew rule
and now i put into dollars will then i can pay and are now left
in the same situation
and it's the case that the bank balance never goes negative
that's really important invariant to
so therefore the sum of the true cost or the amortized cost upper bounded sum
of the true cross
this is the sum of the
emma tries cost here is
i go i would want
this is
three and
so the point is this i've now bounded
the sum of the true costs by three m
let's go back to the stable here and we'll to see what happens
if i put in
c so i had
and the bank balance
so in fact
so the first thing i do is it is inserted
i charge three dollars
and i do an insert
how much drier rough
two dollars
turns out matching the charges two dollars and have only one dollar left
so this is i'm actually going under charge the first guy
because if i charge if i only show you that works if i
charge everybody three dollars except for sky charge to
actually save a little bit of one
OK then
this guy in charge three dollars
i've got it
what's the size of my
of my bank balance from down like copy one guy is all paid for foresight
two dollars left
with me
next kaieteur three dollars actually returned all these guys dollars
so here now
basically get two
i've got a table size before so i basically
i have
to copy of one insert the third guy i'm going copy two guys i will
use up that's all have only two dollars left in the table after the concert
now i search for sky
OK and that's a good one because now i built up above
balance here four dollars
because in have to copy and by
now i said this guy i'm going to copy for items so that expands that
OK i charge three and then to left
here basically have two to it
two to it
OK and at this point i use all up
go back to two
what centre
you see one of the things i want you to notice is i could have
charge three here
and i would add an extra dollar lying around throughout here what matters
still would be upper bounded by three n
so the idea is that different schemes for
charging advertised costs can work
and all have to be the same
it's not like when you dramatize analysis that there's one scheme that will work
i could charge four dollars
it would work
but it turns out i couldn't charge two dollars for everybody
factors two dollars for everybody at my balance would go negative
balance would go negative
can charge three dollars now work
four five six like the charge that the bound i would get would be simply
looser bound instead of it being less or equal to three and
the lesson call four and five or what have you
but if i tried to do too and it wouldn't work
because i wouldn't have enough money left
to copy of what would happen is i would have only one dollar
in this and then when it came time table bubble
you know that if this were data from a physical system this would mean that
you found love to understand the behavior of physical systems so
the most obvious thing is to say well there's a mathematical equation going through the
however like his points right away
there's always a mathematical equation going to any finite set of points
that's obviously
the case especially colliding whose
wonderful mathematician the simplest proof is probably what is now called the plastic interpolation which
actually was afterwards but
things like this invented the calculus we can assume that it was obvious to me
you can do you can put an equation for any finite set of points
so says like it's the existence of an equation going through a set of points
does not enable you to distinguish points that come from scattering in random on a
piece of paper or points that are measuring the physical system which obeys
physical laws so
what unable to distinguish well he says if the equation is sampling
that's a lot but if it's for compose a
then you can always find such an equation and its meaning
so this is the inside of
well that's another problem
that's another problem this is the criterion which is theoretical but it doesn't mean that
you could actually enables you to apply in each case and say to these points
following along to actually see what the what the simplest equation is passing through a
set of points are well if you limit yourself in algebraic equation may be used
OK in my case this model the expected the data is given
you know and you just trying to understand and that predict so make trying to
make it more closed but you
so yeah there are all kinds of epistemological problems this is just a question of
understand what it means to say there's a lot of it doesn't mean we can
determine if the law
OK so so
so so so
so this idea is mentioned by line its environment also says the world is comprehensible
that's in paragraph five you have to remember like sixteen eighty six is the year
before newton's principia
you know modern science is just beginning it was called mechanical philosophy and and all
of the medieval ideas and religion were still very much alive modern science and i
get obliterated all opposition
you know newton himself was half more in the past and the future was volterra
created with whom we consider to be used in the modern
scientists newton was not modern thinker he was more like about law sorcerer you know
and believed in theology so alive it's at this crucial moment in time when the
old school of thought is colliding with these new mechanical philosophy says well why is
the world comprehensible lullaby it's always try to keep everything good
you know he wanted protestantism and catholicism to be reunited he wanted to be able
to combine theology with modern science and not give up either
you know so so that he discusses in the score
how can you tell the science applies to the world the world is governed by
science and why
and the reason he says why is because of god i mean god creates the
world which on the one hand is very rich and diverse phenomenon
but on the other hand all this follows from very simple laws
so he's declaring that
the world is comprehensible is really the world is beautiful because it follows simple laws
of all the richness we see so this is like a postulate saying that science
is possible the world is comprehensible
so this is which which
alignments of proof of of
since we're jerusalem i can say it is the proof of of
the greatness of god that is that this beautiful world is made from a small
number of powerful brakes we say are powerful ideas
it's it's OK
so so this is why it's in sixteen eighty six now mobile takes this up
in his two books the open world nineteen thirty two and the philosophy of mathematics
one of the
so long
the more that is from
one of the from
every man
the name
and all
and are
one of graph
well known for example should be
we're not
i the think
lot of
these are all
by default
the first is
all right
one of
or i should
how we
so long
one one
and it follows
that means that
because of the
the problem
why we can
for a all
one of the
ontology there
on top of
i think that we can develop some sense of the evidence for above or some
degree of predictability set and not the mystic predictability
that is is we can do much better
then the fed has told us we could do in the system so i'll stop
you and i apologize for thinking it thank you
thank you
we decided
for me
they may of
problem one
you will
all right
and there were
this is
let me respond to that
i see that not just in social sciences
you a good example in matter engineering
the issues
prediction the assessment of the lifetime of the structure is the major power in the
US where all bridges are getting and so anyone
everywhere you want to the plane can fly safely and so i want to
predict when they are going to fail
what is the start of the process mechanical engineering
i really summarizes approached by looking at the tree in the forest where they do
they they do very dedicated as expert
assesment non-district non-destructive testing
to look at
you know
where are the micro cracks
how the acoustic emission how the measurement of the kids
it is here and there and they have these exactly describe these global markets me
detailed information the big problem is that in order to make a prediction
you need not only to analyse not only to gather data on how this huge
unitary aggregates information
indeed the information of the global collapse
is not was so weakly encoded in the indian elements you need to reconstruct
actually i was lucky to work at the time that was actually the beginning of
one entity of the crashes as a precursor
eight years before that
actually i developed with the major european companies
a system that now is the industry faced to predict the structure in all the
things that fly
europe satellites and rockets
two basically do this program of aggregating the information about them
through what physicists call there
course going approach or renormalisation group approach
something that actually
he's out progressively the noise
to extract the information the main point is that
i think there is a misconception in many sciences many endeavors or in policy-making
that by
again a very simple-minded approach but it seemed to work
much better than just using the words two
there is no again as data miners we can actually think of our more fancy
models are a bit more topical kind of models using latent dirichlet allocation and they
come up with some measure
maybe based on hellinger distance is not a better job but again but this is
the main idea is kind of captured in this
slide here
so again another for drawback using word matches of words so they the what matters
work well if you are matching on frequent words what about rare words right then
rare words
so if you look at the top if you look at the distribution of words
there is
he was long tail distribution that eighty percent of the occurrences are conquered by twenty
percent of the world's but then the remaining is all spread out across a lot
of different so
so how do we tackle this problem so one one way is to start building
aggregation on the tail and had phrases instead of using words
they were again the other problem with the information retrieval approaches static so in a
given the content
it just give you semantic score now does not take into account external factors that
might affect relevance of for instance there might be
the your interest in basketball players might
really increase the large because there was there was recently there is a game
held at the giants stadium for instance right and that's not captured by semantic
that's not captured by in information retrieval based matching approach and this is something external
that happens that has to be able to take that into account so this is
something that you miss if you just do information retrieval approach so click feedback using
click feedback is a powerful way of capturing such latent
effects that might happen over time
you know
this is definitely a very difficult to do it through relevance so that the problem
with the relevance score is it does not correspond to click-through rate let's remember
if you recall the revenue model
in used to CTR times bid to rank now if you use
relevance as a proxy for click-through rate
that's really not mac optimizing the click-through rates the long it optimizing something about relevance
is not equivalent to probability although
you can normalize both these things on the same scale from zero to one relevance
o point two doesn't mean the probability it doesn't mean correspond to probability of point
right so then you have to come up with some other ways of translating this
into something that would translate of optimizing expected revenue so that's another problem maybe it's
a better idea to estimate the click-through rates directly and use that as the normalisation
rather than using relevance school so
so again these are some of the other
the other thing is as many of these information retrieval approaches use something like a
single TF IDF school so the idea of of war
is again
uniform across the entire corpus of that's not really true if you look at content
there could be so many different problem you have publishers alsop's as most publishers also
camera now
you know the idea for valor
cannot be uniform across the entire corpus it really depends on the context and you
know captaining that is there is no good way of capturing that these four now
in the information retrieval literature so these are again some of the drawbacks of the
information retrieval approach
many of the information retrieval approach based on the notion of getting feedback
so you will give some query documents two
humans and they tell you it's relevant and not use that as your training data
to come up with the model
now that's not very scalable in the case of online advertising is not scalable we
really want a system that is scalable automated and generates revenue using low marginal cost
that's the first slide that the most leading to so
so that's another reason why using click feedback could be more advantageous because you get
a lot of feedback
the other thing again
and then again not all text rights so if good landing page you might have
video image
and all sorts of things so how do you how do you get relevance when
you have
a bunch of things on the given date right if here video and text how
use the information retrieval
not very clear right so that's that's another
problem so
no one to kind of
we get all the effects which we had in the previous slide is too large
this too
use machine learning approach that can learn from click feedback
obtained from the system
and again a few using that so so there have been several papers that have
been a lot of work in this area by the other areas not seen a
lot of work but this area has seen a lot of work so
for instance so there have been several papers that have explored feature based models to
estimate click-through rate so what the feature this model so
you characterise every query by a bunch of features you characterise every have a bunch
of features
the could not because your response variable and you try to build a machine learning
that can mean
take these features and predict the three
so those are really feature this model
people have also been working on hierarchical models or the hierarchical models do is basically
try to get a better estimate of click-through rate by borrowing information from multiple resolutions
so if you start working with models at very fine resolution
there is the
extreme data sparsity and
it becomes difficult to reliably estimate parameters that resolution so you might want to make
the estimates more reliable by falling back at coarser resolution there is a lot of
data and improving estimates finer resolution so there have been some work in that matrix
factorisation and collaborative filtering techniques that have been investigated quite a bit now in the
context of netflix
and the movie recommendation problem and now kind of also being starting to use in
this area
and then there are several challenges and open problems which i'm going to describe and
finally you know
and with the online learning so
right so
so so we've already so this is the estimation problem which are trying to solve
so given a query given that and given the user what is the probability of
the user clicking on the right this is what we really want estimate that's going
to be of interest
so this is this is a difficult problem
there are several reasons why this is a difficult problem for stuff on
the labels which we get click or no click are noisy so not all cliques
reflect the intent of the user
not i don't think so reflective of the fact that the user really like that
there are many unscrupulous users trying to game the system so you might have heard
things like click fraud no
click fraud is solely done
generate revenue do using unfair means that the user has no
the intent of actually clicking on that and looking at it so
that kind of
but you'd see our data when you're trying to learn click rates
secondly the it's not it's not clear what is the negative in in this case
so there is a user who never clicks on that
if there is a user never edits some and then
no matter what you show him his your she's not going to click on that
doesn't mean that he that is not relevant to the query the ultimate goal is
there are actually either this only nine or ten different interpretations of PCA this is
this is another one point of a way to right PCA in you get to
play some of you get to play playoffs PC ideas morning
what i want to do next is
what i want to do next is on
all about a few
castaways was PCA is used one is visualizations right on
very often you have high dimensional data sets and someone gives you a fifty dimensional
is set
and it is very hard to
for used to look at the data set the three-dimensional and understand what's going on
to become part something fifty dimensions
on so
common practice if you want to visualize very high dimensional data set is to take
your data and projected into say to d part of project into three parts you
can render like display computer on so you can better visualize the data structure
what physical example that that the roundabout of doing this we see it was enough
precision noise last appearance stand in which he
he had readings from fifty different parts of the monkey brain i have the there
is number fifty percent tens
of parts different possible among iranian so you have this
fifty dimensional readings of fifty dimensional vectors correspond to
different amounts of electrical activity in different parts among people is actually fifty neurons tens
of neurons
but also tens of neurons in the brain and see if a fifty dimensional time
series on and very hard to visualize very high dimensional data
but what you instances it was his PCA to project this fifty dimensional data down
to three dimensions
and then you can visualize this data in three dimensions is using every part and
say yes visualize what the money is thinking over time the the school
another common application of ICA is compression
if you have high dimensional data you want to for it with the overall number
PC is a great way to do this on
it turns out also that all
sometimes in machine learning sometimes you just give an extremely high dimensional input data
for computational reasons you don't want to deal with such high dimensional computational data such
high dimensional data and so on
fairly one one common user PC is taking a very high dimensional data
and represented here with a low dimensional subspace why is the representation of time just
so you can work with much lower dimensional data and on it turns out he
son to see if fact of life that we given an extremely high dimensional data
on almost all the time just in practice paul hi hi very high dimensional this
is i've ever seen high very high dimensional this is often
have all the points lying on much lower dimensional subspaces
so very often you can dramatically reduce the dimension of the data and really not
and really not before in too much too much of the information away
let's see right so learning algorithm to take a long time to run being on
on very high dimensional data often use PCA to compress the data to low dimensions
of your learning algorithm runs much faster and you can often do this with your
sacrificing almost no performance problems
this one of the use of PC for learning of which is
you remember we talk about learning theory we said that
the more features you have the more
complex hypothesis costs exceeding the classification right if you have more features you have lots
of features
then you may be more prone to overfitting
so one other thing could do with PCA is used that to reduce the dimension
of the data
so that you have fewer features and you may be slightly less prone to overfitting
this particular application PCA to learning i should say you know it sometimes works often
world so i actually to show couple of examples we salute this in works on
but this book application PCA i find a way looking industry it also seems to
the over use of and and in particular
markov model tells you about the probability of tran making a transition from state to
to state three which is just you know a particular epoch through the word if
you like and so here is that the top row here is that market model
just the first order markov chain like before but now
the whole point is to excite that model
from observations and so the way you
two a graphical model of that is used sort of backwards you explain the data
conditioned on this your belief about what the word model is you say well if
i simulated in a particular way drawing from the conditional probabilities at each time step
each of these yellow blob from left to right is the time step and so
that i have you know state once they once they were on the stage two
stage two stage two and then in this direction you have to have a narrow
which says well given state to what is unlikely fragment of spectrum you know his
the his the signal going to get to summarise this signal as the sequence of
little slices on each slice your describe the signal spectrum doesn't matter if you don't
know what spectra signal spectrum means but i think the point is it's just some
features of the of the signal so we going to predict what
a set of features of this the signal likely to occur conditioned on a particular
this is the kind of thing that they do in with markov models in in
speech and then this is a hidden markov model because the markov chain now
and refers to some
variables that you can't actually observed directly things you observe directly are only indirectly related
to the variables in the markov chain he must have an awful lot of this
even says yes
you agree you have an awful lot of this kind of thing
and you know we can even use this kind of thing directly in vision but
in a very different way than what i'm going to talk about the just you
know have interest we can make a motion trackers rather like belief tracking that i
showed before and also rather like not that will
this is a sort of primitive form that's how how we would have not tell
ten years ago with the kind of this is the clanking suit of armour here
is the kind of underlying model but all
all done as random variables so the angles of all the joint random variables and
the angle of the joint at time t condition on time t minus one is
another probability distribution and so on and
here's another of the same kinds of things and just you know by building one
of these models
the model itself is learned from a lot of data in this case but hand
constructed in this case you can make something which will make inferences from
as a temporal sequence of image frames now this sequence of yellow blob each one
is an image frame time t t plus twenty plus two and so on and
these blobs here the underlying markov chain are you know that have joint angles at
time t effective joint angles at time t plus one so so you know we
can do good things with those hidden markov models in vision
but what we're going to talk about now for the rest of the time is
a very different kind of markov model getting back to the array of pixels and
how we would like to link decisions in this array of pixels now
if i make a graph
out of
even the simplest linkage of pixels then you know his the simplest graph that you
can imagine it's it's not too simple to be useful where i simply link horizontally
and vertically adjacent pixels on the chessboard
and but this graph is already problematic to the point of view of inference because
it has many cycles and you know from
the weak selection is the doing inference in graphs that free of cycles that are
actually trees is very much more tractable everything in such a tree
can be done exactly all the inference can be done exactly and if you have
a hidden markov model in which the hidden part is one of these trees and
there's a linkage from each node in the tree
to some observable
then you know the the inference can be done exactly under all kinds of circumstances
in that kind of structure and before i cannot abandon that idea of you know
abandon hope of having a tree to explain what they think it is in the
image i do i would like to point out that some people have done this
successfully but it's very hard to do it in a way that is completely general
overall images in other words it's quite hard to think of the tree
which is you know the tree is going to be the graph that i would
have liked to the whole of linkage is removed to make it back into tree
very hard to decide which linkages to remove completely general way which will work for
all images but what you can do much more effectively is for a particular
a particular image construct a particular tree where a set of edges has been removed
that works well just for that data set and this is what effects this paper
in two thousand five dollars in rather clever way and so she what she does
this she sold for a minimum spanning tree with respect to some particular set of
edge weights that are related to the the details the data what going to go
into it but it's a beautiful idea and you know i think a lot more
will be made that but OK now i'm having just you know after that final
hopeful message i'm going to descend into the abyss of
of fully connected graphs not fully connected but of graphs with cycles in them where
every every neighbour in this horizontal vertical sense is connected up
so what this means in graphical model terms if you got undirected graphical models model
is that when we tried to work out
conditional independence
of this guy
all of the rest of the nodes in the graph in fact that conditional dependence
is limited to the dependence on the immediate neighbours
so you might think well that sounds like a rather impoverished model because what that
means is that when you make a decision about this guy is only going to
take into account its immediate neighbours but that would be totally wrong
conclusion to draw in just the same way that with the weather the you know
the text example of the whether the direct link is only from one day to
the previous day that doesn't mean that the beginning of the week
it doesn't affect the inferences you make about the end of the week because of
the knock-on effects from one day to the next to the next it just means
that the
it the functional form if you like about non knock-on effect is constrained in such
a way that it can be expressed in this very efficient way in the case
of the
of the weather model by conditional probabilities that only bother to link adjacent days and
in the case of this pixel array model by functions we'll see
shortly functions which only connect
adjacent pixels but you know i conclusion that that it is often wrongly drawn is
but this was not used
i think
if you want to be a
what's wrong
right now there is only one work
what you want
so i think
again you
all right
it is
now i want
you were the one
so this
you be
or the
all right we already
it is the only difference in the sense that the maximum likelihood estimation
is that when choosing
you know the math is that using them as like value of data
yes that maximizing this which which had like nation
and in times is the quantity which is the prior
let's see
one intuition is that if your prior
it's called
data being gaussians with mean zero some covariance
then for distribution like this most of the probability mass is close to zero rates
of the gaussians centered around the point zero and so was probably master causes
and so the prior distribution is saying that you think most of the parameters should
be close to zero
on and if you remember our discussion on feature selection if you eliminate the feature
from consideration
that's the same as
setting this is the value of theta
it is that theta five to be zero that's the same as
eliminating feature five hypotheses
and so this is the higher the drives most of the parameter values to zero
two values close to zero you think of this as doing something analogous to do
something reminiscent of feature selection
it turns out that what this formulation parameters one one one actually be exactly zero
but many of the values because
and so
i guess in pictures
if you remember i said that if you have say five data points for the
four for the polynomial
well i think that too many problems and
if you find any for the forefather if the very high polynomial to very small
dataset you can get these very large oscillations
if you use mozilla like estimation
in contrast if you apply this the bayesian regularization
you can actually fit the high order polynomial
but still get
so events move to the data
the kristol says he kristol driving the transistor because because zero
and that in practice so hard to see the article
that's how small is smaller on the cross tend to the your data also becomes
friends with the same ten
less and less overfit even even when you fitting a large number of parameters
but c
one last piece of intuition that just toss out there you get to fail more
this particular set of ideas more in on problems at three which of course online
this week yes
is that whereas that's likely who tries minimize
right rest mass likelihood first a linear regression turns out to be missing this
it turns out that if you look at this higher turn there
it turns out that the optimisation objective you to optimize
turns out to be that way you add an extra term that you know
penalizes you transition state has being like
this ends up being an and is very similar to most likely that except that
you tend to keep the parameters small
and this has the effect
discrimination of death
shape northfield and so on just but the culverts horizontal
it is also there were about six in essen and doing
in which gained given the picture they also try to recover the three d structure
of the image so that's also very interesting piece of work in this case they
have more the representation is not so simple they try to recover the may be
more complicated
and they also try to get absolute depth so it's not just to say that
something has a particular shape but that some of particle at this time so have
calibrated information
and the idea is that once you have this kind of information you can also
include that in order to build better detection
so imagine that you have an image and you have been able to defy what
the support surfaces with are the vertical surfaces what is the sky and so on
now you can use this information
to incorporate
to go to incorporate the town of detectors let's say they scientific
because cars you could have a feature that
thanks to decide if something in the past in which you are able to cite
another kind pressing corresponds to an object surface like a vertical surface and the part
below corresponds to an artist on the surface
that could be an important feature that you could use in order to improve current
so here are some examples of
thing to the cars and now is integrating also this additional features test to check
if the part below the tower exactly ground
is the ground surface so in this case this may look like a car but
the part below is a vertical surface you can
i assume that this is a false alarm
the use of that information can also be incorporated by having more qualitative representation in
state of trying to get an accurate representation you can also reason about just what
are the qualitative relationship between different surfaces like the fact that the car is on
the road you need to have a very
state representation of what is the three d shape of the car or road one
capture these qualitative relationship that the car is on top of the road and that
the fact so given a bunch of text is if you encode these qualitative three
relationships well you can more or less get some of these labels right so the
sand was detected here but you know that the sun is not supposed to be
on top of the waves is supposed to be above
so this should be the right protection for the sand and this away from the
there are some but it's here
so you can clean to infections by incorporating this qualitative relationships
OK so that's for detection
in context with the
so now
i'm going to move to a different aspect
that has been now more and more attention the piece to incorporate
very large data bases in order to do this recognition task
so these are the families of the things that rely on the fact that you
have very very large databases available to two
we are trying to solve the same task finding talking about until now
one of the most important aspects when you're trying to do the recognition is the
data have for training and
and for many many years people were thinking that OK if you think about how
humans learn about this from knowledge of course humans have many different input modalities they
don't have don't give them as input label images now they go in the world
walk around and interact with the world so they get to know how can you
move obj is how they feel when detach them so they have a lot to
access to a lot of different data that is
take an unsupervised there's no people nobody given due labels
is active system
and of course you can have a teacher also going to some of the traditional
labels colour from many many different ways of many kinds of information
so people would think it OK we want to have the same kind of input
for computers well then we have to work with robots
the problem with what is that OK
is it seems like an interesting idea has many input modalities but nowadays they are
very poor and they are active but are they don't really go very far they
don't get out of the lab to not exist in a small office the problem
is that we would like to appear to have realised that look like this but
we have always the latest
so we're going nowhere with this
and certainly something you appear
that nobody was really
four seen at the beginning is the internet so the internet has given people the
computer vision researchers with any sort of information that this system is reach it also
has many different input modalities there are millions and billions of images out there
but you can use this input modalities that are different from input modalities that human
but still there may be more or less have the same kind of challenges you
have to put all this information together
you can also reach everywhere has very large
the very last fingers and toes of data probably even more data than the amount
of data that than fun has the first ten years of life so now you
have an amount of data that is equivalent to what people get to see is
different kind of data but the same sort of this some money to then also
conditions no more than what want formalise and so on
so people know how big using internet in order to build big databases and thus
have an important audition
and in principle that plays
two very interesting instance learning
this is joint work that i've done with the remnants and i'm here today and
her quite sir at the parallel computing lab at the university of california berkeley and
our work is on that support vector machine training and classification on graphics processors
so just to
over the outline for the sort of person going to motivate why anyone should be
interested in thinking about general-purpose computing on graphics processors and and what it means to
be compute the general computing community as a whole
that we're starting to see such massively parallel general purpose processors then i'm going to
talk about our support vector machine training implementation and unlike the
the two talk so we just heard were actually interested not in linear SVM but
in kernelized SVM
and we
implemented basically all go through the details of the algorithm that we implement including are
working set selection heuristic and then also
talk briefly about support vector machine classification graphics processors
so to motivate i think that to talk so we just heard have done a
good job of motivating why support vector machine training is expensive and and kernel based
support vector machine training is
it is even more computationally intensive because of all these kernel evaluations that we have
to do is make it hard to
do the math very clever things that people have done for linear SVM training and
we often have a lot more data than we can process so we're we're all
interested and scalability
on the same
on the other hand we're at the point now
in computing where future
performance increases are going to come primarily through parallelism
so i don't know if you've noticed but over the past few years clock speed
of normal processors has been increasing and the
single for performance of of normal processors has been increasing but at a much slower
rate than it has in the past
so in order for us to think about scalability in the future and we're going
to have to think about parallelism i really appreciated the previous sock they did a
good job of paralyzing and and that
i think that's the direction that were we're all headed so
the difference is now though compared with in the past that we have the opportunity
to exploit parallelism on a single chip
and this changes a lot
what things are possible
and to paralyze because
synchronization is much cheaper so
to synchronize the cluster CPU is they all need to synchronize over ethernet are mere
nanda or what have you it's much cheaper when
all of the processors on a chip
our synchronizing using on network or the external memory interface it it
because synchronization is so much cheaper some things that were bottlenecks to parallelisation the past
become tractable
and that's that's what we see with our SVM training
graphics processors out a lot of you may have heard of general-purpose computing on graphics
processors in the past and people have done a lot of really interesting work in
that but it's always been kind of strange like you have to think about all
of your data in terms of four vector floats and you have to pack everything
in terms of graphics textures and use open GL shatters and and so forth so
i'm i'm here to tell you today that that area is over graphics processors are
general purpose you can program them using see the restrictions of the past are basically
gone there are still a few works that are being worked out and then we
run into some of them but
we we didn't at all the implementation that we did here is applicable to general
purpose parallel programming which in five years old the CPS from int'l are going to
be highly parallel as well so that the techniques that we apply here are kind
of in their we see them as being indicative of the future program
so i i'm i have on this slide a picture of
the di four invidious latest greatest graphics processors the
the g-force GTX two eighty
and you can see i don't know how many of you have to bypass before
but usually on a dive what you see a big huge cash
the thing that looks like cash on this processor all all of these clusters right
here right here those are actually the cause of the processor on the chip there
are two hundred forty cause
there are arranged into clusters and you can see ten clusters around around the edge
and each of them has three
clusters inside of it and each those clusters has eight processors same final at the
two hundred forty cause and the big stuff in the middle which is
the memory interface and synchronisation networks and so forth
programming such as a parallel processor is is very different in the sense that
we like massive parallelism and we're not afraid of launching a million threads at once
so the hardware actually has context to support
in the GTX two eighty up to thirty thousand friends that all can be sitting
on the chip and all have their own context this is not swapping contacts on
and off the shelf these are resident threads each have their own register file and
so forth and so when you when you know on on a normal parallel processor
today and say say an intel core two duo u you think about wanting to
threads at the time
here on a graphics processor we think about wanting a million president time and then
the hardware takes care about crossing into groups as i said we can have multiple
tens of thousands of threads running at the same time on the same
so the GP is also have large
peak throughput ratings lots of big memory subsystems
it's interesting to point out that the register file is actually larger than the cache
is by a considerable amount so register files becomes
a really important places to put data
and the amount of memory that the graphics card has to work with in the
ones that we're using is about get by in video does so ones with larger
memory cache capacity up to four bytes but we're not dealing with this
so just to mention briefly about how we program use
programming is
these GP's is done through cuda which is a small extension to c plus plus
and basically the way it works is the programmer expresses computation in terms of serial
which are called grains and each of those grades is composed of
fred blocks
and when you go to a particular i
let's get this one you have got this is one bit one bit output fall
between so let it slide here
and then she with
sixteen location because you from it about and and one so then what you do
is you want to make this here
you want to implement this is logic in the editor you will make
too stable of this into which has
and it would be if i knew what the
because court the memory for each
the value of the
so you have
you have sixteen bit memory which would be loaded with this but there
and because you have loaded down at the end when you get this a b
c d and this input you
corresponding to it's quite quite simple extremely flexible because you can implement kind of twenty
you can you can implement one gallon fuel
if you have one of the major don't care to do that you have to
duplicate the existing so it's it's three
the connection between the film to legitimate
the school is switch
metric so you are very fast lock and connections of this one
will be
he could have done in in the fast way connected to this one now if
you want to connect this one this one
of this one this one you have to go with this
switch matrix which which would introduce a me but again you have a lot of
of capability also one
the software we we know we manage that fall on
how do you
do you hold your your device so you have
basically three types of a fifteen years
one is
it's just that the configurations so which means that the whole thing is
the content of the media will be loaded in in static
it means that when you pull off your device you lose your configurations so you
have to be polynomial time
but that's extremely flexible because also it means that you can
on the fly change the functionality of your device you
no flash over all other but almost so it's
it's it's a bit more difficult but still you can put on the article even
even in second you don't have to think that you want to put it a
special programme can be a key parameter in you know about and then you have
the the fusing of infected some tissue is system where you just blew his physicality
you blow some connections so that's less flexible in the sense that as soon as
you have problems which you it's far far forward to ensure that it takes about
what is good is that
partition theory and information theory on because it's not issues is completely blind to audition
yes harm is not blind to education so you could have because of addition you
could send to shipping and then you have to to apply special tricks
i said that very very useful in the in the in the county you is
the fact that you have got its
on the eighteenth and prepare
high-speed so cellular
and you have seen that in our application we see a lot of that on
the continent on the from the front the
so if we already the villages
building began
so because we would you like it
from which we have an article since one could argue from the optical to electrical
conversion we and the easiest and that so
is the so-called get you from inside are good
some kind of things today
maximum speed that you can get to the point when given best which which is
a lot so
and you are one of them as you would so there are a number of
of on those forces fifty years
most popular magazines and they are
exactly this is the is one of the of the first one use of this
kind of device was
more than twenty years ago when
and you have a different different from formula
then i can the is is
in a flash based on tissue so we've got a lot of these devices in
and it's experiment because of the addition of everything we can to make them
and others
the devices which are available so if we take design is the vertex six of
process which uses fourteen nanometer process seems forces you can get energy two
twelve of the input output be cheaper
a lot of input output you can get
close to the meaning of logic says that immediate needs for a close to forty
million seven million
two thousand DSP slices so that you can use for that image processing on a
two thirty six i italian consular if you want to edit the it's because you
can use the same
a bit more you know saying that you have also some general-purpose processor inside and
so of course when i say to you do not have a device which i
got all of the neuron in the familiar you can select what what
most that
so in addition these devices is that
something extracted from the veins presentations since
in twenty of the number of
system of structural equations again very briefly describe what about very very briefly related very
closely related to that the graphical representations in case what what's called path diagrams which
if you like can be thought of as the precursors
to the modern theory of graphical models and particularly directed a cyclic graphs
so what we're going to particularly concentrate on in these lectures
the use of probability distributions and the slide extension using what i call extended conditional
as the fundamental building blocks and the use where appropriate which is not one a
hundred percent of the time
of directed acyclic graph representations to
describe the problem and analyse and manipulate
but also say something about something other topics there
right so he has
a simple provides many many of you will live
dance some very basic introductory statistics course
statistics one o one
where you
i mean the
comparative trials
those of you do give the treatment of controlled by neutrino variables zero one
zero control what exactly treatment
you measure some response variable and you basically interested in
the difference may be the difference in the main between the treated and untreated due
to be learned about the two sample t test so one sample
it is
two samples
in this case for example
so that that's pretty much the basic statistics get nevertheless there are different things we
can do with it
the same for the time being i think of the various the simplest case of
a randomized experiment so
we're not we don't have these problems of the observation studies are we comparing like
with like we've tossed penny to decide who gets the treatment
so if we do see differences between them we can interpret them as genuinely do
to the treatment
i'll also say that
i'm not going to be concerned with inference in the t distribution
most of what i'm going to talk about is not the add that what i
got is the second level of you know what the bread-and-butter will statistics courses is
the sort of inference from data when you haven't got enough data and you don't
know things we showed go to quantify or uncertainty that's fine but i'm really
almost everything i'm going to say is predicated on the idea that you could actually
know the underlying
you've got enough data enormous amounts of data and a lot of the problems have
still not gone away
this request is having got all those protein distribution of other relevant to my question
one my going to do
so the problem of statistical inference actually a little wrinkle on top of the problems
of what might call identification understanding the structure of the problem
so let's see how my we
the final measure what we might intuitively called the effect of the treatment we got
this data we
how we had how good is the treatment compared with the control
fisher basically told us what the
from the we got these two groups two arms of the experiment treatment arm control
arm in the treatment lot of data so we can estimate the distribution of the
response in the treatment
normal that's for simplicity does matter called normal women one and variance sigma square we
know the parameters OK we love them
similarly in the control arm we've got another normal distribution what any distribution doesn't matter
with a different mean which we've got from the data museo maybe the same there
is that doesn't matter either
OK so just example think of the standard sort t test formulation with the distributions
can be up to the point is we know them one distribution for treatment
that's the distribution response were treated group and a different distribution typically for the control
colin p one and p zero as well
and then they and the answer is in a sense quite simple we've got these
two distributions and we going to do is compare that doesn't solve the problem because
there are many many ways in which we can compare two different distributions i'm not
going to force you to choose one way or another way that up to you
depending on the context of your problem
but some are the going to do a comparison between these two distributions if they
in polynomial time but i won't into that that's a major problem in this area
of linear programming the ellipsoid algorithm was the first algorithm to solve linear programming in
polynomial time so for a long time people didn't know
around this time people start realizing polynomial time good thing that happened around late sixties
polynomial time is good
and they sort of the first one to do is very general and very powerful
theoretically completely impractical
but it's cool
it lets you do things like you can solve the linear programme that has exponentially
many constraints in polynomial time
all sorts of crazy things so it's not just a polynomial time can't say something
nice about it and say well OK it's impractical
interior point methods are sort of the the mixture they run in polynomial time you
can guarantee that
and there are also pretty practical and this sort of this competition these days about
whether simplex or interior point is better and i don't know what it is today
but a few years ago they were neck-and-neck and random sampling is a brand new
approach this is just from a couple years ago by two
MIT professors
respect CMS and santosh vempala both ones in e guess the others like math so
just to show you is there is active work in this area people are still
finding new ways to solve linear programs this is completely randomized and very simple and
very general hasn't been implemented so we don't know how practical it is yet but
has potential
OK we're going to look at a somewhat simpler version of linear programming
the first restriction we're going to make is actually not much restriction but
unless we will
a little bit easier to think about so here
we had some polytope we want to maximize some objective you feasibility problem i just
want to know is the polytope to empty can you find any point in the
polytope can you find any set of values x that satisfy these constraints so there
is no objective
just find x such that
the axis classical b
it turns out you can provide very general theorem that if you can solve linear
feasibility you could also solve linear programming
one present here is actually no easier than the original problem even though feels easier
it's easier to think about
actually no easier than LP
OK the next restriction like to make is a real restriction simplifies the problem quite
a bit
and and that's the difference constraints
and all the same to track so far we now
ground suffer little bit so a system of difference constraints is a linear feasibility problem
so it's LP where there's no objective
and his with the restrictions somewhere
each row of the matrix
so the matrix
has one
and it has one minus one
and everything else in the in the row is zero
OK in other words
each constraint very simple form involves two variables
and some numbers so we have something like the next day
minus x y is less than or equal to w i j
so this is just the number these are two variables a minus sign no no
values up here coefficients no other of vx
cases appear
just to the
and you have a bunch of constraints of this form it one per row of
the matrix
i haven't thought about what this means
i think it means the hyperplanes are pretty simple
so we can do better than a little hard to see this in high dimensions
but it will start to
correspond something we've seen namely the board the next
very short
OK so let's do very quick
only to have something to point
all the when
this system changes completely the behaviour
which was following
taking into account these
and the composition which formally applies only to linear system but conceptually is the general
view of all dynamical system we can understand better our modelling for the water level
are located
OK so
let's move to the second part of the of the talk which is talking a
little bit more about more than
now we just so
a one way of modelling
our dynamical systems and then our time series which is using state equations
out equations differential equations or difference equations
they can go into account that for certain kind of systems
which are systems that it is always possible to write the dynamical system using first
a set of first-order differential equations
so we have limited our analysis just one
kind of
modelling of view of the system
as a matter of fact we already so
he said that
when we have a system and we start from the very start instead of starting
then the knowledge about the internal structure of the system we can use the input
output or black small block sorry black box warning
we can
using this system is what it what we call the
these are somehow different with respect to the
way of approaching the system
interim more dynamic differential equations and what is the basic idea
the heart this kind of system well the idea is that the input output representation
it tells us
a lot of things about the system even if i don't know exactly what are
the state variable but i'm able to
have in good insight about this is that if we met but we go back
to that sold to this point but
if we we remember
the column and the composition
in some way using you put out modelling
say well i hope
the system is completely reachable and observable OK i hope the timeline here and then
i will try to model in some way
what i'm not able to
put into the input output more something else like noise
i'm trying to say well i would like to stay here actually and i think
that these is enough to describe what's happening to the system
in this case the outcome of the so
i just need the
two more than
the input output relationship and then to estimate the parameters of this model using the
using some good
you may to do that
we already talked about the idea of was restless and transfer function we don't talk
we will not talk about convolution of the convolution models because we don't have time
but just to tell you that the examples of
become modelling in the case of
drug distribution
over time we have here
it's a simple input output more than
which bordered these
a system in which we have we have even asserting the right to the patient
at time zero
and we certainly over time the drug plasma drug concentration
we use in this case instead of using a state space model
we just use input output more which relates the inputs so i'll drug to the
output of the measurement of drug concentration over time and you see here that these
models may have hansen and no parameters
which are these in fact
that we have to estimate from the using proper estimation
make the least squares squares or
maximum likelihood
or any of the method that you probably already a soul
within this scores
of course we already sell systems and systems modeling what i would like to say
it's one of the point also all the edges of the ribbon reading the book
is that when we are
approaching the problem of
modelling inside the the systems using state variables we are of course in more
if a knowledge about the current about the
real functioning of the system and we can try
to arrive the search in a representation of the system you again what the
compartmental models that we have used the exact is examples of a before well we
with respect to the data modelling we we are using these notion of the state
equations and our goal of course is trying to
compliments the view
all this is the
voting for example some knowledge or guesses about the overall system OK so also made
parts which are
not necessarily reachable in the end of suitable
OK talking about
time series for completeness say a
it's important to
not only
deterministic models but also
two bodies which are
applied in the analysis of time series when i just have a a collection of
input output they or maybe also
only all out
because sometimes i don't have exactly
my good little small current running through the voltmeter that you see the that's so
small that
can always ignore these you get double
you might
now what i will do
so i have now about two vols
between these two plates
two batteries in series
and i have a little bit like both here
and i'm going to
turn on the light
and now what you'll see
is that the voltage that you measure right here that's all you can do you
can only measure the voltage
at the plates of the battery that now this voltage will drop
because of the internal resistance of the battery in addition you will see some light
but that's really not my objective
those of you who was sitting close you can see is light bulb
going to be lit
if i do this now
i can see the light bulb a little bit of light
notice that the voltage goes down
and so this value that you measure now
you will be
now lower
and the one point nine holds because of this term you lose
the battery internal resistance
you lose their
potential difference
so let's take this out because this produces a lot of
a a lot of smelly fields
that's fine
if the charge
moves from point a to point b
and here the potential
three eight
and here the potential is creepy
and charge dq move that suppose for simplicity
that the
the mind a
now let's let's make the a larger than VB just a little easier to thinking
that those terms it's not necessary to collapse may be a larger than he
the electric field from a to b
and i move charge
from a to b
then the electric field is doing work
and the work that the electric field is doing the w
is the charge
i the potential difference which is to be a minus b
this work
can be positive
if the charge is positive
the negative charge is negative
because we have assumed that this is possible in this case
i can now do something that you shouldn't tell
your math teachers
physicists do it all the time
we defined by dt
and i would say half of we have on the left side is no work
unit time that's power joules per second
so there is no squalor
pqt genes current
how many calls per second flow
so this is current i
and the potential difference i simply call use that symbol v
so you see now you that
power the liver
by a
power supply
is the current that it produces
times the potential difference
and this is independent of ohms law there's always holds
if you also includes
ohms law
if you can
we use it
last time we discussed the limitations of but if you can use it and vehicles
i are
then of course
you can also write down for the power that his eyes grey are
and is also be created
divided by our
power is joules per second
when we write
for that
due the second we write for that what
just the capitol w
named after the physicist what
we always express the power in terms of what's
so suppose we have a
resistance are
and we want to current through it
this resistance
and we want to current i through it
and let's take an example that the current i is one and here
and that the resistance
is one hundred o
and the power which is dissipated in this
to be provided by a battery
that power
is is now
one hundred watts
i squared r
you want to use this
it has two and
you don't change the resistance
and he becomes four hundred watts
i square are idols
four times higher
o was energy
this debate in the form of heat
and if it gets hot enough
maybe you can produce light the idea behind the light bulb
the element into in tungsten incandescent light bulb
becomes very high
twenty five
under a degree centigrade maybe even three thousand
not so high of course that the tungsten melts
and so
you begin to see light
so for instance a hundred what
the light bulb
four from here
so if we have a hundred watt light bulb dormitory
and the voltage
it's on the ten of just
plug it into the wall
and the currents
that run is about o point nine mps
it was VI
this product
the hope
and then the resistance
that you have
is about a hundred and twenty on
because i are
so even though
well not really i mean the original out of this algorithm looks like
and adaboost has an exponential the log there's renormalisation
well this looks completely different
but the funny thing is that this thing take everything into account to get from
here to here is just an analytical squish there's no approximation
and the reduction from here to here uses the fact that is the binary matrix
so what this is in fact is an iterated map because it's an equation for
the weight vector at time t plus one in terms of the weight vector at
time t
so gives us a way to directly update the weight vector
and the existence of this map really enables the study of low dimensional cases so
that's exactly what i'm going to do now
so i say well i had this tool can analyse what dimensional case here goes
this the simplest case that i could come up with
this is the case where the major families like this we have three weak classifiers
three training instances each classifier misclassifies one training instance
OK now the weight vector
remember we have three training examples
the weight vector has three components and their
probability they form a discrete probability distribution
on the on the instances so what i'm talking about is the fact that the
the weight vector is always lies somewhere in this nation complex
but i didn't feel like plugging things on the simplex
so what i'm going to do
it's going to be putting a lot of triangles are going to do is i'm
going to take the simplex in squash it onto the purple triangle
so when i'm writing triangles in the future what i'm going to be plotting is
the simplex projected onto the first two dimensions DT one and DT two
and what i'm going to do
as i'm going to start somewhere in the simplex right in the middle simplex where
the weight vector is just one thirty one thirty one thirty
and then i'm going to send out into the dynamical system
tell me where to go to the next iteration so i'm going to be topping
all around the simplex and
well you know what you'll see is going to be jumping around on the on
this trying on purple triangle
according to the dynamics and that's exactly what what i was doing
OK so the question remember what i'm doing
and at each iteration
when i i just wanted to do this you could follow the dynamics earlier iterations
one can apply more blue circles and later iterations and apply large red circles and
the time increases the circle gets larger and larger and they happen to get more
and more red the the college not important that it's really the size of the
support OK so so
i'm going to start security one
with the weight vectors being all equal so pt one is one thirty two two
one thirty and DT three is just one minus the humanity t one which is
one third
so it's here
i think this and i sent into the dynamical system and it tells me where
to go next and in fact it tells me to go over here
so any guesses as to where it's going next
and it's impossible to figure it out i'm going to put all these articles up
so you can see where the
so you can see what's going on here
at equals three
we end up actually over here at equals before we end up here articles five
here people six here people seven here people eight equals nine people ten eleven twelve
converting to cycle the weight is converging to cycle
OK so what's really going on here so let me let me analyse the for
so what happens is that the first step in the street in our tracks
what that does is it divides the simplex into three regions there is one region
where you choose we classify one one region which is classified to the regional wages
we classify three
and the next step what it does is it projects each triangle to align
so the data of one triangle gets projected onto this line over here
it it was triangle ends up here in the eighty three triangle ends up over
here so that in one iteration
they are
the the dynamics on the dynamical system on the two dimensional simplex becomes the one-dimensional
iterated map on the
and the edges of the inner triangle
and then from there what happens is that different chunks of the triangle map to
other chunks
by a
montana contraction in fact so this child gets knocked over here which gets better here
which gets mapped to a subset of the
so what happens is that within three iterations each chunk of the triangle gets mapped
to a subset of itself by monotonic contractions
so you get nice fixed point
because everything
so there are in fact six fixed points there are three fixed point three to
two possible cycles
so what in the world is you talking about well
the thing is what i'm saying here
if that converted to a cycle of here but it could equally converge to another
over here
o point he's gonna ask me well how does that know which cycle to converge
to well known
it was like to converge to
because of this that
this is this is jt is in argmax blah blah blah blah blah
so there could be more than one element in that set
in fact the very first iteration of adaboost there's three elements in the set
it doesn't know which of the weak classifiers to pick
because all of them all of them are the best we classify for the job
so it makes an arbitrary decision
and then iteration two it also makes an arbitrary decision between the weak classifiers and
those two arbitrary decisions determine which of the two possible cycles adaboost converges
and the nice thing is that i can actually calculate the coordinates of these of
the fixed point
by using this equation
it just comes right up
OK now the nice thing about this temple is that the maximum margin solution is
actually team
the maximum margin in this case is one third adaboost actually choose the maximum margin
so when i was studying this this is obviously the first case that i but
i was looking at because you know this is the case where can really analyse
that and here you know maximum margin solution is attained and no one would ever
proof before that was achieved the maximum margin solution so i will present all my
goodness this conjecture must be true at this must always achieve maximum margin solution
and i was studying statistical learning theory at the time and i should have known