you may get something unexpected if you have a small the sample size to get
unexpected somehow have to find
the middle
they have optimal equivalence emphasizing questions now what properties of data
actually determine the value of the equivalent sample size
so we treated now as an additional parameter
that we want to learn and among all the different
criteria that we could optimize we just follow the objective function of time still under
and co-workers from last year that we want to
marginal likelihood again and find the alpha and
the graph maximizing
and that can be done easily in accordance percent
approach just iterate
two steps in the first step
you optimize graph
for a fixed
sample size value that can be done with any standard
structure learning algorithm
and the second step is now optimise the equivalent
sample size value
for a fixed graph
and that's not interesting
part how can we do that
and what i do is now do a lot of very crude approximations
because i just want to find out what are the main effects of main properties
of the data that affect
the equivalent sample size value
so let's start out again with the marginal likelihood
and this
peter grew out mentioned yesterday you can understand it
a measure of predictive accuracy in the prequential
that means that you assume that theta arrive sequentially
and then every
that you predict that point
given all the previous data points
and now i approximate that by
the frequentist test our
which is very crude i admitted
so this is not the test error that you
typically get when you cross validation
now as the next step i can approximate this one
on the one hand the
a great information criteria
so i
and just computed from the training error and the penalty
and doc ic ac information criterion independent
so that's the one thing
and then i can do is second approximation
there i assume no
that in this test relates my
described by the model
test distribution that now this
true distribution takes the form as implied by the patient approach
i don't know the optimal
alpha star
and now i can just create both of those
and get a leading order approximation my
excellent performance optimally equivalent sample size
and as you can see it's a ratio of the effective number
of parameters innovation network
basically the negative
entropy of the empirical distribution or the maximum likelihood
divided by n
and the other term is basically the cross the likelihood of the
prior q and the empirical distribution
divided by an again
a sanity check we can now see that the nominator denominator is indeed
a positive number
if q is uniform because it can be rewritten in terms of entropy is and
KL divergence
and so we actually get that the
star is in the positive test p
now we can also derive a few properties
i would like to thank your organisation of the wide wonderful workshop i really enjoy
being here
and i might be talking about stability selection and i think it's a good idea
an example
what i mean by stability
and so i think this is indeed one example stability
i say what
not sleeping beings
i will not so easily change his mind
i think it just means that we can
what makes
airplane going to tell me
and so
this is the what she called
there's actually
congratulations to the humboldt prize
i think that the right place to say that replaced here you've got it
well let's good jokes young side
they talk about
my talk
what i wanted
explain you can show you that
you want to do some kind of better detection bars
recovery happen all variables
of components or
factors in the
and the top of the race kind of the
burning question how many people
actually you know what
how many components meaning
so roughly speaking what today
talk about
regularized estimation discrete structures
in high dimensional saving and i think
this is very real and in many practical applications
often also substantially more
here is another example of his example this biology example would be willing to fix
just go with little example
it's an example being the
actually quite a lot of success by applying this last type one station
so what about
finding it for transcription factor binding sites in DNA sequences
roughly speaking this just decide the protein can bind to DNA
i mean mean it
have to tell you the information about the problem
univariate response variable y
a major some kind of binding intensity on of course
we have a very high dimensional exists
and the j th component j covariance matrices score of candidate binding site so you
put together a lot of candidates
and want to link
so what you do is or what we do is a random variable selection in
additive model
so we went
well why
in the function of x and y
sample sizes to eighty seven he is not super high dimensional but in many real
they have problems in high dimensions in biology
if p
o one million
really very high dimensional
so the random variable selection is that model because the same for the next four
you want to reason why algorithm and
twenty six going
today then you would say OK these twenty six variables these are interesting candidates interesting
binding sites in
you report these findings to the biologists
we this
i don't trust this selection algorithms
the burning question how stable are these
and to be honest i mean never quite many biology problem
i would never support when
we really want to make sure that your findings are kind of more stable more
robust and only then you reported to the biology because it's quite laborious biological station
OK so
how can we address this question
we trust our in-house they findings
and i mean
i don't have so many great idea
i think the simple idea
let's use subsampling or bootstrapping
and applied to biology problems
the run sparse modeling
it includes the variable selection two thousand seven he almost
the first subsample dataset maybe select variable ten
some of the variables are selected over and over again
and of course you end up with a keep the variable be declared to be
stable if have occurred
more than eighty percent seven or ninety percent or in general high threshold to cross
he was reported variables
and in this particular data
only two stable findings me
initially twenty six
i this subsampling stability procedure only two stable remains
and actually is too stable findings they are highly interesting was blocking the protein
one of the covariance its corresponding to the function
like nonlinear corresponds to a true known binding site
stable covariance
response to the people which is almost linear
and this is an interesting can be used for elements of the particle
and do
a lot of citations because i told
this is stable
OK so biology aside this kind of my introductory example
and this is what you want to ask questions how she
and in election he
it was really more than eighty percent of the time ninety
OK so
this is game with an outline the show you
in our experience and i actually spent quite a while
subsampling bootstrapping in the context of selection you
the course is nothing else than the procedure on selection are solely or primarily you've
heard about the
it and the predictions are just doing this
and it really works
he were in our many empirical example what's new is that we can justify
this procedure a very simple procedure and very interesting properties
what will be able to achieve and i'll show you
you can show
finite sample control of reform
easily able to do so
so in a sense what we're doing is really a marriage of high dimensional selection
i would like to see that the graph modeling
OK so here is what it is
let's just
we simply consider linear model
so these are the
three main classes of approaches to
two graph comparison
the isomorphism based approaches to graph edit distance based approaches and the approaches
based on top logical descriptors
as i have said
they either suffer from the fact
they have worst-case exponential runtime
or that they neglect important topological information that is encoded in the graph structure
that's why
and this is somehow what inspired to work on graph cards people are interested in
a polynomial runtime alternative
graph edit distances and to isomorphism based graph comparison
that captures
as much of the topological information encoded in the graphs as possible
so graph kernels
similarity measures on graphs
let's compare substructures of graphs
which are computable in polynomial time
and ideally such
a graph kernels such a similarity measure on graphs is computable in polynomial time
would be expressive
although most of the topology that is encoded
in the graph structure
it will be efficient to compute
it will be positive definite and that's a requirement
machine learning such as this color can be used in connection with convex optimization tools
get more into this later on
in the tutorial
and a fourth criterion is that
your graph kernel - your similarity measure on graphs held be applicable to a wide range of
of course you you might be able to
define efficient draft
kernels for subgraphs of graphs strings
or trees
graphs is cross in general
is interesting and not all graphs that are being produced in application domains of trees
all strings we really need similarity measures to do that work on graphs in general
now we have an idea of how
graph kernels related to the other approaches
two graph comparison
but we don't know yet what a kernel really is
so this is the next question
try to answer what is
graph kernels and starting with the first what is a kernel
the easiest way to explain what the problem
in feature space
and you do so
measuring similarity between objects in your feature space or by computing distances between objects in
your in your feature space
and one way of measuring similarity between objects in your future space is to compute
an inner product
between the objects in your feature space
so what you do is
you map your data points where mapping phi from input space to feature space and
then you take an inner product
between these objects in your feature space
and the kernel function and now that's that's it was crucial in the message here
is a function
on two
objects from the input space
which is
that inner product between these two objects in the feature space
this means that we can compute
the similarity between two objects x and x prime
in feature space by evaluating a function
in input space
and that's the famous commentary
there are several important consequences of this
one is that
by choosing
another different kernel function k
you implicitly
move your learning problem
two are different to another feature space
another implication is
as long as you've defined this function K
and as long as you can show that the corresponding feature space exists you do
not even have to know the mapping phi
to that feature space
because you can compute all similarity scores between objects new feature space by evaluating
this kind of function
and the third and for our purposes most important consequence
that x and x-prime need not be vectorial data
they can be any type of structured data strings time series and graphs
as long as you can measure the similarity in terms
of a scalar
and as long as you can show that the corresponding feature space exists
in which
this scalar corresponds to the inner product between
these two graphs
know this
previous slides I will answer the question of what what a graph kernel is. a graph kernel is a kernel
operates on two graphs to measure the similarity
in terms of an inner product in some feature space
in this graph problems
to the larger class of our convolution codes
which were defined by haussler  in  nineteen ninety nine
the idea here
it's simple but it has inspired a lot of important work
on constant structured data
a convolution kernel works by
two given a structured objects x and x prime into days parts
to give a very simple example take two graphs decompose them
into this set of nodes
and then this convolution kernel compares all
pairs of substructures
from the first
graph from the first structured object and from the second structured object
so all pairs of sub-structures are compared to each other in my example of all
pairs of nodes
from g and g prime
would be compared to each other by a second
kernel function the kind of function k parts here which operates on the
substructures of the two structured objects that we want to compare that's to simple underlying
and graph kernels as I have said before
are such convolution kernels
where x
is a graph and x-prime is a graph as well
if you check the literature on graph problems
don't be confused because it the second
way of using the term graph kernels
and in fact my
my professor in cambridge
uses other terminology in his paper so that's really confusing
sometimes people
will refer
to a graph kernel when they compare two nodes in one graph
by account so they can be
quite confusing when i refer graph here in this tutorial i always mean that measuring
similarity between two
obviously if we decompose
two structured objects to graphs in a different way for instance if i decompose two
graphs into a set of walks
rather than the set of nodes
then this results in a new type of graph coloring so by changing the decomposition
i changed graph problem
as well
and why is it useful to have such a graph kernel because
nation senses
it is i
i was so this is what i want to use
it's all in
this is mess
this is
citizens who were
what to do
that was i schools
does not as some management right
the answer is yes
you can see how this
well done is a town
so take it
so i
the property that every edge
the number of five so know
every edge is
connected to try
well maybe not time
you can see it that all
that's fine
so has been on the exactly two forces zero
so the time
it's example that
which i been don't to exactly one
this it that
under those circumstances very
policy that
this is about science and scientists
this is a
did not
next step set of centres lost
the back question of
statistical used
here it is
to this end the listening
will be learning about this
now are about
so what is it like this one
this is
there some statistics
suppose that the statistical set
originally came from some
scientific rules one nation
the main reason
so they
so some
new zealand music the
o is the same as well
to measure the
one one one
and what we will be
is that you are
are actually test
it's not
so that's it
what want to see
good song one
it's time to find song
for this
one that human races
this is a new this by show
however there's problem
which is
finding these
i a
question to ask is
how do make sense
this is from the
that you
you want
someone has a child
is actually one
and what one
there is a problem we have
one of the variance
but very very unstable
the quality
presented to losing changes
pretty famous guys i'm harry shum who was believe
head of microsoft research asia
the computer vision place and with the risk records that LSP who's over microsoft as
well in seattle
and they basically proposed in the non is that
you could instead of
instead of trying to have this he pluses delta p
if you waltz
allow this compositional
and a final does so if if if anything whatever you just think of
philip's army of what was on the board
so there is the final piece goods is that if i have a whole heap
take one x x one
but i got some and
which is my final
the pixels which
where x one is of where x one all these axes the two vectors
the nice thing about this is that this is in fact
the multiplication so i'm not adding anything here
and what i can do is to say i had let
prior that guys from this
this trying to sort of kind of like this small trying to start off with
i composed this EM
and it makes me bigger
again so it doubles doubles what's on
now five floodplain if i could composite what i can apply this exact same end
to the strike
and it will get twice as large
you get twice as large again
however if i do and added walk
so if i don't represent if i don't represent these what is composite bodies adding
on the update
i want to get this effect he was taken to scale were taken to rotation
it'll just basically the what if i'm adding the what the world be specific or
where exactly i am mean the image and so
what this is not about is that i don't i can actually get some very
big computational savings by taking advantage of this compositional idea
and so
what's going on here
is that instead of thinking that people are still to be
i've got a very actually walk wx p
composed with
delta p
and here and so on
this is a slide from from so many and actually and they basically demonstrate here
that you can actually break this down steps
i've got my imply
and i can what this template first by
just delta pay so instead of doing the entire world which report me into the
source image i can do it delta p that's slightly distorts things then i can
match to the image with my final p such i finally get there so i
can break it into steps rather than having to do here
i have to do everything
in terms of
this single what function to go the source image not compose things
so like i i will
still don't quite follow that simon so why is it useful well-reasoned useful is that
i can actually inverse composed as well
and i was talking about i was talking about this before so if instead of
me trying to work out
how the source image should move with respect to the template
i could actually work out how might imply should move so i could get the
gradients and here
i could work out how this template should what should change this delta p
with respect
two source image but instead of them having to what template
i in the war
and i want to the source image
and the next thing that happens here
is the gradient and the actual template stay the same in every iteration
so there is no
jacobian doesn't have to change every iteration
and will
i've got here
the intrinsic value of the called of the yellow line
and this is an intrinsic value of output we've got them both the same exercise
all right
and then i've shown here the stock price when the blue line
stock price again stock prices just a forty five degree line line with a slope
of one
well you notice that if i were to buy a call
and write a put that senior shorting inputs
i would have
the combined portfolio with just those two
the yellow line here and i have minus the pink line here
i would have a parallel straight line looks just like the stock price just shifted
thirty five by a call
and short a put a right put
it's the same thing as owning the stock minus the exercise price
so that's that's what we have here the
put call shared relations
so we're taking account of dividends
that diagram didn't show the fact that stocks were paid my pay dividends between now
and the exercise
but you can see when i was just saying
got i said colonies what this is what i call
minus the price of i have a minus sign in front of everything
but it is just the with the diagram shows so it put called charity means
is that we only need
the theory of
either call prices or put prices
and then the other one falls right output called parity
all i need is the theory of call prices so we we just forget about
and we just talk about calls
from now on
and then if if i give you a problem to ask you
what is the input price what is the price of the put you would go
in and calculate the price of call
and then calculate
we we the put option price will put this on the right-hand side of the
the put price
would equal the call price
plus the present value of the straight plays
thus the present value of dividends minus the price of the stock
so that and so that makes it very easy or we have to do is
worry about calls
and so
we're my
the question for financial theory is
what determines the pink line we you agree that it should be above intrinsic value
as as the option gets closer to exploration
as time moves on and the exercise days is getting closer and closer in time
this pink lines and go down down down on the last day
he hits the intrinsic value
so but what what is it before they exercise so
i want to start with
theory which illustrates how we calculate these thing
but this is a theory that
applies to us
so so we can understand it easily
it applies to a stripped-down situation
i want to derive the price of an option
under the assumption
it's very simple there is only one period now an exercise
it's in it's a european option we're gonna
exercise in one we have
exercise data one period
and i also under the restrictive assumptions and this is for pedagogical purposes just to
simplify up
that the stock price s is the stock price today
and the stock this stock is very special because
next period it to have only
two values
it's as times u
if the stock goes up u stands for up
and it's less times d
if the stock price goes down
and what i'm saying with the what's arbitrary here is i'm saying that there's only
two possible prices for the stock experience as you
or SD
that's not real world because as you know
there's all kinds of infinite number of possible prices next year
but again this is just
i think that we should be able to figure out what the price of a
call option
on this stock should be worth
it's very simple
but it's
this is very simple but the people who invented this one the nobel prize so
how hard i don't want to make it this wasn't so simple in the history
of financial thinking
but anyway so you understand the situation that we're proposing and it's just like this
is very funny stock that we know for some reason we know
s is the price today
and next period when the option exercise dated
it's pretty either going to be as you are going to be as as times
are going to be as times the
OK and then there is an interest rate then we can both by our land
at this risk this interest rates so what should the option be worth
OK so in this case
i'm going to call c
the current price of the car
today this is before and this is before
the exercise dates so
the price of the car was going to be worth more than the intrinsic value
i'm going to call c sub you
the value of the call next period if the price is up
and see some of the the value of the call next period if the price
is down
that we that's the thing we read off of those
like broken straight lines
so a CU would be you know the stock price mind if it's the stock
minus the exercise price if it's in the money
we know that in advance
because we already know what the two possible prices are next period so we already
what the two possible options values are next here this is the intrinsic value
if it's up and this is the intrinsic value of its down
will call either strike price of the option exercise price of the option
is everything clear here
when alpha is constant if alpha in particular is
if it doesn't have to be constant lesson com
o one right
or equivalently which is what you said
it is all
which is to say if the number of elements in the table
these were
upper bounded by a constant times and
and the search costs cost a lot of people hashtable
runs in constant
search time
that's actually wrong
depends upon the load factor of the
OK and people have made programming errors based on that misunderstanding of hash tables
because they have hash table is too small
the number of elements putting in there
doesn't help
number way know in fact will grow
with the
this is one plus an over and actually grows with n
so unless you make sure that keeps up with n
this doesn't stay constant
it turns out for successful searches also one out
for that you need to do a little bit more mathematics
because you have to conditional on
searching for the items in the table but it turns out is also one plus
and that's that you can read about in the book
and also there's a more rigorous proof i sort of have glossed over
stop here
OK doing for more intuitive proof so of those things you should look for the
so this is one reason why caching is such a popular method is basically let
you represent a dynamic set
we were one
cost per operation constant cost per operation inserting deleting
so as long as the table you're keeping
it is
not much smaller than the number of items that you're putting in
and then all the operations end up being in constant time
but it depends upon this strongly upon this assumption of simple uniform hashing
and so
no matter what hash function you pick
i can always find a set of
elements that are going to hash
that hash functions crashed badly
i just
generate a whole bunch of them and to see where the hash function takes them
in the end
recall once hash to the same place
actually way of countering that but in practice
i understand that
most programs that need to use things are really reverse engineering hash function
so there's some very simple hash functions
but this game will be fine
a large margin classifier that perfectly classifies all the training examples and with large margin
and we show that adaboost is finding this maxmin strategy by applying general game playing
through repeated play
so what are the consequences of this so one of them was
i suggested in the question that was just ask so the first thing is that
it's showing that the weights on the weak classifiers
are actually converging to an approximate maximum strategy for this game so this is telling
us what the weights are converging to in adaboost
likewise it's telling us something about the convergence of these distributions it saying that the
average of the distributions computed by adaboost is converging to an approximate minmax strategy for
this game
it's also showing that this connection between margins and edges that i mentioned before before
imagine that we can show that larger edges imply larger margins
we now see that the reason for that is because of this game theoretic view
of the algorithm that margins are edges
are connected by the minimax theorem they're both
exactly related to the value of this game
and this also explains why adaboost maximizes margins
looking up
because this general algorithm it's got parameter parameter where you can
two and how how how good an approximation you want and adaboost is setting that
parameter in one
particular way
i'm not explaining the details but so it's it's only finding an approximation of it
OK so
that's what i want to say about the game theory actually wants a one other
thing about it so it different instantiation of the same game playing algorithm also gives
online algorithms for those of you have seen online algorithms metric there's a tutorial on
that but for instance the weighted majority algorithm so this provides a connection to other
learning models as well
that's what i want to say about adaboost in game theory
so what i want to do now is to go on to the second way
of thinking about adaboost which is thinking about it as an optimisation algorithm
if i'm sure you've seen in this
summer school
that many or maybe even most learning and statistical methods can be viewed as minimising
some kind of gloucester cost objective function
which in one way or another is measuring the fit to the data so classic
example is least squares regression
we're trying to minimize the sum of the squared areas of your model
compared to the correct
so adaboost also
can be viewed as an algorithm for minimizing
what a loss function
and why does this matter will it's helpful to understand this
because the first fully kind clear flies with the goal of the algorithm is
and it's also useful in proving convergence properties about the algorithm
if we can beat decouple the algorithm from what it is that it's minimizing then
possibly that would make it possible to derive faster algorithms for the same objective function
or conversely we take the same algorithm generalize it so that it can be used
for other loss functions and their by other
learning problems of various kinds
what is it that adaboost is minimizing
so if you go back to the training year proof
we show that the training error the final classifier is at most product of zee
is these normalisation constants and we showed that this normalisation factor
can be written in general as this function of epsilon t and alpha t
excellent is the weighted their the teeth we classifier and alpha t is the parameter
and then we selected alpha t to minimize this expression
giving this expression
OK so if you look at this more closely well
first of all as i just said i alpha t has been chosen to minimize
in this expression and also ht
the weak classifiers being chosen to minimize the weak classifiers or epsilon t
two things change
and different techniques of being exploited in computer vision
together with about visual word representation
for classification proposed
and both generative and discriminative meters have been used
and among the disconnected needed support vector machine is one of the most popular
that there are some special least addressed
for image categorisation
by the way
generative approach
obtain competitive results this means explaining this discriminatively has been discussed
this school
one of the
the first
more than that have been used
with bag of visual words
in two thousand three
and also discuss justified probabilistic latent semantic analysis
it is one of the state of the art approach to
there will
the classification adequately station in
for some patients
you are probably and
in this case the visual world
and if we have a problem with a hundred visual world
is an indicator vector well
there's one position and zero in that position
dublin old
indicator collection
region one
the image here the degree and that topic
for instance
within that scene
and the simplest generative model
is there naive
by small
we have just you know
and the set of nodes in this is the set of
within an image
one of the class of the image
this graph decomposes
in this too
this too
probability prior probability
over the last
and the likelihood of observing a set of
vision were even
independence making visual words
we can get this kind of probability
what we should do is to estimate
the probability of serving a specific region were given the class
and taking into account the
we can approximate this posterior probability
five is the composition of that
we can use that marks to infer the class and this was the first the
most simple
use with about the visual world model in two thousand three
other the problem
image categorisation
object categorisation specifically
and the set of objects was like this
there are seven
is also obtained by sort
although these that set
where we have some object class
i've been using SIFT descriptors
and a simple thing means
to build the vocabulary
and the naive bayes classifier
and i
very nice results but not too bad
because this was the first war
with this number of classes the diffusion
and by the way if you
say some
powerful medium for classification like
the linear
you can obtain better results first
and moving on more sophisticated models
the probabilistic semantic more than that
it is mother from text community as well
and in this case we have three nodes
no the for the documents
and topics
and then of the visual of the words within a document
and with this definition we have the process of the generative process of selecting an
image with probability with some some probability
then given
the common because some topics and even at all this we can select
is no conditioning and then we infuse CRF and we wait an hour and see
what happens in the sham animals don't have any lesions have about dublin of startle
that effect is totally blocked animals with lesions to the bed nucleus but not all
animals that have lesions of the central nucleus of the amygdala
so just like the difference between light hand startle and fear potentiated startle
CRH enhanced our looked more like lightning and startled
so again we get this double dissociation these be the amygdala and the bed nucleus
fear potentiated startle being dependent on the make the bed nucleus when i say they
may on talking about the central nucleus and vice versa for light enhanced darwin's serie
so in the schema them CRF seems to
act on receptors in the bed nucleus and we have much better evidence for that
now if we give an antagonist into the bed nucleus locally it blocks the effects
of zero
so it turns out we've also
got a hold of a very selective CRF antagonists and peptide peptide great big molecules
they don't get into the brain when you given systemically so large drug companies are
trying to develop seraphim tag because they think they're going to be very interesting compounds
for blocking stress and depression and anxiety and so forth and it turns out that
when we get this compound it blocks the slightly enhanced that's not very pretty dose
response curve but lower doses fallen here but interestingly even over wide range of doses
the CRF antagonists doesn't touch fear potentiated startle so once again we get the difference
between the role of CRF in fear potentiated startle versus all linehan startled
or which is right hand stalinists case and more recently we've been finding that hormonal
regulation seems to occur with behaviors depending on the bed nucleus and not potentiated startle
so testosterone in male rats reduces fear anxiety attacks on the bed nucleus and that
doesn't do anything to fear potentiated startle and progesterone in female rats and so
tentatively what was suggested as you really have these two systems that act in parallel
in the brain you have a fear system that accident very phasic way
it recovers quickly so you can get onto another to you know be ready for
something else whereas you have another system that acts in a more sustainable way
and in this kind of sense that's roughly the difference between fear and anxiety and
zion is less specific last longer seems that to be activated by a more diffuse
the question though
is you know what is the fundamental differences are just words fear and anxiety can
we come up with the more operational definition to try to understand in the more
detailed way what's going on here so the two differences between fear potentiated startle
and light enhanced startle CHI and startled is fear potentiated startle depends on conditioning whereas
lighter sear enhanced oil doesn't require conditioning and the second is fear potentiated startle is
very short term these three seconds ten second life
whereas seriation and starlight hence total is much more long-lasting so to disambiguate those two
what we did is purposely took a long queue
so specific you but it's long in duration
and now we condition
and so
if in fact that's depend on the bed nucleus would say duration is dependent on
the central nucleus it would say was conditioning
in this work by david walker so what we do is take an animal given
clicker because that's quite salient so the clock comes on click click click click click
for eight minutes and then at random times during that we give the animal some
sharks we do that day one we do that and day two so basically what
the animal learns is that when the clicker comes on the risk but they don't
know when they're going to get
so it's kind of the state of heightened continual apprehension and now we assess startle
all i mean we assess
fear or anxiety in the presence of this eight minute tone with the startle stimulus
either with the qu yuan or with no click around
and what we find is that when clickers on there's no change from the previous
post is actually a lot of context condition here
for the afficionados and the
but when we turn the click around we get a big healthy increasing startled
the question is is
is the central nucleus or the bed nucleus mediating this long-term activation
now this is a complicated slide but if you get it you understand right away
and if you don't get it i try to explain it again
we're looking at startle now when this tone is on for eight minutes and we
just broken up to the first half the town in the second half the time
we have animals that have can tell us so we can activate either the bed
nucleus the central nucleus of the amygdala
and will either vehicle or this compound in activates glutamate transmission so the vehicle animals
do which you think they're afraid beginning at the time of the clicker in the
end of the clicker karttunen here's different experiments stoner clicker
so they basically sort of level across this time that's not significant increase
the really cool thing is that the animals that have the bed nucleus and activation
we have lots of fear at the beginning of the of the stimulus but not
all of the and very little
and it's kind of vice versa with the central nucleus
at the beginning they have some fear but it's certainly less than the bed nucleus
animals and at the end they have perfectly normal fear seems the vehicles
so as i said if you get it you get it right away and if
you don't get it it's the idea is that when the stimulus comes on the
first thing does is activated the central nucleus because ripping down to the brain stem
to produce the phasic fear response but then something else activates are sort of hands
after the bed nucleus and the bed nucleus can respond in the same way so
that's why we activate the bed nucleus earlier nothing happens but it blocks later on
and sort of vice versa for the central nucleus and the reason i'm sort of
waffling here is that we don't know how long the all we know is the
central nucleus were totally what if this is a three-second tone we don't know within
three seconds to four minutes and we're working on that right now
and when you activate the bays the lateral which gives the sensory information to both
bed nucleus and the central blocks both phenomena
the cool thing is if you use just the right dose
now if you give the CRF antagonists so here's the control condition for four minutes
second four minutes so that's kind of level if you give the CRF antagonists this
fear to the first four minutes but it's got the last four minutes
so that some evidence that what's happening in the sustain fear that we call it
is there's release of CRF and actually that release comes from the central nucleus the
made by now higher dose i have to be honest does blocked both that's again
because we're we're we're collapsing of these big chunks of time
these are the exploratory data analysis phase
then we use descriptive data mining
to deter mined unusual it is
to narrow down the search list for
and for that
inspection of suspicious list
and then in the second phase of the make
we will make inferential data analysis
here we will use predictive data mining to the indicated that needs to be expected
and as a tool ospreys
we plan to develop an expert system
to help the
time consuming
inspection process
now i would like to call it is
for this
the first phase the exploratory data analysis phase is used and is used in the
here what we do is the customer that can't actually be
the consolidated comes
only because of the cost and then we look at the work the customer
so the cost cluster its introspective some behaving variables
and the customers close to the
the centre of the clusters will be regarded as
and not least because
and the one five way from the cluster centers
could be a very good this potential
first suspicious
i don't think so
if you believe that all bad guys behave similarly
then they can be
together in cluster one
i believe
at the end we will see
on the issue of how we can say that the customer showed unusual behaviour
for example is the customer who made fifty
money transfer last month
is unusual
actually it could be or it may be or may not be
for example if it's if is an individual we can suspect
but if you are the only the small business then we may be regarded as
if he's doing this always
it is more probable that it is not
if if you don't do it if it doesn't belong
one to three month and lost most of them
i mean if the transference
then we should also suspect from
the question is if it is normal now depends on the
demographic behavioral segment of discussed image
for example if user blocked and unblocked may have some
common behaviors
so we have to know its history pieces what you have
by looking at this time
the aspects
only after that we can
we can judge if it is a model and not
the first aspect the finding the period of of the clusters is handled automatically by
most clustering of all your sins
but for the second aspect that is to cope with the voting behavior of the
end of the customers
we can create new variables
like we did here
the we calculate the deviation
and then use them in the cluster
by division i mean
the value for the customer value in the last month
minus the evidence
well in in the last six months
so it's different from its past
divided by the standard deviation of the behaviour of the last six months
that if the deviation values
these large either negative or positive
then that means the customer is showing
a different
behaviours from
his routine
for example
what we have used for this page
some very well
for example
we use the
current number of crude transactions
the variable itself
next to
we develop
here come of good contamination deviation
in this case the variable itself and the divisions
for this very well
on both
taught as important and well taken place in the cluster cluster
likewise we have some other means
then the
that we're using k variables
the number of being able to be used in the closing is k
and assume not decided
to have and clusters
then are making plastic materials
the first part of the here
something very simple
we have a well
just after big after all
back to using the the number of the big fj is the high level feature
this is
fj of x y
mine is divided wj
of this
z function
part here
going to be
let's go is going to work out this is going to work out to be
very elegant
but it takes a few lines to to work out what it is
good question so
this is a partial derivative with respect to parameter number j
and this is the sum
he said
all the other one disappear
it's a linear function of w is all the other ones disappear
to get some room
divided wj log p
x y
i i d w j
divide the wj others e
one minus divided wj
log c
so this is one of those e
day by day wj
when we
OK i'm just looking at my own notes and trying to figure out
well that went along
OK so easy is the summation
this is
one of us e
some of
why prime
this is actually a minus here
is that
OK now
the mine is here not here
one of fuzzy
then xe is the summation
and so i'm going to bring the derivative inside the summation
the sum of the y prime
of my
day by
day wj
and then
inside here
we have an exponential
the model
some of the j prime
wj prime
two primary accent my prime
of my
so really the only thing down here to write out what see is
which is the sum of the numerator so here's the numerator
the derivative have an exponential is
the exponential
times iterative what's inside the exponential
so we have
one of us e
some of the the y prime
and then
which is the sum of the j prime wj prime
okay so
for those who know what this means is far from hamill tony and just like an instantaneous time unitary
transformation that has some known easily prepared ground state then you slowly transition it to
a hamiltonian whose ground state encodes the solution to guarantee complete problem and there's a
theorem that says that as long as you vary the hamiltonian slowly enough thee
grounds that be the state of your quantum computer must just get tracked you know
along with the ground state and so then at the end you'll be able to
measure and get the solution to and be complete problem going to be key the
million dollar question here is how slowly slowly enough
i and here the problem is that you know the running time you need to
run this algorithm fore is determined by what's called the inverse igon value gap of
the hamiltonian
okay and what you find when you try running this on you know hard like
three three-set instances for example and people have tried it both numerically ants you've analytically
a very know that the last decade okay find that of any other igon value
gap just one little point it becomes exponentially small so it looks like the two
i can values are crossing each other you know they not quite okay but you
know because you know because about one little place where these i can values almost
kiss that's why you have to run the algorithm for exponential time
okay so far he told me the story that he once asked an expert in
condensed matter physics but based on your experience you know over decades those sort of
similar physical systems do you think that this i can value gap is going to
decrease polynomially are exponentially has the size of the system increases and the experts said
well i think it will decrease exponentially and far he said well why what makes
you say that any experts said well because otherwise the algorithm would work
so you know if you believe strongly enough people
the problems are hard you can reason backwards from there
but right
so what we know today is that on some fitness landscapes these diabetic algorithm can
reach a global minimum exponentially faster than classical simulated annealing but on other types of
fitness landscapes it us about the same or even worse to know what sort of
behavior predominates in practice would help a lot have a quantum computer test it our
but now some of you might be saying that is under this company that's you
know already you know claims that already built quantum computers that can you know ronnie
quantum adiabatic algorithm one day there's you know it's called d-wade systems you know and
they they have these devices right and you know here's the situation
we know that there are devices assertive can solve optimization problems on up to about
one hundred bits you in fact sell them reasonably well you know fairly quickly we
also know that we use the one qubit level there is some kind of quantum
coherence intuitive devices what we don't know at this point is whether the quantum coherence
is playing any kind of causal role in speeding up the computation in other words
it remains consistent with what we know today
that's what do wave has done is basically to build like a very fast special-purpose
classical computer for simulated annealing okay now there's a group of your essay which is
currently running tests with this machine and hopefully will know a lot more
in the near future about you know about
it's characterization that but for now i'd say it remains you know so to speak a black box
sorry sorry as an aside
you know you may wander can on
you know is actually true that you know as all the popular articles
the in qubits can encode to do the empower classical bits well you know that's
the number of bits that you would need to describe the state event qubits but
you know the number of bits that you can actually read out by measuring the
qubits may be much much smaller than okay in in fact you know i was
able to use the machine learning type of ideas to show
that in certain you know
operational sense is a quantum state event qubits behaves effectively like it has only a
polynomial number that's rather than an exponential number
so here's one theorem that
that approved
the given any and qubit states i suppose that you only care about size behavior
on two outcome measurements in some finite set cave then there exists a subset of
those measurements caught a very small size only analog measurements such that is a few
training process research started with the maximally ignorant guesses about what's i was a new
posts selected on your state giving you the right answers on all the measurements in
the city you want all analog and have them then you would end up with
the state there approximately simulates the behavior of fly your desired state on all
the measurements in or in the entire set
okay so what you know andy the idea of the proof is the use darwinian
sort of training process similar to boosting she repeatedly find measurements were carried guess is
still badly wrong even conditioned on being right on all the previous guess is okay
and then you know if you condition on being right on the new example then
review much you must learn something right and if there's no you know example we're
badly wrong then you're done right and then you and then you prove a bound
by using the linearity of quantum mechanics on the number of you know training steps
you have to go through before you know you must have a state that you
know that works for everything
okay i know well what this means is that we can describe the behavior of
an and qubit states i you know on well enough to survive reproduce you know
that the probability that you're gonna get a yes you know under to the end
different measurements and we can do that you know using just a summary with only
and squared log in classical bits it's a polynomial number of classical bits case only
at this sort of question you know quantum states if you to shrink down the
size in some way
on you know no later approved another theorem which he knows even more directly from
the machine learning flavor it is given in cubits states i suppose you only care
about its behavior on two outcome measurements that are drawn from some probability distribution did
and then you can do
draw some sample measurements and one-upped
you know independently from day and the number of measurements only has the bi-linear not
exponentially with the number of qubits over sample measurements then find any hypothesis states that
approximately agrees with site your target state on all of those sample measurements can then
one can prove that with high probability over the choice of sample measurements their feet
must also approximately simulate the behavior of site almost measurements drawn from the entire distribution
okay and the proof idea is to use the notion of fat shattering dimension from
there is some common caching strategies talk about that
you would want to do and adaptive algorithm why because
the applications are
the the the
the optimal caching strategies application as well as time dependent
choosing one is suboptimal
is it the screen where may be straight or window of three hundred
OK the best strategy varies with time
twenty one of these good as the best but also shift somehow
and here needed data
mister rates got worse
so what's it good compare everybody would say oh my arguments online that
so one of the main thing in this research and practice situation is to come
up with the stringent compared
very simple compared to is best fixed
OK here twelve policies
in hindsight you look at the whole data compute the mystery of the
apologies to all policies and pick the best one
dublin of core course should be as good as the best
fixed chosen in hindsight
this is trivial to achieve actually in the state because it is highly variable
he is best three things
is the minimum number of missus
with the most are factors
what is the reason for
some users who are not you decide to get back
so we fetch
OK and
is the minimum number of missus with most are factors
when you have a sequence of switching policies no metadata switching over time
so you might be in the situation where this policy is best then this policy
is best then from trials
fifty to seventy and size is best from seventy two one twenty
GDS is best and then is best for the segment
you want to be as good as the best switching policy but
what happens here
well when you want to switch
from this capture this cash you need to be
why because this guy has different things kept different things and this guy did
there's a reef edge cost how many files so how much how much you have
to refresh
the cost the mister miss rate of these combined policies miss rate some or all
of these segments plus the total
among the three factors so we this becomes the point in now blocked
tony revenge
total mess
so interest each of these composite strategy gives alpha point
and we interested in the lower envelope of this
which means for given me we will look for the
for given number three is we look for the best paul pascal combined
that means in terms of miss rate
so i'm going to go this goal of this game
i'm not interested in comparing just against the best fixed policy and the interesting
compare against the best competition policy
we should use
politician over time this time
each time i shift from one policy to the next time you refresh
this guy has to discard it so it's five one three five
and this is the highest firewall this one had find five one but not the
five minutes ago and you have to get three five
to remove edges
have after some of the factors that drove point for the total this is my
sort of like cost the number of features
total number of missus
for a given set b is i want to get the point is the lowest
because they want to minimize missus
so i'm interested in
the lower in the question
you have to understand this
so a lot work on this was designing online comparison
and in the definition of the input about of serving a process so just serving
the let's say the y variable the output variable
so in that case i even in a situation which is even more so
with respect to the situation of the input of modelling which is still in that
case i have an input and they can model some colours i two relationship in
some way in this potential functions
so is the
it is very important to take into account the in that cases
what is it because i've shown that we want to derive a statistical model
of the of the data
which the the data
structure of this place as a function of
they are past venues
in the classical theory which is the case with this problem usually refers to
what are known as ottoman more is the first oo
we will see briefly what these modelling are because they have to arrive at the
end of the lesson with the
delete according to the embedding algorithm that is reported in the book
one thing which is that you can assume that when we just observe one thing
series all of which
i have also just the output variable
is that the the it is shown that the time series
is stationary which is the following that the statistical property of the process which generates
the data do not change over time
so if you start time series the nose
statistical book time series you start defining two different kind of the mothers of the
time series before the first one is the so-called out aggressive more the which is
also used in the engineering tradition
because is something which seems somewhat similar to the a difference equations someone here is
just reported the simplest out aggressive models in which we have some data which are
sampled over time
these data are all fully evenly spaced and this more than just says that the
the next value of the time series is a linear function
all of the current value of the time series asserting noise
what is interesting if you want to make it parallelism with the dynamic modelling that
we have used until now
is that if you if you think of the noise which is easier it is
to use which affects the next value
as an input
you can see the here
we have the dynamical system
because we have the this relation is
difference equations so
this the relation of the next value is a function of the current one which
is driven by the noise
so the noise
is this sort of unknown input
it makes the dynamics the system change over time so is
very interesting to
see not only the noise is the some
sort of disturbance but let's say
but this is the sort of inputs which makes it the time series behaving that
way in some way so it can understand another way to see this problem is
of course to estimate the a one but it can also be used to estimate
what is the what are the inputs which are
the drivers of the dynamics so what your goal can be effectively to estimated is
there these noise that k by k
that is what exactly you are doing it
in other more than which is
related it's possible to show using popular during
theorem which is related with a data model is the so-called moving average model
in this case the effect of this driver which is the noise these since some
way integrated over time
so the next value of the r
barely all the time series is the function
all of the past noise values not only of the current web
if you think of this notion of the noise is the driver of the dynamic
you understand that this kind of model because you see
you say you are saying here that your comment output that is the function of
the past story of the inputs of the system
seeing the noise is an is an unknown output of the dynamic systems
that we have
again if you take a look at the literature
you find the high number
of combinations of the
being are made in in image
mothers in which two
at the end of the story you arrive these are my modelling which is the
following way
a new flow together
we did
the output we have also some deterministic input so something which is known to serve
as the input of the system we can write to them
even more general model of the input output system
of the time series which is just the composition
of to aggressive there it remains of related to the moving average part and that
the which is on the contrary related to the extent that puts which are even
which have no so these these are known and these are known say
mister k
looking them in the dynamics is the function
this is just the two
so what about reinforcement learning
is a little bit of back material available here if you shouldn't ignore get
OK so i guess the first question is what is reinforced
and reinforcement learning is probably the most general
former learning problem and we try to solve
so yesterday talked about
classification and in various forms supervised learning
there's also something on a semi supervised learning work people have in addition
a bunch of unlabelled data that try to learn from
and then
this is the simplest form of reinforcement learning which
to reinforcement learning in markov decision process
and then there's the general form of reinforcement learning which contains everything
it is
the question is or why is it important to study reinforcement learning
if you facing learning problem in the real world
you can ask questions is this reinforcement learning problem
and it turns out the answer is always yes
so in essence what does it mean that interesting but the point here is that
if we have any kind of theory for reinforcement learning then it can apply very
generally all kinds of problems
now it's not the kind of things we can prove for reinforcement learning
are not as strong as you might hope because
in reinforcement learning is incredibly general
nevertheless you can prove some things
these things can
help you
understand how to get solutions to individual problems
when face some problem in the real world
you start out as stubs reinforce morning you know the answer is yes
need to ask yourself is this something which is simpler than the full reinforcement learning
so the goal typically
interested airing down what problem you have is
you start out with general reinforcement learning in
then you discover that you know maybe
this is some sort of simple problem
there are other problems as well which are here
and then what you discover exactly how simple you can make the problem
then you can try to attack it
by the way
questions are good so should feel free to ask questions today
i s
yeah it is actually pretty interesting
versions of learning so in bandits
what happens is
you have it's like you go to the casino
and you have a bunch of machines you can put money into any component or
in some of the arms payoff more than other times
but you don't know which pays that the most intense
so the goal in and then learning is to try to
do as well as the best individual are by exploring and some according to some
active learning
is a different setting
so in general reinforcement learning what happens is
you can interact with the environment
and the process of interaction with environment changes
what's going to in the future
in active learning that's not true
but you are actively interacting with the environment so that he is you want classification
so you start requesting
labels for individual examples
and then
at some point you get some labels introduce classifier
so active learning is sort of the interactive version
just classification learning or just supervised learning
this is one of the very basic things it seems that
interaction the ability to interact with the world
is radically more powerful than
just the ability to do
batch learning as we talked about yesterday
so what i mean there have been more probable what i mean is the number
of labelled you may need to request
can the logarithmic in the number that are required to learn
if you just
using batch
learning we talked about yesterday
so always logarithmic example where might be logarithmic is
suppose you
you just trying to
learn to predict
a threshold online right
so the and of there's no no is going be very easy to
the first query in the middle to see if
it's a threshold above and below
the query point
and that partitions the set and then you can just because of the query
just narrowing in very quickly on where the threshold this
we have some kind of a
the loop feedback loop here going on
and this is why i wanted to be a little bit of time explaining how
we can use the challenges as as a teaching tool so this reaches a little
bit also the theme of the second speaker because
in the class i taught last year
on feature selection i used the
feature selection challenge
and as the motivation for the students to r
to do some projects and task was to
match outperform the results of the best challengers in the NIPS two-thousand three challenge
so again you know this is the
for the book which there is that the data sets are and also a lot
of teaching materials so this is i guess you know my attempt to create curriculum
this is the curriculum consists of a
the city was the head of the challenge chapters contributed by by people
ten chapters that are tutorials and which show followed essentially in in my class and
then there are chapters that research papers written about the results of the challenge on
the data
it same class people had to
these different aspects the two illustrated so they they had to produce results on all
five data sets of the challenge
and the data sets to include just one by one in the in the curriculum
in the class
associated with a particular difficulty in feature selection
and there were classes that were
link to dr
the tutorial chapters so they were then
a simple courses that i would give their classes which were linked to readings so
this is a more like some the students had to read the chapter then it
was all researched up upturn in that case and each student to complete the class
had to choose one of the research chapters and presented
so this was one of the requirements for the class the second was to produce
results on all five datasets
and the sole requirement was that they would make a poster and then we had
the poster session
in end they would present the poster about the results that they had on the
five datasets
in addition to that because i had no assistant this class was a class i
taught in switzerland tth and i was just guest professor to give me your system
so for the class sometimes discussed how to
produce results on the dataset but sometimes they use datasets close to familiarize the students
with the hull you become a consultant in machine learning because this is my job
and i thought
this would be a little bit different view for the students will always start by
academic people
i came there and can from the practical world and then delivering to them in
a class on machine learning i told them right away well by the end of
the this class i hope that you know you can do consultant like me and
go unsolved problems in the outside world
so i told them also about how to write the proposal to get get contract
how to file for patents
to protect your intellectual property
other you know practical aspects of the of the work that they didn't
so this completes the biggest the curriculum and and i wanted to give you a
little glimpse of the dataset
that that that we used
there is a story about the massacre which is the computationally efficient way
represent functions in very high dimensional spaces
the to some extent
in the your minds just for you
up to this point
we have discussed
the classic or did that he
and the deep inference
and the classical pattern recognition problem
but all the questions we can ask we have asked
find the function
going to be the classification
if you in in real life you don't care so much about the function because
not going to classify everything
but there are many cases in which you can ask questions from all points
and the
one of these cases with called transduction
traditionally at least in the western world
when you make
you have two steps you start from that
and you have an induction step what you find the general rule
and when you have the general the theory
you apply that
applied to that
and then you make your decision to take an action
but why should we go through that
intermediate function
which is something that is
difficult to of ten one maybe sometimes you can go straight from the
let's set the poem formally
so you have training data
but then classes
the pattern recognition the class of plus and minus one
and you've given in advance
the test
so what happens
so you know
what questions you're going to ask what answer you want
so now among the admissible set the classification vehicles
so basically possibilities of answers your going to give you all the best this but
then this but
if you would like to find the best one
if you if you think about it that to think about important here
the first one is that you assume that when you're given the training data
you have a very precise idea about what questions to be asked
so that was the case but in many significant case
this is true
and the second one is that
well this is all the discrete
now we have is the longer one in three dimensional space or a continuous space
all in and this is the problem that purely combinatorial
you have
the set lasted for possible answers you could give
and because you have a limited number of there's the the set of possible and
is limited
and try to find the best one
so now becoming combinatorial
and in fact if you look at the prose
of the VC theory and this is the first part the called the proof is
purely combinatorial discussing properties here that are just as
as essential for something like the law of large numbers
so the first and the important concepts in the context so the first important concept
is the concept of equivalence classes
so here the red points
the red circle and the black lexical
there are two classes examples of the class
and the triangle
of those that have the ones we would like to classify
now if you consider all hyperplanes
you don't say that
some plants like all these here
i going to classify
all these formed the same way
so for whatever
for the purpose of this financial problems the equivalent
so for this hyperplanes here between these are going to
with this two one thread all these red and or this one black
and we're gonna see whether you think this one or this one or anyone there
they're going to produce the same output
so somehow the size of this equivalence classes
which is you see in particular is related the margin of the more margin there
are between the point the more you will be able to fit hyperplanes
the size of the equivalent class
is a critical factor
in the kind of generalization ability we going to happen
so let me often gives this example which is from the KDD cup and the
problem was to
you had the
part and binary patterns dimension one hundred forty thousand
with the training set of only two two thousand example
but this set has only one of few examples
during that competition
there was the distribution of of was about these and the we was about
but think sixty nine something like this
if few
maybe one or two years later jason weston
right so as we end with four smart encoding so
it's not is of the pure result at this point and gotten much nicer result
was seventy five percent correct
by using exactly the same thing
but being in front the the model that is
making your system
that would not only
use the training but in the training level but also the test but down but
of course not this label
he was able to go to eighty two percent and that is very significant
so that was the funds of the
fans of the four
to follow that object
i should say by the way the people who do computer vision have a variety
of motivations for this there are those who see it as as
looking at the mystery of how is it the human c i then we have
this wonderful living existence proof of humans walking around the world making a great deal
of this is your data and so on
we can be completely confident that is possible vision is possible we're all the living
proof of this but how can it be done and some people want to answer
this in a very biological kind of way and look for mechanisms in the brain
that could map on two
is your processes and then there are psychologists call themselves like physicists to take the
brain is a black box and use psychological experiments to see
how you respond to particular
patterns may be the most famous
those are better utilisation his random dot stereograms which are the precursor of those auto
stereo grand christmas cards were very popular ten years ago when you have this sort
of with the cardinals something emerges and that you cross your eyes a distinctly uncomfortable
and then the other end of the spectrum there are people who want to make
things make inventions that
use the kind of imitating in in a loose way human vision but you know
would be wonderful if we could make certain machines that react to visual input in
the same way and as i think you were saying cameras at two dollars are
thrown out so i it's used to be the case that you have to apologize
for making machines which had cameras in people would say well you know why don't
use an accelerometer what user touch sensor you know other senses the perceived as being
cheap and that's no longer the case the camera is now pretty much as cheap
as any other senses so we anything we can do with vision
i think the problem of yes the telling when people falling asleep in their cars
was mentioned well that's no longer
something that you can only think of as exotic that i'm interested in a number
of different kinds of inventions and applications
here's one idea which a colleague of mine in microsoft in redmond was looking at
the idea that
using the camera on your mobile phone actually have to be pointing the other way
this camera for this particular idea to work usually point backwards needed to point forward
could you have a program in the mobile phone that looked at you speaking and
was able to pick up enough of the variation of your expressions and so on
to transmit two
the other end of the conversation
very dense code about the
the relate your expression so that at the far end you could animate some
cartoon or it could be a replica of yourself
this is the sort of thing i mean the lady on the left is real
by the way and
her emotions are being picked up using computer vision
and so on ad hoc methods in computer vision that have specific feature detectors from
mouth and eyebrows and so on because we'd like to be able to do these
things in in a systematic way
it's quite cute isn't talking to the cartoon on the right is actually in many
ways far more acceptable to do this than to talk to
a realistic replicas so there's been a lot of progress actually on
face painting by numbers in about two hundred number seems to be what what you
need to code up a realistic face so you could actually take
take the numbers
calculated from the moving picture on the left and send two hundred and numbers per
video frame down the wire use them to reanimate sort of photo realistic
face but we're very sensitive to very to slight artifacts in reconstructions and even though
they are very good now i have the feeling that possibly people might find it
more acceptable to be looking at something like this where there is no pretense that
favour realism and yet there's a lot of emotional content
another idea that's been around for awhile popularized by xerox
is the idea that you could have
result is always the same statement that is if the restricted isometry property holds which
i even need in the noiseless case what if it holds then surprisingly
this is the solution to this
the linear programs
it is easy to solve on the computer
it is very accurate and how accurate this is what the cheese
the are called bound is it achieves its adaptive this errors it's mean squared error
is proportional to the number of coefficients there is times the knowledge level
a factor which is proportional to the
logarithmic of the total number of dimensions you have to pay
and so when you solve this kind of
this kind of data fitting problem by this
the dynamics selection you have i mean squared error the index indicates the stochastic noise
exactly proportional
so is it true unknown number of parameters achieve what we call statistics that activity
is when the object gets simpers i mean squared error decreases
and then in the constant you pay log factors that you have to pay
no matter what
and that's the price you need to pay for not knowing
that's the price you pay compared to zero articles at the price you pay for
not knowing ahead of time or causes significant cult i have to search for them
and you have to pay a price for it
and that's log p
this is to ask you can show that no estimator whatsoever
can actually do better than p times in six months so you really at the
limit of what you can do
OK alright so in fact you can you get really small error is as good
as if
you know ahead of time which components are big and which components are small
and that means that the
you can really around these things in practice
now there are all kinds of articles that you are more sophisticated than one i've
presented that goes back to the whole literature model selection statistics where you can actually
much more precise or calls
but since i'm running out of time i'll skip this
but you can only get what you would get by meaning by
which coordinators you're which are not but you could actually by having even more so
powerful are called to tell you in the case according to is not deal
it was a towards estimating unknown
and you could mimic there
performances are calls as well you can get very sharp bounds which are
OK so there is no
a lot of theory and statistics about an one minimisation these days so for example
i've shown you results for the lasso but these results inspired statistician to actually pull
similar results i should be reserved for the dantzig selector but is inspired statisticians to
prove similar result for the lasso
and that this was achieved by peter be calling his colleagues by tom gen
shortly after
and then in the statistical world it seemed that
you know l one minimisation in connection with model selection
it is getting a lot of attention it's very active community of britain researchers managed
to get new and exciting results on almost on a weekly basis at the moment
OK so there's a lot of and perhaps could shinseki talked about some of these
last week
OK so it's connected with model selection and so on and so on so in
practice the dantzig selector works
really well so
if i have
of size speed close to fifty six seventy two measurements gas in matrix noise level
sigma which is point eleven i choose the threshold to be about three point five
so that
so a transpose or is lesson points thirty nine
when i look at the
the selection offered by the dantzig selector in blue you have the original factory red
you have the reconstruction
and you see two things first of all each time the signal is not always
the dantzig selector is actually correctly identifying the not zero
and whenever he was dantzig selector correctly identifies its
but what you can see also is that there is a little bit of
of the bias that is dantzig selector since two
bring observations back towards the there's shrinkage effect which is due to his l one
norm so it's a bit like a soft thresholding type estimates
in fact if a is orthogonal was then it is exactly soft thresholding
and so there's something so there's a little bias
that it is introduced by you want to shrink down the amplitude somehow
and so there's a little bias that you can correct by
having this two stage procedure where you rendered the danzig selection to find out those
components in the genome say that have
the predicted response predicted value which is not the and then you get your sparse
subset the new performance queries on
so when you do this
you see that you receptors your observation you can eliminate this bias now
so you have a two stage procedure where you find the location that are not
zero by znd selection and then you performance was
and that would remove the
OK so in practice it works extremely well in fact if we were to compare