i think an interesting future work is to try to combine these two methods for
using state splitting approaches for the tag based grammar
OK so
now that's an instrument i want to talk a bit about machine translation
as well application of these kind of models and the interesting thing here is that
some of the techniques of showing in parsing not being carried across two
machine learning machine translation
so in statistical approaches to translation again we think this is the structured prediction problem
mapping strings and say german strings in english
and we have a potentially very large set of example translations to we might have
a few hundred thousand examples of translations between the two languages
now you can think of two possible approaches roughly speaking one approach pretraining this mapping
you don't make so much use of latent structure
a second possible approaches where you might use the syntactic structures
maybe this grammatical relations
as the number of intermediate structure in form of this mapping
so let's talk about these two approaches
so the first is free space translation
so this was a major breakthrough in statistical machine translation is really impressive will be
i have worked
in phrase based models
the basic
the components of the basic entries in the model
is a lexico
of the so-called phrase pairs
each entry in this lexicon
looks like a german substring
for example and then again
with an english substring over here
and we might potentially induce very large lexicon of entries in this form for a
set of example translations
now given this lexicon transition proceeds in the following two steps
so firstly we segment the german string
two series of german segments
and for each of those segments we choose an english translation
so essentially the step you
we have a bunch of we segmentation
and now we have a bunch of english fragments down here translations were drawn from
this lexicon
in the second step
we choose some
the resulting english forces
so we might move things around a little bit
so in particular
the subject here elections
this come after the verb take
in german german has quite flexible word order so you often see this kind of
what the subject was asked to appear
for the first in english
so we sort of scrambled these phrases arrange them to produce this new translation
these two steps the choice of the phrases in the two the ordering of course
probabilities or associated costs
which is somehow estimated from from corpus in particular in the real world instead
you make heavy use of the language model
the strings in the language for example the tri grams language model
so these government in transition
but they really don't make any direct use of syntactic information
you might think for example that knowing
the different arguments arguments with the different grammatical relations are on the german side might
be useful in predicting the structure of english tree
so recent work for example i assign the two examples of shown you share
has started to fray the transition process essentially as opposing task
so it would very interesting take i think on translation and shown they were quite
impressive results
particularly in chinese which is the language which has very different from english
in this idea
the phrase is augmented to carry with them
pieces of syntactic structure
so now for his entry in our model
my ten this german strength
with an english crane which has appeared tree fragment of it
so maybe past the english corpus
and annotated or in the strings with these past tree fragment
and say, you figure it out, try and maximize this
and that's a much better way to do abstraction
so if i believe there should be a vertical edge i can say
get rid of all the,
you know, that modulates the correlational structure, but you figure out what the intensity should be
so i don't have to know what the vertical edge means in terms of intensities
i know what it means in terms of correlational structure
and that means i can leave the fine details to the guys at the level
who of course in turn off-load to the guys in the layer below that
that's clearly very good as a management structure
where my new graduate students that come in
i just explain the objective function, which is the number of papers in my
and leave them to just optimise the details
i'm gonna finish by
showing you how to apply all this to time series models
and we have applied this three-way factored stuff, and it's published in the latest ICML
conference two thousand nine
graham taylor and me
but i'm gonna describe stuff slightly before that
it's obvious how to generalize it to three way
normally when people have to deal with time series
they would like to use non linear distributed representations because they're nice and powerful
but they're hard to learn
so they tend to avoid distributed representations and use things like
hidden markov models or avoid nonlinear and use things like linear dynamical systems
we'd like to have our cake and eat it
and if we really do want to use these distributed representations
to make it feasible we want to make inference much simpler in these models
there's a couple of tricks for doing that. the main trick is to say
instead of having a directed model, we'll have an undirected model
in other words, we'll have hidden units and visible units that are a little restricted boltzmann machine
so i have an undirected model
but now we're gonna condition that model
on previous frames of data
and that's gonna give us a temporal model we can learn and then we can
stack up in multiple layers
so let me show you the application domain first, and then i'll show you what the models look like
you put markers all over somebody and lots, have lots of infrared cameras
and then you can see where the joints are in 3-D
and then you can convert that into joint angles
and then you can represent their motion by frames of data in which each frame
has like thirty five joint angles
six more numbers that say the translation and rotation of the base of the spine
actually for the rotation
for rotation this way,
you give the
change in angle
at each time step
but for a rotation this way
and this way you give the absolute angle because physics cares a lot about you being like
that if you're walking, or being like this
so for roll and pitch we give the absolute angle, and for yaw we give the
delta angle
and we do it all in body centered coordinates
that all turned out to be important
so the basic conditional RBM looks like this
here's your RBM
here's your joint angles and your translations and rotations of the base of the spine
here's some binary hidden units
these are gaussian variables
here's previous timeframes
here's some conditioning connections here
some conditioning connections here
so the effect of those conditioning connections is just to change the effective biases
of these units and these units
so as far as the RBM is concerned, is an RBM whose biases keep being changed by the history
if you ignore this stuff, this is an autoregressive model, it's a standard autoregressive model,
right? you have linear stuff that's linearly dependent on the past
now autoregressive models are pretty good at dealing with continuity
but they're not good at sustained generation
their biggest eigenvalue's either bigger than one or smaller than one
so either they'll blow up or they'll collapse
if you make the biggest eigenvalue a little smaller than one and drive them noise, they can keep going, but
they won't produce models nearly as good as the ones i'm going to show you
OK so we know how to learn this
we now know how to learn these connections
you put in data
you then activate hidden units
you then reconstruct the data but taking these conditioning connections into account
and then you reconstruct,
reactivate the hidden units
and you use the difference in the pairwise statistics to learn those
you learn the difference between the activity levels of the hidden units with data and with
reconstructions of data, take that difference, and back propagate it to learn these weights
in other words, that difference times these activities
learns those weights
and similarly the difference between these states with the data from these states in the
this activity here, learns this weight
so we can learn all these weights and these weights and these weights
we can generate from the model
like this
given two previous frames
that determines the biases here
via these connections
and now we can go backwards and forwards for a while
and generate a new frame
and we don't have to go back and forth very long because
with these biases strongly determined by the past there's not much this can do.
it typically has to be very similar to this last frame
most importantly we can stack them up
i can learn this model
with no connections here. these connections aren't here yet
once learn this model
i can now take time frames
of observed data
and convert them into time frames of hidden units
but without these connections here
so now i've got a hidden sequence
and now i can say, well that hidden sequence,
let me go back
these weights
a prior distribution over these hidden units
given these conditioning connections
and they also define the conditional distribution for v given h
or the two PY type of orbitals that were combining so this the same shape
as the shape of the orbit or the shape of the wave function
and we can call this either two p a being compiled with two px b
or we can say since the same shape it's two PY being combined with two
and in either case if we first talk about constructive interference what again we're going
to see is that where these two orbitals come together we're going to see increased
wave function in that area so we saw constructive interference
so again we can name the molecular orbitals and these were going to call also
to point out there is now a bond axis along this nodal plane which is
something we didn't see before were combined as orbital
so we go ahead and name is we're going to call these pi orbitals
well call it either pi two px if we're combined at orbitals four pi two
the reason that i wanted to point out the nodal plane here because this is
why it is called a pi orbitals pi orbitals molecular orbital that have a nodal
plane through the bond axis remember this is our bond axis here you can see
there is this area where the weight function is equal to zero all along that
plane that the normal plain so that's why these are pi orbitals instead of sigma
so again we can think about the probability density
in terms of squaring the function so now what it is that we're squaring is
that we're talking about the px orbital pi two px square
and this is just equal to
that two p
x a plus the two pxb all square or free read write out all of
the terms
we have two px a squared plus two pxb square and then this term here
and again this is our interference term in this case the constructive or destructive interference
constructive interference we're seeing that the wave function adding together and giving us more weight
function in the centre here
all right so we see constructive interference of course we can also see destructive interference
so i changed the colors here to show that these are two p orbitals with
an opposite
or opposite signs so what happens when we add a two p a and we
subtract from it
two pxb were the same with the two PY eight subtracting two PYP that we're
actually going to cancel out the weight function in the centre so we now have
two nodal planes so again this is an insight bonding orbital and what you see
is that there is now less
electron density between the new to the two nuclei
then there was when you had a non-binding
so we're going to call this the sigma two px star
or talking about the two PY orbitals will call this
the excuse me the pi two px star and the pi two PY star
and the pi star orbitals result from any time you have destructive interference from two
p orbitals that are either the p acts or the PY
so now we can move on to an example where we do in fact have
to use some p orbitals so this would be be two
how many electrons are in boron
i the same hand going up there's five electrons so what you'll notice here that
i only in three electrons with what do these electrons represents
valence electrons OK so sometimes you're going to be asked to draw a molecular orbital
diagram where you asked to include all electrons and sometimes will specifically say
only include valence electrons that happens because of space issues that you have to do
that because you can always assume that all of the core
orbitals are already going to be filled so in this case we're just trying to
molecular orbital diagram for the valence electrons so we have three for each and what
we see here is now more combine the p we have our two px two
py y py orbitals that are lower in energy
and then our pi bonding orbitals that are higher in energy
you might be asking where the two pz orbital and then we'll get to that
soon once we need let's just first villainous for the b two k
so we can start at the bottom two electrons in sigma two as
two electrons and two sigma two as star
now we need to jump up to using these pi orbitals and what we're going
to do is put one electron into each of our pi
two px and two py y orbitals
so again you can see as we're filling up molecular orbitals we're using the exact
same principle we used to fill up atomic orbitals
so let's think about what the valence electron configuration is here
so now we're looking at the case of
p two
and what we're looking at is a valence electron molecular orbital diagram so let's just
rather electron configuration for the valence orbitals so that will be thinking about two hours
that is each survey of x is equal to h survey
of y
what it means
for them to clive
so that implies
that the sum
i equals zero to are
a supply
x y
is equal to the sum
of i equals zero to are
of the supply
why so i
actually this is congruent
nine and so congruence those people have seen much number theory
is basically the way
of essentially rather than having to say
mod everywhere in here and mod everywhere in here
we just at the end say OK two and model
you know PN everything is being done model
o module m
and then
typically we use congruent sign
it is more mathematical definition
but this will work for her as engineers
everybody with me so far just applying the definition
that implies
that the sum of i corps zero to are
they are i
x y minus y i
congress zero money
data stored on the other side and
apply the distributive law
now what i'm going to do is pull out
the zero position because that's the one that i care about
this is where it saves me on the map
comparative i didn't
say there was zero
i have to pull out i wouldn't matter but it just would make the map
a little bit
OK so now we just pulled out one term
that implies
a zero
zero minus y zero
congruent to minus
remember that when i minus number mod m
i just map it into whatever into that range from zero to in minus one
so for example
you know minus five mod seven is
OK so
if any of these things are negative
we simply
translate them into by adding multiples of them because adding multiples of them
doesn't affect
and now
the next step we need to use in number theory fact so let's
the latter number theory
take a little digression
OK right so this comes from the theory of finite fields
so for people who were
that's where your plugging your knowledge in
if you're not knowledgable is a great area math learn about
so here's the
the fact
so let m be prime
then for any
xe element of
xe seven an c them is the integers
o mod m
OK so this is essentially numbers from zero
r two n minus one
with all the operations you know times
minus lost its error
OK defined on that such that if you're and the outside the range of zero
ten minus one the renormalized by subtracting or adding multiples of them to get back
within the range from syria minus one
the standard thing and just doing things modulo n
so for any easy such that c
OK is
not congruent to zero
there exists a unique
xe inverse
and since the them
such that if i multiplies the times the
produces something congruent to one mod m
so for any number it says
i find another number
one multiplied by it
it's me
so let's just do an example
for an equal seven
so here we have michael table
so is is not equal to zero so i'd just write down the other numbers
let's figure out what the inverses
OK so what's the inverse of one
but number one multiplied by one gives me one
how about two
number one i multiply by two gives me one
OK because
two times for his age
in eight is congruent to one
mod seven
OK renormalized
what about three
five good five three ten five fifteen
that's congruent to one mod seven because fifteen
divided by
seven is two remainder want
so that's the thing or about four
and six
sixty six
six times six is thirty six
OK mod seven
basically cracked up thirty five
his me one
so you people observe some interesting facts that
the if
if r one numbers and inverse of another
then that other is inverse of the one
that's actually
one of these things improve when you do
like this
there's a book
because i think it's called the world according to wavelets
friend barbara per hour
so the world
a world that according to
she is a hyphenated last name or
one hundred
and published by
a local company
he became few
OK here's side
very nice
people and this book one prices for
so popular exposition so it's quite fun to give the story more than i could
do it
a short time
now we jump to
what we was
four on
scaling its box
well actually
yes it we know this way quite
is the box
now i'm going to take
i mean hard
context set two coefficients
plus and minus
the low and high pass filter right plus and minus
the a combination of boxes and we get this
candidates from zero to one
it's a box after box meinshausen
that are weight
so you see
there you know
where the scaling functions
making up averages
this is key e
for this lecture
the key example
and in
several ways to be jump into
the way is
the spaces w what i call them
the lecture outline called w
one is w
fair enough it's all combinations
so this what remember the day
it was all combinations
the kinds of functions that
at scale
this is the same
that scale
so that we use
and this is
now let me
with this example
put box function in here too
next to it so this is the key
this w
also from zero one
and here's the first one and
the equation
thirty four
you wanted to check from i
all the functions in the zero
at all the functions
two any function w zero one like it
the answer is going to be
p one
functions these are piecewise constant
on intervals
these are all you know the rules
so let's just wrong
so for example
got out
what's what's w zero
state between zero and two
i was in w zero
multiple nominations for this guy on this
so there's a typical
ten i'm just trying one typical
i can be zero
to o thing w zero
the combination of
and it she
with certain rights rights to two-thirds ideas one point six one
combine those
put i was signed yellow here
i wonder what kind of functions like
kind of function that's
because this is piecewise constant union general
automatically on fills
this is certainly piecewise constant also the
results in v one
but now the point is
i think everything you want
from these two
everything one can be split
see here's the decomposition here's the wavelet decomposition
you know what fourier decomposition is useful
wavelet decomposition is used but the thing
multiple scales
believe that i could take any function he won why don't have any function i
don't have all the one right here
the only finds and got some functions in the one here but they're all plus-minus
plus-minus plus-minus
what process
but if i
next the two
all i'm saying is that
one by combining one one
with one minus one
with the right weights
any the a b
that's the on
if i'm sure if something goes up
goes to p
it's a a
not find one might find this guy
but some coefficients of this
what produces
and then you have to learn the
parameters from this training examples that you have available
but again if you don't have the labels that's even
more time to test
and in all parameter techniques
as you know you don't assume any
knowledge of parameters
so use and then use this parameter techniques to estimate the density of the distribution
and some of the well known technically the histograms parzen
in destinations
can be used to estimate
OK i just presented to you
approaches that belong to statistical based techniques
one of them is smartsifter
they can diminish
so this is proposed for the mixture of continuous
and discrete attributes
in this case histograms
i used to represent a probability density for categorical attributes
while find it to make sure
i used to represent probability density for continuous attributes so basically what for both these
types of activities you estimating the that's the first
and then for every test instance this smartsifter
estimating the probability
of the test instance to be generated by the learnt statistical models
this is usually defined by p c minus one
for the first time and minus one
then this this this this is added to the sample
and then the model is re re estimated so right now the probability of the
test instance to be generated from the new model is estimated
as BP
and i trying to measure the difference between this model
and anomaly score for this test basically the difference between this one so basically consort
all the new data records according
this difference
in order take the top as
of course
or anomalies
very similar idea is from a scan from from columbia university
so basically your constructing the new distribution you exactly the data distribution from data because
the data can so we have a m majority distribution in this case this correspond
to model behavior
and a is an almost distributions so constructing the new distribution d
which is one minus lambda times lambda a lambda is some users specify parameters
in the first step
you assign all the data across two majority distribution
and then a is initially empty
then for every data records
from basically
first estimate the parameters for and a of course is empty you you need to
estimate anything at the beginning
and then you compute the log likelihood l of distribution d
right now
you removed data record from initial set
and put it back into a
right now you are trying to re estimate these parameters
and your computing log likelihood l prime of the same distribution
and very similar like in the previous approach computing the difference primus out
and if do this is larger than some kind of threshold
then they to recognise correspond to anomaly otherwise
they record is normal and is moved back to m and then you're repeating this
for every
the data from the dataset and of course
this may be time consuming
this may be
the may be problem because
extremely large
if you move on a track that may not leaving if initial basically is sufficient
the difference in the in log likelihood so
this may not work some the some
real life
kind of metal
there are also some other techniques that combine different
approaches from different communities like information theory based
spectral composition people use visualization techniques
the first talk about the information theory based techniques and
the main idea here is that
anomalies are outliers
typically significantly change the information content from the data
and the general approach here is to detect data records
change this kind of the in information and usually require certain information theoretic
and i think
it measures
obvious advantage is that they can operate in an unsupervised
what they do not require any labels
some of the drawbacks included these techniques require
information theoretic measures the sensitive
to detect irregularity induced by very few anomalies
sometimes this may lead to very poor performance
the simplest in the simplest possible way is to try to use the entropy
try to find
OK size
data subset
and we trying to find such subset whose removal musical leads to to the maximal
decrease in entropy of the data sets so
if you remove certain
data subset and this
delete the maximal
maximal decrease that means this points total because they correspond to the next phase can
apply this incremental fashion one by one data record could
or you can do by
regional or actually subset because of the baby subset
when people use different techniques like linear sort of data
to search for this
substance it does the lexical
in entropy
some researchers use other information theoretic measures like conditional entropy
relative conditional entropy information gain
relative entropy like all book library divergence and so on
there are also some special techniques
and this analysis is based on i can the composition of the data so you
are familiar with the concept of i can converted composition and principal component analysis
so the key idea is to find a combination of activities that captures the bulk
affordability so basically trying to become principal component analysis
and this reduced set of attributes
chemical if this is the set of factors can explain the normal data well
but sometimes they cannot represent anomalies also so
advantage that again they can
perform very well in a surprise more but
they are based on the assumption that anomalies basically
these techniques
try to capture the majority of the data so basically they they try to retained
most of the variance
so the assumption that basically
that in this new space you're assuming that anomalies in data records also very well
distinction which may not be the case so that's why these techniques may not be
able to detect some numbers
this approach exactly this idea so basically
if you have two variables
remember that the ideas we sample x one given x two
and then we moved to x two given x one
and then we moved to x one
given x two
and so on that there was big ips
so in other words
given a particular value of x one
you look at the cut
and you sample x two from it
now next
you look at the next cut
bring some other column
we look at the next cut
well you sample
and new sample
then you
sample the new value of x one
and you keep doing this
the problem with doing this this way
is that if you're doing this cuts and if this thing is very big
we can take e for effort
to get to areas of high profile
now if something is very elongated and you're doing this cat if something is found
you just think this little
increases very little steps
so we want ways of doing this more efficient
the first ideas call blocking
the idea of blocking is you group variables
that are correlated and you sample them together
if you can draw come up with an exact sample of a group of variables
that's very useful because instead of
because if you can sample from directly from the group that instead of sample by
doing stupid things
what you do is you just examples from one thousand today
and that gives you good samples much more efficient
here are some examples i could block
but you have a graphical model
happens to have a square lattice a random field
then you can sort of break
the lattice into two groups
now each group then if this is discrete is just an HMM
if the black guys are observed
and the white guys
inferring the white guys from the black eyes
is an hmm computation if an exact computation there's no approximation there
for example the black ice you computer white guys
now to sample the black guys
because they happen to be in the chain
you can do this forward backward algorithm
we had before
so we draw an exact sample from the distribution the forward backward takes into consideration
the correlations
so we deal with the problems of correlation
in practice what you do is you sample this given this an the example this
given this so you only have two samples
they use a lot of analytical computational and to live with this and that makes
it easy
and then you can do this for other types of graphs factor graph based medicines
when you compute estimators of this
you try
again this is
that actually by is not different from this technique of
because of the theorem of brown black it's called rough localisation it's also known as
and it is when you use an estimator of this
instead of using samples he use these analytical expressions for the expectation is the conditional
yeah we haven't seen the emulator then if anyone's going to describe the
but sometimes you can't exactly and you want to call it to the
there's also a parking and an example of the sort of thing
we have two views of the house he one reconstructed three d model
this other ways of doing this with ransack on that actually work
from one
on balance it's no we're not quite sure in this case case you think this
probabilities ought to be quite useful to see
more precisely how these probabilities can help us
the first thing want to be able to use the probabilities in order to make
decisions in the simplest kind of decision is to minimize
the rate at which we misclassified so we've got to some of the population of
people not to make as few errors as possible in a classification
so to simplify this instead of having a whole image vector this just have a
single variable x is the quantity we measure for each individual
and what's plotted here of the
probability distributions for
the two classes so this is for class one which also is the normal class
and this is class two which is the conscious class
and the problem becomes of course because these distributions overlap
so some of the some of the times so we observe a value x here
this overlap region belongs to class one sometimes belong to class two that's why this
is a hard problem
let's suppose that we introduce what's called the decision boundary so will choose the value
of x hat and everything to the left of that x how will classify as
we call the region one that's the region of normality
and everything to the right of x will be region two will be
classified as cancer
so we want to reduce the rate of mistakes the probability of mistakes and mistake
occurs whenever
x really belongs to class two
but it lands in the region classified as class one so some who really has
cancer we classify them as normal all the way around they really normal we classify
them cancer
what is this probability
well it's just the the interval of the density over that region so for for
vectors which really belong to the cancer class which are classified as normal
the the fraction of images which which have that property is is obtained by integrating
the density of the region ones but it's been to over here and so this
is the density the interesting p of x and c two and so it corresponds
this region here so the sum
of the green and the red regions these are
these are
vectors x which really attentions were classified as normal the red the relations and it's
only images which are normally classified as cancerous
that's the tale of this distribution that's the blue region
now we are free to choose the decision boundary anywhere we like so we can
move x had happened and this this set this axis causing we also have multiple
decision regions but i'm just assuming there's just a single decision boundary the two regions
well should we put well we can see pictorially where to put it because if
we slide this up and down
if we move this let's say this region to the left some of the green
area will become blue
OK so it's still misclassified the red area sort of disappears
this region here was sort of stuck with that sort of irreducible minimum rate of
misclassification can get around that we can get rid of the red region and i
think can see pictorially the place to put it out is what i've called it's
that's the place at which the the total area this college is as small as
possible and if we move even further to the left we'll pick up another red
this is the point at which these curves
cross each other
so the decision criterion can be expressed as follows will classify x as
a region one as normal if if this
joint distribution of x and c one is greater price recalled p of x
and c two
and if i divide both sides by p of x that says we assign x
the region of the high posterior probability which is sort of obvious
very happy with that
so he said it's obvious nobody is considered don't understand i hope that's clear me
all right
so so why bother to do this so we first saw computer probability then we
made the decision why go to all this trouble they give you four
advantage is that it brings
it allows us to do something called minimising risk in interfaces some called loss matrix
this is important because the loss matrix itself could change over time you don't want
to re compute probabilities and explain explain all these four detail it
it allows us to do something called reject option allows us to handle unbalanced class
priors that allows us to combine models together let's go through each of those
in turn just have a look
so loss matrix affects the fact that some kind of misclassifications are more serious than
others so let's suppose that this is the true unknown class was a person standing
in front of us that have cancer or they don't we don't know but this
is the true unknown classes the decision we make
now this loss matrix with assumed that if we make a correct decision if classify
cancerous cancelled classifier normal normal there's no cost associated with that
if we take somebody who's normally misclassifying this cancer that means two things that means
first of all the person gets a bit worried because they've been recalled after test
that we pretty stressful unpleasant experience i'm sure
and also we then have to spend money
giving them more tests
so since this tangent space
this linear space
you can think naturally of tangent vectors
and one point i want to make
is that somehow there is
the connection between tangent vectors and curves
so if you think of as curve so what occurred
fear of t is the curvature map from our two mk
OK so that traces out the curve on the manifold
and should take
the derivative of this with respect
you get a vector
and that's essentially
the tangent vector
so every tangent and vector can be identified with the curve
the tangent vectors in tp where p is the point on the manifold so every
tangent vector can be identified with the curve that passes through
oppose derivative
the vector
tangent vectors can also be thought of as derivative in the following way
if you take a function f from mk two are
and you pick up vector
in the tangent space
since we already discussed how
vectors are identified with cool
so the vector v can be identified with the fear of t
from our two mk
and then this object makes sense by composing the two
f of fear of t
and that's just a regular function from r to r
and so have a function
from m two are
you pick up point p
on the manifold
you consider the tangent space at p is p
you pick up vector v in the standards based
that the vector v can be identified with the color
on the manifold
that passes through p
and if you take
of of
just get a regular function
and if you differentiate it
with respect to t
which we know what to do from general calculus
that's the same thing
as basically taking the directional derivative of f
in the direction v
you can think therefore of tangent vectors
as operators that act on functions and take
directional derivatives in certain directions
the tangent vectors and five it curves on the one hand and the directional derivatives
on the other hand in this way
the thing that gives it its riemannian structure
will be
norms and angles in the tangent space
so that you can talk about inner product between any two vectors
v and w
in the tangent space
since everything here is embedded we don't have to consider it abstractly right now they
can do this abstractly but you see the tangent spaces is just an embedded linear
subspace are just naturally inherits the inner product structure from the space in which it
is embedded
so this is v and w is exactly what you would think it to be
from this picture
but that's what gives
the money in structure
so now that have this
you can talk about length of curves
and you can talk about geodesics
so what is the length of a curve c begin that what has occurred
a curve is a map from
zero one to m say
and if you take its derivative
you actually get
right defeated by dt is actually a vector
and if the norm of the vector that makes sense because all the vectors
living in some space where you have norms and inner products defined
and if you integrate that
along the length of the curve
you get the length of that good
so that's how you would calculate the length of any cut off
and now he between two points you can set up variational problem to ask for
shortest curve
that goes from one point p
the another point q
and that more or less
evidence combining matter
that are being used in the asian network
you can look at some at average weighted sum
you can also
in the publication to grow
you see also that
and or combination
it can be
for instance can be incorporated here in the computation
of these norms
so this model is known to have
quite good results
it is also incorporated
indeed quite insistent which was longtime well
well yes
it's estimated that good retrieval models
developed at the university of
perhaps i forgot to see that for the language modelling approach
you have two kids of leaving
the most toolkits
developed at CMU also in cooperation with the university of
and this is
the software open source of open source software
where you can
change the language models incorporate new language model
four computations
thank you
i think i
he is
most of about
if here network model
you see in this model
you can easily come combine these sources of evidence
you can combine sources of evidence
coming from as as actually also in the language might
which is applied to the simple form of action and that my
you can combine different sources of evidence of development
so we have also study that you outline must instance
where you combine you have
you computer
you compute action video back from BBC
so you can combine evidence
coming from
metadata to be used
the technical metadata metadata
to alter the producer of the video
also information
the image
forty manually annotated manually labeled
but not only the text but also
all the information about
this multimedia sources can be easily integrated in such
the problem is of course
computational complexity
you see that a lot of independence here in the network
let's go back quite well some level you define then you could
find level
so that you can see that you take into account in model
so you have a lot of computation
also lots of numbers to keep track of
of the probabilities of each note
although alternative and croft
give you a
he convenient implementation based on link it at the node that are sourced at each
node still this can be if you have a large document collection considering that
you want to answer to your query
instantly almost instantly within the second you want to know this is this is too
well this is quite a bottleneck
for such an approach
but we have
you believe that the technology failed currently
so i think you know the model
of four
twenty years ago
maybe not so long ago but still
quite some time ago and we have a newer techniques for approximate the thing
and maybe there we
we could proceed again in information retrieval research in research
can also be you
in different ways
so in this case
we have a crystal field splitting energy
that's less than what we call
the pairing
so the pairing energy is how much energy it takes to pair up the electrons
they prefer to have their own orbital
they would prefer not to repair it takes a certain amount of energy to pair
so in this case
the this is small
set of orbitals up here are really not that much higher in energy than these
so it's not that hard to put one up here and it takes more energy
in this case to pair them up
than it does to put one in the higher level
so this one would have
a drawing like this year for electrons you put in
one of them goes over there
in this case
we have a really big difference it would take a lot
of energy to put an electron way up here
so in this case
this wedding energy is greater
then the pairing energy
this is really a lot higher
here is small makes not much difference
here the energy is large
so in this case you would want
to put your for electrons all down
in the lower level
so let's just take a look
some of those
rules and save them again so here
the splitting is small
this is called a week
so the link in here will be weak field ligands and only strong field ligands
and we're going to talk about that next monday
how you learn certain ligands and whether the weak field strong field
but if there are we
why they did not release that energy very far they don't have a lot of
strength they can do a huge splitting they just you know they just do a
little tiny amounts splitting there pretty weak ligands
and in this case you would have a strong
a strong field
are you have large splitting so those ligands come in and why they take those
d orbital energy levels and they put them really far apart so those are strong
field ligands create a strong field and this is large
right so if we look at some of these rules then
so here are pairing energy is greater
then that energy difference
that means you have a weak field
not much difference is weak field not much
not much wedding the wedding is small
and then what you're going to want to do is put all the electrons in
singly e to the fullest extent possible so you use both t two g and
you put them all singly until you're done before you can
on the other hand if you have a strong field that's going to have a
really large splitting
the energy difference between the two g and PG sets of orbitals
then that's where the energy is going to be greater than the pairing energy
more favorable to prepare them to make that they jump up
two this higher energy level up here
so in that case what you want to do
is you want to hear them all up
in t two g
and only after this is completely fall and you can put any more electrons in
do you want to put an electron way up there
in e g set
of orbitals
what this is what this means then
it is in this case
we're going to have
the maximum amount of unpaired electrons
because you're going to try to keep the unpaired first long as you possibly can
and so this is referred to
as a high spin systems
in this case
you're going to have the minimum number of unpaired you're trying to pair them up
down here before you put one up here
so this is a low spin
system minimum number
of unpaired electrons that are possible
so these are two two
diagrams that you'll see
and one question on on the problem that has you drawing these these diagrams for
these different conditions
now this particular one that we're talking about
this particular complex is high
so next week we're going to talk about why that's true
and you'll learn about some of the ligands and be able to predict whether it's
going to be a high spin or low spin system
we can also go through now and two
electron configurations and also the crystal field splitting energy
so in this case
are RTN
it is going to be equal to
there are three electrons
in t two g
and there's one electron
in e g
and over here we have
you cannot close your eyes to move from the back room you don't even need
to do that you can sort of guess what i could probably tell what that
documents about
without looking at all the other word without knowing what the order is right so
it sort of seems like a reasonable thing to do
the topical classification
it sort of seems reasonable you should be able to look at this information and
make a categorization decisions
so technically
it's nice to think about this
representation so internally what you would represent in the computer is basically some sort of
hash table which gives you the word frequency which would write the mathematically it's nice
to think about this as a very long sparse vector OK
where are the dimensions of the vector of the entire vocabulary not just the words
that appear in the document to they all
three hundred thousand words that are used in english
OK and on each the i th component of the vector is the frequency of
the i th word
all right so conceptually you can think of this is a very long vector where
most of the entries are zero
so mathematically it's much more convenient so
as i go through the rest of these that's the that's the mathematical representation to
use but you know under the hood inside the computer what we're really gonna milk
that is the sort of
word frequency paper representation
OK so a little bit of history now OK
really serious experimental architects text classification
was david lewis thesis university of massachusetts back in nineteen ninety two
so was computer science goes and machine learning goes nineteen ninety two is not that
long ago
are so just
for the purpose of comparison
the first
machine learning paper talking about classification of
you know
vector data that i know that's widely cited studied under are the ones that go
to go that earlier that was fisher's nineteen thirty six people talk about linear discriminant
so was in nineteen thirty six
david lewis did this text categorisation stuff was fifty years later so why fifty years
later when people look at text classification for before that given that there are so
many different applications of it
well one thing is just we had to get computers that we're ready to handle
the problem right so the typical text classification problem
and here's one that you know i had a while back with your singer so
we have three hundred thousand documents are pretty short but still there were sixty seven
thousand words that turned out to do we do have a little bit better from
used for ground so we had like three million four grams so looking at
thirty three thousand documents and three million features
OK so
computationally there's there's there's a cost and storing these things and and are
and working with them even with efficient methods like days
but there's also a conceptual problem
in fishers data
he was classifying flowers based on four measurements OK so every example and four numbers
there was the belief that as you increase the number of dimensions the problem we
are intrinsically harder
so here we are talking about learning with millions and millions of features
OK and typically more features and have examples
so how does network
so from from the theoretical point of view it seems like it shouldn't work
and actually even in nineteen ninety two it was unclear why it work
that sense only sort of come to understand why
classification can work and does work and basically several different pieces to the puzzle so
for efficiency
you don't need to represent
you know this matrix of three hundred thousand documents and three million features by representing
on with the matrix it's three hundred nineteen thousand rows and three million columns where
every values explicitly represented so by using sparse matrices you can represent the stuff inside
the computer without too much work
for efficiency you need to use sparse representations
but the other important observation was if you're using simple classifiers that have wide margins
and you can theoretically showed that the course of the dimensionality is not going to
come back and bite you
so i'm is going to be a a little bit
the intuition behind these observations so what's the idea here so you got some examples
in just in two-dimensional space rape get some positive examples and no negative examples down
so this line right here
is put in the middle of these things OK of course lots of different ones
you can draw between these
i am destroying if you here
i mean
of another class
this is this is already having explained somewhere here
i don't want better than a bunch this is full of class
this carries class class k
just people to see want to try to write that but i need to do
is i reduce the support of all these will all the world's the perfect i
reduce the support somebody world had off you
but that would be the new
so that's all you're doing introducing very general rules
and then when you find patterns that contradict that will you're just the will just
make it a bit more special but it doesn't fall for this contradiction any more
and then you have these two steps you introduce a new one or when already
had one it really don't do much
you can show that this algorithm terminates converges wonderfully it's not problem
it's actually also computational in another big problem the the coverage is easy you just
need to check if the problem is that in one of these rectangle to find
one of the things they do commit it's very easy to use and rules for
real shrink these space that's summarised coming how you avoid this conflict you can reduce
it you know you could also use here you have several choices the conflicts in
our case for users the volume based on our strategy you just try to keep
the world's largest also
the output of these this hour and this is the world system
that has possibly very small number of rules because i mean if you find a
region here he would model this region up the the the the large rule covering
all of these belonging to class high and then down here you would get three
smaller rules that say OK this is a region belongs to class low this region
as class high in this region in the ones that so only introducing finer grain
relations in areas where you actually need them
and not all of these attributes need to actually going to the the rules so
this will appear for example may not even constrain itself towards the x axis right
i mean it was introduced infinitely large towards all dimensions so all this one is
probably going to say is well y needs to be above a certain threshold somewhere
here then it's plastic x class high in the stand here a little bit more
more restrictive
so just to
i mean that this actually available online on our department's website if you care about
the sort of the nice thing is so this fuzzy rule learning algorithms free fuzzy
rule learning our first set of rules the complete is that perfect all-round will classify
all the training patterns correctly and it actually does generalise reasonably the armed force only
as long as the training data is conflict three if you have a couple of
instances device actually the same input patterns that have different output classes there's no great
that you can build rule system that differentiates those for the ones that do you
have any background in machine learning mitchell version space that the the interesting thing here
is that it's generating partial hypotheses each of these rules is describing is representing the
partial hypothesis for part of your training data sort of responsible to model the part
of your training data but the core region is the most specific hypothesis the generating
here this core region is the smallest rectangle that you can possibly find enclosing patterns
of one class
and the
support region is the largest one that you can possibly find just avoiding conflicts right
the baby shrink this it's a very large rectangle that tries to cover as much
space but that does not contain only come any conflicts
the support is also more general than the core doesn't really matter and the nice
thing here so you can interpret that as the core region is the one with
the highest degree of confidence we actually have seen patterns that resulted in creation of
the correct angle if seen patterns of the class and the support region is the
largest area and we have seen no conflict but we have not seen any couple
i have a little bit more that in a second
there are many different i mean if you go in the literature and read journals
conference articles on on fuzzy rule learning all rooms the silence around you'll find thousands
if you wanted to classify them you could try to do it like that it's
at all they have the ones that are constructive like the one i just discussed
now they try to find fuzzy rules by either growing and shrinking them i mean
the one i just discussed was one that finds fuzzy rules by shrinking them from
being very very general to just avoiding conflicts it could also opposite way try to
grow fuzzy rules so that they
not grow from one pattern and try to grab more and more patterns of the
same class to grow them from singletons
you can have grid based approach one mendel higgins goodman that have this global partitioning
of space
you could do more things you could try to adapt those those those boundaries between
the grid cells
you could even try to merge grid cells neighbouring grid cells that belong to the
same class could be merged together rows columns even if they don't cover any points
of the same class you can have adopted tolerance initial ice rules randomly
but you use an expert knowledge sometimes have partial expert knowledge that you can use
and then you optimise rule parameters exactly where the location of the membership functions you
could even sometimes try to optimise the number of membership functions there are algorithms that
are based on genetic systems evolutionary algorithms to try to find fuzzy rule systems to
and our so this looks roughly correspond to this first
as skip this RDF
for RDF i sets is just encoding of graph nothing think so
if you have a description one
so data
scrapped in RDF this means that one atomic unit is
triple object attribute value
and which is just a note link and another can be constructed out of this
one bigger structure and an upper-level low levels like RDF schema in our actually at
semantics for this graph
i was keeping it so this is what what i
what i have here basically
it's written like this
x and this
but i was keep this hollow
this is the next level let's see if go back to this
so RDF research graph and ontology
it is smallest one way how to use this graph two
describe more abstract models now
what our what you need to know about our not to go too much into
the data is basically it
it's logic language
description logics so this is the common
with this set of operators
first order logic which still enable you
to be
in tractable so that you can prove
proof of any claim so all our lives is the
simple lists
version of our language very well allowed to use only a couple of operators and
these are just a couple of simple constraints and basically what you model here so
all the light is meant just to encode taxonomy three nothing more this
i DNA
so this is maximal expressivity
of logic layer which would still allows
that every claim
for every query can be
proven by to improve small s
it is but the
and i would fully small this
full logic of the first order rich
can be also so these are three levels of our language
roughly correspond to set of operators which allowed to use
which is well user can can can use to describe a
usually ontology
OK this
keep this ontogen also ontogen is one
system our system for learning ontologies but i was keep it's not so
and go
the last part of the semantic web which is a description of the
cyc system
so semantic that if
it's about bringing semantics
are common understanding into the as
i said before now there are a couple of systems which
i are related to
semantic web or which are quite characteristic like strategy is very popular
ontology editor about this ontogen is getting also quite popular for learning for building ontologies
straight from the data and so on a a couple of water
but one tool which is very
well known from the past of AI
is site so probably some
well i'm sure
she knows about it but
well there's no about site OK before
so psyches
an example of
really it is
semantic that dream but
still these dreams didn't come true completely
a little bit of history
so it it was
a site was
and attempts from eighty eight these early eighties to encode common sense knowledge into one
knowledge base common sense knowledge would mean this
knowledge which we have on which we operate with on the basis of the project
started saying
eighty four
therefore and as a response to the japanese project few generation computer that's on the
times of
although built again
i guess remember this
i was in high school at that time
and so probably this cyc is the only remaining
i think are the only remaining effort which which is still alive after his fifth
generation computer which started which was started in japan and in ninety four the company
cycorp was established in austin texas and later on the company well its own life
two thousand five the cyc knowledge base got open and available for research so we
have two version of
cyc one is open cycle which is
a common vocabulary
which can be used for
four applications or whatever is maximally free
licence and researchcyc which is what this everything what side these the in this twenty
years what's interesting let's be open this site in europe for the last year
so in the down as part of our technological park
and was maybe also interesting to see to know is that the use
two thousand six after eighty million
o dollars was spent into developing in this knowledge base
and this knowledge base
aims at least two color more all aspects of
actually is written in a slightly different coordinate system might find you to be elsewhere
though there are then you get this very simple form and actually it is very
simple form is exactly what you get if you have a negative cosmological constant and
maximal symmetry that's like should the sphere with just
an appropriate time according to keep them here
so that's the geometry that one looks at
and now let's do the following men tal
exercise suppose we want to think about low-energy excitations in these
what are all possible very we have very little energy at our disposal one to
excite the system what can we do what we can definitely have
gravity tons of extremely low frequency extremely large wavelengths
stressing that crossed the geometry and those who live out in the bulk of the
definitely fair
and those have arbitrarily small energy however because their wavelength is so huge compared to
the characteristic size of the throat
they don't really see the for all you can not probe the throat with something
that has a wavelength that's no millions of times began
therefore we have gravity in the bulk but which decouples
on the other hand we have everything
near the horizon because remember there was this infinite to achieve whatever you put there
can be an elephant would have actually minus that redshift in two zero so you
can exciting the horizon anything you wish and it has arbitrarily low energies
and therefore what we get are all possible excitations in the throat
due to the large which gives rise to the top of the gravity of the
now let's think about the same problem now as all as users but thinking about
it from the string theory point of view namely in terms of the brains
what do we have that what had this the brains we discussed
in the last two lectures how there is a gauge theory living on them
in the case at hand it's actually the most supersymmetric gauge theory i would say
a word about it which is simply
in equal for super yang mills in four dimensions show it's a theory that having
the use non abelian gauge fields plus a big supersymmetric or will describe one
so this is the massless states of open strings living here and then we have
supergravity has usually been in the bulk
therefore again the low-energy excitations of the system are a young music theory on the
and the copyright line into super gravitons in the bulk big problem because the coupling
of gravity goes of energy if i go to very low energy gravity couples
so now you know if you
look at these two equations
one plus two is equal to one plus two two
there is an obvious thing you want to do
a plus b is a policy implies because to c and therefore you want to
conjecture that are four let's forget the gravity in the bulk
any one of four super yang mills before that mentions his maybe exactly equivalent to
the full string theory or anything you can construct out of the string theory but
in this very funny for the geometry which is a just five five
and this is the sharpest statement of what one also holographic correspondence holographic duality was
most sharply stated aim of the same name ninety seven in this very auditorium actually
know what works back to
OK now
let me say a few more words about this very special theory trying to force
pretty amazing did not the kind of gauge theory we want to discuss priority if
we are interested in the standard model because it has indeed
big age boyzone's of you when rescuing young males
but it has also for every gauge boson four gauginos
six scalar partners
that makes it very very supersymmetric as met because it gets
but on the other hand this theories of
great simplicity for the simple reason that is nothing else
but supersymmetric missing and dimensions i discussed this be the first lecture just dimensionally reduced
down to
four dimensions where you decide to call the gauge bosons of the extra six dimensions
instead of a phi
so these are the scale as we have the usual
in their actions of gauge bosons usually community squared
the whole structure is therefore very simple fixed by these
and then measure means
now these much supersymmetry has one advantage in some sense
namely it gives you vanishing paper functions
if you compute the data functions for this coupling here
it's the ability to vary the basic function kappa vanishes this happened doesn't around so
the theory is conformal scale invariant
for all values of the young is coupling constant that's very unlike you should be
aware of the coupling runs
from very weak
values are asymptotically free UV region
two strong coupling in the infrared
there is also no confinement in this theory is also always called like forces between
charges because precisely the coupling never gets wrong
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this MIT opencourseware OCW MIT
that you do you
welcome to five eleven one
and today we're going to do is introduce you to the course and the people
teaching the course
and we're also going to let you know
that you're going to be part of the great when exercise that is OCW opencourseware
so this course is being videotaped this year and this is the
the announcement that i have to make so
the videotape is in the back and if you want to
come up front and participate in the classroom though that you'll be videotaped if you
want to
hide your face or whatever you can do that please pay attention to the lectures
this this course will be available
on the OCW site in the future not sure exactly what they're doing is going
to be
so today we're going to introduce the the chemistry topics which we will cover five
eleven one and give you general information practical information about course number points you need
when exams are that kind of thing policies and introduce you to the teachings that
i am again professor kathy drennan and one of the lectures in this in this
so because his MIT we're going to start quick
OK not crisp points or anything don't forget
but i do want you to tell me
who these people are
so what about this person
that's me
this is my college yearbook photo
OK what about this person over here
it's not me again
not elizabeth taylor
if we could roll known as phoebe on friends
we both went to college at the same time we went to the same college
does anybody know what college that was
vassar college very kind
and graduated the same year now no one has to
say what year that was even if you know
what we did graduate the same year
all right
given what you know about us
what do you think
we thought went to college to study
computers now
the inner
surprisingly no
nuclear engineering faster
no for a variety of reasons
any other gases
english now
biology a i heard it
what do you think i went to college to study
the other contract
and or had made up my mind exactly
bio psychology or drama
so by psychology was what they called sort of brain and cognitive sciences in those
so those are two my at the two things i was thinking about
what do you think we use that ended up majoring in college
not bias psychology
what do you think i majored in college has to be a bit easier
chemistry correct
and of course are professions
actress and chemistry professor
so one may ask
what happened here
my understanding about lisa kudrow
is that she came from hollywood family she went to college and said here's my
opportunity to study the thing that i find most interesting and that was biology
and then she went back and participated in the family business which was of course
the acting profession
for me
what happened well
i have to say
i did not like chemistry
in high school
so i do not think about going to college to study chemistry
so why did i not like chemistry in high school
i think it was because of images such as this one
we spent a lot of time talking about the transition between alchemy and modern chemistry
was very interested in that kind of thing and there's nothing in these photographs really
appealed to me personally
i mean the god rho fund his number
and he is in fact an interesting
if not frightening looking man
this just didn't connect with me
but then i got to college and they said well after thinking about anything bio
bio psychology biology you have to take chemistry
and i said to my advisor no no
i have taken chemistry in high school and i can assure you the chemistry has
no relevance whatsoever to the life sciences
and they said well sorry you feel that way it's incorrect and you have to
take it anyway
i like some of you in this room
are talk
freshman chemistry because we had to not because we want to do
and i like hopefully some of you in this room
discovered the chemistry was actually a lot of fun and that chemistry i got to
college was pretty much nothing like the chemistry i had seen in high school
so let me introduce you to some of the topics we're going to be covering
in chemistry this semester
there's more detail on your syllabus detail of what will cover every day
these are the kind of basic things that were covering you need to write this
down to become familiar with it is this last time
we start out with some really basic principles so what here atomic theory periodic table
bonding structures of molecules and there will be a little bit of history in there
so that's for collaborative filtering has also been applied to things like
causal this kind is not really causal but graph structure discovery for medical diagnostics protein
complex discovery an independent components analysis so
and this is what by
david also
and i think quite nice model so it kind of goes as follows so
each image
we're going to express
each image is basically a and and we feel that this is an array of
pixels with this kind of vectorize that so each image is this can be a
vector of pixel values and we can express this fact as a linear combination of
sparse features so this vector here x i is going to be some of the
features k of some basis vector lambda k times the value of that feature
why i k
so while i can think of of it as the activity of feature k
and in ICA we want a sparse prior on on y
and the sparse prior which we can consider is
basically a mixture between gaussians and the point mass at zero
so why i came to the prior of waikiki account looks like
something that has point masses are mixed with the girls
and we can
describe such point
such a prior as follows y case in game
well i k simply going to be a product which is is that i can
a i k where k is going to be drawn from the girls and i
can either zero or one
when is zero
we just get the point masses zero and one this one is simply going to
be a k
and this z i k is going to be this matrix that can be drawn
from the indian buffet process
so we're going to have an infinite number of features
to express our
to describe image only finally many of which is going to take on a non-zero
non-zero activity
so there's quite nice actually gives ICA model with infinite infinite number of features
he yes so
so this gives us a case
and that i cases you could equal to one with probability me OK and you
go to zero with probability one minus mu k
the next thing autobots hierarchical dirichlet process so
one of the motivations for the hierarchical dirichlet process is a topic model which takes
place going into great detail describing to us and the topic model goes as follows
right so for every we have a set of documents
this is given by the outer plate
and every document we're going to describe the words in the document as a mixture
model is a mixture of topics
and so documents so document j is going to have the mixing proportion of pi
j over topics
and for every word in the document the generative process is as follows with first
gonna pick a topic z j i from
this distribution over
and once you've picked the topic
then we pick there were from a distribution prior
that he
from a distribution over words
the specific to that topic so that's given by theta k here
so zack GI is going to be drawn from multinomial parameters pi g and xj
i is going to be drawn from a multinomial
there is given by the distribution over words in topic z j
and if you are bayesian data can place a dirichlet prior
if you are simple minded business you can use conjugate priors so we can use
the dirichlet prior for theta
we're also going to use the dirichlet prior on pi so
we have the dirichlet prior pi
so this is the prime minister and dirichlet prior on
on the
on the distribution over words in each topic
and what we want to do is to say that all we don't actually know
the number of topics so less
imagine that in fact there is the potential
that's potentially an infinite number of topics in the world but
you know we only see a finite number in the finite corpus
so somehow we have to take k to infinity in this case the
number of topics that could potentially
be out in the world some
but this this model was right so in both the the
mixture model and in the
indian buffet process we see that we can just a allocate to infinity and everything
works out
and so in this case it doesn't work
and we have to fix it somehow so
i can we can call this sort of problem
a group clustering problem right so every document in every document we make sure model
so the clusters the words together into different topics but we have lots of different
documents in each document we have
a clustering problem
and what's interesting about this clustering problem is that so
so imagine this document one document two dutch documentary
in document one week we cluster the
data points in the cluster
OK so
in document one we cluster the words in the document to in the different clusters
similarly for document tool and similarly documentry and what we want to see
i assume is that
the clusters
we could across different documents so this is saying that a topic can occur in
different documents
so we want to cluster
each of these groups
groups of data points
together such that the mixing components are shared across the different groups
this is this kind of
have domain knowledge language knowledge or robert knowledge or objective knowledge about objects and object
but in the sense if you look in the end if you look at what
they publish the inference i of are quite similar
so the vision we have here is that we can abstract to some extent i
mean you still need to be an expert in the field to back to some
extent into something like
each one is working on what really makes their cost different
where they are the real action
we share a common toolbox and inference and learning task here so that we benefit
cross fertilize each other right whatever the NLP guy is developing
computer vision can use directly and actually that's happening one of the my opinion very
interesting cross benefits are topic models so they started something like just to understand what's
going on in the collection of text documents but then if you look at CVPR
in recent years to find a lot of topic models of visual words where people
were inspired by
these ten words in text trying to identify what that means in image coming up
with ideas of this is something that catches and then they try to
learn topic models about the visual word which is then foreign-backed on computer machine learning
where there's a lot of about dictionary learning which means how can we expect learn
these words automatically so if we can somehow their combined forces i guess we can
make much more progress than just working independently of each other
that's vision
but in the state the motivating we're interested in combining logic and and probability is
why this tutorial
well it's very active there's really a lot going on multidisciplinary
because as has argued that a lot of subdiscipline of AI
unfortunately having said that they still speak different languages
right so we managed now maybe within ten years to almost have agreed on
few language two languages in the sense within the statistical relational learning community and actually
this year i guess we managed to also extract from these languages and really identify
some of the core problems
then if you talk to other people
they still have their own language right and we have now two chances we can
try to learn their language is go solve the problem so that they should be
interested that's what we will do
but this tutorial celso
to show you
maybe it's a benefit for us just tried to jump on the train
so why should you be interested
well of course advertisment here but i guess is really a success story not because
i'm finding that this success story actually one should take petrol holding success story several
times but it's also if you look at
many of these papers these papers could best paper award at
the conference at the years of the specific subdiscipline right so there have been best
paper board for example in NLP
right and so why should they give you the best paper award nothing at all
interesting so there is really something going on
in bioinformatics there's a lot going on because these experimental design issues and you can
ask about relations between different experiments and if you make use of that the were
and the group by color has shown a lot their within the planning community there's
a lot going on currently there was follow-up
champion at the probabilistic competition which was used in planning competition which using a relational
probabilistic approach so there are a lot of stuff people start to see oh yeah
really then
OK so after this motivation i help you got a bit excited
let's give a short overview of what
but his relation to the next to these two few applications i've shown you the
textrunner stuff already in this kind of toy story about submitting papers they of course
really a lot of applications today
so there have been NLP information extraction a lot i think one of the main
how basis safer applications including prediction so within machine learning all the collective classification task
you can quite often be nicely represented within this relational learning
framework within social network analysis there's a lot of work
going on
think of mixed member so you can view them as related model
in robot mapping there has been some work by for example
petra again but also by peter fox we're trying to work on the current activity
the best in show had once one paper on using markov logic to explain activities
computational biology there's a lot going on and so on and so on so let's
have a very brief look at them
in particular the first example petrol will talk much more about that later where you
also don't understand how you can model
this kind of problem using markov logic networks and information extraction for example assume you
have certain references
it's a problem than that
so first task is to
i understand that these are different papers or or they all paper
so then next to that you may ask of this paper so then i know
talked about all authors title and then you like you proposing like petrol
memory efficient inference relational domains is the title and triple-a iowa six second trying you
do that for all these
different papers
well then
you start realising zingler p and personal are actually the same person right although from
from the evidence you've got there looking different but if you do some reasoning for
example by making use of
the title here there are two papers with the same title you expect that
the two of us are identical so you see how to take if you take
really count we get a better picture of
and then so on and so on so you see that information extraction and NLP
tasks definitely we can benefit by
making use of relations by
solving tasks jointly by
making use
of all the knowledge available or all the information available right
relations are really hard
and the reason
well in the early days
something on for example gene localisation if you do just collective inference
where you say the location of one gene also depends on
genes with similar function
then with a rather very simple
kind of graphical relational model
you can be better than the KDD cup winner
right so not saying this is the best model nowadays for this kind of task
all right
robert here of course
well i mean
of course
all o
well are
o he
i don't know
however we have
this is all about
they want
i'm sure
that seems uncomfortable for doing machine learning we want them the machine to really learn
everything including the preprocessing transformation
so this is exactly what we do in this work
so a war guassian process incorporates this preprocessing transformation which is going to be warping
function of the output space as an integral part of the probabilistic model
and this allows us at least one way to model not nongaussian processes of those
there are other ways to do not get the same processes
the idea of working the observation space
is that we assume that there
vector of latent target values
sets of
that is modeled by guassian process
but what we observe are going to be
piece of and
and we need to find a mapping between
z and t and
so we make a transformation from the true observation space t
raw data space
to the latent space the
by mapping each observation through the same
nonlinear function f
and that nonlinear function
it's going to be parameterized by some parameters side
the question
so there are a couple reasons for that so let me just explain one of
them here
i think you could do it the other way around as well
is sitting right there
but it's a bit simpler to do this
what we do is we require to be monotonic
and mapping onto the whole of the real line
and when we do that basically it means that the probability measure will not
otherwise probability measure would not be conserved and transformation
and this will induce about distribution of the target
but i think we could do it the other way just below more complicated
when we want to learn the parameters of this casting process in the regular guassian
we had to minimize the sort of cost function
as a function of the parameters if we're going to do optimisation of the parameters
for going to be really bayesian we would do inference over these parameters data so
we would
computer distribution over data
proportional to this
these are data doesn't appear in here because it appears implicitly as a function of
the covariance
matrix OK remember the covariance matrix is a function of data
so that's where theta appears
this is an ordinary guassian process in the war guassian process
we have not only the parameters of our kernel or covariance matrix but we also
have these parameters of our warping function
we want to do inference or optimisation over both of these things at the same
essentially the work as in process
has exactly the same form
log likelihood as the regular guassian process
except that
instead of
here and we have
fifty event because
each of the target system that through the working transformation
and the only other term here
is we need the jacobian
that walking transformation
changes the that's the measured the changes the probability from one space
so this is our new
log likelihood and we can simply optimise this with respect to both of these parameters
all we can do
with respect to both these parameters using this