is the way to represent the entire application in terms of an abstract more than
it will be basically
this stuff
so it will talk about whatever it will be possible to do with applications in
terms of abstract way of using it
on the other side here you have the more the better
try to address the content
so i brought it here ontology but actually my have multiple ontologies in our case
we will have an ontology for musicmoz anybody from musicbrainz an ontology for EV
OK so
all of these will
the representation
of that series in the semantic models
right and we develop than before we started writing the court
because this is part of the development process you start from the more than you
use the more the all from the way down to the implementation
and you said step which is important i believe which is don't forget that you
need the data
so that's the state it's time to try to model the data from different sources
in these models and see their feet because data on you will have to write
to the way you start to the data and the like these you will have
them represented already in terms of their
of the ontologies
when you have done all these you can design application as the court
when developing an ontology
of course you should follow
all engineer process to do that we would normally follow them it on the methontology
upholstered unbiased some governments parents at you but one can use it in a different
approach that you might like the idea is first of voice things about reusing
so there are tons of terminologies outside in the web don't do it again
normally you cannot find one single more than that satisfy you so you have to
merge them
the different more that you want to reuse
and sometimes they don't satisfy even when you merge them all you need so you
have to extend but basically these three steps should be enough to develop the ontology
even if it is the application ontology of the content on the page
i would try to show them
during the
the tutorial
then we got implementation and we broke down implementation in four steps you know the
first two of them
the importance first step is to implement the initial knowledge base so what you want
to do
as i said you have an ontology here
ontology here
and here so you try to develop these ontology
and to put them together and see if they fit together
and you put the this simple scene and you try to show to show you
said that you're not going to derive the knowledge that you are not expected
i mean the things that you inferring things that you are not expecting or you
are also trying to show yourself that all of the knowledge that you want to
give it from the congo requirement is represented down here
if you do when you have done your
two these input and implementing integrated model which means that connect connected
all these interpretative abstract more than you have the complete more than
you can start writing queries and checking the more that works without any java called
around just brightest under greedy century cave or the police are working properly
all the data that expect that coming out using this simple content
and here i stress that this first approach so you've right all the testing of
and then you keep trying them because every time you change one of these things
something broke down so if you have the tests you can find them and check
if everything is keeping working on this standard software engineering approach
and here i come with the last two implementation things which are about how you
extract the data
from your sources you i call it choose content annotation methods because in the old
semantic web days we we're expecting to extract the most of information for web pages
so it was a way to
get annotation from content
as an extended meaning or extracting data from a database we call it a content
annotation but i mean you you can see choose the extraction methods as as it
different label for start
and when you have done all this real data coming out from the your sources
and so you can implement application as well as
of course the spiral
so you go
and validation
you start the game
what we see this tutorial just one
we cannot go free for many many times
what we did was user needs analysis is a the style you give me events
so what i'm going to show now
is the requirement analysis from content
as i said
the content will be extracted from existing sources we selective the event that bayes and
these two musical databases sources
if is a quite famous i guess application i guess the today's called eventful and
i believe these are all like one but i might be wrong is owned by
you know when not coming
it's the one boy born by like google
what you can do
it's these
go to
page right as i did up here
a query
these query
i don't believe you can read it but in any case he said i want
to events in san diego
if it is it occasionally ventures so it is described as educational events in the
schema then we throw it away because we don't want it to be there
of things like that so if there is edit information in down so we use
the that
information to fill things away but in the end whatever is there
we think it
OK so
after his transformation which is pretty easy
what you do
is creating a
with the constant query
OK the leagues
so again using sparql this time we are using to construct the triples so we
know which that we were asking if he did before
we know they then that come back we feel that some of them but this
is as i said to reveal in the way we did it in very difficult
as the problem
and then what you do is basically saying OK you got any event
say it is related to the performance
that i was asking for
so the sparql query
it is actually the way
we implement these might be good
these last the linking here
so this is again linking
but unlikely is one that was done
by the people that knows what they were doing and they correctly we have a
right which is with some person that's correct them with some other not connected to
OK these guessing that is link and not the fact that the reality because out
there and if you go and look up to bp your work you will learn
in the dance of these
i mean they wrote down some the interesting query that tries to draw links out
of information unstructured information which is
inside wikipedia
i can give it is in the PD
a lot of things everyone in reason is you can you cannot really know
if a link is not asserted if the link exists you must write down a
piece of code that try to guess it
and then you
check if this was a good at guessing
so linking is probably big problem
rather than the
one is just looking
a long long time ago this
OK sorry
do you know what rest is
i will not accept and
so you may know that some years ago
w three c came up with this stuff so
you have a simple object access protocol
which is the way to exchange messages between services in XML
then they came up with don't
which is a way to describe the services and then they came after we've it's
played of other standards
that i about security addressing
so far and this is called the web
thank you know
it's cool stuff
it was very well inside the organisation
it really works
but when these this was claimed to be web services OK so people should have
use it on the web
but actually what came out from the developer's web two o was
why are we doing this
we have
plain XML
and we need that the very very senior year of service description which looks like
it's a page right is written for your money
may learn about
different queries but they can do
and it's community forest as the one that we are using this one search
as a bunch of parameters
the location the
for a random variable
of f of x
and so it defined as above there
so far so that for for the discrete viable expectation of f of x is
the sum of the exciting f of x times by i
not admissible decision theory that i really easy for bernoulli variables
p one is the probability of can being one piece you is the probability of
x being zero
you by applying the previous formulas you see that the expectation is p and the
variance is actually p tends to one minus p
and expectation of any function of x is is this one
it is instead of having
of observing only one converse you observe two of them then
we may define random viable
that takes values two
that takes values that are
two dimensional
so zero zero and the two concepts
ten is
zero one was the first one is there and the second one is its
once you're
and in one one
o are the possible outcomes of of the random variable y
so why has to according to random vectors
and you can define its expertise its expectation
you can write a few right
the vector x one x two
with x one x two to two bernoulli distribution the two bernoulli parable corresponding to
the two going to assess
the expectation of y is the vector made of
the expectation of x one
and the expectation of x two
the and the variance of y
a little bit more tricky to define actually you have to represent volumes by the
covariance matrix
it's the rating matrix so in this case it's the two by two matrix
and the its entries are its diagonal entries are the volumes of of each of
the coordinates there
so the diagonal entries here
well the covariance of y are the values of its one divided into fixed too
and on the other hand on
outside of the day i goal
the entries of the covariance matrix of similar she senior former as
the variance it's an expectation of x one x i x j minus the product
of the expectation
right so if i is equal to j then you find again the variance
so it's it's a measure of
how similar are the two random variable x i and x j
i think i did the computation for the very latest revision again
you have the expectations of the
of the
two distributions and the covariance matrix if the two acquaintances are independent
so i
come back to independence afterwards
but you don't necessarily have zeros on the diagonal here you have used because they
assume that the two going to is independent
OK then know there says independence implies correlation but the inverse is true so the
correlation is the fact that the covariance between two
really random variable is you
and then of course i'll come back to that later as well
if instead of
taking values in into discrete then x
these values in in
three line for example then you get a continuous random variable
well what you could see is that
there's not much sense in in saying what is the probability of x
being exactly is equal to the value small acts but more
the what the when and the probability is going to be able to measure is
axes easy actually in interval
let's let's talk about the expectations the expectation is defined as before on on omega
so it's the integral of x of omega
the appeal again
and in few
transport people to the real line through px
and you find that the expectation of x the integral of x p of x
so that would be only annotation now what happens is that east you can write
these these probability
a product of positive and negative function times delivering measure so the living measure is
is usually your usual measure when you right into walls on on on the real
then x is said to have a probability density function f of x
and so this expectation there is nothing more than the integral of
times f x of x dx
now for any measurable function you can you can define the expectation of f of
x and you can also define the variance of
of x
which has the the
same in the same format as before
we OK
so here are two really is really common distribution on underlying the first one is
the uniform distribution on on this thing and a b
so you can
definitely easily see that the pdf of
the uniform is aware is o one divided by the main this is the stuff
the indicates the indicator of x being in
here's the gambit that's how you're going to solve these problems to go through this
the set of operations
go through the set of operations so just to recap
if you go to look at this simple cubic
the hkl sequences one two
three four
five six
because there's no sum of integers that will give you
seven if you some squares of integers
so give you all the lines but this is
eight squared plus k squared plus elsewhere in ascending value
right body centered cubic
body centered cubic has to be
two four six
eight ten twelve fourteen sixteen
but when you first do this you don't know because you divide by the first
sine square and so you don't know it's two four six eight you can end
up with one two
three four now that we have a problem simple cubic is going one two three
and body centered cubic is going one two three four but watch this perseverance
half of ten is five half of twelve six have of fourteen seven
so if you guessed that something
when you divide through you get a sequence that gives you one two three four
five six seven
you know that it can't be simple cubic because there is no some of
integer squares to give you seven the seven in fact must be fourteen divided by
this is body centered cubic
face centered cubic is the easiest one to pick off because it gives you three
eight eleven
twelve and i just need to see three four and i always check for fifty
cc first
always check for FCC first
so was that's how
that's how different commentary works and it allows you to index
crystals in determining crystal structure more broadly speaking there's database
all sorts of
minerals and compounds and so on
let's look at the second technique the second technique is called allowing the fraction
allowing the fraction named after max von who got the nobel prize
he was the first person to demonstrate x-ray
identification of crystal structure that the nobel in nineteen twelve
nineteen twelve for this
and in lower we fix the angle specimen is stationary and
variable with
radiation so how do we get variable wavelength radiation look at that spectrum up there
you see the bremsstrahlung branch round gives you a range of wavelengths
well we're how do we get monochromatic radiation
how do we get monochromatic x-rays don't tell me big by an x-ray laser
how do we get monochromatic x-rays
it's really cool what you do
if you take
you take this
brahms strauss
with everything on
and you presented to a single crystal
you presented to single crystal
and the new park over here this is the entrance slit you're different armor
what will go through that inference split
there's only one
wavelength will go through that inference and that's the wavelength that satisfies the bragg condition
for this lattice spacing
this angle
so what i can do
as i can make a single crystal monochrome under the basically takes
characteristic spectrum on top of the gram strong sense that in
i present single crystal
and there's only one
the wavelength of light that will come out of fear that satisfies the bragg condition
for this the spacing and this angle
so the single crystal axis of monochrome
very cool
very cool so this is called a single
the crystal
just use regular that's all on this case we just we take the whole
the whole mass
and here's what the specimen looks like the specimen goes into a
a darkened
box is called a camera obscura
camera obscura
and what happens is i can put the specimen on the frontier
the specimen is on the front to some crystal
relatively thin
and i put film on the back
films on the back so i have
the film is sensitive to x-rays and now i send the being in
so this is why x-ray
y x y x meaning it's variable wavelengths the whole spectrum
and what happens is
the white x-ray
interact with the specimen
and shoots off at different angles because of the different
initial wavelengths so each wavelength will be diffracted at its own special angle
and so what happens is we end up with a spot pattern
on the film
we end up with a spot pattern and
spot pattern spot pattern is the output and the symmetry
on the spot
and i'm going to take you into k space and so on but i we
simply tell you that all you need to appreciate at this point is that the
symmetry in the spot pattern is imitators
was imitator of
the symmetry
in the crystal
symmetry in the crystal
so when we say something about atomic symmetry
and this is based on the time years rotational symmetry because we're looking at something
on edge so for example if i gave you the
all all one plane
if i give you the all one claiming cubic crystal looks like this
right so now what i want to do is look at rotation rotation about
a normal access
rotation about all axes somewhere to put a normal axis right here at the centre
and rotate this one actually the question how
from one angle do i have to rotate this
in order to get this back
so if you close your eyes and i start rotating suppose i rotated forty five
you open your eyes are going to see that you going know something's move
how many degrees you have to rotate before i get this back
nine by rotating ninety degrees i will end up with
this and these are indistinguishable so ninety degrees
here's what i need to rotate and the crystallography first instead of talking about the
angle of rotation
restore what you're looking at the talk about fall
node c so in both the notes c is going to store like one and
nobody's going to store link to but in addition that like most the past that
they use
so now what's going to happen is that each of CNT is going to during
the next advertisment step c india and also advertising information they have about the
links in the notes they can reach in the network
so i'm only showing advertisments for node easier course at the same time c and
d are also advertising the fact that they can reach themselves and maybe the ability
to reach other nodes in the network shelter just looking at you but their mind
all the advertising is being done for all the time
c send an advertisment this says i can reach no e and the way to
do it is to centre and i can reach node c via c and then
and similarly he sends out a message says i can reach no d five d
and e
so OK that's so up to this point we haven't really seen anything very interesting
but now during the next iteration step we see that these two nodes b and
now have now have heard in advertising to give them a path that allows them
to reach node c
now every node has a path that allows them to reach node you but this
advertisment and
integrations process is going to keep going on so for example
nodes a and b
we're going to advertise that they can also reach node e to their neighbors
and in this case it's probably unlikely that either
any of the nose would like to switch to a new route so for example
it's it's not clear that there there is no reason for example the eight would
want to forward it's mass is probably unlikely a one for its messages
through b
to reach the right because
that's going to to
it's going to be longer happen for a to send its messages simply three c
and e but if the but he doesn't actually know whether or not a knows
about the
so it needs to continue to broadcast this information out
so this is very this this is this is pretty simple it's pretty clear how
this works and once this process has been running for a while you can see
the network is going to converge into state where every node has a pattern if
the long is the network is connected it will converge into a state where every
node has a path to node
and the amount of time it will take for that to happen is equal to
sort of the number of hops the maximum number of any node is away from
once this notice converge now we can trivially build up our forwarding table simply by
pulling out the link number from from each one of these nodes so for example
we can see that he sends either these four in table simply says for each
node in center my and and layer these four people would say to reach node
you send it over my like two
season four in table would say to reach node is the overall one
b forty table would say to reach node is sent over my one so going
so it's once we've done this path vector routing at the end of this process
we all know which links will built up four in table you can use for
saying links
so this is a very simple process but now let's look what happens when something
what we said here is just that each advertiser step we're going and after each
advertisment we're going to go and do integration
integration basically we're going to do is try and pick the best in some way
we've shown here simply taking the shortest path or we the shortest possible path for
every node to reach node
and in case it wasn't clear i didn't explicitly stated states state is important to
realize that nodes are going to ignore advertisments with their own address in the vector
space so if for example
so for example when node e here's no d
advertising that can reach node you know he's going to say oh well i i
am no d i don't actually need to pick up this pattern i don't need
to send my to myself through node you obviously do
now we create a routing loop which is something we presume we don't want to
do so this is a simple way using these sparse vectors we can use to
avoid creating
OK so now let's look at what happened something a little bit more interesting let's
look and see what happens when for example there's a failure so this is just
exactly the same network and i showed you
but suppose for example that the link between d and fails
OK so now
the network
no longer has now note the no longer has around to node
remember the way that describe this is that this advertisment process is just going to
continue going on in the background rate so what's going to happen is that at
some point nobody is going to realize that it's linked to note he went down
is gonna
across the stable table out of its into it so nobody is going to
basically stopped hearing advertisments from node
when it stops hearing advertisers from node e
actually it's going to do something it's basically going to expire entry from its link
so after hasn't heard advertisers finally for while that entry
and then some time later it will hear an advertising from node c saying i
know how to get to know you
node node node d can go ahead and integrate this new pattern to right
now notice that this process is just going to propagate through the network so once
nobody stops hearing advertisments for how to reach node e is going to stop sending
advertising for how to reach node c
so similarly we're gonna because b is also routing its information
had previously been routing packets to reach node c by where he is going to
we have
going back to
rotating objects
i have an object here
has a certain velocity
it's going around with the angular velocity omega
and a little later
the angle has increased
bynum among theta
and then the velocity
is here
we may now
do something we haven't done before
we could
if this object in this circle and acceleration
so we don't have to keep the speed constant
v equals omega are
so that equals state of times are
and i can take now the first derivative of this
that i get the tangential acceleration
which would be
only dot times are
which is paid out double dots are
and we call failed w dot
we call this are five
and of five
is the angular
which is in radiance
a second square
do not confuse ever the tangential acceleration which is along this conference with a centripetal
acceleration the two
both there of course this is the one that makes the speed change along the
if we compare our knowledge of the past
of linear motion
and we want to
transfer it now too
circular motion
then you can use all your creations from the past
if you convert x
and a
two of
and the well known equations that i'm sure you remember
can then all be used for instance
the equation
x equals x zero
let's be zero t
was one half
eighty square and
simply becomes for circular motion
he calls
data zero
it was only god
zero t
one half
of five
the square that simple omega zero is then the
angular velocity at time t equals zero
and theta zero
is the angle
at time t equals zero relative to some reference point
and the velocity
what's the zero plus eighteen
that now becomes
that the
velocity goes to bangalore
velocity omega
people's omega zero
plus of
it is really not much and it
in terms of
remembering equations
if i have a rotating disk
i can ask myself the question of which we have never done before
what kind of kinetic energy how much kinetic energy is there in a rotating disk
we only dealt with linear emotions was one half MV squared which we never consider
rotating objects
and the energy that they contain
so let's work on that a little
i have here this
and the centre of the disc c
and this this is rotating with angular velocity omega that could change in time
and that this has mass and
and the disk has a radius are
and i want to know at this moment how much kinetic energy of rotation is
stored in that this
i take a little mass element here
m of i
and this is radius equals are of i
and the kinetic energy of the element i lung
because one have
and of i
times your of i squared
in view of life
is this philosophy is angle of ninety degrees
this is for your
now vehicles omega are that always holds for these rotating objects and so i prefer
to write this
as one have
and the phi omega
of high screen
the nice thing about writing it this way is that only god the angular velocity
is the same for all points of the disc whereas the velocity is not
because the velocity of the point very close to the centre is very low
the velocity is very high
so by going to make
i don't have that problem anymore
so what is now to kinetic energy
of rotation
of the disc
the entire this
so we have to make a summation
and so that is
only gas created over two
find the sun
of the five
is how to get the best c value now because
you are in this area we have the same plot the number of features here
and see values
that's the same kind of features and and si value
but just to display something is this was the population of bounded support vectors
now we displace the performance
well was the best performance so you want to know
these are around what kind of surveyors we provide you the best performance and then
you see
this is something with which is
you get high performance
for one particular sitting i don't tell you just use one or one because it
depends if you dataset
a few problem but i just because that's what i see in practice
the tendency is to have a linguistic values to to to provide the best performing
so that's one thing
and besides we also
this questioning and and that's why we are still working on it because
we have also these
should a very large feature vectors you might get worse performance than what you would
get here if you were selected features
so we don't know it yet it
what's what's really happening
we observed
a performance dip
for SVM we gave we try to give some some explaination because we spoke about
everyone around two or three but we didn't speak so far about the performance dip
and we observe in between two and three
there are two and three and
and what
we did is just plot as the proportion of bounded support vectors
the proportion to the number of support vectors
so here we have a
if you have this four cells and documents four thousand lines in your metrics
you might have a maximum force cells and involved documents feature vectors in your solution
so we should start at about seventy five percent here three thousand
and you the total number of support vectors which decrease in which you increase again
what's happening
we have the number of features below
what's happening in between it just enabled by the support vectors which is dropping
to minimize
that's what we saw here during interest rates so you have less and less and
less and less about the support vectors and on the other hand
you have more regular
support vectors
a new solution
and fortunately
for us this much approximatively as the performance dip of as SVM
another and comment on this figure
is this
now we have rather regular
solution was very small number of bounded support vectors what's interesting is to observe this
so if i continue increasing the size of my feature vector
solution which are
which involve more and more and more
more more training points of my data set
anyway i have less sparse solution other increases the feature space the size of the
feature space
that's quite expected since
with dimensionality
the more you increase the dimension of few of your problem more points will lie
in the boundary
if you're a few of your problem
it is it to to see for everybody and because
but i'm quite familiar with it but
it's just an illustration of circus of dimension eighty here
you you we need more and more points
the more damaging thank you will be more and more points to
to make the boundary of your class concept so you have a class you have
two classes
the boundary of each of each class
and then you will be more and more documents to
to more it
you expect from has been have sparse solution but here we
in practice we see that
even in high dimension you have more and more the commence involved in the solution
so that's a nice illustration also
if it's good or not i don't know what is very specialist but that's racing
in practice
is is specific to text classification
i'm working with biologist have big data set it in the times ten thousand
it's very similar to text mining we have zero one two values in the data
and actually i could be produced as the performance dip result in
you do not have
this performance dip
you don't have these one but you have to
we have a case
OK so let's do case analysis
in this case one
i minus one is an exact
so the i had
is equal to
all CI is now just i
that's the case
and then we have the rest there plus to minus two ceiling log i
minus two ceiling of log on this one
that's equal to
five plus two
let's see
if i minus one is an exact power of two what does this term
i minus one is an exact power of two
thank you
that that
good as doing we say because for
that is so there is actually y and being a pretty good
theoreticians because i
because i don't ever trust what i've written down
as i write down in a way that i can verify it because otherwise i
just i'm not smart enough to carry through five equations and rowan
i expected every
one is going be transformed appropriately
so you write it down so i always write down so i can verify that
fortunately has the side benefit than other people can understand what i've done as well
OK so what is this one
this is two to the longer by minus one
because the ceiling
this is an exact power of two
then ceiling of logo by minus one is just
what of i minus one so this is to to the log by minus one
which is
i minus one
things that are too then log is
right so taking the ceiling air that matter
during the ceiling
this one however is not an exact power of two
but what is it
it's just one more than this guy
you know
i must one is not an exact purchase is going to be
the next bigger one
so that means this is what
this is going to be
these two compare
how much bigger is this one and this one
twice the size
you know this one is
they reasoning from first principles
this is going to be
a lot of
i minus one plus one
in reduced to this
i think i think about those floors and ceilings right
like what's happening in the round off their
so now we can simplify this
OK so what we have here we have
OK so so i have
i multiply this through i have an archive plus two
minus two y
plus i minus this one
a lot of people i know a lot of your ninety percent you want to
this that
you go directly from the step to the last step
and that's where
thirty percent of you some number
we get it wrong
OK so let me encourage you
to do that so that
OK it's easier to find your box
OK if you if you take it slow
it actually taking it slow is faster in the long run
hard to teach
give this is the best one but i'm not a graphics person so
nice couple of my story ends there were marred mitsubishi electric research laboratory in that
they do both vision and graphics very well so
they're looking at this paper and extending it to briefly mention that OK so let
me briefly mention what's in here at all basis of the data and the reflectance
function you know characterisation this is the
transfer functions and this is the lighting conditions
and this is the intensity profile so you
you you have this guy
and the way you collect this is using random projections OK and then you are
concatenated all of these guys and make a matrix c
as i have indicated here and then you can have some basis be transposed because
the orthogonal basis and therefore
you can put this problem in a very nice you know compressive sensing framework so
you're trying to figure out d from c and l is how you would get
a list random patterns that you use to generate c our
OK so
they describe and i set for how they construct to use the camera to collect
the CRT monitor is used as the control of
high resolution light field there and how they think they use gauss
random projections and represented in the hoc basis and that's how they create the patterns
and in fact this is somewhat similar to what is done in the single pixel
camera and some acquiring compressive measurements and then they take you know photograph and then
given methods so this is an example taken from their from compressive measurements and this
is actually the ground truth and so forth so this is a great example of
a practical example of using compressive sensing for graphics power so my story and said
well reflectance functions are not just are going to be sparse maybe that compression over
so they basically added another component to it i'm going to some rush through the
grid and i'll show you how
OK so
so they have a way of characterising sparsity
as subspace compressibility i feel most images will probably fall as as vote not just
sparsity because i'm not sure if we really have a really good signals that we
just have to cater things in some basis and poof day away i mean it
is not possible in fact is something on power law in what if if signals
are not case possibility but they will be something and has power law in as
as the variance goes down the value here is is this and they are greater
than everything here that that's the power law most images don't will be that so
but the IP properties good firepower loss signals also
anyway so my story and said well let's not just do the the sparsity thing
l one r will also add an under the l two norm and they put
together and so on so it's some minor modification to what is being done in
they work from here at the top and these are my two store and you
know they're working on it and have made some
i guess is in terms of how
measurements you need to take because you're doing joint consideration of sparsity as well compressibility
OK so
this is the set up they did in march and this is the kind of
the the matrix they use the random projection matrix they used to collect and all
measurements using this camera
and the scene is over here
and they collect whatever the number is needed by the theory and they do the
using the criterion function i mentioned and this is still ongoing work
in there
OK so so
the relighting pattern using this this is really terrible it is even in vision person
shows the graphics
paper makes it looks even worse
whereas the vision period graphics we will make our results look better
somehow when we show so i guess session shows anymore sorry OK
right so i have ten minutes and i want to keep is five minutes for
a discussion of the next two slides
this lot more going on that i have not talked about you know c is
for background subtraction can look at ECCV paper and professor larry karen due is this
talking about compressive sensing and particle filters
this is kind of the conference is going to be here and you can think
in september
statistical signal processing workshop somebody knows about that
last week i'm sorry OK so there's this paper and we can show our data
behaviour with me and for mcclellan how is useful for bearing estimation and
have but i support this and this is there to will be able to rise
to on c espinosa damaging historian who knows bit the works are and we looked
at it in
i'm sure there are more here that have not
as i said i started my career in nineteen eighty one is almost like twenty
eight is something you know
the great one
the fact that make you go through your entire life story and a number of
parties and then the dark matter that makes sense OK so
background knowledge is very important if you want to learn from very small number of
examples OK so one question of course is how do you use the background knowledge
of end about ontology is not complete no problem in the learning you're trying to
get the background knowledge about the same time if it is already there
everything that you need to learn in the closure so one of the interesting kinds
of ideas would be
two x two sort of characterising what parts of explanation
well you know i it's not the concept you are sure what parts you're not
OK so
and the idea is that i might not know everything about how that's what i
want my knowledge about specific sub assemblies of god my company
that's when i give you
part of the explanation meeting was that subassembly of the card then in sense actually
and complete and so there is this whole notion of
characterizing local completeness of your knowledge
and using that to decide how much of your rather than say explanation company correct
not completely correct i can see
here is the explanation these plots i'm completely sure is but i'm not sure
and then you can use that in a much more interesting feature selection
i think that's a good direction for and in general the values dbl here is
that some of
there are various terms have been used in the machine learning literature including BBL KBL
on the relevance this learning knowledge base learning exploration based i just mentality and i
use the word is here
additionally adhered to stand for alone
that gets me so i'm basically looking at this picture and i learned rules to
try to find vanity that using
explicit policies that i want to say a couple of things about this and this
and then go to the other side
i have been mentioning earlier that one of the you can improve the performances to
remember plans remember all plans
the number pieces of wood plants and when the new problem comes along either you
know you basically just starting from scratch and try to use this flat
there's a whole bunch of work that's been done in this area many many different
ways of doing this sort of reuse
and i
cannot possibly explain you all the possible finer distinctions so instead i'll just give you
some of the main dimensions along which this sort of the first and so one
of course is the structure is being used so if you're talking about using plans
are you talking about the using opaque plan that means if you take the whole
take you don't change anything in the
OK i dual averaging
idea allowed to modify the pieces of the plant
OK so if you're loving too much if you're allowed to modify the piece of
the planets in a sense i think the first five steps of the old man
at the more things and add some more new steps and then bring back supply
so it turns out that one is called macro operators that land use and similarly
do you just using the solution which is the plan that has been stored and
are using the following process to the ones that additions that were made in generating
and finally it's so and and the second issue is whether these plans are given
to you by hand by humans outside of the loop
OK i these are plans to the planet has generated in the past you story
and this is an interesting dimension because if it's not automatically according the sense you
solve these problems in the past was then at least you know exactly why plan
to correct because you have enough my knowledge
explain whereas these are given by humans
three times in fact in real world use occurs because we don't actually know all
are how to make this plan from scratch so you think something that somebody else
has made and we make smart weeks and hold that local warm effect the correctness
so that's the kind of way i changed my car and i might change itself
i don't know how to make it from scratch but i might change my problem
the car assuming that one change too much OK so
that's the important thing so in in the area of what case based planning board
have been considered so bought the issue of war
humans giving it outside what says automatically acquired and it turns out that
so it turns out that if you are interested in the human in sense the
planet doesn't even
have come doesn't even need to have the company domain knowledge
and then in terms of mechanism use if you use these operators that are using
them as multiple plans and if you have multiple plants coming coming out of the
library how are you going to do
put them into the
extension process OK is just an example i mean often the kinds of work that's
been done on use this is because i am familiar with it so the in
this particular case you are using the additional traces which are officially not only the
plan but the decisions that were taken
to get that class
OK and
furthermore when you have a long planned you don't necessarily want and that plan is
the single case if this plan was let's supporting fifteen goals you want achieve in
and it turns out that those goals of all independent that means and if you
actually what each of the all separately are the plants that are concatenated to solve
all the people that it makes no sense to him and work plan but due
the g fifteen another plant what you wanted you fourteen of plant but you want
keep thirteen and so on it makes much more sense to discuss the planning pieces
which are twenty two independent subproblems so you could generalize people do that independent problem
analysis again using explanations of why the planets correct c
rather the explanation are interacting explanation product was independent subgoals setting
OK and then finally stalled the plan in the library and it's been achieved if
in fact are you won't try to start with that plan the next like extended
and brand speed that you have to come out of it then you try to
analyse why the land that they and remember to sign up and will rule saying
that these
conditions under these conditions don't know what the previous plan again
OK which is sort of like this that central activities like italy will control so
we think these plans would not be here the
one thing to mention i guess in terms of the EBL and the use of
so the two individuals with that property
they got the DNA they did this stuff
and they plotted them into d
so if you think about what that two deep what might look like
the answer is it looks like a map of of europe
i'd like to emphasise that
nothing about their analysis
new where these people came from they would just literally given vector saying these are
whether there this normal type of the sun normal type in the DNA these locations
then if you do that and you apply PCA
a new project in two d
and draw scatterplot then this person came from italy
and the and all the brown people came from italy and the central people is
and similarly
all of the colours represent which country people came from and if you look at
the topological arrangement of it is very very closely that matches map here
so even though this is like a horrendously large problem to deal with these features
when you have many more than people it's quite possible to pull out
like real structure the way the
we evolved is that people moved out across europe and as they did the DNA
changed and at least in this dataset was carefully selected the main dominant feature of
the DNA is
at the location they picked
what's the sort of
nematic process across here
so i thought that picture was really dramatic i can really believe it when i
saw it but
the important thing it tells you is always plot whatever you're doing because you might
see something interesting actually they they've people knew that that was going to happen they
had to had to model a there pretty sure that they going to get a
map it and expected to be that good but they expect expected to get
but whatever you're doing
try and come up with lots of what you're doing is you're going to project into
down into some dimensions have a look at this and see whether
you can see anything obvious popping out may be able to identify the big outliers
that are likely to secure analysis that you might want to toss so you might
want to model you might want to look at
and that will help you make a machine learning system that works but there is
insights can also be valuable
in themselves so
if your consulting for someone
if you want you to solve a particular problem you turn around so you know
this is actually interesting stuff i saw in your data it might be stuff they
don't know and it might be useful to them as well as a system that
does what they actually are
i have laundry list of things to do for visualization where
time say
visualization is a whole
research topic of its own and to be honest it's not something that i'm an
expert in but it is something i do whenever given the dataset so i always
just a bunch of very simple stuff i put histograms of every single feature and
label out and look at the list does not millions of
i draw scatterplots of lots of pairs of features or the features and the out
idea scatterplots based on PCA i might also be random projections look at all these
plots and you know it might only take twenty minutes to look through a whole
bunch of pages what that could tell you something that you wouldn't notice in weeks
passion your head again sort of just applying algorithms without looking at what they're doing
there's a piece of software which is really neat called you gave me that
does a lot of this stuff so one one of the things it does is
it takes if it does fly through tolls of your data so it will randomly
projected to two d and show you the data and then it slowly tilts the
projection it's using so that that you get a movie review data set that sort
of tumble for high dimensional space so
if you imagine it keeps spinning your listing that animation you can you can look
at it keep spinning on a two d screen and you have an idea of
the three d q gave software that will tumble high dimensional spaces and maybe with
some practice you can actually get some idea of what these high dimensional spaces look
this figure doesn't show that what this figure shows is that you gave you have
lots of different ways of visualizing the data and it has the
trie told can do things like ringo dataset in one representation and it will colour
in all the other different representation so you might see outliers in one projection you
so what do we do next will be bigger
like two
might have four months wise were wise words why would be some nice three i
my right
that somehow we can
if x is really a giant
what's y
most of the time right
almost the same as x right but not but slightly less because the square is
forced one so so
is that i think i'd rather asymptotes like this the forty five degree line here
the minus forty five
and i think this curve
is something like that
not bad
it's not a parabola looks like one
but it's a hyperbole
and now for changes to it too
l started swearing to
again another hyperbolic
it also works i want
don't get out near that guy
but at all
something like that
this is all there all approaching at forty five degree as an
and of course could be smaller
what have
and get somebody in here
so i got a whole family of curves
so it looks to me like this
this all
now one the so those were the equipotentials
now one the other curve other family of curves drawn
the streamline streamlines come from the stream function
so i want to drive those as equals
two x y
equals cuts
i i meant to
make a little note as i usually do
which sections
of the
lecture connects two
section three three is specifically about the possible equation
section four point four
it's about the complex variables stuff and then there's one page
you have no
here the one page
two seven seven i think that has a formula
that will
touch OK
right now think
OK i'm going to try and the the equal the streamlines and just complete that
point so this is what kind of a curve is two x y constant equal
one that's
so let the concept b one
anybody recognise that kind of a curve two acts like one it's also a hyperbola
so by a total
i like chance here we've got two hyperbolas and if i try to acts like
one of those that hyperbolas are swung around by
ninety degrees or something
these hyperbolas go
right through
perpendicular had like like x y one of like x x y one is if
x is big why small effects is small is being in between
they crossed where x equals y
so they
you see how those things are going the next one will be steeper
but it will never
touch the axis of their asymptotic to the axes were the first guys were asymptotic
to the forty five degrees
OK and the beauty of the whole thing is that this is these are all
right angles everywhere they meet is a right angle
and that comes from
these crucial equations which i'd better write down she named after carl she who was
a great french mathematician
and every man who was greater
when he was one of the the great mathematicians of all time and the two
equations connect
the real part you
with the imaginary part as its riverview
agrees with the y derivative of s
and that actually comes from our now are raced
the first derivative
because like first derivative and
the other one is duty y
comes out as minus the
other great equation
and they come directly for any as the real and imaginary parts from our first
they tell us that these
occurrences of the curve as equal costs these are the streamlines
and these were the potentials and those equations would tell us that they need writing
so it's the the geometry is test
and that will still be true
even for these curves which would not be
so easy to draw well i could draw the easiest one would be one if
the streamlines if it if the potential function is x
let's should look at that he really is the case if the potential function u
of x y is just x
what are the equipotentials
just lexical concerts vertical line
and if this stream function is why
what are the streamlines whereas white constant there the horizontal lines and of course was
made writing
so that x and y this is the the case when the flow
it's just like
like on the mississippi or something that flow is just following the streamlined
one straight
well maybe the mississippi
it doesn't go straight but out in the middle of pretty
and then it's a valid codeword
i can show you the code afterwards is just a little tricks i i took
the image
you're correct i made a codeword that's tricky and then i added some some redundancy
bits in the czech and what we're running with some product
right so it's doing about
it is not optimized for doing ten iterations on something like fifteen thousand nodes and
you can see it's reasonably fast people
to use this algorithm in practice
OK so
those are some applications i just happened to cherry-pick those there's many others right natural
language processing things like parts of speech tagging graphical models are used all the time
statistical image processing computer vision things like image denoising
image segmentation image disparity computation people use graphs all the time
there they actually use grids like this often because those are good for modeling spatial
what are some other examples
phylogenetics computational biology genomics these all use graphical models as well
so there's there's many applications in the applications depend both on somehow the
simplicity that we get from the graph structure and also these algorithms that i'll talk
about tomorrow
what i'd like to do in this last part is
i'd like to come back to the hammersley clifford theorem i'd like to drill down
into that a little bit more sort of been high level but i'd like to
why it is the case that if you have something that factorizes like this
it must satisfy all these conditional independence properties
so let's let's start drilling down a little bit to understand that
right so if you remember the statement the statement says if you start with the
whatever undirected graph you want
and you build the distribution
that factorizes over the cliques of the graph
that's the same as if you start with the graph and said that you had
all these markov properties holdings
so let's
let's work through that one direction of that argument
any questions before i i sort segway into that
hammersley clifford
so they were so probabilis at oxford on the original papers actually unpublished
i think you can get your hands on scanned version of the body has never
been published so there are probably and they were sort of interested in essentially generalizations
markov processes on chains play such an important role in probability
and they were interested in these kinds of generalisations to graphs
so i think one of the first published proofs was by julian besag
unfortunately passed away i think last year but he did a lot of the pioneering
early work in the seventies and graphical models
among other things he was very good naming his papers he had a great paper
called the statistical analysis of dirty pictures
by which is meant image denoising exactly what i did with codes that you pictures
that are corrupted and he was going to noise and with the graphical model
it did i think the british kind of naughty sense of humor they like those
kinds of jokes
americans are just more crude more direct about another nice proof i think was the
student granite in seventy three had a very nice proof i believe he was a
student of one of the two i don't remember
so let's let's do one direction
anything else
that's a good question i don't know that to be honest i always wonder i
feel it has to be an american
it's not a scandinavian because scandinavians are not you know scandalized by
unmarried parents having children
maybe pearl but i don't want to cast aspersions
someone could search and find out i'm sure
OK so let's let me just walk through just because i think it's useful to
do some some of the technical work so let's show the following that show the
factorisation property implies the markov property on any graph
so i'm not writing this statement and the world trying to show is is one
direction of this
so what i'm going to assume is that you've got distribution that factorizes in the
way we've written there
is we don't have these basis functions at all we can use arbitrary functions
interested to know it and polynomials
i'll skip forward
so let's cheat
these basis functions
so i x and convex
thank you
the actual model came from signing let's be
they realistic
and let's say we're looking for sinusoidal functions we should include sign cars
take account of all possible phase
so something isn't a long here because there's no width parameter are
o going result i straight away
so i don't like it here because there's no are
i just simply
a this basis function in
and so this is far more probable
the reassuringly
and then all these basis function models
model actually contains the true sin x
it is more probable
you have be price price at all to see on the error
this model also gives there
of that
because as one more model
if we really were going to cheat
you might be interested to know what is actually sin x on the same line
well what
and about that
that's even more probable
and that of course is what you would expect
because if we had a bit of concepts into the model
noise means
data means that we're going to find a little bit of cossacks random
and so this model was the either is probable my clients is good prediction
so the trace
is the most probable
course gives us
the lowest there
take home message from this in this application
it's likely that you can see
a certain amount of evidence for the fact
calculating these marginalized probabilities
offers the potential for doing some quite interesting experiments with model selection
using models without having to
before many validation
or use any extra data for testing
it's purely based
on these marginalized basing quantities
so this if this looks too good to be true
there is one of the function is the challenge the audience
can anyone think of another function has as much probability
it is probable
as sin x
the engineers new orleans signal processing people
many with nitrous there
now the but also think about aliasing
these samples are equally spaced
and the band
signed fifteen x
just show is
you can't just attack the problem with you talk it would actually thinking about what
you're doing
i'm quite happy to show this thing falling over battle
if we take sign fifty x
because the sampling theorem the fact that the samples are equally spaced
smaller basis functions perspective you can't tell the difference between sin x sin fifteen x
where we sample
this function has to high frequency across something frequency
across the x axis
so far the data is concerned
it looks exactly the same as in a different sin x phi matrix is identical
it looks just as probable
if we evaluate the test error of course it's totally rubbish
because the test error when evaluating in between
so this isn't a failure
good it is on the fact that you've never seen and this is another question
and most of the time in fact you want to solve the two problems at
the same time we want to find the best function
according to some data that you have
and to know how good or how bad it will be even though that you've
never seen but it's important to see that these are very different questions and
if you only want to use two
to find the best model
and you're not interested in knowing how good or bad it's going to go to
be then you need to do what we call model selection but when you do
that you don't know how good is going to be you just know that you
have the best function
if you need to do the two
so if you make the risk of a given function then you have to estimate
the risk often you need to do both of them at the same time and
other very values practical ways to do that going to quickly summarize
evaluation and cause variation but of course there are other ways
these are the most useful ones
so this is the formal
explanation of valuation and going to try to explain it in words so
let's suppose that you want to find the best model
and you have you are given a training set of m examples
and you want to find the best model according to the training set
what you are going to do is going to divide your training set of examples
into two parts
one of them you are again going to keep the training part and the other
one you're going to call it evaluation part
so they have to be disjoint
and basically what you're going to do now
is that over your training part of the training set you are going to select
the best function
and over the evaluation part
you are going to estimate
there the risk so you're going to compute the are you you do on examples
that were not seen why you try to find the best function for these examples
somehow you can see locally known for giving them all the time as examples you've
never seen why you selected the function
so they are very similar are two examples that are in the set that you've
never seen in fact they are the same there are just sample of them and
we know that this
is an unbiased estimate of the expected risk while computing the risk and those one
would be advised to estimate so that's why we separate them
so far so basically we are going to
two for several value of what we call hyperparameters
for instance should i use a set of
polynomials of order two three four five
the question i have well i'm going to
to search for
two three four and five four for each value two three four and five so
far too for instance for all the sets of function for me
for the two i'm going to search for the best function according to training part
of the training set and estimate the value of polynomials of order two on the
validation by
and i'm going to do that for polynomials of order two three four and five
and now i'm going to compare these values the one estimated the initialisation part and
i'm going to decide whether we should use the
polynomial over the two three four and five according to the minimum of the values
of this to make a good and that's what i'm going to return to and
again i get the best of polynomial of order
two three four and five
and i can tell you whether it's good or bad because i you all the
data to decide to take this decision so i don't have any more fresh data
to tell you how good it is because any of these to make now
globally are going to be biased because i think
good decision using the
so it was used in large sense as training
cross validation now
it's when you don't have enough data to take your whole they don't cut it
into two because when you cut the data set of course that means that you're
going to have less data to train so it's often bad so sometimes you don't
have enough data to cut it to two so what you
we do is to
to cut it into more than two strange but that there is going to give
you more data because you're going to decipher system to capture to case separate
distinctive subset
and for each subset
i'm going to use the rest
train your data
estimate the value on the subset that you never used and you're going to to
do that for all the subsets of for each of the subset i think the
for training and i use that subset to estimate the value they do that for
all possible subsets
in fact i cannot go into that but is going to give the same idea
and i'm going to estimate the value of the
the of a given function with given the hyperparameter by summing all the years of
the semantics of this one by induction given the the semantics of this one
simply mainly this i imagine i have mapping that takes
o point
in my latest
and this is another point
remember my memories here the points for us all
o point of the poster
it is
so i called
a mapping
what is now in annual it is monotonic
if it preserves the order
so he was leading
and you can imagine canada mapping
i want to associate to the next
six like relation
when will be monotonic because if i if i take two sets one embedded into
the other
the for this so the first one will be embedded in the predecessors of the
if the mapping is just give me the predecessor
the this is so
so here
that's what i call my lecture on the fixed point
you can define the fixed point of every mapping
point the defendant unless
mappings are
your mapping is monotone
this is a mathematical one
to define something
well relevant men that meaningful
but you have to keep in mind is that if you have a lot of
the new function
you have
an element OK
whatever you take
can be called the fixed point if it maps onto itself
the fixed point
i don't mean that you need not be to define fixed point
this but clearly defined
x is mapped onto itself
if i not just introduce innovations is how many times a f
before the
with the new function i mean
composing monotonic functions remain monotonic
the problem
and now comes the big big big hero
that's the one that is always
mean always the one you need when you're in
very standard settings so that you have is that the early eighties
and in general i mean that the medical journal based across related
you need some extra property which to be complete
what it means
the objects when you can combine as king the
meet all the joint
it would still be
this is not always the case
again to make electronic databases and computer completely this is so just i mean
nearly four
oppose that basically this
their complete because the significance of this intersection of two sets and the union of
two sets
that's fine
in middle ages
this is always defined
for every time i mean
points in the latest to take aways that you need
low to exist of a bunch train test
it's full of apoptosis
and if you take
all points altogether due to you take the
the love of you get the element which belongs to the to the latest so
we have to open but on
four sets of positive construction and bottom is the empty set and t
subset of
so this one
i think it is
this example or this
it is
the other side
we use
so much for sure
this what
sure it
this is
when you buy
if you wish
she also
and reason
well i
it was
so the patient
this was
search engine
it's not just the rest of
just read
and this was actually
the lines
o one
he is
to pick the right parts of the probability of choosing the right boxes so if
these two distributions are very similar it's going to be
very hard
so this probability is going to be
large otherwise to easy
what's the cost of being wrong well if you're wrong you'll pick and again notation
easily messed up here you picked the wrong
base classifier you'll say OK base classifiers the interval from delta one self from zero
to one or vice versa so what's the price you pay wild preservation given by
these because
OK even if you picked the wrong since it is close to level one half
you don't pay that bit of price so the
the cost of being wrong is on the order of tell race to the cap
OK because of this
you can look OK what's it
what's the kullback leibler divergence in this case was given by this expression where n
is the number of data points to collect and
it appears here to tell
it especially to do with that gap between the level one half zero so if
and as doing exactly this
same here so it's the squared pretty much
OK so from the tower in order for this to be a constant so
just because of that if you multiply these two terms these are the only known
constant terms here don't have the constant means that the probability of being wrong is
your point one
it's bounded away from zero
then we can put all this together
and because this
for this particular problem doesn't depend on the estimated that we know what the best
thing is so the probability of
yes DSS risk being greater
the same
just replacing tau there
it's going to be greater than zero point one are created and the across
so very have our
lower bound
this is not exactly the form we've seen before
if you want to get in the final before
you'll have to use
i markov inequality and i don't see this may be a point of going through
this in very detailed
so we just showed this
you can use markov inequality that's inequality that characterizes what happens to non negative
random variables tells you a relationship between the tail behaviour in the expectation of the
so if you put this all together what you get is
something else about the same but now it's in terms of the expected risk it
tells you the expected risk and not that faster than that constant times
so that's the way you prove to lower bounds here so
such as the seeds may be a little bit hard to digest at first because
you're are used to think about upper bounds of the time so you see the
inequalities going the wrong way
but there's the question of what happens in passive learning ways passive learning so so
let's just
please exactly the same game but for passive learning
now not take samples everywhere
OK you don't know
what i policies find distinguish the only possibility sample somewhat uniformly over the domain so
you're taking samples like this
so only a fraction
tau of the samples are informative right on the samples that land on this interval
informative all the other ones are rubbish
if you look at the kullback leibler divergence in this case the difference between the
two distributions is going to be exactly the same what we had before
but there's this actually culture
because it is saying is that it is only a fraction of the samples are
we just have to play exactly the same
the same game and that you see where what's changes in the phone itself having
two k minus two now we have two k minus one that's that was a
big difference
so you see that
the lower bounds for passive to the only difference is this is that you're collecting
samples in place so you don't get any information
now we're going to generalize this would be true
multiple dimensions
let's make just big break if there's any questions or so
before we start
a little bit of time to prove so
as any questions at this point
so the question is what if the class the underlying class of problems is different
than this one so maybe there's two transitions and you don't know that well then
this procedure for active learning is going to do properly
four lyricist we don't know exactly what it does but the passive learning procedures might
do better if you say use empirical risk minimization or something like that
that's the problem but the task here at hand was actually trying to understand what
active learning can do for you not
that's what i said that maybe the problems of contract but it tells
it it gives an indication of what that one can buy free by you all
should you go about doing it it doesn't really tell you to solve it in
it's unfortunate but it doesn't tell you that it just gives you a better understanding
what are the trade offs
there are some ways
so in this case you be made the object was to performance comparison between these
two heuristics that i
so this has been used to forward to think about this case i want to
which he also do a good job in this case
so what we should do
it is which is all always cost
the they get
can be
so it's a good way of
well verifying experiments
we have some
machine repository
so we could be introduced the study
a differential equation
the top of the of also search space so simply try randomly
the points the search space
and if you check the best for your answer
so if you lot of
there should be
you don't have any heuristic is just trying point
there's always some of launch
and you know it you can use cases with very simple iterative local search which
can be used clustering algorithms it is
two things to say very often because is deterministic
this is just some random points
it is this is what you get
so if you have many many times
what's the best is again
so was that you can you several times also because of be but still have
to make it to be competitive with
so what we did is that if you give all these
among of candidate solutions for evaluation because they always the true
currency to measure for search heuristics how much you have to try to find a
solution because it usually the combination
OK so
just put a lot of pictures
we just as want these days
in the challenge posed the clustering problem regarding the whole
number of clusters
what is
oh yes and no
but they basically generated based in
number distribution
so noise simple
let's on
we took the classic
which is what
you wouldn't believe how many papers find the status
and which is the most the status of
the is usually
so to
more this is one of the best
wisconsin state is which
this sort of different chemical properties of china
the trust
one of the support station
you to g OK so these problems to
the problem you can get
so talk about this is very difficult to analyse
it states that very difficult to discriminate is close to neutral
this one be
i think this is a very simple
OK this human speech is the official there's no
you have to
this to show that this criteria
he married traces the space to
i think the all numbers
these were results was be
compared to the other evidence so you
the me the best of
she she's just be
some statistics about
results are
just to chime with over
and as you can see this
and it's community only
so we have
there is that there is any but so far is
we need to go to the set
the price it
but can see
it depends on the use
do it for you
also satisfied with increasing difficulty
the challenge dataset you can see here so we can do it you have to
he became the performance
and the end
decency clearly like this
one of the ways of using the french revolution and somewhere here we'll to get
this is in data
section also use of search
in this case we use one hundred thousand population
what we get is actually quite time sure that so we actually with much fewer
sheet of paper just to work through and see that it does
i have an intuition for that
i don't have an institution of i one by tomorrow morning i'll let you know
any other questions and place the very place have questions by the way
OK so
we've got we put priors all the promises so we know what a bayesian mixture
of gaussians
we're interested in doing things like finding
posterior distributions of these parameters for example
or in
evaluating the model evidence
the problem now is that the models now become sufficiently complex that exact
bayesian inference is intractable
we can't simultaneously marginalized
over all of these latent variables and all of these parameters we can't do that
so we have to resort to some
one approximation
i think by now you're all experts on markov chain monte carlo methods
they have a lot of advantages i got a major advantage is that the only
approximation which one generally makes ice i suspect is really the computational one in other
words one is forced to resort to analytical approximations
but it's sometimes difficult to know
whether it's giving the right answer not and certainly computationally expensive
so i'm going to talk about variational inference which is quite different philosophy the idea
is to make some analytical approximations rather than
numerical ones
it has some some nice advantages i think one is that is applicable to much
larger scale problems
and in markov chain monte carlo seems to be and i think it also provides
a lot of insight you get a lot of mathematical insight into the structure of
the model in the form of the solution
and an approximation
so obviously we lose something in the process
but police were able to say a little bit about what it is that we've
lost what the effect of the approximation is going to be
variational inference i think could be of could refer to very large class of sort
of analytical approximation schemes
but also
it is sometimes called variational bayes in which case it applies to represent a rather
more restricted class of approximation schemes and that's the one that i'm going to discuss
and there are there are other variational like schemes such as expectation propagation
which are which are different and have different strengths and weaknesses time
and so we have chance to discuss those
and even within the variational framework partial focus on a particular special case of a
very interesting one
so i'm going to use the notation z now to denote all of the latent
variables in the parameters in the model so i apologize here switching station slightly but
so i give you a heads-up get confused server moment also i'm going to think
that is being everything them in the gas mixture modeling with latent variables and all
the parameters are all hidden variables in the model
a little bit later again all switch back to the special special case of the
gas in mixture with just represents the latent variables hopefully get confused if you feel
confused stop and ask
so let me remind you of this this slide that we had this morning because
this is the
this is it really this is this is variational inference in sort of one equation
so understanding this is quite important
so we call
the same as just in a slightly different context i fully bayesian context z is
the set of all
latent variables and parameters in our model
and recall that he wrote the log of the marginal probability of the data something
which show call the model evidence for reasons that will discuss later
that can be decomposed into the sum of two terms which are given by this
term in this and call this morning that by applying the product rule to this
joint distribution here we we prove this decomposition
we prove the decomposition holds for any choice of q and z
as long as q that is a valid probability distribution to be nonnegative and sum
or integrate to one
and again i use use integrals
but if these are discrete variables placed into my some
i said a little bit about the kullback leibler divergence on to go back and
look at the kullback leibler divergence
in a little bit more detail recall from this morning
but the
if we maximize the lower bound
or equivalently minimize the kullback leibler divergence with respect to q said we get is
true posterior qz would equal the true posterior distribution
so look at that in a bit more detail
again this was the picture that we had we decompose log
model evidence into classical badly
so if you have a closer look at the kullback leibler divergence
the kullback leibler divergence between
q and p
it is minus the integral
qz long
just writers pz this condition on the data so just look at the KL divergence
in general from moment
so that's the KL divergence
and the first property it has is that it nonnegative
so to see what's nonnegative we just need to recall the
the loss function is
convex functions
that z
lord z looks like this it's sort of
it always occurs in that direction
the definition of convexity is that
if i take two point on that curve and joined by straight line
and any points on the straight line
is always
below the curve except at the endpoints
so i've expressed that mathematically by saying that if i if i take these two
i think these two point
over a convex combination of sort of lambda this one minus lambda that there will
be a point on this
o point on the straight line
can generalize that slightly i can say that
if i have a bunch of nonnegative parameters lambda i which sum to one
a bit like policies if you like
then the someone i
lambda i times
this convex function which this case is z
long that i
is less than or equal to the log
the someone i lambda i said i
so that's just saying that the
the linear combination of the logs which is this point here
lies on or below
the log the linear combination which is this point here just by saying that the
convex function
and then if you allow me the liberty of replacing the sum by an integration
weighted by
probability density so nonnegative
function which integrates to one
then we have the following properties the intricate of q
log of p of q
minus that in general dz