and that strings code
of the original data
and the following notation is crucial i always use this so if i want ever
use notation l subsea of x to denote the number of bits needed to describe
x satisfying codex x using the cold water five bits
and this will be five for example if i use
something seven bits
it will be so right so this is not the culprit itself but only if
now let's go back to
so let's say something about probability distributions
on a countable sets
we know of course that the sum of outcomes of the probability of the out
of that outcome must be one
making it into weaker statements more equal in one
this holds for every probability distribution
so one way of thinking about that is that most outcomes must have very small
what do i mean by that
well you can have only two outcomes with probability at most one half
you can have only four outcomes with probability at most one fourth you can if
eight outcomes with probability at most one that's
because otherwise you don't some two
you don't sum to one
if you have more than eight outcomes with probability one eighty some to something larger
than one
so if you have let's say thousand twenty four outcomes than
almost all of them must have probability
it's more equal in one of thousand twenty four
so now
if we look at code
it turns out that a similar phenomenon occurs so suppose we want to encode sequences
of some length as binary sequences so in this special case we met binary sequences
to other binary sequences
now of course there are two sequences of length one only for sequences of length
two eight of length three etcetera
but there are totally and sequences of length n
so the fraction of sequences that can be compressed
two encoding of length one
is very small only two of the two to the sequences can be compressed and
encoding length one
only four can be compressed and encoding of length two
it's so in general the fraction that can be compressed by more than k bits
it's less than the number
of sequences with mines k bits defined by the number of sequences with n bits
it's two to the mines k so in this sense only very few symbols can
have small code length
so no that called in this talk
and in any MDL and general culture always uniquely decodable codes
so this means that if we have encoded something
we must always be able to decode the original data
from which the encoding k so you cannot have two different data sequences mapping to
the same code works
and therefore they can really be only two things
with codeword one
because you cannot meant different things
to the same code
so now i can also explain to you the reasoning of the very first light
said that if you have a random sequence
generated by tosses of a fair coin
but you cannot compress it with very high probability is suppose you have a sequence
of data sequence of length
in binary
if that is generated by fair coin tosses then the probability of each sequence will
be the same will be true to the mines
so then
the probability of the subset of size two to minus k
will be at most two to the mines k
right because all of the two to the minus and if you take two to
the a minor scale the the total probability of such a set will be to
to the minus k so therefore
the probability
that the actual sequence you get is in set which you can compress like a
bit more is at most two to the mines k
so this is the likelihood of
common in modelling the data
can you see hopefully
if i try to maximize this
try and make the data look most probable
by changing the way
consider sigma scratch should say
so if we look at maximizing this doing maximum likelihood with respect to the parameters
i maximize this i get the same result as least squares
and i can see that because by maximize this
the same as maximizing the logarithm of it
if i maximize the log for the against some of logs this
and look at this obviously gets rid of that and that give we minus
some of the minor squared error
so o
i minimize that
take out the minus sign
so maximize the herd is equal to least squares
under this assumption
all comes from the assumption of the gas in nine
so sort of framed equivalently now to the square
the interesting thing of course is the prior distribution
so as i said before
we had to specify prior
which sort of encapsulates all believe in what values parameter should take before we start
i might see there's a lot of thing there's a lot of the in how
specify the priors
and specifying prior sort of keep on this very important is a lot of expert
knowledge and
well actually we'll see
another example
and that we can assume
perfectly flat prior
in many cases
and still gets really powerful results
occam's razor actually will still work for you
even in cases where you seem if i prior
however in this case
for i would be appropriate because we're actually looking to find smoother functions
a conventional choice
it is zero mean gas
so instead of realizing lightweight as we did in the
all conventional treatment
we're actually going to make small weights more probable
so is specified
gas distribution over the weights that makes each weight individual weight
independent for each weight
but they share this parameter alpha
it is an inverse variance parameter
so from alpha very large
i made that way prior very tight around zero
land is large
the apriori very certain the weights small
settle on this very small value
gaston becomes very flat
and it's almost uniform and informative
so we sort of now
common analog
regularisation hyperparameter
in this
bayesian treatment
and we now have this inverse variance hyperparameter we need to consider
let's consider how we do inference
to finally bayes rule is
so we take that likelihood function
we take the prior we combine it
in bayes rule
gives the posterior distribution
over the parameters
conditioned on the data
so this is written this here because bayes rule often appears in this form
in bayesian calculation
typically the multiple of likelihood which is the probability of the data conditional some parameters
from the prior over the parameters
over normalizing factor
and the key point about the almighty factor is this term doesn't depend
the weights of the parameters w
so this is independent of
so the posterior here
because this is cast in this is captain
so happens that the posterior is also guessing
has mean given by
this term here
but also has
a measure of spread has a measure of uncertainty the covariance matrix
which is kind of expression of how to ensure the model is
the values of the parameters having seen the data
the idea is what will see practice
for example
is it the more data we see
intuitively as you'd expect
the smaller the narrow this covariance matrix get
well OK so far with this
can a little refresher slide on the rules of probability if anyone
there's acknowledged they would like to see it
right i mean to do that
this may be good pointers to remind
reminder refresh people about the basic rules of probability is all we need to know
but doing manipulations in bayesian inference or a lot of the problem
the following rule of probability
the two variables
the joint distribution of those variables
is the condition of one
on the other
time the model of the other
because this these two terms can be reversed the symmetric
and form
simply the
that's what the two variables
so typically a bayesian inference i
you know
my life
so that
what you do for you
the people
OK so
and let g it's my first time
thank you
i realized this morning that kat playing along
i was very impressed
although they did
on my hand like the one that might
but anyway
also see kingdom
and the way that
in fact i came from tokyo this time some i don't like it's not so
and i will talk about the brain computer interface thing mainly
i this is joint work with benjamin blankertz also from afar
and dublin core will show the team
goble is a medical doctor so
and as you will see it as the lecture goals there's a big component that
is physiology and
that will try to
delve into
and this is due to him
i was asked
to say something about myself and my group
but you know group intelligent data analysis group has
about forty people
so i'm i'm
currently professor at university of oxford put some and also directing eleven in front of
and founder of
and as you might know
has some constraints these constraints are that we have
we can do some basic research but we wanted to be applied at some point
and this means that we also
need to get
serious funding from industry
and just
so this means that we have some scientific and industrial corporations
so from the scientific profile that might be most interesting to you there is a
big part machine learning and
i mean
i don't know that was in berlin a while ago
quite well and alex in fact as well and we
studied some of the SVM business
so this means that we have
maybe it's too short
well i'm to show the new so really so
so we do work and SVM
but also on unsupervised learning
i would lead detection clustering
feature extraction
the whole
a wide range of things
on the other side
we also
working on blind source separation denoising methods
and the third topic is time series analysis
and maybe one thing that that is very characteristic for for my group is
is that we do data analysis
from the theory to really the practical
principle and to the product
but first this step before that and we like to pick stop there and if
you do some theory then then you realize that this theory typically doesn't work
you first iteration from
theory to algorithm two application so you have to go
around this article many times and this also requires a number of
people with different backgrounds and different abilities and also the willingness to talk to each
other and and go forward in this circle
and ICT one smiling in the back because he's one of them and
the chemistry background
OK so
i will mostly talk about brain computer interface thing in this series of lectures but
i was set
i asked to talk about independent component analysis as one part of the methods to
so if you do that and then on the kernel matrix you just classical multidimensional
scaling you get this visualization for the stick man data and this is really characteristic
of envy you get these little
may relate to the question early on euclidean
distances actually because you're forcing this thing
in isomap
this thing is constrained positive definite as i say the paper stanford i haven't fully understood yet claims that the
so this is the same as doing isomap with an additional constraint that these distances
must all be euclidean and actually embeddings look very similar apart from these little zigzag
you get which is not due to noise in the data because the data is
very noisy free
so i don't know about some so side effect by forcing the distances to be positive definite
you can't do the oil data because the dog doesn't fully connect all these thirty
neighbours are used and then this is
too slow
because as a semi definite programme
to do this maximization haven't talked about how you do the maximization
because a semi definite programme
on the constraints
and i didn't apply approximate version of the algorithm
but you do get
you know again reasonable visualization for thee
great vows data
and you know a makes that i find works generally quite well so that high
quality embeddings with no negative igon values but it's slower than all the other methods
so it's got if you don't like the negative igon values it's the sort of
thing to go forward he got smaller datasets
what i want and then present is inspired by maximum variance unfolding is a new
perspective actually unifies these things into one framework okay
so maximizing variances what's being done in order-disorder paul
they manifold apart so these image that
lawrence uses when he talks about this is if men pulling on a sort of
i think it is like a tangle of mattress
so you are pulling on the triangle mattress and then
where the springs are
you can't pull apart animosities just basically unraveling
and they do this by maximising the variance but in this case what i'm suggesting
is well let's do maximum entropy and the maximum variance
because entropy and variance are quite closely related the maximum entropy leads to probabilistic model
so i'm not gonna spend much time talking about maximum entropy
but they're each spectral approach turns out to approximate maximum entropy unfolding in some way
in fact locally linear embedding turns out to be
a pseudo likelihood maximization and this algorithm siu and then laplacian i can maps just
turned out to be i didn't bother setting the parameters
so all these methods can then be seen
from this probabilistic point-of-view
and i should say this is sort of research per say
but this is research that was entirely down to try and pull these methods together
into a unifying framework not for any other motivation
so maximum entropy
constraints you'll find distribution
um in maximum entropy it's a way of looking for distributions
subject constraints on the moments are those distributions
and the moments we're gonna use it
are the expected squared distances
so whereas before in maximum variance unfolding we just put up
these distance constraints in this is the difference between these things
can we not defining where the moments are coming from yet we just saying the
expectation that the distribution which is appeal whites could be a probabilistic model
why should be such that at the moment on the pier why give me the observed distances in the data
all the neighbors
we should pause at this point because it's kind crucial
and i know
time constraint for time i've got a little bit quicker than i really liked over the last little bit
so we can look for
such that's when we sample from the density the expected squared distance equals we observe squared distance
they can be written in terms of the covariance
of the density
it doesn't matter what the density is
it's always write a bill in terms of the covariance which is exactly the same
constraint we've seen before whether that's a covariance matrix a similarity matrix or anything else
you see the same theme emerging as we saw in canopy shimei so on forth
which is in effect
specifying we don't know what the covariance will be
maximum entropy
as defined by james is a really lovely sort framework where you just into include
the grande multipliers on the distance constraints
and she also need to include this thing is slightly annoying thing called the base
distribution in continuous case so this uh
this term
here on the left
it is called the bayes distribution
and is actually in this case is just a guassian
with a very large covariance spherical thing
tried ignoring you can actually take nothing for zero and make it disappear but things
aren't formally correct then but it still sort of works
but what you do have is the grande multipliers associated with all the distance constraint
services over the sum over jay
four all neighbors um
what changes each neighbour i and the sum over all i will grant multipliers on
every distance constraints and this is just the formal writing down here is the
the known solution for maximum entropy
that emerges from applying moment constraints so you can look this up
in maximum entropy textbooks
what's nice about again is you can rewrite this
in one of these forms with this is the matrix of all distances and this
is lambda these are the grande multipliers which is sparse in fact it's the same
as the adjacency matrix we had before
so you end up with a spherical term this term from the base distribution and
to neurons are close together in this grid
that corresponds to neurons that are allowed to turn on and turn off together
according to this penalty
or the often represent slightly rotated or translated edge detectors
so effectively what this penalty is done for us
is shown how we can learn invariant features
so normally with convolutional neural network
or with pooling system in computer vision we hardwire the assumption that we want to look for
translation invariance
we hardwired the invariance that we want to look for
but this algorithm actually grind through the data and figures out
translating edges
are very common
transformations that you'll find the data and does this without video
so the reason that this is possible
and not to get into
but roughly speaking
the fact that you see edges translating in the world
says that whenever i see an edge on the left an edge on the right
there are also lots of edges between
a and so what is algorithms able to figure out
that that particular structure of my data
is something i can
i can i can exploit
to build groups like this
so even though we have talked about it too much
you can make a fairly
small tweaks these algorithms and get them to learn these invariant features
so those kinds of tools
you can actually try to stack these things up
and learned high-level features
which we sort of would hope that after two or three levels we should get
really cool abstract high-level features like
parts and objects and so on
but it turns out this is pretty hard to do because if you don't know the task
through hard to figure out what information you should keep what information should get rid of
so it turns out to be pretty tough to do well in practice
because these high-level features just are trained
tune for exactly what you i want to do
but pretty cool trick
that turns out to work well is to use this unsupervised learning algorithms
to train up a set of features and then use that network as a starting point
for your supervised learning
so even though the features might not be perfect for task use them as starting portier supervised learning
which people also called supervised fine-tuning
actually get pretty darn good results
and in fact
and this is the sort of procedure that was responsible for a lot of this renewed interest
in deep learning is probably why hurdle heard about before
so the basic procedure for this
so we're going to train at each of these layers greedily like i said before
using an unsupervised algorithm
we're attack are little supervised classifier on top maybe we'll train by itself ahead of time
but then we're just going to go back to the back propagation algorithm we start with
a big at the beginning just train the whole neural network
starting from that location
and whether this actually matters
is a little bit open still
it turns out not always useful there are applications in the world
where this doesn't work so well it turns out something like
a large imagenet problem this can matter
and monot almost out of time here i
want to just wrap up by saying
even when you don't
care about supervised task
there is some evidence
that we can find high-level concepts like objects and so on
in these architectures some maybe familiar with this is so from quocle a team google
we actually find neurons in these high levels
that select for objects even though they have no idea what an object is
we have a another piece based on a different algorithm can do the same thing it's not just specific to
those methods
there are lots of other unsupervised learning criteria
that are worth talking about
so if you want to get to dig into the neural networks research
learn a lot about unsupervised learning
i've given you maybe three or four
penalty functions that work out for unsupervised learning problems
but there's a whole bunch of different ideas some of which is video for example
and finally you may be familiar with things like rbms dbms
this sort of here for reference
and case you guys want to roll through the slides online
i want to
you know
questions of the answers to the questions of what is the typical hypothesis will compete
to be the function of other variables and so on and you sort of yes
on the now
just just for this purpose
on you know learning are also about using the new hypothesis class of a little
bit actually did this quarter was talk about much more complicated hypothesis classes and washed
off the higher order functions as well
a little bit later
so for the learning problem then on how we we choose the parameters theta
so that a hypothesis h one make accurate predictions about holding
right so you know one reasonable thing to do
seems to be that we have a training set so and just on the training
set hypothesis one you know make some predictions
predictions of the housing prices of the the
prices of the houses in the training set so one thing we do is is
just try to me
on the predictions about running out of
accurate on the training set for a given
some features some correct process why you might want to make
let's see the square difference between the prediction of the algorithm and the actual price
titus ground to state someone to minimize the ground states are of the so of
squared error
between the predicted price and the actual price
and so
the reason we have m training examples of the sum from i was one of
my m training examples
price predicted on the ice holes in my training set on minus the you know
target variable minus actual price on the i th training example
on and by convention is the minimizing this
so most swiss differences just like the one half their which
which which will simplify some of them
some of them that we do that
so let me go ahead and to find j if they to be equal to
just the one
something like this one and on the number of training examples the value predicted by
my hypothesis minus the actual value
and so
what what do they say is minimized
as a function of the parameters of data this quantity j theta
i say to those who taken linear algebra classes on or maybe to those
basic statistics forces some of you may have seen things like these before
on in and c colony only squares regression order release queries on many of you
will not have seen this before i think some of you may have seen before
but either way regardless of whether it's seen before this keep going and for we
just to those you have seen before i say
eventually you actually showed that
this algorithm is a special case of a much broader class about obelisk going we
will get there eventually on
so i'm going to talk about the couple of different algorithms for performing that minimisation
over theta j of data for several unsolved about is a search algorithm where the
basic idea is we will start with some
the value of my parameter vector theta
maybe this may be initialized my parameter vector theta to be the vector of zeros
and he's right
right so right zero of an arrow on top to denote the vector of all
and then on
you keep changing
my friend to vector theta
to reduce
j a terrible bit until we hopefully end up at the minimum with respect to
j of theo
so she the
laptops they think know the big speed
so let me go ahead and
show you an animation of this first album
for minimizing j of data
which an album called gradient descent
here's the idea you see
on the display appliance on and the axes of the
the horizontal axes are the even if the decision might minimise j of data which
is represented by the by the height of this plot
so the surface represented function j theta
and the axes of the function of the inputs is function of the crown to
save zero the the one written down here
so here's the hungarian descent out of
choose some initial point could be you know better about zero randomly chosen points useless
we start from that point denoted by the by the cross by the by the
staff by the cost of
and now we should imagine that of
display actually shows the media landscape ranges of the holy parker something and this is
the three the shape of the hole in some part
on some actually actually standing physically at the position
that's part of that process
and on imagine can stand on that hole
right and look of free-thinking fantasy degrees around you and ask if i were to
take a small step was allowed me to go down them
imagine that this is physically whole you're standing there look around and ask if i
take a small step
well that's the direction of steepest descent they would take me down here as quickly
as possible
so first goal for our in the hot and i will be talking about how
to trace the flow of information through networks and what kind of applications algorithms one
can use for that that would be for the first hour and a half then
at ten o'clock we have half an hour coffee break and then thirty twelve
then the sort of the second part of the tutorial where we go
and try to understand the sort of go beyond
analysis of networks where always save the internal nodes indirect connections but start saying about
what if we started singing how people are friends with one another what if you
start reasoning about what is the strength of the connection how can you predict links
in social networks and so on so this is the sort of briefly the outline
of the tutorial so we're starting with the first part it should go away for
an hour and a half feel free to stop me for questions of things are
unclear and so on the other thing i should say
the slides for for what i'm talking about are available on this website
they don't link is also of the the tutorial web page from the conference site
and if you go to my my homepage and on the WBC sort of search
for social media analytics and there is a link to the victorian website where the
slides of the first part in the second part of the life of the first
part i think around ten megabytes so
be patient with the network
OK good thank you so
good morning again so this is the story along social media analytics and i be
sort of start so the first part we'll be about the flow of information in
online networks right so here is how how we can start thinking about right so
if you think about how information reaches us us as individuals like that sort of
they got the most ways how we how we get information one is sort of
through that's a personal influence of our social networks example of here hear stuff from
our friends and the other way how information reaches us is through the transmission by
by the media by the mainstream media the web and so on right now if
i could and the social media one of the definitions what social media is it
is medium is designed to be disseminated through social interaction right so what what is
now the sort of the
question here is how does information transmitted by the bite by the media interact with
the personal influence of these arising from our social networks
right and the idea here is the so-called there is tension between global effects of
something that mainstream media it's pushing information on top of us and the local effects
of coming from the from our social structure i thought only hear what our friends
so because social media is is disseminated through social interactions and lots of these in
social media is going on on the web right what this also makes a change
to the web is the web is no longer a static library the people sort
of passively browse but the web has become much more rights to the top of
the web is a place where people consuming create content right and the other thing
is they also interact with one another right here it's sort of list a long
list of different places venues on the web where people create where people interacting create
content right these are sort of on line four discussion forums blogs social networks to
return to his slide sharing side bookmark sharing site product review sites commenting sites and
so on the right and one of one of the important thing is that since
march two thousand ten the amount of litter facebook traffic is bigger than the book
right side of that is there is a lot a lot of people are a
lot of data being transmitted on or through the social the social media sites and
because any user can share and contribute content express opinions in creating links to other
users this means that sort of data mine opinions and behaviors of millions or billions
of users to gain again sort of actionable insights right to gain insights into human
behavior of marketing analytics product sentiment so right sort of these are now the applications
that that that we care about so here is really what how one can think
about social media analytics right so the idea is that we have these consumer generated
content sort of lots of the non edited not authenticated noisy and what we would
like to get it would like to get some kind of actionable intelligence right so
we'd like to get some some useful knowledge out of that that with that would
help us and what they will do next is i will go through a few
examples of what kind of applications or what what can one do with these kinds
of things right so so one of the one of the most common applications of
this is reputation and brand manager management right so you can start asking how what
are people saying about my brain and this is this goes under the name of
consumer brand analytics similar things you can do marketing communications were basically you can you
can start asking about where should i spend my budget what people thinking about my
products how how what what is the sentiment we my competitors how do i how
people perceive my products and so on right and the last thing is again sort
of mining product reviews because we can start asking her what are the product features
that the people like about my products or what the new requests they have right
so is my brother easy to use is it is it lightweight is it's certainly
does do they think do they get a good money for the bus and so
on that so these are sort of all the thing all kinds of things that
i can mine from the social media data basically from this traces of human activity
that is left on the web
another another moving on the right so another important application here citizen response right so
for example in for for politicians or four
it may of help you very much if you choose the wrong look any loop
is allowed
you then attach an open surface
two that
i penetrate
it is now the current
its surface
according to this
and the direction of rotation
it's free to you how you go around half
it's your choice
but that the fines and the sign of the
penetrating of the curve
of the of the current according to the right hand
so now we can for the first time
calculate the magnetic field inside a wire
because the current
using MP is long
i have a wire
as the radius capital are
and the current is coming to me
let's assume that the current is uniformly throughout the y
it has a uniform
current density
i would like to know what the magnetic field is everywhere cylindrical symmetry i wanna
know outside the wire
and i want know inside the y
let's first look at radius which is larger than or
so here we have the cross section of the wire
these are
the current i is going through this surface
i i have to choose a
closed class
since we have cylindrical symmetry
it is clear
that we will choose
a circle
this radius or
so we can be sure that the magnetic field strength
is the same everywhere because of reasons of symmetry
since the current
is coming towards me
and i am free to choose in which direction i'm going to march
i know that the magnetic field is in this direction so i might as well
so margin is our actions
sort of my dl
all in this direction i don't have to do that i could march on the
way around but if i march counterclockwise
and both terms left and right
of MP's law will be positive
i now have to attach a open surface to my path well this will be
the blackboard will be that open source
so now i apply MP's law
so i could be
times to by the or
the l and r and b are in the same direction so to trivial integral
that now is called
new zero times
i would not penetrates my surface uniquely determined
all these currents on this why comes to me
by surfaces
times i so b
equals museo
i divided by two pi r and that's the same result that we found last
when we applied
BIO and survive
but it's no surprise that you see this
now we have way
of finding
magnetic field also inside
so here we have now the y again cross section
current coming out of the blackboard
and now i want radius which is smaller than capital are
and of course my closed last again for reasons of symmetry
it's going to be a circle
with radius r
and my surface that i catch
the flat surface
so here i go
i'm compiling
he called new zero times
ah now i have to be careful
because now not to fall current i is now penetrating my surface
but it is only a fraction
that penetrates
the surface
and the fraction that penetrates the surface is now the largest grant
divided by kappa so are square
you see because the total current comes
capitol are but
i only have now
the circle was radius little or
so i lose one are here
so you get very different results you get now to the magnetic field
because new zero
and i
it is nonlinear in the are
divided by two pi
capitol are square
and this
grows linearly with are
whereas this falls off
one of our
and if you substitute in this equation are
because capital are
which then would be the
magnetic field right at the surface of the wire you find exactly the same result
they are becomes the capital are
if there are becomes the capital are
was one capital are you get
same result
so if you make a plot
of the magnetic field
as a function of little are
that looks like
like so so this is are
this is capital our
this is the magnetic field strength and we know that it is
gential e to the circles
it will be
straight line
and then here
it falls off as one of four
and the maximum value here
is the value that you find there if you substitute are
capital or
i will show you that we can using MP as well
come very close to calculating the magnetic field
inside what we call a solenoid is a solenoid
it's like a
current that goes around
in the spiral one loop after another
i want to remind you that if we had a look
nice currently
coming out of the blackboard here
and the current going into the blackboard
so it is circular why am but i only show you the cross section
i want to remind you that
the magnetic field as we discussed last time
would be clockwise here
the counterclockwise here
in the middle
it was like this
and then in between
it was like so
was sort of the magnetic field configuration
in the vicinity of a
which we have the current going
now imagine that you put another loop here
current again coming out of the blackboard going into the blackboard
and the three i want to deal with
the first one is whether this is a high-level or low-level language
basically says how close or you've got to the machine a low-level languages to call
this assembly program you're down at the level of your primitives are literally moving pieces
of data from one location in memory to another through a very simple operation
a high-level language the designers created a much richer set of primitive things
in high level language square root
might simply be primitive that you can use rather than you having to go over
and the trade offs between both
the second dimension
it's whether this is in general
verses are targeted language
by that i mean to the set of primitive support a broad range of applications
or is it really aimed
and a very specific set of applications that argue the matlab is basically a targeted
languages targeted matrices and vectors and things like that
and the third one i want to point out is whether this is an interpreted
verses are compiled language
but that basically says is the following an interpreted language you take what's called the
source called the thing you write
in may go through a simple check about but it basically goes to the interpreter
that thing inside the machine is going to control the flow going through each one
of these instructions
giving output
so the interpreters simply operating directly on your code at runtime
in a compiled language you have an intermediate step which you take the source code
it runs who is called the checker compiler both
and it creates what's called object code
that does two things one
it helps catch
bugs in your code
and secondly it often converted into one more efficient sequence of instructions
before you actually go off and run
this trade between both men interpreted language is often easier to debug because you can
still see rocco there but it's not always is fast compiled language is usually much
faster in terms of its execution
it is one of the things you may want to trade off
in the case of pi
a high-level language
i would argue
john degrees means basically general-purpose languages happens to be better suited for manipulating strings the
numbers for example but it's really a general purpose language
and it's a
should separate is an interpreted language
OK i
as a consequence is not as good at helping debug but it does let you
try run was things not as good at catching some things
before you run it is easier sometimes and debugging as you go on the fly
OK so what is python look like
in order to talk about life on
do it
we need to talk about how to write things apart again let me back up
slightly and set the stage
our goal
to build recipes
there going be great chefs by the time you don't here
our goal is to take
problems and break them down into these computational steps the sequence of instructions that allow
to capture that process
to do that we need to describe
but only one of the primitives but how do we capture things legally in that
and interact with the computer and so for that we need language
we're about to start talking about the elements of the language but to do that
we also need to separate out one last piece of distinction
just like with the natural language going to separate out syntax versus semantics
so what's syntax syntax basically says
what are the legal expressions
in this language
my handwriting approaches and there's there's an english sequence of words
it's not syntactically correct right
it's never been there and you're sick was announced same thing in our languages we
have to describe how do you put together legally formed expressions
and as we had contracts to the language going to talk about that
the second thing we want to talk about very briefly as we go along
is the semantics of the language and here we're going to break two pieces static
semantics and full semantics
static semantics basically say is
which programs
are meaningful
which expressions makes sense
is an english sentence
it syntactically correct
i am phrase verb noun phrase
i'm not certain it's meaningful unless you are in the habit of giving your furniture
personal names
what's the point again you can have things that are syntactically legal but not semantically
meaningful and static semantics is going to be a way of helping us decide what
expressions what pieces of code actually have real meaning to it
the last piece of it is
in addition to having static semantics
we have
full semantics
what does the programming
four different way what's going to happen
when i run it
it's the meaning of the expression that's what you want you want to know what's
the meaning of this piece of code when i run what's going to happen that's
what i want to build
the reason for pulling this out is what you want to see
is that in most languages and certainly in pi fun
we get lots of help here
python comes built-in with something that will check your static so yes your syntax for
in fact is the sidebar if you turn in the problem set
it is not syntactically correct there's a simple button you push
i will check your syntax if you turn the program not syntactically correct is give
you zero
as i said you didn't even take the time to make sure the syntax to
correct the system will help you find
in python little find i think one but at the time john finds one syntax
error time so you have to be a little patient do but you can check
the syntax
his is right
you see that we get some help here
on the static semantics unknown example in the second
meaning that the system in some languages are better than others on it but it
will try and help you catch
some things that are
semantically correct statically
in the case of pi founded doesn't i think all around time look you can
join i think there's no
there's no
every time jackson
so i
there is some OK
most of them i think they are primarily can't run time and that's a little
bit of a pain because you don't seem to be going run the code there
are some are going to see an example of the kind of secondary find which
you do get some help there
the problem is
things that you catch here
are actually
police were box
easy to spot
you can run the program
with them there's not going to get weird answers
not everything is going to get caught
static semantics checking some things are going slide through and that's actually a boy
the problem
because it says your program will still give you a value
what can we say about this transformed table well
first of all the size of the table is unchanged
by design we haven't allowed any rose disappear because if if shifting down would have
led to arrive that was already there
we didn't do it
so we've got the same number of rows
whenever secondly the VC dimension
because increase
OK so whenever we got
when we got transformed table shattering some subset
of x one to xn
the original table must have shown some subset share the same subset
and you can
you can see that
by thinking about what happens
if we left with after
after shifting in particular column
right if we're left with a shattered set
so so here we can see x four and x five right we have minus
minus minus plus plus minus plus plus
OK if after shifting this column we're left with a shattered set
then we must have started with a shattered set that's you can see that by
considering what we have a plus plus here
we didn't shifted and all minus
OK and so we must have the identical wrote
below that in the table
right and so
you know we've got a plus
everything and minus everything so we've got a shattered set before we shifted that right
OK so so shifting
if we have a shared that after shifted we must have had one before
so we might decrease the VC dimension that we can increase it above its original
value which was no more than
OK so so the other property i mentioned already that we've got this close below
property once we don't wish shifting every class that's in the table if we change
it minus we get another of the table
well this is probably the makes counting really easy
OK we know we have an increase the VC dimension
then a new table
we've got the same number of rows but now we can count the number of
OK because every row has no more than the ones
why is that the VC dimension is no more than d
so we can shatter set of size d
suppose we had a row
it had more than the ones in that we've got everything below the right
right so those d ones
that those that set of ones
right indicates is appointed to a shattered set by find two what two plus one
that indicates the next that the corresponding x is x four x five
former shattered set because i've got everything below these two clusters so i got the
two q
OK so i can't possibly have
a row with more than the ones because the VC dimension is no more than
OK so how many rows can i have that have
no more than the ones
right when i've got everything below
well just many rose can have that no more than the ones was just the
up to the avengers i n two zero number of ways of choosing a row
with zero ones with one one with all the way up to d once that's
the number that's not upperbound on the number of rows
and the even here is
these are of about on the
on the VC dimension
OK so the number rose to synthesize the tables and change the number of rows
in the original table
it is no bigger than
then this this summer
with the VC and you can come up with an example i mean i i
and going to present to you
the main speaker of today
it is professor mubarak shah is
full professor at the university of central florida
and the distinguished scientists in computer vision particularly he worked a lot on video analysis
he is a fellow of simply SPI
and he has received many awards here in full favor of words that he received
so i will not list of
and for probably more important is that he has been
associate editor of people body
transactions on family is currently associated ACM computing surveys
and the editor-in-chief of machine vision and applications
professor chen
we use today a task which is feasible crowned survey and this is like
hydro dynamics so challenging talk
thank you
thank you very much for the introduction
place to be here
i'm not going to show you these pictures of me when i was a young
girl has made sure yesterday i was thinking about it but
i don't find them in in most dangerous so one thing you will notice that
you know
i can be compared to
ninety five students in the last year so that's kind of proportion OK so i'm
going to talk about the visual surveillance
in crowds
and there's a bunch say this is going to be talking in computer vision which
is called ventricles multimedia and in particular the talk about
video analysis and so
this is one of the most active in computer vision given to you
these are the main steps so first you want to do that
just interest and you want to
training these objects from for free and then you want to many countries objects in
their car power some basic and so on and anyone you want to look at
the of these objects actions that users and there's a lot of work in computer
vision from or through a lot of a lot of work
so for example in tracking you can train
one point on
apart like
images or you can take a bounding box where you look at the
it's change from previous frame and the background is change from frame to frame and
you can get their properties of the regions and so are you can train the
contour of objects which gives you much more information about the articulation of objects and
this is the case where actually the camera is moving similar example of the odometry
many tricks these cases next thing here is that you can shake actually the choice
of the person
and get to see
each of that now given all that then you can do that in the example
meeting in our and the object star
you know somebody is making us and share and somebody can push the sky away
simple events which are based on the occasion tracking information can do that also trajectories
you can get the trajectories by these and get some properties of that and is
what we construct the phase space of its trajectory cuties chaotic invariants
there's a wonderful writer mathematics but we in physics come things almost in the opposite
extreme you see i didn't show you a single table
i didn't make a single maximum likelihood estimate MLE or anything of that sort instead
we do things primarily using plots on the assumption that if we can see with
our eye it probably doesn't really exist just some artifact of the computer algorithm which
happened to be to be using
and and and in the case of economics the statistics community has been very successful
analyzing vast quantities of data but some of these properties and we've pulled out by
application to economics of ideas that work in statistical physics which is first and foremost
to analyse huge amounts of data if we're trying to find rare events and secondly
to look at those data i in such a fashion that we're not a perturbed
by strange properties such as crossing over from one distribution in the centre to another
distribution in the tail something that's hardly repugnant
too many decent humans particularly if there are mathematicians
so i think this is important take-home message and the most important take-home lesson of
this talk for me this is that one should start always with the simplest model
that comes to mind for example random walk in the case of both the part
of the problem and the stock price fluctuation problem but then immediately tried to build
in a systematic corrections to that in order to
c to to reproduce the data in the case of the part problem those corrections
have been built in and the model called the self avoiding random walk is perfectly
successful in describing to palmer's below four dimensions whereas the random walk model is not
and the case of finance problem we not yet found such a model and some
of you in this audience would like to work on that problem in particular if
you you want to come to boston a working with open arms thank you for
your attention
what the significance is not known at all
as of the same is true here i have no idea the significance of the
exponent minus three over the
this is a little embarrassing but again gets empirical fact after we don't have understanding
of the exponents occurrences simple physical laws like coulombs law
that's we particle physicist something else don't understand
so that's roughly where we are in economics can relate these exponent one to the
other can relate exponent of let's start price fluctuations exponent of five fluctuations of time
interval between trains and so forth but we don't really have better understanding of where
they come from that and probably never will certainly don't report from any understanding of
subject parameters that describe the system
or earthquakes
but we're so much is that the expert in the good repair laws not minus
three is for stocks
earthquakes but instead is roughly minus one million china knows better than i
we don't understand what it's like this one
the question
it's about that we know all of
but what is going to is weight
you can
more precisely in this one
one of first we need microscopic all
his friend is a great body of knowledge inspired primarily by kenneth g wilson
he was awarded the nobel prize for this in the early eighties
and that work involved building on the idea
the random walk
does not describe the real palmer
at all below four dimensions
and that's because the random walk intersect itself below four dimensions
building on that simple simple geometric idea wilson was able to
make a theory of exponent which i should describe cancer professor strikers question that you've
expert gave numerical values for exponent and but a real intuition for why they are
with the idea this few years no
but it certainly needs to explain why some bigger than others
susceptibility expert prevents this and so forth but i have the feeling that there is
one additional thing
in addition to wilson's work which is the concept it is important to expose students
who may not be familiar with which goes by very pretentious name of universality
and this is the idea that all
interact in complex systems comprise the view on the matter what they are
can be partitioned into a finite number
or a small number of classes usually called universality classes and the definition of the
classes that all the systems in that class
have numerically the same values of the so very dramatic example of that is the
universality class for simple one-dimensional space so called i see these experiments that class encompasses
not only
systems like flu
right described
the main idea that of fluid is model but also binary mixtures of binary alloys
and the number of all the complicated systems and similar two-dimensional order parameters like helium
are describe different universality class three three-dimensional another so
so so that this these two concepts the concept of renormalisation group universality together give
us about the state of understanding that we have in critical point phenomena present
i don't think that they has increased dramatically
in recent years
what is needed is in my opinion the scots proprietary question is somewhat analogous calculation
we need to consider all sorts who can make the model
for something that we saw
in way for her defects the facts
that is very very light that's a model but a bit more complex because interactions
so anyway so here's a little methodology to check yourself so as i mentioned the
reason this is so important
is because this is in practice the thing that you
most of the time you don't just use the data structure as given
if you take a data structure say i my own operations i one layer this
so really the methodology and what i do as we go along as well as
of order statistics trees
to illustrate the methodology
course steps
OK the first is
we choose
an underlying data structure
which in the case of order statistics trees was one
a red black tree
the second thing we do
is we figure out what additional information
we wish to maintain in that data structure
which in this case is
it's the
subtree sizes
subtree sizes what we keep for this one
and you know what we do is we could make
mistakes right because it always keep the rank
we start playing with discovery
well can do that just because really slowly
take some creativity to figure out what's the information is going to be able to
we're going to be of also to maintain the other
other properties that you want
there's that is verify
the information
can be maintained
for the modifying operations on the data structure
and so
in this case for
for a red black tree for OS trees
we were the modifying operations were insert and delete
and of course we had to make sure we dealt with rotations care
because rotations are part of that
we could break it down into the tree and search tree delete and rotations and
once we've done that everything was fine
we didn't for this particular problem have to worry about color changes
but that's another thing that under some things
OK you might have to worry about
OK for some reason the
the color difference
usually that doesn't make a difference
the fourth step is to develop new operations
there's only use the intro
you have now stored
and this was worse
o rank which give but which is there and which also a nice little puzzle
to figure out yourself how you would feel that was right
now hard code
so this is actually this methodology is not actually the way you do this
as one of these things where you know
this is more like a checklist because
you know
check is see whether or not you got some of you know when actually doing
this may be developed in new operations first
keep in mind the new operations way of verifying the information you can the storing
can be here maybe you're then go back and change this is sort through it
this is more checklist that when you're done
this is how you write it up
OK this is how you say
i document that we've done is in fact a good thing ever checklist say here's
my underlying data structure
here's the additional information i need to see i can still
support the modifying operations that this structure used to have an now here my new
operations and c
he with those are
this is really a checklist
not a prescription
the order in which you do things
you must do all these steps
not necessarily in this work
OK so this is a guide for your documentation so when we ask the augmented
data structure generally were asking you to tell us what the four steps are to
help organize things and also help make sure you don't forget some step along the
OK so i think people who added the information and determine the
roll outs
and monte carlo search as when used you want to value state in u
will sample many many games and as a solution to the famous curse of dimensionality
so let's look at that little bit
the initial thesis is just the power sample based search is under appreciated
tree search
roll outs you can you can get you can work with simulators and find out
about the values of states we can do without a model that's what call reinforcement
learning because you if if you can work with samples and you actually need them
all world you can just
two things and get samples from the world itself
this scales really nicely with computation and the accuracy is often unaffected by this size
in the space so this is where getting the curse of dimensionality so look at
that little bit more the quality of sample based estimates
can be independent of the size of the state space often they will depend on
the number of samples on this i think is one of the key sources of
of power
so the example really prominent now is roll outs and monte carlo search in computer
so in computer go our state space is effectively infinite
but it doesn't matter
it doesn't matter so if you want to do some if you come to position
and you
two bunch of sample games from that position so senior policy
and you have a single position interest you can play games from that position using
a policy
we call those rollouts
and so if you want to get even though the value that state in one
percent you could just have two thousand rollouts
and it doesn't really matter how big the state space is going on within one
percent because the outcomes are zeros or ones were lost if you just average the
outcomes you can you'll get high quality result we get independent of the state
so here are some slides are still from the coulomb was one of the originators
of monte carlo
research in
computer go
so here suggests the ideas of place in a state of interest and we can
consider possible successors and from each one we can do a bunch of simulations we
actually play out sample games and a lot of research goes into
what policy should be used in the sample game because you want to be quick
and you want to have it as some of the properties but you can actually
do very good if you actually in computer go and surprisingly many games many problems
if you just do random o
if you just two lots of random was all legal moves pick from the random
go to your opponent of the his legal was picked from the random and you
just play out you actually even that works works pretty well in national methods they
use not
tremendously more sophisticated because they want to be able to make the samples very efficiently
so then having done sample some then we win some them will be losers and
then this one is winning nine times out of ten which is better than the
others then that might be the action you pick
and can this a little bit further you can use them user statistics instead of
doing random
instead of fame considering all possible moves equally you favour the ones that are doing
better than the children and you develop the tree rather than just the simple rule
and this has revolutionized the game go you may have heard you may have heard
people talk about goal is like an impossible problem right computers can play chess but
they can't really
think like humans and they can they can solve goes store more complex and spatial
it turns out that's not true we just didn't have the right method you with
monte carlo tree search last few years has revolutionized the field of computer go
this is a rough diagram the situation if we look at scale
the program's first versus time for many years things were going up slowly these are
all really poor
players is really like you and me or something
and this you know is actually easy not too difficult to get better than really
poor players but it was things were really leveling off and people were very
discouraged or
not pessimistic about making getting anywhere and then in about
like two thousand four people started sample based search methods and and first i got
up to par and then things just kept me skip it better and better and
we can say that even this is nineteen by nineteen gulf rule full-bore go
the we have master level players
it's it's it's very striking change and it's really all these two different ways search
you can can spread your search around differently when you samples as opposed to traditional
thank you
questions reactions good
so this thing
it's partly
and extrapolation
well it is an extrapolation no this scales really well search so just with more
is law
we have a good idea about what the slope is so i mean there's no
slide that that david silver who i got this information from has where we just
take one is the top programs like mogo fuego
and we vary the amount of computer power thereafter how many samples per move
and if you tell it there's there's a clear relationship you have more more more
my computer power more some more rollouts performances just goes up goes up and goes
up in
and it looks pretty much like
the world champion
human is is
and the cosine of five point seven degrees
is one
four physicist at least
so therefore
for all systems of IQ is not absurdly low
you can say that q one
people's minus q max
output here we go
but it's an extremely good approximation
so therefore
my solution here
you can now be changed
by simply replacing
the q one
and through it should be in approximately
but the approximation
is extremely close
the pencil q
if not you want to plant this
you can of course something completely similar to what you have here
that you do not and up zero
the q is not zero but it's offset by this qx
if this is the
if this is zero
and this is qx
which is where ultimately
the charge will be if you wait long enough
then to plot now this
will then give me a group like this
very careful the period
is uniquely determined to area does not change
that's determined by that omega
two pi divided by this omega is the period
so you're going to get you started with q zero
and you see
if you wait long enough you end up with q max
it is this one
whereas in the case of the spring if you wait long enough
you end up with nothing x equals zero
and this is something
that i can
demonstrate to you
in very
very nice way i must say i find is one of the most
intriguing demonstrations
instead of having a battery
and throw better in which case you would only
for an extremely short amount of time
for the amount of time which is roughly
through divided by gamma
which may only be many seconds you would see
this thing
but we want to give you more than a few milliseconds
and therefore what we do
replace the battery
seventy seconds
constant voltage
and we repeat that
and every time
we show you this portion
so you will see it on the tectonics
we train with every time it comes up here and then it comes up here
and you will see that
this will be staring you in the face
i'm going to give you the values that i will be using so you can
digest that home exactly
what you are going to see
and what all the constants are in this problem
we are
it's going to be fifty ohms
it's going to be fifty
many at least
ten to the minus three
so that tells me that got my
is one thousand is are over l
that tells me that
two divided by got my which is the one of e decay time
it is then too seconds
it's going to be o point o six
micro for
that would give you a
omega zero if you interested in only garcia i never have a good feeling for
omega guys i like
it's much better but if you are interested in omega zero
which is one over the square root
that would be eighteen point three times ten two two thirds
and that is radians per second
the frequency in hertz
which is two pi lower is then twenty nine
o six hundred
so now you have also q
which is omega zero divided by gamma
and that q
is no eighteen point three
and that means q divided by pi
which is the
the problem i called
q divided by pi which is
the number of oscillations that you have to wait
for this function to go down by a factor of the men we did that
with the pendulum
that is now
about five point eight
so we're going to take a look at the kind of like that
and then we go into in the czech
and two or three
so let's go again because this is tricky
so let's look at this but here the first thing you should look at is
that if there an the tail to tail or head to tail
immediately these graph here has an observer tail to tail node
for this
so this is what we need
this is block
because you have these sorts of
these that look now let's assume that we didn't have because of for efficiency
i assume that you have full service
now these back here
it's not a black and white
any observation
so we can only be blocked if there is a had no
which is not observed in which is not observed
these are not observed and should not so
we assume that c not
so in that case it will people
you see is not well
ATC is not what
eight soon
there is only one
to be considered
which is this guy in the middle
you want to nodes in the middle of the that the ones in the in
the end you consider
because they only have one which once head back
and these is known for these that here there is no this one
which type of node is this one for this
page head to tail
forty four this sparsity block
i had to tails models need to be observed
is this absurd
sort of work
from a to b
depend on the path of particle which
which that
so you have one had here
yes you have one from it to be
what's the questions
with respect to that that's thing with respect to this that here
noel e
his head tail
with respect to these that
note is head to head
so it is with respect to the back
so this is something new to
thinking about after the class
now we
come to the final concept
which is the cause
concept of the separation and i want to see the condition part the rules
we just say
that is a set of nodes if i have here
the set of old
is the
this is used to be
a wonderful wonderful
i say that
a and b
are separated by c
separated because of direct separation because this the
that's why we it
see that in your disappointed by c
but the feeling that there always is tangent to the curve because this curve is
trajectory is always supposed to be going in the direction
given by the way i feel that there
it follow
a trajectory means it is always
to the field that there and therefore always perpendicular
the the normal vector
it's equal to this is zero
died in is always zero
everywhere on the curve that it has be here
there is no flux of this field across the curve because the field is always
in the same direction as the curve
never perpendicular to it has no component perpendicular to
now let's do it the hard way let's use green's theorem
so by green's theorem says that the flux
across c
should be able to the double integral over the region of one of the divergence
of that
it's like grouses theorem in two dimensions this version of it
so the divergence of and that's the function
i double integrated over the regions and then that's the XTY relaxing a because you
might want to do in polar coordinates
and the problems that you certainly will want to do it in public or
i think
right how much is that
well we haven't yet use the hypothesis
well we don't set up the problem now the hypothesis was
the divergence is never zero anywhere in the
therefore the divergence is never zero anywhere in are
what i say is the divergence is either greater than zero
in are
less than zero
everywhere in our
but it cannot be sometimes europe posit and sometimes negative why not in other words
i say
it's not possible the divergence here is one here minus two
that's not possible
because if i draw a line from this point on
along that line the divergence would start positive
and up negative and therefore have to be zero sometime in between
because it's a continuous function
it's a continuous function i'm assuming that therefore sometimes positive sometimes negative has to be
zero in between
you can get continuously from plus one to minus two with that i think is
so the reason for this is since
since the divergence is
never zero
in or
therefore must always stay positive are always the negative
now if it always stays positive
the conclusion is
if is always positive then this double integral must be positive for this integral is
this double integrals
is either
greater than zero that's the divergence is always positive or
it's less than zero if the divergence is always negative but the one thing it
cannot be is not
well so the left hand side agrees theorem is supposed to be true
we've got to start with the same as the bedrock
eighteen o two would crumble without that so must be true
one way of calculating the left hand side is zero
we calculate the right hand side is not zero that's called the contradiction
with the contradiction arises from a contradiction arises from the fact that i suppose that
there were was closed trajectory in that region
so the conclusion is that cannot be closed trajectory that region because it leads to
a contradiction degrees here
let me see if i can give you some of the arguments for the other
well let let's at least eight other
criteria i want to you
suppose for example we use the
this is the next prime equals
the set limit cycles
there's that a limit cycles
but then
we calculate the divergence of the vector field
two x from the top
function the partial with respect to access to x the portion with the second function
with respect to y is negative to y
well that certainly can be zero in fact this is zero
along the entire line x equals y
it's divergence is zero here
along the whole line
so the best i could conclude was
i could conclude that there is no limit cycle like this
none is no limit cycle like this
there's nothing
and there is a whole
there's a whole suite of area is basically a loop of areas are connected in
the brain areas in the prefrontal cortex areas in the elements each of them if
you wish and you lose this habitual behavior so there seems to be a whole
group of areas that are involved in visual learning
on the other hand is another loop another host various
another group of various
the dorsal medial striatum in various there
related to its as a slightly different part of the strait where if you lesion
you get the opposite you get animals are always habitual right from the very beginning
this is the best part of it in the world because these are very both
of them are very well but the idea is the regular behaviour here after short
is this the difference between the developed and undeveloped
and there is no difference
after relation in the past year or so we go straight come in other experiments
these two words high is this one this experiment is
bad choice on my part but there are many experiments showing this
so the idea is
there's a whole
loop in the brain that is responsible for goal directed learning and if that doesn't
exist from the very beginning animals are habitual
or they don't show sensitivity to devaluation
right from the beginning of training
so what does all this mean
on one hand we have learned one thing we've learned the same action that we
look at we see the rat leverpressing
it can arise from two psychologically dissociable pathways so the fact that these leverpressing doesn't
tell us why he's leverpressing
until we test with evaluation we can see that he might be leverpressing in called
directed way
dependent on outcome representation putting that together with the contingencies or you may be pressing
in habitual way just because all this is the lover i press lovers
now because this slavers gonna give me food
same as tried right get into this car i get to the disjunction i take
the right to see stimulus response
that's the habitual and goal directed i'm going home so i take a right
and to complement this association the psychological dissociation there's also the lesions suggest that there
are too narrowly dissociable
parallel systems in the brain that support each type of this behaviour of behaviour and
they can support any stage of training if the other what isn't there the the
second one can if one is in their second one takes over
so what we asked here this is the study done by
my colleague nathaniel daw
myself peter that was can reinforcement learning help us make any sense
of this
behavioral mass
and this led us to think about reinforcement learning and the two main strategies in
reinforcement learning model based model free
so think of the task like this
set of leverpressing it's hard to draw the leverpressing MDP although it
it's not that difficult but it's easier to draw an MDP four
four so the right here is navigating the maze and tries to get the maximum
reward has to choose
what to go left or right the reward this rat-like moses cheese that's why worth
compared to carrots in water
and we know that there are two ways to solve this problem the model based
one is learned the map of the task learn the contingency plan the transition state
one take left you get to stay two groups
this should have been zero one two
and the values of the rewards and then
if you have these transitions this reward function you can use
your favourite model based methods
dynamic programming or any other method of look ahead of planning
and figure out what is the value of taking the left here and taking the
right here it's taking left to say
taking right so taking left the value before taking right the value would be too
so far the rest should
go left
and importantly this is
computed on the fly so the dynamic programming problem has to be solved on the
fly which means this computationally costly it can take a while especially if the maze
is bigger
but it's also flexible
and immediately sensitive to change because if the rat learns that
the reward function here has change it will immediately affect
the computed value of taking left in state
in the initial state here
so this is a model based reinforcement learning
on the other hand we can solve the same exact task with model free reinforcement
the so it
we ran the shape context things that i mentioned yesterday around them because high dimensional
description histogram based description
the shape
and then we vector quantized in that space
to get an output signal that we can use the advantages of this is that
when you extract silhouettes in real images you get sets attacked sometimes extraction method doesn't
work so pieces of the model missing
but if you only look locally this got past model right
and that can be signal that you can use to do the regression correctly
so this video to
so you can see also silhouette extraction is by no means perfect we still reasonably
convincing will commission from that
just ring is just the alignment process for the
and there is no space and
OK now you can also do this
what's images rather than so it's in there we use these guinness histogram of oriented
gradient descriptors to get a nice high dimensional representation
we had a nice novel
statements which is that if you do this thing and you've got for example tree
or pole or not sure if something in the background you get these spurious edges
and the model
which tend to study the regressor
so what we did to reduce that is that we learned anomaly to make matrix
of the dossier
i don't know if you guys know one the next matrix factorisation is OK so
you can think of about this is
but with the match these have to be both
make both sides have positive
so the positivity constraints so it doesn't give you orthogonal matrices out but it does
give you a nonnegative decomposition of the signal so all the basis vectors have two
positive and the coefficients positive so things can add
and what that means is that if you get all stuff that happens
only occasionally
the were basis vector devoted to it
so there's nothing that can add up to that thing and they forget suppressed from
it's only the things that happen consistently
they give basis vectors and therefore i think they will get non negative coefficients in
the final model
that's why that works with it
getting a lot of it yesterday
so we added artificial class here just to show the models quite resistant crops
because it's not perfect but it's it's at least a reasonable first approximation
on two trying to learn priors for human motion so humans too
all sorts of strange motions
even walking is an incredibly complicated motions
and if you want to capture that any kind of
system we want to use it to predict the motion person tracking
or to to do motion capture is made the movement in three d
you basically down to doing semantic because there's no other way to to to capture
the context the statistics
so this was an interesting model that came up fairly recently
he uses what's called casting process latent variable models
so you digestive processes that you to guessing process processes just
kind of regression methods
that gives you a probabilistic estimate
it's not for
latent variable models the model that has some hidden variables and
the way this works
is that it learns
the hidden variable model
so it's the kind of dimensionality reduction
in this reduced dimensional space is learned probability distribution for the kinds of motions kinds
of positions and movements that the first doing this reduced dimensional representation
and then to go to the high dimensional representation given by the visual signals uses
guassian process again you've got
a probabilistic model
both models fully probabilistic which gives you full probabilistic
characterisation the possible motions in high dimensional space in terms of two
relatively simple components these this simple because low dimensional and the gas prices you kind
of you know what the statistics are so
you kind of can control that side of things
so does this by a kind of expectation maximisation or optimisation procedure
the that
finds a good
low dimensional space in good positions in that space
nodes and you and can also so you see how to build up there
and then
the same time we can measure
the speed of sound
the only reason why we make this and
is that
as i move it
and bring the my
first and note
i can make sure that the link is just a resonance
and so that's just my beginning
to make sure that the node is as close to zero as possible can be
so if we know
get the
image up there
and i think we're going to get light situation
like this
going to
one of the sound
it is the sound
i can turn up the volume so you can use that
the school connected
are you of course thank you
i didn't connect the microphone as a
it's the first movie of twenty four nineteen ninety nine the better so let's first
moving around two in the first thing to note
born it's nothing left anymore
and now i'm going to change l
i think this is
i cannot do much better
so however it is not very important
i said al so that i think the system is that resonance
in a moment you can calculate if you know how many nodes are
i'm going to search for
you see and i notified we see that i'm moving it now i'm moving it
further that way
you get to another node
see that wonderful
i going into it and i know
here to another node
this node i'm going to measure the position
the rule in there
and the ruler
the position of the mind
and this one is fifty two point eight
o fifty
o point eight centimetres
is this position is somewhere and i can put market for to help you very
my accuracy is one millimeter and this is a very crude way
and i'm going to pull it back
because you and i know
here it is a very
no it's number one
no number two
no number three
no number
and and we'll all
now the reading in nineteen
four point three
time twenty four
o point three centimetres
by subtracting the five
twenty eight point five centimetres
this is film lab
and i know this really two i would say to women
certainly no worse than the disease and there is no uncertainty for sure in the
you can get your life back so i can now
calculate what the velocity of sound is for that is twenty eight point five
i divided by two
give me forty point two five
centimetres this was just
rough number that i gave you
now i multiply that
by the frequency twenty four or nine
and then i find three hundred and forty three
so v
three hundred and forty three
i would say plus or minus maybe two
meters per second
we measure the speed of sound
high degree of accuracy
and of course at the same time you've seen
it's wonderful
resonance normal mode behaviour
where you see them the nodes and i nodes
in this case
of pressure earlier you saw of year in terms of transverse motion now you've seen
them in terms of
longitudinal motion
there is
and the
in a
travelling wave