it was indicated have just
sixty more
and three of them are
twenty five thousand
and nowadays you give this
impressive number of dental
there are two important
things in fact
on the bus on the
one hand
this calculation started the of using computers recruitment zeros
if it was done by children would be done by somebody else so it's not the main contribution
what is important
is the methods introduced by children
and this message
was used
no consequent calculations
nobody else was able to invent anything but
so this message is
and actually use
up be
i spoke about
two papers
published by
student about their
remains that the function
repayments this talk i added a lot of papers about student
and practically all of them say them for the same
the legacy of q numbers it consisted of a number of unpublished manuscripts
a number of that no other mathematicians
and this manuscript sent letters
and what ideas
but was published
not just these two papers
but this is not
is so
there is a sort of labor
there he did this that one function
it means that the function
but somehow
this paper
remains unknown numbers
they don't cite it
they don't know why
maybe they don't appreciate the result obtained by consist paper
or maybe they simply don't know the paper
because it is difficult to guess
from the title of the paper
the paper was titled
system of logic based on ordinals
and text it was
student dissertation
done in princeton
section city
and his dissipation
because the title
number statistical science
give a formal definition
what you understand by
numbers that it because you
but numbers that because here we show them in a series of the form
i think the effect vanishes for infinitely many natural numbers x
they sit there is there a primitive recursive function
okay she here's a footnote
i believe
there is no generally accepted meaning for this storm
numbers that considered
but it should be noticed
that we are using it
in that other restricted sense
then he gives
an equivalent definition
an alternative form for number-theoretic theorems
for each natural number x
there exists a natural number right
such that f of x
when issues
where f of x and it's been omitted because
so numbers cities may
we not that if i decide the finish and
of what they're doing
so the notion of primitive recursive function used in the definition
but the same class of systems can be defined
in a more arithmetic
we can consider the
well known as hierarchy
the public
and medical formulas
they're all quantifiers are bounded
and then recursively constructed the following levels
to use a particular vocabulary for relations objects and so on in
RDF graph you can define vocabulary in RDF schema you could not this figure vocabulary
in a hierarchy
OK so you can talk about persons you can talk about different types of persons
persons that was readers and relationships between these two
so the authors communicate to reader so this is a relationship with domain or the
range reader around and then you can have instances so is a particular instance and
here's another particular instance and they may have this particular relationship
because she read the book written by
and here is your comment about what your particular instances
that are organised in this particular class
OK so this everything there is to say that RDF schema
well you should
five is part
and what you do with schema you can define classes subclasses in this hierarchy
you can find properties
between these classes and also for these properties can be defined hierarchy so fatherof subpropertyof
in terms a few somebody's father always also some experience and these properties can have
domains and ranges
so it is to which the property applies in what the are the class of
third element in the triple
you could do little inferencing on this
if i know that frank is an author i also know that the person
and even if i didn't know notice frank was also
what i that frank communicates to that
and communicates to this is domain therefore frame must be also
so we do this all the time i say
marco is married to
and then we have a lot of memory two is relationship between two people
right so we mean even if you've never seen the pair of them before if
i give you that statement you could you would have for most people
it's not to get some householders so we do is inferring of of class membership
based on relation instances we do it all the time and it's also a legal
inference in
in RDF schema so you see here are schema is a little logic
in the sense that i give you some facts and you can derive some new
facts and i can exactly predict which means that you're going to drive because they
are exactly the derivation rules that are sanctioned by the
but here is that it is time is IDF's way of spelling instance of this
kind of of water or is it simply the two ways of looking at the
domain and range definitions in RDF schema we look at them as sources for inference
has overseen markers married and then i can infer the type in other paradigms you
can use the main range is as real as constraints is instructions so if markers
married and then i learned that that marko is not person but something else then
this this could be used to constrain conflict in RDF they are not used such
constraints they are only using the sources of inference
so let's
i could but
it comes from this
that's not discussed terminology this is just the magic words in the language which you
also see is that it is because of these for example do not use this
constraint is impossible to say anything inconsistent in RDF schema is simply to weak
you can also
they are not a
because you could say anything not
there's no indication in the language you cannot create such conflicts right
having something in the class it shouldn't be because there is no such a notion
of constraint so i was logic but it's very very simple if you use a
very simple view of the world where on the one hand you have instances and
on the other hand you class but RDF and RDF schema actually allowed
these two parts of the world to be completely makes something can be both an
instance and the class at the same time
so you could have a class that in some instances
and this is subclass of the class but it can be an instance of some
of the class which suggested not only class because as instances but itself is an
instance because
members some the class
so something can be both things and the class every calls properties like instances properties
even worse in my view
the classes can be members of other classes including themselves so class can be member
of the low-level image features and then based on the clustering they might build
some SVM on top of it so in this case you could again
do nonparametric clustering using this DP mixture model and then kind of test it by kind of
plugging it into some supervised learning algorithm and see whether that works well or not so if
you have some external if you have some problem that you want to solve with
some external measure of of of how well the model's doing than you could actually
check that is doing well or is not doing well okay I'll move onto a Pitman
Yor processes  this are basically generalizations of the of the  DP of
the of the Dirichlet process and the easiest way was a Pitman Yor processes
basically by this random partitioning by by these Chinese restaurant process right so we saw
that we have this Chinese restaurant process where the probability of a customer sitting at
table C is gonna be proportional to the number of customers already sitting there
and the probability of  customers sitting  at a new table is gonna be proportional to alpha and it has
this rich gets richer property there are two other properties which of these Chinese restaurant
process which is I think quite important in terms of modelling and they are called projectivity
and exchangeability so I'll just kind of give you a very simple example okay of projective
exchangeable models of data imagine that our data set consists of this six data
items and we're gonna label and it's a supervised earning problem classifier is  the
data item in the blue clust or in the red clust suppose that that you will
be tested on one  new test item but I don't tell you what it is yet
should this change your predictions of should you should this change the decision boundary
over your data set anybody would like to say something no okay yeah yes
sorry you might have
but if you don't really know where this item is then it's probably hard
to optimize for that so at least the simplest thing to do would be to say
that it actually doesn't matter one there being one  test item yes
this is just a classification it is two  classification  so
we don't really exp at least as a simplest approximation we it's
probably easiest to think of this as not really changing our predictions whether we have one
test data item or not especially if we don't actually know where this test
data item is if we knew knew where it is the  that would actually tell us something about
the data set and that might change our prediction but if we don't know where
it is then that doesn't change it so if we have five additional test items than
that shouldn't change our predictions either because we don't really know where they are so
we might  as well work with the data that we have okay how about if we our
item labels were permuted so if I take X one X three and X two and
we premuted the labels should that change our prediction it shouldn't change either because is this idea
I mean  the the labels actually doesn't tell you anything about the data
set itself unless you do things that the labels actually tell you unless that
you have some sort of time series data or sequential data in which case the
which observe the data items does have an effects on the on
the model but in this case if we assume that's  IID it shouldn't affect your
predictions okay so models which are which don't really aren't affected by additional by
right here
o standing
these are the things i mean all
you can see
all o
there were
how they on
and it grows
o o
i mean
i think i'm right
they are
i agree with
will be
all you do that
the right
in are
these are called
they are
the plan being
and there
that we
forty eight dimensional space but i rotated all rotations of the sixties and what we're
three hundred sixty six is rotating at different points so
the interesting question is well
should we be trying to find these sort of space is not trying to find
not trying to model in the original space and that's what motivates mensionality reduction in
this case i would then say and it's clear that this dimensionality reduction has to
be non linear because you can see that it's not a straight line so the
relationship between the observed sixties and this thing here is this article has a circle
because as to connect is also a little bit noisy because using these interpolation methods
really do your image rotation you get a little bit of noise so i really
think that's a great way of thinking about data that your data is really some
corrupting process
being applied to something
and it's actually inherently low dimensional now obviously the cases six is pure rotation is
just too simple
you are you need several distortions so that it could be thinned and translated and
rotated but
i think it's always the definition if your data has any structure if it were
true that your dataset was covering the three thousand six hundred forty eight dimensional space
that's happened then
just put your hand down and go home because you'll never model in that space
so that's the curse ofdimensionality you one model in that space but that space as
far as they concern is just noise the structure itself will be in a low
dimensional space so we're interested in
reducing the management of data the lasts of algorithm i want to briefly mention this
OK so
i don't know if i've got probably enough time to go this in detail so
one way of representing the status of is unsupervised data now we just got why
we don't have
i know that was the label before we don't have anything but wise but why
is now i data so
one way of modelling the state and this comes from statistics is just to measure
interpoint distances distances between each of these data points so
we can represent our data
by these distances so for any dataset we can then display that basis matrix d
and what i wanted to show you is is that
matrix has a lot of structure so this is just the distance between
two points
in of those rotated six status is being visualizes matrix so i did one degree
rotations and the three hundred sixty data points what you should see
is this interesting structure actually benefits to find the we should be able to might
make out these boxes these boxes those rotations which are ninety degrees so that easy
to do so there's no noise and you see that structure on here you see
the fact that there's snow distance between three hundred sixty eight point and the zero
point so blue is low distance radius high seas saying that structure and here so
another way of representing data as the distance matrix
so i want to do
dimensionality reduction
one thing i could do
i really don't think would be
OK so i want to is find a configuration of points
that such that the distances between these axes
look similar to this
now really don't way of doing that would be to select a bunch of columns
from y to just extract columns from y
and say this is my reduced space so my features and now
actual pixel columns from y
and use that nomination follow that way of doing that and what it turns out
is that to minimize
this objective function which is just looking at the squared distances
between each of those elements and measuring the absolute difference
to minimize this objective function
he y
what we need to do is to retain
for x the columns of y
that have the largest variance
so this is my pictorial motivation for that i have to give you any proof
for why that's the case the pictorial motivation so here this is the two-dimensional y
and we want to retain one of the columns of y which is either retained
that directional that direction the distances
the distances between all these points if we want to retain
the distance is that most accurately reflect the original distance we retain the ones that
are in the variance the highest variance direction which in this case is that direction
so that's sort of lower variance than that
because here we go beyond four now we're going nowhere near full so basically retained
that and now we can compute interpoint distances between all these points
so i want to show you is what that looks like for that data
so if you retain
two columns
of y
is the structure you get
the approximate structure you get for all
for that distance matrix we saw before this is our approximation so it's not very
good some diagonal properties if we retain ten
then you can see we get
from the little bit better but we still mostly much structure is a hundred dimensions
and this is a thousand dimensions of and only when you get two thousand dimensions
that you start seeing
this structure ninety degrees you can just about see that
so this is obviously a really crap way
doing dimensionality reduction
we have a very simple
extension which is even make it on we can see some dramatic effect so what
i want to suggest is well we can do the same thing
but before we look at the data
before we look at the directions to retain we can rotate
such that
the columns of y are the largest variance here so basically before we actually look
at the
columns to extract we rotate the data set to align the largest variance directions with
the axis so that would look like this first rotate the data right now notice
rotating the data see any the interpoint distances changing is i'm rotating if anyone spots
any changing tell me
sampled from loveless distribution
and let's make sure that the distributions have the same meaning in the same variance
so we don't want to make it too simple
so here's our plus in distribution
here's the goal to have the same meaning in the same variance
you can still see some differences here in the middle here on the sides probably
also contains
just small so these are two distributions and now we find that function that best
can distinguish samples from these distributions
because the people with with this function function that
makes this quantity here extremal
and we do this in particular
was kind the space in our favour precision kind the space is one of those
internal so we just do this in in the gaussian case and it turns out
the shortest the function the best function with unit norm in that space to distinguish
these two samples is that red function here
so it's a function that whenever there is a sample of points coming up in
the middle of
that function gives it positive values
if point comes up somewhere in the side negative values
and it turns out that then in the end this function tends to have larger
values larger values for
plus in data are and small but goes in the task in that sense the
function distinguishes goes in plot data from each other
and this the best function in are given reproducing kernel hilbert space which was one
of a gaussian kernel of some with that i don't remember
if i had changed the width of that goes kernel would still find a function
but the function would look a bit different so effectively if i had to those
income that's why it is my reproducing kernel hilbert space
the generating kernel i would find the function may be which is qualitatively similar but
it would be a smooth function may be the pumps would be a bit smaller
on the other hand if i had chosen a linear kernel
just the standard product
as i kernel then
i cannot express this function because all the functions that can be expressed using a
linear kernel are linear functions so i can write this red function which makes sense
because we said before with the linear kernel we can only distinguish datasets that have
different mean and here by construction i
i've chosen distributions that have the same meaning say even the same variance so also
with a polynomial kernel of degree two
i should be able to do this because the data sets have the same variance
and maybe you can imagine that it will be hard to write this with the
problem of the two
so let's
let's move on to measure sralan functions
we like like probability distributions of measures
how do we generalize this
we make certain technical assumptions about expectations of
kernel functions being finite
don't worry about this from now one
condition that make sure this is true is that the kernel has finite norm
they of these individual function find nominal space don't worry about that now
but what really define is so before i remember we had this mapping of data
points that it into account functions
centered on those points that takes me so now
we simply realize that
rather than the set of points we have a distribution over probability measures and
again we never to kernel functions but this time we don't take the average of
the kernel functions but we take expectation with respect to the probability measure
so that's also some function
in all space in these conditions make sure that it's a function that lies in
the same reproducing kernel hilbert spaces
we we have mapped our probability measure to
one point in all hilbert space
one point in the input space is a function of the hilbert space of functions
we get the same properties as before also these two properties this
map mean represents the operation of taking the mean of the function
and also a large distance
of two sets of points of two means corresponds to
finding a function that distinguishes the samples
so now we have the same the mapped probability measure
it represents
the operation of taking expectation for function
twenty representing the sense of this it gives us a linear operation dot product for
which i
that is
so well
and the
when twenty
so i
and then we show that
and i said
they are now
that was
and the
it's a
we can say is
so in
on a mission
you have a very
so the last thing
the way
i mean it
and when reach
and the thing
in fact
that is
we have
we use your real name or
they are saying
and you can see the same thing is that she
right so this is the formula going to put this
box because this is by far
the most important formula today which we
used to derive pretty much everything else
and this is the way that we're going to be able to
compute these numbers
let's let's do an example
this example
we call this example one
i will take the function
which is one over here
that's sufficiently complicated to have an interesting answer
and sufficiently straightforward that we can
compute the derivative
fairly quickly
so what is it that we're going to do here
all we're going to do
it is we're going to
plug in this formula here
for that function that that's all we're going to do
and visually what we're accomplishing is somehow
to take
the hyperbole
take a point on the hyperbola and figure out
tangent line all right that's what we're accomplishing when we do that so accomplishing this
geometrically but will be doing it algebraically
so first
we consider
this difference
delta over delta
right out its formula so i have to have a place so i'm going to
make it again above
this point x zero which is the general point will make the general calculation
so the value of f at the top
when we move to the right by f of x i just read off from
read off from here
the formula
the first thing i get here is one
zero one
the left-hand turn minus one over
the right term and i have to divide that by delta
OK so here's our
and by the way
this has the name
this thing is called
a different
it's pretty complicated because there's always the difference in in the numerator and in disguise
the denominator is the difference because the difference between the value
on the
right side
and the value on the left side here
so now
we're going to simplify it by some algebra
so let's just take a look so this is equal to o
continue on the next
level here
this is equal to one over delta
all i'm going to do is put over common denominator
so the the common denominator
is x zero mostel to act
times here
so in the numerator for the first expression i have a zero
for the second expression axial delta x
so this is
the same thing as i had in the numerator before factoring out the denominator
and here i put that numerator into
amenable will form and now
there are
two basic cancellations the first one is the x zero and axl zero council
so we have this
and then the second step is that these
expressions can so
right the numerator and denominator now we have a cancellation that we can make use
of so
all right that under here
and this is
equals minus one over a zero
time zero
and then the very last step
is to take the limit
as delta x tends to zero
now we can do it before we couldn't do it y
because the numerator and the denominator gave us zero over zero
now the mean
just this expression here
so that's really just the
that's the shorthand for saying well this is
the vector
of k of x sin x
for all those locations here
rip it out for one point in time
the inverse covariance matrix
my observations
the thing is i can precompute this part
and afterwards only have to take an inner product between
the vector fixed
something that depends on the location
that's the expensive part all
do not invert the matrix explicitly if you can avoid it or at least not
if you've got problems lies in two thousand
it will be slow
is it something like conjugate gradient
incomplete cholesky factorizations of things like that
otherwise just wait expensive
is the variance
exactly the same expression is what we had before
this the covariance matrix
this is basically should compliment for scanner
this we undermined and also we get k x x plus in this where
it's just the additive noise component
and here's my parents correction by having observed the rest
now the interesting bit is this does not depend on the white
this is actually a big criticism
garcia processes
custom process regression
my actual observations will not change my view of how unreliable data is
there are ways around this
why essentially
design heteroskedastic casting processes
so if you want to know more about that this paper was if can use
when we did this
the optimisation is a lot less trivial so it's not just a simple matrix inversion
anymore but it can be done
the case
if you do that
it will typically actually work really well
what you get is
well first of all of course the point
well typically by using the boundary
but you can see all here we're not so much about my parents goes up
this red line by the way the variance itself and also at the boundary
right i don't have any further that over here
i get some additional variance
this is because while at the bottom line
i don't know how to continue things properly
and that's where the variance goes up
now let's see how well we did
OK with a fairly well so overall
in most regions stayed within
one thing single variant
it's actually quite handy if you have two
the practical implementation and you actually need to be able to make predictions of
well at least it will tell you how uncertain things might be
this is ok as long as surprise
any questions so far
here's another example
and well OK sure it didn't work
quite that will be found in any points here so you can see that
the predictive variance here is really high
all this casting process is simply saying this will happen but served only that the
here so i really don't know what's going on
rest over there
lot of thought
i know pretty well what's going on
this is when you can see actually this
that is fairly noisy but
consideration of the various doesn't really change of for instance here i mean it should
probably assuming that the points are really quite at the boundary it should actually probably
increase the predictive variance estimates here
but since
the approximate answer
this combination of
a trial
yes that's right it's nothing to do with that CMS would i be better i
would be better to call these
unknowns are that would actually be a lot better
should i could i
it would it would be a lot better is to be
to be a for the u i to be there
the weights
of the feet
why is that better
because finite elements actually has this wonderful property
these guys
you would have been handled better there
because those
because use are actually the values of my approximate
so you could say this is you the approximate guide
and we hope it's true close to the
to the real one
you see what we did we minimize or we worked on over this finite dimensional
so we arrive at a finite problem
OK you weep left
instead of differential equation
instead of the differential equation we got to a finite matrix equation
but the job was to figure out the matrix so that's the stiffness matrix
and this is the load vector
and to see what k is the the can i just say what
what's the typical member of k
and then
you've really
been a long
they are not going to
go over on this but what's that
what's typical
what's the i j entry of this matrix k
it will be
it comes from this is the angle of cmx
so i j
like into the weak form
and the k part comes from the quadratic part what's the what's the load
it would be the end will come from the linear park it will be in
the middle of sign
as is the side k
yeah i think
times f of x
all i've done is plug in
the u
and the yves
ah the article
was these in rules that that are involved in assembling that
in producing the main
and hopefully those enrolled are not hard i mean how would you actually do this
what's what is the fee i dx
this is a piecewise constant just too little constant over a little piece of the
and what's all
what's what's the derivative let's take the feces and the size of the thing
so this will be another piece wise constant
OK so what's up
what kind of of matrix k of going have here
well why you got it you got it the first time
absolutely i thought what i have great and i thought i haven't made clear enough
but it
it's true why is it right i go there i have the
because they only ride this guy only overlaps with one if i is it different
from today by more than one
there's no overlap
so that the local basis paid
they were quite orthogonal
this guy
and this guy do overlap
but it try diagonal and that
that's fine
i mean if everything was orthogonal then we whatever diagonal matrix
because all the other products would give zero
but that's try diagonal is just as good
that's OK
so that
so please
it's these calculations that are now
what of what are we going to do with this effect
are we can actually do the integral exactly
probably not
if c and if we do have some variable
so the the of x really depends on the
the conductivity or
or whatever that
physically represents if it's if it's changing continuously hey we're not going to we will
approximate that by piecewise constant or piecewise linear some
we all we want is a good approximation to those involved
these and these
then we would solve k equal f and we would have a darn good approximation
that's the
the whole idea of finite element was making this kind of a choice
that's really real and then creating the
a million dollar systems that would do it
do all the calculations for
can i
ask you to move for these last move into two dimensions
suppose we had a partial differential equation
these are double integrals
p x p y
and there would be
there will be a wide derivatives in there
are functions are functions now of x and y
can you invent finite element
in two d
what's good what's what's an invention of two-dimensional finite element these were
great one-dimensional finite l
this one the next one and the next one an extra now let me draw
drawn to the region
from some two miles from two dimensional region
might be an air aircraft
surface or something
right here and here you would
this you would now here's the beauty of it the
i don't have the use equally spaced mesh orders
really kind of mesh
it it's the edge of the that's the surface of the plane and the nice
or maybe where i expect shockwaves up put in a whole bunch of
little element
so this basically it's empirical result substantiating the theorem which is that for this parameter
getting larger and larger and larger beyond some point is rescaled
parameter and divided by something beyond some point the probability of support recovery being correct
goes to one below that it goes to zero
and this is done for number of dimensions growing and we see that bites by
scaling things in this way is log of p
basically the dependence vanishes we get these curves lie on top of each other
so this shows that we actually have the right rescaling and log p is great
he says that you know p can grow
very quickly
relative to an
and you still get support recovery exact support recovery
this very different so angle here is the
angle this has to do with the support overlapped function
so we did this under different regimes for that choice for the particular divine matrix
and what is the support overlap function
well what you do is you take it some facts about the the the the
the parameter matrix OK so if you look at the
the gradient of this
l one l two norm on b
you know you you use that to form a gradient matrix
you normalized that
or the equivalent and normalizing the former certain gram matrix where the gradient times that
the covariance of the part of the x matrix that has nonzero coefficients
and in this function i was talking about here is the maximum like value of
of this matrix
OK so it's as if the quantity can calculate in simulations and
that's what it is
OK so long if you want to spend more time with the paper you can
do that we go through very special cases of calculating this and see how much
overlap we get and therefore how much we're dividing that
scaling factor by
OK so i'm not going to get into the here just to get different examples
of choosing this part just choosing coefficient matrices
and getting different sparsity overlap
so there some favorable cases where can have orthogonal situations if you have aligned regression
where everybody has all the columns
of this gradient matrix of the same you don't do any better than last so
otherwise you do better than last shifted to the left feature
here in a few data points to get the same problem of correct support recovery
being correct and so and we have a simple situations in which you get you
can get up to a factor of the number of regressions improvement
so five k regressions
i can actually
i ni kefu are data points in the most favourable situations to be the the
independent last
we originally thought that we will never do worse than the actual as o independent
so that turns out not to be the case so we have some kind of
somewhat pathological situation we could do worse than so in general you improve
OK that this is the statement that kind of care about how much you perform
relative to the
ordinary QP
and arrested this particular situation where the covariance matrix of the
that a fraction that portion of design matrix is the identity and we actually always
improve over the independent cells but in general you that's not the case
right the next few pages are proof sketch and i put them in the slides
i'm not going to cover them but
you know this is meant to be very talks if you will look through these
slides received the techniques that have been used here it kind of is convex optimization
meets sort of concentration inequalities that's really what's happening here gail kind gaussians
concentration inequalities for some semantic projection arguments and again use large deviations to establish some
kind of rate then you bring that into the optimisation story and
well before but only other so let's skip all that
OK so let me just briefly kind of again kind of running through all this
just to give you a little flavor of kind of this these these ideas is
a large literature also on sparse PCA so if we want to PCA but we
make assumptions on the sparsity i vectors maybe we can
use PCA in really high dimensional spaces into it probably
so a lot of people are working on this in general if you don't have
any sparsity assumptions you can't do it a classical result on that but if you
have structured ensembles like sparse lichen vectors are sparse covariance matrices then you can actually
get consistency even though he over and going to infinity and seemingly impossible but the
true these kind of conditions
so one of the theoretical situations where this study these were called spiked population covariance
matrices our covariance matrix as a sum of
rank one matrices so these are the late night i can vectors plus some
matrix typically the identity matrix
i then you look at different sparsity models either give hard sparsity where these i
vectors have exactly k nonzero coefficients or you have some soft versions of that in
you study these things theoretically
OK so
we have a project where we were interested in doing this first PCA using kind
of sophisticated optimization tools implicate the SDP
and this is kind of a pretty straightforward lactation you saw talk on convex optimisation
you probably know how to do this to remind you remember that the igon values
according to the core of fisher variational principles got by
maximizing over the ball of this rail a kind of
and you can rewrite that problem using the
is it a semidefinite programme just using a linear
expressionist traces EQ
and you do that over all simple positive definite easy that have unit trace
OK so you may be now know how to go from there there after the
lecture the other day
can use this idea now than to relax
first PCA so there's the same component pulled down there
all right then we want to sparse PCA so we have an l one norm
to the objective function now we optimize that this is still a semidefinite program
OK and now
russian mini and martin wainwright to prove the theorem about this
that year they have the kind of the same kind of classifier and we talked
about for the other situation which is that you actually do recover under this is
just a simple example of just to rank one is one i conduct an identity
one large organ vector and identity
despite covariance matrix
the to get exact recovery you know here's the rate
and in that situation
using spp
so that was they actually theoretical result that and there are some known results on
thresholding estimators which achieve a slower rates if q is equal to zero it's the
same rate as before but it's slower for q not equal to zero and so
if you know this is for the first eigen vector but you will separate organisations
get this for the first time that the whole was
these change in weights telescope over any therefore
i want to find shortest paths
you just find shortest paths in this reweighted version and then you just change it
by this one amounts
you subtract off this amounts to an idea that will give you the shortest path
weights in the original weights
so this is the tool
we now know how to change weights in the graph
what we really want change weights in the graph so the weights all come out
non negative
how do we do that why in the world with the function h
that makes all the weight of edge weights
making it
it makes sense
it turns out we already know
you should write down this consequence
first order so in particular the shortest path changes by this amount
and if you want to know this value just move the stuff to the other
side so we can compute delta some h then we can compute delta
the consequence here how many how many people here pronounce this word
OK how many people pronounce the corollary
four one can also
usually at least one other student and there that which usually canadian or british or
something i think that's the
access i always avoid pronouncing this would also really think core
we say zeenat our
we have
so what we want to do
is defined
one of these functions i mean this is right that what what we could hope
to have we want to find winning h assigns weights to each vertex such that
w seven h
it is nonnegative that would be great
for all edges
on you can be
OK then we can run dexter
i could run by extracting the delta h is
and then just undo the reweighting and get what we want
and that johnson's army
claims that this is always possible
why should always be possible well let's look at this construct wsum h of UV
that's w
view v
was each of you
minus HIV
should be nonnegative
let me really want to redraw rewrite this little bit
what i want
i'm gonna put these guys over here
o thing it should be mine is a agent of view is less than or
equal to w of movie
i look familiar
you get it right
the right
anyone seen that inequality before
yes correct answer OK where
previous lecture
in the previous lecture
what is this called
replace each with x
charles was good
anyone else remember all the way back to episode two
there's a weekend
it has this operator called
on subtraction by
the courage
and i'll tell you
the difference constraints
this is the difference operator
so good friend difference constraints
so this is what we want to satisfy we have a system of difference constraints
hv minus attribution be we want to find these these are on this subject to
these constraints were given the W's
we know
when these difference constraints are satisfiable
can someone tell me when the constraints are satisfiable
we know exactly one
and then he was
denominal verbs which
taken down
and the
no it's a
but anyway
we need to i
but there
one way
typically derivational morphology changes the part of speech
and derivational morphology is represented in cyc with reified suffixes
and there's a rule
that says
the form of the derived word is drawn by
attaching the suffix
string to the base form
so you have
reified suffixes i o
and it will attach to
words like sesame
give us
this complex four
it was shown earlier
which can then be given semantic interpretation
sometimes it can be hard to decide whether something is inflectional morphology or derivational morphology
so comparatives and superlatives were
initially represented in the KB as inflectional
morphology but then we had to change that because of semantics which i think is
kind of interesting because
things are semantics can get rid off
so inflectional analysis
you have tall and presidency of tall taller tallest all being forms of the same
word which will map the addition to
the meaning of it all the time for senators
total prime
and also we don't need to tell us
but if you
variational analysis of two different words
this will be from tall
table b for this work
and the know
separate concepts which you need
for interpreting queries like patients heavier than one hundred fifty pounds which we have this
where doctors are trying to get access to these medical records and
could well make this kind of query you know
give me patients whose weight exceeds
eighty pounds and we don't want to interpret that as
given the patients who are heavy
we want the comparative
if there is a comparative analysis
so we have to represent derivational morphology
here's an example of the generative rules
gives the
semantics were compared
give semantics for the actor
unfortunately it doesn't have
OK if the coverage is not
very good this is sort of just the proof of concept is just we're just
at the beginning stages of
working on this kind of rule
but the idea is that you take
an adjective that means are very low
the low amount of something
and then
the transfer translation of the derived adjective
well mean
i think
maybe it's better to give an example
so little earth
it's something
that means
a little over x means
so seven
a little
x littler then y
it means that
that's still not a good thing for variables
all o
a little earlier than b
can see that there are some obvious that there is a value x
which is less than the value denoted by the
public object to the
o thing in the van pp
and the size parameter of the object is
this value so in a
so i'm trying to let's say
try to figure out what this particularity is going to be annasee's coordinating so i'm
subtracting the mean divided by a standard deviation so i'm handling looking at a real
number over here
so this is well
if i'm doing a matrix factorization you know i'm going to factorize acts as you'll be transpose so
the corresponding to be surrounded by a factor u i i its role
and the effective immediately responding to this column
my probabilistic model is
that exciting
is being sampled from a gaussian distribution
was mean you why transpose vijay
and with some standard deviation sigma squared
um and then that's the more right so
and then i have a factor like this
four each wrong
and i'm assuming these factors you why themselves are being sampled from another multivariate gaussian distribution
with zero mean and some diagonal covariance and similarly the problem factors are being sampled
from a zero mean and diagonal covariance matrix
this is insanity right so you're taking a simple problem you're cooking things up on the fly
we love doing this
but you have to show that this walks and i can assure these are some
of the most popular methods we have got or disposal and this doesn't fit the
usual machine learning framework of where you're doing
clustering or classification
this is the graphical model structure is a generative model and this is how it so so they actually showed
fantastic results
back in two thousand six seven
in the netflix leaderboard some of these discussions
that they are doing pretty well to to register and said it was a different
one we just use gradient descent to do the
inference figuring out what those factors are
they made one more step this at all
i have i am using
a zero mean diagonal covariance gosh and why should i be doing that's should i
put some non zero mean and some general covariance
so that that's so this is the prior over the latent factors
well if you've observed are the small fraction of ratings in this matrix everything else
is latent variables and remember the example was that one latent variable heart disease
and this is pretty much everything is latent
so you you're putting russian distribution with mean mu and precision matrix lambda
and then putting a wishart prior gaussian wishart on top of these parameters that's that's it's one more layer
and this almost looks scary somebody who has not actually played with these models we're
starting with a sparsely filled matrix and we are talking about this story line on
each side
by putting latent factors being generated from russian distributions whose parameters are being generated from some unknown distribution
and so on but you know that's the route they took
and then i'm going to show you some results
so this is the sort of the full the full model
we we added a few things to it but it's not very major it's essentially
this model is actually very fast
well for the last model they uses embassy embassy which turned out to be extremely slow
and since
can forties
millions of data points problems
is there two models we sort of cooked up something in between which we call a parametric be map
not a large difference money to get into the details so
if you actually sort of see how they performed in comparison with something like this
is what the netflix baseline school this is the netflix put all the chance that
try to beat us
they can be re so there's no confusion about this this is what netflix used
to do the best they could have done
and this is sort of the four stock the pianist model
it's really actually starts overfitting
because because there is there is no regularisation
right there is no regularisation have a number of epochs number of passes over the data increases
it starts overfitting it fits the pocket sees well
it it fits the park it sees very well
so i'm seeing this five numbers and feeling it very well
but i'm messing up on the others and this is the lesson we have learned
with regularisation you should be trying to
the things you are observing and is very is fantastically well actually doing what he
warning regularisation start off and this is what a lot you'll see
as you go
but if you see the pianist models with more epochs being better
bayesian be map of course is a little bit more to come
imagine that this was a slightly better algorithm it's a little slower they have some
time numbers we have tried to improve them we have not managed to
so our model which is somewhere in between
um it's much faster
but we can outperform them but this is sort of i'm showing you a part
of the literature that slowly growing in them so this matrix some vision problems okay
we'll go back to overview
i give you a predictive model a lot of detail on graphical model trying to
convince you that these practical models which scales to millions of
sort of data points and features
and this is one of the things machine learners very excited about these days
other thing you really excited about is online learning
and this is how if you're trying to fit a support vector machine
on a billion points
you will have to use online learning there is really no other way i mean
sorry the number of views you
and yes in a still contrasted with the traditional combinations so basically whether it's combination
is that this guy here is just a course and which is the weight that
you give for the particle OK and here we have much richer structures and
OK so how are you are missing again you do maximum likelihood and we
yes you some bitterness and the priors in this case we seem to be working
in order to world and they know how to do inference we are gonna do
multiclass classification and the only thing that we use to maximize over the class and
then we get the class which has the maximum response
OK so let me go over the different examples that mario was working on this
so here is my area a few years ago
and so we were looking into these big disagreement dataset which disagreement in this case
let me explain what it is so
we have this scenario or which we have we ask questions to the set of
subjects and we record the review as well as the or the and the and
the view disagreement is the fact that you can actually respond visually saying this and
moving your head writer the two views which are going to be the only be
actually give information about this
the fact that suggests right you can yes cds but the move your hand in
that case the
it's actually corrupted innocence right the single view information that actually the saying yes and
the same thing can actually happen before the interview
right so in order to have a controller sitting we simulated is really this agreement
by have been broken motion in the case of a
in the case of the gesture and the the is for the case of the
OK so this are yes resource as a function of the view disagreement so much
of these nice days there so in that case that there is no disagreement there
then in this case one of the classifier is really good so you actually don't
even need to be of use to classify and you know the similarity the MKL
you do
these complications can occur in any combination you actually do fairly well and in the
case of you have a lot of disagreement dismissed seventy percent of the samples have
all these have one bucuresti OK either the all the all the review and in
this case you see that there is both the performance if you actually try to
capture the fact that some of these examples are corrupted which is basically what this
clustering is the
OK and here is again the the the the and the media which are the
the two modalities
so we try also this in the morris under the condition that the dataset again
is called the one one three seven hundred one categories with the same example social
before and here we are to compute multiple the occurrences by using different features that
people have billion the vision community
OK and so the good news is that actually we perform more you we might
to the state of the art of the time so this is one year later
so you see that is much much more people actually trying to combine different sources
of information now the the bad news again is that we get more or less
the same resources by the kind of communication
OK and the main research here is that actually having this richer structure
that's o
when you have an isolated or when you have this this locality vary in theme
actually we really mean is that same way that will have enough data to actually
capture these this variation
so the report was that with was in performance and we didn't get the the
so i've seen a version of the paper which the
they didn't have much less so than
what was the
what they did to make it two to work but here so here's we we
couldn't really make it to work and actually here is seen as an example as
a function of the number of clusters we really have flat performance
and now we similarly missing data and in that case you actually come up with
was the performance
respect to you simple MKL
so no
so here we should before was actually what clustering and having a simplified version of
this and now the
so what we try to do is so very preliminary cells into train to estimate
the full non parametric covariance another question if you want do this was actually the
regularizer avoid this massive overfitting then you would expect to have so we thought of
two possible regularizers which are pretty big operator is the laplacian regularizer will be so
some measure of
this distance similarity you have or
if you have some estimate of maybe what you know good estimation of this then
maybe you want to have the frobenius norm that minimize the distance to estimate the
you think it is possible for example this can be yes the fact that you
know the course and weights or yes if is the average cannot all once
and so we simple experiment were
and these are the only other result dataset and actually we got both of performance
if we learn the complicated matters is very interesting thing they call single training
which was developed by yuille NIPS a couple of years ago and the main idea
is this is going to be for active set in the main idea is that
you want to enforce an agreement prior in order to regularizer solutions so you're going
to have different views here you're gonna have to get some process function for a
review and then you've got some process priors on each of these guys and then
you have no gas generation this big o thing about using this is that you
can actually marginalizes in closed form and human the then you end up with a
gaussian process of business here which i covariance which is a combination of kernels in
innocent four so what you get is the members of these some of the inverses
of the kernel now the good thing about this is that
by doing the same you actually can use this in a semi supervised setting so
it's going to influence your to be the covariance therefore the covariance of the end
and the thing about this is that the masses of as are
you know i'm going to be pretty bad condition so you have to be very
careful when you when you do this
and so some i said he was interested in
this extend this to actually have
more complicated functions so is the case of catalyst first where you expect again the
nice vary across data points and the idea here is that
basically he again citizens scenarios before we have a subset of clusters and in this
so the assumption makes the observation true
and this action pressing the alarm signal button
it makes
the conclusion
of the maintenance school true
so this
inductive logic programming agent model has a very natural proof theoretic
operational semantics that looks like production systems combines production system functionality
with logic programming functionality
has meet
link to decision theory but has a shortcut to a stimulus response associations all of
which in turn have a connectionist implementation
so as i said before there is really no need to say it again
the agent's world is really a world of its own creations
for the most part
it's beliefs are entirely made up
they're all in the head of the agent
the only point of contact the agent has with the world are observations
and these observations must be made true by its assumptions about the world and by
the actions it performs and in addition to those observations
being true it also must fulfill its goals
so the actions of the agent embedded in the world
must be such that schools can be made true by the actions it chooses to
of course many different solutions exist there are many delta many different set of assumptions
about the world many different actions many different plans and achieve the same results
so it's not enough simply to say
to be justified simply to get along from day to day
the challenge is to find the best delta you can
the image does
most you can with your life
subject to your own capabilities to the computational resources the u
i have in particular
now in classical decision theory
the value of an action or course of action
is measured by the expected utility of its logical consequence is not simply the
cause and effect consequences but the logical
this expected utility as we know incorporates notions of probability
similarly in the philosophy of science the value of an explanation of an observation is
measured in terms of how likely
how likely a state of affairs in the world might be too
explain the observations for example tear gas is less likely explanation of smoke and fire
and explanatory power more generally
how many observations that those
and an explanatory hypothesis explains
the more observations explained by hypothesis the better in the same way the more goals
achieved by applying the better
the same criteria used in decision theory
help us choose between different courses of action
the virtually identical to the criteria used in philosophy of science
to identify
preferred explanations of observations
so an abductive logic programming
we can combine the two
we can combine
both measures of
the value of a solution
and use this
not only to help us make decisions
but also to choose
as we search
to search out better
part of the search space
more likely to achieve goals than others
more likely to achieve them to higher degree than other parts of the search space
so as i said and as you all know better than me for the most
life is uncertain
but what you may not appreciate
except for
if few words in the audience perhaps is that uncertainty
fits in
with logic logic and uncertainty go hand-in-hand
so in particular
it's quite natural for the state of the world such as
being rich to depend upon not only what you do
and actually of your own such as buying a lottery ticket but what the world
so you will be rich
if you buy lottery tickets and your number is chosen
and you can use this kind of belief
two are false
you can use this would be better if it's true
you can use this belief in order to guide your behavior
if your goal is to be rich if that's what makes you happy
then you can buy a lottery ticket
but the expected value
of that decision
has to be weighted by the probability that your number is chosen
so decision theory incorporates probability theory
and it is absolutely essential in any kind of agent whether it uses logic or
so logic alone
is nothing without probably not logic in a decision theoretic context in an agent
it doesn't survive without some capability for reasoning about uncertainty in in terms of probability
that depends on the size of the perturbation and depends on the sound speed
and sold for uconn
figure out to what is the time for pressure
if they equalised in time for the pressure is much smaller than the dynamical time
it means that whenever you create this perturbation like a sound wave this perturbation doesn't
grow and go crazy and create tornadoes but it remains like sound waves and eventually
OK so now we understand why there were no tornadoes in this room
but what are the implications for cosmology for these well the implications for cosmology that
the olive perturbation for weeks
the pressure time
is large it is larger done dynamical time can grow
but the west perturbation them growing your left with something like sound waves
so this defines a particular
size of perturbation
define the genes lens and deduced lens to define it when the dynamical time is
equal to the
depression time
below that the lens
o thing scanned
over the next region larger than the the influence can collapse about smaller than doctor
they come not to and therefore you just get the situation you get something like
and so when we write this equality
we can define these genes lands the genes lens for the area ten to the
five kilometres which means the sound waves
but any kind of wavelengths that you can use for hearing me
so what are the implications for cosmology well we can't go on substitute things in
figure out what is the typical size of the genes land the typical size of
the genes length depends on the dynamical time and the sound speed and the dynamical
time we can write it like this and remember this reminds you a lot of
the inverse of
the hubble parameter
so for the universe
we have a relation
the genes lance's factors of order unity the sound speed divided by the hubble parameter
so let's say to plug in some numbers in the radiation dominated i and the
sound speed it's very close to the speed of light is the speed of light
divided by the square root of three
and sold the genes length is three c divided by eight
but remember that this looks a lot like the size of the horizon
remember what was the
problems arise and how arise and was exactly these
so this is telling you that inside the eyes
during the radiation dominated there
perturbation unstable
in other words during the radiation dominated her if you have a perturbation they behave
like sound waves
you can't create galaxies stars or anything like that
and so
when you look at the universe and you get an image of the universe when
basie culley was very close to radiation dominated which is something that you see for
example the cosmic background this is what you expect to see
if there were some perturbations were not growing but they were behaving like acoustic waves
and the kind of mathematics you may actually need to describe this perturbation must be
very very similar to the kind of mathematics used to describe weights
one then when the universe started the bain dominated by matter instead of by radiation
so let's just prior to the sound speed for body and because we know how
to compute that and then we can write it in this way then we plug
in the numbers and we get the sound speed for body and is much much
smaller than the sound speed than than the speed of light
in other words when the universe passed goals from brain radiation dominated
two something that looks like body and dominated something that behaves like this
then the genes length decreases immediately like that
by a factor three ten to define
and that
same is well like that from then radiation dominated the brain dominated by something like
which means that the gene smartarse
decreases by
you know two times ten to the fourteenth
perturbation inside your eyes and back then
you know it's a scale that is really be could grow only perturbation outside items
imagine how big they had to be they couldn't go
but suddenly then they can
so suddenly after the universe becomes matter dominated then you get to that the mass
of the perturbation the constantly growing is about ten to the five solar masses
surprise surprise
this is the size of the globular cluster sizes more galaxy
and surprise surprise it turns out that globular clusters of the object in the universe
that cost the all this the stellar population
is almost like as soon as the universe cooled started growing its perturbations former globular
clusters and then globular clusters that are forming stars and the stars that we see
today in globular clusters have an age that is very very close to the to
could have
but the universe expands and so now we've done everything forgetting about this function of
the universe and this function of the universe must do something for these
right because you have this perturbation the start collapsing and wants to be crafted by
gravity but you have the fabric of space-time that tends to you know looted away
and so there is going to be some sort of
the tug-of-war between these two different forces and so we have to write that in
the equation and we can do that by following are very very similar calculation as
we did before but reminding ourselves that when we write down the other that city
the background density gets diluted and sing and if it is among the
then he gets they looted like the scale factor to the minus three
and now
i will not to walk you through the all the steps of the equation because
it's boring and because you can do it in the comfort of your own
room or your own homes but what you end up having is an equation that
looks like this remember before we had an equation where we didn't have this that
we didn't have decided to adopt we only have delta doubled up and out
but now we have this extra term here and this looks a lot like you
know forms a and and and are
acoustic oscillation right
and this term here it's called hubble drug
somebody might be too much
or to go
or smoke
trying to achieve satisfaction through the mouth
of the sort they didn't get in this very early stage of development but it
can also be more abstract
if your roommate is dependent need
you could then go to your remains a your oral person
the first year of your life did not go well
a phrase even more popular
is there a stage
and that happens after oral stage
and problems can emerge
if toilet training is not correctly
if you have problems during those years of life becomes an animal
personality according to freud and you make it say your problem is you too
according to freud literally meant you're unwilling to part with your own feces
it's written down here i know
and the way it manifests itself as you know from just now people to talk
is compulsive
queen used in g
this is the anal personality
then it gets a little bit more complicated
on the next stage of the phallic stage actually this is not much more complicated
the focus of pleasure
shifts to the general
and fixations
can lead to excessive masculinity
in females
or if you have it nails or
if female need for attention or domination
now at this point something really interesting happens
call at this complex
and this is based on the story
the mythical story became who killed his father
and marry his mother
and according to freud this happens to all of us
in this way
well all of us by all of us
so here's the idea
three or four years old during the phallic stage
so what are you interested in what you interested europeans
and then you seek external or object for a sort of vague about this but
you know
think some sort of satisfaction but who's out there will be sweet and kind and
loving and wonderful
so to thailand for inference model is not
so far so fast it is not crazy
well boy falling in love his mother
now this is going to get progressively worse but i want to say as the
father of two two sons both sides went two phase where they explicitly said they
wanted to marry mommy and me
if something bad happened to be that would be the worst thing in the world
so so does this
but now
it gets a little bit aggressive so so the idea is the child determines
that he's he's going to kill his father
every three and four with texas
but then because children according to freud don't have a good sense of
the boundary between or mine in the world which is this a problem the problem
is is they don't they think their father
i can tell you that you're plotting to kill
and the figure father is now angry at them
and then they ask themselves what's the worst thing that could do to me
and the answer is
so they come to the conclusion that her father is going to castrate because their
illicit love for their money
and then they say that
and then don't think about sex
for several years
and that the latency stage the latency stage is going to used a moment
for the love of my
i wanted to kill my father
that is going to castrate may
i fell of my
that is x business
and it's x repressed until you get to the general state and the general stages
this stage we are all in
the healthy
adult stage
now adults in going through all the developmental stages
would you stand in words yet
unconscious mechanisms are still even if you haven't got fixated or anything
there's still this dynamic going on all the time
with you in your ego in user prego
and the idea is to use super eagle remember super eagle was stupid
super is only telling you
not to do bad things
it's telling you not to think about things
so what's happening is your e
is sending out all of this weird six stuff
all of these crazy sexual and violent desires of killing
i'll have sex with that
i have actually helping some i deserve
and then
you're super is necessary to say no
and this stuff is repressed it doesn't even make it to consciousness the problem is
for the very hydraulic theory
of what goes on
and some other stuff slips out
and it shows up in dreams and it shows up on slips of the tongue
and in exceptional cases it shows up in certain clinical symptoms
so what happens is
freud described a lot of normal life
as in terms of different ways we use
to keep that horrible stuff from the is making its way to consciousness and he
called these defense mechanisms
you're defending yourself against all the horrible parts
of yourself
some of these make a little bit of sense
i mean one way to describe this in non-technical non freudian ways certain things about
ourselves rather not know
certain desires rather not know
and we have ways to hide
so for instance are sublimation
sublimation is you might have a lot of energy
maybe sexual energy are aggressive energy
but instead of turning into a sexual or aggressive target we do is you focus
in some other way
so you can imagine a great artists like castles
i i
we going to
one thing
much more
i mean
one year
good morning
all his
here we
before i move on i want to the to the junction tree
algorithm but but before before i backtrack a bit
judging from some questions bring the break let me go back to some of these
just to recap and sort of point out how these kinds of sum product and
max product algorithm is why these inference problems would actually be interesting in practice
right so let's go back to the stereo pair
member of what you're trying to do is to figure out an optimal shift between
these two guys to try and match them so you can detect that
what people actually do in practice is
they can model the pair image field and what the modelling is not the pixels
now what sort of trying to model is what's the shift the relative disparity shift
between the two images
so what you're trying to compute every point is
you've got to images and you're trying to compute for every point how much is
this point shifted relative to this point in in the two images how much is
this point here shifted relative the shift is going to change a lot depending on
the depth if you think about the geometry of it as the depth changes the
amount of shift is going to change so it's that shift called disparity that allows
for instance artificial system to recover a depth
and so in terms of the graphical model of message passing
we don't know quite how to solve this problem yet but this is really one
of those motor problems or most probable configuration what sort of thinking about his modelling
the set of possible disparities using one of these big lattice models will be much
bigger than this of course
and what you'd like to do is sort of search over all the disparities to
find the one that's most probable
what you're doing is sort of modeling the set of disparities in statistical or probabilistic
way that's what he is these compatibility functions here telling you this sort of telling
you how likely are you see certain relatives ships
and so
there's lot of heart of people in computer vision spent a long time figuring out
what the right functions here to use let's not worry about that but at a
high level the key thing is that this is exactly in in prince problem and
the interesting thing this is an inference problem that you are doing right now that
you know all mammals with the most members of bayan ocular visual systems are solving
implicitly this inference problems on the fly all the time
so it's it's interesting that were capable of doing it but currently computers were not
so good at it yet
so that's one example of inference let me maybe talk a bit about graphical codes
in and explain how this and other inference problem here
i didn't cover the slide before but
remember the coding problem was thinking about transmitting a message to your neighbor it could
be people speaking or could be computers talking to one another
if you're concerned about the fact that the channel over which was speaking has noise
so sent something it doesn't get received exactly
and you have to somehow protect you have to fight that noise
so the way graphical codes are built we now consider understand this picture but that
this is a factor graph and so what you want about the seven notes here
these are
it would be binary very labels they were telling you're going to be sending a
string of seven zeros or ones
so this would allow you to send a certain set of messages to your friend
you you know you might have messages that are text but you would sort of
map them to binary strings and that's what you mean to send
what's key here that you're not sending just any one of these strings you can
only send certain subsets
so that's the factor graph comes in this guy thing about him is that as
the policeman is going to check up on a bit one three five and seven
the way these particular graphs workers
what he each checks he checks the parity of those four bits so he wants
there to be an even number of ones
so this guy this guy's find is zero zero zero zero at those four positions
so zero wants this guy is bad he's got zero zero zero one so he's
not a codewords so this is something that doesn't get sent this is something that
you could send
the decoding problem say your wireless card is transmitting to the wireless base station
so your wireless card sending the strings of zeros and ones