the columns of the matrix would be an identical
plates but which would be orthogonal
you know ninety degrees aligned was the first one so you have these rules you
know here and is here
and this would be the inputs and this would be the outputs and you could
exemplify what is this learning like you know in this in the hands will simplified
visual style
well you have an association between input
rho and an output column if there is a hole drilled
that creates the communication between the first plateau in the second flight sick this could
be hydraulic model of plasticity of memory now if you have an input you can
just put a little bit of water in one of the rules and it goes
in fields
you know the rules and groups
into the commons you can collect into the core this time and and you will
get your output runs
OK so so i'm hoping people will have other ideas of that kind and i
was inspired by some of the kids that people made and that they saw the
lawrence hall of science which is very close to where i live
and you can now buy you know for between ten and twenty dollars a teacher
for four kids where you can make experiments on your kitchen counter
in electromagnetism in chemistry and mechanics and all the elements that that you need to
do the experiments you can find you know in in your kitchen essentially
so i was thinking well one do that for learning as well we can have
the simple experiments that illustrate with very concrete objects what it is to to learn
and in the process of doing that actually i think it will make us also
reflect on what would you know the very basic principles that matter for
for science
so i would like to to state this effort and and slowly build it up
i think there is opportunity for us to write more wikipedia articles
because wikipedia is a great vehicle for the for the broad public the opportunities to
the amount of the volume of documentation that there is in the past calendar website
and also i think make the pascal website more visible so people should know about
its should know that there is material here for example i didn't know myself that
there were all these videos that were available so people should be downloading it from
from the outside and it would be great if people you know which started making
games and interactive software that is that this pedagogical and vision that we can have
a website that would link to all these different resources
and then i talked about in the kitchen counter demos for children and adults
and more sophisticated demonstrations that could be then presented in science museums or in or
in schools and could be then part of teaching curricula as well
so it is my attempt as a two proposing a number of themes around which
we can we group
four different types of research
i'm thinking of two poles
so the top call has to do about learning
as a means of helping survival
so why do we need to learn as much as
physical entities or humans as animals why do we need to we need to learn
to survive two
to improve or quality of life and live and so on the second goal of
learning i think is creation so level is against the basic thing that need to
do first and then afterwards you have some spare time and you have you know
succeeded in surviving qx brain energy
you can spend it on on creation
and to create things you also need to learn from your peers so if you're
an artist you you will learn from the past artists you know and if you
are a researcher who learn from past researchers to make new creations
so those two poles
for me would be fueled by a certain number
a fundamental building blocks so the
intention survival and creation of the applications and what the red
blocks here are the the material that that you need in order to
tell you
well might have revealed that the very start
it's really laughs
the reconstruction was saying the
this is really
function and the way
really this series
i'm sorry that really late
you sort of sort
why it's true
it's the ages
to find the coefficients
and the as put everything back together
so all
is a scaling function
so the full picture is
OK i this
link function is usually written detailed views of features
and the way that use the word w told uses h ones
but those are
those are in this step of finding coefficients
so you don't really see them
and in the reconstruction CS
the discrete time
here w
right so
very good if i rewrite full filter bank
the signal goes through
each zero and h one
now if transformed
we compress
inverse transform upset fall
the other filters
after one of the pieces together
and you
reconstruct x
just writing what we
we're looking at last week
so the whole point is
it is
these numbers
the filters
are by very same numbers
go into
continuous time
these numbers
changing faces
the coefficients in new basis
continuous time these are the spaces
and she said w given the bases
the coefficients
it connects everything still
they don't wish repeat don't wish
magic numbers because she was the first to five
numbers that work
just what
the numbers were
one plus
three bus route three
three miles three three one nine three three were
it's not enough one is the flip
i guess is
and that's where we are going to the trouble fly
h one n one
so those
one is the
the same four numbers here
because it over she was shooting for cycle
she uses the same four numbers but
signed first
by reversing every other signs i do get a high pass filter
and this guy is orthogonal to that guy
the result of orthogonality of vectors is orthogonality
we it's
that was it it you might read the original paper by don't wish
i field
thank you
communications on
you're an applied math
when applied it's york university courant institute journal
it's just
very striking paper for the amount of
inside brought the progress is made on the problem
extremely tough to go back to the second problem was to find the basis
that was orthogonal
this is the distinction
because of course
and as you might
that is
is what you are
course you are
i find it was on its back right
and on top of
so we should i
the those
you my
this is far
and the sense of from the
the change was in between two rules
and which was the gap between men
as you will that right now
this is really do need to what's just
so many wrong is not from the perspective so so
the BBC's you all
and he is
peace now runs in a game
the sense of
is a
one of the simplest kind
so this is
this is
so this is my computer
they're lying
rule also states that this
random or nine lots of space
yeah i see through his
it is that it is
what are these procedures
for was
i don't know that
some problems of my master at low robots
and it doesn't matter to me
these are the the role
and now for you
the the business
that comes rules one
now that the main thing is to find
it's not
i see no
which is the
there's an image
now again from most
i find hard to read i see no
that means this is that
so in two dimensions because it is
one reason is this
it just means there
so this is how it works so in two dimensions
here this
large the rules inside this
and the amazing assumptions in this tutorial
and this
i thought that the name
this is a
so you see what i mean
one is
i i was too
of e
dot elves dot product
so the line integral
equals minus the
and this is a magnetic flux
through road surface
that you test
two that closed loop it is an open service
any surface
you may choose is fine
it is an open service i cannot
stress that enough
you choose a closed loop
you can do it right here in space
you can attest to that an open service which could bones out into the audience
any moment in time
this the whole
so whenever you deal with
the line integrals
so let's do
the line integral
and then see what that
boundary condition that leads to
so we do the same thing with their
so we have here conductor
and here we have a vacuum
and so he field here
everywhere zero
here is your electric field vector coming in
from your electromagnetic wave
so here is your e t
here is your and
exactly in the way
that i find this is the normal component to serve
now i'm going to make a closed loop
this is my closed loop
from surprise you
that i choose it this way
and i'm going to march around the closed loop in any direction that i want
to i chose this direction makes no difference which direction
you choose
that this be dl
and that this
the db
i'm going to do exactly the same thing
i'm going to go in the limiting case when dl goes to zero so they
get the boundary condition
at the
so if you're ready for this i start here
and i move in this direction so the EU the UFT has no impact because
it's perpendicular to the direction of motion so the dot product is zero so all
i worry about is this one
and so i get one half could e of and
and one half
one of the l let's suppose that this is one half of the l and
this is one
but that's when i go from here to here
so now we go from here to here
and of course you've and has no effect because it's perpendicular to dl
l is a vector in the direction that i'm moving
so now i only deal with u of t
now we get plus
he of t
times the
now i mean i go down
so now you have to use up i go down to the dot product creates
a minus sign
so now we get
one of
and so on
l a set u of t but diamond you've you've and is in this direction
and you're moving in this direction
so that's why you get a minus sign and you've has no effect
because is perpendicular to the wind direction of motion and the electric field here is
so this now
becomes minus
chains of the
magnetic flux through
that surface
this surface if you wish or surface boulders out in the audience i don't care
it is minus
the phi
and that
goes to zero
because i'm going to make the non-zero so there is no surface left
so that one goes to zero
notice that this one
councils of again this one
so now we find
that is that at the boundary condition
and gential
but that's the one
i want to remind you though that is the skin depth
so in reality
there's an exponential decay
all of this
e vector
that is in the service that decays exponentially over that
the skin depth delta that we discussed earlier
that is that skin
so that is the kernel of b
which is your two
so you're going to do a closed loop integrals
of these ltl you work your way through that
and then you will find
the magnitude
of b of t
that is the
component of the magnetic field in the plane of the conductor attentional component
that magnitude
his museo
what we call
of s is the surface
current density and it has units and p is the leader
and so
i actually currents
oscillatory currents
on the surface
that occur when the electromagnetic wave comes in these currents change with the frequency of
course of incident radiation
so not only
is there all the time
readjustment of rove s which is the surface
charge density
but all the time is that electromagnetic wave interacts with the conductor
it's going to be a current
in order to make sure
that we need
this boundary condition so real things are really happening
so we can use these four boundary conditions now
you start looking into some
results and i will start with a very simple example
because i can demonstrate that
and you can delete leaving sorry this is not actually very yesterday for example you
can believe that
when you add more and more of adding more and more by grams to to
a model
entropy of models so number amount of information in the model
and field
increases pretty fast
every new piece of information is important this information talking about
frequent word of frequent viagra
but then
you can see that number of information usually
increases very very slow
and i think that you have this intuition
that's only
some small number of war
i have some strange distributions that whereas with a very free
all the roads and all other combinations of words are pretty random and they uniformly
how we can do this
imagine that we have not only unigram model not on the distribution of earth to
but also
higher order models
viagra model trying to model
so we can use
simpler model
models of low order
next models
imagine that you have this stuff you know they are going to use this model
in our system and we don't want to create huge files and some complex social
structures were loaded something into memory
going to seed for example model
three gram model of the whole english language
into memory of all ordinary computer
more than that because it's not the main task of all search engine we only
suggesting result
maybe we can feed it in the number of megabytes in our memory
what do we want to
we can create
our model
for example from unigram model three grandmother
then we can assume that we have some
algorithm that can calculate
probability for high order model
using results from
three this order models
using this algorithm are called usually such
collection is called the coffin in the english one
and then we can come up with
OK to have this information from all higher order models
and they have the same probability but calculated using low order models
and become quite them and if you see that we already had
i have pretty good
the difference in this really is lower than some threshold
we can simply remove
this from higher order models
and then we can do it interracial so we can
starting from from for example
the higher order model because of the highest order model in this is the biggest
i understand that for example we have much more power so worse than simple words
and three grounds is much more than viagra
so we can
stop pruning from the highest order
and do it in iteration always control precision of all
and removed
this probability that can be predicted by another information
how can we use
low order model to predict probability of higher order demand
consider this
simplest around have unigram model and they have environment
so you have probability for word one word two
this is a slide
then we can
of black
simply using ordinary formula of
probabilities of conditional probabilities
but we have
this so
the probability of just war we have
they don't have combine probability from the above
combining probability about two
but what we can do can
i have
independent assumptions
you can think OK
this more completely independent
if there are completely independent
the quran is simply
play of
case we can we can use it
this human behaviour would entail and just briefly go through this spatial reasoning is of
interest having the memory i mean making mistakes not not too often i think twice
is OK but three four five times becomes a bit tedious commonsense reasoning using goals
in what you do
possibly some gold using tactics planning in team games communicating with each other coordinating what
you do adapting if you see that what you do doesn't work to change and
these are in the way the most interesting ones human behavior sometimes pretty unpredictable ways
but often interesting ways and they have errors and weaknesses they make errors and have
weaknesses but these have to be again not running into one weaknesses right you want
exploitability weaknesses
and interesting weaknesses and then if you explain them three times you want to that
have to be closed right because the funders in finding another weakness that you could
so here's an example of that that is actually being done in commercial games
the idea is to control a car on the track and the first goal is
to have a to follow a certain line on the course in in a believable
and also handle interaction like recovering when you happen to bump into the wall or
or a handle interaction in the sense of overtaking people
the other thing that people then i thought about was wouldn't it be great if
the car if we could emulate the driving style of particular driver so if you
were playing the game and you would have to go to the toilet you could
just switch on your substitute driver you driver as it's called and that
guy would then go on there there were others there are other ideas like you
train up your driver ta and he plays online tournaments against other drivers and so
you have to play in tournaments director your more like the culture of of the
so the example two examples in which this has actually been carried out when is
colin macrae rally
and there neural networks were used to to learn how to negotiate track but directly
of course it's relatively simple in the sense that there was little interaction between the
cars in this game is about negotiating a given track in
as short time period as possible and
but the i was using neural networks and that that seems to work quite well
another example is forza motorsports that's some colleagues of mine a working on that and
it's going to be released for the x-box in a couple of months and this
is where these driving this driver technology is being used so one of the features
is that you can actually drive the car for a few tracks and then the
computer learns your particular choice of of a of the line for the track
so the idea is quite simple i don't want to go into the details here
what you you need to player in the game for learning you have this avatar
that you want to train and you use the learning algorithm and the game state
is sent to the player and the avatar and the learning algorithm
the player then behave in certain ways and
the learning algorithm and the game of course get this information and the avatar behave
in certain ways
and then the learning algorithm can give feedback
depending on the discrepancy between the behaviour of the avatar and the behaviour of human
and that's the learning process so this is example
this is an example of a of the racing line here on a given track
the blue thing is the racing line and
this is rolled try ralf herbrich my colleague trying to follow the racing line as
precisely as possible
later i he was tired i guess
that's essentially the training data
these young people in the audience you should know
uh and all this additional information so that's high dimensional data as well
another area i work is computational biology gene expression
so you can characterize the state of the cell
effectively be concentration and location of all the chemical compounds that are in so i
think the size of the state space
u have i don't know if my memory is something like thirty thousand genes in
your body eta those genes has products
maybe in the form of proteins many many more proteins and the are genes
so if we think of the state of an individual wanted yourselves
u need not millions
variables that characterize the state at any given time plus position
velocity everything very
very very high dimensional
how do we deal with complex data so i tried to simulate some complex data
and this is very much starting from what goes on in a low dimensional because
typically people don't show you images of high dimensional data because you can't visualize it
so when i first started doing machine learning it
u looked data like this it looks complicated but people had techniques for dealing with
this they had mixtures of gaussians models and hear with the so called located in
the center and a little ellipsoid
denoting um
thee covariance if the
you've got a mixture of gaussians bit about data which think that's really good because um
now looks quite complex in terms of data and density modeling is something we want to do
understand the density of the data and i tell you is actually perfect because it's
these model i generated the data from so this is even if it from the
data this is the true model
once you've seen use anything
complex structure isn't a problem for mixtures galcians yeah i mean it can model these
things quite well people do a lot of effort into selecting the number components into
dealing with the fact that there is
multiple local minima
but fundamentally surely that's the problem solved
that's not the case and it's not the case i'd argue because the way you
look at data in two dimensions is somehow so the wrong and the galaxy and
maybe a nice model in two dimensions but straightforward calcium
calcium where you're not thinking about what you're doing
so if you just apply calcium and that its covariance in high dimensions it's gonna
be quite a bad model very often
i still argue the gaussians can be very useful you can do a range of things gaussians but
you have to do things like structure the covariance matrix
in order to fit them
why is it you know this is the sort of thing that
i came into machine learning from a fairly naive perspective that in those days machine
learning this was about how the brain works and neural networks is how the brain
works and these bunch people came along with support vector machines and messed it all
finally with deep learning going back to doing what we were doing fifteen years ago back to
these are the drawing these circles and putting lines between them
on and i came in from mechanical engineering background with the naive view that neural
networks is where it's at and then when i saw these statistical models mixture of
gaussians i thought well surely they're very powerful to
but i think the reason that they aren't as widely used as they should be
is because in high dimensional data they typically don't work very well
these two-dimensional parts against can be misleading and a low dimensional intuitions can fail
dramatically and there's a couple major issues
in high dimensions in a guassian density all data actually moves to a shell
now i'm gonna try and show you visualize what i mean by moving to a
shell you may have heard this before
there is no data near the mean of the gaussians so
way of thinking about clustering model like this is what you're saying about your data
and i like this way of thinking about it is that each data point is
really a prototype that's the mean the calcium
has then been corrupted in some way according to the covariance calcium so you're saying
you represent your data by prototypes that the mean
plus corruption which is the covariance how they move away from the mean
sometimes you don't show this thing
what what what moves
so for this from a patient you have an ordering
i have an ordering
of items
it's called full full full ranking
so in this let's two
it's called for ranking because all of these orders meaningful
and this bar he is
it tells you that you prefer the heat and item
on the left
of it
so this year this thing here
is what i wrote in blue
you know this permutation leads to
it's this
or this for ranking the order of the
but i would say that
i do this
the set of items
no large
and large here means
maybe anything larger than
anything larger than thirty is because you know the number of possible
permutation with the
and this is quite
to deal with
so that comes this
this idea of partial rankings
you know of talk about core sets
so how you how you make partial rankings
you take this presentation
then you multiply
by a subgroup
this subgroup while
i will
use the following notation here
this means that
this subgroup
the first two numbers
and the last one
it's a
you don't care
so all elements that fixed the first two numbers
good you take those elements for this approach
and they all did
the are that's that
the order the ordering of the the
two numbers can
can move fixed and
doesn't matter
so this
this this will create the following
all agree
this gives you an ordering
permutation pi
this is an
normally used
notation for politicians
partition one one two
you know the sum of this thing has to be the order of the group
and in this case for
we have to construct the first and show you
first of all which are the elements elements of these
of the subgroup here
certainly the identities here
because the identity
the identity
with which fix everybody
one is
that's that's we use here not this notation look i'm not using various appliances
i'm only using the the
resulting order of the
permutation so this is the identity
one two three four
and this is one from of limitation that fix
the first two numbers
look less and less like the underlying distribution
in this case you started off good but as time goes on you might get
example but it is simply concentrated near the boundary
and so you know how some labels later what you're left with is a training
set looks very unlike the underlying distribution
and so now the question is do we really want to optimize with respect to
this training set
it's very different from the distribution we actually care about who knows maybe by being
close maybe the point right near the boundary are actually noisy points and we don't
want to pay all that much attention to their labels
OK but simon says that many ways in which to sort of summarize what the
issue is
the simplest way to say this
is that it's the problem of biased sampling
OK that you
as time goes on your training set looks very different from the distribution you actually
care about and so there is some danger in optimizing with respect to the training
so by the way feel free to stop me at any time
any questions
this is the nature of the activity
this choose
you are
yeah it but it seems like this one does want to choose informative points and
yet at the same time one wants the resulting classifier to do well with respect
to random looking points
so it looks like this is going to be some sort of trade-off or there's
some source of conflict of the here and so the question is how does one
resolve this conflict and
so that's the sort of thing that will be talking about
so concerned about bias
on the distribution of the four themselves
one of the finest
the control labels given one
as you can see the
no so so they they bought the right to be able to source confirms the
second would be a source of concern
right so it's so so the two
the two
the two problems the first is that the the distribution of the x values is
not nature's distribution of the x values and the second is the distribution of y
given x might be different you know you might be by focusing on the boundary
you might essentially be in regime where the distribution of y given x is something
like point five always and so those labels might be less reliable
so this this is sort of at a high level and a little bit you
know touchy-feely this whole issue of sampling bias so just to make it more concrete
let's look at a specific example
OK so here is the sort of generic strategy that i talked about and i
said that the variance of it but i was just looking at the kind of
a high level
OK and now suppose that you know just to just to keep things simple suppose
we have a really easy hypothesis class OK so the data all lie on the
line so the one dimensional dataset and each hypothesis is just the boundary on the
line and to one side is green and to the other side it's right OK
so a really simple sort of a hypothesis class
now here's an example of the data distribution
forty five percent of the points like in the greens forty five percent live here
and these are red
and so on in the middle you have two and a half percent richardson in
two and a half percent agreed to see what would happen in one of these
in one of the active learning heuristics
so you start by sampling from random points but since the
data predominantly lies in these two clusters at the far ends let's just say the
initial batch of points pretty much like here and here
OK so you look at those two points maybe have four points here in four
points and the other one and you do something like you know a maximum margin
classifier something and based on that people the boundary somewhere in here
OK now you're going to query points close to the boundary to end up wearing
points in here
i sometimes and it's time goes on you will
query points closer and closer to this middle point and you basically end up converging
to this hypothesis
now this hypothesis has got five percent error because it gets things wrong in the
optimal hypothesis is this one
because it has only two and a half percent error
OK so this is an example of
the problem of sampling bias
basically what happens is that
you know you start with this hypothesis that sort of in the middle of all
of you greens and reds it looks like a good hypothesis and then you become
really confident that all of these have to be read
but you really have no justification for being so confident it's misplaced confidence and so
you end up with you end up with an algorithm that
not even consistent you know which is which is a fairly basic statistical guarantee you
forget about optimizing the number of labelled one would hope that as the number of
labelled goes to infinity at least converge to the right page and in this case
that wouldn't happen
OK it but it's something that's not consistent
and it's an example of
an example of how this might play out in practice if you if you think
back to that pedestrian identification pedestrian detection thing you about it that after seeing the
first few labelled images the learning system this gino then sees an image of a
fire hydrant
and it's completely certain it's a human being you know a child or something like
that and so it will never ask for its label there's no there's no need
you know
the cluster of fire hydrants in the space of data is the cluster fly hydrants
in a cluster of phone books that look like this the cluster of fire hydrant
so everything
there's been a bunch of experimental work is this an example of that
there's an example of
sort of study in
so this is the the text classification setting in which the sort of hidden cluster
effect in word you have one of these active learning heuristics where initial sampling process
missus some clusters
and and as a result the learners completely sure about the label of the cluster
at the local level there are some zigzagging so we want to keep might be
the sp three hybridization
sp three
gives bonding along
the chain
that in fact
and this is one hundred nine degree angle
and also if you are really close you say well this is clearly bad but
if you make this long enough you get far enough back
in a general sense this is termed a straight
this is termed a straight chain straight chain
there's there's one other thing that is is similar to
what we've seen in the past in the case of
of silicate and not shown here
the as long as we got one hundred nine degrees
along this axis between the other bonds there's no specification what happens down here
so this this should remind you of what happens in a silicate when
the oxygen is done online
so it's possible to get disorder and so here you see
one case where
you have the the hydrogens on adjacent carbons
not facing one another words here there are lined up so if i were to
look on and from
the left down the chain i would only see one
the all the hydrogens are lined up and we call this configuration eclipse configuration is
slightly high energy whereas this is a little bit lower energy staggered and what's the
fact that the effect is not to give us the straight chain that goes
in the line for that you have to have the eclipse configuration here's two
examples of c seventeen h thirty six
they're both straight chain because once twisting a little bit more than the other inherent
talking about just the carbon carbon bond twisting these are both terms straight chain but
they have different conformations
so this is starting to make you think about
the plurality of possibilities even within the same chemical composition that would be
present in polymers here we've only got seventeen imagine if instead of seventeen became seventeen
what this condition
this is an example of what we mean by straight chain but it doesn't mean
that it's a rod like
OK but i can now show you something that's not straight chain so let's also
look at something called a branched chain
that's different and go look at one
go look at butane
you know that's the gas temperature is users
fuel for
cigarette lighters guess that's not pcr or so
we all now we can use it for lighting candles
right useful i think i can say that
well i can do it so let's look at the butane so that's number four
right so i'm just as smooth things along it's possible to just write them in
a straight line even though we know these are hundred ninety degrees
and we know that if there's nothing put at the end of the stick we
assume it's hydrogen so all of these are hydrogen carbon hydrogen linkages so i've got
one two three four
carbons are about one two three four five six seven eight nine ten so this
is as it should be c four h
ten and certainly this is
this is identical to
something that could be represented as follows
right so now i'm going to have the four
outlining a tetrahedron so there's one two
three four one two three four one two three four
remember when you're in carbon chemistry four sticks four sticks of every car
as what check
OK so this is
this is the the linear
but there's another way is another way we can do this into the following we
can put
and if one of the carbon
i put a branch
branch and then i'm going to use the force the rule
so one two three
one two so one two three four this has one two three
so let's count one two three four four carbons
and three
six nine ten ten hydrogen so on a formula basis this is also a butane
but it's the different noises as as a solid state chemist we're we're
very much attuned to molecular structure in this molecular structure the linear one is different
from this one is the branch one so this one is called iso butane
and the other way to look at it is
the backbone is only three carbons
so the backbones only three cards according to this rule there should be some kind
of propane
this another way to name this is called a propane
but it's got instead of just hydrogens one of the propane
how we started the transformation process approximately
well in concrete in OT employees about
twelve months ago
we started renewing our values
we checked
that's how can forty five thousand people making not a very human company that delivers
human technology
we need to change
so the nokia way had to be in years and values need to be changed
so our business is changing
and we know that it's of the dialogue with technology markets
we annihilating all the time with the society sorry of this
this going going from and another way to another just should be time so what
we did was that we opened we used to like
two ways of
driving the change
we had high touch
and then we had high tech by high touch women that we organised so-called nokia
way cafes as the method we
rolled around we went to
we went around the world in fifty nine days we had this huge participation in
one-day workshops where people from different types of works different layers of the organisation has
the flat company we do have still some layers
is that we met and we discussed about values had to renew them
and how to what does it mean for us as individuals the company to become
an internet company and then on
on me
fourteen to seventeen
and we organised nokia way jam
and that was the combination wisdom of the crowds combined with artificial intelligence
and that was something that i do is i will remember all my life because
there were seventy seven hours online and i was awake sixty hours of that so
this is how we renewed nokia way process so we engaged people first we started
deliver print airline tickets to mars
and the question was that one of our values you would like to
what kind of our ways of working you would take we due to the journey
of the market to mars had like two times for your suitcase i me and
then the habits the bad habits that you wanted to
one did you leave behind and we made small and we wanted to make it
fun we make like small inquiries we ordered like gadgets of small small and well
i forgot to bring a small
yet it would symbolize the martian
and then we had the video in on top senior leader saying that the question
was what what is the colour of martian
and then we started by loading actually that what what really is the journey about
we used real marketing
and that's something that so when delivering these airline tickets
and the idea was that hey share with your own crew and so the people
who think that have a good idea
in in how we should look like in the future well dull corporate internal comms
we got two questions after this
first one was what's the right answer for the question what is the colour of
right there is no right answer
and the second was was that what does it mean because i haven't got yet
the airline ticket and we were going like
this is so nineties then that there is no right answer all the color side
equal and by the way here five airline tickets to you coming immediately and shared
with your best friends and so we got the mix of the good mix of
people and we renewed our values we had a world cup faster sharing where our
CEO extent but so not without giving any notes had to confirm four new values
they had build from our previous ones they are achieving together engaging you meaning both
consumers and using employee achieving together
and very human and passion for innovation and i think the latter last one is
why we are here and then it was time for nokia way jam
we were the first
but first commercial customer of of the IBM so in that was our vendor we
have again fun that's very crucial in when trying to block
and generation people to work with as it has to be fun
well i forty five and about forty five thousand
thousand employees and then we need to kind of exclude our factory employees because they
involvement to nokia way jam was bit different and we we have forty five percent
of our our employees participate in jamming the the ball of the jam was threefold
it first of all
it was kind of to ensure what's happening
so let's first do
look at the consequence of the conservation
of mechanical energy
very powerful concept
and as long as we deal with gravity
you can always use
you see here on the desk something that looks like a roller coaster
and i'm going to slide and objects
from this direction
created a little bit better
he was that roller coaster
this is
and then it goes up again
and that if circle has radius are
this point eight
i release it
zero speed i assume that there is no friction for now
this point b
i define here
y equals zero one is even more important i defined it
you equals zero
and this is the direction of the direction of y
at eighty object has no
velocity no speech
a b of course it does
it has converted some potential energy
the kinetic energy at this point c
is had reached maximum
velocity that it can ever have because all the potential energy has been converted to
kinetic energy
and at this point the
if it ever reaches that point
that will be
the velocity say
OK i start off
o point is at a different distance h
above this level
and so i apply on the conservation of mechanical energy
so i know that
you have a
plus the kinetic energy at any
which is zero
must be you would be
plus kinetic energy b
must be u ed
plus kinetic energy density must be you would be less kinetic energy and if there
is no friction no other forces only gravity so we lose no
no energy goes lost in terms of friction
we know that this
by different
these two are
so now i can write this in general terms of y
o point six this
this point the single that being
location y above zero line
and i can write down now
that you a which is MGH
that was given when i started that was all the energy i had it was
my total mechanical energy if i call this you zero which is free choice i
you have be which is now
and g
plus one half
the square at that position why they should hold what you see there should hold
every point
that i have yet to hold for a full b was seen for the for
any point
i lose my and
and so you find here
we summarize the squared
the clothes
two g
time h minus y
so they should hold for all these points
therefore it should also hold for pointing
at point d
that is
something very important there is a requirement
there is a requirement that there is a centripetal acceleration
which is in this direction
eight centripetal
and that centripetal acceleration
is a must
for this object
to reach that point to d
that centripetal acceleration is we remember from when we played with the bucket of water
that is the squared
divided by or
and this
must be larger
or equal
to the gravitational acceleration g
if it is not larger
the bucket of water wouldn't have made it to that point to d
so this is my second equation that i'm going to use to look very carefully
so the square must be larger or equal than
so i have here the screen which is two g
times age
minus y but why for that point he
these two or
so i put in two are
must be larger or equal
two g are
lose my g
o two h minus for our
must be larger
o equal to our
q h was be larger or equal
two and half hours
there's is a classic result
that almost every person who has taken physics will remember
it by no means intuitive
it means that if i have this boy and i'll show you shortly
and i let the ball
go into this rollercoaster
that it will not
make this point
we defined as well class in
we saw that very nice properties
we formulated the spectral clustering algorithm that we just so it's more or less computing
i vectors in doing this implicit embedding into
our t for some t
and this gives you a clustering in some way
and here we see no way of
why this might actually be a good thing
at least in innocent
so if causes derivation
as lots of
lots of things what i didn't tell you is
of course
you want to find more than two clusters you need to something different here
it becomes a bit more complicated than that i really have light on it but
what what essentially to do here is actually might have like
i have it on the slide
essentially what you do is you don't just define one indicator vector
but we define a matrix of indicator vectors
so you could find something like
if you if you want to find k clusters
you define the class then became director of
which is just
i is zero
excise in the cluster ck
and it's one otherwise
so you case that indicator vectors
and and then you can do it actually by matrix which which is similar to
the ones i presented to you but the mass gets a bit longer so i
don't want to show it
can can write down a very similar way and what you end up
so this matrix eight years actually what is what they call a few so maybe
call it a ge
so it's just a matrix of the cluster indicator vectors
one can then see
but one can write spectral clustering in a similar way i did but you just
now in the matrices here instead of just f transpose unless we had no the
matrix h transpose lh
this matrix just as many columns of this
classes we want to find
and then there's some more complicated version of this very with serum which also tells
you now
that the solution of this problem
consists in taking the first k i was
so this is
once you understood the first thing this is just doing them as a bit more
complicated so it will work out
OK and actually have right up where you can look it up if you want
to explain later
OK so
i showed you the simplified problem where we just say we want to minimize cut
subject to a equals b
if you do ratiocut
it becomes a bit more complicated again actually the main trick is you just need
to be a bit more clever when defining the vector s
and then everything else works of
and it's exactly the same principle we also do the exercises you one
so what happens then is if we do the same thing for a ship at
the end of the
exactly the thing we ended up
simpler version the angle vectors of the mathematics and
if we don't do the same for normalized cut the whole
mechanism works again after twenty here there but in principle it works and then
you just end up looking at the eigenvectors of l about the anxieties of the
normalized graph laplacian
the intuition is now
if you if you look at
clustering from this graph theoretic perspective where you want to find clusters in data which
partitions of a graph
then if you
i want to minimize ratiocut
if you take the iron makers of l use unnormalized spectral clustering two as the
if you want to find out if you want to optimize on the normalized cut
you just take the i can vectors of the normalized graph laplacian and then it's
called normalized spectrum
sorry how
four OK
OK so that's it
for many clustering algorithms so first of all
they just output
the clustering of the data like the discrete partition of the data set to give
them as input
now there are different ways to know that you can the most standard way or
maybe the most appropriate way would be
so in some way you need to extend the clustering to the whole data space
so that you can create new data points
and for some algorithms like in a very simple you just assign them to the
next centuries some of the trivia
for some i mean for spectral clustering this mathematical way of doing it
but i don't want to explain there so
you can see that instead of taking matrices you can do it in a continuous
basically take integral operators whatever and then you can define it but that's actually very
complicated and nobody does it apart from mathematicians so what i suggest practices
i mean essentially extending clustering tools spaces classification right so you have a data set
you have labels on part of training points and the points if labels on them
now you want to assign labels to other data points so this is exactly the
problem of classification so you need to sort of justification problem as an extension operator
of clustering
and then of course a lot of questions i mean what classifier and so on
so it's it's that's nothing which is really trivial so
but of course it across the problem in practice
OK so there are a few things which i want to comment on that
OK we so i've already told but i want to stress again so we don't
have any quality whatsoever
when the relaxation beat
is anything related to the problem originally wanted to sort of
so somehow
but things can happen and you can construct examples very bad things happen but those
examples often very and constructed
in practice this often works surprisingly well it's really i mean if you compare spectral
clustering to other clustering algorithms
at compared to k means it usually works
the reason why we use
k means in this final step after the embedding in three so they actually wasn't
reason so this is just after the embedding
suggesting that any out more less should be able to
five one b can index
first of all let's decide how we can
put all the information that we created this index into temporary five
the simplest idea what we can do
so i don't know why but in all this slide i put it from
right to left is likely of writing on the desktop
but what we can do it can take
first works
then we can put a number of course in this work
then reporting
number of documents then the next sentence
so far and going and doing this procedure so we the file
this file contains sort it
he is from all
index file all words sorted
this is the order in which processing our dictionary
and for every he
you have the document is always sorted
in order of increasing because
we decided that we are adding documents
in creating and using increasing idea of this document
when he
index enough documents of
keep all memory bees
so OK we don't have enough memory
we simply take our index from memory and write this file this structure
we want to match them
how to model them
because every temporary file is already sort
it's very easy to create an article started fires
and the reason is
married and so on
and the result is very very simple algorithm
imagine that we have
only two stars
and what are doing
we are taking work from phil source and
work from second source
and they look OK
first is smaller
so in this case from the first stars that put into the output index
four and post lists of this works
then moved
four in this first index index
now we are equal
we have put into the results only one word
and in i was first leased and then put was this to this word
and in doing so
four for the whole two
sets of data
this was
so we're taking two words from from two possibilities
we see that we have the same word can be put into our numerous index
to it's dictionary put the first work a in this example
then we see that
in both files
there are
two closely
link to
so we that input for this work to postulate
then we see that there are different
and a smaller we are processing a b
then this species to be and
so we're doing this again and again and to emerge index
this is a very common variation in
in data processing if we have sorted data
because every temporary index is already started the whole industry is very easy to create
and this is very good separation because
again during this process
the always working only with the one
sure processing right now
and we actually don't care about all ports for this work because the energy only
when we can merge
but by force so
we are very limited
on memory you can use very small amount of memory
we know how many iterations iterations will do
and also
as i said in the second lecture
more than half is always faster than they doing sequential access when accessing byte by
byte and they don't do any jumps ahead or
keeping data
so this is linear access to data and it's also very
so what
merge its basic
algorithm that
nearly every search engine is doing during building index
any open source project that saw
during the building of the index is doing this
you can
i see this as a very good example of this in a very good example
so you can see that
it builds everything in memory
created this temporary index
down into the file into the into a temporary file
and then they are them
two there
bigger index
this is the main approach
without this approach if you're trying to create index
so another another approaches try to remove from memory possibly indexing
combine them together
but i can assure you that this approach is much faster than ever everything that
has been invented
during the whole history of feuding of indexes
OK so
we are going to compress so index and also said sometimes
data is not on the smaller
but we can access it fast
and in the second lecture during my short introduction to compression and all that what
is compression
for compression we need to create some more the following day data
some approach some algorithms that maps of data to states
more probable and less probable states so it should output this state probability of the
and someone quarter that can encode
we have to move around the minimum number of all
two men john edwards and we have
like many specialized relations this is not just assertions
would start with the nineteen ninety
because different strokes for different folks
document that
in the year and we certainly want to connect less than average over a number
of other people
also on documents and day
in each of the people we get most
four randomly pulses
financial supporter of parents
to get my
which can be
people use
do you take the go into water
four neighbours and users
rules so we faced with real issues
can we what was
is something everybody everybody else
many of us
well this is a
made by this everybody else in the networks so we want to have her abusive
husband she would about
king and her with
this new venture
literally case
a great personal danger
there's reason why computer scientists the social sciences
to avoid class actions suit
i want to see that some
so we talking about a partial membership model that works what i call this FLC
it was found
so you can to be just a bit more referencing that the your mother of
in fact
it's interesting when you think about all the time
of that and so can you do that with this year
has been the century from thirteen percent
nineteen eighty down to four percent
and was that trees are coming out of the paper on this in the whole
of course this is maybe one thing
so this is an actual
but to ensure that different kinds of people close to the resources that are of
and while the first pursue solid
that you have to look at this important
that is is is
so but this is this is all have a lot of different ways
are being to
and this is different from the old traditional small groups where there was a village
this morning
so i and my moving to that some of the most important
it slow
necessary that is one of the
we then moved this is my
i have evidence for
two what i think since world war two two in england and the netherlands per
travel to london
the situation
which is the fact that was
typically home
or ten minutes and work
but that travel between them
this is
well let me be the one that we never have been done
when you get are expressed
we're trying to play go point to point you have to have vols
but you know this when new world of course wall
you know if you need to sort of pieces
and then something
the total of the number to call networked individualism person's individual unit of interaction
he said that all have private concerns therefore we have this
all in many ways
the baseline algorithm that we compare ourselves to
it uses fast distance transforms and dynamic programming in order to compute all detections in
image in time that is linear in the number of parts in the model and
also linear in the number of locations in the image
the problem with this is that in modern set up
we typically have very dense feature maps and resample scale space very densely as well
this means that the number of locations is typically huge
and also because we use these rich filters to represent parts often the cost to
compute a part score is also quite expensive to these two factors are the bottleneck
in practice for the baseline algorithm
as we all know cascade algorithms have been used over and over again to speed
up here
methods in computer vision so here we appeal to cascade architecture in order to compute
parts causing many fewer locations
so we empirically valid
evaluate our approach
using some models that are a little bit more sophisticated than just a simple star
model so what we do is we take in the next year or disjunction of
star models
so each component in this mixture model is itself the star model which is defined
in terms of nine parts
each one of these parts is implemented as a linear filter on hard features so
there is the group part which captures entire objects appearance and of course resolution
and there are eight additional parts which capture localized regions of the object of finer
each one of these parts is allowed to move relative to its anchor position but
it costs something that is modeled by separable quadratic equations function
so the two more ingredients so we need to formulate the cascade algorithm for star
models the first is we need an ordering of the parts which implicitly defines a
hierarchy of models the i th model this hierarchy is defined by adding the i
th part the previous model hierarchy
now if you recall the definition of the score function for every location omega we're
maximizing over part locations individually
this means that as soon as we place in your part in this hierarchy in
its optimal location there remains the optimal location for that part as we
place the additional parts because of this property we can say that the score of
an intermediate model is a partial score
which can be extended to the full score simply by adding in the optimal scores
of the remaining parts
the next ingredient that we need for the cascade algorithm is a sequence of thresholds
the star cascade algorithm operates
by going between two different steps
in the print makers step we look at
in the current partial score
of the model and we compare two threshold in order to decide whether or not
we should abandon the real location omega
printed away and move on to the next location
in the next step we do prune delta operation
what this series replacing on new part
into the model and we need to search over displacements but most of those displacements
are going to be too costly and therefore we can immediately discard that by using
a threshold test
so now walk through simple example of how the algorithm works in practice you can
understand exactly what it's doing
we need a three ingredients the object model part ordering thresholds we take the test
image we converted into feature pyramid representation
to simplify things of focus on a single scale of the pyramid and a single
component of the model
also because it's much nicer to look at images rather than visualizations of feature maps
of simply replace actual image
the cascade algorithm operates by maintaining score tables for each one of the parts during
the showing score tables for the root part in the first two
after that so the going to begin by testing root locations with the root filter
most of these locations are going to score poorly in their going to fail the
first print maker test
this is represented by shading the corresponding cells in its core table grapes
so we keep testing locations most of them fell
hopefully eventually
we get to
a location that scores high enough to pass the first threshold test
now that this has happened we have to consider the contribution in the first part
we do that by conducting and displacement search
in principle we have to search over all possible displacement however we threshold test in
order to reject most of them
therefore we only have to consider a small number of locations which are those indicated
by this
part one score tables so in those locations we have to compute part one score
we do that we find the optimal location for part one we compared to its
threshold test for the next egg operation
here it fails which means that we reject this root location and we move on
to the next location
this location
as is like the previous one
again we conducted displacement search
displacements are rejected however there are few
that do pass and again in these locations we have to compute the parts for
the now know that there is significant overlap between these locations and the previously computed
locations which means that we can simply reuse most of the computation that we already
have done this
element to the algorithm is the key to making the cascade fast for deformable part
models there are only a small number of locations here where we actually have to
compute new part scores
so after computing this cause
we find the optimal displacements compared to threshold in this case it passes which means
that we can move on to the second part we repeat this whole process again
and then we continue doing this for all the remaining parts in this case all
the remaining threshold tests were passed which means that we can report the object hypothesis
and then move on to bigger and better things like finding more bicycles
essential to the performance of the algorithm is choosing good thresholds
now we want to specials to be effective meaning that they should for a lot
of true negatives because if they don't the cascade the fast but they also have
to be safe and in the sense efficient for many true positives because if they
do will lose recall that we heard are average precision score
we can make the notion of safe threshold to more precise and we do so
by introducing probably approximately admissible thresholds you can take x to be an i i
d set positive examples drawn from some unknown distribution d
we can then define the error rate of a sequence of thresholds t
to be the probability under random draw an example from d that the cascade algorithm
computes a score other than the actual score
now if the error rate was exactly zero
then we would have admissible thresholds we were never proven false we never print not
be great but the problem is that it's very difficult we don't know how to
heck provably
admissible thresholds that
are also effective in practice and or in other words make it fast cascade so
we can relax is a bit by just saying that we want to have a
epsilon delta probably approximately admissible thresholds and what this means is that the probability that
the error rate
exceeds small number epsilon is bounded by a small number delta
so as has been used in other work on cascades one method of picking thresholds
is to select the minimum of partial scores over the examples in your training set
now we show that if you do this then that leads to probably approximately admissible
well i construct the laplacian of this graph and this is something we have seen
earlier and in the case of such a graph the lab class is just
for this
it's just adjacency matrix almost like the adjacency matrix of the graph
so if you actually look at it it's mine was adjacency matrix of the graph
and on the diagonal i have the degree of each vertex
now what the spectral clustering spectral clustering is just taking the first i can vector
of this rather well the first one is actually the zero i connected the constant
functions of the first one we usually think that the first known const
constant will not be useful
i take no one equals one the one said i can vector problem
this i can vector
well i have a six by six matrix so this i can vector is
six long vector
moreover you know if you know the first row corresponds to the first vertex
i think that one the second row corresponds to the thing to this one in
and so on
each entry of this vector corresponds to a vertex of the graph
OK so this i can vector is actually on the side
often number to each vertex of the graph
so i can vector is a function on the graph it an assignment of the
number to each vertex in the graph
now how do i clusters
well i think it's very clear from this one right we see that the first
three negative the first for the next three are positive
well why don't they just cluster positive versus negative
and it turns out this is actually the correct way to cluster this graph
you know i didn't define what it means to cluster y it's kind of just
from looking at it it's clear that if you want to copy it is located
in the middle
and that is the normalized clustering which is a variation of what would become scheme
this is closely related to something called the min cost and the mincut basically if
you just mean car
you want to cut
the number of
that just which are cut to split this graph into parts OK so for this
graph it's best to cut it in the middle
so mincut is OK and there are some problems with it because if you have
for example
if i have enough another vertex here in one edge connecting it i can just
cut this out
the mincut is the same
right this this i cut this one that but
but somehow not as nice as cutting it in the middle so a better version
of it some sort of balance cut when you say well i would like to
have it cut which is small so i removed the small number of edges but
so that the two parts of the graph after i cut
stay balanced
in some sense you know
you don't want one five to be
much much larger than the other one otherwise this single isolated vertex would kill you
OK so this is nice so now if you think about the class and so
the luftwaffe matrix has the following basic properties this is really an but has mentioned
several times but i would just like to emphasise this
what is the property well if i have an assignment
numbers to each vertex of the graph
the club plus for suppose left the laplacian matrix is nothing else but the some
the differences square so
i take the difference between every two adjacent vertices
vertices and a sum them all up
OK so i take the difference between f two and f three f one f
two f one f three f three and four
four and five and so on but only more just once
so it kind of measures how much the function change us
along this graph
and this is a lot less
now if you think about it
what happens when you havoc on the way to think about the cost one way
to think about
well if a cut is just
you want to say that some of the vertices will be brad some of them
will be blue right so i cut is just a subset of the vertices
if i have a subset of the artists
i can assign
one of that to the to the like in SM one can send zero to
everything else
if i do that what is going to happen if i just think the some
different square
this sound is going to to be
if two vertices are in the same class then the value of the same because
someone for the same partition
and the difference is going to visit
if the vote is same different class
the difference is going to be one
so the difference
is going to be one vertices which are not in the same class which in
different parts of the graph and zero
four vertices which are in the same class
what does it mean when i some them all up that means i'm just summing
up the edges which cross the boundary of
the cut
that's exactly the cost
so plus actually calculate the cost for such functions
and that explains why
so far have not give exact derivation although it's not hard but that explains that
while minimizing the plus and minimizing reference pose lf basically is an approximation of relaxation
for actually finding the best cost
that's the outside
what happens when
so this the spectral clustering that's how it works
and this is if you have a graph it's a pretty good way to go
in there are the methods but this is this is a very popular
now if you have data
you want to conferences graph from the data and one way to do it is
to actually do all
the gaussians edge weights
OK and there some results basically saying it's actually kind of interesting it turns out
and you get more and more data
the real world is complicated
if i fit the if i look at the curvature tensile strength as a function
of concrete
the components that go into a concrete or world
then that isn't going to be
a linear if it is going to be exactly quadratic it is going to be
any parametric curve i write down
so i want to be able to use
a complicated model so that's why i want to fit
then when we do it in practice we get these crazy fit
don't work well and we knew that they were crazy
so i introduced this idea of the validation set so that we'd have some way
of computing knowing they were crazy but when we looked at them
we knew that these wildly oscillating has one sensible
rather than relying on the validation set what we can do is tell the computer
in advance
don't accept solutions that we know that we're not going to like
i don't accept solutions wildly oscillate
that's the general idea we want to be able to specify
what makes a nasty complicated curve
the way mathematically we can do it is often by what's called shrinkage or weight
which is to say
you know i think many of these components of my weight vector w are going
to be close to zero
so they remember the w one says how important is the first column in my
training set w two is how important is the second column
if i'd extended my input
space that had many extra column
but the weights those columns with zero
then they wouldn't have any extra facts
and if the weights for these extra column very small then they would have to
begin effect that will stop me from introducing wild oscillations by adding extra features to
my model
it's often the case in a lot of models is the machine learning saying the
parameters are close to zero
similar to saying don't make
regression surfaces of classification boundaries very weakly
and the reason that early stopping is really working is that
the way the code is implemented as you start with the weight vector that close
to zero and the optimizer makes the weights grow bigger
so by stopping the algorithm early what you're doing is preventing the weights from getting
if we have identified that's really what we want to do
we just don't want quickly because we can just tell compute that we can say
don't give the solutions that have large predators
the way that we tell the computer to do something and specify what our objective
should be
it's a
if f was the objectives that we talked about so far something like squared error
likelihood look like
then what we can do is add another ten to that object to say we
would like you to do well on the training set we want to be able
to explain the training set well but
also a
don't make the way it's too big so we could actually objective minus lambda some
positive number times the sum of the absolute values of the way so if we
get massive weight vector this term will be very negative and that will give the
bad objective so the algorithm will find solutions like
this some choice here say
i chose to take the absolute value of the weight here and that has a
particular names this an l one regularizer
and in the context of doing the squares it's called the last so has this
the particular combination of doing least squares and this regularisation has name so that indicates
that might be useful tool another particular combination has another name if we take the
square of the way
and we're doing least squares regression then called ridge regression analysis lt regularisation just
so that that's a way of setting up regularisation
it's not the only way
another thing we could do
is say a
i think i know how big my weight vector should be
remember w is a vector is something which you could imagine pointing from the origin
out somewhere and it has a length so
the sum of the squares of the elements of the
the square euclidean like
so what i could do it i could say
you know i think i know how long that's going to be
because i'm going to use the length of the weight vector
as a proxy for how we my surfaces
so i could say i maximise my objective but make sure that the length of
some particular value
or you could say make sure that the sum of absolute terms some particular value
instead if you wanted to use that as your proxy
and that might be
easier to think about because you might be able to look at the parameters and
see what they mean and decide how to set this up whereas maybe
this is sort of a fight between fitting the data and
not making promises too big and it's not clear whether that fights going to end
before you actually do it and so maybe you're not happy with that
happily it turns out that these two stories are actually exactly the same thing
say a
and of isolated the conditions under which
the become false
now we do this thing called explanation closure an explanation closure basically means i'm going
to add some formulas
and what these formulas capture is this common sense principle of inertia
something should not change
value function change value if it's not like explicitly mentioned in the effective action
the flow into described in the following form called explanation closure actions in which several
local says
it says that
if the four f was false
the the sort of politics is just the vector of possible arguments for my take
so if the
if the if the flow was false but after performing some action it becomes true
then of course positive conditions must have be true
now wait for that to occur unless the positive conditions which
similarly if
the flow was true but then it ended up becoming falls
and that must be the cause the negative conditions which are
now we can rewrite these if we rewrite then we see that there essentially disguised
sort of frame axioms i rewrite the first one
basically says well look if the flow was false
and it's not the case that any of the
conditions to make it true
i happen to be the case
and the thing states false
OK so i've uses the contrapuntal that is
this what the
if you know the last two bits of the first four around
and i've done that similarly to the second floor
that's how we can improve these articles so similarly for the second formula just as
it if the property was true
and now the conditions that would make it false
we're realised that it remains true and that probably the mainstream
so if the cap was white
and there was no action is now
condition under which you could changes colour then it's going to remain one
we might skip some of the because it turns out you gotta have a lot
of other stuff so in logic this is another listen to draw from this
you know this thing in real life things are really simple but in logic things
become much much more complex
so one thing you've got to do is you got to say that for instance
you know these two whitecaps different and also on different from the one cup as
because obviously this an interpretation under which means the white captured exactly the same thing
so we've got to actually say that if you got a symbol that refers to
an object
you you got to make sure they used to distinguish it from other possible
OK now it turns out that if you stick all of this stuff together you
come up with a formula which looks like the following one and we're going to
call it the successor state axioms is one
what the successor state axioms has noticed equivalent is this is the by implication
the this formula tells us exactly under which conditions
four fluid has the particular property after doing an action
because it's an infinitely from that we can sort of see whether true
but we go can also reason about when it is false
so this essentially says that it
is true
after doing action a precisely
the conditions to make it true
it was true to begin with and under the conditions to make it false support
i happen to be the case
so setting just trying to
explain in plain english something is true precisely when
none of the conditions to make it falls happen to be the case
it was true to begin with
and so was sorry
it becomes true if was the conditions to make it true in the case
and all sorry it was truly begin with another commission to make false
well because
so if we have a look at this particular example we see that
we can say that x is broken after doing action a it precisely when
either we did the drop action and it was fragile although exploded the bomb next
to it all just happened to be broken to begin with and we didn't do
anything to make it not right
this formula captures all the conditions to work out the value broken so can work
out with the broken that something is true
breaking of the white cap is true or can work out whether it's false once
we have this form
and we get this form as i say by adding a couple of extra fullness
and what the extra farmers
sort of
it is encoded this common-sense principle of inertia that something will retain its value
if it's not as if it's not sort of describe the effects of the action
i always think quite well under pressure from
you know the big thing is corrosion studies in the sea and you can see
what what
i am phases in the iron oxide is if intuitively if you for whatever faces
there if few too
that will show up in the raman spectrum quite easily you look at what's happening
with with the grain boundaries and it's like that because SEM
you're look even half my transport picamoles spot
the are some problems potential problems remember using a laser in vacuum
so you heat dissipation was way samples are actually have potentially
the honourable they will burn in here
because he will not be dissipated of the sample
thank you
now come on you know and i don't believe
the some they wanted when the going for lunch yes
i did not know something this stupid question
so how do you not degrading because of
yes i know you
you know that is one of the advantage of using FM
you can actually be scanned area into the dot is that you can watch the
dots disappear
if you're hitting number two much
when you search
fact if i go back
if you go back to
number one
if you would
if that those of the quantum dots
you analyzing if you
are doing any damage at all
you can very quickly that politics
a few seconds to acquire
that image
and because you you know the way you do this using imaging you just quickly
acquire that image and if you get degradation you see the support the disappear issue
right you have to be very careful all we're going to use you have to
be very careful how much power years
this is a beautiful picture
you could actually
that takes
that takes longer to acquire then it would be to destroy
that quantum dot
you could start like quantum dot in
it's not necessary because the question the question is there because i believe me people
have been right thing for all of a whole raft of quantum dots placed close
analysis the head with a one micron laser spot
we go by agreeing exactly no information at all
and they go back
of the site
scanned docs
as i said with all of this material united states
size tends to be going to become less and less sample preparation orientated trying to
make things simple when you start to do this kind of what
it's not simple
the sample preparation is an important understanding your model
there's even more important and destroying model is very easy
you know this is not a panacea this is this is the media technology
this is a beautiful
if image this is a good
rahman image
and this is a very very nice
way profiles through that pillar
but this was done by people who have been doing this for probably about ten
you know so if they've been always which leads to use but also which polarisation
other ways to do music but how do you like your naturally polarized this i
would say no
you was campbell is so that people
so you're not going in engineering you can get some materials like this with the
polarized laser again around the signal at all
because the point the
elizabeth straight through the crystal plane you know reflect no deflection depolarized always you get
some you can name should the polarization of the laser
to get the maximum raman signal back from the material hopefully hopefully not damage the
sample the same day
yes basically if you have a combined romany FM
you do this two ways you can either take bfm stage amount just onto the
the normal microscope stage
or you have to be very fancy and have no money
what we call i don't actually do let me show you
according to the two
this is this is an interface system
that combines both
this is the ritual spectrometer
seventy five
triple these three six four laser back
this is double system this is your
if fact
and here you have the standard
three space microscope for doing other experiments you can do it the other way around
you could have a standard FM of the microscope here and then
but a couple so you would have them both in public
one after another so you have your
you if m here
you have used and the microscope for you rahman here i knew spectrometer here on
just one the couple through
if you find a couple
you can then take of the fibre would come over here
and we go to the
if m
so you still have you stand alone running
and you can use them independently together
we do it
this wooden unless you specifically ask
to have
just on the FM only system
we automatically supply a stand-alone rama systems
clearly FM in this case is directly coupled in the case of an onyx AFM
it's five a couple
so you do not using any of the