nine one
there are
are what they are
very wrong
thank you
o is working
there were one
on you
and all
one year
very good
are you know
but it is
the worst case
i think
you using your
here are
you are
three i four
it's easy to see
not all
he right
on very
eight year
need the
the Dirichlet process is defined in this way right where given a partition of
the space the the prior distribution of this random vector here is gonna be
a Dirichlet distributed with the two parameters given by alpha and h let me see
that h is the base distribution is basically the mean of the Dirichlet process
while the alpha parameter's related to the in the inverse of the variance so
the Dirichlet process is basically a defined in terms of the Dirichlet distribution which has
this conjugacy property with the multinominal or the discrete distribution and this conjugacy actually carries over
to the Dirichlet process and that's actually part of the reason why Ferguson actually
was interested in the Dirichlet process to begin with basically it's this nice conjugacy property
that you can calculate a lot of the the conditional distributions easily okay so and this
property kind of basically goes as follows let's suppose that our random
probabily the measure G is has a Dirichlet process prior given by alpha and h
since G itself is a probability measure we can think of it as also a
distribution over our space and since is that this is the distribution we can
define random variables that are G distributers so each of them is gonna be sample
from this G distribution right so let's call this theta I so theta I I from
one to n each of them are gonna be IID draws from this G distribution
okay so that's perfectly well defined now the question is what this is our
prior this is our kind of a likelihood sort of term so the question is what is
the posterior turns out the posterior is also gonna be a Dirichlet process it's a just
as in the case of the a final mixture model we have a Dirichlet prior
on missing proportions we have a likelihood term which is kind of conjugate to the Dirichlet
and then the posterior's also gonna be a Dirichlet so in this case the posterior's also
gonna be Dirichlet process okay so the posterior over G given theta one to theta n
you can work out to be basically a Dirichlet process where the
mass parameter we incremented by n basically n corresponds to the total number observations that
we have here and the base measure is updated by basically adding atoms
one corresponding to each observation and then normalizing okay so alpha H comes from the prior
and then we add in N atoms each one located at theta I and
then we had to normalize it by Alpha plus N so in this sense
the this alpha parameter is a prior mass parameter right so the more data that we observe
we simply add a larger N to this thing so if we can think of N
here as the mass or the effects of the of our data this alpha here
we can think of it as the total effects of our prior okay so the
nice thing with this posterior Dirichlet processes is so one things that
you could do is now you could define an iterative process defined in terms of
this Dirichlet process so imagine that we have the following model again so we have
G is Dirichlet process distributed and then we have a sequence now is could
be an infinite sequence of theta one theta two and so forth each of them
is going to be IID draws from G okay so the model looks like the following
G goes to theta one to theta two theta three and so forth right and we can
ask the following question what is the conditional distribution or the predictive distribution of
the N plus first theta given the theta one to theta N alright so we have
observed theta one until theta N and would like to compute the conditional distribution of
the next one given the observed but marginalizing out G ok basically you know
which is being base about this G is unobserved so we just integrate that up so we would like to compute
conditional of theta N plus one given the first N thetas because the posterior distribution of
G has a base measure which is given by this form here which is the
mean of the of G is the basically the posterior mean of G we can work out
that the predictive distribution of theta N plus one given theta one to theta N is gonna
be given by this posterior mean okay and so if you look at this it's a
goes as follows so it basically says that the probability theta N plus one
being equal to theta I is gonna be one over Alpha plus N alright so that
term here looks like okay and this term here is basically a degenerate probability distribution
that gives probablity one to value given by theta I and probability zero everywhere else okay
so with probability one over Alpha plus N theta N plus one is gonna take
on this value theta I okay  and there's N of those and with probability alpha over
alpha plus N theta N plus one is gonna be drawn from from the base
distribution H yes yes that's right and there's actually the first simple
result about the con convergence of the consistency of a Dirichlet process so if you
use it as a prior to estimate a distribution then as we have an infinite amount of
data then this term will dominate and this term goes to zero and so the
do dominating term basically converges to the empirical distribution and that we know is consistent
okay so and then this process here is called an urn scheme basically
sometimes it's called polva urn scheme sometimes it's called Hopp or Hoppe urn scheme  sometimes it's called
bčackwell macqueen urn scheme okay so they're basically the same thing and the metaphor
is the following so we start off with an urn with alpha balls and this
are of  a special color okay  and at each iteration of the of the scheme we're gonna
reach our hand into the urn and pick up a ball at random oaky if the ball that
we picked is a special color then we will make a new ball with the
color sample from H and then we drop we know the color of the ball
and then  we return  balls back into the urn both the special color ball and
OK thanks
all right thank you very much
today i'm going to talk about on mining ending in game theory i think it
would be a nice complementarities talk it's it's mostly theoretical work
in experiments
so how many of you are familiar with the weighted majority analysis
OK i'm just kidding i'm not going to have a bunch of equations for the
last talk of the the of the week so i figured i'd try to do
the theoretical talk but i'm just gonna is mostly pictures and i'll see how well
it works hopefully you get the big picture on the main ideas in some experience
as well
this is the talk about learning talk both about online learning and how it relates
to gain game playing repeated game-playing
one of the questions you know how do people learn how do
what's the right model of learning
from a theoretical point of view
so one model of learning
would be OK you just got a bunch of data
that's the training data drawn from some distribution
and the goal is to learn the function which is
predicting y from x
and that's the batch model right you get a bunch of data
you have time to run your training algorithm get samples from this distribution
and your goal is to output function that will predict well on future examples
from the same distribution
that's the setting that i guess which was working in and another model would be
the online model which i think you've heard about already but i just described again
we're it's more like a repeated game model where
you have this child is sitting there gets an example yesterday side to do make
they began writing together and he finds out the answer so each time if there's
an example makes a prediction
and finds out whether or not he was right
and this is this is much more difficult setting here because we don't have a
probability distribution is no guarantee that future examples
coming from the same distribution as previous examples
and this is the way many real world situations are
we don't have this kind of guarantees
t and we're going to see today is that there's a lot of similarities between
these two settings in that lot of things we can prove that the same kind
of rates happen in both
the online and offline settings
when i mentioned how to my slides
lot this talk is not things that i did myself it's just the summary some
of it is what i've done myself joint work with some crocodile
and feel free to ask questions i want to go slowly make sure everyone understands
and i don't mind if i don't get everything
OK so
well i'm going to talk about online versus batch learnability of functions
and we're going to explain why not surprisingly online setting is harder than the batch
i'll give an example of a simple case where you have just a small number
of functions and you want to learn to do almost as well as the best
and then i'll show
why these two settings are
roughly the same
i mean in the second part of my talk about online learning in repeated games
and i think the are pierre some of that is that right
i was here first lecture but maybe go over that again and then i'll talk
in for zero sum games he showed how you could use boosting to play games
that right
no maybe not OK well it would be nice and also general sum games where
it's not the one player wins and the other places it's just a general game
and this very nice algorithms for learning in those settings that could convert to something
called correlated equilibrium
so in the online setting again we have know example we have this adversary let's
so make it really hard and he pick some points and we have to predict
its label either plus or minus we make a prediction
minus we find out the minus OK we got it right
make another prediction
we find out we we predict minus its plus we got it wrong
and so on this repeats in an online fashion
and it in the and how we can judge their performance well look at our
air will simply count the number of mistakes we made
our hundred OK
and that this area is between zero and one
and obviously one below
in the batch setting
it's easier setting we have with probability distribution
because if the
photons carry momentum
and if the momentum
photo photographi photo photo photo i feel the force
you remember from eighty one force
is ppt is the transfer of momentum
if i throw rotten tomatoes that you
then when you get these estimators on your face
they you like this and then they go like this
thirty come in a certain direction and they lose all their momentum in that direction
that gives the force on new in this direction
because that momentum in this direction is destroyed momentum is conserved
and so you
get that momentum
if for instance
i through one kilogram
main you each second
one after the
all the time average one kilogram per second and each domain o
had a speed of five meters per second
and i call it the x direction
here is your face
they had to face and then they go
so all the momentum in the x direction is destroyed
then you will experience a force in the x direction
is in the x direction
which is one thousand five which is five militants
this the time average force
if for some reason
the the two main of wood back to support the elastic collision like tennis ball
then the
momentum transfer is twice
comes in with momentum and come back
sort out momentum transfer is twice the number is not just destroyed no we first
so in that case
the force on your face
would be doubled that
would be ten newtons
so we can now carry this further to our
electromagnetic radiation
and we can return to our poynting vector
here i have
one square metre
radiation is coming in
and i know exactly how much radiation is coming in for every square meter
there is this value as
so s
which is an energy
per square metre
a second member that's
but i mention of the poynting vector
if i divided by c
and i this by c
you know what i have here
i have energy divided by c
the energy in electromagnetic radiation divided by c
according to einstein
is momentum
and i don't care whether this is a hundred billions of individual photons
that's okay with me
that is the momentum
and so i have no momentum
unit time
that makes it the fourth
but the force per square metre makes it the pressure
and so
this is pressure
and we call that
radiation pressure
this means that if you are
exposed to bombardment of
electromagnetic radiation
and you absorb it
that you feel the pressure
relation comes to you and you being pushed backwards
and this is the pressure
that you will experience
it makes a difference whether the radiation is absorbed
or whether you're capable of of reflecting radiation just like receptor made of
and so if i'm trying to be as general as i can
let me
first of all
specify the mean value of as that's the only thing electromagnetic radiation with matter is
the mean value
so the mean value then
if i divided by c
and i multiplied by a factor of phi you'll come up short tell you of
is that is now to radiation pressure
and all five
if alpha is one
then i have fallen short
all the radiation is absorbed
if there's no absorption if it's completely transparent and there is some radiation that goes
straight through you
and also a zero
but if there's hundred percent reflection
sense to add levels to it is still
we marginalize out the top of hierarchy are sold by some distribution at a particular
so you know that you can make this go up
infinitely long it's not really making
but hierarchical principles often used define priors
empirical priors
essentially correspond to the idea that you want to learn some of the parameters of
the prior from the data just because
you know you're a bit nervous about setting up your whole prior entirely in japan
and so a lot of people actually do that we call it empirical basis
in some of the work that a lot of work people do few hyperparameters and
you just optimize the
fit the data and you cross your fingers in your that doesn't cost
too much damage
one thing that helps you with is that it makes things a bit more robust
if data with something
if you specify parameters are hyperparameters in your data is something that you really did
not expect
a new model might not perform very well whereas if you optimize the hyperparameters that
you will make a bit more about at the cost of building a little bit
and then finally subjective priors
your prior to capture
your beliefs as well as possible
and it's important to to emphasise the priors these priors are subjective but not arbitrary
it doesn't mean
you know anything goes
only when you actually believe it goes right
you know if you if you don't actually capture things that you believe and then
you're not being here in this
OK and the dutch book theorem in this talk contains axioms
i really about subjective priors
i really about capturing
police as possible but many people in statistics and machine learning just don't like the
idea of thinking about all this stuff
intersubjective framework
so another distinction this sort of very important in the field
is this idea that there are
parametric models in nonparametric models let me try to waving and definition
so parametric models
you have a fixed number of parameters that
finally the number of parameters data and regardless of the size of the dataset that
sort of number of parameters that you have
given data the predictions are going to be independent of the data so you parameters
data are meant to capture everything about the data there is
right or prediction
so in the parameters are a finite summary of what the data is
we can really had to call it the model based learning approach
in nonparametric models
in a sense you allow the number of parameters to grow with the data but
in fact is usually there defined so the number of parameters was always kind of
infinity and so the number of parameters that are getting used up
grows the size the data but you know they're always sitting there
alternatively we can think of the predictions as depending on the data and possibly usually
small set of hyperparameters of we call that memory based learning and this is what
nonparametric bayesian methods like gas processes and there's hypotheses which you hear about next are
based on
the argument is that
we ought not to limit the complexity of the models that are a if we
don't believe that the world the data in the real world was generated from a
finite parametric model to the real world doesn't correspond to idealise physical models
so we shouldn't say that the real world corresponds to a mixture of three gaussians
that just doesn't seem to make sense
so here are some common misconceptions about this is that
if you choose the wrong prior you'll do poorly
if you choose the daily prior you'll do poorly
you don't need to to study this
this thing is
that we want to get close to get as close as possible to the unknown
true covariance matrix so we want to minimize the norm
of the hour
estimation of the true covariance matrix
so this
looks like hopeless to calculate it because this sigma of the true covariance matrix is
it turns out if we restrict the search space for this
you can calculate optimum come in this
calculation of the true covariance matrix
kansas out
the the optimal parameter gamma only depends on very
simple value
correlation coefficient
the variance of correlation coefficients across tried
after optima gamma
for shrinkage
and now if we use NDA restricted shows the covariance matrix we get
drastically reduced the error rate for then only use four percent error
so this
you should decrease
students range
and in
so in this
that this works very well this
not only for this particular dataset theory
because you have some results for the classic matrix speller was setting
participants who
naive and so new to the paradigms not pre-selected and here's the classification accuracy for
number of repetitions of the
so it is accuracy in letter selection for the chance level three percent
and you see that is only
very few
it intensification get very high
classification accuracy so if we
look at the mean across subjects
you see that this for intensification
the median across subjects percent
so just this is simple techniques
just introduced so if you want to see more details of the
study see poster w seven hundred years later and other applications use this classification technique
it to public settings and
w ten mm on this
so in summary this linear classification this trinket is very powerful
the third and but of course
linear methods enough depends on the
kind of features extracted
but if you can do it a linear methods and it's very nice because you
can visualize what was known as agree
so i suppose it's spatial temporal features for the classifier weight vector can be visualized
as a sequence of
so this not
spatiotemporal features so no short section about spectral features
so i was this was already
introduce smallest by
got be look either isn't over the sensorimotor area
and then we see some some peaks in the spectrum
and the rest for example you look at the electrodes
fuses this peak
the ideal result
and if
the movement is performed just dimensions and these peaks decreases
local blocking of sensorimotor rhythm and
this also called the
gibbs then governments also
i said that this is a very strong spatial smearing so here
if calculated from one data
correlation coefficient from the that to all other electrode and you see that
correlation coefficient is
almost point nine or about four nine four four electrodes
so that's a very strong
this page is smearing and that means if you look at the data you should
first apply
spatial it and this is especially true for the differences in
spectral content
we use the example it would illustrate the need
this is for left hand motor imagery and try to motor imagery and we look
electrode CP four and then we should
decrease of
vector energy for the left hand
o train
was the black and if you look at the ranch and then we don't see
any difference at all
to make a bipolar bipolar up
if you have a little bit of common average references
but only in the lab
place in the
you can see that the original features
really composed of two peaks and in fact the lower peak is
from visual for this has nothing to do with motor imagery
and simulations
happens only in the
this offer p
two to look at it you should always apply the best fit and
then if you calculate CSP which introduced next which is the data driven method to
something and not something else right this is the standard type of question we ask
what's the posterior
believe for distribution on my variable of interest or a set of variables given that
i know
this happens from this happened so these might be for example
medical tests and this might be a disease
it may be the other way this might be some sort of conditions that you
have your asking what the probability of observing the symptoms
so we can there is actually no back and forth in terms of actually
show that you know
it's nice to have the full joint distributions because we can ask all kinds of
questions but of course we never get beyond
five six ten
we can really do anything that there are two big reasons discrete variables even binary
we have variables we have
two the ten possible
we need to do ten
minus one parameters
minus one
because this into one
we can deal with these joints as is
one with the objects we have to do something to
reduce complexity and allow us to two to get the benefit of the jones without
actually them explicitly
there's a little graphical models two and there are named after these two guys
so there's two kinds directed the bayes an undirected markov networks and other names for
these things so these called belief nets
directed graphical models
these are called mrfs markov random field markov nets
undirected graphical models
often sometimes called log linear models or we signed in the tree i talked about
when you cannot represent the log x
something that's a log linear model
and so these guys in the event but they had a lot to do with
the mathematics of
probability and many poems and conditional independence assumption
this again if you can see that this is something that is
you can see here
it is
it's just that are also
judea pearl is the guy i think if we have to pick one guy who
is responsible for
making graphical models popular in machine learning
the same year euro this kind of seminal book
in the late eighties
eventually turned the tide from more
in logical approaches to AI
two probabilistic and one of the major tools was was graphical models and so he
did not like the theory for actually the semantics of graphical models you know what
was the graph mean and what kind of axioms can cancer
getting at the semantics
it is a lot of work lately on causality using these kinds of models to
think about causal kinds of events right so but you know the government has been
around for awhile geneticists and statisticians use them in
the nineteen thirties and
vision research people
used an even earlier than the pearl so in
it's late seventies but really serves
the momentum after today
today really pushed hard for
anyway so what they do the allows to play with you know who they are
the joint and compute degrees of interest by representing them
not as one big table but as sort of local
easy to specify
so what we do is we sort of variables that interact with directly and we
specify how they interact and these local interactions if everything is set up properly will
give rise to global interactions
and cohen global distribution
and that that satisfies our assumptions
this one is of course an upper right so this is a model and if
you can read about
it's a model of
car in our model
where you alternate fan belt engine when car starts spark plugs it's about it and
variables here
any model of course is is wrong all models are wrong is is the question
is whether they
they capture enough for you to do something
useful with right
so we might not have every variable that we care about
we not account for all the different possible interactions between variables that we have
right there might be other constraints are we're not thinking about
but the but when the goal is to capture interactions that are the most direct
and are sort of our are not you know
mediated by the any other interactions
OK so to get into the more concretely and so given these models is going
to show them but
the wireless let me and maybe later i'll try to log in again this there's
a job that allows you to to play with this
model and other models
so you know one thing we can do it for example
say that you know the car doesn't start so start simple false and ask you
know what's the probability that a battery each there
it is
all right so
so actually the other end
so this explanation so we have some some some some tape recorders and start many
radio is dead
and then we're asking given those two things with probability the battery which is
OK so that's reasoning upward
in this kind of if you think about directed direct causal reasoning prediction is kind
it's because
i tried to use it for
so good morning everyone
i'm going to present the group paper
this is joint work with my advisor fairly
given the human and object we want to recognise the interaction
such as playing saxophone
however this is not a trivial task because human object interaction cannot be fully understood
by simply considering the co occurrence of this human and the object
in this case it is possible that
the human is holding the saxophone but not putting it
recognizing human object interaction has a wide range of applications
such as it sort
such as teaching always hard to interact with objects
automatic sports commentary
two analysis for medical care and so on
higher while recognition of both humans and generic object has been extensively studied
the analysis of human object interaction has been mostly north
although there are some works that use image context to improve the recognition performance
the focus of this work is still
human object recognition instead of the interaction between them
in this talk
let's look into human object interaction in detail
this is all line
firstly the intuition
then we introduce the group the feature representation in the heart we could use it
for recognition
and then we show some experiment results and conclusions
OK let's see our intuition
recognizing human object interaction is a very challenging problem
given this image about the human is playing saxophone
the same interaction can be observed with different human pose
lighting in the background
different interactions such as playing bassoon always have humans
you know very similar pose as playing saxophone
also humans might interact very differently we start same object such as holding the saxophone
but not playing it
and given this is a very challenging problem is visual representations have some limitations
for example given two images when humans playing and another playing saxophone
bag of words or even a spatial pyramid which is very similar feature representation
and the part based methods such as constellation model is also to cause
to tell the difference between the two images
the reason is that from the pixel labels that we images are very similar and
only have some subtle difference
to address this problem in this work we propose a novel feature representation called grouplet
it is up on based feature
and it explicitly considers the co occurrence
of different image parts
it is also a discriminative
and the tenth
feature representation so it is able to capture the subtle difference
between different human object interactions
let's look into the group the feature representation in detail
given the image and the reference point
the group considers the co occurrence of a set of highly related image patches
the group here contains to image edges
so we call it two grouplet
the those image patches are encoded by feature units
and each feature unit considers the specific visual appearance and image location information
and if the appearance is encoded by visual codeword and the location is represented by
a two d gaussian distributions
and in the case of human object interactions
fifty thousand words chosen a small so the hundred features usually anti-spam system
let's see in the bayesian logistic regression implicit claim descent you get twenty percent test
error which is which is unacceptably high
so this is bayesian logistic regression
this is just as the likelihood that with that additional long descriptive term and when
maximizing rather minimizing was so so this miners lambda this was the first one is
the question is on the semantic web page images aggression
and you test on a test set on the set the high error so what
you do next
you know one thing could do is think about the ways you can improve this
our this very what most people do said well let's sit down and think what
could gone wrong and try to improve the article
well obviously have more training data
helps only just try to get more training examples
maybe you suspect even one hundred features was too many seem like try to
get smallest the features
on the more common as you might suspect if you just like in enough the
west byzantine the email headers see figure out better features for new finding spam emails
or whatever
all right and rights in just sit around the of the features as the even
you also suspect that been descent having quite converge let's must five hundred descended belong
to see that was clearly that can was
so i'm going to set longer maybe remember you know you are hearing loss that
may be newton's method converges bellies let's try that the
so you want your value for lambda
not sure that was right on or maybe even want to try and as you
can media
o thing and as you might work better which is actually
i mean this eight things you can imagine if you actually sitting down building machine
learning system options you and you can think of
hundreds of ways to improve the learning system elements these things like we're getting which
an example surely that's the whole so so that seems like a good user talk
and it turns out that
this approach in ways to improve the learning algorithm picking one thing going for it
on my work in the sense that it may eventually get used to working system
but often very time consuming and i think is often largely washed that to block
what end fixing with the problems
in particular
he's eight improvements all fixed very different problems
and some of them will be fixing problems the don't have on and if you
can rule out
six of eight these saying if i somehow looking at the problem or be you
can figure out which one of these things is actually the right thing to do
you can save yourself a lot of time
so let's see how to go about doing that
the people in industry and research that that i see very good will not
going child change learning algorithm and
lots of things that will put obviously improve learning algorithm but the process so many
of them is hard to know what to do
so people i know the really good ones that run various diagnostics to figure out
what the problem is
i think whether the problem
for almost story right we said this is basically just a regression test error was
twenty percent which was the theme on high on
let's suppose you suspect that the problem is either overfitting
so high bias or you suspect that you may be too few features across five
spans on was his i think i
wrote that's wrong
this person has this forget get details services policy the high by the high variance
in some of the text cosmic
you want to know
if all overfitting which should be high variance or get too few features features cos
i spent high bias to sorry
how figure out whether the problem
is one of high by is or high variance
so a simple diagnostic if you look at all tell you
whether the problem is high bias and high variance
if you remember the car to its increasing high variance problems when have high variance
the training error will be much lower than the test error
and a high variance problem that's when you fitting the training set very well that's
when fitting ten for the polynomial to eleven data points
that's when you just fitting that a very well the training of much more than
and in contrast high by is
that's when your training error will also be high
that's when your data is quadratic say
but fitting a linear function to it so you want to the training
just in cartoons i guess this is that this is one of the typical learning
curve for high variance looks like on on the horizontal axis imparting the training set
size m
and the graphs in some part the error
and so
let's see you know as increase
if you have high variance problem of nodes as the training set size m increases
you test error with people in decreasing
so this suggest that what we can increase the training set size even further maybe
believe that period
you just
that's all
all right
o who are
and the more
you are
and if you want
and he said
at the distance from source to reflect to the destination
and that gives us this propagation to like
OK these are very with time
but in our retracing approximation we assume that are independent of frequency
i originally assumed that the antenna pattern was a function of frequency
we don't want to say anything about that
so we have a total of capital j pairs
we put in input of cosine two pi after a what's going come out
is an electromagnetic radiation
which is the sum
of these different attenuation factors
times e to the two pi IFT t
this propagation to lie
so everything you can do with the ray tracing is included in this formula
what you might be able to do in wireless system
as you might by looking at the received waveform and knowing things about the transmitted
waveform you might be able to figure out what these attenuation factors are and what
these propagation delay factors are
just like when we try to do frequency recovery
we can find out what the transmitted frequency was we can do that we can
play the same sorts of games here but the harder and we'll talk about that
if you ever hear the term rake receiver
rake receivers receiver that in fact measures all this stuff
in response to what i will talk about that probably next monday
OK if we want to look at the reflecting waters is an example of what
this formula means
beta one of two a mainly for the direct path
we have an attenuation
which is the magnitude of the antenna patterns divided by or zero plus b
for the attenuation on the on the return path from the wall
the same alpha
why is it the same output because we assume that with the same outfit to
make things simple for ourselves divided by two d minus or zero minus the today
if you look at the
that these propagation delay terms
the propagation delay terms
or zero plus the today
divided by saying this gives us doppler shift the were interested in here
we're also going to have an extra term here
which is really caused by the phase change at the transmitting antenna in the phase
change the receiving antenna and interface stranger to reflect their there's any there
so we have the same sort of term in both of these places
the reason but i talk about that if you look at the electromagnetic wave that
you receive for this reflecting what problem we talked about a good deal
the second term is there with the negative sign rather than a plus sign here
everything is put in with plus signs
you can create negative signs by phase changes
of pi
so the assumption is we put a phase change pi
as part of this term here
all these terms can be expressed in this general form here
OK we said before you only have two choices with the cellular system
you cannot
solve the electromagnetic field problems at the self
the person using the cell phone is not going to do with the cell phone
is not going to do with the base station is not going to do it
and you're not going to store all those changes because these radiations change remarkably within
the period a small fraction of one meter and you have the coverage here
which in fact
it is at least area coverage
it's a one kilometre times one kilometre
and then the reflectors are going to be moving also
so you can't deal with them very easily either so hope this problem to try
to solve electromagnetic problem and stored someplace
electromagnetism helps us to limit the range and the likelihood of choices
but it doesn't help that fall detection
so we're not going to deal with the kind of thing that we just talked
which is the sort of a general expression
four electric field
in terms of of attenuation factors and phase changes
as opposed to
which is
which is much more detail
we're going to find channel system functions
as just this sum
of these attenuation terms times phase change terms OK the reason that we're doing this
is that if we put in an input eighty two pi i have to say
and then what
and what we get
is the system function here
times access to a which is a to buy i have to say so we
get this quantity here
here's the minus two pi i f tell
that term coming down there
and here is the
eta two pi i to coming down here so
all of
this term
and this term are both included
in this system response term
OK this is linear also so we know what the responses to an exponential we
put in
mkt a little bit here by going from bi going from real
by going from real to complex
and they do that a little more carefully
anyway we ought to be used to that now
if i put in input
x had that either the two pi ftbs and integrated in other words if i
the common the normal thing to do
so it's constructed from these two things that the the marginal distribution for the parameter is the prior
the conditional distribution for the data given the parameter is the likelihood if we're modeling in this
direction that's a generative model and then multiply it to give the joint distribution
it is worth I'll just repeat that point that it's the joint distribution of theta and Y
that's really the key idea and in fact if you started from that point you don't even need
bayes theorem to do bayesian statistics
which is a slightly scary thought
now ) gonna talk quite a bit about priors later where do they come from but
bearing in mind what I've said about two sorts of uncertainty typically
those two factors the likelihood and the prior can be quite different in character
the prior is often entirely subjective now subjective is a bit of a dirty word
I I don't really like it because it has that pejorative
connotation this is something somehow you just made up it'd be much better if we said
scientific judgment I think it's much better way to think about subject subjectivity
but the prior is very often based on on scientific judgment that's not hard you know isn't
quantified in a particularly hard way
whereas the likelihood may well be something as open to empirical evaluation
you know in a lab you could perhaps create data and actually assess assess distributions directly
now there are many many positive things that come out of using a probability theory
consistently and this is just a very simple example of that and it's something
we use all the time what happens when data acquire sequentially
OK so every day you get and you
every day you get a new set of weather and you know we we we we
we want to update believes in the light of
what we now know and so imagine there's this some sort of state of nature theta
is our focus of our inference and that the different data we acquire are conditionally independent
given that that that fact
In that case the the joint distribution is just the product of the prior for theta
multiplied by the likelihoods for all the individual
data and that's
you know that's the basic law of probability so we can infer from that that the conditional distribution
we want is proportional for that product
and notice that we can break off the last factor and we see that in fact what we're seeing is
that the
the the the the posterior after N data is is the product or proportional to the product
of the posterior after N minus one data and the likelihood for the
for the last observation
so if you like the the the prior for the
the last data point is the posterior
from the step before
very nice sequential
sequential coherence and consistency of the distribution as you learn more stuff
OK so I put I put prior and likelihood on the on the table for many people
that's where we start but I was starting at slightly different place
so is there anything else apart from prior and likelihood and and very importantly there is yes yes there
is and it's not always a center stage
and this concerns issues about utility and loss
often we don't need to think very hard about that
if you're contend
you know to display or visualize a posterior distribution and that's it if that's the focus of your inference
than don't need to think about anything else but if you wanted to make take
decisions or test hypotheses if you wanted to do a serious job of estimation even
you have to think about something else and that's that leads us into areas of
decision theory
so decision theory is a big subject a bit drier I would say actually but I just need
a few key ideas from that
there's a theory of utility which says you know what do we how do we
evaluate uncertainty it tries typically it tries to evaluate the the cost to us
as individuals of being uncertain in malatory terms so we talk about utility on a pseudo money scale
but let's try and just formalize this process in a minute and we'll see we'll see some
practical consequences in a second what's the sequence we observe data why we gonna make
a decision on that data based on that data
so if it's based on that data than our decision is a function of the
so the decision is delta of Y and then we pay a price
and the price we pay is a function of the decision we took on whatever the true
state of nature was
so that's what the loss function is it's a function that the decision you took and the true state
of nature
so it allows us to ask the question how bad is it to
decide delta Y
when theta is true
and the idea we can use then is to try and minimize our losses
and that gives us a means of deciding things
well let's make this concrete the simplest possible thing you could do is decide between the
the two
hypotheses about a parameter
suppose they're just two I've written it as a omega zero and omega one so it's theta and omega zero
or it's theta and omega one
we're gonna use data to decide which of those things is true so we can we can take a decision
D zero
or D one
D zero is I think the theta
is omega zero
Ok so it's just a true or false situation
I think it would be simpler if you get a right answer fine
OK everyone's happy so there's no loss
if you make a mistake then there's a loss and the losses might be
different in the two cases so if you decide D I I zero one
if you decide D I and you're wrong than the price you pay is A I A I is a positive number
OK so that's the setup and we now observe why would what do you do or or or what's the what's the
what's the decision you should take well if you knew theta of course there's no problem
but you don't know theta you only know Y and a natural a natural thing to do
and indeed is correct according to a sort of a meta theory
axiomatic theory of utility is to minimize your expected loss
So notice you minimize L of D theta is your loss and we
integrate that with the spector posterior distribution but you don't know theta but you do have the
posterior distribution that's the expected loss and you do the best you can and you can
that work out very quickly the the the expected loss if you choose D I is A I times
the probability that you're wrong
and that's the posterior probability that you're wrong
and so this amounts to essentially yes
but you don't
why can you just use the expectation well I think the simplest way to think about is just
as a long run thing you know so
this is not the only decision you gonna take in your life you gonna take lots let's suppose
you know when you're a teenager you learn how to take decisions
and you stick to that process but this is this is the law
and pedro domingos from the university of washington and this is the on practical statistical
relational learning
i will start with
make point to be usable which might be possible can you see this
well i guess i have to do with that appointed them
if anybody has a nice
you know
thick brightly visible pointer that i can of the grateful in the mean time i'll
just what with what have so
i will begin with some motivation
and then the tutorial has three main parts
the first part
well you can think of is the core foundational areas
all statistical relational learning mainly probabilistic inference
statistical learning logical inference
and inductive logic programming
i will then
let's see how this works
this is better
i will talk about how we put this all together to build statistical relational learning
is that the second part
you know
this actually part is probably going to be long this because once we know the
pieces putting them together is actually surprisingly maybe not that hard
and finally i will spend a good chunk of time talking about various applications things
that you can do with statistical relational learning today
so let me begin with the motivation
most machine learning algorithms assume
that the data is i i d
meaning that you objects are all independent of each other and you know they're all
the same height
they all have the same kind of distribution
and of course this is very unrealistic but in the real world objects have all
kinds of relationships between the properties of one object affects the properties of another object
and you know we we would like to be able to model them
we'll that we want to be able to model the means of multiple types of
objects we want to be able to model relations between objects the dependencies of object
attributes on the relations between the dependencies of relations on each other attributes and so
i think it's pretty much enormous i think every domain with where we have always
been assuming i did it i think it's the case that if you look closer
there is not i i d
here's is a random sampling of the mines web search is the famous example
if you use links between pages you can get better
page rankings than if you don't
information extraction is another one if you do joint inference between the various things that
you want expect various tests you better
natural language processing is another example of the same kind more general perception
in vision in speech
it's true you have dependencies between the various objects that you're seeing
medical diagnosis is another interesting example right the UCI datasets large number of them is
medical diagnosis problems and of course the first thing you assume that all the patients
are independent while in reality not because you know academics happen and if somebody has
the flu you know the next person is more likely to have the flu and
so forth another interesting examples computational biology
it's one thing to model you know individual problems like you know is this the
promoter region not what we really want to get into these believe is to build
models of how the entire so works and that involves a lot of dependencies among
you know proteins genes et social networks and other obvious example your preferences your habits
the things you do are influenced by your friends your co-workers et cetera
well we could computing is another important example sensor networks
are very hot topic these days the readings that you get one sensor
are you know not independent of the things that you get new sentences for example
and many many more examples
you know i could spend the rest of the afternoon just going over domains with
modelling dependencies between objects is important
what sort of statistical relational learning is really trying to do this trying to model
domains where the objects are not independent because tribute the benefits of doing that well
potential benefit is that we get better predictive accuracy
because if there are dependencies between objects and we ignore the with trying out some
of the information that we could use for prediction so that's one important potential benefit
and that one is better understanding of domains
if we if we ignoring all of the dependencies or the phenomena that are going
on in the main probably won't understand very well as if we do
and also more generally i think SRL offers growth path for machine learning from small
isolated problems through solving the large big massive problems that real intelligence systems have to
deal with
i think we can grow progressively more ambitious
in this way
i took you to offset the
benefits unfortunately there are also some costs
one crosses that learning is not much much harder
if you are dependencies between objects you know the
the number of parameters of the model you have to potentially go up exponentially
and this is going up exponential person was already exponentially large so
you know building on eighty models can be really really hard problem
another another issue is that
you know when you're just doing something like living a classifier you can ignore the
problem of inference because you know inferences just computing function
you really getting inference any more inference is really crucial
because you know no no different classes for example different articles each other you need
to figure out how to compute the and indeed in a good chunk of
this tutorial is going to be talking about
the inference methods that are relevant for for statistical relational learning
here's what is perhaps the biggest problems
the biggest problem is that it's much more complex for the user
two model one i i d domains
this is probably the biggest thing that is holding us back and white people have
always tended to assume i did there is that is just so much easier the
number of options they have to contend with the number of things that you have
to model the number decisions that you have to make you know all of this
when you have a non IID data
so those are the downside what i hope to persuade you today is that thanks
to recent progress
the the
and if it's not the cost and necessarily something that you can do effectively in
practice today without a lot of investment on your part is the researcher or the
so our goal
stated in one sentence
is is to enable learning from non IID data
as easily as from i data
we would like to learning from inevitably to be is easier something like the playing
c four point five was cent classification problem
now they can never completely which disco because after all the problems are complex but
i think that you know we have a fairly close to the
there's been a lot of research on this problem in this year's lot progress
and i think we are at the point where we are close enough to the
goal that you know you can just give statistical analysis to these people and they
will be useful things with them and the that's experience and so the goal of
is to try to unite share this this knowledge
we have these techniques
that was developed in the field with all of
and will also point out that this is also symmetry in in the field work
there is easy to use open source software to do these things
as long as to do as i really need to go into your system and
we add a slope to y
with this slope is obtained by differentiating the corresponding component
at the solution to the corresponding solution
similarly for the
for the
in this is the in the linear i'd in this is
we just revert again we differentiation but we revert to reverse the order of differentiation
we differentiate the conjugate instead of the original
of course the subgradient duality
so you can reverse this universe that
if that's convenient algorithmically
and that's leaf
if you have both green and blue there no
there's is no
the there is no fixed there is no specified direction up if you have only
blue approximations and approximation below on the green approximations from above but if you have
a mixture there's nothing you can say
some problems for some problems it's easier to do but for some components of the
cost function it's easier to do in their out of the station
for example the simplest in cutting plane methods you may have a cost function
you become a constraints
and it may be easier to
just after the linear arise the cost function and in the linear the constraints k
may just be more convenient to do some extra flexibility
that you may or may not be able to use but it's there
and makes the brother
OK now let me explain the enlargement
the allotments step
remember we have this approximation
in we solve
and we find an extract by approximation
for every
out there
approximated function we want to add a new slow
so we have the corresponding component x
he is the corresponding slope wildcats
and then we go up here and we pick up a sub gradient of this
and it's not the flat subgradient OK it's just something that happens to be at
this point
and we have this
this two slopes
for the inner functions different kind of process
we find had
and we have the slope y
and these solve the approximated problem
and now
we find a new point x tilde
such that because the subgradient because the slope equal to one
and then you form this approximation of functions and then fit again and so on
it's reminiscent of simplicial decomposition if you can remember that picture
now let's talk about the duality here
we have this
approximation of the original problem
if we do realize that this is any MP because the dual and the dual
involves the conjugate of this f this blue
after this green
and the dual is denoted by h
the do of f i
h i but now becomes the green function because remember the conjugate of
over and out there
is in
the nb the
and similarly here the conjugate of a green becomes the blue
you can solve either this or that or solve them simultaneously whatever it's convenient for
you for a given problem it may be an algorithm
there may be an album that favors just solving this or that favors just solving
or an algorithm that solves both simultaneously
so in the dual the roles of in outer linear decision have been reserved the
and the choice of primary goal is just a matter of computational convenience does not
affect the output can be mathematically the two are the same
the primal and dual sequence was used exactly the same no matter which one you
so regarding the solution of the approximation
in some cases you may use an algorithm that simultaneously so the prime on the
in one traffic programming
almost all the algorithms
so some of them to the primary do network flow problems and that's certainly the
and then
you would have simultaneously at the end of hats and white hats
in other problems it may be preferable to focus on the solution of either the
primal or the dual
and then after solving the primal
you can define the approximation by differentiation you can go into the enlargements that differentiate
and this may be using it is easy in the cutting plane method you just
subgradient at the pattern many point but it may be non trivial which happens in
the simplest decomposition method we have sort a substantial problems
to find
to find the and not be allowed to be quite frank point and a new
extreme points defining extreme means solving a linear programme is not simplest differentiation
however you have the subgradient duality that may be useful
i can just jump
to the hospital so hyper media b
that's going so i can go back
some scaling back to
simple solution
one of
precision is the possibility for satisfiability for four seasons
that should be
the asian if you don't application you can get a contradiction can essentially
so you see
so in order to
in an essentially trivially satisfied are totally want to get rid of cattle
that's right
people tend not reliable
it's impossible anything in our or
well this is
here is an
because it's a very
right now
you're very little so so it's actually quite far
this is very
but really
one consequence
there's not
not has nine children
so we're not the only reason you
a search
ontology is is probably these are all almost all children of the pages they have
all sorts of whatsoever an easy way to test
is too
four nine
this is big enough radiation make the this everybody read in the back
who was me
would you like to think that's fine
i understand the words make it bigger don't understand
do good enough for OK
so you can see here we call
changes were
because have explicitly said
and they moved
right and that's the way it means that your definition
the world
it was
here's was
well the
from all
we know
you've plausibility to make
one more
strong support this by looking at what that means in terms of what what it
takes to get
we should get
some consolation that that's the goal
this is the name of
just follow the treatment but it's also possible to get more fine grained
the more detailed view of the structure of the ontology
for that reason visualizations
so this is still a very strong association
so she
in the case of nations since we're not
the reason this is just a certain
i can see a lot of
it means that you don't to explicitly asserted so this is just a
and the that
as of two possible ways
well it's possible
the idea is
in two thousand four
relation between all the nations
for example
the rear face and this is actually pretty pretty unusual
so i just to
do a little bit about visualizations
i'm not even remotely following the size and scope do pretty organically because
so last
he adores
you got
the name
so we go to advance
and you can fly mothership
this is of
this is probably more sensible but well so it is
it is an advanced features is an experimental feature
i should say that if you're interested in visualizations
for ontologies that shape and this is where telling myself pay for these
this association was
messy and so on
so we get a sense of the the overall structure of the ontology
nesting again this atrocity select something it will show up over there
you can drill down also the immediate children so animal which is this class here
we have for
also told that
the numbers of children which can be useful
if you select the children will
it will go through and you can and you can zoom up and down to
do what i call
the christmas tree lights
which i is kind just soothing and relaxing to be able to go back to
work but is also find it useful first rapidly scanning with the challenge of this
is equivalent to the energy industry
collapsing everything
only do that actually
it's actually really big controversy
what kind of visualization
systems in parallel across the part of speech
and his and in f one score for all of us all of task
and you can see that the performance is like you know
quite fair
and then
come on guys
i mean
when use the whole sentence rather than the words performance that still sucks
wasting my time i mean so you know i don't but the good results at
the beginning of the book so
actually says afterwards
i mean you're you're quite right it kind of sucks
even so we are like in you know the ballpark of
four years later with processing is sitting on the planet
but you might wonder why he sucks
actually if you think about it well the capacity of like all this work is
mainly in in the world for children right so the first question we we have
in mind is we training this one which is right
she was in is
because you know sometimes the cat sat on the mat
it should have the same kind of play than the feline sat on the mat
on the mat even sort of felines
you know it is
compared to cut
maybe it doesn't even exist actually in order in july
the ones on things
we're close to each other gap on filling close to each other in the what
is then it would be really great because they contradiction by continuity the tax which
would be the same right
so here i look like some random words in the dictionary
and as you have like
the range in frequency of the y so small smaller number means the world is
quite frequent in the last moments is quite well
and reported that encloses wall according to the euclidean distance of from the top one
hundred and see well at least according to the euclidean distance
and would seem to get anything
it's strictly not surprising because in fact in this region is about one million of
world's fifteen percent of the most frequent what IP like ninety percent of the time
so many what only like once or twice on ten times
so you cannot expect to train a fifty dimensional vector always like you know what
would happen after a few times
but fortunately we have like you know a lot of unlabelled data available on here
you just take the web and been infinite so in this part we are
two liver the
labelled data
in our system
if we have the books
i mean the black box
which was able to answer to the question sentences actually english or not
it would be really great because it it wouldn't like books
is able to capture you know the syntax and semantics of grammar which
so actually such a mean some people tried to of black books like you should
have been the resolution in two thousand
try to to make what is called a language model
this was
predicting the the probability of the next world in the sentence according to previous wars
in the sentence
if you know because we think that no dealing with politics it's so complicated you
no normalisation problems which are and actually the on to be greater than they use
tend to be the termite mainly by the most frequent phrases so
instead we prefer to use a ranking criterion
so if i consider like
network which is again
going to be all window approach network this network is going to give me a
school which states if my sentences in the charlotte
and i want
the school
window of text in
some copies
to be larger was the southern margin
then any source for the same window of text but where i replaced
the middle one
by some random walk so basically
the true piece of text coming from a corpus is my in a positive example
i might negative example it is going to be this you know
same window of text replaced in the middle by someone the more
gamma to train as is your language models
by stochastic gradient descent or ascent
and i'm going to say it on a lot of data
we actually first considered wikipedia which is which was about the time six hundred uniforms
then we like to consider an additional data set which is called reuters RCV one
which i did like
two hundred million of examples so it's a massive datasets you cannot expect you know
two two classical
training validation scheme like you know you train
you train on like margaret of parma does on trying to find the right ones
it's impossible it takes too much time so instead we did like a bit like
in biology you like a train new breed a couple of networks lines and you
know every everyday you check or
i was going
you try to make decisions according to some validation set too low
stub line or creating new ones
one of my preferred
problems in statistics is a mixture models are mixture model
is simply
the convolution
several simple model that can be written as as a weighted sum
of density so you have densities and j
and you say k densities these weights p one p two p q and the
sum of the weights is one
and that means that in terms of sampling you start by selecting one of the
with probability p one p two p k
and once you have selected from this density you generate from the identity
via value x
and so could could on of the selection mechanism
you get observations from this weighted sum
so that's something very simple
we would pick
the densities f one f two fk as parametrized entities and we're interested in the
of these entities
all right
we can
density is given in advance and we want to allocate the observations to each other
densities and that's more like clustering or classification
and when you write down the distribution of the sample
of size and
the this
what product of n terms which are all
fans of k terms so it's the complexity of the time and but as we
will see in a few slides
the complexity is more of order
k two c and which is the number of possibilities of allocating c and observations
to the k
in the simplest case it is like if you have a mixture of two normal
we've known weights point seven
and point three and non violence is one and one for you only have to
estimate the two main u one u two u shape
i have
the process of surface of the likelihood is about the same thing and they have
two modes which is if anything because in
actually it is the only identifiable problems they should have one of the forty to
five minute ovation you keep having two modes and
this is a complex problem to find the city mayor of new one u two
and for instance if you use the standard agrees to estimate both means depending on
where you start from that you can see really well from the back but the
part of the EM algorithm would depend on where you start from an out of
starting point here
two that two pairs
of the that stops at the wrong mode which doesn't mean anything in terms of
the real value
so that's already a complex problem even though you can write down italy
the light field
so the fish on in in addition to the bayesian statistician so
examples will also be mostly bayesian
and the basic is just
starting from regular statistics so you have a model with an unknown parameter
observations x from the distribution indexed with by these unknown parameter
and all you do is you
introduce two which is called the prior and which is usually a distribution probability distribution
on the parameter space and you start to work with both
and part
and the way you work with it is to use base and that is you
you think that my is the distribution of theory
and your observable come from the conditional distribution of x given c
you just apply the standard privileges herein called b here and that you can't use
the same distribution of seed given xt river
the other
of conditioning the the likelihood condition x on theta but no observed x u condition
on x there is so that's your
quantity you want to work with and
i know that the regular probability distribution can supply a given that is the basic
tool for doing bayesian inference
and so it's over in terms of formal
inference except that
of course we have trouble to use this posterior distribution
so would keep this this points which are more like advertising for
bayesian statistics
so in very
special conditions you can walk out
every single enclosed terms and i took this simple example where you have binomial
so if have the binomial BNP BNP you're unknown parameter
and if in addition on p
the probability between zero and one
using a beta distribution
which is just the poet distribution on the one
you can find your city mayor
of p
which is the posterior expectation of p
conditional next and so if you write down
what it means you take p
you take your question which is the product of your prior because n minus one
one minute speech to be minus one by the likelihood which is peter the x
y minute speeches he n minus text and bingo you get something close form which
looks rather like x over and your standard estimator except there is a kind of
term here experts a in a plus b
as an
but have a very special case which is called conjugate prior case
and conjugate priors
night because they give you closed form solutions but are terrible
because the rest effect
the use of prior information
they have offer specific forms so
they are too sensitive to the choice of the prior parameters
this is a bad situation that
was sold by new computational methods in
the the early nineties
we it when we get out of computational
computers simple
priors like conjugate priors
we have a range of difficulties
kind of blocking the the more widespread use of vision techniques
and here's a few examples of computational problems
the first
the parameter space may be constrained in very
as we will see later
for the area
the founding model itself the likelihood
may be complex enough so that we cannot write down we cannot compute explicitly the
likely to to point
and again in some missing problems like the stochastic volatility model
this is the case you cannot write down the likelihood of the data set itself
may be a problem that if you have so all
millions of observations the single computation of the likelihood may take too much time
and of course
it is clearly easy to do guassian process regression you've seen it done numerous times
now i think where you choose covariance function for the prior
and then the output is some fitted
some predictions but
i think what might and
i think one might prove difficult here if you want to apply this methodology is
that it's got to be done over time so not only have you got have
the prior
in the former guassian process which is sort of the input to you're simulation measurements
but the the posterior afterwards as also got big as impressed what you can come
you know reasonably propagate guassian prices that way
i'm not sure if you could do it the nice thing would be that you
could specify
get better gas progress is that one can do parametrically because it turns out that
para these parametric estimate we start with the gas in in in parameter space and
and then employ guassian the
guess in envelopes are not uniform is actually impossible to get a spatially invariant guassian
process i mean it would be nice to have one which is a guassian process
which is a
simply a function of the difference between and pride i'm sure you've seen that that
seem to be sensible property for africa so for example i want to start with
the circle and say OK what's my initial uncertainty position the circuit seem intuitive that
you ought to be allowed to say that the variance is uniformly distributed over the
circle and with my
formalism you can't do that if you look at you know whatever
gas distribution you specify over control points or over
over find parameters you tend to get sort of lumps in in the in the
uncertainty in the ground could you can't make a completely uniform
what's going to happen to think
just because
with any luck
cameron to do that again
is that what can to groups chris bishop two
so repeatable behavior across machine
put damp anyway
OK now we need to revisit the fusion process that we that we looked at
but now
done for age observations so you seen this picture before the normals cast out from
the our estimate
the of the console
and now we need to
few edged measurements remember these tangent measurements they're not not points like you do
with conventional regression they have to be
tangent so our the fusion work remember before
we had this simple picture shows what happens when you refuse one corner measurements and
that's the green distribution with the prior in blue and you get the red posterior
so how is this going to work for observations of tangents presumably
distribution is not going to look like this
green thing here because we observed
the tangent
and so you can replace that
observation likelihood by discrete observation like which is of the general thing it's a pair
parallel lines and
so it's covariance appears to be unbounded in one direction which is you thing was
messy thing to do deal with but if we think in terms of information the
inverse of the covariance that's not a problem so the
information matrix for this edge observation
perpendicular to the normal and
has a an information matrix which is just proportional to n then transpose and you
can see that some
only has one non-zero eigen value this
it has rank one matrix
so that deals with the
the edge observation
quite nicely now the posterior
well look something like this the posterior will have covariance because the prior
stabilise things
OK so now
the remember the principles of summation of information and the information weighted mean we ought
to be able to apply those now
absorbing new edge measurements into the
consul space into the shape space and so
what should i write down i could try something like this the new information is
you had
and if you look at this ratio that's enough to decide whether to take this
guy or not
but you need to normalize
my proposal to make this by
two to satisfy that
and we also see why these terms are necessary
but this is the acceptance probability so if you flip a coin
which is the number thing
so this will be between
zero and one
so if you if you flip coin and the coin is less than this
in other words if this guy is much better than this guy you take it
if you flip a coin and it's not
then the and essentially what you're doing is
what we're doing is something from a discrete distribution
just going to resampling trick we did yesterday because this is what we have here
is a and we have one minus a
this is when you know
accept new
next star
and this is when you
x i
so have a candidate
nature provides something for you
if it's much better to take if it's not
this is but you don't take it
if you're not sure
you do the flip of a coin and probability a you take that you can
and the way you choose a sort of detailed balance is satisfied
they next and gets update
welcome to that now
if the guy across the OK for you if the woman across the bottom looks
more or less like the one you have
you might not take too much if you're already with some hard bay and there's
a hot babe across the bar
so much effort to work
you guys guys guys well
you have to probabilities provide acceptance probability of rejection when something is much better
and this you term will dominate the bar will be much harder than the other
so quite often
it will be
of the original one when you don't have this q if q is symmetric if
this guy asymmetric in disguise disappear so the argument is when these guys disappear
because there is a symmetric so this is the same as the
then if this guy is much better than
if x diaries but the next slide is is going to be larger than one
so you will always accept
in general we do need to have the keys to satisfy the power so what
you really could do is to compute a in one minus a
that neither of what
now you will need it because there's going to be these cues
the club analogy problem but it was fun
but that's pretty much the idea
OK so maybe you the club have this special by is this going to be
no special by bias
the magic point that tells you want to
go for a hunt
good question so we have to question the it all the positions their annealed
now to that next
this is how the algorithm works in practice
after one hundred samples you have sort of
after five hundred you have to fit and i would run by the mathlet simulations
which show you that this happens this fast
and up to five thousand samples you have a pretty good approximation
of the target distribution
how do you choose that q
it's an important question
if q is just a random walk
and these are the things you have to keep in mind
if you start markov chain in one mode
the markov chain starts here
in the past winners we can delay the onset a little bit
and i told him with about cross validation expected look like
i think questions here
everything clear immediately that
well my master so frankly asleep
should not
what not looking good
well we can actually use it for a couple
useful practical things so
one with be novelty detection
the idea would be willing to find the least likely observations
and so what you do you could for instance perform with a system that in
the interest
without the observations events discourse lowest
and so what i could do is just compute the density estimate
this here
and then sort with respect to i and just
print according to the magnitude
what would you can
network intrusion detection
for instance you want to find out that something unusual is happening on the network
the jet engine might fail
you might want to cling it places like somebody inserted started with typos
mislabeled digital and on that photographs
fraud detection
as of collaborating alarm so
park your car somewhere in
you know sometimes it's very quiet back to street and sometimes it's a really nicely
highway and when he said the car alarms
you should the
i installed the city to the highway runs
otherwise it'll always go off the highway
but it might not be sensitive enough to detect the thief early on the back
so you want something that's calibration automatically
that one
this these are typical data
from these space so this is like the ones that i showed you
these will be outliers
the fairly of the most of them
at least i hope you agree
and that's just
from there in in decreasing
order this
you can see why
what this is anybody's guess
very badly segmented
this apparently suffice
it could have been an eight or nine
that i think is too
what that as well
probably something like
german for but badly written
what that if nobody knows i think it was six but
basically what it means is these are really
it it doesn't again guarantee that you'll find all the bad ones but you'll find
a lot
you'll see pretty pictures of outliers
now there is another useful trick that you might want to remember
it has to do with solar mass automatic adjustment rule
the problem is let's i have
pick some kernel with
and unfortunately doesn't really work well
it's say
that could lead to the final density
because what you would actually want to in regions of low density
because what coral person regions of high density you outcome
that's a bit of a technical problem right
because i'm trying to the density estimation
but actually it will need to have a good density estimate in order to the
a with density estimation
so how can we work around well we don't quite eustace this estimation but we
use a very very
sloppy scheme which will give us a rough idea of what's going on
so all i do is i just find out what the average distance of points
x i is to its nearest neighbour k nearest neighbour
and then using that
to adjust the range of radio system
and improve things quite a bit
so for instance you can pick
the kernel we
be something like point five that quantity
link is actually pretty good this estimation matter and you can use it for regression
and classification
so that would be exactly such events the idea here
so they feel there so you want to live out there and everyone over here
and if i pick just one scale not terribly good
i picked different scales
you can see it actually works very well
if you know how to implement this you'll will be able to get approval to
classify regression estimate already
the idea is well i've got past observations x and y
and it's a one plus one is one
i want to find some estimator for the conditional probability of y given x
why i can just
and i want to find p of y equals one given a
well that p of y equals one and x two are quite a few things
just worked this out the negative pressure
and whenever this racial here
less than one-half mile sites class minus one
underlie cell sites class
i can easily just say well look that we take the difference between the positive
and the negative class
and then they get this expansion here
which happens to be
essentially the same thing as the naive it's the incredible classifiers
that will be talking about much later
but basically
what you do is you just take a weighted combination of the labels
according to how close you are to them
and that will tell you tell you what you're label is
so this is very similar to what we had in our nearest neighbour remembered