play femal
i think it was the piano doing
it's the same courtyard
actually i'm seeing the melody they're playing a chordal accompaniment against
all right let's listen to the next iteration of this theme we've identified this is
being who's got the females exactly the same and one of the strings up to
in terms of string technique here
so who had the theme
can but was in exactly the same
not really is kind of noodling around the varying a little bit when the strings
doing they were playing the accompaniment and what string technique where they use it
mentioned the first chapter of the book there
you've got a nice laplace
pizzicato good OK pizzicato we can write that we write the termites OK we've got
it up pizzicato that's help
with the in that particular case we switch the roles around
let's let's go ahead two ten we can move this along just a little bit
here as we come back into this i think we've got a situation where the
the piano keep playing for
key building enough attention and a cascade and the team comes back let's see what
it's not
one two three
all right so that's an introduction to a three movement piano concerto happens to be
the first of these three movements it's pretty spectacular music i hope you like music
it's one of the one of the great melodies of all time it's bit of
a wonderful example of a of a scene
having talk just a little bit about genres we can conclude by saying there are
other kinds of genres in music of course we're we've been introduced this idea of
the tone poem the strauss zarathustra is a tone poem that's the kind of one
movement work in which the composer tries to tell the story or play at historic
events or in the case of the strauss i guess to give us the beginning
of the contents of the philosophical novel through music so tom on a one room
we've got other kinds of dramas music we've got opera we've got cantatas sonatas and
ballets things such as this will get to each of those in turn
so that's the end of the discussion of strong let's go going now to talk
about instruments and how instruments produce sound a heater come on this is my friend
longtime colleague music library an extraordinary and professional french horn player peter who will demonstrate
here come on over here right in the centre gene campbell was in the basement
somewhere recording all of the
so it's very exciting time to be alive so he was going to just demonstrate
the physical
processor playing the french horn
this is a very common
in this case they come close
there's a whole
that what
we go
i have
was just note
that's hard
what about
is a short line
like car
so what
i think which was
OK that's fine that's great that's that's the principle which is actually overblown what that
means is more keep emphasizing is pointed out that new partial that once sounds made
you have not just one sound but that to tube is dividing it up into
sections and all kinds of little sections of that one two are certainly not just
the biggest sound but the partial of the overtone behind-the-scenes intervals in the harmonic series
so it's a whole series when we listen to a single tone is a whole
series of what he was doing there is playing out the nodes in that series
successively will keep banging on that now if you would ever play just the beginning
of the our through struggle with the trumpet part can you do that
well whenever here in what do you
what you would do do well to do what can we do see an
that's not that that's another thank you very much thank you
OK have another gig out in guildford to this morning so she's going to have
to run off and i'm going to show you maybe if we get our slides
up overtone series OK it's not
i hope i got it on the slide gentlemen can you i'm going to hit
but i was told to do
the function
f eight is that right
alright something came up and then disappear
right so can we have the technical person please bring
press it one more time
OK so we don't have read
all right so let's i tell you what we're going to just leave this up
and i will bag the other slot i have slides with all this information on
it but we can't seem to bring these
what we've got here is the following this idea of partials even was talking about
with ratios
two to one three two four forty three five four sixty five and so on
you can prove to yourself or higher order
how the half-life various concentration so i said we look at the other which is
second order
second order reactions and
here's an example it's dimerisation of
try chloride try chloride can form the dimer failed to
cl six gas phase and right off the bat and let c be the concentration
of illumina
try chloride and its second order because the rate of disappearance of aluminum try chloride
goes as the square now this is one of those instances where it's really tempting
this reaction has the two in front of it and it turns out that the
rate of disappearance of aluminum try chloride goes as casey square but do not do
not want to say three times do not assume that this is the rule that
because you sort once that this is always the case that the stoichiometry gives you
the order of reaction this is not the general case it happens in this reaction
for reasons that will go into later but generally you have to measure
the order of reaction
so if we go through the same analysis one minus
the c overseas squared equals
kt t will do the integration blah blah blah
and eventually we end up with this relationship the reciprocal of concentration
it is
a linear function of
so that means that the functional that we need is given here so the way
to determine if something is
this first order in the second order and
is to take this
concentration versus time
which is always look like this to the naked eye because i don't know if
that's first or second order but i can detect the straight lines of instead i
map this into one over c
first this time i should end up with a straight line starting at one overseen
and the slope of that line should be
so when i see that this is a straight line
i go
and equals two
and the slope is the rate constant if this were not a second order i
wouldn't get a straight line so
this this allows me to
to proceed and get the order of reaction in fact what i'm showing you is
one of the ways people
determine order of reaction they use the integrated form of the rate equation
so this is called the integral method to determine order of reaction
the order of reaction
the order of reaction the first way is
integral method
and it's essentially a comparison
so comparison with the integrated form of the rate law
comparison with
integrated form of the rate law
integrated rate law equation this really inspection this is trial and error
we also try to america
from MIT so we use faster reducing by inspection
that's a televised what you're doing just really have to do this by inspection
so what i do is i try and equals one if i get an arbitrary
data set i try and equals one
i try and equals two after that i said forget it i'm going go to
the other methods so let me show you
a couple of slides that indicate this
so here's the data set up i pulled set some somewhat this is the reaction
so this this time this is the concentration some species and don't worry about that
will get to that in second so here's your data set designer you have if
you plot these here's what they look like this is concentration
in animals per
unit volume as a function of time and there is a c
normalized to one unit and its attenuates over five hundred seconds were down to about
twenty percent of the initial value so i say what's the order of reaction i
can't tell
so i want to do
yes i'm going to say OK now let's take the natural log of c
versus time then go straight line
so that for on this basis i conclude that it's a straight line and the
slope of this line is the
rate constants
but just to show you that doesn't always work i said just for grins and
chuckles plot that same data set as one overseas and look what happens when i
plotted as one over c i don't get a straight line
so it really does discriminate doesn't give me
what i was going to expect in terms of the straight line except when i
have the proper order of reaction
so now let's see another way that we can get at this and this is
called the differential method
and i'm going to use the integrated form of the rate equation
will use the
the differential form
and i'm going to to compress the notation on the left lower case are
the the rate the rate is lower case are which i'm going to
let stand for miners d by DTC how i give my thoughts more and more
compressed i start with the big with the square brackets and i get to this
and i get to this is getting
tighter and tighter
OK so now i can write the rate equation as the re
goes as
c to the and so there's the arbitrary radius equation
and i want do something to take the logarithm of the equation
so i i can map that into the logarithm of the rate
the log of the product is the sum of the log so that'll be the
of the rate constant plus and times the logarithm of concentration
now i can do
that does exactly
what generates black
so if
anybody ever tells you to the density estimation
this is really the first thing you want to do
it's called parzen windows
and obviously
you can also use that to build the classifier
princess binary classification
two this statement one class
the density estimate for the class
computer asia
if the ratio is larger than one
class one
iteration less than one
plus minus one
this is exactly
that equation here
and then we can just go
several let's compute the squared distance
between p hard
into that
if i do that
to a little bit of algebra that's what i'm getting
now those functions k
i just the integral
of k f x minus t
and kale ex-prime honesty dt
these actually happened to be proper kernels
this function k
not the campus
and i obtain those
by just doing
the past windows density estimate and then computing the squared distance
the questions at this point
so obviously if i have this i could say well if this quantity is small
then i can
argue that people's q
and if this distance is large
and i would say p is not you
would have probabilities
the catch to it
so let's assume p is really q
and i said why
so who thinks
this quantity you will be zero
if i use the same distribution to generate x and y
he thinks it's going to be here
who thinks
it's going to be large
who thinks it's going to be small
OK quite a few people
that's exactly what's going to happen
this term is not going to vanish
even if people q
it's going to get smaller and smaller as we get more data sure
but this term has the bias
and this applies mainly comes from one thing
if you look at these expressions here
they well they're all those terms here
i was j
now how likely is it that the name drawing from a distribution that i'm seeing
the same data twice
extremely unlikely
and if ever discrete distribution
so the self-interest in trends describe everything
and later on we'll see very similar quantity to this red line
which is an unbiased estimator
that is exactly the same policies
it will be deriving it in a very different way
slightly will be slightly different normalizations up here but that's really just in the details
and that time then
will take care of all the self interactions
so this is the really simple way it actually works reasonably well
well there are a couple of for
that's true that's hard
and i didn't bother doing it
will see a much simpler way of
getting this to get things similar case
but the very accurate confidence level
based on the results
it should they not be too difficult to get the confidence level
on this text
OK but
think that the question that the fast so much harder than the problem i'm going
to show you how to sort
OK so we're going to be lazy to solve simple problems
the problem here is what we're accustomed dimensionality when we estimate those things it is
well we have problem with the statistical analysis because well you know
we need to
basic is a multi-stage procedure first we need to estimate the density and then we
compute the distance and then we want to get the confidence
that's really hard
and besides said what do we do on strings images and structured data
all graphs
so i mean how did the parzen window density estimate on graphs
i don't know
and obviously this quantity is biased
OK so
but the problems
this is the thing that we're not going to do
now let's
look at the simplicity
so the key ideas
to avoid the thing that there was a lot of problems namely the density estimate
use the means directly
and now he is the key criterion and world
we reinvented the wheel and then realise that people in nineteen fifty three already had
done something like that
his friends also the profit of metric
on distributions which uses something similar in someone's kontorovich problem and all that which are
very close related to
the setting
what they usually do when i have the density
estimation well
i will use it at some stage eventually to compute expectations
of some sort
for instance i would compute the expectation of
say the loss being larger than hundred
i want to compute
so the average amateur compute the average gain that i'm making audience but at the
end of the day quite often will
compute expectations
and in fact
in some way uniquely defined distributions they they define uniquely in the weak sense
basically except for some pathological cases that i'm not going to get into
this is why fourteen said well
if i have to distributions p and q
for the moment i'm going to assume that we know them and will get into
how to get those estimators afterwards
i can define the distance between p and q
with respect to some function classes
to be
the so so basically the search of the worst possible function from the function class
over the expectation of f of x
sp three hybridized carbon along this axis here
that's why i turned around here comes the other
sp three hybridized carbon and i'm going to let these two
sp three hybrid wave functions overlap
so that now one of my ISP three states two electrons in it
so here
one of my doing right here i'm letting those two sp three wave functions overlap
constructive interference hey i'm going to make
a sigma bond because
this weight function is cylindrically symmetric around that axis sigma bond
it is a sigma bond composed of the carbon
two sp three hybrid wave functions
and another carbon two sp three hybrid function
i just for carbon carbon bonds
OK i just brought in some hydrogens
in each one
in each case
i now have overlapping
between the line as weight function
and the sp three wave function of the carbon in the molecule that here is
let's look at and this angle here is one hundred ninety degrees right
one hundred nine degrees
because you had the hat-trick
tetrahedral configuration around the carbon
because that's how
as the two as wave functions and the three two p wave functions around the
constructively and destructively interfere
to give you
he drove for a
for the SP three wave functions
let's take a look like at but we can do this
let's start right so we may be VCH bond here they're all sigma bonds also
OK so that carbon
this sp three hybridization for carbon
but other atoms
and also wonder
this sp three hybridization
and one of those atoms here is nitrogen
here's the electron configuration for
in this case we got
two electrons and two st then one in each one of the two p states
what we're going to do here
is going to allow now
these three function for which functions to constructively and destructively interfere what we call
and the result will be
four sp three weight function
except the difference is that because we have one more electron nitrogen
one of these sp three state is already got two electrons in it
right so it's not going to be available for bonding
in nitrogen
the electron
arrangement of the function arrangement is also tetrahedral right
st three to the score sp three
sp three sp three
except that one of these wavefunctions is this three functions
really is kind of two
st three wavefunctions are so electrons here in this
this is the lone pair
on the nitrogen and sp three hybridized nitrogen atom
this is the long pair pointed at one of these vertices
then each one of these loans has just
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this MIT opencourseware
at OCW MIT that EDU
good morning
try tried again good morning
thank you
this is six hundred also known as
introduction to computer science and programming
my name is eric grimson together professor john good tag over here
we're going to be lecturing the course this term
i want to give you a heads up getting some serious firepower this term
john was department head for
ten years felt like a century in a course six on the current department head
in caustics john's been lecturing for
thirty years
all right i'm the young guy only been lecturing for twenty five years
you can tell i have less gray hair than he does
what i'm trying to say to you is we take this course really seriously
we hope you do as well
but we think it's really important for the department to help
learn about computation and that's what this course is about
what i want to do today
these three things
i'm going to start
should starting in a little bit of administrative you the kinds of things you need
to know about how we're going to run the course
i want to talk about the goals of the course
what it is you will be able to do
at the end of this course when you get through it
and then i want to begin talking about the concepts and tools
of computational thinking
which is what we're primarily going to focus on here we're going to try and
help you learn how to think like a computer scientist and we're going to begin
talking about that towards the end of this lecture on the course throughout the rest
of the lectures to carry on
by the start with the goals
to give it goes into levels
the strategic goals of the following
we want to help prepare
freshmen and sophomores who are interested in majoring in caustics
to get an easy entry into the department especially for those students who don't have
a lot of prior programming experience
if you're in that category don't panic run get
we're going to help you ramp in and you'll certainly be able to start the
course six curriculum
and do just fine and still finish on target
we don't expect everybody to be a course six major
contrary to popular opinion
so for those who you not in that category the second thing we want to
do is one help students who don't plan to major in caustics to feel
justifiably confident in their ability to write and read
small pieces of code
for all students we want to do is you want to give you an understanding
of the role computation can and can not play
in tackling
technical problems
so if you will come away with the sense of what you can do what
you can do and what kinds of things you should use to tackle
complex problems
and finally we want to position all students so that you can easily if you
compete for things like europe in summer jobs
because you have an appropriate level of confidence and confidence in your ability to do
computational problems
so the strategic goals
this course is primarily aimed at students who have little or no
prior programming experience
as a consequence we believe that no student here is underqualified
for this course you're all MIT students are all qualified to be here
but we also hope that there aren't any students here who are overqualified
for this course
what i mean by that if you've done a lot of prior program
this is probably not the best course for you and if you are in that
category i would you please encourage you to talk to john right after class about
what your goals are what kind of experience you have and how we might find
you of course that better meets
your goals
a second reason we don't want overqualified students in the class sounds a little nasty
but the second reason is
and overqualified students somebody who's i don't know program for google for the last five
is going to have an easy time in this course but we don't want such
as student accidentally intimidating the rest of
we don't want you to feel inadequate
when you're simply inexperienced
so it really is a course aimed at students with little or no
prior programming experience and again if you're not in that category talk to john after
and we'll help you figure out where you might want to go
OK those are the top level goals of the course let's talk
sort of other more tactical level of what do we want you to know this
is what we want you to be able to do by the time you leave
this course so here are the skills
we would like you
to acquire
the first scale we want you to acquire
the of the in his name down
they do
he got to mixtures of spherical clusters spread equally in the space of higher dimension
and a very large number of points the number of clusters the number of dimensions
and how far the clusters
this should be over sigma here so
so the difference between the news defined
the separation
so there's a specific term
they use the best c and one of the problem which was the
with a projection of the visible
remember this is not the in general this is best for or what they found
to be that was for clustering or cluster were sort of semantically space
so there are some similar to the
two things that the
and with the initialisation something like
and they want
the cheetah which is
yeah mean
seven years
so you know where to start
and smart enough to sustain their return to send something very close and give the
correct clustering so we get a lot of help
and then they looked to see
you find clustering anybody could maximize like
now we can never know what the likelihood is maximum
you can only say
things like
she'd followed
you the solutions for the
what assumptions are different from us close what hired like
things like
of the rest
we never could increase the likelihood of of what the simple you
you can see the default
and what they found is that
an interesting fact
to some it is not surprising but it's not i see mentioned is basically that
if you have enough data points
and two years in the house
what depends on the degree
the number of dimensions and so on
but if you if the number of points
the regime
he also always the solution
and you should also
so having lots of data
order parameter problem that
there is no to understand the initial find
there is you
so solution to is the global optimum
the true parameters are like so here you can almost guarantee that you have maximize
this is an important result
and maybe not surprising but it's good for
and then
the regime of poor to little
when they want to know how
that's too bad you don't even though they don't have to know anything with with
the original
because just two days
or at least you have enough to be discovered by the model
thirty years
and then night you didn't find anything and cheating to find and basically the correlation
between the two
and the true clustering with
no the incarnation
and then
he doesn't find
the anything relevant
however she that
i think
find the most
you don't you think
well away from the person but is significantly better than the cheap
but the likelihood the class
which means that in fact there is information then you can multiply
OK surprisingly
the things that are nearly sorted but often it's just you know it's sort somebody
wants to make sure it sort it
just sort it again rather than checking see if sort
in those cases one side of partition
each partition
has no
so that we can write out what the recursion is for that
so it's here and if one side has no elements
we're going to have to zero on that side
and on the other side have to give n minus one
for that which is running out the recursion for this
so one side has no elements the other side has n minus one elements
and the partitioning of the bookkeeping and so forth is water and
so what is to zero
what's two zero
but what does that asymptotically
yes constant or one
OK so that's just
o or one
plus here than minus one
first order and well
the order one can be absorbed into your and so this is really just saying
t then minus one
four and
and what's that equal to
that's order in square
k or m squared
why is that and squared
yes an arithmetic series
OK actually just like
we got more
insertion sort
just like for insertion sort
because an arithmetic series went all that work
we have an algorithm called the quicksort
it's no faster
then insertion sort
well as i said good algorithm
the reason is a good algorithm is because it's
average case time when see is very good
but let's try to understand this little bit more just so that we understand the
difference between what's going to happen in the average case what's going to happen in
in the worst case
so let's draw recursion tree for this
here's an equal to zero
and minus one
plus and i'll make the cost explicit per se
OK so we get an intuition what's going on so some constant times and
and then
we have to and is equal to and we write it with the
in part here c
in nineteen zero here
t of n minus one here
i know there are you folks are really fast and want to jump immediately to
the full tree
but let me tell you my advice is that you spend just a couple minutes
writing out
only costs to since the tree grows exponentially only cost you constant overhead
to write out the small cases OK and make sure you got the pattern that
you're developing someone go one more step
here we he zero
and now this becomes to see this become c
times and minus one
and now we have another over here
t of
one minus two
and we continue that
the dot
until we get to
so that's all equal to
c and with two zero here
sometimes and minus one
the key is zero here
single interest groups
as we've come to call them
whereby and religions one of those right to have the some reason why you will belong together
and if they create a sense can ship
and if you think the language used in a lot of religious brothers sisters fathers mothers
will kind terminology it's the language family and kinship
and so
the reason route
down that's beautiful creating a sensor belonging i think what it's all about is creating
some grand project this is clearly one religions what is a grand project that we're
all trying to achieve
so you have to have the sense of the big project which everybody signs up
to as bright i belong to the club
and we see that all the time so you know
they were are
you know so the band you say you've you you go to the bar and
i'd be so in the guy sitting next you turns out to be
a profound founded the same football club u you know and then your mind each other drinks or not
just on the you never met the guy before
you know we do something that gets kicked in
when you have the sensitive
belong to a club some kind of doesn't appear to be unique to human so
there is a route down there
question is what kinda grand project can we have that is religion
that would create sensitive
okay thank you for the talk i really enjoyed it
my question was
very related so i'm gonna have to change it i guess my original question was
you know that the
framework that you posted the beginning about why isn't facebook
opening up these new vistas for u i i feel a little bit like that
straw person argument given that's
we know that that's just
sites like facebook are typically
used to
articulated previously existing relationships so so
i don't know that
i haven't seen in scholarship a popular press this idea about
that work kind making
entirely new sets friends
sites like facebook but rather using them to
kind connect more deeply in our
and easily with people that we already know
so i guess i wanted to kind of push you a little bit on this
kind of
idea that's that's what they're supposed to do and that's a feeling you know i
i mean i think the argument really hinges around the fact that facebook or another
social networking sites in principle when the set had vision in my
it implicitly if not explicitly
like that could allow you to connect up lots of people and so
that's my
interpretation why facebook started to give you in particular started to give you these linkages
you itself senses a friend friend friend you may be interested in signing up them as well
most people i think we have resisted at temptations so hasn't really worked in the way they probably originally intended
but not everybody and some people clearly do
and i think there into this with a competitive game problem
if anything
but it's clear that what i mean by facebook and the like
ah have really filled an important niche and that's the next that come about as
a result probably only in the last half century
whereby as we become more mobile
three all life you end up having little
blocks are friends
scattered around in the world where you've worked or been to university or whatever it is
what it does is allow you to keep keep those
going in when they were clearly drop the great question is
well they drop out anyway
doesn't know facebook level contact there's all it do is slow down the rate of decay
what is it hold it up
we guess that we have no evidence at the moment
that's it just slows down the rate of decay because what's important ultimately keep a
relationship going is actually doing stuff that together face-to-face now face
social networking sites start to be able to introduce
you know videoconferencing talk formats as
google groups and
people have been doing that's may solve the problem but it still hasn't done the
virtual touch things because we actually release close friends we engage in a lot of
physical touch
so the question then is
well actually
in astronomy
if you have a binary system and the stars exactly do this
to determine all these quantities that you
would like
i first would like to show you know
some slides
the first slide
o i have lower described by the way that would help wouldn't it
it's a spectrum
made in the laboratory
helium and calcium and sodium
it shows you
emission lines no absorption lines
o lines are produced by lamps
and the frequencies are very well known
you see the famous sodium yellow lines
so here's the red part of the spectrum and is the blue part of the
so we know these
frequencies node wavelengths very well
and here you see
of the sun was all these absorption lines that i mentioned to you
last was absorption lines
each of them can be identified
these are due to calcium
i hydrogen and so on
here is the real part of the spectrum
is the green party the green party and and here is the red part of
the space
and here
you see
the basic idea
a binary system
suppose you have a binary system that only one stars visible and the other one
is invisible
and the one star show you three clear absorption lines
then as the star
moves around the centre of mass
you see them all these lines drifting unit
and out of this information
you get the radius the velocity and the period assuming that you are on earth
in the plane of the orbit of the stars
if you have a binary system whereby
both stars are visible
so you get the spectrum of both stars
there you see the doppler shift of both stars in the spectrum
here we have the simple case that we only have two absorption lines not to
confuse the issue
so in one in the case of one start
the shift will be towards the left of the two lines
but the order of start to shift will be to the right
because if you have a binary system and one star comes to you
the other start goes away from you and vice versa
so now you're very lucky
now you have an ideal situation
that you can find football stars
the radius of the orbit the velocity in orbit and the period
for each star which of course is the same
for both
and here you see real data
you see here first of all
the emission lines which are measured in the laboratory
i just showed you always done simultaneously
with the measurements
you always must be sure that you have good calibration of your wavelength
and this spectrum eight pop spectrum is store binary system that has a period of
twenty point five days
you see here a single lines if you have good eyes that means at this
very moment both stars move relative to you at angles of ninety degrees so you
don't see any doppler shift but now look here later in time
you see this line
split into lines and this one is also split into lines
clearly one component is coming to you
and the other component is moving
away from you
and so you get all this useful information
in astronomy
the doppler shift measurements
of binary systems
i want to
so the idea of
binary stars
they give us
not only the information
that we want regarding
the orbit
but there is even
that we can get out of it which is even more
so i will remind you want a binary system looks like
remember exams
the second exam sure you'll never
forget that second examine maybe never forgive me for that
binary system
star one
radius are one
mass and one
v one
and start to
going about their common centre of mass
mass two
radius r two
and the velocity v two
and one or one
he calls and two are that's the way the centre of of mass
is defined
imagine that you as an observer
somewhere in the plane of its orbit
and you are you
you observing system
going around
capra's third law
which derived
on the exam as well as on i
the period squared equals four pi squared
times are one
plus are two
the power three
divided by
times and one
plus and two
we checked that to make sure you have the right yes
that is correct
imagine how you can make the doppler shift measurements of both stars
you make the doppler shift measurements of star number one
so you measure lambda one prime as a function of time
this is actually applicable to any kind of discrete rituals
for example we could do stemming if we if we like
so you could
apply that the stem once you've lectures use capitalization features and things like that this
kind of features you can
you know use
it is
actually this idea is quite all as well all over world
it's more reasons and that works in the field it has been published in two
thousand one
by yoshua bengio
four like actually training error which model and what you one
so once you know how to force from once interact
well you are you are already on was done
you just
you can actually
you know you consider a sentence like you know like the cat sat on the
mat on suppose you want to tag
the one on
so i'm going to take a window of
one one of interest
so it's a fixed size window
of it's a window of size five
and for each one in the window you consider all your features of interest
and for each features on each one you apply
you're lookuptable or idea
so you're paying for each one like the corresponding feature vector
once you've done that you can just like concatenate concatenate everything and find that classical
or you know
nine network layouts and you train
it's in
by the competition
and surprisingly it works well for many tasks like you know part of speech tracking
to children is it's it's OK
the only thing is that
four best which led to require long range dependencies like for example simmons' column
you cannot expect this to because final before semantic quality your thinking one with respect
to have a neutral beforehand and then might be even that outside the window
so instead of that you know you cannot consider
just a window of text you have to consider the complete sentence
so instead well just like consider the complete sentence
the point then is that
the sentence might be of fibre lengths right and z is a is actually like
a quite common
no network architecture to deal with this kind of things it's cooler conditions
one this time it's a bit like a generalisation of the window approach
basically because you don't
again a window of
size with the right answer
you can look at the net all of this three vectors together and you play
metrics are some indication
which points you like a kind of local features you shift you do the same
for the next three it gives you again like local features and so on
come on this is done in nineteen eighty nine when presented this energy towards two
thousand nine because you forgot about it
actually works very well for fixed so
so that
they basically are going to train again disbarment metrics
as a result you know knowledge work
once you you you you produce like this you know local features
you still have like a number of vectors
which is which is like
dependent on of of the number of walls in the sentence so you still have
to get rid of this you know the time dimension
so for doing this here we apply max over time so we try to capture
the most interesting
features over time just playing a max of
each feature of time
and that's it once we got that we have no fixed size feature vector which
like represent opted sentence and we can fit fit that two classic or no at
so we're going to do that actually fall
each one in this sentence so we need to
and some extra features
to the network which what we are interested in
and with respect to which we want to thank you
so the network in that case looks like that it's again and this time you
posted on the complete sentence
all one in this sentence you
consider on the features you are interested in
you apply the lookup table four
all of all the words in the sentence
play operations if you like but look charlie
you apply the maximum time
to get rid of the
the time dimension
and then you find that the classical millions and that's it
we have to train this beast
we actually like to use like i mean we are we are much also we
consider our training set right and we are going to
temperate some of
on on the talk outputs as priorities
so after all so i will show you two ways to interpret this
network puts us point
but once
you've probably is you can just like maximum maximize the log likelihood
apply stochastic gradient descent you know parliament also the network
that they represent him
and you
train like
i mean people sink usually is on that there is a lot of tricks you
know but actually we consider only two classical tricks we divide the learning rates by
what is called the finding actually the nonlinearities fixed
and we initialize also according to the opening the singers
what this
good christians if it's a sentence internal make sure it's
like number of
inputs you have initially basically
OK so somehow you normalized by the number of
parliament also in the late
input parliament
so what
your knowledge workers are kind of
if you look at it like you know exists
it's really like module
and actually we
it's what you're
computes is its derivative was
i mean it's model as to compute is density with respect to the parameters right
and this can be done efficiently by what is called a competition which is just
an application of the general
so it's more you're basically computes its derivative with respect to its own parliament
it started with respect
so you might be interested in actually looking at that
the posterior distribution itself forming some kind of expectations with respect to it
for example
if we set is a function just to be xity itself there will be calculating
the posterior mean estimates which is the minimum mean square error estimator for the states
you may also wish to allow ourselves the lack to make it more reliable estimates
made moving
for example estimating the state of the lack of
or we may wish to fixed interval smoothing trying get the distribution of the entire
state sequence over some time axis not
so that it illustrates that filtering is concerned with the media estimation is you get
a new data point smoothing
give you some look ahead of future data points and hence you should get a
tighter distribution on the on on the states
right so filtering there is the main focus of this this work so let's consider
filtering at time t
suppose we solve the filtering problem up to that time so these things are divided
to right in a recursive fashion usually
we've got the filtering distribution we want to update it one time step with the
input of new data point y
t plus one
in principle we could do that with the filtering recursions in the first of all
the prediction step
so first of all take
the filtering distribution and update it one time in the future
here is the distribution of x t plus one given all the old data
we can do that by taking the joint distribution
the old state and the new state given all the old data and marginalizing with
respect to it
thanks old state we can factorize that in terms of thing that we have
so factorized in terms of the filtering density that we've already solved at time t
multiplied by
the conditional distribution conditional density of the state at time t plus one
given the all states and all the old data
but because of the assumptions of the model
that's not the state transition density at right comes this marginalization in terms of the
previous filtering density
time the state transition density taking the time t plus one
and then base their kicks in because we now want to incorporate effective a new
data point y t plus one
well that's got directly them from that from the remaining terms in the model
we've already got the predictive distribution of xt plus one given the old data
we multiply that by the observation density
the GFY t plus one given x t plus one
divide through by the normalizing constant PY t plus one given y north routine that
bayes theorem is given us directly then the corrected formula for the new filtering distribution
so that's all very straightforward except that you
probably can't do this integral in closed form it could be high dimensional
you've got all the usual problems of dealing with nasty forms nicely unknown forms for
the for the pdf there
and so
but in principle it operates simply you just progress through time adding more data points
as you go y t plus one y t y t plus one
you do the filtering getting timesteps sold it to t minus one
you do the prediction step two to two
predict one state in the future
then you correctly using bayes theorem predicts correct status as leapfrog type approach through time
but as i say this can be done in in general approximations must be used
especially when x is high dimensional
and f and g are nongaussian on linear
so i'm going to go through now the basics of the the kalman filter
because the say that this is fundamental to some of the particle filters and there's
a very fundamental idea underlying sequential updating bayesian sequential updating
OK so it applies for
where they did actually use study and compared the learned system with google MSN search
and another search engine top ranked in a blind testing and the way they could
show yes you know this combined system performs better than all of the individual search
engines and here's a here the weights that were put on the different features so
you can see query abstract cosine has the highest weight so this is kind of
you know the vector space model type of thing being among the top ten in
it was you know rather to get relatively high weight the key cosine between the
query and the euro the euro words if we segmented and so on and so
forth and down here you can see some of the
the ones that have negative impact like the URL length
for instance is usually that's fine
OK so
so this is you know another example where
you use relatively weak data but you have large volumes of these data and use
it to optimize an information retrieval system
OK so
and any questions about this yes
in this experiment ran instance we talking about several thousands of users who have used
the system for
and again it depends on on what level of granularity want to choose
but i think you know this is a very interesting and promising paradigm in general
also while this is not to say
you have a system
it has some key
component that is parametrized in some way by
has has been impact on the
and as users actually all use the system and work with the system interacts with
the system the system is highly able to use
you know just
the information collected during the user
optimized performance
that is a very attractive here because you know
the user doesn't even know that anything is happening there is that proxy is used
kind of reports you what need to click also to the user it's completely transparent
and in the long range it produces this is
OK so that may come to the final
party on structured classification
which i also think is is
you know you can not exist or not to mention that the
we'll see
so what i'd like to talk about here than in the last
it's kind of
does that mean
i mean
he does not like the pressure
the problem
i'm talking about but i think it might help to get a second opinion on
the same subject
see it might help too
so i thought i'd like to talk about you know what i call structured classification
with some people call structured classification is actually the following setting and particularly interesting thing
of all the information retrieval is that you know traditionally we've been looking at problems
classification problems in regression problems for these two types of problem we used to working
at and classification really typically we're looking at binary classification and we're very courageous we'll
also maybe multiclass classification right but there already it's not so clear sometimes how we
would do multiclass classification whether we should combine binary classifiers or two proper multiclass approach
so what i'd like to look at here is the situation where the outputs that
and port
we can call them ready results into the index
for example we can
no that
force this force zero and four five
they was long
but they have a small number of intersection
in this case
we can create
c of the war
that is combination of zero and five and create in advance this
and during search we can use this
special auxiliary police
and it can increase the speed of search for such phrases in
thousands or even more than some the time
it's a lot of so there is some research in this area
the problem is how to
we nol that how do we know that we need to create this special auxiliary
force these
the simplest idea we can take the the longest
post lists
the most frequent
and create all axillary
intersection for them in advance
this is a good idea
the problem is
we can create a lot of these axillary texas
some of them can be not so short as we want
and it can increase size to follow in the again significant
another way
tried to fix
to predict
what can be frequent phrases
so what are phrases that
can cause very slow execution of all
follows search
what we can do so the idea is now looking to all documents and thinking
so this document contains these two version
produces this situation when research very very small we have a lot of documents we
zero and five
OK so
let's create this
axillary forcing police for them
we can get this information from our collection
we can take for example some subset of the whole collection and do this
collect this information
in advance and then created this still the war
and what's this for them during our index spewed phrase
or another approach we can build our index and then post process this index
it's again good idea pretty simple we you can implement it
you can be most more can things that OK
of course i can do this but for
is doing this query
maybe our auxiliary index is is not useful
maybe users are submitting another phrases and we need
to create in this for this special phrases
so we can take a very long
if you are looking for some search engine only you have access to query logs
you can
this hard queries from this query
and create this index in advance this forcing the postings in advance for this
part careers
and the jumping ahead
we can look into this approach has a look at this approach has static caching
so we
in advance process information
OK but
the problem is to here
even his all artillery units
time of our search
is always
linear from the type from the size of foul collection
and this is this is the main problem
if it getting more documents for example internet sites on the internet
it increases risks
exponential growth getting more and more documents every day
if they have a linear speed of our search
we are we cannot all be dubious this law is slower and slower
in in using all our
advantages and using all complex structure so we need some stories
that can reduce
speed of CRH
to some constant
or on the other hand what we can see that nobody actually needs this
thousands of millions of documents
the user will never read all these lists that we are produce
maybe the right idea is not to create full result
maybe we need to only one thousand most relevant documents and that's
so stop processing after we have enough
relevant results
you can check all popular search engines right now that are available on the internet
on the internet can see that they always
you can come to the last page you can see all
five hundred million documents in the result i can see only for thousand or even
so everybody's doing this one because we need
we need to do all search during constant time even if internet grows exponentially
OK so
we need some assumptions again
it's another question on the last lecture you your intuition how to calculate number of
results how many documents we have
even if we don't have
and if you're playing any search engine you very easily can see that this number
is very far from the real world
we need to do some assumptions
we need to things that we have some ranking function it's
it's good assumption we different have ranking function
the second assumption is not so good because it
it doesn't always work
but the idea is that
if you have to wait for four
we need to know is that it
it turns out the very powerful theory called stochastic approximation theory for applied mathematics is
actually talks about the convergence of algorithms
which have the following
even a deterministic algorithm converges to something
and have an equivalent circuit if you have a stochastic version of the algorithm that
essentially have mean zero noise and every step the deterministic algorithm
under certain conditions that i could find
the stochastic out converges to the same thing is deterministic algorithm with probability one and
q learning fits exactly in that
in that
in that stochastic approximation framework or the conditions the conditions of this
the step size
after some to infinity
and the solve square the step size has to be finite
i'm thinking how can that be
one instance of something like this is outside one over time step for example
so one of t
sums to infinity one rt squares some still find quite
what's the intuition behind these something out infinity simply means you never stop learning
the the step size
doesn't shrink to zero so fast
but you cannot recover
you can do that you can then you cannot recover
right so it it it converges to zero slowly enough
but you always have infinite time to learn
that's what this condition ensures
what this condition ensures is that the noise is being shrunk to the variance
is being shrunk
advances in keep going down and keep adding
so these two conditions together
and the very important conditions
that you have to ensure
as you choose actions
i can tell you how to choose actions i just told you given trajectory this
i update
we choose actions somehow
provided you choose actions in a way that every action gets taken in every state
infinitely often in the limit
you get convergence to the optimal value
number of people
made this connection i did some work with the mike jordan proving this charted simultaneously
john stickers
bringing in the notion of stochastic approximation theory to reinforcement learning and since then it's
been the how where we have used
to prove convergence for a lot of reinforcement learning algorithms
once he made this sort of connection between q learning stochastic approximation
OK yes
what you
so he goes well
the land
it is also
the very
it was
this this and this is what we need to ensure that the the way
exactly one
we have to see what happens with require
this what
or give some intuition is two
so so
this album was the first
direct adaptive optimal control algorithm
the first algorithm that solves optimal control problems
without building along
one of the key contribution of reinforcement learning even dropping the control and operation research
prior to this there was no such out available at all
so this is really
important and key in key contribution now
let make a couple of observations about the
the shift from learning state values state action values there was key in making this
possible and to do that let me unfortunately go back should put that slide here
is well i forgot
go to the bellman optimality equation way back he
this one
why do we move from
state by state action values
now i can make that point six
moving from state value state action values move the max
inside the summation
well the max
inside the expectation
which was key
what is property
that a random sample
it was unbiased
that is if we sample the next state look at a sample quality
its expectation is exactly the right hand side
while so if play different for those of you just meaningful
max is a non linear quantity summation easily acquired
so into changing the supporting the max inside the summation
allowed for a direct algorithm whether the max without side information you lose this quantity
that is if you just look at the
sample value of the square brackets because the max outside the expectation is not unbiased
well in this setting it is unbiased
so into changing
the max and the expectation
let to this critical
o thing that allowed us to develop large chris watkins
to develop a direct method for reinforcement learning where he stayed with the state value
that's method for
metal super position
and this method says that the output of the circuit
again focusing on linear circuits
so i had this remember had the ground where l applies
and within that playground and playing in the salt goal area
in the south pole area
in that subset of the playground circuits are linear
OK so in that part of the playground
so the position applies because there circuits are linear
so the output of a circuit is determined by
something of the responses to
it's source
acting alone
in the statement here
the source stands for independent source
haven't talked about independent sources dependent sources
talk about dependent sources a few weeks from today
just so you don't get confused four
dependent sources you will be looking at section three point three point three
of course notes
to see how supervision works with dependent sources
remember we haven't covered dependent sources yet it will be covering them of about two
weeks from two weeks from now
so let's go back to an example
and apply the method of
super position two examples
so the method says
some of
the outputs
applying one source acting alone
so let me do this here
let me start with the circuit
and let me start with shining by all
so i wanted to be
are two and i'm showing i
because of the places with an open circuit
so i is
so let me
we call the notable page
to reflect
that component of the node will change
that arises due to be acting alone
we should look at this pattern here and very quickly be able to write the
answer for patterns like the cell voltage the two resistors that's called a resistive divider
it will appear again and again and again
is simply
the times
two by one close to
that's that's the micron or
OK so
but what is here is simply the voltage
divided by the total resistance is given the current
multiplied by r two
given the words across the sahara
remember this pattern became applied voltage divider patterns
three more times than any other pattern that you might imagine
so that's the acting alone
now that we do
i acting alone
so far i acting alone
pointing out
and what to do this time around
the places for the sharks
replace the word sort the short
and we call this voltage
e i for the voltage that is the component of the world that due to
the current i
and we are in this case is simply given by yet another pattern here
the current across the pair of resistors is simply the effective resistance multiplied by the
so line
and effective resistances are one two
there are one less active
that's your life
that's the component at node to the current i
so that it says that's in the biggest components some them up and there you
have the answer
e is simply EV
because EI
the components of i acting alone
just simply the time
doctor quite close to
class one or two
never go
unfortunately the fates have been kind to us and answers the same as the answer
to the node
the surprise here
so this is actually incredibly simple method
so you can take a very complex
OK what is usually done here
you can think of a complex circuits
and you can solve it very complex circuits by breaking it down into many simple
individual subproblems
we do this in you years time and time and time again
OK but it in software systems hardware systems are what have
often times building complicated systems remember human decide
and the way you put assistance together that's a large software system is not right
the whole piece of software starting main and you going down
you belong to components and then by the components together
in the same manner here
take a big circuit
and if you find
its behaviour for each source acting alone
lots of little including simple circuit
in your use examples in your homework where you are given a big circuit
but because the set of the ice to zero and the other of eastern europe
the whole circuit almost vanishes and all that you have to do a little research
OK so this is very very powerful method
OK i like to do the latter
demonstration for you
and what i'm going to show you in the demo
is a that of water
i'll tell you what it is second but assume human saltwater for now
can apply
two homepages
in this case reply
it's a
very good
the sinusoidal
and the triangular roof
what we do
his measure
the response at the site
maximize we suspect
it is more possible that by doing so then
the right hand side the maximum can reach the minimum of the prime
so this is still to the peaceful nation that i just gave is called we
so we can do it says this is medium primary school historical amount of these
going we do a
so this probably an explanation but this has nothing to do we support vectors
because we're doing this problem deal with for optimisation people and this is this is
nothing to do support vector machines is just pure quadratic optimisation problem
and so
a o
and this from the point that point of view we don't worry about why we
with more about the meaning of support vectors but maybe you can see more from
the point of view i don't know
maybe you can come up with new
explanation of primal and dual using
from the support vector point machine point of view that would be very good
but i don't have a good is about that right now
OK so now this
to say OK this is the lagrangian do
so the next thing we will have to do is to simplify the problem
so how to simplify it is
but this is looks like the complicated optimisation problem maximize user minimize so that we
can do is to assume that point to
think about the situation where you fixed so to check if is fixed then
how to solve the minimisation problem inside these big processes
so this is sort of is fixed
is fixed
the immediate what we can see is
even some additional by y is not equal to zero and we can be we
can make this minimisation to go to minus infinity
well how to see that
so you can see you
i alpha i y
time to be well so you can
you can for the out so the becomes beethoven's some measure of my y i
so yes i mentioned by why y is nonzero
and are minimizing with respect to w and b so you just want be too
you look process or minus infinity depending on whether this is positive or negative well
if it is positive they just move b to plus infinity then
this minus the you you get minus in here
so listen this minimisation problem with respect to w b can be rewritten as is
so in situations so the first one is evil is why transports off
this image is actually wages whatsoever is not is not zero length
this minimum has a minus infinity but on the other hand if want impose optimisation
then we don't need to write this terms we
related to be
if you you have these some asian to be zero then you can remove this
term so we don't have
we don't have to be here we only have to minimize with respect to w
so we simplify do a little bit
i really think it was more complicated in you so not so this is the
problem we have so far
then that we took the second the situation where the white transfer is zero
there's no we are going to minimize with respect to w this function so that
so this policy right now
OK so now by fixed
so that is the only variable
it is situated the convex function that
so you know what the convex function is or street convex function is
when you this one is strictly convex because of this country to that transport stop
so from optimisation and we know that the optimum happens when the partial derivative with
respect to w easier
so we do this
so there
so we do
so for the
that has to stop that's actually that and then if only we should remove them
we have w
is equal to the linear combination of
training instances
so now we have these so that means give up his face
and what is most about is it
these optimized that must be
the linear combination of training data using these up
so we can further simplify our dual problem
so now we have a formal that in terms of the
so so we can we not represent that community in combination so you have
we want to remove remove that
the reason is we to simplify these so we know we hope that we don't
have this minimisation so we want to remove variables that could be in this formulation
so we put stop there too
this objective function
so we have to do something creation
so this checked that transports the first
so now is about these linear combinations transposed for these linear combinations will say this
is something you should i fail
x i transpose exchange with this is this is already very close to the project
in terms of our due problem
exactly k clusters if my stopping criteria is stop when the distance when all the
distance is now bigger than
the get rich miss
i mean i can rearrange the points to get any
clustering by just saying i stop when the distance the minimum distance left it up
and i get
consistency but is not scale invariant because this are is fixed so we find blow
up my that it will fracture into more clusters
if my
stopping criterion is some scaling things
stop when i get to the distance alpha times the distance
then it will be scale invariant because if i multiply by scale this will take
care of it
i'm going to lose their consistency so any pair of them is mutually satisfied all
reasonable but they can be
three satisfied simultaneously
talking about the clustering algorithm is supposed to look at examiner that and decide which
is the correct number of clusters and then cluster
into this number of clusters
right it may say well i it returns everything in a single class or every
point in singapore on that answers my question about this cluster structure
those requirements are pretty harsh as we saw
OK so where do we go from here so i think one of the big
mistakes in the community i don't know how many people were looking but people and
it is that people had this talk of climate NIPS was very widely
cited and people don't remember what exactly did as well but they
conclusion is there's no way to do it yourself clustering because there is this impossibility
and so on
let's forget about it there's no way to do here
well i'm trying to claim that is that is very it's very nice results but
it has limited application which says that this choice of three axioms was misfortunate of
fortunate in the sense that it led to a contradiction
but it doesn't mean that you cannot do any theory so
what would be the next step what can we do
so what
i would like in an ideal theory is to have
two types of requirements one type of axioms and axiom should be a requirement that
any clustering method satisfies the so
in particular the clan
axioms are not because each of them we know is falsified by many good clustering
we went whenever he saw an example
that's too
properties are satisfied by some clustering algorithms
inconsistency we know that this clustering algorithm fail
the third requirement
so each of those requirements is found by some natural clustering algorithm so if i
gave you the axioms of geometry
and then i will tell you all these axioms of geometry but some lines and
points satisfies axioms but some other lines and points don't satisfy the accent so you
want to call them axioms
y actions you want to do that by nature he wanted to be something that
says but by all the objects trying to describe i can give you axioms of
group theory and tell you OK these are the absence of group theory but some
groups satisfy them and some groups don't
that is contradictory to the nature accent so
when i want access one something that any clustering method was satisfies and we know
that i'm inclined to themselves us that his actions are not
like that because each of them is failed by
the same clustering as sets for the other two
and the other requirement is even more difficult to follow
well i want to any function that is clearly not a clustering will fail to
satisfy this one of the axioms because i could be relaxed i can tell you
maxims is that there what you should satisfy
is there a requirement that one plus one equals two
so now any function you give me which satisfy the axioms and we all have
but it doesn't distinguish good functions from that functions
so we want to
mutually satisfied the requirements set of axioms and it may be difficult to two two-way
formerly because what do i mean by clustering that is obviously not
a clustering function so it's not going to be an easy task
on top of it
i would call the kind of axioms that climate is called properties rather than access
so i have properties
which hopefully will distinguish between different clustering paradigms so i can say here is the
clustering paradigms that is scale invariant he was clustering paradigm
that is rich in the clustering paradigm that satisfy the property so now we have
a user that wants to apply
clustering trees that could look at the list of properties and choose which properties i
you want me you
one of the
so you get the picture in the
is this
very low
i think
you know
one one
while the
you not
in nineteen ninety eight
and then you can give them to some other technique
which may be slower but better
and i can tell you which was you really want
but at least you can get it down from a billion documents two hundred thousand
in a few machine instructions
but i should emphasise only if you're using documents indices
two indexing on the document that makes much more sense if using images
so people at MIT have tried this images and it works pretty well
these a nice work much better than things like locality sensitive hashing which was the
first thing before this
unfortunately the people at MIT very smart and they found another method that uses this
idea of going to address space but works even better than using the networks and
we in our work better to compete with that
so the people of a wise from fergusson antonio torralba
and they got a paper i think in the last minutes about this other method
some spectral method for getting these codes and spectral methods used work even better than
our method
we're gonna make it we can figure out how to do better
the shortlist found this way we've only tried it for twenty bit codes one million
documents and for many documents
and it works very well
OK now i'm going to something else
what i want to know is about what kind of generative models we really want
so you know
talked about learning generative models
and we have assumed that the generative model is the sigmoid belief nett
after we learn many layers
and the way to the top is an infinite sigmoid belief nett otherwise known as
restricted boltzmann machine
but you know do we really want that kind of model may i mean obviously
want to be able to other types of variables
but maybe there's something else we want to try and convince you the something else
we really do want generative model
the makes the gentleman more complicated but it's very useful
so let's suppose that you want to generative model i a square and i tell
you as part this and you can reduce the square in that
and the generative model has several layers and is one layer consists of things like
edges and corners
so i need to get from the level of description this this the square and
how big and what orientation one
to level of description tells me were all the pieces
well one thing i could do it is
i have very accurate
top down information
the given this computes exactly where all the different pieces should be
but it needs to be really accurate
otherwise i'll get square with the corners quite join up
i could generate some redundant stuff like this where this is meant to be a
distribution over whether samples from a distribution that web about whether editors this is samples
from distribution backwards
but i could also known
these things have to join up
you know the edge has to end article
so now given these distributions
i can do some cleanup
and get i tracker square like this
and i'm going to argue this is a much better way to do business
most the rest of the show is going to be about trying to show is
the best way to do business
my analogy is if i'm an office and i want to hold bunches soldiers to
stand in an ice rectangle
i could get my GPS i could tell each soldier what GPS coordinates able to
stand up up and the stand
unless i'm really really accurate
it's going to be a pretty ragged rectangle
it will be erected rectangle just in the right place exactly the right place brother
alternatively if i'm more worried about it being nice rectangle and being exactly the right
place i can tell the soldiers sort of stand roughly here
and i can tell them all to do this kind of business and that far
away from the neighbour
so i set up a markov random field between soldiers
and i get a nice rectangle
i don't think the soldiers know their markov random field but that's what they're
so we can try and do the same with a generative models
the first thing to try and do is get the
the hidden units
two just affect the is visible units with the talk on connections but also have
lateral interactions
and then the next thing you do which is more exciting is to get the
hidden units to directly affect the latter interactions
so we need to specify the markov random field as opposed to just and is
unbiased is a markov random field
it's still pretty easy to train this thing not quite as easy as the standard
restricted boltzmann machines
what we're going to do is we're going to
take the visible units
this was all logistic units activity in unit
we can get some binary state here
it's important to have noise you see contrast real values
and then holding the binary state fixed
it's going to right top down input
to these visible units as this MRF settlers who settled
a bit
i will use mean field down here is there are
and we get a reconstruction
and then migrated news again
this is non trivial
if you want to use stochastic units because you don't get the nice
division and you can be all these and update all of those it's everybody's talking
to everybody here you have to really up to one using the next generation song
on or you can use mean field which is after all a little bit in
so that's what we do
then the learning signal for these bottom-up connections is just the same as it was
before the learning signal for these connections is just the difference in the correlation here
and here
and that will tell us how to update these lateral interactions
that's what you ought to do if you do the something properly this is what
we actually do because it's quicker and you have to download it it to prevent
so you say
as your settling down the new value the new real value between zero and one
is lands until value plus one minus lambda times what the new value ought to
be given the input comes from the neighbours and from above
so simon osindero tried this on patches of natural images
he was using twenty by twenty patches
he was using garrison units to model the pixel intensities
except that this data is already being wind
so because the data already been morning and we didn't need pairwise interactions here
it's already whitened data
so there's no sort of power structure
so the way you learn it is you learn it with no lateral interactions among
the hiddens
because the semi restricted boltzmann machines
particular for maximal scheme
i don't know if you've ever worked together
a lot of people coming two six of schema was converted to make it already
are all wonderful
except semantics
really what you want
a little semantics
one of the
all o
we are step we can expect to get from this
what happens in the region
some better than others to help do this already in XML schema and try to
generate some sort of our from
so one example that were was that all of the whole world
there's this field of semantic web services and a lot of these things look what
love is happening is people looking at the XML formats that people industry generate this
people in history who actually build schools
and this
we get some of his
we can predict some sort of versions and try to convince people that this is
so the biggest of which is great because it's really simple
the reason
which this
these are security a certain
on one
as of june
one to the destruction so it's pretty obvious one specified
there you go
reliable messaging and some form of security or something else
there's a lot of stuff
and semantic formal semantics of
for example
i suspect around the distribution mechanism it really is best to find a little tiny
bit of a logical
here is a very simple example
this is one of the
a series of
this is the all one one
they were
and this is what you want to
sounds good
presentation of policy of
twenty eight
here is where you have to get some joy it's not just
he is
the disjunction of these
we can do actually seems like a sensible way to go
there is in fact contrary to my understanding to a hundred times two we can
the first
has names for things
significant gains in the area of peru you know you
thing here
we're going to
all right
something instantiation relations between policy these processes
and if fact managed to
get him to dig up
his initial sketch before
o seventy four
can see
this is not the only that it's reasonable for what he was trying to do
i guess so we have the notion of an operator for search we have these
three contracts with all
operators and then within the operator for
all in exactly one
one of the
really really do
it doesn't
he manages to get any sort of syntax checking or or or guidance anything
so far
i have constraints we managed to the children
it's not actually constrained instances of that shape that
very hard
this is very
converting x models
there's a better way
one of these
so these are the same things that use this template
reliable the
all these
this is one of any security and uses some form
correction or other times
the structure we can take this and instead including the syntax of the schema we
can map the language over