periodic functions
so one way of generating periodic functions is to
start from the axes but then map the axes
the space corresponding to
because going to sin x and cos sin x
so if you look at the first look at x and the new map it
into this two-dimensional space
and say OK it should be a smooth function
of the latent
variable u
so not just place a galson process in the u space
then you can work out what is the covariance now as a function of the
values of x y you get this expression here
where it has
in principle has two parameters product that tells you how fast is the period
which is set to one here the period is one of the sky could multiply
this by thing and then it has this smoothness
the squared exponential kernel that lives in the conventional that in the new space
missus l here
so here are again three different functions that are sampled from
so the samples of
of periodic smooth functions
but we don't say anything about the shape of the function
so here one where the
where the length scale
quite long compared to the period
that means
if the function can actually do very much within the period
because it's constrained to come back
to be periodic
here's here are functions drawn from a distribution where the length scale problem has been
the function is free to do stuff
inside period to get these are interesting looking function
which are guaranteed people to to be periodic
so here's here's an example
sort of a little bit artificial example because you probably wouldn't do inference in this
dataset in this way
i think it illustrates quite nicely the way
that you can use
different properties of the covariance functions to actually model
real data and and in this notion that you can look at our promises and
i'll tell you something about
what's going on so this is the observations of carbon dioxide concentrations monthly measurements four
fifty some odd years
and you can sort see that this is that this upward trend
one thing that might be interested in is what had what's going to happen in
the future
so i'm going to treat this
just as the regression task
just the one dimensional regression problem i want to predict what is why
as a function of x
probably if i want to do this in practice
i would also want to know something about
you know what happened to the world population in the same time and what happened
to his economic factors think that's the sort of the city where the
how do actually do this
well i don't know very much about atmospheric physics here but i can sort of
look at the data and i can say well
there seems to be at least the sort of this sort of this trend
going on here i situation should have some way of modelling that kind of thing
that's what would be a good
the idea of modelling this sort of
small trend
well maybe one of these square exponential terms
so i put that in my comments function
OK so i have one term here which is just on the long-term smooth trend
and but actually i'm not particularly keen on saying exactly what the length scale of
because i simply don't know so i leave that up to free parameters so that
i eta two here
and also i don't really want to specify what the magnitude of that we're trying
to that given by theta one
also want to look a little bit more carefully i see well
there seems to be some some seasonal variation going here
so i went along direction
there is some seasonal variation going on
this has to do with the fact that
the biomass
take up you two from the atmosphere predominantly
in the summer
and there's more landmass and on the
northern hemisphere so
the net
uptake of of CO two from the atmosphere in the summer and that released in
the winter
know that what gives rise to this fluctuation
but actually we look at this thing
i'm not so sure whether this is
well this is
adding gamma nor
the first five
together nor
or not
so what we generation
five one five two
o five three these are all the formulae i'm going to start
x nor is gamma
so explore is equal to whatever where gamma was that i was given and now
i'm going to construct x one
however i can only say
if x nought
that's gamma
o five one
so we're going to assign phi one
two x nor if
x locally deduces
so if you pick that guy and you check with the phi one is reducible
locally deducible from x and if it is you add it
so you just made your x not bigger
if it isn't negation
now you just repeat
you take five two
and you say whatever the answer was here
c where the fighter is deducible from that locally if it is then at its
negation and you just go through every one of those
it's an infinite process but
constructive here
then you take
the union of all of these xn one x two x three and every time
i adding on the formula or its negation
and at the end i take
every stage is deterministic what i mean by that i mean that all that stuff
OK why because i fyz deducible local
this is the classical notion so
if i or you let its negation
of course not effective
there's no way this in general
but that's fine
we're doing an infinite construction
now i not have
for a particular formula five why can't i edit
like and is
because if i did then some mixing with being
and then i be able to trace it all the way back to find where
became inconsistent that's the whole point i'm avoiding inconsistencies
so either your gamma not was inconsistent which is not a consistent gamma
or your step somewhere went wrong but the step is designed not to go
all right
one more
one k
because it depends on the choice
you give me a different mission
and i might get a different set
so in fact
depending on how you enumerate your formulae
i just wanted to show there is one i think of the money
they basically because what local did you
what local deducibility properties
that is a finite subset
and it gives you an actual
if i can use local deducibility
a finite set
can get into trouble because i have to start wearing only
and also there is the property of this local deducibility relation which aren't
precisely this
if i one and i don't like in
they actually you can go to this
OK so basically just doesn't work
if you use the form of deduction that i've given you you can't do
a maximal consistent set construction with the tation
you this deduction is not equal to local deduction not OK
because it's saying you're not allowed to use necessitation lasted right it's one of the
things that i say
you in order to do that the construction you have to go to this
there was another question somewhere
you have question
because the other way
the exercise somewhere here right
if it's locally deducible then it's deducible
but it's
exactly it's it's the deduction do that one half of the deduction theorem doesn't go
it's exactly that point
thank you you
that side to that side
so that's fine
got we've got a chain of consistent sets x not which is a subset of
x one which is a centre
max melody
well at every where whatever five choose with this phase in
or not right will sooner or later external come be put in or its negation
put so you have an externality
that ytxt are itself is consistent in other words when you take this union
you don't read
how do you prove that you say well suppose for a contradiction that inside that
somehow got in their right
then you know one of them
calculate the work that you have to do to bring all these charges in place
if it is easy you can take the electric field everywhere in space if you
know that and do an integration
over all space
we could do that for instance for
these two parallel plates now
and we can ask what is now the total
energy in these plates
in the field and at home i would advise you
do that the way that it's done in your book
whereby you actually assembled the charges minus q at the bottom and prosecute top
and you calculate how much work you have to do that's one approach i will
now to the other approach
and that is by simply saying
that the
in the field of these plane parallel plates
is the integral
of one have actually non-zero e
over the entire volume
of these two plates
and since the electric field is outside zero everywhere
it's very easy in the world
because i know the volume the volume that i have separation is h
so we still have a part of this volume that i have is simply a
times age and the electric field is constant
and so
i get here
this is one half
absolutely zero
for in
i want to i can write
sigma divided by actually non-zero
i can square that
it's doing integral over all space
i mean simply i get a times age is the volume of the box
so i get a
so this is not the total energy
that i have i was one
actually you have an absolutely zero gravity after long
i also remember that the charge q
on the plate
is a time sigma
and that the potential difference the
this now is not volume is the potential difference between the plates
is the electric field
times age
the electric field is constant to go from one place to the other interval don't
pl going from one place to be out of this we potential difference
so i can substitute that now in here
i can
take for a sigma
i can put in the q
you can also show
this is one half
the being out of potential difference between the plates
and so this is a rather fast way
but you can calculate
what the
the total energy is
in the field or
say the same thing the total work you have to do
was family
these charges or to say differently the total work you have to do to create
electric fields you have created they created electric fields that were not there
i know will introduce
something that we haven't had before
that's the word
i will defined
the capacitance of an object
to be
the charge of that object
divided by
the potential
of that object
and so the unit is
cool urls
before this useful knowledge potential
but we never say that school all of evolved physics we write for that the
capital at
which is far out
we call that one ferrari is the unit
of capacitance undoubtedly after the great maestro faraday
we'll learn more about fire they
later in this course so us
go to
a sphere which has a radius are
and that is calculate what the capacitance is obvious
think of it as being a conductor
and we bring this charge q on the conductor it will then get potential v
which we know is q
divided by four pi
actually non-zero are
we've seen it many times
and so
by definition
the capacitance now is q
divided by the potential
and therefore
this becomes
here are
that is the capacitance of a single
so we can now look at the
as a function of are
i have here some numbers
calculated for defender graph
i calculated forty earth
if you want one far-out capacitance
that's the real big unit radius of nine times ten to nine metres it's the
four pi actually non-zero comes in there
that's used that twenty five times the distance from the earth to the moon big
whatever patterns of one farad
itself with a radius of sixty four hundred kilometres
seven hundred for
invented around thirty centimetres radius would be for typical for picos ten to the minus
and if you take a sphere with a radius of one centimeter
then you have
roughly one bickel for ten to the minus
so far so this gives you a rough idea here
about the size of objects
and how they connect to their capacitance
so if i bring all these spheres
at the same potential
as we call them now
let's do
something first
i now
excluded mutation from this algorithm by setting its probability to zero
can somebody
predict what what is going to happen
and have to be able to find the solution
depends on the
initial population
you see
here we are
this is what happens
no mutations
no way
to get the solution
in the entire population
there's no
see it in a certain color
mutation is not just something to
perform random search component with this algorithms it is also very important because it can
or reintroduce
i needed
the genes are needed components into our population if they were not present at all
or if they were lost during the search procedure so it is very important
so of course this could run forever to stop it
and now
how about
increasing the mutation very much
let's say one point zero
what does it mean
if i said the probability of mutation to one
this means our algorithm actually turned to
random search right because this mechanism will be so strong that the only solution to
actually be generated randomly
in this case we can forget about crossover about the selection it has no role
because we actually generate every solution randomly so
you see everything grey area
the programme works now
this test the efficiency of random search on this problem
by the way what is the number of possible solutions
yes right ten to the power of ten because it's
ten digits and ten
values at each position
and again
i hope this
simple them all
convinced you of the efficiency of the evolutionary search
we had let's say
something about
one thousand or even less
solutions checked on average
so this is really a small proportion of the entire state space
it's ten to the power of ten
the number of solutions
OK this one really is this one is not too successful but we can see
the best solution found so far was with eight correct digits
and then we are quite lucky but
do not enough
not enough to
the optimum solution that's the number that is generated in the background
still with genetic algorithms from toy from
then all problems to more realistic problems
it's that here
so this is just for an illustration we saw
five problems saw of demonstration of the efficiency of these algorithms this is a short
illustration of the practical industrial problem where genetic algorithms was used it is actually from
one of the projects done by this institute in one of the steel plants here
in slovenia called the chronic still plant
i do a short but just to explain the essence of the problem and the
way the genetic algorithms was used
the problem is as follows means
work on the continuous casting of steel
which is the process of producing steel that is then used for
producing any kinds of for project products so
what happens here is that liquid still that comes from the furnace actually and a
certain device which is called continuous caster
and this device or this machine actually
cools down
the steel
and it's just is solidified and these
he the so-called cutting point where the is cut
maximum likelihood is consistent
as we increase these data points the parameters become better determined by the way you
demonstrate maximum likelihood is consistent is by looking at kehl divergences between the true distribution
you don't know
and you approximating distribution you assume you approximating distribution is in the class
the true distribution
and you show that you can get a sample based approximations about cayley budgets which is the likelihood
that's sample-based approximation gains infinite data points
u will recover
the cat true cayley evidence minimization
that's not true here because the sampling is being done across data features
so this is consistent has you get in the data features for a fixed number of data points
in this case when a man comes into office saying i can give you one
hundred extra data points about the case you are interested in you know about will
make my parameters less well determined
don't give me any more data points that's the converse so the guy who came
in saying here's a hundred extra data features
so the blessing and dimensionality
which is exactly the consequence analyzing model independent across features shows u u want many
many more data features and you don't want any more data points
so it's exactly the opposite lesson
from the normal
of-course it's all a little bit of a joke because it's just about your model
definition it's nothing to do with your data
so i think a lot of those ideas about large piece more than being a
problem should be put to bed because the consequences are all tied for statistical analysis
and it becomes really clear for these models
if you're in philosophy small and you should use a model like this
this model will be very well determined speaker is large and it's interesting that all
the dimensionality reduction algorithms i've just been presenting are effectively trying to approximate or doing
something like that so they are well determined as the number of data features goes
up in fact that's withdrawal example is a nasty example because this peace three
and is three thousand
and if you do locally linear embeddings on it if you've ever applied at you
have to induce a regularizer if your neighborhood graph goes above the data dimensionality
you have to regularize it in this domain where pierce three and is thousand that's
freaky why is that's there your answer
it's the wrong domain
it's not what you should be looking you should be looking at swiss roll and fifty thousand dimensions
nine three
because it's hard to plot
fifty thousand dimensions in the science paper but
that's why they do it
so as we increase data points parameters become better determined normally behave as we increase data features the parameters
become better determined this is completely turning a large piece smaland problem on its head
i mean this
you know so it's a blessing and dimensionality but actually what is really saying is
that there is not a characteristic of your data
and it is very characteristic your model how you're using the model
don't fit models which will lead to badly determine parameters
so that's the difference between the two
types and modeling
customer interactive blessing of dimensionality cancer which voting
and this becomes really clear if you work with things like microarray data which is
not always clear which is which is then
because sometimes you are interested in different data points being genes
sometimes you
but sometimes using those as being the data features
things are you interested in you know and experiments on the features of the genes
so you can try is just a matter of transposing these matrices and fitting the
other way around a cause it doesn't need some practical consequences in this
model it's very easy to include all predict for a new data point test data point very easy yeah
because it's just independent
and you've got the parameters
in this model it's not easy to predict for a new data point
because you need to compute
pretty simple recursion
and you you you can have some kind of a different approach
if you are the original you can say
well let's look at the binary expansion of the sequence
one is this
two is binary
four hundred
seven is and read
and if you
count the number of ones in there
you have
and all number of one of these
you can say well let's carry on let's
keep looking at
bigger and bigger binary numbers and just keep the ones that have an odd number
of one
this gives you one two four seven eight
eleven thirteen
it's said that just
as simple
or well you can be
even more
torture and look at high in its early years i removed the three rites three
one four one five nine that would be five
and two seven one eight that's would be
and and they say well OK one two four seven so the next one is
why not
and what you
well i'm observing one two four seven but i think later on it will keep
at seven and this is my explanation for it
basically you see that you can come up with as many possible expansion of that
sequence as you wish
it you know a matter of
which one do you consider the simplest is there is no notion of simple thing
like happened because some people would argue that the binary expansion is natural i computers
would argue that
reasonable people might argue that this one is
i mean it's really up to you
well some of the example in the same thing if you look at the sequence
i think well OK we said so many numbers there is only one way to
to continue the sequence right you can be sure that
these are all prime to the next one is the prior
well again if look into this semantic encyclopedia you can see two answers one is
the next prime
in one is
another is the order of the next simple rules
probably don't know what it what is simple or maybe you know
but the are my point is
you know
it's a matter of what you're most familiar with you know people are familiar with
prime so maybe we can say OK natural continuation of the sequences sixty one
but again
there is no we cannot prove it i cannot say for sure
this sequence will continue with sixty one there is no other way
another example which gives a little twist on that the
the following
so we observed a sequence of numbers
if it's i mean you
looks random just
but you know if you don't know
the specific number that is very popular like if i have given you another less
popular number
you would have said OK that seems to not have been a factor
so in and if you look at the frequencies that if you
count how many times each individual member
and you can
i assume that the probability of the next
being i is proportional to many times jobs you have observed is i've divided by
digits observed
this probably you can see that it will converge to
one then is
because what this is
kind of random in the sense that every number can occur
with the same probability
but as you say you noticed
in this really looks like the expansion by
so why do we prefer this
and for the last answer
well because we
obviously not is that there is a structure
even though it's not you know you can formalise by
some kind of recursion like CU and is equal to the u n minus one
was something
but still
we managed to not is that this is
something that their structure and actually there is
the reason that the reason that would produce the sequence and continue it so which
would so these salaries you can think of it as a model for that sequence
it's it corresponds to these observations and gives you
and expansion
OK now let's rock
is there
in general principle for
providing a good answer to these these results write these questions of nineteen twenty well
i mean there is one approach that seems to be
satisfactory which is called these occam's razor
try to find an explanation which is consistent with what you observe and which is
patterns it has two
proceed farther
for shortlisted to just one
for the algorithm has the second step which is the selection
whatever you need to look what do you do
consider this register
it can be now considered selection step so in in the first step was that
i have part
no we have all the other musical knowledge that can be used in the second
step to list in order of preference the different cases in that case for example
one of the of the patterns is goes up is an update action selection is
that and the other one is down
one of the criteria is the
that direction
the system select preacher
the same night action because the input from those that
after this election
on the bottom
what surprised me was selected because it has the same direction i think problem you
could have used also automatically strength or the traditional formulation actually
in in for this particular case in in all these three situation direction durational cumulation
and medical strains in much especially so that gives you even more stronger and stronger
confidence that this is a very good
this is very good precedent to solve problem
the one on the right is a better compression to solve the problem what you
have that well you have to
most of the most difficult part actually has been done
this is inferring press n
what you have to do now is to use the solution
that means imitate imitate what has been done in the in the in the present
so the precedent cases there is a side that is out that this is the
dynamics with graphical interpretation for to make it easier
and the the onset the onset and duration of the note is what is about
and articulations of the this the the second of nodes are quite all but the
reason is that between the first and the second terminal this is what i try
to i try to represent graphically with this with this with this a few words
here so since all this information is that so we have we know
how this node has been play along this five expressive dimensions what we do is
to transfer it and we copy that we need that work with some of the
patient obviously
because maybe
the average dynamics the average reward to the average articulation is the precedent case
it is different
then the dynamic articulation of the of the of the problem
the SMS gives us also composites averages so this has to be a scale it
is factorized right
but what is important is that there is this going these these even when the
in the dynamics
the first of these is the onset is is dissipated the second one is delayed
what it means this graphically
and of the not is
nothing has been changed the
all these things are then imitated and this is what the system decides to do
it could be that after the selection the research in this election there are still
more than one precedent that would be applicable
it's not the end of the of the story that it could be still do
this unless we we have left more than one possible president we need a good
if this is that it is the case well we system provides the possibilities of
making the final decision and to come up with just one
one precedent to imitate
majority minority continuity diversity in we provided by default majority
and in case there is no majority because maybe there are two and both are
the provide different things once a siding normal dynamics
and there are only two this time so then we you wish is randomly as
as as a last resort
so let's see now some example of of the system how it would work actually
and as a set
we will listen festival
almost in expressive phrase
and then we sit around the ring
a different one is label joyful
all the other labels such
i label them these
because if you notice here that disaffected values right
so so that they can save the beginning is that the user can that can
say well i'd like to have a joyful interpretation of this input right well this
is relatively easy we have the memory of cases is categorized into in different clusters
and all
these interpretations are performances that are
joyful together and cluster one you one cluster in the centre of the cluster the
melancholic and another cluster so when you say that you want a joyful into joyful
performance of user although we only look for former presidents in the in the joyful
cluster consists of source as simple as that
but let's let's let's listen
paid attention the long that is a lot of difference after
is not completely in this present because in terms of dynamics is the most difficult
expressive dimension to control freeman performance he could not avoid
doing some little crescendos and things like that but for the rest
in terms of timing in terms of onsets
if you were you know if you are measuring
you not is that the nodes start something where when when they should not not
not not before nineteen ninety after
so far the rest was pretty good and
w but they were not there were no be proud to call especially in the
long notes where terrace ex-player feels more
round of
division that looked very much like mitosis where these x structures would be split into
two pieces
the notion then their parents would go to singletons and then upon fertilization singletons would
come together to reconstitute a pair
really didn't fit mendel
and thus was born the chromosomal theory of inheritance
the chromosomal theory of inheritance
are you overwhelmed by the chromosome theory of inheritance of a given you overwhelming evidence
to believe that
now i
seems naturally now but i mean the only evidence is that there's something else that's
got pairs in cells right what's what's to say that the some other thing that
appears open cells actually is the carrier of genes
the chromosome theory of inheritance is that mentals abstract factors genes live on these chromosomes
are these chromosomes or something like that carried by these chromosomes and simply the fact
that the choreography the chromosomes
it is not the same as is the same as the choreography of men those
genes that correlation infected ex post facto correlation and many prediction that these chromosomes are
doing just sort chromosomes did it and i said OK you know that that could
medals observations about genes and there's a world of difference between that could explain
that is consistent with
the data and
that presents a compelling case that this is true
so there are some people immediately bought into the idea
of the chromosomal theory of inheritance and there are other people who remain great skeptics
about this that these chromosomes were
themselves quite irrelevant to inheritance and indeed many people who at this point the early
twentieth century felt that the whole business of genes was still not such an overwhelming
idea anyway and trying to unite these two was going a bit far out so
now i have to bring you back to some of the things that that we
left unresolved last time
which is mental second law of inheritance because if we're really going to start
building a case that chromosomes really do carry genes then we better get some serious
consistency with much more complex aspects of the theory or we better look for some
contradictions so
your call and i mentioned that
mendel studied
seven different rates two of them around this and green this
both dominant phenotypes underlaying by these hypothetical genes
big are big are big big g
and the recessive traits associated
with the same genes wrinkled in yellow
there are little are
a little too little g
when you make a first-generation cross
what do you get
you get around in greenfield typically engine typically what are they
big are little are
big g little g
that would be the genotype these organisms would be
that they be double-header i be heterozygous for the gene that controls shape and heterozygous
for the gene to be heterozygous for the gene that controls seed color
now suppose we do across back
so are are gg
the parents that is has the recessive phenotype for both of these traits were practising
our words here
what will this parent the second parent
contribute in its garments
well again it's from apparently
little are little g they have to be little are little g
because that's all it's got off
so little are little g
well this pairing contribute
i could give big big g
could give a little are little g
could given principle way
are big g or a
big are little g
in theory any of those are possible
what's the ratio that mendel reports
one to one to one to want equal that's one to one to one one
that's the
independent assortment
of traits
that's what he calls this independent assortment of traits
that is to say the inheritance around the inheritance of green are uncorrelated to each
other right knowing which when you've got around this which when you got green is
they don't convey any information about each other
so how can we explain this in terms of personal theory of inheritance well
we could explain this in terms of the chromosomal theory of inheritance by saying for
example that
in this heterozygous parents here
big are
and little are carried on
how we can solve this problem
and we are going to use the same
can treat
and it would be quite easy you is the formulation without the
six i answer formulation just with the
without noise so without the idea of
soft tumour technology
of soft margin so it
and here
you see i just replace
and the formulation when i see this kind of put between x i and x
j just replaced it
by sick and then
the value
of the can then k
taken at x i and x two
in fact
we had we as we we are going to solve this problem of optimally imagine
that plane not
is the original input space but
injured in the feature space
define the some reason camaguey
so of course we have
the formulation for instance of w
in the feature space
and formulation of w will be in terms of the implicit function phi
but never mind you remember that the function or functions solution as the lines from
inside you
again you use enough for that
to compute the
the answer of classifiers
so again maybe here
it's even more care remember i tell you that k
can it can be seen as specific similarity we have a very nice property of
being a semidefinite because it
in order to classify acts
x you ask to some extent data sources of data
in fact
as you know you are going to see it
these data are not
in our very placed near
just the parish and we're going to make the link with this is the first
program and the number one but again you are going to try this is supported
that you have to combine their advice
so look again here
is the prediction is representation the input space
offshore nonlinear
decision function
you've you've found SVM
this is a
the decision function frontier
is this red line is
green line so i'm not sure you
see run here
for instance here
and it's you
in fact it is green
the decision function
corresponds to some hyperplane
in into feature space
OK and
what feature space i use here
i used in fact cautioned him and so in fact i am usually
an infinite dimension
feature space
and i'm doing as i was working
in this case
in fact i working space but only using this kind of put
so the magic the magic of comments
is the fact that
he's very complex
the non-linear decision frontier
is a linear
decision function in the future
the second point in the city to decision which is important is that the place
of the support vectors
you can see this about the picture
this idea is wrong
runs across
was a brief
so we're going to talk today about
binary search trees
something called randomly built binary search tree
don't really a binary search trees is BS through the lecture and you all
scene binary search trees in one place to another in particular recitation on friday
so we're going to build up
the basic ideas
presented there
and this
talk about how to randomize them and make them good
so you know
but there are
good binary search trees
which are relatively balanced
something like this
behind is log and we call them balanced
and that's
anything order log will be fine
in terms of searching for then cost or log n
and there are bad binary search trees which have really
large high possibly
because and
so this is good
this is bad we sort of like to know we'd like to build binary searches
in such a way that they're good all the time or these most of the
there are lots of ways to do this and the next couple of weeks we
four of them if you count the problem set believe
today we're going to
can use randomisation to make them balanced most of the time in a certain sense
and then in your problem so you make that in a broader sense
one way to do this topic so define randomly built binary search for
one way to motivate the topic is through sort our good friend
so there's a natural way to sort
and the numbers using binary search trees
give you an array a how would you sort
that array
using binary search tree operations the black box
build the binary search tree and then to a or exactly
we have some initial training
which is empty
and then for each element of the array
inserted into the tree
i that by building the search
so we insert a i'm going to treat this is the binary search tree insertion
standard sessions
and then we do an inorder traversal
she in the book is called an ordered tree walk
you should know what is out of the car
but just for very quick reminder
three insert walk is basically searches for that element AI until it finds the place
where it should have been if it was in the tree already
and then it as a new leaf there
to insert that value tree walk
recursively walks the left subtree then prince out the roots and then recursively walks the
right subtree and by the binary search tree property that will present the elements out
in sorted order
so let's do a quick example
because this turns out to be related to another sorting algorithm we've seen already
so while the example
pretty trivial
the connection is pretty surprising based
it was to me for some this class
so my array
three one eight
two six seven
and i'm going to visit these elements in order from left to right and build
the tree
the first cell i see is three
so i
in insert three into an empty tree that requires no comparisons
when i insert one
two just naively work with the best one and that actually if you think about
it for well that's actually a special case of overfitting
so what this algorithm is doing is trying to
trying to keep the intuition of going with the functions that have done better
in the past but it's not going to just go with the best function it's
going to kind smoothly
move towards the best function without putting all of its weight on the best functions
so how do we analyse the
the number of areas of this simple algorithm
but every time this algorithm makes a mistake every time this weighted majority prime algorithm
makes a mistake
so we had a majority of the functions
we're on the majority of the weight was wrong
more than half of our way was wrong it will be have to be cut
in half
so we will decrease are total weight by these twenty five percent
so the final total weight
at the end of the day is if we've made a a certain number of
then are weights which started as if they were functions went down by three quarters
each time
are we will be no more than five times three quarters to this number might
be much less depending on how many people mistake made mistake each time
on the other hand
on the positive side a total we cannot be too small
in particular total weight is just the sum of the weights of each
of the
and they started one and they got cut in half the time they made mistake
and we know there's one function we hope there's one function that did well this
comparing ourselves to the one function in made the fewest number of mistakes so if
there's one function of there that whatever it is that makes the fewest mistakes
its weight is at most
this quantity to to the minus the number of mistakes made
and when you take these two terms and put them together
so it so this is bigger than this
what you get out when you take logarithms used a log here you have like
it comes down and a lot of three-quarters times mistakes
what you get you can work it out yourself and you can see here is
the number of mistakes will make is is not too much more than the number
of mistakes of the best function this is not agree guarantee
saying he making almost twice the number of mistakes of the function
this is the best guy i had an error rate of ten percent will have
an error rate of twenty four percent which is not very satisfying
but still you know interesting it in a simple algorithm
so what is the
right algorithm to use here what's nice
a better guarantee
you can modify this algorithm it it turns out that that that cutting the weights
in half with a little bit too steep and we should have just
not the way it's done by a little bit so
i think this is upset that we should have knocked on the weights by one
and this should be the square root of sum log f over n
some terms which is less than one and we want to
decrease the weights by that time and then you will get to guarantee
that the expected performance there's no no longer perspective to now you have effective one
plus a second term the number of mistakes is no more than the mistakes of
the best function
plus the second term and so
what you get is that actually
the regret which is the difference of how well how well we did on our
data compared to what we could have done
is this term here which is going to zero
quite quickly
in fact that's exactly the same term
we had for the case when
when the data wasn't coming online right
this is that one when we had to go back
so the
that's member this is what we got over here
so in this case what is what we got over here we have the same
same term here
up to constant factor here
and this constant is not constant in front of our progress is not if is
the best may ten percent were made making twenty percent this saying the best may
ten plus ten percent were making ten plus epsilon
or two epsilon mistakes so really it seems like
it's not clear that you really need to have this distribution assumption that you really
need to do is coming from distribution it might just be coming at you
from some
arbitrary order arbitrary data and still somehow
able to do the same this kind of very surprising things
that people in online algorithms in online learning have been noticed is that you get
pretty much the same kind of guarantees
when you're in in the online setting in the batch
and questions
let me tell you some other cool things you can do with this weighted majority
you might say well
what if the world is changing over time i mean you're making this nice assumption
that you are not assuming that the data is coming from some distribution the data
could be changing over time
but still
you only comparing itself to the best single function in hindsight
it is not a little unfair
would you want to do as well as the best
changing function
OK so
you might compare itself to the best
in fact in one nice thing you can do is you can compare you can
take a window of the sun with
OK to take a window w and that it has with
the length of w with w
then what you what you look at you can modify the algorithm so that you
get a very similar guarantee but you get this guarantee every window on every window
with w then almost as well as the best function in that cluster it on
that one
so now i really adapting to
changing things of course if you make that we know very small if you make
window one then you not just comparing yourself to the
best function on
every single example
and you can get very good guarantees
any questions
let me just explain a little more so when you compare itself to the best
when you when you said w call one comparing itself to the guy who got
everything right and
i have to do work on stock market for start with what people want to
know why can't i compare myself to the best stock every day why do i
in order to do this
i would need to
to have those recipes
somehow in an electronic form online
how should i do this
i don't quite have the time
two to do this but
the first model
she's retired so
she should by definition have a lot of time
the problem is she's not very interesting computers
she would need
something to
what i think is it
that you can understand time
so this is a recipe
four a
stop it is made of
you can rise
and the
we can agree
on the former here
it is understandable to her it understandable to me
for being the domain expert here
how to
that we
came to
to terms with four months
how to actually
implement the
because only have twenty minutes i i decided that i should go too
as you go away there
in until yourself
and i chose ruby
because it is a expression expressive language
these proposals
it is not particularly good
but as i said only have twenty minutes
i have several methods
which received
by the end
ingredients here
actually of type hash or met in some languages
i've seen i've noticed the similarity here
but should
i also have units likely to end
often those methods on
on numbers here
this one is a slightly different
to write a recipe
as you can see we don't
however that hash anymore
now we have a block of code
the block of code is executed
some time later
and his
methods that are
the time
actually ingredients
and all those methods don't even have to exist
we can just intersect
method missing for example
say that
if intercept that
then it is a ingredients
much of that
that's what they just said that is actually about programming
way too
to change the cold while run while the program is right
ruby is not the only expressive language
i'm sure that something similar could be done for
as i've seen those nice in example six operators
for example this is
examples from
using groovy is a
programming language which incidentally runs on the JVM
we are we have a cash again
this time is in there
and the syntax is even though it's say a
then the one in new
now that two
i decided on a four-month and how it will look like
it is time to choose how shall we implement that
there are several techniques
in ruby
it makes depend on language shows
first technique is
well pretty basic one
it can be
replicated so
i suppose any language
i just implement
methods on an object
and that's a project dot
recipe object
but it's not not really
nice one
i mean
it has this
o thing in front of it
that is
out of place if
the men expertise using not program
o making it best-selling ruby
is to use
study or class methods of base class
we've seen it before
and here they are
belongs to has many
those are
static methods of a class a to record
and if it's quite nicely here
another method is to
consistency theorem for locally weighted average classifiers actually baggage one nearest neighbour classifier
a weighted nearest neighbour classifiers and we can take away
of this far
we come about
actually i'm going to give thanks to god just storms this was the which is
is always join size is sufficient for while
OK wonder if be
we cannot accept
when she waits
what we have to prove consistency is just to verify the condition of the urine
conditions during the true
that the that one classifier because it it because you think
but then as you suggest
seven minutes ago
this is not original others brand
if you download the software of course there are many different ideas which are
but the software key idea
different important i the key had the way we get
so remember this was my original from observation mission church
so o
what would you like to show white
i could actually deviation from the
instead of choosing according to separate from the other
i do concentrate direction with
point i just got this
i can see
you could run like
of well of course they don't say anything about the way cut you can get
it right you can use some more
we could by
g argument so i mean square
what you can do it the direction where
the point along
the company of few observations
point itself or the intention to make an arbitrary decision
once you've got to get to the point of this
he said the call all of the set
this is
and of course
you see that this is very different from what it was before
because that the number of seventy of
completely arbitrary may change from one tree to another this is very different
this is the original
algorithm which have been proposed by the much
i want to go truck
one track is
of course you can also it for regression is exactly the same progression
in addition decide what just forty seven to
now the question is can we know that this is very interesting question because it's
not so simple at all
the way we have analysed the previous reason which is
some of the tree
it's completely different partition is not specific to this
number of these which can be specific for it's completely different geometry
the first question what are the important point going for what what
i understand that you want to do the role
i mean we feel that the channel around
one place in the world
what are the points which are important point
this one
so this is the most important for that reason
first of all for
now the question what is the geometrical properties for
interesting about it
you see that this one of parameters property
that that you draw rector between
see that of the
one have the same property
before we it to sixty
draw the for example
and of course much choose there's someone
so that means that the reason just defined some kind of similar to form
which has nothing to do with
was going
so far away
the can point clothes from this point
and the reason just concentrate on some interesting one charge
fred around the time point
here and so define some kind of cannon some kind of identity true identity
now the question is what want
and the fact that these points have been
so far
so what
been discovered by
true talent six and brown was really exciting to know
this point
that is called the
a layer nearest neighbour what's
so now the question is what can we say well this one
this year there
just some observations observations
you were point
the body
of course said that the number of responses
this is of course not one
one than
number one is not always the same
the first question is known about this one
it turned out that a lot is known about here
when the sample uniformly distributed over o one
lot is known for a period of one
so for example is known that the expected number of responses about again
you might want
it's just
accounts for quadrants around important
you have some right of consistency property of system
so if you're in the violence nonsense many results on the
actually just because this is connected with the problem of searching for
the effect of the non since
so that's used but it's not really
because this is true only for uniform distribution for uniform one
should think
this is kind of binary relation
now show observation which i say this is thing
results are the
company for the reporting this and that you can use any you kind
trio triple the case when see
the first thing we had to do was to understand
how disappointed when you
so this is a real number
what we have known
music march
so suppose we have an observation which are independent of according to the
improve what can we say about
we have proven these two results
which are essentially realizes proof decision geometry
definitely not a colony of
from the number of
because you can provide without assumptions
moreover should suppose that this is what we're that they have some kind of
the following one
and these results are just
the result over the the the results are simple we can use them to understand
the way first before
before we jump to run the first of course give i i
an interesting
which is
and then
regression testing it
one of get
can just take the average of all y
which are the nearest neighbor
in the sense of the scope of this true
e two
the a of
you may
all the time
on whole
o right
so we have a qualitative and quantitative one chinese we have is how to combine
the findings
OK i you combine the qualitative information quantum information
you may have a combination with the quantitative informations from a large sample
the qualitative from small sample so how to combine them
so we talk about interpretive consistency making sure
that the information that you combine with the from the quantitative and qualitative consistent
given your sample size is in this phase
and some of these when you look at the box when you look at these
issues i books
typically will associate that something quantitative of qualitative one things we like to do is
mixed methods research say when i mean
you could do any of these
you got you design
OK with this kind hard
so there's least twenty four
types of sampling schemes
again look for the will clark et al
not clear that will
have all these in
the the first five around them
which quite a while with the third of simple random sampling stratified easily
cluster sampling systematic
and then
others are
what's called purposes
none rand
so example maximum variation
is where you might choose people
such that there is wide possible there as diverse as possible BW
any kind of you know cointreau anything when sampling process use your own
you have many other types
there you see
and including politically sensitive sampling
this is an important
when and where you might choose someone because of their
you know
essentially there are
the expectation that they have information that you need
in a position of power for example
another important situation is
sample size
that's really important i see so many
study some especially dissertations
questions may have too small a sample size
to be able to
you know
i have
article power to detect difference or relationship with this one really there
so it's really important that when we do quantitative study
all makes mistakes as the qualitative component
that we pay attention to the issue of statistical power
there are some guidelines there
for example if the college's study
you need sixty four
participants for a one hypotheses and eighty two for two tailed and so forth
as there some the funds and then i one further recommend that have no affiliation
with it
it's called so you may have to keep our energy power
g p o w e r if you do a google
search engine to find that you could get a free download
and some once you have to pay for so that's why would i
i recommend keep out for those who don't spend money on it
and that is really nice put in the there was you need information you need
to spit out the
sample size that you need
if qualitative some quick and dirty
the numbers of people looked to over the years so for example if you doing
the case study christian recommend three to five and so forth
most studies now coming out
we actually look at sample size in qualitative research
and that's one came out in film methods couple of years ago
by guest all with a looked at
the so was about AIDS in africa
and really big sample size is one hundred
typical quality with a start code data
found that after twelve study after twelve
the data starting repeat themselves he had saturation
they found twelve
maybe a number
quite quite significant in qualitative research getting saturation
job place
as a question is asking
it could be in terms of your fatigue
you can you you start to you know especially if you don't want to take
it was the case you start start to
i get tired and so some of the other things we look for the
information you know as
you know you know fresh to look at that that's that's why because my mind
in that case if you found that you have
don't quite students have analyse all of them
so you might want to look and see if there were of equal quality that
you think that you might want to use all them if they're not
you could take you could take a selection of them
so yes so that would be my main answer to that you question
OK you have questions
OK so
way when quantitative or qualitative samples concise configuration is important
so if you see that this place
you get to get partial credit i would say no in that situation
so was designed looks like that initiation tito's grew up
but if you those unfortunately
OK when you have to remember again in in mixed methods you can have least
one quantitative phase one qualitative phase
so when you combine together it gets much more complex
and if you just to the modern method because you have to take into account
not only each individual sampling considerations but the
comm combination
so we came up with a
the one typology
we identified two major things that you need to consider
when you something
one way you don't have a concurrency with we can collect the data the same
that wants to inform the other
and second if sequential
you see that there
and then you have the dominance which once dominated
and then you have the relationship
identified four types relationships
the first type is identical
with the quantitative and qualitative phases have the same people
so they contribute to both the qualitative and quantitative information
you might give a survey
there has
opening and closing the questions the same people
or you might
i have some
some quite a face
followed by interviews focus groups where everybody is quite a face
also participate in the qualitative phase
it's is where you have the same type of people
so if we look at politicians in england
the different people in different phases
so that you know a group of people i in the quite a face in
a different group of people the qualitative phase but that all politicians all the same
it's is where
you have
scrap anything
and sacrifice since
might not be thank you solely the paper instead of the
OK so let's let's
look at the simplest graphs with cycles
because we can get intuition from him
it's about three nodes
that sort of think that
i set some marginal distributions
so mu one x one i'm abusing notation a little bit but we think about
it like vector
so i'm set my marginals to be have have
no one is to binary problem node one is equally likely to care about whether
either one
the same thing for node two
we'll do the same thing for no three
OK so
the marginals are somehow easy they're boring
now let me send set some joint distributions
so on the edge and have matrix and also to be put some numbers and
year output
o point four
o point one point one
is that a valid choice
what i've done so far
and and why is it valid just so we're on the same page
right so by some point four point one point five the rows and columns both
so so that's good so far
up with the same thing on this edge
so on
for me
user pen that works on two three all do the same thing
o point four point four
o point one point one
and so
everybody still happy
now the last edges the interesting edge of course try because that's the only thing
that distinguishes us from if we're on a tree and the last edge all do
a bit more interesting
in this right and then all uncover is trying to make a mess
so last enjoyed the same thing except that put the point ones on the diagonal
right so locally if i just think about it as the tree
and local sense everybody still happy because
everything's set up so all the row and column sums are have
but if you sort of think physically about this problem you should be bothered by
so let's let's sort of think
whether this makes sense if you sort of thing can you have a set of
random variables binary things that satisfy this kind of behavior doesn't make sense or not
one way to think about this think of these as people think about them that
you know people have opinions
and maybe the voting on something and if they say yes to something one if
they say no it's zero
right so if we think of it that way then what this means
is that eighty percent of the time whoever is that no one agrees with whoever
is node three
eighty percent of the time they
have the same opinion
we use that interpretation what's what's funnier
right so the funny thing is when you go around the cycle one agrees with
three eighty percent of the time
two agrees with three eighty percent of the time
but somehow one and two
i disagree eighty percent of the time they only agree twenty percent of the time
right so it looks a bit suspicious it sort of there's this maxim friend of
a friend is your friend kind of thing or
what is the enemy of enemy is your friend
well there is that two this is friend of a friend of a friend which
may or may not be true i don't know about you but only when it
comes to the green this is mathematically impossible
this little exercise you might want to play around with it it's just not possible
to build the distribution
over three binary variables such that this pair is eighty percent agreeing this pairs eighty
percent agreeing and despairs only twenty percent agreeing that's not possible
so this is sort of an instance that when we moved to trees
when we move away from trees
something goes wrong right this is an example of the vector that sort of locally
happy it satisfies all of those strains
but it doesn't make any sense globally
so what it means is that the reduction that i did if you only put
those constraints that wouldn't be an exact reduction anymore
because i should have had things that came from some global distribution q
and they should be consistent globally
but these guys are locally consistent not globally
and that's if you think about that well what this statement here saying this deep
fact is that these kinds of games are only possible if you have cycles
if i didn't have cycles of any one of those edges was raised then everybody
is happy it doesn't matter
so that's what that statement saying saying well both the trees are exact but a
sort of extension of it is that for any graph that has cycles
there are vectors that are locally happy but not globally happy
OK so
what we've seen so far what i've told you is that if you run the
max product algorithm on a tree what it's actually doing is solving a linear programme
and the message is that we've spoken about those actually have a concrete interpretation is
lagrange multipliers
should understand
and now we have a mixed terms
this thing with this and actually we have this twice because this
combined with this will give us the same thing so just try to
this thing
and here we have five x i five x
the mistakes of
and then we've got this basically the same thing now with the difference that here
we have a plus one and here we have an plus song and of course
there's a minus you in different so it seems
you we must
is very soothing sound
it reminds me about of mathematics classes at university so
OK so this is this one
goes away
and then we are left with something that doesn't depend on x
is this thing here is something that does depend on x
and let's see if we're already there
OK so one difference is the factor of two but of which
the factor of two we can just take off because sign function and so we
can multiply the argument of the sine function with any nonnegative number that we like
without changing things so so let's just
divide by two
which brings us this thing here
and then we recognise OK this
these two together they should give us our factor
b down here
and the other to the left should exactly give us
so i've called this and instead of them but not exactly give us this quantity
so we've got his first two terms we've got to be
will set
any questions
OK so i have to apologize for those who find this trivial but i think
it's very useful to try to do something because it's you know we to say
this is one simple example of how to analyse algorithms we take the logarithm this
trivial algorithm computing the means in feature spaces and then you can get this difference
between this with distances and you already have a classification algorithms
it's just something that makes sense from statistical
OK so
i want to make sure is only four hours i will talk about statistical learning
theory intellectual control taylor we talk about this in great detail normally at this point
lecture i have a couple of hours about statistical learning theory so i'll ask you
is that same to more about kernels
c so that
let me let me give you some examples
off kind of
the weight one introduces non polynomial what people call polynomial kernel functions
so so so so maybe forget everything that said so far and i will do
things the other way around
so let's assume we have some two-dimensional
we have some two dimensional inputs
and we have two class classification problem and suppose the problem is such that the
true decision boundaries this ellipse here
so we have some
the red class inside the blue class outside we only given the training points but
not these this decision boundary which is the ellipse
now suppose we first preprocess all data points mapping into the feature space into a
three dimensional feature space with his prescription prescription here so the description is we compute
all possible products
of two input coordinates in this case this just three possible such
three such products is x one square next to square the next one time six
actually let me put square root of two in front of the
if we do this
making three-dimensional problems
but the three dimensional problem in a certain sense is easier now
it turns out the three-dimensional problem can be solved with a linear decision decision rules
so why is that so if we think about it the first alternate
because that one is exquisite the third scotland six two squared and if you're the
ellipse equation for this simple
axisaligned ellipse
in terms of these two called
it becomes and find equations like a linear equation plus constant
it's not
it's always
all this means is that
so there's a structure
so the
results of
he was
so we can
she because they can use
i was being true because you would probably
as you probably agree the way we are feeling is the way we are thinking
you can't assume that people are robots and you know they come to the meeting
can they will start being productive
there are human beings
and it all depends upon
how the hell do they feel
and it's good to know about it because then
you can accommodate the meeting in such a way
so it's very important to start with the very basic very humane question actually
just a few words about to meet to explain you why am i getting q
how to have had to have a meeting
because i've done lots of meetings lately
in the past five years being the only licensed trainer for the bonsai techniques
and much more important his school years doctor the bone actually than i am because
i don't have the bonus evangelist
actually and that's the expression i'm using all the time
here's the guy
who is considered the leading authority of creative conceptual thinking
he made us
i realize that thinking is only a skill
and then we can get better at it it we tried
the tools that he invented
then we just train on train ourselves
he was the doctor for thirty years
here the PG medicine impinge in psychology
and being conductor made him realize right actually he was starting to think
if think that you know
the researchers he was doing in his body may be saying that can happen in
the same in the brain
and in nineteen sixty nine
during these these brother revolution in many the right to build the mechanism of mind
a book about what is going on in our mind how is that our mind
to structured
the brain is working
about you now every input that we are getting is already
becoming a better
and we need to break this batteries in order to
go away out of the box out of the box is the expression that he
it's also the expression he doesn't like to use any more
because he thinks it's now not in the same way he invented it
he actually realize that our brain was maintained for routine
which is excellent
that's how we don't need to
learn every morning how the how
you know to tie their shoes
and make coffee
and who are those people say hello to us in the office
that's good about the routine
but then there is no other things when you need to break out of the
like to deal with the rising called the time
to find new concepts
to be better to be more effective
the ball like to just gave us the tools
to do it
because otherwise we are knowledge is waiting for the idea to come
sometimes it does
sometimes it doesn't
and now we can use tools for it
the tools are just for what you said not
normally at meetings were just debating and debating and debating
now trying to show off how intellectual we are how many but we at home
you know
notable and i realized something that's he's calling it the intelligence tracked
the most intelligent people
are not good thinkers at all
because they think they know everything
but if we want to think about it not to know it normally
in our normal way
we have an opinion about everything
and then we have this needs to defend our opinions
i'm right you're wrong you know that
is what he's trying to features with the six thinking hats is
explore forest
all of us
the same at the same thing
and and then at the end
let's make up and opinion
we all agree upon
of course
because then i'm not trying to push you my dear
and you will percent it
but you will all leave
for this idea that is common to all of us
so then we can design
the idea and that's how we design the future of it
if you have these problems
you get this genial idea
and then you try to show it to your colleagues
and what do they do
you have a meaning in the night during came out in the sleep you've got
this great idea you come to them
we think next day you show it to your colleagues what do they do
that does not is it they don't have brought
and what they do them
you defended it so i will show you how good do this
and by the they
that even more
and there are comics you france people who work together
and that's why that happens
isn't it
the question is
is it helpful
they criticizes that helpful
you defend the idea then meaning to defend yourself
is this helpful
is this constructive
not really
you know
it's something in our culture european and middle eastern culture
that we think we are always right
and the we think that argument is always winning
that's what we think for two thousand four hundred years
it's not constructive but we're still doing it
it's a now culture it's not breeding
our friends criticizing US
because they want to have a normally isn't it
it's called the constructive critic
i think this is the end of the fight to hear something constructive critique because
it's the structure they
tell you what's wrong with the idea
in order to help you
to improve it
the masses of the w z something the particles
when you went through five this actual sales of around TV and that's become the
standard electroweak symmetry breaking news words
mass this broken symmetries
it depends on is one example of this
supersymmetry can be another manifestation of this but what this is
it will take place on the TV and scale that one designed to scale
so this image is very much one of the things that people will be looking
for and you hear a lot about it
in the subsequent match
so the probability now
and where we are today
we have the standard model of particles and forces the standard model the quarks and
instead of spending and the one missing link
the higgs boson
we've been seeing
in the simplest realization
that's how it came with the idea
forty years ago
since then there have been many
we find some when he goes on
to incorporate supersymmetry into
the higgs mechanism meaning higgsino
and so on
so it is possible that there is a whole family of higgs particles with spin
or maybe was
these are things that there is some crazy ideas about
and if one of them is located right nine nine thousand of those will be
wrong the experiment shown
high energy early universe
is a profound one that we have in the last twenty thirty years realized that
these experiments are recreating
the conditions of the physics of the early universe showing the the origins matter showing
the existence of structured patterns below one TV which is where visitors can stop for
the last three thousand years
maybe revealing something
of real symmetry of montenegro about to
and the puzzles are
the nature of the dark matter
it turns out supersymmetry if the lightest supersymmetric particles are protein is what we know
switch which are to neutral
it is possible
under the certain scenarios they could be metastable states and if that's the case
then you could
there is a universal gravitation together to make a large
close which will not challenge
it could be that they are the they succeed
dark matter
if it turns out that he finds the licensing
articles are neutral and stable that would be a remarkable connection to get the cosmology
particle physics but if that's the case
major knows that the experiment hopes
two years
the problem is you around forty years is now being solved
what perfectly
it's somehow with the
the fact that neutrinos have masses
exactly what matters are we don't you know
the observation of neutrino oscillations detail has not yet been really
everything one
question one of the three generations
why not why
well mathematically it seems that if you have three you very naturally generate a solution
for matter and antimatter
the rather arcane time strange spent much of matter
but why is the asymmetry between matter and antimatter the basic stuff that makes us
it is still
really question which is my argument and we are hoping to get some further so
is there is no mention
it mentions well
that is an intriguing question string theory suggests that the three space and one time
we know
obviously the large scale remnants of higher dimensions
but are there is maybe we want to do this
very early times
the possibility that one of these might be
large enough effect to manifest itself in c
this something like sighted people
and you hear something that is well i'm sure
so what do in the last twenty minutes or so
these two
try to look into the future to give the qualitative theory what all the symmetry
breaking stuff that underlies the is
from the first lecture
where we came in
with this temperature scale this energy scale physics place at different times see if that
get the full patterns
the change from one temperature to another
that's the whole thing
in more
so we started
temperatures below
freezing point of water imagine snowflake
so you have to have the same thing
i had a my speech
we have is not because the snowflake
people sixfold symmetry to it
the underlying rules makes snowflakes
satan or in snowflake
in the original
complete rotation symmetry says this ways for that individual snowflake falls
and let's say it's got one of ten to twelve o'clock that forces the other
ones to being that they are
and that are more so the snowflake
made the h two s
and frozen finds
now if i increase the temperature above
two hundred seventy three degrees kelvin
it melts
so the pattern has been lost to h two survive
and there is not pattern which is called the periodic table the atomic elements
ten which is in a sense a pattern in the physical part pattern is of
the palace which
it's about
and that to survives as long as you temperatures almost ten thousand degrees all your
energies less than
if you
about entities above temperatures
the atoms ionized completely destroyed plants
so when that happens no one
that's what i mean by different isotopes by you going to some new laboratories you
a pattern of nuclear isotopes wall
that's what this strange died there
this pattern
to invisible GV's which points
they begin to melt away see the quarks gluons manifest themselves
and and that is where a lot of many years
energy is where the base class
and indeed it
and it's from that generated the standard model
so the present as of the quarks leptons
is the standard model is a pattern based on mass
the up and down quarks
chance to get heavy top bottom and and if it were not about
these three different levels would say
the photon is massless w z or not
but otherwise it's the same day the sun shone for five billion years because the
w has
we're not
in the town if it's just like this
so this mass is cracked is
four so
of the lines of true
and that we suspect reveals if we could know calculate these patterns and the theory
suggests that not always takes place
very well the way
professor stevens would think of this as being segments where each segment is made up
of a bundle of these distinctive features
so that that's how it works for him
this is guided in people have attempted to build systems that look like
the other important component that i that sort of left out here and that he
addresses in sort of a separate thing is the notion of being able to
these hypothesized word sequences by really basically taking these hypothesized sequences that you that you
produced in your own mind here in
he then sort of re synthesize landmarks and accused accuse somehow internally compare those with
the evidence that you've been given
and then possibly risk score
the the hypothesis that you that you have come up with so the idea is
that this rescoring process allows you to incorporate some other higher level source of knowledge
some other context that might not be part of this initial change
and we
and again for those of us in ASR in language processing in natural language processing
it's like work restoring alastair
OK so
is how we do the times and we
so we use the break timer should i keep going
eleven OK
o i'm fine phi i was the need to hurry through that stuff in
what we've done is we've just
motivated by the use of these things with
talk a little bit about fundamentals of distinctive features theory
and describe how all this sort of fits in
two models of perception
now we will sort of go into
how we can exploit these models and automatic speech recognition
we'll talk about methods for
phonological distinctive features
and will
talk about how we can actually incorporate distinctive feature knowledge in ASR model structure
rather advanced models of articulatory
of vocal tract dynamics
that's sort of the holy grail
can we model the entire system
and what you know what we got that we're done think and but that's a
very difficult problem and then the
and then i'll talk about
work that's been done trying to integrate distinctive features in traditional ASR systems
the that's less of the holy grail that's easier
we know what can we do to sort of take
feature representations somehow complement the knowledge that we have an existing resources
o too much one
i'll talk about
in when we talk about distinctive feature defection
i guess the first issue is is
what sort of systems that we use to describe
the distinctive features will have some examples of that
talk about how we might obtain acoustic parameters from surface acoustic measurements you know what
acoustic evidence to we use as input to these feature detectors
how we might incorporating pdfs and training incorporating them in ASR systems training detectors and
the actual algorithms themselves
it turns out that there
really not too many systems that actually exploit direct articulatory measurements in the big exception
is what i mentioned earlier is in audio visual ASR you can imagine having the
real system
with a camera that that provides this
this visual side channel
and that give you these visual features that provide you with sort of partial articulatory
another example that's that's actually got a lot of attention there's these things called gems
sensors and i forget which m stands for now talk about later but the basic
and low power radar sensors you put here you right around your glottis and they
there's was pretty substantial research project about
i think about three or four years ago
when people would be wearing these things and you actually use those as as complementary
you know i
information for doing is are
it's that kind of thing is really valuable and really high noise environments and you
fighter pilots those guys are wearing these masks that every another super-high noise so they're
looking for
nine acoustic
the information to to use for controlling
voice control systems only in the cockpit
professor while mention the there's a colleague of mine who actually had a voice controlled
cockpit at MIT
but you know it's there are there are there are functions that are good to
have a voice control and those that are not like you know writer down into
control the radio and the fact that they are not the car they they're playing
but on the other hand we have a lot of ASR systems that exploit
phonological distinctive features and the the way they are exploited is by way of
the hidden process they can sort of service and under underlying state space
in in an HMM system
and we can in using them we hope to
exploit all of these great advantage is that we discussed at the very beginning that