here we
so we will continue the introductory part on the classification of data mining tasks and
and finally on the visualization we will distinguish between two sorts of data mining tasks
mainly predictive and descriptive in predictive tasks we are dealing with the same classification problems
and then the approaches which we take his learning sets of rules or decision tree
learning when we have one target variable and this target variable would be typically discrete
like reading or not reading are being the readers of the law more being leaders
of vichy and france so on we could have a binary classification problem for multiclass
classification problem we can also deal with prediction destination tasks and that we would typically
use regression analysis then the data can be in the form of a single table
or in the form of of a relational database all my multiple relational tables and
then we'll in that case we are dealing with so-called predicted relational data mining or
inductive logic programming other sorts of tasks where we don't have specified classification variables so
we don't want to distinguish between members of different classes would be descriptive tasks like
description and summarisation dependency analysis like association rule learning discovery of properties and constraints segmentation
or clustering as well as subgroup discovery so
if we try to show it almost the picture in the simplest classification problem we
would distinguish between
members of one class versus members of the other class and the classification would be
the main the ultimate goal so we'll try to distinguish between populations of one class
and the other one is here with our data is not labelled with the class
but it is non specific variables is the
class or the target variable and we just interested in finding some properties which hold
on parts of the data we would perhaps want to cluster together the items the
individuals which are most similar to each other and that has to do with the
segmentation of clustering we can try to find out
characteristic properties which holds on part of the population we can do dependency analysis like
association rule learning as we have seen in some of the applications which we have
illustrated before
separately we can deal with the text web and image analysis again
the tasks can be either predictive of descriptive but then the mechanisms of doing data
analysis are obviously pretty much different
so i have already shown this distinction between predicative and in descriptive and
here we are in predictive the main goal is to induce classifiers and we have
classification and prediction task which we want to solve
by inducing the classifiers from the data
classification rule learning decision tree learning we have also support vector machines which is one
of the new
newer approaches to classification extremely effective and high quality classifiers can be obtained by support
vector machines then we have artificial neural networks bayesian classifiers and so on so here
we generate a hypothesis out of the data and then we test it
and it's similar in statistics you can do so different sources of data analysis in
setting what with descriptive induction the task can be different just like discovering interesting regularities
in the data not necessarily inducing classifier
discovering patterns here we could use symbolic clustering
association rule learning subgroup discovery and that would be more in the face of exploratory
data analysis is done in with statistical methods
if we take rule learning perspective when we induce rules
in predictive induction when we want to induce classifiers we use not looking at individual
but we are using sets of rules
for every
so we want to sets of rules acting as a classifier for solving classification and
prediction task but in descriptive induction we are interested in finding individual rules
we describe a certain interesting property or regularity in the data
distinction in terminology and also the types of tasks we are solving is between supervised
and unsupervised learning
so supervised learning occurs when there is a specific target variables
representing the class
you have patients some patients have a certain diagnoses so different diagnoses would be different
and you would have a certain
and values of that variable would to represent different classes in that case we can
say we are dealing with the supervised learning problem
instances all the training instances are labeled with the class labels
and such a setting is used for predictive induction what is supervised learning setting
there we do not have a specific target variable
representing the class
no class assignment and this is usually used for descriptive induction we can do descriptive
induction also unlabelled data obviously inducing some individual regularities from the data but that would
be the most common
used distinction
in subgroup discovery we have labelled data but are using are doing the kind of
descriptive induction tasks so we will talk about that later
so i was skip this and i will show some visualizations
so let's look at the visualization of the data
so for instance here you have three variables we do to data is described here
is a childhood time of course crystallisation and the time from the past from the
from in
there was an keep implant put into the patients patients heap
and that these are different data points and then different colours would represent different classes
so this is one possible way of visualizing the data this is called the scatterplot
obviously you can see that most data
here but then you have some outliers and then can look at this particular data
points and try to understand whether it is
indeed an outlier you whether it represents noise whether there was some typing error in
you the most of what something much more general modelling approach is something that in
the end might be rather similar to bayesian networks and graphical models
that was the main difference is that well
in when people talk about bayesian networks it's usually the discrete values variables and then
things are really much simpler
always talk about continuous valued variables then they always have culture medium
and yes they so so this is this will not
is a sense of those in the framework of bayesian networks doesn't really it's not
it's it's it it's simply a simple in those cases but when you want to
model something like images and you want to model build models which are similar to
this one then things get actually very much more complicated
yes it is
yes in US
so they are not independent unconditionally they are independent if only we know
this is given the very
so i use these
yes yes this user completely independent so unconditional independence
so we kind of continuing this philosophy of ICA that's somewhere there will be some
kind of more-or-less independent sourcing signals of some kind of independent courses for the data
but then they are just mixed up which in many many different ways and then
there are some of the other variables that also intervened
OK then well the point is that at the likelihood for this kind of model
is then something very complicated so we need to make approximations and so on but
i'm will not going the details but the point is this is what you get
is then in the end when you estimate topographic ICA for images
so here so we still have a linear decomposition of the data
so which means
image patches can be represented as a linear sum of certain basis vectors
with certain random coefficients it's just that now these coefficients random missions will be
not independent
and by the because this random coefficients
get on this topographic created we can also order the basis vectors on the same
topographic rate because each coefficient corresponds to exactly one node basis vector and space
so this is what we get when we all the basis is to make the
basis vectors
and show them in this in this original topographic reformulation
so as you can well as you can easily see there is some
uh-huh this this ordering is not random this seems to be something interesting going on
and actually what claim is that we get the same kind of the same kind
of topographical ordering that has been observed in the visual cortex
i'm going to do this but
and that's
that's one of the reasons that our explanation basically for why we for well is
an explanation but
well that's that's all
justification of why this model is is in his interest interesting
the main point
the babies
here i have a right
one of the best
it was
yes well i just went home in my last sentence i realized that i should
if someone justification for what you before this
this model well for
for these independent subspace analysis
the whole point is that this is how you get invariant features that are presumably
better in whatever you want to do something for example pattern recognition because you would
get features that are there for example you get this kind of general concluded that
those that do not care about the phrase
all the contour
against just where it is just
you know you're never going to see them again
right just
you're student who signed up to go in this experiment in which you from the
screen in the office the money and
the people still like to do fifty fifty
i i mean this is human nature
but interesting for a game theoretic perspective is in a certain sense i mean this
keep nine give one in that sense you choose are kind of is is
my project i mean at some level
you start thinking that
it's interesting to think about
the people
i mean you know you mean
if you think about that so
in fact in a certain sense
i mean that user might be offended right from million dollar might not be worth
to them the dollar not you know nothing but their surprise right
you know
in some sense actually the fear that happening
could potentially help
make further
the more fair
exact OK great great great great great great great great so
so this is an interesting thing that happens with non zero sum games like this
OK so
please let me just right this is the matrix
this is the case with four dollars let's say i have it in in o
now so
just kind of right this game is the matrix this hearsay with four dollars is
to make the matrix smart can choose to either offer
the player can decide
since it used to do this we can decide how much offer the user you
say one dollar two dollars three dollars we could offer zero but that's
now there's no reason to example could offer for that's not very interesting thing to
do this but there is not getting anything so there is natural things are one
two or three
and now that user can decide so what does it mean to have the user
strategy significantly advance the user kind of thinking how much money is going to take
for me to be happy
but you might think OK
one dollar enough to make me happy two dollars and how much is enough for
me to accept right
and then the future kind of user that accepts even with one dollar could be
the kind of user accepts requires two dollars to accept could be the kind of
user there are three dollars to accept then you get this matrix so for example
if the user wants
any nonzero amount then
that's what they're offering one dollar user is that user one and this further get
three offering to xtutux two offering
three three one
if the user was the kindest canny two dollars to be to except that the
weather offers only one that nobody has any money
if your offers to ever because developers three even three one if that user is
the kind of user requires three dollars to be happy then these two options will
give both players zero this option will give the two three and the other one
so we can write the game matrix just like we've been talking about
the interesting thing about this matrix is there a collection of nash equilibrium is not
just one a bunch of nash equilibria and
so i was mentioning in the back
if you are that user in this case one nice thing you might want to
it's say i'm in the right
you know what i'm going to write a little computer program is going to play
for OK and this program is only going to accept if i get three dollars
there despite
OK you right you basically right this little program going to play for you it's
all i can accept if you get three dollars and you leave
that the sweater can not
negotiate with you
all right and now it's letters the alright but are basically like this is that
right i mean we can do it myself three dollars know
it's not necessarily the case was whether really has all the power
it's a funny kind of this is exactly what is being suggested
it's a funny kind of game because
with zero sum games we worried that may be committing first part the minimax theorem
says well it doesn't have to hurt in
non zero-sum game sometimes being able to commit first
and really stick to it
can help
so before you even do that you can say with certainty that i write the
instead of there being a small number of growth factor receptors on the cell surface
there are ten or twenty or fifty times more than are normally present on the
cell surface
in other words this growth the growth factor receptors are what's called overexpressed
and therefore the delicate balance is disrupted because normally let's say
a cell will have on its surface
five hundred EGF receptors
but in many kinds of cancers probably thirty or forty percent of all
carcinoma carcinoma are are the two most epithelial tissues you'll find overexpressed EGF receptor
well why is an interesting it interesting for the following reasons
i told you before that the activation of the receptor
depends on its league and persuading two receptor subunits to come together and start firing
as we just discussed
but if you now all of a sudden the cell contains large amounts of this
growth factor being expressed of the growth factor receptor being expressed on the surface
ten or a hundred times more than normal
then these growth factor receptors are going to be rather densely packed on the cell
surface and now they may just come together
because they happen to bump into each other very frequently they don't need the growth
factor pull them together just because there's so many of them so those random interactions
randomly bumping together and these two growth factor receptors may just bumping together it and
send signals into the cell
persuading the cell
there's been some kind of growth factors in in the extracellular domain it's been encountered
when in fact all happened is that there are so many of these growth factor
receptors around the constantly bumping into each other and while they collide with one another
they can activate signaling and release
growth stimulate or signals in the cells
there's another kind of alteration of growth factor receptors also seen
in many kinds of human tumours for example in in glial blast which is the
brain tumor
and the clear last doma has the following kind of
of receptor on the surface it has a truncated forms of the EGF receptor
on the surface
where a lot of the domain is simply not present
so here's the normal EGF receptor
here's the truncated EGF receptors were lot of the extracellular domain which i'm calling the
domain is simply been locked up houses and lopped off well there's been a mutation
in the gene which has in effect deleting segments encoding the n terminus of the
receptor protein which normally sticks his head out of the cell
and now you have these truncated receptors and such truncated EGF receptors
we are able to fire constitutively
constitutively implies that these receptors are able to fire
in a fashion that is no longer regulated by
busy logic signals it so high
steady rain so now these receptor molecules these two truncated receptor molecules flood the cell
with gross to military signal and for reasons that aren't really clear to this date
these two
these receptors truncated receptor molecules can dive arise they can come together
even if there is no extracellular ligand present even if there's no growth factors in
the extracellular space
and we now realise for example
that there are a variety of structurally altered receptors that fire constitutively into a cell
in many kinds of human tumours and in each case the cancer cell is deluded
into thinking that some growth factor has been encountered out here when in fact there
is not at all
once again
what we see is the situation
in which the cell
the cancer cell is being deluded into thinking this growth factors present extracellular space none
has been present at all
there's been a variety of drugs developed against for example lung cancer
and there are a variety of different kinds of of lung cancers one is called
non small cell lung carcinoma we don't have to deal with those subsets of lung
cancer and it turned out
it turned out
the one of these drugs it's called arrests
i had very mixed effects on patients
in about ninety percent of these of the class of lung cancers
patients that were treated the drug arrests
we use over the last several years had almost no effect on the tumor treating
patients continued to to proceed to their deaths it had really had no effect but
in ten percent
in fact there were some random magic responses and the tumors shrunk down
now normally
a ten percent response rate would be enough to cause the drug company to abandon
all further development of the drug because it's just too low response and who wants
take a drug with the chances of having a good response as low as ten
percent it's just not a good situation
but then some analysis here in boston one group at the MGH and another over
to dinner farber began to look at the long cancer cells that respond
i e from two reservations that responded and triang in response to the drug
and the long and the lung cancer cells in patients who didn't it turns out
that the rest is an inhibitor of the tyrosine kind is of the EGF receptor
that so it was designed
in other words this drug to low molecular weight drug
and it goes into the terracing kind is domain that rectangular thing i showed you
before very schematically and shuts down the firing of the receptor
that was the motivation behind creating this drug
so you rest rest shuts down the EGF receptor and ten percent of lung cancer
patients the tumour shrank
the other ninety percent didn't weren't affected at all
and what these two groups geneticists found over the last three or four months
is it the patients whose tumors responded
had tumor cells where the EGF receptor was mutated
and therefore firing in a constitutively active fashion
that is to say
there were actually structural alterations in the receptor
this is a massive structural alteration receptor here this truncation but in fact in certain
ten percent of patients
the respondent there were much more subtle changes in the cytoplasmic domain of the protein
which allow these receptors to constitutively dimerisation once again in the league and independent fashion
so the size limitations mimic in effect the consequences of the leading truncating the extracellular
domain in that in both cases one gets legally independent receptor
in those cases where these with the patients head a mutant EGF receptors structure EGF
receptor was fined considerably there were dramatic responses to the rest of drug
you know
the names of each
that you have to satisfy
invisible in
markov model
you have some states
so you don't know the names of each word senses in this sentence
it's going to be really
you might not
so the two
might not really worked
just leave the interesting information and
as well states
you might stop for the common sense
so there are still
so you don't
well you can not so easy to compute from
the transition which
he is
so that
so is
the probabilities of initial state
the state transitions
and also the problem of
the mission that
this problem is for
so if
you can compute
transition probabilities and conditional probabilities
so the transition of
from going from state to state
you just come out
in your
how many times
when he wants to live many times you go to state
consider this whole states lines
you also consider the nominator
all the times that you are so just count
how many times
like it
that you will see the line to see line history
and is similar
four of the emission probabilities one see it
you can't how many times you it
a system consisting of four
so is
and then consider all the time is that you
state so
again maximum likelihood estimation
you can compute these
the decision problem is issue
problem is
if you want it
it's not for
you need
you need to estimate the actual
so the problem is that
i don't know
the states that the previous examples include
so usually we
but approach
so we start with an initial estimate of these
so give me
mean you
what something of is
well some
this is something which is more likely to occur
and then
very hot stars
which produce
white light
why this we can
think of it
in the next slide you see that creates
and is immediately obvious that you see blue light coming from the vicinity of those star
there are these very fine dust particles
few microns
and they scatter light new direction from those stars and so the light comes blue
the same reason why are sky blue
the next slide i find even more interesting
as a man walking on the moon
there's no atmosphere on the moon in the sky would look completely dark
absence when x is
but dust
on they on the ground and this aspen out walking on the moon
and therefore some of the dust
thrown out
and its surrounding
the light using
they can
by the camera
clearly scattered sunlight
scattered all these very fine dust particles
and his group
the same reason why are skies
so you see the really
scattering here
dependence on wavelength
but that's online courses
as white as we call it like
and i want to demonstrate is the u
by creating very fine
dust particles
and those very fine dust particles
will be
dust particles in cigarette smoke
the demonstration that i don't like because they have too small
the center all the way there
bright white light coming up vertically and the reason why we let it comes straight up
and here
i'll put
smoking cigarettes
and whatever comes to u
no matter where you are
always comes out roughly ninety degrees
that's why i get the double bonds for this thing
and in addition the particles are fine but only if they are very small few microns they will be blue
the smoke will be blown
and since you have a linear polarizer s
we should be able to see what you rotate it
the light is polarized anyway
in this plane at ninety degree angles
which is this whole horizontal plane or during this horizontal plane more or less doesn't
matter is sitting there with there
you should see the light
pretty much polarized
all right
sitting here in this election
all right here
so first
try to
create is very fine dust particles
by simply
having some
smoking of cigarettes in there being there
like beam make it very dark when we get to it
and i have to
can we just like check that for a moment so I believe that that this
is the this is 3
doesn't look right
and see what you want to know what devices we wanna find a pattern
and and actually where this 1 is I wrote that 1 down 1st because it's
uh because the pattern will be easier to find 43
somehow see it's already works OK now I have to ask you how you checked
it and how did you do that matrix multiplication you probably did roles
here times columns there
all right fair enough
actually here is that you can just make a comment on that it's well worth
looking because it's terrific to have actual numbers
OK what I see what I mean the crucial thing in these all these matrices
is pattern minus 1 2 0 minus 1
and we're going to recognize that as as a kind of 2nd difference
so I'm not surprised if I take it away I notice about that column is
that it's like linear 3 to 1
and then if I take a 2nd difference of a linear thing I expect to
get 0 just loses take that I do minus 3 plus or minus 1
and if aware that role by this 1 well of course it's linear it's even
constant so I get minus 1 plus 2 minus 1 and getting 0 and then
of course I should check that I got the diagonal right minus to plus or
minus 1 right that at least 1 OK so that is the inverse
and we could yes OK so match mathematics is often wondered I think it would
be fun to see if we can find the inverses here and uh
by a mixture of guesswork and then maybe understanding sort of inspired decimation
and in the y
now can move to the inverse
with question mark of this of this 1 this 1
what about was
I wrote down the word nonsingular because you told me to
but now
I'm not so sure about this 1
I believe what you think of
the rows and 0 right
so that's suspicious
In fact that should actually tell us that is not invertible right and what's a
good way to to recognize the matrix is invertible well you could say take is
but don't say that the the matter of Matlab will take its determinant and and
you for 3 by course we could do it but it's a much better
like recognized of vectors
that it takes to 0 if I if we can find a vector that that
it takes to 0
so what so what what I'm going to show is being 3 is is singular
so that with with both of these
both the 1st row last row altered
that brings the matrix down those matrices are will see positive definite this 1 is
dragged down to being only as we'll see positive semi de OK what's the
that's that's not out by being
all ones right constant vector right and that's exactly because as you said when the
when the role when the rows that is 0
then why multiplied by all ones then I'm adding that what I'm doing is adding
up each row and getting all zeros and you see that we have now demonstrated
that the matrix is singular
it's it has to be a singular matrix effects taking some vector 0
it couldn't have an inverse if we have a solution we have waited for this
be 3 we found a vector X so that
is completely knocked out
OK now if there was an inverse
we could multiply that equation
that inverse
and what what we learn
we learn is
so it from ever matrix and part not square matrices here if it has a
only vector
X that would solve this equation would be the 0 vector
and that's the case for those 2 but here we have an x not
that solves the equation so we know there's a there's the vectors X not connected
just repeat that argument from this if there is an inverse I can multiply by
and I would learn X was 0
so so having an inverse means not only solution
so in these cases which still have inverse the only solution to t 3 x
equals 0 is that it is the 0 vector but here we have other solutions
in fact while we're at it
more solution to be 3 x equals 0 to tell me the whole
the null space of this matrix so this this xxx adjusting use that word this
X is in the null space meaning just what it says of 3 OK and
tell me another exits in the null space
yeah any constant times 3 3 3
or 6 6 6
and in fact that's the whole null space the the null space is any multiple
of that particular vector X
and that
that the null space is that line
of OK what 1 other point is actually an important point is just 1 over
degree matrices
how do I multiply a matrix by by a vector weatherwise what see going on
I like to multiplied
like columns a column time so I see this as the multiplication of matrix by
vectors as I think of it as 1 times the 1st column
keep slides from
now the answer that's true
can you it's not mathematical sequence
this is a real life sequence
in city
new york was the seventh avenue line
in new york city is the my favourite somewhere in new york
what's called feature of the new york city subway
is the skip list can answer
indeed it is
so if you want to experience skip lists some practical
they have been implemented
in the subway system
cause that
boston subway is pretty cool because it's the oldest subway
definitely in the united states navy in the world
new york is close
it has other nice features like it's open twenty four hours after it has no
a plus but it also has this feature express lines
it's a bit of an abstraction by the seventh everyone has
essentially two kinds of cars
there is that these are street and by the way this is know
penn station in times square
and so on
there are essentially two lines there's the express line which goes fourteen thirty four forty
two seventy two to nineteen six
and then there's the local line which takes which stops at every cell
and they have they accomplished this with four sets of tracks
the express lines have their own dedicated track if you want to go stop fifty
nine from the same penn station
well i would say from from
lower west side you take
you get on the express language up to forty two pretty quickly and then you
get good switch over to the local i'm and going to
fifty nine or reverse
i was going
so this is
and local lines and we can represent that
with a couple of lists we have
one last
we have
one list on the bottom
so we some space appear
this is the local
quite well too
thirty four
forty six two
you know i
sixty six
seventy two
seventy nine and so on
and then we have the express line on top
only stops at fourteen
thirty four
forty two
seventy two and so on
not going to redraw the whole list
you get the idea
so what we're going to do is put links between
the local and express lines
wherever they happen to meet
that's are
to link to link structure
so that's what i actually meant
when i was trying to draw some pictures now this has the property that in
one list the bottomless every element occurs
in the top was just copy some of those elements and we're going to
preserve that
so l two
stores all the elements
and l one store some subset
and it's still open which ones we should store
that's the one thing we need to think about inspiration
from the new york subway system
because there
that's the idea of course we're also going to use more than two lists
we also have links
the same links between the school fees
in l one and l two
so just for the sake of completeness and because only this later let's talk about
searches before we worry about how these lists are actually constructed
one four
so if you want to search for an element x
what do you do
well this is the taking the subway algorithm
and suppose you always start in the upper left corner of the subway system
you're always and
lower west side of fourteenth street and know exactly what that is
four less somewhere down the of
if you want to go to a particular station like fifty nine well used standard
express line as long as you can
OK thank you
so today i will talk about support vector machines so this is the a specific
classification and regression method
so so i'm getting to some details about his methods
so the plan is likely so we have several topics so i'm hoping to
OK so for the first part
we have to finish the first two
so the basic concepts and those go
to derive the SVM primal and dual problems
then for the second part i will talk about training in linear nonlinear support vector
then i was partially issue of parameter and kernel selection
and also some practical issues
and those mentions some possible research using support vector machines
with some of
some of those issues will be left to a certain part then we also mention
multiclass classification and then have some discussion
so please feel free to interrupt me if you have any questions
OK so maybe the question is why we are here to talk about support vector
this right now it is one of the very popular classes
so in quite a few situations you can give you a competitive performance we use
existing classification methods we're not claiming it is
it is that where you in my view not mutually reasonably good learning about using
such images well would say it is relatively easy to use
well i have to say only relatively well don't come to what i can use
that of course in public spending in in this case you want to try k
nearest neighbour just like consensus among monday but compared to some very sophisticated classification techniques
where it is the as is is not so difficult to use
so i see there may be one reason why
it is possible write this you the visual kernel
kernel technique
so we have a whole canaries bigger area so next week singer alex smola is
going to give tutorial
kernel techniques
so there are many extensions so as own is only a kind of kernel methods
so let's talk about two class classification first
so i was thinking about very simple situation so this is something that there is
no training services so we x i i don't want to have
so that the
and you can in euclidean space
and each feature vector is the so-called feature vectors
so for example you representing each patient as feature vector human components like height weight
blood pressure et cetera so you have get along the
so beautiful such that we weekly denying states
now we consider a similar situation we saw only two classes of data
with same properties you're they come in many many cases for example you can read
ten digit recognition then you're going to have ten classes
but not before
what is it starts from
dealing with the case of progress is only so far
easier description we define an indicator vector
so these lies we slept with remember is the number of training instances
so this is a component of y is has value to plus or minus one
so here that lies training says is in the first place
then we say what is class one but if x is in the second is
that we define
the minus one so actually we define this one and it
it plays a role in the data vector
then the basic idea of support vector machines is to find a so-called separating hyperplane
well just like
this figure shows so focuses of training instances some circles in the summer triangle
so if he tries to find
separating hyperplane because separate all the training instances when the two dimensional situation that this
is just a straight line but in in higher dimensional space we call it a
so what we intend to find is this started online so once we have started
to line then we have a model to do prediction
the reason is
so if use it is that light as your model then for any new data
there's also services which is on top of it and help users to
find interesting information
so what those services are well there's search
anne there's user recommendation and various other forms a recommendation
which help people to understand what is going on
so to the extent
machine learning is relevant to query is relevant and helping
to help users to find relevant stuff
it's not
the only way do so but there's so it can be actually quite useful
so take a look at the problems which i so
with machine learning and otherwise
one of such problems search
all the relevance in search
some people come to certain clare their search for a number of things one of
such things as users so people will find other users users could be celebrities
could be bloggers people already know from somewhere else
so really find
another thing could be events
so i know something is happening
i want to come here and find out what is going on
but this particular event maybe this election happening maybe there's earthquake may be something else
the people of two minds about this so one is show me the freshest stuff
about this thing whatever there is
even it's noisy so the typical and before hatchbacks
gave interesting of
and another way to look at edits like i really want to find it
relevant information about a particular event
so i want to
find out about occupy wall st movement but not
because blow-by-blow accounts of what everybody's doing that maybe
just the things that more informative people
i have said about this event in the recent past
so those things are not necessarily in six class which however
the trick is that the so the rose bowl in real time search
which really is an open question right now in the research community have the so that's
the second problem
is how to grow the tree graph
so as you probably know
the way to receive information into areas before other people
so i can follow other people for a variety of reasons
this could be our friends and family colleagues co-workers
so and so forth but also could be medial sources
could be influential bloggers
could be government agencies
so forth so it could be a vast variety of reasons why should be following somebody
end on top of this is also the time scale the interest i could be
interesting somebody for a very short time
so the figured out with budget
and they
thirty recommendation problem
is the problem of called the recommendation so
yes i can be following other users but
do not necessarily guaranteed to provide useful information
which i can be finding interesting
so for example news stories
medium videos school pictures also for something that could be happening
it right now which
could be interesting to me
how do actually figure out what the show to what to who
and there's a bachelor problems
so this
how they the trending topics
how they should take language
how the antispam and similar
how to optimize revenue optimize graph and so on and so forth so like a myriad of problems
and these for some other machine learning can or is playing a crucial component
so you can see from those
examples the problems which i self can be cast more or less as recommenda style problems
which i recommend
items to people
asked people
so she does i recommend there's still problems
they can be solved partially for solving second-order problems such such as classification and clustering
so surpassing machine learning problems
so is this really big data
so if you do the math
you think that go welfare and fifty million tweets per day
it is multiplied by the size of the tweet
so you could probably fit new laptop
early on ebay
but then
if you actually combine all they associated medium which come with those three
andy clickstream of all those events that could be happening whilst on this the graph
and so on and so forth
it becomes
so just give one interesting numbers so
so injustice file log data are
just about
ten terrabytes per day
and then other things like one
the idea is if you say well if you knew
center the process data in the long term
that's really big date
now what the challenges
i mean there's many challenges is name a few
after is very rational
over seventy percent of all users actually
are outside the us
and doesn't mention before through real time
this is very important so people comfort wear and really expect things be relevant whatever is happening right now
and that's the key
because the brevity
the tweets are very short
you know the showed a search query
by the really short and sometimes very noisy
so having said about
got the question is
the fact that you create
some general statement from particular observations and that's also what
creating the series is about so learning and creating serie are the same thing so
how can we talk about learning theory is we have to make a theory about
making series so it's kind of a circular process here
and that's why it's so i think it's an interesting topic because it's really
the fundamental issues it like this because the process of learning underlies
most of the sciences at least for example physics
most of physics is
building series so once we know
how to be series then we can do physics you know
so studying learning series good is it can be helpful for studying physics
you know it
OK so this is a rephrasing of what they just say in that induction is
the process of building theories learning series main focus is
induction which is also
building series
how can we do it
so there are of course
we can talk hires about this topic because
there are lots of his philosophical issues regarding whether this is possible at all
whether this makes sense
and i will try not to go too much into this philosophical issues but give
you some some ideas
now what the y
what we do that why would we do
sorry would we study
learning serie OK this is kind of a joke
i'm not saying this is the justification for doing it is
just a like this quote
but the real motivation is here
we want to understand systems that
learned from data
we want to understand why hardly algorithm that we have been studying in this
in this place here for example in the last week or so why do they
work at all and when with a work when we did not work
provide a framework for studying their properties
being able to
formerly prediction so once we have created the series as i said before serie is
a model that you can use to make predictions and in this context it means
prediction in here means
being able to tell that
such an algorithm should be good
in such a context or not
of course
the ultimate goal is to help design better organisms
OK so
coming back to this distinction between induction and deduction
there is a fundamental difference which is that
deduction somehow
there is no argument about whether it's fine not to deduction because once we have
agreed on the rules you just apply the rules
four induction is completely different and you can argue
powers and actually you can't really justify
or what induction does
because justifying induction means you have to say
these actions are correct are these actions are true
and actions
they don't have to be true of all wrong they are there because you decide
out there
right so
unfortunately there is no
real justification for induction so we i will not give you prove that such that
some learning algorithm is good or not
because that's not possible
so we'll see what's can be proven and what kind of people
so previous some examples
here is
very classical example
say you observe every morning you
you wake up and he observed that the sun
rising and someone ask the question so how
how likely is it that you think that the sun will rise again tomorrow
he observed
the sun rising every day for
the days for the blind
you want to predict how likely it it is that the sun will rise again
so there can be plenty of different answers to that question and here are a
one and so would be well i cannot say anything because tomorrow is not like
so why should i be able to predict something for new they which is not
the same as
one that i have the ones that i have all served
that's a bit pessimistic
the optimistic
statement would be to say well it's always rise so why wouldn't we did not
rise tomorrow so probability is one
and actually anything in between zero and one or
not not three playing in one is fine
it's annoying
do not to do
but maybe it's because it does something new
he wants me to install new software
which is to break the feedback between the overall cells
activity which is the electric potential
and the protein mechanisms are opening and closing the generate electric current
and if you do that
it's familiar course to physiologist is the voltage clamp experiment in which you hold the
voltage constant you can do that experimentally we can do it in the model and
if you do that in the model
what you find is that all oscillations disappear
there is no molecular drive
of the oscillator it is an emergent property
or systems level property if you prefer that occurs at the level of the cell
below a certain level the property simply doesn't exist and that's why it's incorrect
to label
particular channel proteins as the pacemaker current has some people do
all the pacemaker genes as others do
it depends on
understanding the way in which forty or fifty
protein components interact
to produce the reason incidentally for the mathematicians here we can show
also this is indeed a limit cycle there's no stable point in the middle of
it if you put back back
voltage oscillations reappear
that that's the limit cycle my heart is
beating a bit faster than usual because i'm giving a lecture to
and we know the reason that caused reminisce coursing through my system
we know what german dance
and to the
pacemaker cells of the heart
it up regulates all of these three transporters and if we put that information into
the model
we get
a very neat reconstruction of kartik acceleration over them as result of the upregulation of
all three of these components it does other things as well but those three are
enough to explain acceleration once again this is an integrative property of the whole system
there is no single
mechanism that is responsible for that acceleration you understand it by analyzing the complex interactions
between all of the components
right this leads me on my third principle i must accelerate a little bit fun
going to get through my ten commandments by the time rate for coffee
we have a little bit faster
and the third principal DNA is not so much
transmitter of inheritance of already referred to the fact that of course we inherit complete
xl but much more than that
the DNA is itself marked
this methylation histone marking and there may be many other processes that we don't yet
fully understand it's worth reading jane choose it'll beautiful article in nature
or if you want much more
a systematic analysis of the possibilities in relation to the genetics the book by
jablonka and lamb is worth reading too
in fact we should
in the usual question the question of landmark markets in other words the inheritance of
acquired characteristics we should ask the question what normally prevents that from happening because is
rampant in your body and mind
just think of this as an obvious point is worth underlining all the cells of
the body have exactly the same gene
heart cells
the cell
but in cells pancreatic cells totally different
and the daughter cells from those cells
inherit that difference
what is the difference it is the gene expression pattern which is imposed on the
genome by itself through
at least partly
through epigenetic marking we should be asking the question therefore what prevents that from happening
through the german lines i try my book to give an analysis of this is
getting choose beautiful article nature
instead she chose the title unfinished symphony before my
book the music of life appeared so we got on to the concept of the
uses music as a metaphore independently
although is just simply from our article
straight into the components of
epigenetic marking the time referred to
i couldn't help
picking this
headline out from the the guardian motherly love maybe email to genes for the better
this is serious scientific study
if you want a reference for it is in the journal of neuroscience i could
just one example to show you
the landmark is some is back in action
you know just as an aside if a picture is i will be doing some
time later this month in paris and i refer to that mark i'm crazy here
if i lecture in britain
and start to suggest that the mark wasn't as wrong as people have explained to
be need to get my head cut off
this is a very good example of how the genetic markers can be used
to get over the difficulty
which most of the
defenders of the central dogma or rather the extension of the central dogma which is
incorrect i would go for which is the the genetic marker is wiped off
at each other
so level
this is an example of how it can be how that can be circumvented because
what happens here
is that the red
the mother as they are
there's a lot of course in the headline
and through that activity
marking the gene in the cells of the hippocampus
has the result that those young men they grow up tend to stress
there you are
so they marked the gene even if the gene and is inherited unmarked therefore
characteristic gets transmitted down the generations that only one of the mechanisms by which the
the central dogma of biology can be circumvented and which a form of landmark is
and can come back
four principle i call this the theory of biological relativity because i think it's important
to recognise that in systems that have feedbacks between multiple levels all the way from
the organisms whole down to the gene itself there is simply no privileged level of
as i showed that analysis of pacemaker with them in the heart you have to
take account of in that case cellular protein and gene levels in order to understand
what is going on that has also major consequences for
the theory of biology means natural selection must be multi level
i go for stephen jay gould therefore rather than richard dawkins and incidentally the levels
is there no longer
they are also
it's not
they are
this like
all of them
you are
he e
went through
the 7
but that
happy feeling won't last very long because is the way from the season minute nineties
switch to come to believe I'm paying out 7 hours which row 1
so that switches to
all right and
are notices OK on row 1 up its own column wants to see which which
the column 1 not payoffs 7 then are would go back to Rho 1 and
pick the 4
and then at some
and then he would then see would go back to wrote to problem to be
paying off to an end
it would go on right
so here were really at the critical moment in this lecture right away
you what
what could be an optimal strategy here what do of course I'm not asking for
the optimal strategy precise answer but but you've got to have some
some randomization yet weighted dice that's exactly right each each player ends up in this
system as we take a case where the numbers a little
the like this which would be the typical case
then there
what the the best strategy is you just you you cannot tell another person that
you can't give that person any information about a particular
particular play of the game
but if you pass up information about particular play of the game
the upon it will use
so the best you can do is
you can do it in front of your opponent is flip a coin weighted point
so that so that are will choose these in proportions X and one minus X
so are choice amounts of selecting the fraction x
of the time of the number of places that that you choose row 1
and the remaining fractions wrote to but
randomly and see similarly
has randomized
paid a price
so well choose some
X and Y are between 0 and 1 so that was some fraction like a
3rd and two-thirds of the time I don't know right this is some fraction like
to fearsome three-fifths of the time well it doesn't sound right that would come to
7 quite a lot so
anyway that that's the idea is
so the best strategy is
are what I would call mixed strategy
next meeting you mix up
the number of rows and that the choices you your choices in a random way
and of course I don't know I mean every poker player with that's just think
about other games for the moment
if we think of poker doesn't affect the way you would do poker or blackjack
or what your favorite
game would be
In poker Qualisys takeover well so there are many many more strategies the trouble with
is five squared of the potentional is five to the four you see that five to the fourth
models of inflationare solid at ruled out at aboutninety-fiveper cent confidence limit and the
value of this in the modeldepends upon thenumberof efolds of inflation which are
uncertainfive squaredmodels of inflation are still consistent with observations so you do get information on five squared and
five to the fourth modelnow in terms of the value of r that`s allowed
by the observations first of all lets zero in on the n close to one region and r
small region and look at various predictions of models of inflation exponential models of inflation
power models of inflation linear modelsof inflation logarithmic models and negative
and small-field models of inflation and you see at n equal one r equal zero they all seem to come together
andthis is the data but the data allows for various models and you can see
you can have models with very low value of r corresponding to low values
todayof omegain the gravitational waves produced by inflation so r by the day can
be quite small you often see papers that state that w map three and sloan
suggest thatrhas to be cannot be very small I don't see
howthose statements are supported by the data so these are models of inflation potentials
that can be generatedtofit the data and you see there's a range of allowed values of the find r
can be quite small so there's no reason from the data i believe to bel to
imagine that we're just on the verge of discovering the gravitational wave background
we can only hope that the gravitational wavebackground is close to being observed one of
the ways the gravitational wave background would be observed in the cmb is through the
effect of polarization of the gravitational background radiationon the cmb the polarization pattern
can be decomposed into something known as an e mode and something knowns as a b mode this is the
moral equivalent of the decomposition of a vector field into a graident and a curl
it's slightly more complicated for polarization because there's no direction there's no arrow associated there's
no direction to the polarization there's no preferred direction to the polarization so by doing an
analysis of the polarization pattern of the microwave background you can get information all in
the contribution of gravitational waves to the density to the temperature perturbations and in
terms of looking for the gravitational wavebackground ligo and experiments going on now
can prove can probe as a function of the frequency various limits on omega gravitational waves pulsar
timing gives us more information and cmb gives us information here
this Lisain thefuture will push this down but to really push down the inflation prediction this is
forr equal to ten to the minus two there is proposals for a new satellite
known as the Big Bang observer which will pushdown to omega in gravitational waves of
ten to the minus sixteen however I remind you that ten to the minus there are models of
inflation thatgivetento the minus sixteen but there also models of inflation that
give omega in gravitational waves much smaller than that so there is no guarantee that this will
discover the gravitational waves from inflation now let me turn to a little bit of theory
and ask does inflation tell us anything about supersymmetry or strings well the inflaton
scalarpotential must be flat so you think it has to be stable to radiative
corrections so this was stopped for a long time to say aha this is
evidence that there is supersymmetry to have a model that's stable to radiative corrections so
that's sort of correct but if you examine it in detail the things are not so clean and i'll
give you a reference to a long review article by lyth and riotto many supersymmetric models of inflation
give apotential that's sort of a hybrid time type but in susy there's no general
predictionfor the scalar spectrum index we do sort of expect n minus one to
be small but there's no general prediction for n the running of n or the amplitude
of the gravitational wave background these are expected to be small in many models of
supersymmetry what we need here is observational guidance and in terms of inflation and strings and the
connection of inflationand stringsto branes cliff burgess makes the remarkable observation that inflation and strings
were made for each other because inflation is a phenomenon in search of a theory and strings are
in search of a phenomenon so you think you know when you put the what ads in the paper in the personal section
you know phenomenon looking for theory and theory looking for phenomenon they would naturally get together
and thishas beenexamined by many people most stringy or braney models can be expressed
in terms of an effective field theory ineffectively in an inflaton model
single-field slow-roll model so the phenomenological approach for the inflaton is probably useful here in
in stringy models of inflation the heavy states seem to decouple the expansion rate during inflation
that just distribution much more slowly
and if you're trying to compete against the best strategy which is everyone so while
so the best strategy which is
k times in hindsight you can by just changing the little bits that can extricate
plus one
so which is no time get one here which is two times the
which is one two years of numbers which plus one basically and that kind of
OK so you can
exactly because it so if you're not worried about the amputation time to do it
so for thinking about
OK good
so one way to see that it's possible
it's possible to do this is the
we think having an expert in we're thinking about switch strategies which k times we
can instantiate one
new expert for every possible switch k times among the old expert so we have
OK so
right OK so so members we've had is an expert to trying to do nearly
as well as the best one and we say OK now we're interested in the
nearly as well as the best strategies which is k times so with instantiate one
new expert for every
you say when they switch
OK so
so just a single plenty time that
we have to say one expert for while at some point today when it's going
to switch and then we can switch to and with can switch to we can
instantiate new experts region switching strategies if we want to explicitly do that actually turns
out that
and then you have entered the n choose k
and to the k possible orders in which things could switch
she doesn't
quebec it has to be able to say what
right across the
right next to the next right right actually we'll see will see another argument
it turns out that actually by just
by just being careful about knowledge and the way to get small you just basically
keep the same get about like so if the weights get very small and make
sure you really have to keep penalizing
i mean it's already been that's your so you know
mistakes and to make some mistakes cutting it down next multiplicatively doesn't take too many
mistakes for someone's waiting in very small you're not paying attention to its weight is
one hundred thousand young you get down to one or two
so i mean this is leave it there and then it turns out later on
that that should be good strategy doesn't take quite so long before its relatively high
OK then we want to estimate out
the predictors may actually go
there is one more thing
one thing i talked about a a little bit actually it's related to this point
here so let me just bring this back up
is that we can generalize this
this we can generalize to the case where our strategy to what we also want
to say on rainy day we do nearly as well as the best rapper in
a day
and what if we want on mondays do nearly as well as the best route
from monday and so in general we have we have a bunch of prediction rules
if that
so i think is and and have or and experts always raise the economic prediction
what if we have an if then rules so if might be if it's monday
use happy or if the document has the word football predicted about sports or
you know if if this database has this property and this property there are the
data that then it's of some fraud
this entry has always
flag has being brought to my but if then rules that you might have carefully
picked out or you might not carefully picked out you might have to generate a
lot of them and you don't know the answer for any of them really good
but we would like it if some of them are good
then you do well to
so you'd like is that for each rule i
you know if relies good
then we like to say have the property that when wildfires
in those times that the times that's when rule i fires you do well
i suspect that this is an actual got a bunch of rules some of them
might be good some of them might be that it might be a great ruled
on mondays introduce this path might be bad
it might be that you know
but also documented exports is good abroad
football soccer predict it's about politics might be about or might be good i don't
if you have a bunch of these things
and just sitting around every day some of them fire you try to figure out
which ones to use and you like to say if there's if if there's the
rule they had
maybe it doesn't quite often one part is really good
so you'd like to be able to pay attention to it so fires you do
well that's what you'd like to do
so for each i guarantee do nearly as well as it does on the time
OK so for all
i i want are expected costs are algorithm to be nearly as good as the
cost of the i th row in the time steps so the cost of our
algorithm when the i will fire should close the cost of the i th row
when fires was
and then i i briefly one of an algorithm that lets you do that
OK actually so so one reason to bring this up now is that if we
think about now we want to think about these as the change
one way to think about that
imagine a rule that says
i want you
to use
this past
but only
from day one hundred
three and
how about the rule
i want to use this path but only between is eighty and
ninety seven
so you can imagine if you've got and have
in your life at each time step now you instantiate and times he's square
if then rules each rules of the form
you this path from this time for that
so that makes sense so got this and different patterns like the gold medal down
to play this game for a long time like instantiate rule where one of the
rule says
in this time window
we should use that
and now this kind guarantee means that in every time window we are doing nearly
as well
as the best trout in that time window
to group them nicely on the disk so that we can answer range queries quickly
given all this it is about a hundred miles from pittsburgh
we want to do it quickly so how does this method works that best represented
from these methods in this class of methods is the so-called trees which are specifically
designed for the disk the characteristic of the disk is that it takes only seconds
to retrieve that this page therefore by based on the disk which is very very
very slow
compared to memory accesses so we want to make as few disk access as possible
and want to park our
cities or of time series or whatever we're interested in in a few days pages
so here's the method are trees stands for region actually so it can be used
to handle not only points are like cities i mentioned before images of stock prices
but even region so suppose we have lakes where represent every lake with its minimum
bounding rectangle
degenerate lakes are points and the method can complement points
so the method there are methods as we have all these lakes all these rectangles
the way to handle them so that we minimize the number of disk accesses to
group nearby
nearby lakes into parent nodes and then
group nearby parent node simple grandparent notes until we have one great-great-great grandfather right and
so this is what we have in mind this is what is x what is
actually happening on the these great so these lakes are nearby there are three algorithms
determined other nearby spatially close so we put them in the same this space so
this forty by to this page
it might be empty might have empty slots that's OK right as long as they
are not too many empty slots this another space another space so this is the
part in this page which has the minimum bounding rectangle but p one right about
and so on so this method can help us search
weekly because we can exploit the tree structure support the queries here this is a
favourite spot favourite CD and says find everything within ten miles away from pittsburgh right
and if we could be the have a would have square it doesn't really matter
what always have the main bottleneck to right how will this help us avoid there
are tree will help us avoid disk accesses
because we start from the road will start from the route ten the seconds to
fit the root
now we are scanning the mmm and we see that p one does not qualify
has no chance of containing anything related because this is the west coast right it's
oregon so no way to to be close to bits right so we don't do
this disk access and we don't know this disc access these are qualifying that that
this may or may not have something of interest so we go down only these
two disc access is of course disappointing example and there is no real system we
have many more levels three four five levels and see if we have a small
query the disc savings will be among those with access five and disk accesses as
opposed to one thousand disk access that somebody else the sequential scan would would
retrieve so this is the idea behind trees pizza twenty year-old method that has been
implemented in several systems it's available on the web so it's it's great and we
don't even have to to think about implementing it we can download code and it
will help us
monads multidimensional points and rectangles so the bottom the conclusion from this part of the
presentation is that we can have fast indexing through
o multimedia objects by extracting a few features
two three four numbers from every stocking months video video clip and then we can
use an off the shelf spatial access methods even the original our trees are good
there are huge there's a huge number of variations of our trees are plaster star
and so on
the survey by get a list of all but the map but this is the
general philosophy behind this method let's see
let's continue here and see how we extract features tried was said let's look at
some of the standard deviation how do we do that in a more systematic way
and here's the many outline the fourier transform we see the free transform singular value
decomposition and then
multidimensional scaling and fast
the discrete fourier transform is an excellent method for
time series
and actually the for images right the two-dimensional fourier transform can help us compress real
signals and we can use a few coefficients to describe the signals here is visual
proof visual hint that
the fourier transform is good for compressing signal so this is the dow jones industrial
average the index from four six to four six months
this is a real dataset and this is
the blue line is its approximation was the first to fourier coefficients
and we see that
we have
half a year so it's what what hundred fifty numbers being approximated very well by
three numbers the two or three coefficients quite because if we do the spectrum we
see this is the frequency of the free transform the amplitude of the next case
we see that the first coefficient is around one million the next is around hundred
thousand to fifty fifty thousand the first few coefficients give you all the information you
want maybe except for the tiny little deviations that we have so the first two
good for your revisions are usually good describe stock prices and so related signals
let's see the optimal method the singular value decomposition how many of you have heard
of this we did before
although everybody OK so it would be a quick review then
this is the optimal method for dimensionality reduction
footnote under the euclidean metric right which means that if we have the cloud of
so this could be
the first demons and we decide the first protein imagine we decided to extract features
area and the brightness right so this area of the first three months brightness of
the second of the first three months second months sediments also suppose we have all
the protein images
and usually them either and probably there is a correlation between area brightness SVD will
captured exactly the correlation
svd will give us the best line
well we can project these points this two-dimensional points so that the sum of squares
models so they use pcfgs they lexicalized all along the rules and basically they typically
which use generative models
and learn the parameters of the generative model by using the maximum likelihood with the
right that of smoothing
and more recently what will be and this is also what we will be looking
at here is how can use more discriminative learning methods to actually infer past reason
so to do
natural language parsing
OK and then i want really talk much about this but here is a reference
like paper that's now a couple of years old also if you think about recognition
of handwritten words
you have a situation where really
you know you you don't want to just segment the image and then predict individually
what the characters are that you see in these pixel images but rather you want
to take dependencies into account so probably on the word level at least so that
for instance what you see here
you know that you not mistakenly taken that from e let's say but rather for
c like courses right because this is more likely so you have a lot of
examples like that where there's a lot of local ambiguities you make a decision locally
right you might get the wrong result but you can help
you know you can use the context of what you see
to the right or to the left what you think you see rates are you
classify these characters
as the guiding know as additional help as providing additional evidence
four for recognizing these characters
and then finally i just like to mention mention this example here and like
a group of people that has worked in this system the freeman's group which has
to do with problems in computer vision where
traditionally people have often looked at things like object recognition
image annotation have really thought that i thought of that as like sort of an
independent problem so i thought i look for particular object in the image maybe a
search over certain windows and regions in the image and then i have some function
that tells me whether
you know there's enough evidence that we actually see and monitor somewhere in the image
let's say
and then the prediction would be OK this is an image that contains screen computer
monitors but what's interesting is also to actually
i understand that there are dependencies between the different things that we see in an
image so that you know this is the computer monitor maybe it makes it more
likely that there is a keyboard and mouse nearby
right so i should make these decisions independently but rather to predict whole scene graph
if you like all recognise objects in the context and hopefully that will help
with the recognition accuracy
OK sorry i have one more example
forgot about this one so this is also related to work with others
reference here and there is some work that was your hands has been doing over
the last couple of years and this is the problem where
the inputs from computational biology where the input is the representation of a protein
so here is the primary sequence so it will be
just a string of letters every letter will correspond to an amino acid and what
we would like to do is
in the case of secondary structure prediction we want to identify segments that correspond to
certain types of secondary protein structure like a certain type of the helix or sheet
or things like that so there is usually a very small
i forbid that biologists happy with and basically what we need to know is which
on this string actually corresponds to a particular structure and then also what people are
interested in and that if if you want to take a step further this to
the way he set up his model was to say it was it was very
much like an kind of i think inspired by this sort of model or or
the sort of model where he said so it's actually sort of like this only
the other way around if you you know it when you see something like this
this is the kind of phenomenon
right you see up visual event like this
this contact thing or imagine like hitting a baseball or cricket ball something things you
visual of annual security sound in your mind conjoined those two
similar kind of thing happens in ventriloquism right when you you see somebody's mouth moving
or the or not but the failures of this one when you see it badly
dubbed movie in foreign language right so your visual system is actually very good at
integrating or sort of deciding should i integrate this set of visual
events with this set of auditory events and you can cut our suggested modelling that
as a kind of bayesian model selection thing where where you're actually comparing hypotheses that
maybe there is one cause of both the visual auditory to maybe there's two different
causes so it's sort of sort of like this only slightly different graphical models
i think in this paper argues that
there was a slightly different way to i guess that there was a debate about
whether it's whether there is evidence that people are are doing sort of math model
selection or actual model averaging and i think that the data are still a little
bit ambiguous that's one of the things people are arguing about
one of the brothers really
you know so that's so that's so there's really active area of research on how
our however probability butions represented the brain and power some of these very basic kinds
of things like just you know computing posterior gaussians or or
about the the the most sophisticated it's got his car common filter like
how does the brain to common filtering people like alex to a
the external has worked on this peter diane there's there's a lot of people interested
in that but
for the most part it's only focused on the very simplest bayesian statistics like how
do you represent distribution all say in the population codes so how might a population
of neurons with different tunings represented distribution and how might you just combine the prior
and likelihood to get a posterior
people are starting to get to some slightly more interestingly structured models but
nobody's really tried and nobody really has a clue how to represent your even these
kinds of structure structure learning problems
i think that's
pretty clearly to me at least the single biggest challenge in computational neuroscience is that
problem it's coarser problem to bayesian computational methods but it's it's more generally a problem
of what cognitive science tells us is that human knowledge has all sorts of structure
to it
yet when we look at the brain
we don't know how any of that structure is represented right there's a very nice
fit between the kind of conventional machine learning toolkit of of learning functions in high
dimensional spaces and looking at the brain where there's you know high dimensional spaces in
the patterns of neural activation or synaptic strengths and so there's a nice fit between
that you know you can do a lot of computational neuroscience under the idea that
it's all about
you know regression in
high dimensional spaces but
i think cognitive science tells us pretty clearly we need much more structured representations and
we're machine learning and statistical AI has gone recently showing us tools for doing that
but bringing that into kind with the brain is complete history and i think you
know where we we have some very speculative ideas but it's
you know that's that's a that's the most important problem to work on i i
would urge you too much to work on it so far but i figure when
i run out of sort of things i can actually make progress on that's will
spend all my time thinking about
any other questions about the stuff
right so so let me let me go into the concept learning session obviously i
won't and we only have about fifteen minutes or so i want to try to
make it much stalinism i can i will finish the next time and talk a
little about intuitive theories
so this was the problem that i used to motivate this
learning learning category from examples of it's it's it's interesting because
as post here
it's not the the traditional way the classification has been presented in in statistics and
machine learning where again the usual in the textbook picture you start off with is
you get a bunch of positive examples in a bunch of negative examples and you
either learning discriminating function or you're doing something like a density based approach bayesian classifier
i'd like
so a lot more non development
and might think the time we were debugging
maybe one or two megabytes
then start to rapidly growing that is right
so it's much more complicated piece of but still
much more complicated pieces of what the but the
so we're going on
go hard hard because you you get a situation where
a person who
o reproduced above
does not have the technical knowledge to fix them
and the development company produced by the way beautifully on the other
is always
all these trains run however the development
because of the one system which is being tested very very carefully
there are some of the things we see which after helping
one of which is do a lot less hardware
when they started
every laptop and its own unique ships every laptop and its own unique videos
there were something like twenty
twenty five different video card manufacturers commonly encountered
a lot of time and then people like complex made their own disk controller
so one of these really helped is that
every laptop today
it's built about four standard designs
every PC today is built from again very small number the
microsoft has also been really really helpful
because microsoft introduced a thing called the windows hardware quality testing wh around
one of the things that mean in microsoft word
to get your driver into my windows live text saying
microsoft says this is OK it's good quality drive
it has to get all this really really expensive testing
one thing is this is done is finally persuaded hardware
do you stand
because there is a
roughly standard windows driver
example USB storage is a USB memory stick
everybody uses
because it is too expensive to write your own windows drivers for XP of vista
and the side effects but is that we have a USB storage drive they normally
working limits as well
the second thing we've got its distribution
most of the
end users we we deal with we deal with it directly
that means that there are thirty thousand people with an obscure configuration but
all banging on canonical door all the on our mailing list
rather than sitting on the kind the same why does my computer
and that's enormously help
we can make these distributions of also authorities about their
the acting is a
go between
between the non-technical users and technical community
there are some exceptions some of the groups are very technique
but for the majority of the distribution
really cheap
the the end user one
from the the kernel
given the kind of things they need
we also have a much better tools
very shortly
so we got better ways of helping users find
better ways also finding but before we should
the final thing which is really good
is of a lot of the users we have no bearing on ten
very large numbers the most you get help
even if you say can you build new
the entries of
not know it's
i have no idea how to build and you can see what do i do
can you send me some instruction
so we're gonna use as you would like to help we just have to figure
out how to make it possible for them to do