he insisted that the rule of very nice but they have
the information and knowledge is the rule effective predictive i needed to separate to extract
only a portion of all of that time is tool for having training using the
remaining for testing just to have some information and accuracy and we ought to have
in the future in the future somewhat more marked more different market just perform
experimental different morphology and to complete rejected
goodness me to do in this case what is important is that the
the idea is working well on articles working not one and the idea is that
the query language that is independent the specific i'm going to
using we can
OK take a we try and use the classification system and about the stacks of
the language is expected
the same
the assumption is that we work on a two d objects because i suppose that's
when you have three d points so we have to define some discrete also for
percent that
OK it's possible to simply and because in the special databases we the support to
represent the geometry at the level and to the dimension so now we use the
two d ed dimension but we can use the three d four d and so
on and then we have just change defined the some descriptive that are interesting for
a specific task because we can use the distance between points and one thousand times
are some other descriptive interesting for some
proximity but it's very close to distance concept because if you say the density density
so OK i'm supposing i'm
describing the term and the reason with drastically two points and the density of responsibility
in these regions i could not
yes OK but in this case we're are thinking the two classes
it's possible to extend in this actually didn't work with these because it works only
with the classification decision
and the typically works with the two d
in two dimensional data
but the framework is done in a way that is simple to be expanded to
all these opportunities
this is my on
on five
what kind of
does the task that briefly percent of the map interpretation by to you have presented
themselves with different landscape
and expert have define the four different landscape his system of find are catastrophic and
system of cliques
so it is used just to characterize these different regions or to extract the classification
to discriminate these different concepts and because of this is discovery of selected on the
side of that belong to the from the landscape and use association rules discovery frequent
that characterize the landscape so some are core core and solve all of the properties
of relations that characterize specific morphology for example as i said before we discriminate from
incendiary that call core the landscape in the ninety percent of
class and the
OK and other applications that we've done is not present you just because it's not
implement integrated but we have dismantled the for clustering score so that works on structured
data from
the thomas represented the graph so you have an neighbouring the relation and you can
cluster to be only objects that are connected in that directly connected in the graph
in the case of the genes
so the idea is to combine clustering of with graph partitioning just to have a
group of object genes that correspond to the graph of the structure and in that
case we have used the the
four class
recognise some class of we can use the same data in this application and we
discover what is it to become original form of cultivation of the olive tree and
and monterrey and on measure for the one and with these data then with these
are two are able to extract the jonson that are characterized by only three and
the most forward see that there is characterising the physical situation so the presence of
font of the close of
two to pass to science
the colliery that opened we walked in song and so we have using these other
applications but to no no
the other application
because of the classification
three of
he also very so much
is consistent with being due to a cosmoillogical constant in other words is W equal
to minus one and constant with time are we just measuring just measuring Einstein's cosmological
constant if the acceleration is not due to a cosmological constant then we can probe
the underlying dynamics by  measuring as well as possible the time evolution of the dark energy
in other words determine W of Z now aware of the possibility that the
answer may be on the left hand side of the Einstein equations we have to
search for a possible failure of general relativity through the comparison of the effect of
dark energy on cosmic expansion with the effect of dark energy on the growth of
cosmological structures like galaxies and galaxy clusters this is hard to quantify but I'll talk
a little bit about it so although our only handle at present on dark energy
is how it affects the cosmological the expansion rate of the universe there is
a rich program that one can imagine for observational astronomy so if you want to
know how dark energy affects the expansion rate as a function of redshift then you
have observations of cosmological parameters that's sensitive to the expansion rate as a function of
redshift and these parameters include the luminosity distance the angular diameter distance and how the
volume of the universe changes with redshift and in turn the luminosity distance as a
function of redshift can be determined by looking at supernovae or clusters of galaxies the
angular diameter distance as a function of redshift can be measured by baryon acoustic
oscillations I'll talk about this  strong lensing I won't talk about because I think
at present it's a not as promising as weak lensing which I will talk about and
the volume expansion as a function of redshift can be determined by clusters and strong
lensing the growth of structure in the universe is an important measuremeant to
make in linear perturbation theory there is an equation for how density perturbations grow
with time this is the Fourier component K of Delta rho over rho and
this is the equation in the Friedmann model and you see the expansion rate enters
so if we can determine the growth rate of structure in the universe it gives
us information on the expansion rate of the universe also this is an important
measurement because if  somehow gravity is modified then there might be a source for the
growth of structure from this new theory of gravity that's not present in Einstein's theory of
gravity and the growth of structure in the universe can be determined by looking at
clusters of galaxies weak lensing looking at the power spectrum how that evolves with redshift
finally again this is harder to quantify testing gravity and looking in the solar
system millimeter scale everyone knows next year you'll be producing Kaluza-Klein gravitons here
at CERN  you know that would tell us something about gravity so maybe at accelerators
or again looking at the power spectrum so there are many types of observations you can
make to determine as well as possible the expansion rate of the universe as a
function of redshift and to see whether it's consistent with a cosmological constant or there's some dynamics
in probe as well as possible the dynamics and also look to see if
somehow gravity is our theory of gravity is incomplete so let me talk about a
couple of these I'd like to talk about supernovae baryon ac acoustic oscillations clusters and
lensing so look using type one A supernovae it's standard candles is a well developed
and practiced technique one measures the redshift of the supernovae or the host galaxy of the
supernovae and the intensity of the  light as a function of time the light
curve  because you ha to make it a standard candle you have to adjust
for the width of the light curve you also have to take a spectrum of a
galaxy to see whether it is a type one A supernovae or a type two B
type two seven you know these different types of supernovae there are
as I mentioned systematics possibility of dust evolution intrinsic luminosity dispersion magnetic fields et cetera the
explosion may not be spherical if you're ever in an astrophysics talk and you wanna ask a
question say what about magnetic fields what about  nonspherical possibilities and what about
dust  what about evolution those are good questions no matter what the seminar is about
the people who do supernovae  make a pretty convincing argument that these systematic uncertainties are
under control and again as you get more and more and more data your system
you get better handles on your systematic uncertainty there is a lot of  information
per supernovae I've lost count of how many high  redshift supernovae we've observed dozens maybe
close to a hundred each one of them gives us a little piece of
information the present procedure is to discover a supernovae by a wide area survey of
the sky looking for changes this is usually done today the state of the art
is with four meter class telescopes then the hard part of this is to arrange time
on eight meter class telescopes to do the follow-up spectroscopy this is very time-consuming to
discover the supernovae you can look at a wide area of the sky and see things
exploding but to do the spectroscopy you focus in one at a time so one
of the questions that people  are asking is do yous really need the spectroscopy
to determine the redshift of the supernovae well enough in a couple of months
they'll be casting the mirror for a telescope known as LSST the large synoptic survey telescope
which will be an eight meter class telescope with a very large field of view
that will basically take am a motion  picture a movie of the sky every night
this telescope will discover in ten years  millions of supernovae however they won't
be able to do the spectrum they won't be able to tell whether it's type
one A or not unless they use photometric redshifts the traditional way to determine the redshift
of an object is to take a spectrum and this is a sort of just a simple graph an
illustration from I don't know where I stole it from probably a textbook that as the
object is farther and farther away the spectrum is shifted to the red and you see where
particular ignition or  absorption lines are in the spectra and then you determine the redshift however today
there are images of the sky taking with taken with multicolor photometry  so there are images
the probability that the next point will fall in this particular being located at x
that's really an enormous this as a function of x
this is the probability that the next point will fall in a bin size at plus minus
a bin of with x located at x approximately right
so if i multiply them by the total number of data points we got
which is an
that's really expected
and in
and that's is equal to
on z
it's a mindset lambda
we want some way of turning this
expected number which will relate to the actual measured number into some sort of straight line away
the thing that we are measuring his x that's
variable that
changes us moving around
and there's a divided by lambda
and it's got an exponential that's horrible but with this we know how to get
an exponential to take the log
so we can have the log
the expected
with with delta x
log expected count is
all hand on z which is some sort of constant
that's now a straight line
the incentive something rather
and the slope of
minus one lambda
all right
if you've been subjected to the physics
training that says
and this is a high school thing to do is and take the data monday
around get a straight line because then everyone knows how to fit straight lines there
i do number one was
put the data into bins and get a histogram
it doesn't solve the problem we now need to do something with the histogram things
we could do with a histogram notice i've done twice the fact beans one sided
with indians the second time to just emphasize the answer we end up with may
depend on the size of events
is e
physics education i take the logo histogram then fit a straight line
okay so the suggestion is
take the actual data
the thing that is true is that the log the expected number is some constant minus x lambda
what we're i'm going to take the actual data
and be
we take the logo at
and plot
against x
what what what what
and with them going fit a straight line
and when as a lot of extra questions getting raised by this approach when we say
straight line how do we fit a straight line to just use the straight line
fitting thing that comes on the computer that's probably what most people would leap to
but something that could very easily be the case
is when you define your bins
if you define them before you actually get the data which is sort of correct
related to classical statistics he shouldn't
change or estimator after looking at the data
it could well be the case that one might have zero count and it
now when you take the log zero
you can have not been
log zero you have infinitely
negative value
to put into your straight line fitting methods
it all sounds pretty good and it looks fairly good if you get lucky
up on the screen here
with nice fat beans and lots of data you can see a straight line is definitely going
it's going to give you the right sort of answer
but i have a universal methods for answering problems
so just used to be
so here's another suggestion
take the data
put it in only two bins
andover gonna fix the beans beforehand or will we sort adaptively move the boundary between the bins
what do you want to do is make sure we get some points in each bin you
and then do something that's a nice idea
so i did this is this slide in number three
if it straight line
i don't know before is just used to be be smart about where you put the been boundary
case if you've got three points
what are two beams can be we could put
well here or here or here or here there is actually quite a lot of
latitude wavelet been boundary and really they have to in one then one another one
one and two in the other so
it's a nice idea probably
you there's probably something in it
but it's still got pitfalls namely if you actually end up with only three data points you kinda struggle
because there's a lot of bitterness now by the way put your been boundaries
are there any other suggestions we've sort
perhaps exhausted a whole bunch of different ways
making been putting the data into bins
and then doing something with those histograms
another ideas
okay so
and other suggestion sufficient number five
could we look at
the cumulative distribution
so uh
residing five
if i give you some data
like that
you can deduce from the cumulative distribution which is
one the
so that's the cumulative
distribution function from the data
and for any particular hypothesis
it says what lambda is which defines the probability density
there is also a senior
four about five lambda
which will be
something like that
and now we've got a thing has little steps in it where the data points have become alkali smooth
and we could repeat now
the conversation we had a moment ago where we say all let's have a measure
of how close this is this
numbers with uncertainty
then and you do so in sort of logic logically consistent way you discover that
the rules which the those numbers perhaps satisfy
i just the sum and product rule of probability
so you might as well call the probabilities you can make them add up to
ten instead of adding up to one or something but that would be a trivial
differences convention so
so the first thing to say is that if you're going to use continuous continuous
numbers represent uncertainty using to continue in in the consistent most consistent way then you
lead automatically to probability theory
which is think is really we using problem the traditional view of probabilities is frequencies
of a random recurrent events frequencies of a coin toss but in a bayesian framework
we using probabilities much more general way to quantify uncertainty even for events which are
not repeatable you what's the probability that the the moon once orbited the sun instead
of the full something you can't do that experiment a million times making the fraction
of means that all that is perfectly OK to talk about probabilities
i think the question actually asked was but slightly different which is i've got a
machine that produces these continuous course how do i turn them into probabilities one
one possible answer john platt some years ago took support vector machines which was trained
which produces a continuous output before the threshold and he treated that is the input
to a two parameter logistic sigmoid so i think we had yesterday so
you've got x you're
have put your support vector machine which was not designed to produce probabilities and he
took get two parameter models and then put that through a logistic sigmoid that's the
function which
so that that maps the real axis onto zero why
took a data set of values of x and labels and worked out the values
of a and b by minimizing a sort of cross entropy measure the label
so effectively what he's doing is retrofitting a logistic sigmoid to this
school function which is something that
you know bigger if you're more likely to be in one class small if you
want to be the class but
but it sort of probability so that that's one way of doing it
but people than other things since then i
i guess this
OK so
yes any other questions questions
he was
OK so the question so what if one of these factors is much more important
than the other so the question is what do you mean by more important so
i guess what you mean by more important is let's say the image data is
very very reliable and really you know most of the time we get to run
the blood data is of pretty useless it's sort of it it sort of sums
is a little bit correlates cancer is and i think that's what you mean by
more important right in that case the in the model should do the right thing
because the because the blood data is very uncertain it she gives posterior probabilities which
is sort of you know sometimes the point six sometimes the point four is always
quite uncertain whereas the image data is really coming out you know point nine nine
nine point and and
the sum product rule probability would do the right thing for you in that case
under that assumption of independence
assume that independence used in the middle once you assume that the graph
and everything else is just the sum and product of the probabilities doing the right
a small questions over
here i think whether
what going to do now is is change topic slightly and talk a little bit
about some standard distributions i'm sure all very familiar to you but look at them
in terms of things like exponential families conjugate priors and so on and these are
important topics that are gonna play an important role throughout the summer school and if
you're not familiar with the the it's useful to get familiar early on because i'm
sure you'll encounter than lots of other lectures
so let's just start with a very simple
four according to have a coin which reflected its heads we get a one if
its tails zero and
we can assign a probability that the
coin lands heads the probability of x equals one is given by parameter mu so
probably vesicles there is just one minus mu
x y and z the and and some of the valuable state of the labels
million you and the men that means that f becomes a function of human genes
and then we can ask ourselves how sensitive is
to the value of EUR and whether we can so that's sort of the chain
of all is something like this and let me explain to you again where this
comes from so
what this quantity means is if we change you the constant what happens to the
value of well why would the value of f change in the 1st place when
F is just a function of x y z and the ability of you whether
it changes because x y and z depend on your success we have to figure
out how quickly x y and z change from the change
well how quickly to do that is precisely from experts you of white offered you
thought the these are the rate of change of x y z when we change
and now
when we change x y and z
that causes f to change how much has exchange well social and next tells us
how quickly as changes in rate of change of X so
that's the change in goes just by the fact that the exchanges when you change
but when and why also changes
why changes this state and that causes to change at that and z changes as
well and that causes have to change advances and the effects of together
does that make sense
and so in particular we can use the chain will to do changes of valuables
if we have a say a function defined in terms of poor coordinates on the
and would like to switch it to rectangular coordinates x and y then we can
use the chain of almost all the little buffer derivatives
and finally the last but not least we've seen how to deal with non independent
valuables so when all valuable x y z related by some equations
so 1 way we can deal with this is to sorry for 1 of the
variables and get go back to independent variables but we can't always do that of
course on the exam you can be sure that I will make sure that you
cannot solve for I would want to win because that would be too easy
um so that when we have to keep all of them but handle you know
take take into account relations with seems to
useful methods 1 of them is to find the minimum of a maximum of a
function when ribosomal them and that's the method of Lagrange multipliers
but because the problem
the the
so we're going to find the minimum or maximum of function that subject to the
constraint g equals
constant what we find that equations that saying that the variance of that is actually
proportional to the gradient of G
so there's a new variable here lambda the multiplier
you know for example if an injury was here I had functions of the variables
so this becomes equations that subjects than that of X X and Y equals land
that is why we have so this is equal and adjacent if and when we
plug in the formulas for F and G well we're left with the equations involving
before bibles x y z and under what song where we don't have actually fallen
dependent variables we also have these relations
genes equals with another constraint was waiting x y and z together
so that we can find and development situations
something easy and sometimes it's very hot or even impossible
so but here on the test I haven't decided yet but it could well be
that the problem of the ones with the players will just ask you to avoid
the equations not the sort of case so thank you cannot missing anything but just
you know before you start solving check whatever problem to to sort moment if it
doesn't then I probably wouldn't come
yeah yeah
of the system
yeah so and so and other topic that we so just yesterday is constrained partial
and I guess I have to be explained a little bit becomes
limitation it's also limitation of ideas and so forth
so so this i think gives you some fluid of what the scope of the
problem is it's been studied for
quite some number of years in the human visual perception and in computer vision
which dates back this forty years
so i'll take you through some examples of how we think about this and some
concrete results
so here is one way of thinking about some image
i don't know what it is
but i have my
i have a set of examples
and the the label elephant would fly except exeter
so what i do is i tried to do
correspondence and matching between query image and the exemplars
and a value to similarity score and let's see the similarity score turns out to
be this
highest of the difference to be the smallest between these two
and then business that's my
if you want to think of what to put it in machine learning framework
this is the nearest neighbour classifier with the set in distance function
and there is something to be said about nearest neighbour classifier asymptotically
given enough examples
i nearest neighbour classifier gets to within a factor of two of optimal bayesian classifier
all the offences scheme that tried to remember the humble nearest neighbour classifier
OK so
if you notice i should you these views but you might ask the objects actually
three dimensional
and current thinking on this is
mean by the problem we we know how to sort two d two to the
matching problems so we deal with three d objects by distorting multiple two d views
so you have
so here is this is anything box and what we do is we want to
store using a three d model but we can store multiple two d views
and here are the multiple two d views
and the matching machinery
has to be robust
working even though you have a small number of two d views
and the answer that you can actually do that there is an experiment based on
some work we have done a few years ago
that we needed to sort this on the y axis is the eighteen x is
the number of examples you stored
so these are different similarity functions and this is obviously the fanciest one that we
proposed and even with four prototypes but object we could get an error rate of
two three percent
so pretty smart
this general idea if you will selective use works
that you can see president three d objects multiple two d views
and this makes life much easier because natural objects we don't necessarily have the models
four industrial parks we do
but industrial parts of a small fraction of what we are interested in the you
just work with images life is better
that's got infected
OK so how do we solve the correspondence problem how do we match
in different parts of an object to each other
so i'm going to go through some of the ideas talk about deformable template matching
and how we use machine learning for finding discriminative features
OK so
so the correspondence problem
can be described this way
so here had two
two versions of the letter a
what we are somehow able to do humans intuitively is to say that these two
some of corresponding points and is the different point on the ship
and these are not identical shapes
but so we still have the notion of correspondence and this in other settings where
mean that from one image to the people the noise can be matched to the
people than those in the image and so on
how do we do this
this the secret is that we try to come up with some descriptive if i
just look at that point
the point is the same
but if i tried to characterise
some more extended neighbourhood
i can
distinguish between the different points in the ship
so here's one idea at this point and newport
i see is this kind of dark wood like that
around that point and you count the number of
of sort of these these image as points in each of these beings
so we can't hear you get four point b points and you get
and so on and so forth
so that's what it is doing is around point it is characterising the distribution of
the points
and because this the shape context
so here is the point and then so we've got
these different bins so that they have been added in space so they have different
angular orientation and the different distances
this is the distance at the angular distance so you get you get so we
had this element of sixteen bins then
and now we've got columns here so that means more columns
so this is what the pattern around this point looks like so most of the
action is below and to the right which is captured here
consider this point
what happens here
i know that the points distributed equally all around you so therefore the distribution with
respect to theta is much more uniform
so you get this distribution
now what is the case with these guys
unlike the original shape
these are now fixed length vectors
because we have
we have sixty bins if i go back
and a certain number of
so if i count one two three four five and that these i get sixty
so now i've got sixteen
i preferred is because it is guaranteed to find the smallest number of sparse signals
but NOL one is this is pretty good in
there are lots of algorithms on this one you know the idea of
this compressive sensing and so on maybe five ten years old because you see publications
really critical ones appearing but their underlying algorithms that contribute to recovery have been there
for a long time for example the matching pursuit algorithm is something that can be
tried for this has been around since the early nineties malakand zhang and variation of
the the matching pursuit algorithm came in the context of the wavelet
decomposition ideas and if you introduce intermediate step but orthogonalise in the matching pursuit algorithm
then you have the things again
from the early nineties but the thing that i'm going to talk about today is
very briefly is is the
the basis pursuit algorithm one which returned ashore in the previous slide and if you
assume a nice free signals then you know you just saw this as a linear
programming problem you minimize the nom l one norm of x that you're trying to
recover is subject to the condition that you have compressive measurements y which is a
fee transforming x but in general we we have all kinds of errors that contaminate
the compressive measurements because there
collected by a real sense are so you can assume
no the explorers and and then you really do as as what is known as
the basis pursuit denoising algorithm
where you have to somehow figure out what the epsilon is to bound the noise
could be really and so forth so you you again minimise the the l one
norm of the signal you are trying to
given the condition that they had to arm area is less than some so there
there's so much return on this and i will
you know i encourage you to
read several papers by professor candies by professor brian wagner and the papers are just
coming like crazy right this is so well
to kind of read all of them to get a good view of what the
field is about
that's a computer vision researcher machine vision researcher
OK so what does it mean what this compressive sensing
going to do for us
because we are always looking for
good ideas from other fields computer vision and you know we
we like
optimisation approaches we like manifolds like particle filters and so forth so
most of these things can come from from left to right center field and always
eagerly looking for new approaches for solving imposed a condition problems
OK and we can all make a
we cannot you know very easily to an optimisation because if you go back to
the mid eighties regularisation can approach for solving will post early vision problems computing optical
flow shape from shading stereo and all of them nicely made as any other two
problem and we have the smoothness criterion and even to the ground equations and came
up with iterative equations for solving them are
is on solvers and so forth so we have learned this in our classes
OK so i have to do is replace the l two and l one
and then see what you know so we can at least the entry for us
it's not totally
alien concept right replacing l two with l one and having the appropriate constraints and
see what it buys so computer vision researchers
you are a uniquely
in opposition to look into this but that's again what i'll argue as argued areas
it's too tempting
right to do that and should be and what we gain by doing that this
is what would like to express now the folks at rice university built something of
a single pixel camera and i didn't put those views here because again the copyright
issue so i was very careful as what slides i'm going to use from others
and so on so you can surely papers on that it's very interesting device that
gets to the compressive measurements directly
OK by introducing
randomisation in the process of acquiring the electron i'll show is similar setup that is
going my stories are using for compressive sensing of reflectance fields that are useful and
graphics my first entry into this field was through
doctor jo r and we kind of look back ground subtraction problem you know when
you have a stationary camera moving camera and objects are moving OK
background subtraction is the first thing you do especially for a stationary camera case to
look at
things that are moving to separate them from non-living backgrounds but the first thought that
occurred to us is that the
background is really
a lot and the foreground are very small and sparks in terms of spatial extent
so when compressive sensing ideas be useful for coming up with the background background subtraction
and we are forced to ECCV two thousand eight and then we came
the next another interesting development is the face recognition paper from berkeley university of illinois
where they used to sparsity as as a way of coming up with the face
recognition algorithms that we know that has the best results now for the bayesian set
and we looked at it and we said OK maybe we can do it for
now i'll tell you why
we motivated for doing out is not faces and then again we came across the
very beautiful paper by appears to this is from press around with his group at
and i think this is a great example of compressive sensing because
acquiring reflectance fields is part of the sense right and
if you
look at the demands on how much data you to collect completely characterize reflectance fields
and we know that maybe the reflectance fields themselves out sparse then it looks like
a very nice out the problem to study in the context of compressive sensing and
so on
object with mass and two so twice the mass
so that should be
the square root
of and two divided by n one
times ten times
the period
one of n one
so i can make
a prediction because this is the square root of two
and i know what this is
so i'll take my calculator
and i'll take the square root of two
and multiply that by
so let's take
fifteen point one five
so that comes out to be twenty one point four two
twenty one point four two is not clear that this too is meaningful
and i'll come to sixty four dollar question what is the uncertainty is the prediction
and this now becomes a little tricky
so what i'm telling you now make confusion a bit it's not meant to be
but i really wanna hold you responsible for it
you may not think
that the uncertainty in this measurement
it follows from the uncertainty in this which is through which is about o point
six percent
and from the uncertainty in this
this has about uncertainty
o point six percent
i got a low because i measure ten oscillations you see is only one out
of four hundred fifty which is low
what you may think that the uncertainty in there
he calls this character
of three hundred seventy two plus and minus one
divided by hundred eighty six thousand ninety one
and now you may argue and it's completely reasonable that you would argue that way
you would say well this is roughly
a quarter of a percent guarantee under the square root
and this is roughly
half percent error one out of two hundred is about half
so you would add up to two hours quarter plus half that's about o point
and because of the square root
that becomes o point three five percent and that's wrong
and the reason why that's completely wrong
it has to do with the fact
these two errors coupled to each other
the hundred eighty six including the three seventy two
the best way i can show you this suppose i measured and one divided by
n one
which would be hundred and eighty six plus or minus one divided by a hundred
and eighty six plus minus one
that number is one with a hundred heroes
this number is one you have to master one object divided by the same object
rather if you would say otherwise however percent error and this is the half percent
there you would say to ratio has an error of one percent and that's not
the case
so i will not bother you was that i will not hold you responsible for
that but it turns out that if you
do it correctly you take the error of this into account of about o point
six percent
that the error in this
ratio is really much less than point two percent you can almost forget about
i will allow generously for one percent error in the final answer
and so
i stick to my prediction
that the ten
double the mass
it's going to be
like this
and now we're going to get the observation
and two
has double the mass
and that of course always has my
uncertainty of my reaction time nothing i can do about that
we will compare these two numbers
so i'll put it in the autumn as on top of it
in here
taken together so that they won't fall off
there we go
o nobody that correctly crowd of two
times fifteen point one five
well given
amplitude something like thirty maybe thirty five centimetres
there we go
much slower you see that
natural perception action
OK so first now let me give you some very basic intuition about unlabelled souls
suppose they just give you to label points red and blue
i think most people would agree
and that's
i i can ask you what the most natural classifier so you have some unlabeled
point how would you could even the new point how would you classify it you
most people would agree that something like this seems very natural evolution b here
red should be given this still point
that of course
you know it can be something quite different but this is the most simple thing
there is a lot of
what can machine learning
you know why this is in some sense optimal classifier
i tell you something that i showed you the thing to point
but i tell you well actually all possible points
lie on this two circles i don't tell you anything about the clusters it's still
a two class problem but i don't any possible points rely on one of the
now i hope you agree that cutting it like this
perhaps is less
then in this case
something like that is more reasonable
knowing something about
somehow what the data looks like about the geometry of the data
changes our perception
of which point i similarly somehow things that points in each of the circle you
are more similar to each other than to points
the circles
so that one intuition and i'm going to repeat this a few times
OK so
similar situation
two red points to blue points
the black point i think most people would agree to build classified as blue
so suppose now i tell you that actually all data licences can
now as you can see well
i think it's pretty self pretty evident that this should be read
so what does it mean that means that the shape of of the curve tells
us something about where
the data is likely to be
so actually
in some sense you can say that even though the two points
very close
this the black and blue points
there somehow not close in the right sense of being close they're not closed
along the tongue and somehow along the curve is what counts
john it is important and this is
what one may call in manifold assumption thing that what counts how you should really
measure distances
you should really measured distances
the space of your data
OK so now there is another assumption which can be made
which may be called cluster assumption and this is the following so again suppose i
give you this points and i give you a black point i asked to classify
the black point you might say the bike point is probably blue
that's looks reasonable
now i tell you case all data lies on this
this is a so a uniform distribution on this it doesn't have to be
uniform you can imagine that somehow the density is high here high and low in
between but for
it's hard to make a picture of that this
so now you i hope you would agree that somehow there is this big clusters
this sort of connected but not very strongly and this
that belong to the same cluster
so now you've probably seen
it looks a little more likely that ran
it should be
the black should be classified as red
so the somehow the important intuitions
which need to be formalized in which will be to some degree formalized in stuff
OK so
not just that i actually didn't say anything about the data i just said i
mean about the actual data i just said something about the space of all possible
but in reality of course we don't know what the things would have the space
of all
digits just for example all handwritten digits we have no idea what the shape of
the spaces
i mean it's some sort of complicated space and whatever eight hundred dimensional space i
think is like
you know resolution maybe like twenty five i twenty five whatever
we actually don't know what it we just have some examples sampled from that space
so really what we want to somehow
to learn something about the structure of the manifold as part was saying in the
previous that we want to learn it from unlabelled data
as you can see if you have one labelled data you can see that
this is of course it example but it gives some idea that we can learn
some geometric features
and we can hopefully you this to improve our inference procedures
so this is really this
the flight perhaps provide some intuition for
OK so now i will be a little bit
more formal so what i would like to say here is that what is a
manifold assumption
it's somehow the functions of interest so we would like to look at functions of
you know function is something like the probability that a given point is blue
versus probability that this point is right so this is somehow function of interest
and it's measure often
represented by sigma squared
that's the greek letters sigma
lower case words
or especially when talking about
estimates of the variance we we sometimes they squared
or we say standard deviation
the variance
the standard deviation is the square root of the variance
population variance
variance of some random variable x
it is defined
the summation i equals
one two infinity
the probability
that x
equals x by
times that survive
all right so
news of x
that news of x is the
i mean we just defined x
this the expectation of vectors are also erected
so it's the it's the probability weighted average of the square deviations from the mean
if it moves like
either way from the mean
this number squared is a big number more
x moves
the bigger the variances
there's also another variance measure
which we use
in the sample
also there sometimes
so this is sigma squared
there's also another variance measure
which is for the sample
and we have n observations
it the
the summation
i equals one
x bar
all over
there should be squared
OK so that's the
sample variance
some people will divide by n minus one
i suppose i would accept either answer
i'm just keeping it simple here
they divided by n minus one to make it an unbiased estimator of the
population variance but
i'm just going to show it in a simple way here so you see what
it is
it's a measure of how much text deviates from the mean but it is it
squared it waits big deviations law
because the square of big numbers really big so
that's the difference
all right so that complete
central tendency
and dispersion
we're going to be talking about these in finance as regards returns because
generally the idea here is that we want high returns so we want to high
expected value returns
but we don't like variance so expected value is good
variance is bad because
that's risk that's uncertainty west but this whole
theories about how to avoid how to get a lot of expected return
without getting a lot of risk
another concept that's very basic here
the covariance
and covariance
is a measure of how much two variables move
the covariance
it is
we call it
now we have two random variables of the covariance
of x and y
i just talked about it in the sample term
it's the summation
i equals one
of x
minus bar
minus white bar
to twenty million dollars probably something like that but the probability of getting this monies very
low let's say that we are working data science
and it is a very decent probability of making this mining i'd say ten percent as the probability actually
for a company that doesn't exist right so that they when we optimise this function and
upward like you know something might to
two million dollars something like that
and look on our site other side all base that this function as basically
optimized for the probability of success
and probably getting lower reward that's what idea that when the joined plays number right
four hundred something
the company was very successful at that point so the the
the probability of success was pretty high
the op leaf was relatively low right let's say that well a person can make like a million dollars
if a person joins a very successful company like that
and probably
successes pretty much one hundred percent by the way that the real stories that
i talked to
to executives at length dna i had a chance to talk with them both damn
left google award for when the and i asked pretty much the same question to both of
guys how could we are you leave very strong successful company and
and join a start-up like when the it's probably were risky
and they gave me exactly the same ansari was very surprised you know what run
there's just no worries it'll
so if we look here and here and up with like knows founding a company our
objective function gives like about to me and
add the areas like you know a data scientist on a very successful companies let the
objective function gives us
one million something like that what i'm saying is the kind of goes down
if you are same number why i'm
this you know early-stage share a start-up
the risk the probability of like getting your money
is the same ten percent as if you are a founder right but your reward is
much lower like substantially lower probably tenax low or something like that
if you join
relatively me established company if you're number fifty something like that dan your probability of success
is not one hundred percent right but your reward steel like on number fifty number two hundred is is
kind of see
so solemn you think or
the estimate about two million boxes the expected value as data science
founder for data science start yeah yeah not ok you know sort of the probability of
the value given success if you want to say that the data science guide three
or a person three person team
ok so i think run may have done more carefully
i have here here's a here's my off
high-level react that analysis
if that were true
given salaries are familiar with for a data scientist these days
in that equation would say you should never leave your job
my guess is it's
this is a new area that we know is in high demand
that we know is is going to be crucial for quite
and and
upcoming times so this is not like your average
start-up addressing
an average you know consumer play in a very crowded space
this is a
great space here right so your chances of getting competition there's so many barriers that have
to do with knowledge have to do with intuition
all of that that's working for you and mices my suspicion
a different way to condition his numbers
data science and big data
i would imagine that it turns to be higher might might have guessed actually totally yeah
but i don't i guess is
you could easily stand to make
ten million dollars in five years
so that would be like yeah i think that it's a definite the ballpark were
not too far away right yeah i wanted to yeah yeah yeah yeah what i wanted
to say i was talking about appli right it's a together with the seller after also
it's like a little bit of
i guess thing here right then forget it i'm not going to check eat thousand foot
going to look for a startup yeah i
take it back
the health insurance
if you like
expectation that stupid move
well because ensures making money so expectations you know that you will spend and
less on your health care
and if you paid insurance otherwise it would be out of business
my point is
very person perspective this male the true
maybe it's kind of the female but
so i'm running the single mom get with nine your own
and his great expectations could make
ten million dollars
i still need to feed and mom and i can afford looking
fourteen now as de side that may fail
i think you're right that
the downside potential actually isn't as
baker it's just last time
the good news is if it was yeah well
yes men other things you can do
it's not like step without a job for the rest of your life right so
the risk
is not bad that ches the point when i entered the game
different expectations on life that came with sometimes for myself some
khushi salary that i knew i would be easily making gladdens i negotiated might terms
joining a
twenty people started saying
equities great
could you
i n for somewhat more security and
that's actually an argument you can have it's not like you have to look for free and look for the big
bang waste in between
ok so i think we
we want our we've moved to one of the we are there is this a
couple questions that seem to have gotten a lot of up votes
a couple down books to
one to take a couple questions and yes yes yes i think it's
time to
go to first when not so from china and the souls
or the ground for close to the first
so this question for everyone much actually put it to someone in our
so you
had to know when an idea start-up or really
so i can
you know if it's if it's personal
you're doing it
it's a completely different objective function and if
you're an investor
so use these days i do this a lot i evaluate
probably hundreds of years to try to the site
how many tens are we going to invest in
my yeah and that are there are many many many many factors right
it's not
my first answer to that question is it's not the idea
it's the team
so where it's it's team team team because that idea most likely is going to change and change multiple times
so and by the way i c team
the interesting thing is in the beginning you graph could be rather pick the white
grow for example you say all
this must be cobbled doesn't cover what it is useless or not frequent you can
drop it was dropped those car belongs the genes or something you find the remaining
part actually may not set by this
that's apart or night start being becoming effective in cutting
that's why in the middle can cut
so this is the way you know you can recognise you can cut the URL
but sometimes it's very shaky week or this pattern inseparable they give you a conference
like this
the vertex connectivity of the pattern is greater than ten
OK but it's conductivity means
the verdict
how many things they connect
but why are you doing the graph pattern mining find graph
OK what is the kind of lifting you have to go back to your data
set to see how they connect with the remaining parts so you can not separate
your pattern
from your grasp percent
so in that sense
if you want to evaluate this pattern
suppose this is spending money that you had to put this pattern back to
back to black
that simply says you can while you're thinking you're doing pattern mining grow growing this
pattern you're never forget this pattern from witchcraft and how they connect with the remaining
that part called pattern inseparable OK
and why you mining find this pattern inseparable means you go back to original graph
you find the constraints can still
can you not be satisfiable
then you can
cut the grass
so that's the local pattern inseparable and with this
actually we
work out
the most commonly used
these you know that different constraints
OK then we check up check about whether it's astronomy
pattern on and a weak pattern antimonotone always pattern inseparable
and pattern separable the good thing good news you look at how many things are
yes because you go yes you and i think of
OK for patterns in several the anti monotone
everybody say yes OK simply to put back you if you know is not a
useful can cut OK some you can see
some part of the yes some part of this now
OK that that means the nice is not always usable but least you can use
the last one two your code can do a lot of interesting things OK
so that's a lot of course we have experiment results our don't have time to
discuss it
i'll go through the index part OK
so actually when we did this
graph pattern mining
we talked to some
chemists and biochemists OK lots of people in our campus
and then the chemists not only want not just like like appear you know like
you coming to work together with the chemists
they said
you do graph mining five u
we would like to do mining we reached that stage yet
what we want his search
OK we get a huge
graph database because the most chemical compound babies
for example i work with one
chemists here is working on those biochemist for the antibiotics
anybody see they know the antibiotics by exposure to human some people abuse it finally
the those germs the they develop some resistance you have the developing new antibiotics
but it's
outside in nature there are lots of chemical compounds but you want to search
your pages those in that in those queries can actually come matching your site
giving a deeper experience the user and more traffic to the publisher
we've seen a lot of work by publishers doing whatever they can to get themselves
more traffic so when you have these kind of natural resources and driving traffic
publishers will be very interested in doing whatever they can
another interesting twist here is that the systems could give publishers
feedback on improving their content so you could say
instead of having to optimize your pages for packing in a bunch of keywords to
gain the search engine that publishers could be told
actually this this is this concept on your page is not clearly expressed by to
express more clearly and then do a better job of matching users
and as the the ecosystem of course is users
there's a fair amount of work on getting users to play games and to create
and improve resources several papers here in this conference on that topic
in addition to these things as they become useful tools for the users the users
can provide feedback to get better search powerset is already experimenting with ideas where users
can give results thumbs-up or thumbs-down
and and then if it's a thumbs-down dive in and actually express which of the
ontological resources you know may or may not have been the right ones or other
kinds of things like that
in addition as some users might want to create ontologies lightweight little simple ontologies to
their own search experience better
they could potentially refer to
their their family members by the rules and then use use that kind of all
the world for the role to matching their family members
these kinds of things similar a group of people to do is to do the
same kind of thing
the third element of this community would be developers there's been a lot of work
lately in vertical search which is people making very specialised search engines by putting a
lot of their knowledge into the system i think it's possible that you can move
this kind of level of abstraction so that the vertical search specialists can really just
packages are knowledge by means of overthrowing to the ontology
and make that ontology available for use in the context of the general search engines
so the
so i guess is the fourth part of the community that talk about which are
advertisers so
advertisers could create and upload ontologies to express all the kinds of things should match
their offering
and that can help make a much better job matching so the interesting thing about
all this is that once you start with a broad platform when that actually gets
deployed a larger scale
then there are
self-interest in all different aspects of the ecosystem that now becomes worse than adding more
knowledge system because it will make their lives better
and so
i think once we get these kind of systems out there
then it's possible that semantic web can take off faster than anyone realizes and we
can go from broadly applicable systems too deeply specialized vertically oriented
experts you know in pretty fast order
so to conclude power sets very active
is and has been plainly very active with the research communities were looking to develop
an open platform where people could use our API eyes and also the people access
technology to build mashups and the kinds of applications world's contributing datasets annotations and open
source software back
we're excited and interested in partnership collaborations and you can now go
try power laps which is our early community
if you go to
www powerset dot com you can sign up now letting in people pretty quickly into
the service
from so that i like to thank you all for your attention
OK to i think to summarise the question i did have trouble hearing yourself i
miss it then you can have some kind of echo going on here in the
so my question the results look very exciting and the kind of things people been
talking about doing for a very long time it looks like our cities using technology
seems to have been around for a long time namely the LFG technology from xerox
parc so why is it suddenly now this stuff is actually possible to stack up
the question correctly
so the the first thing is that are
it's not that the workers just was done
twenty years ago and has been sitting around and so now
some things change sort of suddenly make make it workable in fact the party group
was founded in nineteen seventy two
and the interesting story here is that every five years the group go address more
key problems and then come back to the management and say well we really need
some major accomplishments but the technology is not ready to be applied
and this actually continue for thirty years
so you know people might remember back in the eighties there was a period where
towards the end of the eighties there was the semantic web you know winter
i people just stopped working on semantics largely in the community
and there was lot in computational linguistics so things like excitement about you know empirical
methods in machine learning of natural language resources but it was all syntactic on the
grammars and there was no and and semantic systems is kind of almost a decade
or were hardly doing anything but actually the the folks apart
and their in our colleagues in the community
didn't stop working on these they they actually kept going so was on the only
place the kept working on the entire stack natural language they just cut tackling one
problem after another so they made some major improvements with respect to ambiguity management
which was really it took a long time to work through
the problem of ambiguity is you know plagues natural language systems and normally what happens
is people make the best systems have long pipeline and they make the best guess
at each step along the way
well if you make a wrong guess
early on then you're guaranteed the interpretation of everybody
so these algorithms are pretty standard and
given a model is relatively straightforward to it to derive an algorithm for doing inference
or learning in your model okay
so one thing which I
which is I always find a bit weird about probabilistic models is that
given our observed data x here we have two things that we don't know
about we have latent variables y and our parameter's theta right
and if you
look above this
the way in which we estimate the unobserved latent variables is quite different from the
way we estimate the parameters right so one is just doing co co one is just computing the
conditional distribution while the other one is trying to do maximum likelihood and always I
always find that a bit weir strange because they should basically be the same process
is both of them are about the process of inferring well we did not
observe from what we did observe okay
and basically the Bayesian modeling approach
does that does both of these both inference and learning in exactly the
same way and to do that of course you you will need a prior distribution
over your parameters so this is our prior distribution over parameters so that we can estimate both
the unobserved latent variables and the unobserved parameters
in the same process which is simply to compute the posterior distribution over
the latent variables and the parameters together given the observed data okay
so the posterior distribution here is gonna be again given by base rule
which is now gonna be
a ratio between the joint's distribution over the all the
random variables whether the observed or unobserved and also with the parameters okay
and then of course this
in the denominator here we'll have the marginal distribution of simply the observed variables where
we have marginalized out both the parameters and the latent variables
again we can do things like prediction and classification and so forth so prediction would correspond
to computing the conditional distribution of a new test item
given your training sets x one to x n and this would be of course
just be
basically integral of the conditional probability of the test item given the parameters where we've integrated other
parameters with respect to its posterior distribution okay so this is just
follows from the from probability theory
and classification would be half similar so we'd like to
we can compute the
conditional probability of the test items given the data set corresponding to the ceeth class where we
have again marginalized out
the parameters corresponding to the ceeth class
so one thing to note is that this prior distribustion is is
is very useful because it allows us to regularize our learning so I guess
you guess have all know that when you do maximum likelihood
learning then you have to be careful not to overfit to your data right and one way
which you could address all the fitting is by regularizing your parameters and one way
which could think about this prior distribution here is basically as a way of regu
of regularizing your parameters okay
so basically if you look at the posterior distribution of the parameters given
our observed
data is gonna be a ratio between the joints between the observed data and the parameters
divided by the marginal and if you look at this joint's
distribution here it will be
high if the particle asset on the parameters
gives high probability of to the observed data and has high probability under the prior okay
and basically we can think of this product here as a tradeoff in finding a
good parameter settings that fits both the prior well
as well as the data well
something else which I like to say is that in the Bayesian way
of looking at things there's really no difference between inference and learning okay so both of
I have the first one
microphones please
you need the microphone
rudi rizman
take your microphone please closer you again proved that power of
interdisciplinary and transdisciplinary analysis and interpretation of the chosen topic so I
take the privilege to ask you whether you would encourage the aesthetical interpretation of
ugliness and beautiful on other spheres of social I'm here referring having in mind especially to use
kind of analytical differentiation to the fields of the history of ideas can we speak
also about ugly and beautiful ideas ugly and beautiful ideologies ugly and beautiful politics
if there is anything like beautiful politics at all if this question makes any sense I would be grateful for your brief comment thank you
I hate metaphors
except except in poetry except in poetry so it's usual normal we
speak of
beautiful moral behaviour beautiful idea but it is a metaphor is a metaphor
except we speak of the beauty and of the elegance of the mathematical demonstration
in that case we are a really aesthetically speaking of a
of a balance of a proportion but to say you have a beautiful idea
is like to say we made a beautiful love yesterday and I want to
have then a beautiful scotch to finish the experience prosm
Ivan ti ja tukaj prosm mogoče bi mel pa kej več mikrofonov pa bi šlo lažje
my name is Ivan Svetlik and I must say doctor Eco I've enjoyed your talk
very much but it seems to me that from the beginning where it was funny it turned to a
very serious conclusion at the end
my friend Rudi took it too far from your mouth and you're taking it
too close to your mouth
make it a beautiful level sorry what is
it okay sorry I wanted to say that I enjoyed you talk
very much but it seemed to me that it turned from a rather funny beginning to a very serious
by which I mean that this disappearing
distinction between beauty and ugliness makes us thinking about what we were
going to and I would like to ask you could you link or interpret
this disappearing difference from the perspective of raising individualism in the society because individualism
has become so
high value that everybody has the right to be different and
and therefore perhaps
there is a natural conclusion that ugliness has become very much acceptable
I quoted this idea that the the distinction
beauty ugliness is disappearing as an idea which has been
put forth there are many essays on the subject but I think it concerns only
contemporary art because in the rest of our life think of designs
design the form of a car
of a TV
set of dishes we are still following notions of of beauty
which are the classical ones we want a beautiful car very well designed with harmonious
shapes so so we have still an idea pretty a pretty traditional
idea of of beauty in the form of a tie jacket and so easy and
contemporary art the distinction has been cancelled because I repeat art is no more interested in beauty
but in something else that these can express a form of individualism and the
decision to be original at any cost that's true that's true and that's probably the reason
why many aspects of contemporary art are divorsed from
the society in which they live that they are still alive only in the circuit of
art galleries and few collectors that's and they don't
do not realize that on the contrary people is watching cinema television
where you can have the triumph as another form of ugliness
to each chapter of my book is I have not which is kitch
the fake beauty but that's another story as kipling would have said
thank you very much
še kakšno vprašanje ja prosm
as an Italian and expert on beauty and ugliness what do you think about darfur which is very close
to us now just accross the mediterranean sea and a desert but I've spoken about darfur
when I said that we are continually continuosly confronted by newspaper or TV
with that OK that that connects to
later parts of the course and a beautiful way
shows our formula shows this formula from from later on to be activities which will
come in March uh to be actually very useful for this puzzle that we never
really result
the nonlinear turned
a direct attack on this inverse
we can get it directly
and getting it directly will be cut will connect to our differential equations so I'm
I'm proposing to a racist
if nobody objects I'll erase this this rank 1 and this wonderful formula because because
you will see that was see it again and I'll just mention it can to
erase it totally out of the way that didn't 1 1 application of what 1
because I spoke about the squares there yet so let me on complete that thought
before I give up
was I'm trying to find the position of the
and people weren't given that show I suppose I'm trying to solve this least-squares problem
you equals
some measurements
OK what's my I a is going to be false discovery rectangular and it's going
to be a matrix with ones
minus 1 1
minus 1 1 n minus 1 1 so it also so far
as a final guys
minus 1
that I'm looking for the positions all of this
but say
satellites and I measure the want the 2 p 3 before and the 5 OK
what the what's up here
it's not
that it shouldn't have
for hope for
1 2 3 4 yeah good effect of the credit so that it no need
to say problem in words and trying to this this this
the a it's moving along
so I 1st measure its 1st positions
make a measurement you want will be 1 is my 1st equation
OK so know approximately where it is
now the 2nd equation is due to the minus you 1 is some B 2
so 1 of my I 1 of my measure there
I measured the difference how much it moved right so I didn't know exactly where
but the 2nd measurements
told me something about where it is now
by measuring the relative error which of course everybody can think of applications where that
would be the case and then the next the 3rd equation would be a measurement
of the next 1 and plus and the next and now pretty well no
I know something about you for
because it's approximate so what is you for is approximately equal
I guess if I just had those for measurements what would be my best guess
for you for
the right
if I wanted to know you 4 out of the 4 measurements if I add
those equations that would be give me you for equal one plus 2 + 3
4 plus errors and that's like the best I could do that would be the
best least-squares now right now only used for OK and that's exactly so that exactly
corresponds at this matrix T
if the albeit somewhat had member what to do with least squares
but had a lower what's the equations so if I have a rectangular system as
I do here there's not going to be a solution so I'm looking for you
approximately is close to be as I can get it and what to do what
equation to ourselves
that A transpose the right
so so so that leads me to believe a transfer of points that for the
best you
is a transpose believed that the equation actually solve now the 1 I had only
when it was 4 by 4
that I had 4 equations for announced actually matrix was completely invertible I could solve
it directly you you gave me the best answer you for it is the sum
of the
but now
I get a 5th measurement
and NFS measurement is
minus you for equals some someplace B 5
but basically it's a it's a measurement of plus there is a measurement of where
the final guy ideas but it's got errors
now what's the best estimate for you for
let me ask you
what's the best measurement for the final position the best estimate of the final position
you for based on 5 data
how you might say OK the last measurement
was measuring you for exactly
could do better than that but you can't
because you had information previous and you're not gonna throw them away
right there there's error in this measurement
so it's not exact
and there and measurements possibly greater because it was like like compounded but still information
is in there
goes and then we inserted in their place and that's why it's called insertion sort
so we just sort of move the things copy the things up and we find
where it goes
and then we put it into place
and then we
now we have that
from a from one j is sorted and now we
tend work on j plus one
so let's give an example of that
imagine we're doing eight two four
nine three six
so we started out
with two
j jake two
we figure out that we want to insert their so now we have two eight
four nine three six
then we look at the four
and we say all that goes over here
two four eight
nine three six
after the second iteration of the outer loop
then we look at nine
we discover immediately it just goes right there
very little work to do on that step
so we have exactly the same thing output
after that iteration
when we look at the three
that's going to be inserted over there
two three
four eight
nine six
finally six
that goes on there
two three four five six eight nine
at that point we're done
there is this year starts one yes
a one day
so this is the insertion sort algorithm
and it's the first album algorithm that we're going to analyse
OK we pick out plots and tools that we have from our math background to
help to analyse so first of all it took take a look at the issue
running time
so the running time depends of this algorithm depends on a lot of things
so for one thing it depends on is the input itself
OK so for example if the input is already sorted
insertion sort has very little work to do
OK because every time it's going to be like this case
and have to shuffle too many guys over because there are already in place
in some sense what's the worst case for insertion sort
yeah its reverse sorted
that is going to do a lot of work
it's not the shuffle everything over on each step
OK of the outer loop
in addition
to the actual input it depends of course on the input size
so here for example we did six elements
it's going to take longer
if we for example do six times ten to the ninth elements
so we're sorting a lot more stuff
can take us a lot longer
so typically the way we handle that is we're going to parameterize
things in the input size
so there
talk about time as a function of the size of things that we are
so we can look at what
is the behaviour of that
and the last thing i want to say about running time is generally we want
upper bounds on the running time
we want to know
the time is no more than a certain amount
and the reason is because that represents a guarantee to the user
so if i say it's not going to run for example if i tell you
here's the program in run run more than three seconds
OK that gives you really information about how you can use it for example in
real time setting
was by said here's the program
you know
goes these three seconds you don't know if it's going to go
for three years
doesn't give you that much guarantee
if you're a user so gently we want upper bounds because it represents the guarantee
the user
there are different kinds of analyses that people do
the one are mostly going to focus on is what's called worst case
OK this is what we do
where we on youtube
to be the maximum time
on any
of size n
this the maximum input the maximum could possibly cost us on an input of size
OK so what that does is if you look at the fact that sometimes the
inputs are better and sometimes there were we're looking at the worst case of those
because that's the way we're going to be able to make a guarantee it always
does something
rather than just sometimes there's something
look at the maximum notice if i didn't have maximum t event in some sense
it is a relation not to function
because the time an input of size n
but depends upon which input of size n
i could have many different times
but by putting the maximum added it turns that relation into a function because there's
only one maximum time
it will take
sometimes we'll talk about average case
sometimes we do this
here two and is then the expected time
overall class
size n
do we have a criterion good criterion what to learn they can we can specify
convex cost function
and they decided to tool use as it is convex function they
the other e
for that if they have just believe that they ask them they want to find
an embedding of the the data that i
maximal margin
the block there
did it
they sort of with a kinematic because
and they have these optimisation problem
that is the min max problem so
i mean you should minimize with respect to the gamma function and maximize with respect
to this problem interesting from the solution is the only one that can be computed
by rearranging the problem opportunity
semidefinite programming
OK you can find the passage on paper
i just to give you
the idea
they have right of the problem and they want to see the labelling data
so i find troubling me the one on the right side
what do they do is if you if you if you look at the matter
is k i t that means that
they maximize the margin only on training data
and but use to the unlabelled data
and let's do the text blocks o
they're not the math explored and the that the rest
and at the same time
was that cannot function
two twenty ton capacity control as shown before what i average
is that this
o effect is coming from
combination of four
some other mixes is
they work by land has been
told pioneering work very nice
the problem is that doesn't scale much soul from
that time a lot of
other people
try to develop new approaches for can combination
the scalar bit more and for example you might like the work by about two
thousand four
would like to remind you think it's quite nice work on the field
they restrict their attention to
chemical munitions combination kind of that for the web
some of them all
you see what why and more than zero so this is the kind of
they wanted or convex combination of camel of the time
eighty five
you can even they're more likely migration
but of course you have to many combination
so two
the design and cost function that you can optimize to find the same time the
solution of all support vector machines and they
i mean that that was you the best can combination
this is quite nice formulation of the problem in the case
these numbers
the problem is jointly convex in in w more
and so that there is a unique global minimum
find nice to be able to apply his approach and discussing in general both can
communication on CV
and they the problem of classifying flowers and flowers can be represented by many features
like color texture
and the tried several features from computer vision system that one
and you see that the right side you see that get quite good results for
example using SIFT
and then
now we can see what do we get if you do also simple cannot combination
as productive can for example or other
some of can averaging if you want
you get
fifteen percent more than using a single feature
then the
apply it can lead to the
shortly before in the collection
and this what they get the same performance more or less but the difference is
that the time to compute the it's much
to compute
additional problem is one and fifty two seconds
that is that if we use simply product of the can is to say to
so i
i want that you can combination is not useful
not need what happened in the following they do some clever stuff and it also
proposed approach to the to the problem of chemical combination
right to the conclusion that if all the future the two you get good
you don't need to be to to select the uganda
put them together like simply summing the can
making the product but if some features are not going to be able to detect
these ultimately automatically then you need
the use of multiple kernel learning
and this is some of what is shown
in the plot the
from the paper
from the very it's like well
when you have some nice to the features of the features
that was some discriminative by
this marks
more robust to use can learning that to automatically
so the two combined can simply by doctor or by averaging
i think is what was acquired
interesting what from
practical and theoretical point of view
i'll summarize bit
so support vector machine system
OK so one of the so i talked about the fact that
noise hurts adaboost but we can actually use that fact one advantage
and use adaboost as a way of finding outliers so it turns out that the
examples that have the most weight
at the end of running adaboost are likely to be
outliers in the sense that they are likely to be they're mislabeled
or just
inherently ambiguous
on this particular dataset these are some of the examples that have the highest weight
on the last round
so the first one says i'm trying to make a credit card called that to
be calling card
but it's actually labelled in the datasets clocked which is just clearly mistake
this one person said hello
that was the entire thing the person said
that was labelled
as a request for rate information
this one yes i'd like to make a long distance collect call please clearly should
labelled the collect call instead it was labelled calling card so this can be used
as a tool for instance to clean up your data sets
OK here's another application also to a similar kind of spoken dialogue task
this is also work i did when i was at eighteen t
so at eighteen two labs they try to start a business called the natural voices
business which would sell
very good text to speech
engine so take text and were converted to very realistic sounding synthesized speech and this
actually has nothing to do with that in particular but but they didn't want to
do is to set up a kind of automatic storefront your help desk so people
could call up and ask questions about this product you know they could ask for
demo they transfer pricing information technical support and so on
and again they didn't one person to have to go through a menu pushing one
pushing two and so on
i just wanted the person to be able to have interactive dialogue with the system
i can give you a demo what that sounds like so you can hear two
the man's voice
is a person calling
to ask about this the woman's voice is the synthesized voice
the name was crystal
this came amazingly her name they bore hole personality this person this made person anyway
man is talking to crystal
the thing i'm going to focus on is that they're having this interactive dialogue in
the computer is
carrying on the conversation in this
fairly intelligent life
now how can i help you
we like demonstration
sure i can help you with that
i condemn voices in english spanish korean war germany
or i can give you an idea of what custom going down like
which would you prefer
that's the voice
OK then constantly for you
one is likely to find
cartridge because the power to move his voice town
here it is
american finished prepared with the the with the prior to the people third when
i'd like to the customer voice again
can be no question answering
twenty five going on
called which has the power to move one town
the other thing is prepared to reason with an impressive sixty third when
could we have vanished when
OK band for you
it's not on the market right now but it will be the next language we
get out
female voice
it found
seventy percent of going that you don't have to go to the people
we custom again
so you get the
idea OK so how does something like this work
so here's
human up here
and the telephone caller telephone callers says something in
sound signal that raw utterance gets passed through an automatic speech recognition is the recognizer
the speech recogniser converts the sound signal the text three noisy text because speech recognizers
far from perfect that text gets passed to the natural language understanding unit which is
trying to extract
the meaning of what was said to the extent
but that meaning can be placed in one of this case twenty four categories
the categories are things like once you're demo wants to speak to sales reps and
so on
that predicted category gets past the dialogue manager
the dialogue manager is in charge of keeping track of the actual state of the
so given the current state given the predicted category
the dialogue manager updates the state
and formulates text response
which gets passed to the text-to-speech engine
this is crystal that's the thing that we're trying
we're trying to sell
and that gets converted to
which gets played for the human and it all has to happen in real time
so the part that i was working on is this natural language understanding you know
which is really just a classification task we're just trying to take text and classified
into one of these twenty four categories
so for the weak classifiers we did the same thing is what i described before
we use these very simple
rules that are like decision stumps that just test for the presence
of the word or phrase
so a few challenges came up and
in working on
so one of the things that came up was an initial shortage of data
in order to deploy system like this very quickly and cheaply
you can't wait around until you have a lot of data
but in order for the system to be accurate in its prediction
you need to train it with a lot of data
she so we kind of have the bootstrapping problem so in order to deploy the
system you need to have a lot of labeled data so that can
so that you can train your system and actually deployed on the other hand to
get the labelled data the best way to get the labelled data
it is for the system to already be deployed so they collecting data as people
carry on conversations with the system
so to get around this kind of chicken and egg problem
we used human knowledge to try to compensate for insufficient amount of data early on
in the training of these systems
i talked about using exponential loss which tries to
minimizing exponential loss were trying to fit the training data
but instead what we did was we devised a way where humans could come up
a model of very rough model but pretty good model called the prior model
and then we devised the loss function
which was a variant on the exponential loss
where on the one hand we're trying to fit the training data that we do
have but we're also trying to fit this prior model which was built by the
human so we've got these two things we're trying to fit both the
and that worked pretty well so for instance on one dataset called the ATP titles
this is showing the air right this green curve is the air that we get
using the just the prior model built by the humans
it's pretty bad in this case but there are
there are a lot of categories are remember how many so even
the very
you see it
i mean that
you know
when you find
you are
people were
it is
these are
many of the
and we
we looked
that is really
thank you
in that direction
you are
by saying
many of them
i assume that your
thing to get
go away
they are