we should stop
so before you make an announcement before
the very top today
so the instrument is the
however a feedback for online
the rest of the feedback form is you just go to the home page
of the summer school new that slash feedback
so the price is right there you just go to
o pages slash feedback
well it's very much appreciated
for the support
the plenary talks today begin by man
and this from
call to action
subject of the
matrix completion
there are convex
OK so thank you very much
so had already three hours and a half
a course of lectures of the convex optimisation guy and you have
one more power now
so don't blame me blame the organizers
all rights are going to talk about something new today we're going to talk about
exact matrix completion
i will try to present some theory in some algorithms
OK alright so before i get started i just want to
to say a few words about why is it that we're setting this problem
so i drive
i live very far away from my workplace and so when i go to work
and the center's radio
and one day i was listening to NPR and they talked about the netflix prize
which i got interested in
so i ssume that everybody is familiar with netflix although we have some international students
who are the people who don't know what netflix
if you a few people so netflix is a company that is renting out movies
so you you go online and you are you order movies and then they come
through the mail
and then once you're done watching them you just returned
and so netflix is a very large company that has
about a million users at the moment and they're running out something like about twenty
five thousand movies
and typically once you
you you rent movies you receive emails from netflix so when you go on the
website asking you to write movies
and so we have a large database and netflix is assembling a very large database
that contains about a million users and has about twenty five thousand movies and people
rate is movies
and so the netflix has the database that looks like this is looks very much
like what rafi was discussing yesterday or you have columns are movies
rules are users and users rate movies
and so a typical feature of this matrix it's set extremely sparsely sampled beacon on
on average users with great i don't know
out of the twenty five thousand movie they will rate fifty to one hundred movies
and so you have very few entries available
about this matrix
and yet what netflix would like to do is we would like to complete this
matrix that they would like to be able to
complete the matrix that is predict the
movies that user has not rated or movie that the user has not seen and
they would like to do this for very obvious reason that is if i could
predict the preferences of
of a manual for movies that he has not seen then i would be able
to do very efficient advertising
and so of course in the modern economy
it's extremely important as we purchase more and more things online is very important for
companies which operate on line to be able to make targeted recommendations because in the
old days you would go to a bookstore and then you'd find books on the
shelves and you will browse through them in you bible stories but now nobody goes
to bookstores anymore
it is very important for amazonian for barnes and noble
and so on to be able to recommend books that you might like
so there are many problems of this kind were
users rate their preferences for a few items
and yet the vendor would like to know
their preferences for unrated item so that they can do fish and recommendation
right so you can imagine that amazon has the same problem
paul was selling selling music has the same problem
facebook have similar problems and so on and so forth now all these problems have
the same flavor in machine learning then known under the name of collaborative filtering and
the idea is that perhaps i can borrow information
across users to actually predict my own preferences
OK in statistics is a familiar problem because you can think about this as a
survey of asking questions to people
and people decide not to answer some questions and you'd like to guess
what they would have answered had chosen to answer this question
OK is famous netflix problem and there many of problems where i have partial information
about a large matrix of interest and i want to immediately
i suggest another problem which is global positioning
so here we are in the area of sensor networks for example and there are
points in d dimensional space that we would like to locate
so think about them as sensors
and the sensors what they can do is they can construct a distance estimate
two other senses so there is a matrix m i j
i think that the
so this is the only one in bar
it in vertical position
a hundred and forty nine
o point nine
but i would think that the uncertainty of my measurement is probably one millimeter
i can really guarantee you that i did actually that
so that's the vertical
now we're going to measure the bar
which we have set up here will
OK this news site
know i measure the length of this are
hundred fifty point zero
one hundred fifty one zero again so minus o point one centimeter
so you would agree with me that i am capable
of measuring some minus one millimeter that uncertainty of mine
now if
the difference in length between
lying down and standing up there were one foot
we would all know it wouldn't get out of bed in the morning you lie
down and clunk
u one foot short and we know that's not the case
if the difference only one millimetres
we would never know
therefore i suspect
if my grandmother was right
it is probably only a few centimeters maybe an inch
and so i would argue that if i can measure
the length of the building two
one millimeter accuracy
that's said several issues
so i need to volunteer
you want to volunteer
like very polite hope
i hope we can hope that we don't run out of
not all in one seventy eight so
what's your name
rick rick writer
you know you're right
i can old guys you come up
we need someone
more modest in size
don't take it personal right
what is unique
the exact
if you're right
the first lecture at MIT
i don't know
OK man
and there
eighty three
to they they don't move
and this is the article
what did i say hundred eighty
only one person
come on
o point two OK
on the eighty three points
and the circuitry
are about
one of these centimetres of point one centimeter
now we're going to make him
or is
they're going don't want you to break your bones so we have labels that you
what you see there will be removed part
watch out for this
right that it's all over
OK i'll come on your site i have to do that
think of this as a small sacrifice for the sake of size right
OK you good
you can you comfortable
really conflict right
five point seven you are on eighty five point seven
i'm sure one of the first make traction right on eighty five point seven
is o point one standing
of the five that is point five one minus o point is
about one installer when you sleep and when you stand up my grandmother was right
you always right
get off
i want you to appreciate that the accuracy thank you very much
the accuracy of one millimeter was more than sufficient
to make the case
if the accuracy by measurement would have been much less
this measurement
i wouldn't have been convincing
at all
so whenever you make measurements you must know the uncertainty otherwise
it is meaning less
galileo galilei
as himself the question
mammals as large as they are not
what's large
we had a very clever reasoning which i have never seen in print
what it comes down to the fact that he argued that if the mental becomes
the bones of great
and he thought the that was on limiting factor
even though i've never seen his reasoning in print
i will try to reconstruct what could have gone through his head
is a mammal
and this is the
one of the collective memory
and these memo
as the size
and what i mean by that is
there must be a big
and cat is a
that's what i mean by size
crudely defined
the mass of the
mcmanus and
and this mammals
five o
which we call the female
and a few more
would carries the one large extent
and that's the full assume that the female has a length l
and as the thickness b
there's a few more
this is what if you were approximately like
so this would be the length of the femur
and this would be
and this would be the cross sectional area a
i'm not going to
take you through what we call in physics is failing or
i would argue that the length of the femur
must be proportional
the size of the animal that's completely plausible
if an animal is four times larger than another you would be four times longer
that's all this is a
very recent
it is also very reasonable that the mass of an animal
is proportional
is the power
the size because the
related with volume
so if it's related to the group of the size must also be proportional
the third power
the length of the femur because of this
OK that's why
now comes the argument
on the femur
is proportional
the weight of the animal
divided by the cross section eight
one of the femur
what pressures
and that is the mass of the animal there is proportional to to the the
mass of the animals
divided by the square
because you want every year
fortunately with
now follow me close
if the pressure
things like that so there's about open field which is due to the interoperability which
gives you an ontology
OK so now had the first introduction what is semantic web ontology
will i'll give you a brief glimpse
of what is ontology engineering
how can you support by learning
and what is mine the semantic web
and the energy is and i will only grow very briefly over that because this
manual approach this was the outcome of the so-called knowledge project
and the task was to build some ontology based knowledge management applications for example to
support skills management a large insurance company typical problems if you have a manual approach
there you rely on the knowledge from your domain experts so how can you support
the collaboration between domain experts and knowledge engineers that's ontology engineers and on the other
hand how can you evaluate ontology so these are the the two main problems i
would say
and then we define the methodology
which is a bit too complex for tutorial so in the not so there's process
oriented and cyclic methodology to manually create ontology and you have pre-defined decisions at each
and others that
and you have pre-defined outcomes of the end of that so you know really what
to do was also to make it understandable for industrial people so there we have
to deal with people who had no clue about ontology modelling or modelling at all
and we have to teach them how to build the ontology for their domain
so that was the purpose so this manual approach is now quite well established
we link to further existing methodologies for certain subsets all for example two
well where to draw the line between instances and the schema for example this is
one very common problem also not from the databases there exist some methodologies so there
we for example pointers that
there's a big but the manual approach is very cross it's a very time-consuming task
and especially in industry
you don't have the time and you don't have the money also to maintain always
your resource manually
so what is the idea
well actually use this
is this technology which already exists and expand
armed with semi-automatic support
for example by ontology and instance learning
this will be presented now by my college london
so introduced i tried to in the overview about how can be semi-automatic these
or bring up the the semantic web as well as interviews and
if i start to
all of you you know about them applications might yes
she can support this automatically step by the shortly say something about why only seniority
might not automatically and
the idea of this semi-automatic
is that the problem is that
a lot of technical technical background knowledge experience is in the mind of the people
that's the problem and
that if data to derive all the things that matter to them
we do not need to semantic that you can all recorded in one program and
can automatically derive like this is a step commit to guide the semantic web contact
to to use the the good things the semantic web so the problem is if
we are not able to do all the things that matter and this is important
we want to which is to support
do you as much as possible of meetings
solutions but the decision lies on the people which are modelling of which
the ontology and which food ontology information and that's very important thing which i want
mentioned as i start to say something about automatically derive the government he
derive some information for ontology so very want to stop so you to discovered
that and it's usually start with this is what we have and the idea is
the use of data mining and text mining knowledge discovery techniques on the and
we distinguished three different i
is subsumed under the topic that that mining and one is so-called that content mining
which focus on the content of to content after pages a nominee also mean by
taking text mining on the second step second
idea is to use the structure which had no meanings between ages but exist dealings
between this the picture to use and to derive some knowledge out of this information
and to find out what is an important website not important which are the content
of this information and
drive this information and put them into the ontology
last that is
to have a look and on business application how use US
users go to the vessel day called that use its mining and basis based on
the prices usually
captured by the that and the idea is that we try to follow because it
seems to me on the page and to find out what he is interested in
and maybe to improve some
that site design want to try to give you some advice maybe what i'm interested
in all make some marketing stuff and if we use ontology to you can try
to make it and the analysis that and
and we can put this information on
into the ontology
the idea is all what i want to show now is we have two parts
which we tried to from that we want to go because is that we need
to talk this ontology layer and for this we tried to apply some data-mining techniques
known this ontology so we learned from the semantic web users those that in a
second one is that we need some instances to fill up this knowledge base that
he can after that are some
ah it makes an inference is not so much knowledge so now i come to
london it's going to give you an overview so as i mentioned ontology learning is
in the middle between knowledge discovery data mining and ontology engineering so we have this
manual approach to to bring up the ontology and we have the techniques to derive
some information from data to capture some information from data we have and you think
those ideas together and try to support this manual approach it's much
and one idea which was done by a colleague of mine alexander mitchell in his
well so so there's a term balanced corpus so corpus is a collection of tax
that you can use to do things like estimate probability of balanced corpus one remix
different kinds of text i want to be fair and balanced so i used equal
parts of genesis and the communist manifesto so we get this lovely hundred words like
reactionary so this is the ground
five airline like model so every letter is being generated depending on the previous four
and you see that
we've got to make sure these two kinds of test we can also do this
instead of doing it instead of doing n grams of letters
four and five we could do n grams of words so this is
word try grounds every word is being generated given the previous two
so we have a
let's see
OK right we have here the bourgeoisie keeps more more splitting up into two great
lights the greater light to rule the day
the interests of the conditions of oppression new forms of struggle in place of segment
to the plaintiff or so
yes because of the ground of the same character into one nation
with one government so what happened here we seem to have switched from one kind
of text into another kind of text and the reason is that we have big
great plagues because that's probably from one tax because of could be from either of
the grounds
so so when you get something like that that kind of risk between two tracks
could be generated once once you've got that can't
you might want to generate next work
so we tend to go for a while from one for from one from genesis
and then switch to the companies
or vice versa
OK so why am i doing this this kind of an in fact on my
i first saw this when my freshman roommate in college wrote a program to do
this just for fun
so why this actually be useful so let me show you a little text that
was generated
using a tri gram model
from the core as you might guess that this is a different corpus
what can you tell me about the corpus
well it's not english OK it's not japanese either many and maybe somebody can guess
actually what language
many closer
o very it's actually cause which is closely related to
right to its eventual language of southern africa nelson mandela's native language for example and
you can immediately tell that it's not english because
you know if you look at the number of cues and disease are much too
high for example the number of spaces is too low that's another way of saying
that the words long
after q
well there's no factor q we have a lot of examples
things like you a
right doesn't show very often in english the kudos in english is almost always
it's going to be very very heavily weighted towards the cost that's not true now
this tax over here is a
OK so
even though this is terrible model right this is only a trying model of
this doesn't look very much like english this doesn't look very much like because you
can see there are still good enough you can tell the difference from randomly generated
it might be that there is enough statistics syntax
just looking at these these programs to be able to tell what kind of text
is coming from
here's an example with four nodes
and again you might be able to start to see what the what the text
is if you look at the english
so i don't know what this is where the colours are being
but this comes from the universal declaration of human rights which has been translated into
i think now over four hundred languages it's inspiring
document which
it and to tell everybody in the world
what the basic human rights are even if
there's only
twenty speakers of the language itself
OK so
that's a little motivation for using probability
as we'll will see you can and i have people do this at the beginning
my course
if you're given syntax is not very hard to tell from the statistics of the
tax which letters followed which ones what language it's written and you can do this
given you know very short substring language say ten to twenty years
with the accuracy if you're only trying to distinguish among the few languages if you're
trying to distinguish between say two bantu languages then you might need a little more
tax because
there's little more like and you might need to go until you find a war
some pattern of letters which is common in one of those languages
but as you get more and more text you're just aggregating so one example of
QA maybe you could tolerate in english because maybe you're talking about the country color
if you see a lot of this then you pretty quickly the probability pretty quickly
tip in favor of some
OK so let's switch to talking about
i am i bring a few transparency is back love this afternoon but switched to
talking about about probabilities
so the goals of this lecture the first of all i want you know
really understand what this probability notation means how many people are totally comfortable with this
a majority but only that you so
so what is this expression means how can you sling these things around to be
very comfortable and words its value from
that's the notation and talk about probability models which defines this function so what we
mean by probability model with talking about language identification
so how do we actually do that then how would we evaluate to find out
of the models
i want start with the word about statistics i think the term statistics is misunderstood
because most people are taking statistics courses in college are taking a course that tells
them how to compute means and medians
or if they are in the social sciences they try to find out whether
there's is enough data
in the with enough subjects in the experiments to find out the answer was statistically
significant i'm going to try here too
one slide stops the contrast a little better is that they
there's a problem that the
computers are on the same circuit
as the overhead lights overturn the lights off the the machine that never fixed
it was recognised as negative of course
and there's another one
u markets
there's distrust in your markets despite some rumors involving his be which is supposed to be
and district of course was also recognised as negative
because some more
this district is referring to
post which talks about that spain contributing to
over the top few dept
of course this also negative news so
this it was also recognised as negative
four some positive tweets so that
it only got a new prime minister
this was recognized as a positive thing
apparently the old one wasn't they're good
and another one wear wear william dudley said that she absolutely things that euro will
survive right so the streets of course work
categorized as opposed to
and can you oppose it now so
and i like this one when one of the user says this this sounds to
me like a pump-and-dump scenario right so
get rid of europe because currently it sponsored by these the dudley got
okay so this is the first part of the video
the of the demo and the rest i'll show you
on the slides
great thanks
what you have seen in this video is that we can kind of categorized it into positive and negative right
what we did here in this graph
we collect the tweets about netflix which is the ust company
maybe some of you already heard about it it's a company that streams
thirty programs and shows over the internet
right hand we collected tweets from
to december
about netflix
and we categorize them as positive and negative sentiment and we display the results
like this a long time timeline
right in in
these blue
these blue line shows you the number of positive tweets
the number of tweets that were detected as positive
these red line shows u
the number of tweets that were detected as negative right
and the yellow one
i will tell you the difference between the positive and the negative to its so
if they is above the zero line
which this means that there are more positive than negative
and if it's below it's the other way around
okay so green dots are some events concerning netflix
that we entered into the system manually
and the great
one is the closing daily crawl closing price
so far the netflix stock
okay so
what does this graph tell us
first of all
this kind of
these are the volume peaks
with tell us
that something important happened at this time so people
more than usual talking
about some event concerning netflix or something happened
which is actually true so we can check out some events so this peak here
that we're looking at right now
is the first-quarter earnings release
right so this one here a smaller one but still
netflix was planning to launch its serve it service in in latin america and the
caribbean so this was the big news
this one here for example is when netflix
c last a couple of years
forty shows and movies
and also something called studies deal
i think if i if i remember correctly stars is also one of the networks which
they tried to make a deal so that the netflix would stream there's there are programs over the internet
so you see this is already something useful we are alerted when something big happens
but you can also see that the sentiment right
was pretty positive
of the log probability of data with no information on the log probability of the
data set given parameters and in effect this log p theatre serves as a regularisation
term just as the generalisation error
it was a regularisation term in in discriminative methods
so it serves in effect is an upper bound on the difference that we believe
to be possible between the training and test this
maximum entropy winds up having the same form can be written the same form except
that we we assume we don't know anything at all about p of data we
don't know anything at all about the prior except that the probability density and since
in the space of probability densities those with large entropy on arms are much more
numerous than those with small entropy
we estimate a lot of prior stated to be by the by the entropy of
the probability density implied by
that is the measure of the probability density is with with high entropy is larger
than measure those with low entropy
all right
and then in testing once we learned these parameters we can compute the
i said that given the given the likelihood function you know everything there is to
know you know how to compute the minimum probability of error classifier also know how
to compute the minimum mean square error estimate of y that can be written that
can be computed from all of these intrinsic variables by just marginalizing by summing over
all possible values of the intrinsic variables
in training we use maximum likelihood and testing we use a minimum probability of error
rather than give you use speech recognition examples of hidden markov model i thought i'd
show you something that you may not have seen before
hidden markov models can be used for regression
just as much as they can be used for recognition
here's how
if we if we have the gaussians states each state has if each state says
that the acoustic spectrum is gaussian distributed
then that is as shown here that is the probability of x given the state
variable is the is e to the minus one half
x minus x bar y minus wiper we're now why is real valued vector that
we're trying to estimate
then we compute we can compute the minimum mean square estimate of this real valued
vector by just summing over the posterior probability the states
the linear regression formula this is the linear regression formula that one gets from jointly
gaussian random variables you take the mean value they are pre or mean of y
otherwise vector plus
x minus its pierre mean multiplied by the core the correlation between
between x and y so here's the here's the
linear regression formula for jointly gaussian random variables and we some that over all the
different possible gaussians that might apply to the data weighted by the posterior probability that
that's the correct gaussians this gives us the nonlinear regression
for y given x
that can be extended to a hidden markov model by by including state
so for example we can assume that that x and y are not just jointly
gassing with each other but there are also jointly gaussians with the
the hidden state variable y at the previous time and the result is exactly like
the regression that i showed the previous formula except now the correlation between the correlation
between between x and y depends on is is a function of time depends on
what our current estimate of the of the y variable might be an essentially work
rather than computing rather than computing a weighted sum of linear regression formulas now computing
a weighted sum of common filters
with common soldiers linear regression with parameters updated over time
here's an example of an experiment we did using comparing hmm regression and and
a switching kalman smoother
the results were unfortunately not too compelling so the the the the task was to
try to estimate the position of the tongue
given the acoustic spectrum
so we have a database of we have a database of of tract pellets on
the surface of the tongue and the set of a set of matched acoustic spectra
and we use we use hmm regression that is we assume that there is no
dependence of the current position the articulators on their previous position except as specified by
the state in hidden markov model
and we also use the switching kalman smoother that is we use the bayesian networks
shown in previous page where the
articulators which otherwise depend not only on the current discrete state which is the as
they also depend on the previous
positions of the articulators with the previous the previous why vector and we find a
consistent but extremely small on europe point one millimeter reduction of the the tracking air
using the switching kalman smoother as opposed to using a hidden markov model regression and
that industry would benefit a lot more
even theory will will be more relevant
huge believer that you know that the most fundamental theories
lies in the most
like little details of applications and building systems and things like that
you know great discoveries in science you know probably test that
but you know
you do yourself a favor
and to be much better investment of your very valuable time that are talked about
if you do that phd just later don't we're too long because then you lose your brains
but yeah wrong ok yeah i just wanted to strongly disagree that finally we have
a lot you get object from move from from the floor but
the problems some cetera is that people don't come back to this statistical factor after five years
even after
three years people people just don't come back so you should take might start to
say that you don't learning huge amount like said
but if you leave the program you don't come back again i just said you need to
think through why you want to do it but don't leave was i can always come back
those yeah my master's award for two years and came back
to years to yours yeah i yeah i actually think that making doing a phd
area of data mining it's very helpful for for being a good data scientist
for a for one reason so like when you're doing your phd are pretty much on your old
and that you need to do good research and you need to have your research published
so you're reaching a level of excellence
dad if you have your papers published kdd and that are good venues right
so you have much more confidence in yourself
that you have done this
and it's a small step a each papers small startup yourself right yeah after all it's
yes like an off year of your life
you do you are all experimentation and sell it so you're doing
all from the prototype to marketing after all
once you have done this like to know five to ten times
and your papers got except that and you have allowed a lot of confidence to come to the
industry and say you know what guys i can do it
ok i spent six years getting a phd make sure don't it all
i probably would have been happy doing something else my life but enough time i had and
from that perspective that runcorn app
good data scientists take seasoning
you have to go for the potholes you have to make all mistake
i can even teach you all that mistakes complete
if a stream of masten have taken to data science courses maybe five
you're still going to have to learn off a lot of lessons so from hiring perspective
i like people with a phd exactly for the fact the
staff five years
and they have a certain amount of things of course somebody who wasn't in this five years i guess i even
back up
back you have to start somewhere cell if you have
if you don't have experience for me phd is a
value proposition
as high as a look at them
actually let me let me
jump in as well because i think
there's a
distinction that's generally not made we talk about data scientists these days
right and if you look in companies there are two very different sources where this far
more to it is leased to
very different sorts of data scientists right
people who are essentially what i would call data science engineers
their primary job building things
and there are people who might say are the data science kind of
scientists research but you know their job is pretty much coming up with new ideas
evaluating and so all right
for the former
ph d is a nice to have
for the latter her you know i mean as quality points out i mean they decide doing data
science researchers craft
and just like most of the mature
right the best way to learn it is the apprenticeship
right you can get that apprenticeship by
by pressing with a really good professor
right so just getting a phd where somebody tells you what to do you go to
do is get help got very much having a really good professor
that gives you a good apprenticeship
then leads you to go on to be journeymen data data you know that data
data scientist right
and so i think it's not really just getting a phd right it's do you
get a good apprenticeship you could also get a good apprenticeship not through a phd but
by saying go in your company as a fantastic chief scientist who really mentors her people
yeah so that would be ok so right there are there are other ways to do and i don't
think we should think about it as the label phd whether that's i think the question is
you get a good apprenticeship
such that you can
come up with good ideas design the right ces sums maybe not build them if
you're not put together the right evaluations and so on
ok i'm going to this song of a lot of questions running out
of time i'm going to two sides tom going to ask the age to address this
in point forms just stalled
out points so
what yeah yeah could you work fresh discreetly because
they're clear i can see them but i can see them in mind that they can see them on this
yeah yeah i can allow of ok come on yeah
yeah just specifically or
disallowing this allowed but lodging objections through technology to which you put your objection ended
everybody votes it up i put they yeah
yeah yeah ok
so i'm ok yeah i was fortunate to have been given the first kdd innovation award
like guys as we speak something ok
so i just professed by saying that i have no look you straight
what i'm going to argue why
if you can you should look phd
i know put it
in a start-up
but i would
argue that
if you're trying to what right reason for doing the start
because i have enough friends in the silicon valley
whipping but it's startups
because i just want to cook point
who really to an important point for us to understand why phd
much since the falling that
actually let me start with the start-up thing
if you are going to start a company
to make a million dollars
and testable
then you should know start a company
what you are doing is
you're putting at risk
like full-throttle people
what the company spent five just like that you
and if your goal is to make only money
you know when to use so
you should passionate really doing something
and that you use to construct
it doesn't make sense
thanks talk bush ok yeah ok yeah so i don't simple phd i'll quickly
yeah yeah i think the point to a phd is
to be able to do
that you was capable of doing
in some sense
your to recoup think at the level
that god has given you are
able to do
our feature mapping and we write down our eigen value problem in the feature space
we note that the solutions live in the span of the training data
we can then come up with the dual eigen value problem which is an eigen
value problem for this coefficients which we used to expand the eigenvectors and that eigenvalue
problem will turn out to look like it will be a kernel eigenvalue
problem we just to compute the kernel matrix again it's eigenvalue it's essentially and we have to
normalize them in a certain way but I think I don't have to go through
all details here so once we have found these eigenvectors that dual eigen vectors
this alphas we pluck them into our expression for the eigenvectors now we have
the eigenvectors as kernel expansions in the feature space and we can apply them to
some test point of which we want to extract features or which we want to
project to another dimension subspace to get these values and these values are of course it's
not surprising in view of the representive theorem expansions in terms of the training
points or kernels centered on the training points okay so I think I'm going to skip
this one long well no maybe just briefly so remember at the beginning of today's lecture
I told you if I map a training point or any point to its set of its
similarities to the training set and I perform this pre widening step it's like a
widening step then I get an alternative representation which
if I'm only dealing with the training set is equivalent to the full feautre map
turns out I can also do this with kernel PCA it will give basically
the same so if I project a point on to all the kernel PCA principal
components I get I get something like this which is almost the same
as this quantity where is D is now the diagonalization of K the only difference between this
mapping that I've told you about this morning so I can rewrite it like that so the
difference between this mapping and the projection of the kernel PCA components will be that
this leading unitary matrix U will be dopped but that doesn't make a difference because
if I'm interested in computing dot products unitary matrices don't count of dot products are
invariant under unitary transformations so that's a side remark so here's an example
of what happens if you apply kernel PCA so here we have a data set
I'm not sure you can see is the same data set everywhere it has three clusters
of data points now you can imagine if I did linear principcomponent analysis on
such a data set it wouldn't make much sense maybe and the direction maximum
variance would be something like this and then the second direction would have to be
orthogonal to it because we're working in two-dimensional space in of components are orthogonal
and then that's it so in particular I wouldn't find anything of the cluster structure
now if I do the same thing in the kernel space using a gaussian kernel turns out to
be quite interesting so it turns out that the first feature extraction function so
what I'm showing now here in gray value is the value of the projection of these corresponding
locations in this space on the first second third and so on principal component in
the feature space so I compute the projection in the feature space this corresponds to a non-linear
function input space this nonlinear function is is color-coded here so the first principle component
looks for whether we are in this cluster or this one and ignores this cluster
the second component now more or less ignores the distinction between these two clusters and just
identifies this cluster now the high order components have to look for additional
structure because they are orhogonal to the previous ones orthogonal in the feature space so
this component now looks for structure within this cluster this looks at this cluster and
this looks at the top cluster this looks at the top cluster again but roughly
a little better than most people know less about the so I would like to
talk a little bit more
about their genetic rule over
transmission of information and what better genetics
what we see here are different cell types of in the body of a ship
television the relative and when all of the different cells in our borders on the
whole with some exceptions have the same amount of DNA from sending their Indiana that
very different and the differences between the cells have happened at some point during development
and that once that happened that fixed
I'm pretty Congress when they were when they added divide they bring the British troops
from all punk skin cells when they provided they produce lost themselves so there is
some kind of memory of the functional and structural their state of the service and
we want to understand what this memory is after all the all the stuff that
Indian I wholeheartedly come to be different and how all of this is very important
for us when we're thinking about that worried about inheritance Howell is obvious difference maintained
we understand that this questions were also some something many years ago but there were
no good answers for that and they became a focus of a lot of studying
when the mechanisms that underlies this kind of 7 memory became clear to us and
what we should see is that it is not just the memory within the balding
but that this kind of differences this kind of variations can be transmitted also between
generations soul
we're when we're thinking about 7 memory and about the systems that underlies the memorial
and the inheritance of particular states and the state's morphological physiological state of cells
we can think about several types of picnic in mechanisms
and when we're thinking about that genetics in general with think also about
it other ways of transmitting information which I'm not to send but our also transmitted
through the development of reconstruction behavior and the culture not before mechanism similar mechanisms of
some hereditary of self-sustaining group structural inheritance chromatin marking an army mediated inheritance and I
would say a few words about picture the ourselves sustaining groups what we see here
not to say let things that bacterial cells from their will invariably bit group off
the dark property the regulatory general overdue and they like part is the structural region
which produces approach and here we are in this gene is not up it silent
and this silence there is inherited from 1 generation to the next the rest problem
the gym has no problem and the other for the daughters of also have no
problems and songs so you have the sense of what happened here is that the
led to the creation of the students and that as a result of this kind
of protein product cost for this broadened probe has told functions while function is to
always have some effect on the morphology of itself and the other function is tool
by to the regulatory region here and make the gene are so it produces more
of this problem so this is a positive feedback loop now what happens when there
is a cell divides the products
the proteins are also distributed to the daughters of as a result of this problem
are operated them in the daughter cells and then by the regulatory region as a
result of the person more of the product and sold so we can come to
this time at this point in time and we see blood types of cells cells
which are inactive in cells which are active in the same environment they have exactly
the staging of a British troops help come because something happened in the history of
the cells which made this which in this case created this figure positive feed group
and creative differences which note which consists of generations now this kind of thing is
not true that many examples of this kind of thing if few groups in microorganisms
and without going into detail from here is just 1 example promised not to live
apart from John Candy that becomes a single-celled from John and we know the different
states from all this funnels morphological physiological state of the fund was arming tech can
be maintained for a very long time tool alternative feedback loops
so there was quite a lot of this kind of thing in microorganisms and we
have here and this is what type of every genetic inheritance system 1 type of
every genetic inheritance mechanism
now you probably all had about problems problems of very unpleasant it sometimes is proteins
Our sells completed from and the lead to diseases such as the mad cow disease
not what do we mean by self-proclaimed and how related to sell heredity you know
we have to surface is normal probe normal brought creates this this type of by
putting problems and as a result the of her particular phenotype a particular morphology would
support now the same prompting on that because of all kinds of reasons can form
an alternative three-dimensional structure we don't change anything in the amino acid sequence in which
a it's exactly the same but the way that it is organized a three-dimensional organization
is different from now once this happens in this particular weight at trial is formed
and this program interacts with the norm of confirmation where interrupted when the confirmation he
makes it assumed its own structures so here we have an interruptions and as a
result of that
all of the white becomes becomes a Bronwen a grave and sold so what happens
is that and this is of course inherited from almost division and what we have
in that are cells are all set ourselves which have a probe which have sprung
type of proteins that Protestant would to create fibrosis and as a result of that
they have a different feel and the game we can look at them by it
at cells but say save studies cells in a particular environment that would see the
output of Sulzer 1 Taipei 1 within the time being they have exactly the same
DNA moving in exactly the same environment and yet there are different and the British
troops and this is due to this type of mechanism that to the simple symmetrical
division of the service
and again we have many examples of the same things in front here is 1
example Iast
and what is not about this example is that the experiment that were done by
Susan Lindquist and her group was that they tried to see
whether the different types of cells which are only different in the sense that 1
has the crime and 1 doesn't have the prime whether they will respond to selection
and they do all in 1 environment they did proprietor of those that bulk of
Iteration 3 I think that the 1st 3
and I have to know I have fliers
8 times like 68
again doubling the same things going on with the 2nd quarter and this distance here
you can see by the time you're getting exponentials the minus sign he I think
this is the this is the
in itself but also the associated to a
maybe it was a continuous Fernando donors in the form of
that would explain OK
here here thank you
OK so the convergence rate of the method is quadratic pursuant to these examples of
very nice but let's just the little credit also was 1 drawback
the see and that's what I thought you
yeah an initial point has to satisfy all those conditions that
let's look at those in addition to that I don't think that's all the all
the all all
so these conditions in a sense I would just rather than the labor the point
these conditions existential right we never know age because if we knew area we typically
don't know don't know like stock and that means we don't know data we don't
know dealt with L but we don't know we don't know gamma using these areas
essential conditions that say if life is very well well-behaved near the optimum and I'm
already nearly optimal I'll really get this of thing that way and the other thing
you should know is that there is an important class of functions for which this
theorem can be made a lot more constructive
OK and I will
I will give you 3 functions for which we can know all these constants and
other things before him
and we will we will visit this when we study interior point methods and those
functions minus the log of that don't write this down unless you just you know
you know responsible for the rest the edges of the rhetoric 1 minus the log
minus the log of the squared minus the middle of the day
might look to squared minus x
authority positive
n minus the log determinant of a matrix X
it turns out these 3 functions
we can see a lot more constructively about Newton's that
and not only that we can say constructively about these but that we in functions
to 1 another
OK we can say with the functions and all of the combination
and believe that it is these 3 functions that are there at the heart of
modernity here that the
so just that
this is little factor
OK so I'm at page 6 cover these bullet points so we typically have another
constant speed H a L there's some amazing exceptions
these 3 years among those exceptions
is a curious fact which is lost a lot of people which is
the rate of convergence in a sense is independent of the choice of norms
but the constants are not
and there is a mismatch
that is not the case for these 3 functions with the same energy so that
it very deep state
OK badges will lead that so
to form
Soviet Union mathematicians in Yuri Nesterov numerosity were 500 page book resolving the question and
it's a fantastic book and and other
very brilliant optimisation
a professor at Cornell wrote 120 page book just trying to make sense out of
the 5 pages and that's really of the 128 is so easy to read and
I spent a semester and have just trying to figure it out there and we
did actually some of early seed of
here also Newton's method we did not assume any convexity
only that the Hessian matrix
but is invertible
and well story have here before we get the prove
note from the statement of the convergence theorem that iterative Newton's method a equally attracted
to local minima and local maxima that is the statement of the theorem just as
much getting attracted to a point where the gradient is 0
linux . says that when we apply the method in practice sometimes we get points
where the Hessian of becomes singular
and when that's the case usually set of
In software is written so that you know if the Hessian is sufficiently singular then
we had some epsilon times the identity matrix to
and that's just
that's called like acquires the Newton method
and there used to be an entire field called causing Newton methods how many of
you know anything about causing
OK your name is Steve and what you know about aquifer
you heard it in what costs
and who taught that was here at MIT OK OK so if and when a
professor boisei requires Newton method
really OK I have to talk to Steve about that and so cuisine Newton methods
used to be all the rage because so what they are is a thinking
so go back 15 years in computing power
because you don't want solve large systems of equations from scratch at each iteration cited
and here I solve a large system of equations I get my Newton direction that
I go over here
right now instead of here
building my Hessian inverting it
I instead use information about this session
combine it with information about
at the gradient here
and some other thing to save a lot of work and unfortunately that's all I
know about causing Newton methods OK except just that they're designed they don't do full
Newton steps they don't do complete Newton steps
but they save on work
pages and
by various forces acting on the body of the there's a whole lot of in
my senses that is literally dozens of classical methods can actually have lecture notes somewhere
question methods
I should try and take them up 1 of these but I don't see users
much anymore again because computational power such that they're not as relevant at the moment
as they used to be
by the way are Katie Nemirovski is going to be giving a talk at MIT
on ice to talks 17th and 18th
but so this should be a big event this is this guy is
a giant really in in this in the field of optimisation yes
the with
I want you to know about
bright patches in the image those are all compressed to within range the neural systems
can handle and typically against differential coding thing comes in this lecture in division so
from regions next to one another will mutually inhibit one another in order to kind
of focus on the stuff is most important and suppress the rest
so typically this logarithmic or power law response is more sigmoid responses
some kind of contrast invariance is this b is built using this these is
and you suppress non maxima stuff stuff it's not the most salient thing in the
image gets supressed
together those two things imply that your code is going to be sparse so
you have
lots of ways of representing different types of features in the image
in your brain
but each of those things each of those filters or whether it is the firing
of some kind of feature is going to find a new relatively really on a
particular piece of image
OK so typically is very high dimensional representation lots of different filters that fire some
basic is the image but only few of them will be found in any one
time not only particularly salient points the image
so this process is important biologically because it meets means neural firings actually quite expensive
i mean you can fire listen if we save a lot of energy
a large part of the food you eat goes to just running brain
a large part of your brain is devoted to vision
and it's also useful for kind of salient so focusing in on things that are
important in the image and pulling them out so that the brain can concentrate on
the most relevant pieces
because there's just some examples of these principles
this is contrast colour opponent coding
so in each
images there are two hours
pointing to two regions some of which are coloured some which are not
and all of those regions are each for each
image to pair regions has exactly the same
pixel greater intensity of colour
so perhaps the most striking one is this
this nice brown
could keep here
rather orange one here there's are interviewed look on screen anyway another brown one here
but the human vision system and so that's completely different colours
and it's right they are in the real world different colours because the shadowing means
that the fate of the colours been modified
so what's happening is you can differentially you're looking on in the surrounding
distribution of colours and using that
two code what the colours
similarly with intensities know this back queries what scare the same intensity don't see that
because once in the shadows so you interpret the scene properly to get rid of
OK a couple more effects on the same line so bands classical fit
you should see
that these things are other non uniform intensity with some h and in the kind
of decay in an agent kind of decay
in fact the uniform intensity so what's happening is differentially cutting edge
and then the stuff that that's
next was being suppressed some extent this is an example not sure if you seen
this one from back if you look at the blue spot in the middle of
all seem to shrink
OK so what's happening is that you know
he is temporarily accommodated
so that it's kind of trying to suppress the signal because it's no longer interesting
this there's lots of other examples of these things but i'm just taking a few
OK so more principles of human vision
the architecture is pretty orderly multi layer
there are a number of vision regions we've got listen the next slide the signal
goes through these regions to go through the one that goes to be two of
the three
he goes into the forest try to get a set of these vision regions the
lower-level ones are kind of understood the highly ones much less well understood but at
least the signals progressing through an orderly chain of processing the processing chain is actually
relatively shallow compared to what you might think machine learning vision algorithms
so typically around eight layers maximum
the response within a few layers very often
and that's typically twenty to thirty neurons the say your responses can actually start coming
within about fifty milliseconds which is very very fast by your standards
we'd like to be able to do that with vision systems but typically vision systems
are much deeper than that
there's lots of chains of processing after doctor processes in order to get things to
so we have really attain the rapidity
this is the basic processing to the human brain has also
in the arctic should tends to separate things that you might find rather surprising that
separates localisation in recognition so the channel that recognizes things in another channel this is
where they are
and to a large extent those actually operates several separately you separate colour intensity processing
things like this
also top-down feedback attention context all very important so you you know scene you start
interpreting it in your attention goes to one point and you start interpreting that in
terms of the context surrounding it
so all of those things and then
mapping the representation is very very non uniform
so what's called topographic mapping written topic mapping
we'll see an example of that second year i is is very non uniformly sampled
and that sampling is repeated on the brain in the areas where we with the
brain treats
information in the spatial way
in such a way that the signal from the eyes basically mapped onto the signal
from the brain but is distorted this perceptions with other senses as well including hearing
things are come to that in a second
sir you the other thing is that a lot of the filtering and this was
going on is arranged in regular columns what are called the columns which typically contain
all little sensor processing different scales different orientations and it's kind of integrated within a
small region
and then passed on to the next the next level
and much of the processing is multiscale
let me just skip over these regions but you can see this a list of
basic regions
well will only mention a few of them later
they have some functionality but when you get about the to the functionality is particularly
v three v four gets a little bit vague exactly what's going on these are
rather different places of the brain the ones in the back of the brain
algerians in the centre of the brain theorize go through this interview brain in map
onto the back of your brain the first stage of processing
OK so written the topic mapping
this is roughly the sampling density of the retina
so the other
it's very very
so hello sorry for the time to
but all of that stuff from me and my computer and when there
a few things i need to tell you before i start talking the first one
is i am not enrico motta
in case somebody one you may see on your USB stick but was she was
to be talk
called semantic web applications by enrico motta and supported through the media
so my name is much like icon
from the nineteen institute the open university
the second thing
i want to tell you that
the good thing is that my talk with it quite well with what jim just
shown in this kind of a continuation making it just a bit more concrete we
see that in a minute the last thing
is that
i intended to put a lot of
live demos live demos of online things when are talking about web here fortunately as
you may know
that would be really possible so i will tell another story about what life demo
we look like if you were able to connect to the internet so
first using the semantic web
i mean
the title is not
say much about what the plantation is supposed to be so what
could there be two
i'm missing something
can we do is on this part
we continue like this is ten
in addition to not having is alive demos you will not be part of the
screen so whenever there would be something in this part we describe it as well
so we will have lots of very nice story today
so what is there
to use on the
antique web
well i mean you can think of the obvious technologies or RDF RDF a great
sparql all these things have been talking about
they are
this ten services infrastructure all these things about there
what i want to talk about is not all this thing is the knowledge information
and data which is why the semantic web is about is what is semantic web
and actually
if you look at a few
i believe what you just said
there is a lot of
now the question is
how other use
the semantic web are use this data on the semantic information that is out there
my answer is
by building yet
i will try to sort it because indeed it seems to be a bit
ninety two two
with a screen
doesn't seem a lot better
but what which is supposed to be the resolution differences
one thousand
yes that's better
thank you
and you and
and there
OK this is the lecture on
the singular value decomposition
but everybody calls it
the SVD
so this is the final and best factorization of the matrix
and let me tell you what's coming
the factors will be an orthogonal matrix diagonal matrix orthogonal matrix
so it's things that we've seen before
the special good matrices orthogonal diagonal
that the new point is
that we need to orthogonal matrices that a couldn't be any matrix whatsoever
any matrix whatsoever has singular value decomposition so a diagonal line in the middle but
I need to different probably different orthogonal matrices that to be able to do this
OK and this factorisation has jumped into important
and is
properly I think maybe the bringing together of everything in this course
1 thing will bring together is
like this the good very good family of matrices that we just added symmetric positive
definite remember the story with those guys
because they were symmetric their eigenvectors
work orthogonal
so I could produce an orthogonal matrix and it this is my usual 1
my usual 1 is the eigenvectors and eigen value
In this symmetric case the eigenvectors are orthogonal so I've got the good might might
ordinary has become an especially good q
and positive definite by ordinary land has become a positive
so this is
that's the that's the singular value decomposition in case of a matrix is symmetric positive
in that case I don't need to be 1 of the 1 matrix 1 orthogonal
matrix will do for both of us
but is it so this would be no good and in general because usually the
eigenvector matrix is an orthogonal
so this is not what I'm that's not what I'm after
I'm I'm looking for
times diagonal times orthography and let me show you what that means and where it
comes from OK
what is meaning
you remember that
the picture of any linear transformation this was like the most important
in 1806
and 1 my looking for now
it a typical bacteria
that go vector let me the ones
gets taken over to sun vector in the column space say you want so you
it is a 1
another factor
gets taken over here somewhere what am I looking for in this SVD this singular
value decomposition
what I'm looking for
it an orthogonal basis here
that gets knocked over into 1 orthogonal basis over there
that's the that's pretty special going to have to have an orthogonal basis
and there are also based
that goes over into an orthogonal basis so this is like a right angle and
this is the right angle
into an orthogonal basis in the columns
so that's that's our goal is defined
it because do see how things are coming together
1st of all can I find an orthogonal basis for this row space
Of course no did no big deal define an orthogonal basis Gram Schmidt tells me
how to do it start with radial basis and greater use grind through Gram Schmidt
outcomes an orthogonal basis
but then if I just take any old orthogonal basis than when I multiply by
there's no reason why it should be orthogonal over here
so I'm looking for this special set of where a takes these bases vectors into
orthogonal vectors over there now you might have noticed that the null space I didn't
include why don't I think that it it's you memory usual figure had a little
null space
and a little multiple
and of those there no problems there's no spaces they're going to show up at
on the diagonal of signal
so that that's not what we're
that doesn't presented the difficult are difficulty justifying the so see what this will mean
this will mean that a of times this
these regions the wire and the 2 up to
what's the dimension of this
rose space of the
so it can be a little smaller up to the ah
so bad
a B 1
is gonna be the 1st column facility here as well and here's what I'm achieved
I would like to have not only have to make these orthogonal but why not
make them orthonormal
make them unit vectors
so this
maybe the unit vector is here is the you want
and this might be
a multiple of
so we really what's happening is a V 1 is some multiple
of you 1 right under and these guys would be unit vectors and they'll go
over into multiples of unit vectors and the multiple univocal lambda anymore
I'm calling and sigma so that's the number that the stretching of
and similarly they need to do is to you too
this is what this is my goal
and now I want to express their goal in matrix language
that's the usual step think of what you want and then express it as a
matrix mobile occasion so
a V ones
signal 1 new actually here here we go
let me pull out these you want you to to you are
and then a matrix with this
but it's
everything now is going to be in this
in that in that
little part of the blackboard
you see that this
sense what I'm trying to do with my Figure 8 times the 1st basis vectors
should be saying 1 times times the other bases of the 1st places like vectors
is basis vectors on the row space the the basis vectors in the columns space
and the use the multiplying factor
so as a to
it is sigma 2 times you to
a v r is signal r times you are and then we got a whole
lot of zeros and maybe some zeros at the end but this is that's the
everybody can fairly accurately predicted position in this room or from outside moving to estimate
fairly accurately predict position so there are cases that really are fully observable that i
can sort hack
potential for observable
on the very close to put ball
and this is OK
so the hardest case i think is the part of the rule case so driving
a car
truly anything in in the real world where every officially is noisy the something state
but not complete
OK so far things are partially observable reinforcement learning planning is very difficult task it
would take it in six hours
OK so this example in several case today
and again if really have to be allocated into really interested i wanted to course
of the next year and we can go more in detail fourteen weeks
in some of these problems
so again active state observations
these are problem
you how map between
i know what
missing my transition slide
here OK so i got water
OK we have the activation function tells us how information that the states we also
know how actions how actions taken between states
OK so there there's
two of these two crucial part three
two crucial properties of it every ten function
OK so stationarity does not change over time
so let's see
i have
the year
australia's ooo
ladies and templates
so stationary function if i tried to predict
the average temperature as a function of
the day of the year
this is stationary function it's noisy
but the day of the year the pretty good average picture of temperature
what i tried to take the average temperature as a function of the day of
the week
clearly this differs about what time of the year year in OK so if you
just saw the day of the week and nothing else has transition function will be
nonstationary active role in the winter than when someone you know how to to determine
change from tuesday
OK that that depends on whether you're you're in the winter and summer resident function
today the year one three sixty five
OK that stationary has a site signal behavior
doesn't change over time
well global warming side
OK another crucial property his heart of a markovian decision processes or MDP
his her a markov chain markov model
more people right from start
OK right
to be accurate right
OK so
when the markov property in any single to problem is is probably european releases because
it simplifies
the problem substantially
OK make something the markov assumption
the next is only depend upon the previous state and the action
so where i go
from the states
to next state only tens or not aware was yesterday
now you say well
this the hacking you can always make the claim that problems marketing well actually you
OK you can always put enough information in just a description
to have a a marketing problem so imagine an elevator
which i think
the rest of the day people come in the morning they're all going up to
four work OK five PM there's mass exodus everyone's going down
OK so the arrival rate is changing throughout the day
and they say this is not markovian i don't have time in the state
the ten depends on time
the surface but time state
but everything upon which the transverse you could depend on the state and you make
it a marketing problem
and in extreme if you see marketers talk i think at the end of the
summer school
so assume
that the state is everything you see in the past
OK and that's surely markovian
you know you if it stays there is everything you've seen that you can know
you possibly no no no more
but key here the problem is the markovian you can always put more
efficient state making markovian so seemed like a big assumption was not
but the markovian assumption will grow simplify
how we solve these problems
OK now it's funny so far we talked about
modeling agent observations action state how it
how how this would be observe how it gets different places based on the action
to take
but we're talking about learning here more and more learning to do something right
OK so it's crucial have some notion of goal reward what is it that you
want to optimize
so OK obvious case of of of of reward simple goal you need to get
to that door
OK so you just make sure that the reward that you get the door greater
than they were not getting to the door
now you might want to get the shortest path to the door that is i
don't want to go all the way around
this way it's the door if i'm here
i want to go straight to the door
how do you get an agent to optimize
the shortest path or we put cost on actions
so you get minus one for every step you take and then you get hundred
going to the door OK
if you you can optimize that
then you can get shorter section
so if you want to infer behaviour you have make sure to reward function
rewards that behavior
OK but not all problems have explicit goals
OK so imagine that you've got mail delivery robots
there's no robot has become a lot has to go live at the mail offices
the males always coming in from today
so really is there's never any points during the day with this this this is
where i can say goal achieved undone because males
more malcolm and it's more of a dead melted two people as fast as possible
what sigma kappa nu metal may arrive OK let's see if the horizon problem because
on today tomorrow next year ten years from now
OK after about last that long OK but there are problems that don't have a
you have clearly reward you get plus one for say
getting every piece of mail to it's it's a it's adresse
but you don't have a single we can just get too and stop you optimize
over infinite horizon
or continuing horizon
so here we just assign utility you're reading more into decision theory using his own
you can also like optimise information
where zero mean
not present
and one would mean present
for instance you could see here
he would read
case one
not on the right
it is not below
and is not inside
and it has be present outcome of zero
absence of the outcome
by contrast to be taken logically opposite case
k seven
it stands on the right
stands below
stands inside
and displays the presence of the outcome
it's driving this data you are
both set of properties school of public space
and you are able to map
the cases in the level of the devil away in this public space
very simple things
this is
tableau way to present the time you see
and of course
these variables could be social science variables right
it is of course textbook example
this is also in a textbook
the same information
exactly the same can be summarized in the venn diagram
then diagram is produced by the just minor
this is just taken i just
coded this
table i got it read by the tasman software what you get
you get the visual representation of the same data
OK so hard to read this is not very real from the distance i hope
you can
graphically the basic idea
we have three properties rights
i have to go back
to go back is here
right below inside so the first properties right second is below thirty inside
so what the band diagram does
it's said that
the many different forms of here's a simple one there is much more complex ones
the first property is right
each property will
we learn cut the properties space into equal
or yes spaces so
the vertical line here
he is
this is the problem space into
what stands on the right-hand side over here
everything on the right of the vertical line has one value on the right has
everything on the left
has zero value
this first condition right
so on the right-hand side you have right
on the that you have no right
OK this left
it's called
this horizontal lines it's also private two
everything underneath is has one value on below this whole space here below
everything about has a
zero value on
this variable
this condition
it is not below
about right
below not below
finally you have this square here
across that the third property
everything inside the square
as one value on the inside variable
everything outside as zero value it's not inside
OK that's the property space
so you have splits the space into eight basic zones
three dimensions
and you're able to qualify
each one of these basic sounds
by combining the three
values so for instance let us take
going back to the van diagram sorry oops
so case one
it's not on the right not below not inside
let's just look at the conditions for time being
so case one indeed it is not below it is about
it is not on the right
it is on the left
and it's not inside
outside of the square so this is this
this is where case one is located
and so on and so forth
the second of information which is then in diagram
it conveys or
it contains
is the value of the outcome
so the dark shaded areas
this whole area with dark shaded area
and the zero value for the outcome
in this area here
the light shaded area
if the area
where you have a one outcome value
could someone please tell me
or express in another way
the area
where they one outcome is observed
one outcome so that the lighted area here
once in the content
that's part of it right
it is on the right
yes it is below and inside so is this one as k seven right
that's great
when you have performed the first ascent by yourself
because indeed there are two ways to express this area
there's a long way
they're always saying
well it is
this area
plus this area
right so we do everything that is on the right
below and inside this one k seven
it's also
what is on the right
and below and outside so case number eight
that's a long way
that's the complex
a way to express this area
that's what stands in the truth table
what you see does actually
is to try to express this area
in the shorthand man
it's called
it's a synthesis of information
doesn't change anything data
you simply learn how to express this in the shorter
and indeed the shortest way to express this area
and this has to have the density with respect to some
measure which need not be a probability measure
could be that measure which is not a probability measure
it has to be the same for all values of
good and
this is something that a kind of mentioned last time introduction but i would like
just restate that
so when i'm talking about
a nonparametric bayesian model here
and i'm talking about bayesian model just as on the last slide which might may
or may not be equation
what i assume is that both the parameter space and the observation space have
i have infinite dimension
this might for example be in the case of of the dirichlet process
where the process starts the prior
this you would be this parameter space would be the set of probability measures
actually subset of discrete probability
the the the random value that grow from the dirichlet process is what we call
the parameters not the parameters of the dirichlet process suppose would be the hyperparameters basis
the the second the second assumption that we have to make is if we if
we define nonparametric models in this way that we say OK
we want to accommodate in
a finite but arbitrary large number of parameters and so we use an infinite an
infinite dimensional space
then we need to have some way of
of actually evaluating the small do what we usually do with models either put probability
on something or condition something if we only have a partial observations we have only
seen a finite subset of this infinite
infinitely many degrees of freedom so for example
if you think of the gaussian process prior parameters something like like function or draw
function for the girls process priors
what we actually observe is not this function the whole function at each individual point
of the on the real line but it's something like a few points and we
assume that these values generated by this function
and so we have to be need to have some rule how we have we
we can substitute this subsample this discretisation fine discretisation of our function into the probability
model that we have and usually this involves
in some way or another integrating out
the remaining degrees of freedom
so that's what i call the partial observations of the random quantity we have has
the dimensions
he might be infinite
and only m of these are which some smaller number of pieces of
but conceivably this might also be like the is is something large but finite ten
thousand or something
and we observe only a few of those who i have never seen a nonparametric
we use the word is used
so this year
is you mean that we once we have a condition on on the sampling model
and we say something about the part of the posterior prior is that is that
the question
OK so
for this to exist at all
for me to make sense by the of here
the existence of densities
you need to have that the posterior is absolutely continuous with respect to the prior
so you you need this year
and this year is is a stronger condition which implies
so that means we have to
it's very convenient because this is all we have to cheque you don't have to
explicitly check
the posterior prime
we could have an expression like this conceivably we could have an expression like this
even if this this expression of this restriction is not satisfied
but but this is really a where where this breaks down
OK and any questions on that before we move on to
stochastic process construction
when we when want to
when we want to do the bayesian nonparametrics in the sense that we put a
probability distributions on infinite dimensional spaces
then we need some way to define the probability distribution and this is why why
so these mk had almost
so there and appended the the
you look at the k nearest neighbors right there certainly highly dependent
but they n over k
things left each of those things are very is one of k
and if they were independent you get is one right
and in fact you can show
let's see i what fifteen more minutes ten minutes
seven OK alright well i guess i will get to some of the stuff but
i think this is appointed really has to be made
it's appointed we saw empirically but but but which actually
after we sort empirically we
we realized what was happening
we thought oh gee you've got a real as the dimension it works very well
as you see for dimensions up to
fifteen or so
five thousand observations
and we said well you know this let's push up let's make the dimension higher
the dimension
basically it went unanswered
so under you grossly underestimated
and the reason for that
to see why that's happening it's not solely reflects the theory so far
to see what happening i think is that the person dimensionality still have something
if you do asymptotic variance something you should
as you know both the dimension go to infinity and the sample size for me
that tells you how big is the sample size b
i have to be in order for you to
to get a reasonable estimate of dimension
well it turns out unfortunately well this is looks horrible but let me just tell
that the sample size has to be of the order of
dimension divided by two factorial
this is very bad at super exponential convergence
so basically
essentially what that says is that unless you have sample sizes which
and are absurd even in these days
we should really trust dimensions over
o twenty
yes some of the trigger
and i believe this is not simply
a floor of our method
it's the floor
it's actually a problem with any method of estimating dimension
not linearly
because what happens is
all of these calculations rely
the nearest neighbour to appointing
in high dimension the nearest neighbour actually very far
you never less
the sample size
is of an order larger than the over two factorial the nearest neighbour distance doesn't
it was
some of this idea as
one will have
you know
it's a
it was
one of the
it's is going to be
i it
so we can
i thing
it's not
the of
one the
if you
it to be
i would like to say
for us
o four
what i want
if you wish to first
it was
that's what
i mean
he e
this is a list of
she just
yes she
she yes
she was here
she she
it is
and the
it was
what do due
i also made by the
she was
this is all this year
these are
o five
as you
all in all
so before the break
well somebody as well
now what happens
why is this quantity
but we're getting here
whether that's always nonnegative
this is obviously not the case
and actually we don't want it to be the case
see what we want to set p equals q
this is a random variable with expected value zero
because of people q we want to have a statistic that
well i will tell us the distance sierra
we want to really is to make the distance between p and q
therefore obviously
if you had a random variable which was always nonnegative
you would be
rather missus situation trying to estimate whether people skills
based on that
so that's what we've done is we've found a way
getting the mean
of that statistic right
so that means
if we have some data
x and y
that's was serious
and we might observe some values here
and then
all we need to do is
just put the threshold somewhere
and we say everything up here
means p is not equal to q
everything down there
it's all right
and then for the distribution with zero mean
and it turns out that this is actually asymptotically normal
that quantity here
so the probability mass of this these events is going to tell you exactly what
the error of taste
so we want this probability mass here to be in the order five percent or
depending on how conservative for want my case
what we have to do it
will have to find out
we we want to set a threshold
we want to get this point here
the next two slides are all concerned about getting this
right threshold
after me
now we want to get to scale
before we do so let me just give you a simple example
what the
and he actually does
so let's say b
this line is the normal distribution
and the dotted line
so the class distribution
that's gonna computed
well the function
that maximizes the discrepancy in the means
and that's the function here
so you can see
with the class distributions larger than the normal distribution
the that is very large
very easy be around
three negative
but obviously we want this function to be reasonably smart
and that's why
it doesn't just jump
so this is
what the
maximum mean discrepancy will give you
now the really cool thing is
in order to get all those bounds we don't have to do any work because
shifting has done all the work for us
so in particular what he showed is that
for the kernel of a u statistic so not to be confused with the past
windows kernel
well the massacre
this thing is also called the crown
the fact that is bounded by are
then the probability
that its expectation which will give us the
true the distance between distributions
minus the empirical estimate
the probability that this exceeds epsilon
it is less equal than
two times e to the minus in its own square or square
so that means that they get more data