section of thing which is going to open for business acumen
i'll check the website and see if it if
that's actually what you meant but it may be may something else
other questions
let me in general i encourage you to ask questions i know that that's hard
to do in a big lecture setting but we have an advantage over over other
courses particularly science courses we're not trying to prepare you for the astronomy part of
the EM cats OK so we don't have to cover a specific syllabus we're not
even trying to follow a textbook and so we have a little more leeway than
than is ordinarily true to ask questions and going we're direction so please feel free
to do that i reserve the right to to put the question off into into
the future or or into discussion section or something but do by all means ask
we have we have some freedom of action yes
an early final
let me think about that i prefer to avoid because then i have to invent
another final the problem with that is trying to make them come out even
i will say this that if i do an early final i'm probably going to
err on the side making it hard
but it's very hard to make them come out even but but but let me
think about them
other questions
it's going to be some of the so the question is what the discussion section
is going to be like are they're going to be discussion of the problem of
the problem sets are is going to be sort of a general discussion of course
material and the answer is both i think they will both in any given discussion
section there were probably both be an opportunity to talk about the previous problem set
out to clarify things about the next problem set and also some kind of activity
that sort extends in advance is what we've been talking about in class so i'm
hoping to do some of both if we veer too much in either one direction
that's probably not a good thing there will be other ways of getting help as
well if you start to have trouble on the problem set during the course generally
i'll talk about those of little bit on thursday
yes sir
however problems such great it very carefully let's see
i think will probably it'll probably be on a kind of zero to twenty point
schedule but but let me say this about the problems that they're going to be
two kinds of things on the problem one are kind of quantitative problems which have
the right answer those are relatively easy to great on some kind of the point
scale you give partial credit and so forth
but we will also because this is of course that's not only about the specifics
of this topic but also about science in general were also going to have things
that look kind of like essay questions and problems that those are a little harder
to great in this way but we've got a great in the same way so
that we can add the points and all talk a little bit more about how
those are great and i will say one thing and one thing that we do
is we make sure that each problem is created by
each problem or as is graded by one t air by myself so that we
don't have different people so that if you're in this section it's not like you're
all the problem sets for that section are all greater by your section leader in
some other section leader great all the other problems because that that leads to imbalances
of various kinds so we're we're we assign each problem to a specific person for
the whole class but it's basically zero through twenty scale although what that means varies
depending on what kind of problem it is also a little bit more about that
i will also say there's a rather detailed lateness policy that's linked to the closest
server please read that we're going to stick to it and one of the features
of that is that there will be answer sheets problem sets are typically do thursday
they'll be an answer sheet up the following tuesday
so if you don't get it done by five days after to do your toast
because the answers are posted
other questions
great let's start
this is this is very useful
all right
this is going to be all kinds of fun right
planets planets around other stars but planets in general so let's start by talking a
little bit about audit planetary orbits
you probably know some of the story originally in the old days
people used to think that the earth was the center of the universe of the
earth was in the middle and planets went around them in circles that's not much
of a circle but you know what i mean and so everything was circles around
the earth
and that's what planets did where planets also included to the way their way of
thinking the sun and the moon as well
and so you have these circles around their this is this is what's called the
geo centric model
or in the middle and its associated with the name of a greek astronomer named
and the problem with this model is very simple namely that if you actually go
out and observe where the planets and the sun and the moon are named after
night after night it doesn't work very well so this doesn't fit the observations
doesn't fit observations
exclusion principle you have to keep shifting the energy's and since you only have 1
electron here as you move out in this case sodium you'll find your filling 2
by 2 and all of the bonding orbitals are filled with the tiny energy difference
and this is out of the reading this is the same same idea only it's
done in the case of of lithium and lastly this is the idea of trying
to get across that here's the metal sitting at rest and now there's a electrical
potential put across at which wants to move electrons even with a modest potential that's
enough to disrupt the bonding here
in the uppermost levels in cause electrons to rise and then move along the
antibonding orbitals quite freely
so that gives us a sense of what's going on in the conductivity of something
like copper sodium but now let's think about something like magnesium magnesium is a metal
was able what's going on with magnesium magnesium has 3 s
but it has 3 to
case of magnesium magnesium history has to so if we start filling magnesium estimation and
we're going to fill 2 by 2 all the way up to the top
all the way up to the top of this is and the Pisa up here
what happens when the piece split into the bands
that's the real issues and mercifully what happens in the case of magnesium is this
is the SVM but for magnesium the peed on the bottom of the penalized
below the top of the acid so recently means this is now the band and
the band energy levels are available so that when we feel the top of the
yes Men we can continue to move into a range of energy that allows for
motion so that were able to account for both unpaired electron atoms and paired electron
atoms by
this overlap of our energies and I think there's a cartoon you're reading that indicates
the shows what happens with the energy levels as a function of distance and you
can see that the p band is now dropping below the
on top of the and so allows for continuous filling into more states and so
this now accounts not only for such things as electrical conductivity but reflectivity metals have
lost because the photons of visible light have the capacity to excite electrons which immediately
cascade down and reflect back so you know band theory became
widespread popularity in the twenties it was known only among few physicists in the thirties
the scientific community in the forties infected the popular culture if you talk to your
grandparents will refer the forties as the big band error
because of this you know maybe you thought maybe you thought that the reason the
big band era was named Big band was due to people like the Glenn Miller
and Benny Goodman and Tommy Dorsey not was due to felix bloch walter height and
fritz london so I don't want to think about those bandleaders anymore this is the
band this is the big right here right so
people now let's go on to something a little bit more interesting 1 of the
other shortcomings that was a manager of addressed by drew was the ability to distinguish
between metals and insulators so let's see if this theory can do that so let's
go to something like dying so if we start with diamond if we stay here
carbon as a single gas molecule and we start off with 2 ask
and 2 and we know that this then hybridizes to maximize bonding capability so this
is now SP three put to here for reasons that will become apparent in a
minute so this is now carbon in the diamond configuration as a single gas molecules
there sort of a sort of 1 hand-clapping but this is this blown carbon that
willing to form diamond and skip over the diamond and the let's just go to
diamond crystal so it will happen at these levels will divide and in accordance with
poly exclusion principle will start up here with the anti bonding and will start down
here with the bonding and what happens in the case of the alignment is that
when the population of anti bonding
there is an energy gap between the bottom of the anti bonding orbitals and the
top of the bonding orbitals
so we have 2 bonds here before we simply have a single bond this would
have given us an estimate these these would be the set all come from S
S 3 forming sigma bonds but in this case there is a big divide here
so this is the energy gap or some people call the band gap and the
energy here is given a simple piece of energy the band gap energy and in
the case of diamond the band gap energy is 5 . 4
electron volts
what happens now
but still that's 1 2 3 4 and accountants properly assuming we've got a single
occupancy we filled to the top of the valence band this is known as the
valence band because these were these were bonding orbitals
we filled to the top of the valence band and now if we want to
apply electrical potential to cause these electrons to come out of the bonds and move
up and down the crystal we gotta come up with 5 . 4
which is a substantial amount of energy and it doesn't happen so as a result
of this is an insulator
so we now have the capacity to distinguish between metals and insulators insulators insulators have
high band gaps typically on the order of about 3 electron volts
metals metals have
but no bandgaps no bandgap continuous availability of these closely spaced orbitals are and why
we're in the neighborhood this upper this upper band that consists of all the anti
bonding orbitals is called the conduction band
the conduction band because this doesn't involve electron is in
this upper band free to move and under the influence of electrical potential
so to have valence band conduction band band gap
analysis look at 1 of the ones with silicon silicon
was look at silicon silicon is in the same family is group for S P
3 hybridized only in the case of silicon we're gonna start with 3 s atomic
orbital and the 3 p atomic orbitals which to to give us the three but
so consider
linear problem with just two water so we are trying to estimate
three coefficients they they all said and then a one and a two
sometimes even though they y is
centre so that there's not that you can forget about this so that but generally
the offset is not included in the independent
so again this is our people go
linear regression problem but we had these
two there
expression of
and so since we're using least squares their function is a
and the contours of these ellipses that our
sitting in the coefficient space and that's what we're trying to pick here so all
the possible but of a one all the possible values of a two and there
are surfaces sitting on top of
and so again this are the contours of the square and somewhere that is the
in the case of these courses
the minimum so
complexity penalty
can be represented by these diamond
so remember
penalize formulation is equivalent to the
constrained formulation so this penalty can be equivalently stated as saying that sort but if
a one plus up to about toys less than a certain value and that is
what we are representing here this is
the the meaning of
if the if the coefficients estate within this region
you made in that
so what if i one plus up to about fe two less than a certain
threshold and so on
the lasso solution is the first point where these conductors touch
in the case of reach regulation that the constrained region is actually a circle
so so
that's that's what you almost never get seed coefficients with with reach regulation in high
dimensional space these diamond becomes our lloyd with many many many corners and so when
they when they did
what i see evidence of this approach is one of the corners that's when you
get a ball into the coefficients equal to say
one so as as the number of a viable increases they
they let's say this straightforward quadratic programming way of finding
the last so solutions gets more demanding computationally and so some iterative algorithms have been
proposed to to approximate the analysis solution and one of those is called the forward
stagewise linear regression to approximate the the the solutions and that is an goes roughly
like this
so at the beginning we start with all the coefficients equal to see that we
need to small epsilon and get to determine the number of iterations and so there
is good thing goes into these loop
it first selects the best predictor out of all that
that fits the core issue of so
we have some coefficients already
that are non-zero and so this is what we call the
they the difference between y and according to model
and so we're looking for one predictive model that for best fits this rules again
the difference between these two terms is what we call the issue and then we
increment the coefficient associated with that particular operator by a little bit
and it's so to this is also called epsilon
it's stagewise linear regression and so we need to maintain each coefficient by a little
so after again jet to determine the number of iterations many of the coefficients will
be zero namely those that were never updated
and in general they the absolute value of these coefficients is smaller than than the
absolute value of the
and what i solution the least square solution
and here acts as the inverse of the complexity parameter so namely we so
lambda equal to see domains normalisation lambda equal to infinity means a lot of realization
so we start with a lot of decision with maximal right ascension lambda equal to
and so the meaning all the coefficients are equal to zero and then we as
algorithm involves
it can only
relaxes the relaxation and eventually we get to the and regularize solution
all the pertinent elements a preferences for this iterative way of computing the
that's so that they
their technique called lars
by from last however it is limited to least score
and then more recently which we mentioned in the beginning and so the ground electoral
legislation which allow us to apply
this framework to different loss functions so lisa square is not best function when you
have outliers and and it's so it's it's it's better to have least absolute deviation
of something called the who are laws for was regulation and so the this this
paper extends that framework or extend this iterative framework into the water was loss functions
and so again as in was evolving
what we have here is something like this and this is what are called the
coefficient path at the beginning
all the coefficients are equal to zero the the the the horizontal axis here is
the evolution of the
here i took the wrong picture because i wanted to to one where n was
here but we know that
n and land
how they are related
but again so that the horizontal axis is the evolution of the iterative algorithm the
vertical axis is the value of the confusion and what we see is how they
want the coefficients evolved at we relax
the realization fronto parallel decision to not decision so there in all the coefficients are
zero in this problem
o which comes from in there
the prostate cancer data that it's also so widely available
out there i think there were one two three four five six seven eight a
lot of rules and so
the first level enters the model and its coefficients starts growing and then another viable
interest model later on and so on there
red bar here is indicative of the optimal value of the relaxation parameter like in
going to do the following so
first i would like to
two something which is kind of
i think new
example of application for this for visualization and for motion estimation that i will discuss
some connection between the lab class and
and she equation
i'm planning to talk about semisupervised learning and clustering and this is
possibly an ambitious
OK so
need to
show you what this embedding so part of this talk about using this again vectors
as a tool for dimensionality reduction
let me just show you what it looks like
this is actually
and you
was red
so there are more than half of them you can see above
many of them you can which is a good thing and basically the same images
of handwritten digits
which embedded in this what appears to be a three dimensional space but it's actually
two-dimensional up since only the projection on the screen using principal components analysis
so this image is taking us points each point
each image
it's just the pixel matrix you can flatten it out as the vector put it
in a high dimensional space the dimensionality being the number of
then reduce the division out OK
so that
so this is
principal components analysis
and need to
so you can kind of see the principal component analysis
bind to them altogether although it's not so bad
now you can
well was a
you can see that
you can see that actually
manifold methods at least
finally tends to you know have some much nicer structure this digits of the same
kind of close to get so
so unfortunately you can see
you just have to believe
that if you
look back you see seven some lines and if you look above the ninth of
may each image is just representation is just to leave the label was the actual
people in the space
i think the point in three dimensional space in each point is labeled as a
little bit of the
of the actual digit it's cut
there are actually four future by nine
and if you think about why that may be so
the force around
if you think about why this may be
in fact it's about point i suppose
they don't know how to use it
and why is that well if you think about what it is
you can see that
if you can
and so
if you have one nine and seven
how do we go from four to seven well one way to go is first
to complete a
and then remove the bottom of the list
right so nine is actually in between four and seven so that's what you
so it's kind of cute
and you can imagine so this is actually useful for many data because people do
want to see what they look like people want to see structure in the data
is in fact a lot of statistics
you know a lot of classical statistical methods to do exactly that like
multidimensional scaling for example
people use it for various purposes for visualizing different relations
between objects and so on
let me
so here's another application which
i'm not
here's the problem so the problem here is to estimate
the motion of the person in this motion is
so you don't actually
of course
again there is no rat so you should believe me that impact around
so this motion
he's actually
there is that i was walking
there is a bunch
i you you see that something like that and this cameras allow you to reconstruct
o point on the surface of the person's body
OK so it's kind of working point five
now the question is well you would like to be able to identify well actually
the question they
the interested in is to be able to identify angles between joint like this and
and so this was
ignored the letters from and these were the models this was the same thing i
did many models that we accepted
in these
indiana's simulations and then i plotted the other models on it
and notice that we incorporated all the models
in an hour
there was inserted prior this there was that norway
did a study where they actually strider separate separate out with air
these two things
and notice where it went
smack on top of vehement
they determine about ten percent
ten percent the drop was due to
ten percent the drop is due to screening twenty percent drop is due to
imagine terribly
conclusions from model them
bayesian approach ideally suited for comparative effectiveness research if you know what that means is
if you don't know what it means
the bayesian approach encompasses the other six miles probability distributions are parameters are necessary for d processing
predictive uncertainty
i would like dredge this up for the occasion
the demonstrate to my knowledge in japanese
seriously i'm told
that this
becoming bayesian salami clinical development
and for those many a view who speak japanese if it in fact says
pay no attention to this idiot
and please don't tell me
so this is the change genes
attitude in
the medical world generally
about the bayesian approach and looking for something better we've achieved this level
they randomized trial
and we sort of complacent and i mean after all the randomized trials over sixty years old
what are the innovation you know has remained essentially unchanged for sixty years
think about
we are complacent with this level
and to take it beyond is difficult
because they worry that you're gonna be throwing out the baby with the bathwater
on the janet woodcock who's the directorate at the time and still is well
the center for drugs that year after year it's a very powerful person
was lamenting the sorry straight
the sorry state
drug development generally
hand suggested that improved utilization of adaptive and bayesian methods could help resolve low success rate
andy thee
expensive phase three clinical trials
the latest estimate the cost for developing a drug
is one point eight billion dollars
anne much that's is
in phase three
and much of it due to the fact that
the you know many other drugs fail
and so you have to pay for one with the other
can't use a bayesian designs that andy understand since i got there ninety nine
we've had
over three hundred trials
designed and run most the run
and accent on the run i mean like a lot of things that you really need in the bayesian literatur
um is you know be great to do this trial
but a course nobody's ever done try
we've designed trials that we've actually run
device companies
many devote many designed by very consultants the over twenty five successful approvals
i've devices taking exclusively a bayesian approach
i give you one example
drug companies most the top forty
companies are taking the bayesian approach sometimes
you know wholehearted way tyre
programs are to start taking a bayesian approach sometimes it's they just getting their toes in the water
so that if this train leaves the station
with e force that some people think it's going to to leave they wanna be on it
some areas the application essentially every area of application just a contrast oncology and migraine
oncology endpoints usually long in coming as you get information it takes a long time to get information about
what they
how the drug was doing in individual patient with my brain registration and pointy end
point that you after uses to make a decision
is two hours pain-free
so it's
essentially immediate information
these are in my short rods
order of common this
bayesian adaptive trials stopping early relate sometimes
you get to the end of the trial and you wish it were over because
they thought about this you of this cannot make sense from the standpoint of the
plum pudding model
this can make sense
because the plum pudding model says you've got uniformly distributed charge so far that positive
charge uniformly distributed and look at the choices of brilliant experiment you shoot neutrals he
shot alpha particles which have a charge of plus 2 so i got plus 2
zooming in at high energy against a wall of positive charge and most of the
stuff goes flying through so you just say well this is like a bullet going
through pumpkin so what's the big deal but how do explain some of these going
way way back and that's when rover says this can't be right I'm going to
come up with something else wants to come up with this model to say that
the positive charge is not uniformly distributed I wanna say quite to the contrary the
positive charge is concentrated at the center in tiny tiny tiny volume so got this
tiny volume with in case of gold 79 + of charge and gets electrons out
here somewhere
and the vast majority of the atom is
this is a lot like democracy
being and avoid the convoy
so now I've got my + 2 little projectile coming in and and plus 2
zooms right through
but there's a positive 79 so the positives deflected so there's a little bit of
deflection because + repels but once in a while 1 of these questions comes in
almost all access and it gets whipped around by the moment repulsive forces so that's
Rutherford's explanation of this set of data
so by the way
there is a 3rd person there's rather Rutherford Geiger there's Marsden Marx's interesting character Morrison
was not too too different from you know Morrison was essentially you're out he he
left school for a couple years he was he was he hadn't got his undergraduate
degree and he come back and Rutherford accepted him lab I think the man was
something like 20 years of age so he said the moznost you don't take these
data only give you the dataset of the scattering angles of
the atoms his arm did model for this test the assignment
get busy
so well
Morrison came up with a model and as you go through 802 in understand electrostatics
electrodynamics you'd be able to do this analysis b is the assumed cross section of
the nucleus and then on either side is nothing so you've got a huge distance
between centre to center and so all always is doing is asking what must be
the if I've got a wall of nothing with spots of high positive charge and
this is my scattering data what must be the relative size of the spots versus
the nothing and solve the problem and he concluded let's get his name on the
board had he deserves to be born Mazda so Marsden concluded buys analysis that the
radius of the nucleus and this is a rather 4 by the way coining the
term it's a nuclear models the nuclear model the radius of the nucleus as compared
to the radius of the entire Adam is on the order of about 1 to
10 thousand 1 to 10 thousand so indeed we are talking about a lot of
void and a tiny little bit of extremely dense b
so they published this and watch the results you think about the finally solved that's
terrific array science at Terri-Jo's eyes out
the reaction to the model was strongly negative do revision was the typical reaction they
said like this is stupid 1st of all this thing can sustain itself you've got
a positive charge here with negative charge
around it cools losses the negative will be attracted to the positive and the collapse
so that's the 1st objection nuclear collapse everything all the electrons fall into nucleus
In the data suggest that's what it is that's the problem is that the period
of the day can explain it so course theoreticians Brussels knows how that said real
to the slaying of a beautiful theory by an ugly fact
nuclear collapse so the cool forces kilometer electrostatic forces are drawn out only to write
you know it means the woman forces and the story right number 2 said was
be able to accommodate kernel inefficient way
so i
i i i might become a bit about later
in maybe tomorrow of on friday but for now you should be sure that we
it's too much maybe in our
general framework
another thing that few
you might notice that there point that we have one degree of freedom
because the the length of this vector doesn't matter in binary classification
because we're going to classify with the findings of this product that's i can scale
w by any
positive constant which means that without changing the sign of the classification which means that
they make this i can make a better longer or shorter
without changing the
the plain so without changing the
the output of the classifier
this for now
we have is that the degree of freedom
OK please ask and questions
all the time especially in the beginning because you don't understand something right at the
beginning then going to be
i'm going be
but we're going to get through the red
i don't wish i with her at me
whenever you there's something that
should be explained that year
so now
and i think about the classifiers so what so what is now
the online aspect of online learning is different from lake regular
batch learning because you don't think of having a training set act as the usual
framework of statistical learning theory refers the
that the lectures by the
here you're changing the
game changing the protocol between the environment which is provided the data the learner which
is trying to to infer something from the
why are you doing that because this helps you to come up with different algorithms
with different analysis under different function and then going you're going to see now why
this is true
so the idea is that learner in online learning
now on the on line x i'm online learning learner
are of search
for example
for example nothing freeman
with this sequence of of examples which are pairs
of instances and labels
a stream of examples is just possibly
on sequence
a pair of instances and labels
which we assume are generated by some devices
and we all know about the introduction of this is that this is just an
arbitrary sequence of examples
how is the learning rate to interact with the stream
so in this argue explaining your protocol of online learning learning
in round
because it's online that you're not learning is what not going to get this treatment
seems this would be possible but it's gonna get a one example of the time
on each around the
around the
one more about
what's going to happen
next is the xt is observed
then the prediction
it is it
compute the
the prediction is why
nine of w minus one
in the brother
so what is that even if one is the current mean right
a part of painted by the online learning
as it
observe the three k
so you may major in that
there is some initial people
initial set of weights that with which the learner starts at the beginning
and then as it goes through the stream
has the chance of
that being the weights
the stream in order to
better classify
for the elements industry
report if you haven't seen it
and are doing business in these five criteria
culture these form microforms
i think how quickly you get to form retail
will really differentiate one developing countries from another
the usta further questions really about the poorest countries in the world
and don
i've it and other chapters recall flat world they don't understand the world isn't of flat not even close it
intermediaries are
four forces at and communities are not in the flat world and that we don't tend to them
on could very much on flat in the world from the inside
the first i simply called to say
and that's communities caught in the grip of is worth losses similar and that everything
from rural africa to rural india
rural russia women
parts you know no diving around country to a lesser degree
that just start to sick
on to be able to take part in the world
and actually talk about interesting ways of collaboration
people are coming up to address some of those problems and talk about the gates
foundation which i think is a very interesting
grand challenges model
a second group called the two unlabelled
again that's rural india rural china and beijing and shanghai depend upon galore
seen the riches
but they need steps to if they are going to be able to participate in this
end on
what i talk about areas i'm a big believer that in in in governments that the
every anti-poverty program is run governments
and local governments and is really a challenge basically today and go community and anti-globalization
movement to make actually local governments
focusing on the priority look in india today india nineteen ninety one when they first there
they are open to the world
i had a hundred million dollars in the bank india was going broke to one
can talk about a country that way today india's one hundred twenty billion dollars in
reserves that's the good news the bad news is one hundred thousand rupees allocated from
new delhi
the village outside galore
on by the time it gets
down ten thousand rupees
so actually dealing with just the internal change governance
we have a huge impact in building a step stool
for people who want to be in globalization
third group whether two frustrated
on the anatomy is a lot easier most
see what's going on in the flat world they want to be part of it
but still very much left behind
and so
two frustrated and the fourth
simply what i call to many toyotas
because when the world was flat at three billion people arrived with on god bless
version of the american dream for them how staccato store microwave and a toyota
if we don't find an alternative source of energy we are gonna burn up heat up
this planet faster than any time
in it in the history of our country
end on or we're gonna be in the global struggle with china overall
china's foreign policy is very simple
summarized in one sentence taiwan and looking for oil
that's all china's doing
and so on
for understandable reasons and so
again get back to their platform can tell you a lot about you know why yes three dollars again
so on
i don't i don't have a magic cure for any country now but it does
seem to me that's what the world bank identified around those issues
on on
of form retailers one
and the other is around how we collaborate
with them give a quick example because just important question that a given the book
on each beat very interesting project in india they adopted a village
and you know their business and that someone did the work of said you know there's a billion people who
they want to a three dollars a day a lot more than you delivered
fifty and one hundred thousand dollars
and we have to think about how we can actually create products at a profit
there itself so they adopted a village in the book i don't the village in
end they went around the spent six months are just asking people
trying understand what they mean but it was
and one that actually could provide one things they discovered was that
people really needed cameras to take pictures
but then you can rest get license pictures you licenses with an
get a picture from license sometimes people would walk all day from one village
to the nearby town that happen photographer
each piece that no problem
we do pictures
you know
so they said on a given campus you know almond you know those
printers and they can print out pictures no problem then discovered no electricity
so they thought about for a while and they said no problem solar-powered
cameras end pretty picture pictures and they developed a mobile
picture by basically photography and print
and they gave it to a women's and go
in this
count fields are working
end on
they want see you know how they would use weather could produce a business well
what they discover for small set just what you know indian villagers like anybody else
the last pictures so something they wanted family pictures and you know when pictures and
pictures when the visitor came to town you so that all kinds and
these women developed a great business objectives
end on after your age became that's great is so great you go
give us a camera back
and this is what you mean we
what are you talking about we've got a business going here you know and on
ah it's he said
you can keep the camera if you can come up with a business plan
well you will pass
x amount money you know
on the paper and inferential they can and they did
and because that's always sustainable is like scale
if it's
you know sustainable network
as of collaborating there were not just coming so when you people only these this but
really getting down
very low
understanding what people need and then trying to design solutions around their life
i think that's
it's one of the students you although if you look like this
the implications might see while on
that's what i've been here all day you know um
really thinking about and then having the pleasure to talk about why i think your
you know all the open university you're doing is a really pioneering i think it's
incredible and i've really learned more about it today i think it's an enormously powerful
we can draw
a bunch of lines
and that's what these these lines come from here an example that you can you
can try
and there's a few details like kind to the u
you you want to be careful about how you all these lines and you can
check this easily by just plotting many line drawings and seeing that there
being generated in the right way
it's easy to
it's easy to generate lines in such a way that you
actually covering more of the
input space of lines in summary in some regions and other
let's assume that we've we've come up with some way of generating lines that we're
happy with it seems to be covering the space that we
the space of decision boundaries
uniformly according to what we think is is likely before we see any data
all right so we know how to generate lines
now we need to distinguish between lines which seem to be
which seem to be
appropriate or consistent in in some way with the data that we that we see
so it's introduce new concept of likelihood
given that we have received some data
how likely is it that
one particular line is the right line
so let's have a simple
measure for this so we've got something which will expresses the probability
and i will say
well this is essentially saying is that for some line
if this line splits of the data perfectly soul yes is are on the positive
side of numbers on the negative side
then that particular line has probability one
and if it doesn't then as probability zero
so all that's essentially saying
let's generate a whole bunch of line so i think you are generated maybe like
a thousand lines and look at the ones which have probability
probability one
so the ones where all the
all the right places on the positive side of the line and all the blue
negative side flying
all right so we generated a whole bunch of lines which
which fit
so now we've got some choices we could
we could stop that we could take one of the lines around
and say OK all of these
all of these lines
fits our training data in some way so we just we just choose one and
that's going to be
what we used to distinguish new new test examples
or we could
all of these lines try to do something else
so as to the latter
give you another
another concept here which is the use of
the use of bayes rule
to help with this this kind of problems
so the bayes rule
basic basic property of joint and conditional probabilities
when people talk about bayesian methods the
the the
the inside that's
using is the bayes rule doesn't just have to be
about things statisticians usually call random variables
you could also be reasoning about the probability of different parameters
which is a fundamental
change in statistical method from from what was classically
applied to used to be that premature with some quantity of you can reason about
with probabilities but why not let
let's give it a shot so if you are interested in the probability
of some parameters
given some data
then you can use bayes rule you
look at
the likelihood of
different different data points
and you integrate this over
so use bayes rule to give you a posterior probability of your
parameter space
so having
obtain this kind of quantity here which will look at an example of just now
we can then use this to
make predictions about new data points
if we have a distribution over what we think of parameter should be
we've got something which represents the space of all possible lines
and we have some measure
of how likely each line is
we can actually use that distribution
to give us
what's called the posterior probability
given the new test data point where we don't know the
class for example
we could say what's the probability
of this test data this acts in the sea
a position unlabelled given all the data have seen
here's another application of bayes rule where we
during some operations and then going back to this was good for filling in the
missing missing elements with missing data
so in some cases you
i alex at something else
OK so
so one day i was this early this intermediate integration you would like to combine
come so we have two come
so i also talked about generalizing comes and he talked about what the kind learning
so we try to find a linear combination of
so we have these combination coefficients here one
which kernel
and then i would like to find the optimal combination coefficients and you can do
this by selling slightly more complex optimization problems which is called semidefinite programming or second
order cone programming and they can find the coefficients
alpha coefficients
what pictures
and the coefficients what kind of at the same time
so it's globally optimal solutions
this is one way of generalizing
another way was to
extent can have a joint feature maps so you not only have come on x
the inputs but can't on the output is about
so we include the labels
in the future
and the type function
and there different ways of using this point conditional interview or i of about the
maximum margin
structured output learning
here the idea is that the
try to learn a function f of y given x
which scores segmentation why were given x
and in this function we can predict label
just by maximizing the function of all possible y
OK so you have some
all possible labellings and just take predict the labelling which has the maximum score
it's one not for training what can we do so we can
so we end sequence is a sequence here
here the input sequence of the of the
and now we would like to f such that
the score for the true labeling
it's much larger than the score all the wrong labels
so compute the difference you have this kind of optimization problems i would like to
find the function f
such that
this difference here this is the score the true labeling minus the score of a
problem labeling
this large so greater than one
in a few cases the allowed to be smaller than one
but but this the very
and we have one constraints from leaving
because they can be exponentially many different probably
i mean for instance when you consider segmentations of sequences so there might be really
i mean different many different possibilities of labour
OK so
other questions
i'm going to use this in the applications later again
so how can we solve these kind of problems so you would like to solve
this now i used actually
so here
he we still had the function f in you
now i'm using the kernel function the joint feature map between
between x and y and the trying to come up with a linear function here
and we try to maximize the margin between the true in the wrong
the idea is that the
solve the optimisation problem what small set up from labeling
it may be just one wrongly leaving in the beginning we solve the optimisation problem
this is the number of constraints still small
and then
using this the solution we can find other constraints other labeling
don't satisfy this constraint
so we add one more complex
how to wrap things up
this is in the passive learning case basically trying to adapt
you're partition to match the boundaries in change points in the image
and if that's working well and it was working reasonably well here you can see
that this partition is starting to point us towards where boundaries are and so forth
o thing that comes to mind say well maybe i'll take some
passive data
like this one the partition and the partitions starts to tell me where i might
want to be taking more samples because it's kind of pointing me towards the boundaries
transitions and change points in the image
so that's kind of the idea of how you might do active learning here
the passive learning stuff we just some money we get this adaptive partition and now
what we're going to do is we're going to do what i just suggest will
take a sort of a random sample
our points uniformly across the image and then
device and adapted partition so we split up for simple budget take half samples to
find this adaptive partition the next gives us course indication of where
the boundaries in the image and then we're going to do is
only in those boundaries cells
with the second half of our sample budget and then apply the same sort of
recursive dyadic partitioning idea
within those resampled areas and that allows us to kind of get a refined estimate
of where the boundaries
so just by repeating the recursive partitioning idea twice using the first step to kind
of give you could indication of where the interesting action in the images in the
second step taking additional samples more densely in the region in repeating the kind of
partitioning idea
OK so
what does this buy you you can work out an upper bound here
for this two-step kind of approach and what you get is
ignoring logarithmic factors and their decay rate that's like one over
ten to the minus one hundred d minus one plus one over t so we
didn't have this one over d
this would be one over d minus one which was the minimax rate that we
actually determine when we are focusing on the simpler problem of boundary fragments scissors game
very close to the best we can hope to do because of boundary fragment cases
just to subclass of this more general kind of image processing problem
it turns out also that if you have appeared just two stages but did it
multiple stages you can try to chip away at that
one over the there and just get down to an arbitrary epsilon seeking get arbitrarily
close to what we know is the minimax lower bound for this class by using
this recursive dyadic partitioning procedure in multiple stages coupled with additional resampling in the tiny
boxes in the refinement at each step
so that's the main result and this was what exactly what we're doing in this
example that i should the first part of the talk we just took random samples
there would be are noisy measurements this would be the result you get from the
recursive partitioning algorithm if you
half of samples about a thousand randomly get a partition
from those use those to help refineries sample more these are the places real go
back and some samples per second half of samples the other eight thousand and the
resulting image looks like this and so that the kind of points to look at
our around the boundary of the lake on the island which are much more resolved
in the adaptive method and they are in the non adaptive approach
and this is the real
have first application of this is something called ballistic imaging this is where you're shining
l a laser through
scattering medium and what's going to happen is you're going trying to detect the shape
and presence of the computer in this has
many applications in bio bio imaging and so forth this is the simulated experimental stated
where they put a small excluding object more shining a laser through the scattering medium
and then trying to figure out where and what the shape that object was if
you just risk and uniformly with your laser raster scanned across the field of view
the result you get this
this reconstruction of that whereas if you take a scanning and lower resolution and then
go back to refine you can get much
better estimates this is this idea is actually something people have tried use in various
one of the last syllables segments of the
the trio is on the question of how do humans use active learning and as
i mentioned at the beginning
in terms of things like vision and so forth it's known that people
are obviously doing something very active and selective about how they focus their attention and
so forth
and what we want to try to see is in the context of the problem
where that we understand very well mathematically characterized these
you bounds on the sample complexity and so forth can we see if humans come
because the light of the stars outshines
the planets planets shine and so the only way to see the planets is vs
weak gravitational effect they give on on their host stars
but this is not my main point because because we see that the only indication
mark there's a lot of that matter that is that there is not made of
stuff that makes up some plants
so the way to get to that is to define what is called a master
so in the solar system the master light ratio
it's not too high because most of the mass in the solar system is in
the sun anyway with some more small corrections to jupiter and you can forget about
everything that
but let's look at galaxies and this is the only major of the optical light
of our galaxy
galaxies are rotating
and if you could actually not seat in the optical light but see it guys
and you could see through the twenty one centimeter line of hydrogen
then you would see
that you know if the optical light is the size of about ten killer part
six the gas extends out to work at least the for thinking about six away
but the cool thing you can do is that you can measure the rotation curve
of this stuff because remember velocities are relatively easy to measure the doppler shift
and so all
if you can do that you can try to wait
a deluxe
so how do you go
well from companies and you don't know the rotational speed of an atom of gas
around the galaxy is given by this simple equation with this now members is the
period is not the pressure anymore because we're talking about capitalist equation here
and and this is a now here is the same e major axis of the
orbit is not the scale factor of the universe so just for this transparency but
run out of symbols and so if they are some model it sequel and then
this is the radius of the circle called are and then you can write a
couple of seconds lowland at the speed is constant the so this is the speed
and then you put this together and you end up that the master that is
campaigning to save the galaxy is that the proportional to the velocity squared times the
so according to newton's law once you are outside the galaxy the rotation velocity of
the gas should decrease with distance
because of the massive them up if there's no more mass and you increase the
induced velocity should decrease
unfortunately this is not what it says so
so if you blocked they
distance from the centre of
any galaxy
versus the rotational velocity you will find that almost all four of galaxies in this
tradition goes goes up as solution
until you get to one the light say well like these and then you know
if you say there's no more stuff where there's no more light than they should
go down
but it remains constant
so this kind of shape is called the flat rotation curves
and this is an indication that there must be a lot of mass in the
outer region of our galaxy the we kind of search
well there's no more like no more stuff
and so like this you can commute what is called the mass to light ratio
and this is telling you already there a lot more than meets the eye and
galaxy must allow iteration must be higher than one
and this is called dark matter
and so
the twenty spiral galaxies have this flat rotation curve and i talk about spiral galaxy
because spiral galaxies have or are
annotation pattern that you can actually measure
if they are not spiral and they didn't get the motion of the gas service
that is a little bit more kartik then you need to do something that contradicts
but you can do so so basically all these galaxies to this latter rotation curves
so this is not the flow
and we
queen we this is due
to the work of erwin and this is where i been in the seventies also
embedding these nodes using some spectrum at that you can use and sort of other
types of things or for example what preferential would correspond to would be the product
of the degrees of the endpoints of the edge right that is sort of probability
of an edge is proportional to the product of the degrees of the nodes of
the nodes and sort of one the main finding is the following so here are
all the different methods and this is the
improvement over the baseline killer the baselines and here the baseline is a shortest path
distance between the set of between a pair of nodes the error bars actually the
the best and the worst case so i'm not standard deviations but this is maximum
this is minimum and its averaged over all five basically maximum improvement improvement over those
five datasets i showed and what is interesting is that
sort of this simple
many that they showed they were sort of much better than random
what i'm what i'm selecting here is for example if you are predicting the
edge based on just the number of common neighbors the nodes have you're doing sort
of quite well
and here also write you like doing thirty times as good as and
if you are using some kind of low rank approximation so the idea is to
do SVD PCA on the graph adjacency matrix and then and then when you want
to this embedded nodes in its in you know some k
k dimensional space and then just use the inner product this as an ocean whether
the nodes closer not then that gives you sort of very surprisingly little improvement even
here the graph was embedded in like i think one of each other's embedded in
like one thousand dimensional space for each node was described by one thousand dimensional vector
and what seems to work best
is this not this measure
damage about which i said is basically just the common frog common friends but this
common friends are weighted by by the degree
right and this seems to sort of be the best heuristics to predict the edges
the new edges in the network so this is sort of the first thing i
wanted to show just how you can go about these just you know given the
network structure somehow quantify the distance between the nodes and the closer the nodes i
the more
you predict amoz oz very that the edge will occur so this was one this
is an now
a completely different approach so here the idea is to model the network of some
kind of hierarchy
what we have is hammer three dendrogram where leaves of this tree they will correspond
to the nodes in the network
and each node we have like a bernoulli parameter that probability of an edge and
then given two nodes the probability of the edge is basically the parameter that is
in the car least common ancestor in the three so
here's an example of this is my dendrogram
the shades here i mean the value of five so that means very high white
means low and now it's so for example this dendrogram could generate the network like
that right so the idea is that the nodes one and two are not likely
to be connected but for example what you know this one and this one very
hot likely to be connected because this is the least common ancestor
right so
what i want to do then is given a network i want to estimate such
the and this parameters inside the tree
just to give some intuition here examples right so even if this is the network
i get that i would have a hierarchy like that right this is a random
graph so there's no hierarchy so all nodes you know joined the same the same
level if i would have this
you know three clusters then i this this would correspond to the clusters and then
they are joined on top so these three parameters would probably be the same here
and then than the edges across i wouldn't want them in in this in an
old and then if i have
like sort of hierarchical structure like that you know this cluster then can be separated
into different ones then i can model this in
using for example of such a hierarchy OK
so just to show you how how to estimate the model
so if you give me a graph and you give me a model i computing
like which is very easy so probability of a graph given y given by the
these these demands
basically all i go i just go over all the the the nodes in the
and i multiply
the number of
of edges go between these two sort of subtrees and and then
the rest of what you just did not occur that sort of i'm assuming that
the edges between different parts of the substrate occur and so this is just the
number of successes number of failures
right and l and i is the number of nodes in the left part of
the subject in the right part of the sub is the number of edges that
occurred between these two parts of subtrees so here's an example if i have a
graph like this
and they have a dendrogram like that
then the likelihood of these dendrogram
you know i can simply calculated to say
here the probabilities one because i have an edge
also here the probability is one but here it's one third because between between this
part of the in this part of the sub TOC one edge so i wanted
to power one
but because it's three versus one i could have just so i have to two-thirds
i have to
power to right
similarly here
where i'm getting no similarly calculating the likelihood is easy
the only sort of long one term is this one when i have three guys
here in three is here so the number of possible edges nine i get to
se one one edge between this part of the up in that part of the
out of nine OK
so that's how i can calculate the likelihood
and what they can do then i can do i can learn that using magic
which in one the carbon that basically you find local moves on this structure where
the the idea is that each node can be each node in the tree can
be in one of these three states
and then what i can do is i can sort of the nodes in this
sort of thing is if the current configuration is like that the i day night
this then i what they do that is by either
change appeared to correspond to this configuration of that configuration and then based on the
likelihood ratio of the likelihoods i basically except this change right so the idea is
something seriously like his friend he runs into the wall and then falls down and
breaks like that if i write at least it would become
so in another area is adaptive input devices sold
if you consider computer game than really
there we have means of the computer communicating to us
what the state of the game is
you know we have sound we have graphics and and all of these things but
our way of telling the computer what we actually want to do is much more
limited it used to be these joysticks another card game pads
which is essentially two joysticks and a few more buttons and some people play first-person
shooters with the mouse
and the keyboard which looks very funny to the uninitiated someone to you know to
tapping away at the keyboard at the same time doing stuff with the mouse and
essentially trying to get the mouse pointer over the heads of opponents and click because
the tension it can look very strange if you don't know what's going on
so clearly here's a potential
four for adaptive techniques to improve this way of how people communicate with the computer
that's true not only for games of course that's true for for any kind of
human computer interaction but it is particularly strong requirement in games because he big band
with took two to control games if you type the text that that works quite
well with the keyboard but to control various degrees of freedom off of your character
using using a mouse and a keyboard or using a game pad much harder so
talk about some some aspects of this
the one that i found was dialogue generation so if you that there are many
games three of these dialogues and you would like them to be in the more
flexible than just always getting the same answer all the same options the speech recognition
another interesting aspect is data from online play because we can connect the lot of
interesting data from people playing online
and this section there's game based on machine learning who make the very notion of
learning central topic of the game
so i go through a few more these in detail so
if you use
probably you know this game nineteen seventy seven space invaders
i q believe
nothing much has changed
we still have a human players
at the bottom of the screen
we still have non-player characters
and we still have humans trying to
she aliens from the sky
why right now
i know there are a few sports games i think it
let me point out some of the problems in current AI and illustrate that one
problem is that the behaviour of MPC's those and non-playing characters are currently fixed development
time and actually this is strong driving force behind that because
i don't know if you know about the model in games programming but there are
programmers and their designers
and their testers but there are of game
so the designers are control freaks i mean these guys want to know exactly what's
going on then they want to be able to exactly saying what's going on and
so they love this
i want to know this guy crosses the street at exactly this point in time
and you know my my test gamers told me that this is great every single
time and so i want change and
if you want to create interesting interesting
the results of this policy unit at least a huge amount of rules that you
put into the system so that there's a certain at least solution of variability
and of course anyone who has worked with large rule sets knows that their first
very hard to design and input and once you have them and you want to
extend them or you want to change when they are very hard to change because
what happens is that they conflict in certain situations and you put in your rule
in you thought you had started through enough but you hadn't and suddenly the whole
system goes crazy and s things yet you never expected and then this guy from
the first points comes up so i didn't expect that and so it's very hard
so of course you get very adaptive and emergent behavior you can of course write
and that's again with the guy from number one the designer hates motor behavior terrible
suddenly something happens that i plan and
there's another aspect which is quite interesting
because it's so hard to script good or interesting behaviour which is also
place these games well
what often happens is is that these characters don't work on the same conditions as
humans do something more no more they know you're coming around the corner or they
have this magical ability of getting their weapon exactly you had
and it takes no time and they can trigger and
you right so this is something sometimes very frustrating and sometimes they even have different
laws of physics if you believe it or not these racing games and it's not
so easy to keep the cars on the track well it is easy if you're
on rails right there not visible but it's often what happens in these racing games
that they the cars are not subject to the the cars controlled by the computer
are not subject to the same physics system that the human drivers car subjected to
so sometimes you think you're driving this core curve in an optimal way and suddenly
you know this
train comes i and overtakes him
and well i don't have to point out that all of this is of course
inherently different from human intelligence but that's
that's probably another matter so
i think the examples actually pick one from our one from our company and one
from sunnyside so to balance this of really stupid behaviour of AI
so this is a fighting game called tangles
and so the idea of fighting game is pretty simple just another word for it
it will become clear they also called them beat them up games
and that pretty much says it usually these easter martial arts inspired characters
fighting against each other and you have control map to your controller and different things
exon exon that's the textbook fifth edition
well you'll notice is thank you very much for your notices this and this and
went back up to
this is something automatic
instinctive and does not require your brain
so your brain is needed for everything
what does your brain do well some things that your brain does involve very low
level internal structures
and these are called subcortical structures because they below the cortex there underneath the cortex
so for instance what we have here is
a diagram of the brain way to read this diagram is is therefore my brain
facing this way
my head gets cut in half
down here
and then you can see
the brain
so this is the front over here that's the back
some key parts are illustrated here
the mid-to-upper for instance is
responsible for
heart rate and respiration
it's very deep within the brain and if it gets damaged you but you're likely
to die
the cerebellum
it is responsible for body balance and muscular coordination
and to give you an idea
a feeling for the complexity of these systems the cerebellum contains approximately thirty billion neurons
the hypothalamus is responsible here for feeding hunger
first and to some extent sleep
and here's is the same brain parts
in closer
all of these parts of the brains are essential and many of them are implicated
interesting psychological processes
but where the action is
is the cortex
it is beautiful
the cortex is the outer layer
and the outer layer is all crumpled up
you wonder why your brain with wrinkles
that's because it's all crumble
if you took out somebody's cortex
and flatten the
it would be two feet square
so like in a helical rod
the cortex
is where all the needs to
takes place fish don't have any event
so no offense to fish within the fish don't have much of the mental life
reptiles and birds have a little bit about it a bit and primates have long
and humans have a real life
eighty percent of the volume of our brain about his cortex
in the cortex
can be broken up into different parts
or lobes
there's the again this is facing
in profile forward
the frontal lobe easy to remember it is hard front
the parietal lobe and occipital lobe
and the temporal lobe
and one thing we're going to return to is this is half the brain
it's this is in fact
the left hand of the brain
another at the right hand everything's duplicated
with some slight subtle differences
what's really weird one really we're finding about these lobes
is that include topological maps
they include maps of your body
here's the cartoon
which actually illustrates the classic experiment
by some physiologist who for some reason had
had the dog's brain open
and started shocking different parts of the brain you could do brain surgery while fully
conscious because the brain itself has no sense organs to it
and it turns out the dog one is that part of its brain is labelled
and it took doctor penfield
mcgill university
to do the same thing with people
so you're doing some brain surgery
he had all electrical thing on i don't know how to do this these are
the zapping
and both
the person is parts are body with
more than that
when is that other parts of the brain people would claim to see colors
in these and other parts of the brain people claim to hear sounds
in other parts of the brain people would claim
two experienced up
and through his research
this is all on carbon have formed anyone's yet
but now what i'm going to do is i'm going to take these four functions
they're all on the same carbon right
but i'm going to let those four wavefunctions constructively and destructively interfere
so now i'm taking the wave functions on the same area
and letting them constructively and destructively interfere in molecular orbital theory
we took the away functions on different atoms
and let them constructively and destructively interfere this is going to be taking away functions
on the same atom
and letting them constructively and destructively interfere
when i do this
what you're going to get
is something that looks like this
you're going to get four different weight functions
that we're going to call
the sp
three wavefunctions the
he three orbitals
more precisely they are the
four sp three hybrid wavefunctions or hybrid orbitals
because they are the linear combination is constructed over there
of these four different wave functions
right on the same carbon in
to make
four equivalent wavefunctions hybrid way functions that we call this the freeway functions
they all look
the same year just oriented in space a little differently
i understand there
and it's not clear i know
we're looking at this how they get like that
but here's one
a simple way to look at one of these
take this to us wavefunctions
and let it constructively and destructively interfere with two PC wave function
so this
here is essentially a topic here
what you notice that the two peasy function is that this part of the wave
is that a positive amplitude remember we talked about the positive sign and one of
these little meaning positive amplitude
and this part of the wave function
if the negative sign is the negative amplitude
but the two as function here has the positive amplitude everywhere
so if we put the two s on top here
well you can see there right here
we're going to have
two positive
the amplitude two ways there are positive there that constructively interfere in the result is
about year right here just these two look at this
you can have a lot of wavefunction right up here
below this plane where we have the positive weight function
at the same time we have a negative weight function
well you know what
this is destructive interference and the result is that the wave function here
is going to be pretty small it's going to be a little negative
but it's going to be pretty small
right so that's probably the simplest just example to look at so that you understand
how i get from here to here
so we're going to form these four sp three weight function now
here's a picture of
so when i take
these four wave functions which are all i've just separated them out in space
but now i'm really just to put them on top of each other because they
really all have the same origin here
when i do that
function kind looks like this
where these
walls here are the positive parts
are my ISP three function
loans landing becomes more easy this of course is pro-cyclical meaning
more money and liquidity support to the thing and of course the money has to
go somewhere so it feels the or even more
the fourth stage
these very weak coupling
between the market
and the fundamental c
and the first stage
the problem is that these are drying phase of liquidity eventually the system is finite
there's no more new investors you've tried out
but then show investors even from abroad
and then that's when you reach this very unstable phase and here i just copied
we don't need to read through it but basically
try asking the burger has this famous book in seventy eight where he doesn't and
it's very very detailed is to recover
a review of some of the major crashes over
the story of financial economics
and basically go through the same conclusions
and he actually was a even more the irrationality i wouldn't go as far as
together form is more rational imitation learning process
we're collectively was tend to forget chris breaks risks
you know way that leads to these axes
so having
the suggestion that they similar the phenomenon from a quantitative point of view let's go
to the second question of why is it so difficult to identify and i want
to contrast the
academic view with the practice of you wonder
the reserve one i think one that so explanation
i want to suggest two of them
three of them one is
many of the terms to explain
o crashed and you see that they put crashes as a can of dual version
of the bible says close association
that people are
often tend to look at approximate causes
crash occurs today
what happened yesterday what the call what what could have happened the week before so
we look at this
proximate explanation
and i think the difficulty with that is of course you have so many new
as you so my list for the crash of eighty seven
people have
but for so many explanation for example i can refer to the presidential
that was put created under the reagan administration with reagan
yet committee
after the october nineteen eighty seven crash
famous economist if you know the prize winner nobel prize
try to understand what the cause
some efficient market hypothesis returned wall and so on and
they agree completely with you all the reports different
the only consensus
it was a paper by
child who
do the world wide analysis and concluded
the only statistically significant explanation for this crash
one line
was that the global world market has crashed
so let me
explain the crash in the US is due to the wall crash crash of that
band is due to the war crash
and so on and so forth
so what is the reason for the war crash not not it the factor analysis
for those who are in this phase they found that the only relevant factor is
the worst crash
is that a good explanation interest to global public
and i think the reason
two for this lack of
ax access to define is that
we don't recognise enough
the crash in and now i'm going to try to substantiate this claim
it is the revelation
of instability that has been progressively developing the system
over the development of the
so an instability we know from
lot of mathematical study is tested in different fields is characterized did with the growing
two external perturbations so in the end
proposition of approximate goes
we can correct
but this is not giving an insight because
in the same way that might offend going down
may go down make crash the table because there was so something
incorrect initial conditions
some sort of air that's approximate cause the final causes what it was prepared in
situation so that we we're trying to do is to try to understand what are
the mechanisms to understand the nurturing of the market in two
and stable
let me come back to the review of this economist at the beginning of concluded
that for
or in the papers to conclude about above all there is another paper that concluded
that there is no problem because you can explain it according to
from the evaluation and
this goes back to you know models of girls
and here i'm looking at one of growth of population but the same thing for
where you have this population growth
and the
which was proposed by matters
and who led to piece of this simplistic economies to conclude that
the worst was going to happen to mankind because of the overpopulation of exponential growth
OK but the malthusian you
the first generalize this equation by saying well but these actually a saturation effect
but what is the the maximum entropy
what is the maximum differential entropy to be more precise
so you can write that you can write that entropy
their relative entropy of the distribution with respect to the gaussians distribution
that has the same second order statistics
the gaussians
that same gaussian distributions
with respect to
i gaussian distributions
that's what i mean by this a gaussian distribution that is
i i d
OK so
in the in the absence of any
other knowledge
before you know they are the second order order statistics then by maximizing this with
respect to px what you're doing is you're making this equal to see you said
you're making the px equal to the gaussians that has
by the same second second order statistics
OK then what you're
what you're left with is with this is the
no the
the relative entropy of the gaussians with a given
second order statistics in the idea so in other words what this is doing is
or saying well
i would like to
to view reality in the closest way
to the simplest possible explanation the simplest possible explanation being
something being i i d gaussians and my observations what is the closest explanation of
my observations to that pure reality
that's the maximum entropy principle
now another very interesting use for nongaussianness this
is essentially the central limit theorem but the non asymptotic version of the central limit
theorem so what i mean by that
you take any
prose probability density function new coevolving with itself and you normalise it so that we
you keep the variance the same you started which looks more around
you do it again it looks even more and then you know what's going to
happen it's going to become more money
so shannon actually nineteen forty eight show
and then when you do this process
once so you take our PDF with with itself
you turn it indeed into more gulshan looking around the bible and when i say
more gumption looking around the bible he did it through the differential entropy
and that's what he called the entropy power inequality
actually he did prove that the entropy power inequality that took
quite a bit of effort but ten years later
for a long time
even though you know it's very
of a simple thing to conjecture from time
it was an open problem to show that at each step that nongaussian this that
relative entropy with respect to the gaussian distribution
actually is monotonically decreasing and of course by doing this and you can prove
central limit theorem so it's like a strong form of the central limit theorem
provided of course that to start with the PDS if you'd understand with the pdfs
then i it is that you have a discrete distribution and is always infinity
the discrete distribution then it's going to have infinite relative entropy with respect to the
ocean even though of course we know
then the characteristic functions are going to converge
OK so this was actually finally shown in to the force in functional analysis in
two thousand four that we came up with a much simpler proof
based on the connection between information theory and estimation theory that we will see later
in some detail
OK so what you're doing here what you're doing here in there
in the world of distributions with a given variants
and two-sided distributions you could think of doing this in other words
you could think of doing this say for example in the world of distributions that
the were but it gets fragmented
so that even an order traversal of the trie
hands up doing lots of disk seeks
six slow
sikhs are
well let's let's look at some numbers
if you
i mean to give you some some sort of ballpark figures of what hard disk
this these days correctly transferred ten megabytes per second
it takes roughly ten million seconds to seek the drive a sort of the constants
that we have to deal with
and generally we're dealing with the structures that are larger than the memory that need
to be on disk
the question is whether we better off
if we got some number of updates to some large database
what we're better off using the tree
we we have to do is seek
potentially to update or maybe we can even improve things a little bit
by by presenting data versus one is it is better to just rewrite the whole
so his his acquittal
so i thought experiment
if you got terrified of data
and you want to to one percent of the entries
so that is ten megabytes is going to be going to say insert into the
what's the cost of doing that
and so
just the basic numbers are that you've got if you if you assume that
each entry is a hundred bytes
and each page
if you're building the tree is ten k
that gives you ten billion entries
well in criteria
and you've got one billion pages
so if you really do is see for every single update
the user adding particular thousand
long time
if you were to
three sort all your update so that you may access each page ones
each tent k block but using the data is fragmented because you have been doing
this for a while
that is going to
one hundred days to do seek to block
that's better you updating ten entries on every page
and only appears once
but if you just take the whole database if you take the updated data
which is well attended by you sort it and then stream here in parallel
with c and
with the entire terribly database which is already sorted and merge together in a new
version of it
makes sense
it takes twice the amount of space because you've got two copies of you care
about the data
it only takes today
roughly distributor about data on the drive
given these these constants so it's
considerably faster
so time and again you hear people say
they want to do indexing or web crawling
using my SQL or the oracle or something and some SQL database you want to
do that was wonderful properties
it and the problem is is is this doesn't scale
if you want to if you do it scales to a certain point you only
get millions of pages something that but if you're trying to get to very large
say representing every link because links are the most
words the most frequent item to deal with links to the next recording pages are
are after that the pages you might be able to store a relational database
links in words are certainly going to going to kill you actually performance if you
try to do it you're much better off with these these
sort merge space
strategies that you know people have discovered this again and again and the keep discovery
but just to remind you once more so that aggression
actually see
so the scene was the thing i wrote in my spare time the
it was a in nineteen seven search engines or not
sure thing that the universe was the
internet stock bubble
was actually
declining many many people but it was over
and it didn't seem like it was going to
never get any larger so that well
i had to do something else this i have my my that's sort of and
i wrote i want to learn job so i wrote search engine on my own
time time off work and something
and then i even licence it two to one client and then the whole soccer
took off and i got wrapped up the things that excite for another couple years
and then finally came back years later and i don't have to search engine written
in java
and i didn't know quite what to do with it realized they didn't want
sort of business that was something i was good at are interested in
so i decided put it up on
as an open source project for free
see what happens
i first put it under the GPL
which seems like the standard open source license
and i got lots of people sending email saying we're using GPL i can you
feel software raising trivial
this was not what i want to i wanted to give something away for free
nine people angry
so i changed lgpl and if you are familiar with licenses i don't know much
about him at the time
we're less angry but were still somewhat frustrated they didn't appreciate that and i a
year later i was invited to
move the project to apache and seem like a reasonable thing to do i
actually i wasn't
that interested in personally but a lot of people that said it was a great
thing to do that like OK let's let's move there
we're starting to build communities i was no longer alone making these decisions
apache licence
and i've never since then received a complaint about the license
but the and so that's a little
reference for you depends on what you're interested in getting out of open source
if what you want is
users and little friction licences like apache in the st
in my experience anyway
get more people using it unless distractions
about the licenses which
i wasn't particularly interested in
in two thousand five losing became a top-level apache project
political technicality
but the nice
let me talk a little bit about what we've seen is and how it works
it's written in java at the time it was time i started losing their job
was new
and had there was no search technology for it seems like a good opportunity i
want to keep the
the interface very simple
so the people didn't have to some class two
to use it
with no configuration files that you had the right to start writing code and using
so the things we're dynamically typed
part the first
well anyway the play be here now
as you see this is this is
i as the title suggests this is really a set of topics
rather weakly related
but do not having a common theme which i hope you discern this
as time goes on
so so let me begin by giving the outline of the talk
i got two microphones and certainly should here
so the first one to talk about classification prediction which provokes here is going to
be pretty old hat
and what i one way i would characterize at least
goals in statistics and machine learning
which differ somewhat but but but
not not that significantly
and certainly not in practice and maybe to some extent in theory
and then i'll talk about what i view as an as an apparent puzzle
an apparent disconnect between theory and practice
and there it is in fact that's that's
part two
the positive theory somehow tells you
as i hope this
theory and i know
somehow tells you that really
doing anything in more than five or six dimensions
you should be able to to anything
and yet in practice right i mean people do things in very high dimensions
one explanation
obviously partial explanation i think is a theme that
if you've heard about already and i'm sure you'll hear about a lot in this
which is
dimension that things may not be as
high dimensional if you think are
so then i talk having
having indicated why that
should be the case that talk a little bit about some theories and they don't
dimension estimation this is
joint work with please let me know
which basically
it is to tell you when in fact maybe the dimensions of that you should
be able to get reasonable results
released this one
then i really rather unrelated line but having
in common the idea that maybe things may not be as bad as you think
they are
is is an improvement by
standardisation which is using ranks
then i may or may not so much about cross validation model selection this is
i think some topic behaviour quite a lot
and really this is just the justification of why
the fold crossvalidation where v
grows slowly with the sample size does grow
actually is a good thing
so in questions results project so so let me begin
the outline if you want o here's
sort of an indication that there may be this can right
so here are two books
one which came out in two thousand one and the other one which came out
in two thousand two
in the same series of books
one is i think it's fair to say basically a book about the practice of
machine learning and statistical learning and classification regression call well
hasty tibshirani three
talking about all
there is
kind of out many many types of algorithms giving some
intuitive judgments occasionally on why they were making statements like you know we have found
that this works in practice
and then there's the book biography kohler chris i can walk
which is sort of you want of the tradition of the overall
much many steven other the people who were here which is a which is results
which is bounds on on on on on
how well you can do
and to indicate that there may be a little bit of a disconnect the later
book admittedly only one year later has exactly one reference and that's one minor algorithm
in the first
right and they're both books which as you can see about six hundred pages each
so now let me turn to sort of an abstract description the prediction problem of
the prediction problem which again i think will be familiar to most people here
so what we're given in the training sample right
of high dimensional
in principle covariance x i
and responses y i
we assume that these are i i d three is sampled from
a distribution p which belongs to some families repeat
and x belongs to some space
and why we can think of as being real or let's in the case classification
just a note to that
but the goal in both cases of course are the first
in is is of course to predict
new y given a new x
that's equivalent to the job of constructing a function
which is dependent on the learning sample phi and it's the function from the space
the predictor variables to the real line so that in some sense
in terms of some loss
the expected loss
distance you can think of it between
the truth and the prediction is small
and so you basically estimating function of x
the training sample dependent rules
again just to make things a little bit more concrete
for the usual when the prediction real number then you
typical losses are absolute value the alpha usually mean squared error is alpha equals to
classification in the two classes y and d both belong to plus and minus one
for example
if there are only two classes
and the losses of course as usual
zero if your right in one if you're wrong
as we all know there if in fact