this is not entirely new this idea of pressure
because you may have seen people's desks
nice conversation piece
you have here
you have your magnet
and this is it
a wooden stick
there's a hole in here and there's a whole year
this is not all thousand almost all the south pole
they repel each other
that's magnetic pressure is the same thing
and if you drew the magnetic field configurations here
go like this
that's the magnetic field from this magnet
and this would be
the magnetic field that nick
get the same idea
you get magnetic
pressure there
if i rotate is magnet here
so the first of all the magnets repel which is in no way form of
levitation i'm going to show you that
to make this
bush up by
where you can look at it
but if you start rotating it for instance around with the south pole here in
the south building on the north pole there
eddy currents will instantaneously adjust to always repelled magnet
even if to rotate it
which still hang them levitate it
what is not so easy to understand why the whole thing is
so very stable as you will shortly see it's quite stable
i'm going to show you there
the idea first have to top it off with some
liquid nitrogen to let me do that when we still have full light
so at the top it off
this disc which is about
the image
in diameter
going to be superconducting
i can even tell you what kind of material it is
it is a copper oxide mixed with
it to him and barium and it becomes superconducting at
ninety degrees
in liquid nitrogen
seventy seven degrees so we're going to put a small
magnets on top
which we will levitate
for that
we're going to have the following light situation
course you want to see it also don't you
you want some light
there you see this
which is should be superconducting no
and here comes my little magnets are there is no magnetic flux going through there
itself is not a magnet
but now i'm going to come close was a magnet
any any comments go nuts in there
and it just floats on top
it's amazing isn't it
it is the magnetic levitation
you can rotate it around
eddy currents adjust instantaneously
there it is
you've also
clear enough
so let me get the
rescue my magnet
imagine the days of counting on this
book four degrees kelvin
superconducting now
you can do it this is is that
there are other forms of magnetic
going to be very promising
in our economy
we hope
and that is the magnetic levitation
can be used for trains
if you ever make you move fast over a
conducting surface
then you also get
you have to move it
where there you don't have to move
so if you look at that
just go view
don't move anymore
then there isn't any current going on with any current never dissipates and eat there's
no ice cream or because are is zero so you never lose the
any current
that's different one is coming out now i have
there is no or
and here is out
so we have the magnetic field
sort of like this
and i'm going to move it over the plate
over conducting plate and output plate here
comes over this conducting plates
the magnetic flux sort of play will change
if the files with fire this is actually miss the lens who says i don't
and so to going to run on any current in here
any current will undoubtedly go in this direction
as it comes over here
and this
current ring now
i will produce a magnetic field
in this direction
and look what you have you have again
is the north pole
of this area currently to the south pole north pole repels north pole
and so if this
as a high enough being
the the change of the magnetic flux
the fight is high enough
train can float
tens of cons
can be made to float
and the reason why in this case the train has to keep going that if
the train stops
any current will die out is no longer the fighting team that there is resistance
in this conductors and so you get only dissipation you get ice cream are you
can eat in
and so then the train just plunged down
and and that's not the case with the superconductor because you don't dissipate any
it's in the superconductor because superconductors no resistance
the idea is the same
but you see now why you have to
keep this one going
and why there
you don't
so again you get crease
magnetic field
like you have there
so we get magnetic pressure
japan and germany
i really the leaders in the world in the technology of maglev that's what these
trains are called
united states try to catch up
there's an enormous reduction in friction
if you can ever train
that is not in contact with the real in fact speeds have been
up to three hundred forty miles per hour
both germany and japan have test trains
we would have got it
in any other way except here on the right we have one flat screen
has this red dots which we can move
and if we move it
someone then we get ranking of the
the results and this what the system bus in behind
it collects google's search results
clusters them extracts in this case three major
topics like SIFT password security passwords and default whatever this means we will be able
to check this later on and i removed these dots stores the security view of
the whole
rankingq we will be
according to security passwords and see that creating secure passwords will appear at the top
was first friends so
all the hits which are all related to secure process with the here while
moved here this would be
passport safety whatever this
and if you go down here fault
this again about some
the forward pass again whatever but the idea is the following so that
we don't changed
search habits too much so
user gets smaller the same experience except that it can
you can move it can increase the power of the of the search of
one of the same search which
he would have got otherwise with this additional
because it's search point
so this is one way to visualize our how to help
visualizing such as answers
we can go there's one back inside so you can try
know they could always crashes when i try to second time
it's still in worked is
OK so for instance
a four would be
how obviously
and paper a four so let's say a few words
moved this point now
how did would get all kinds of a for all this stuff
if you would go here
this would be about the a four
probably former or whatever a four
it can mean something else
the car will be
also by the obvious this
i was basically the same idea
it's important
just say that basically server calculates this
this model
pretty much on the fly
and then sends all the data together with the search results on the client and
then basically everything what happens here happens on the client side lot
so this was another them up
then the next text visualisation demo which is not our stuff is text are which
is all the same
one way how to visualize the this
many watercourses feet go to
the web and check it
just find
the harm that this is
this works
so basically this is innovation of the
how i mean i'm not saying that this is the best possible way how to
visualize this going but business
it's good to see that there
so we can move the mouse pointer can see each of the word
each of the words and relationships this is what is called coker scorpions of these
words with some other works
and it's
let's say the word brought would be connected to some other which certainly
hunters would be sentences i think
i'm not sure how useful this is but certainly it's fun place to click
so here we can check for each of these words where they appear in
the least dense
well how they call copula so is basically it's fun and clicking it but as
i said so it might not be very useful
for instance when we click the word ghost
we see this ghost is connected to all this
other words which were highlighted for this one
OK this is an example of another type of exposition
and this this algorithm is
by the conditional probability tables that represent
the relationship between acts
and all of hair
is not a message this term here is
part of are directed graphical models specifying the probability distribution of the variable given its
so i know this is like alot of notation in that involved
two pick up if you haven't seen it but i just want to put all
review and
you know we can work through it
a little more detail one
in complete detail you want to actually implement all this we need to know how
to compute the messages that
it's going to stand with parents
and we need to compute the messages that
active in then
two its children
and these are the expressions for those messages
they're not as mysterious as they look they come from basically applying the rules of
and the conditional independence relationships
encoded by the graph
and we can actually look at slightly more carefully
and we'll see interesting things going on
let's look at
let's look at the message
act is going to stand with parents
this is the function of the possible values of the parent
and it combines
all this stuff that x got
from downstream OK so imagine active learning methods the use of and
the message explains the use of and
all this stuff x got from all of its children that lambda x
and then he also combined
are all this stuff
x got wrong
every other parent of x
next step
u i
so if you're spending a message to you i combine information from all your children
and all of your other parents
not including URI i
so this is the totality of all the
that x is gathered from all sources when it gathers all that they can send
a message to you i
OK the it what the message is is
a vector
of nonnegative numbers
they don't have the time to one
the message don't have to be normalized and the vector will be
the land of possible values the you i can
right so you i binary that just vector with two numbers that this is a
here in this is not equal to
we see the idea that the methods access the URI does not include any information
that you are
and similarly
the message that
it's going to spend two child y j
it includes all the information that's not from its parents
and all the information that x got from all the other children not including white
so that the way to
decode all this stuff
and if we have time i can go through
it's sort of a demo of the propagation with politician a
this hard this in my of cringe when i go through it again
that was belief propagation or a directed graph
what we do with factor graph
well the good news is that
factor graph propagation is just notational simpler in directed graphs we have to worry about
if i
i have this some right now and i invested for one year what do i
have i have
one plus our times one of one class of dollar
so that works out exactly right
so you have to discount
something that's one period in the future by dividing it by one plus are
the if it's
this is
present one dollar in one time period
which are taking to be here but it doesn't have to be here
the interest rate
has units of time so i have to
to specify a time period over which i measuring an interest rates
so typically it's a year so if it's a one year interest rates and the
time period is one year
the present value of one dollar in one time period is given by this
the present value
one dollar
in and periods
is one of the one class are
the and power
that is our
that's the all the is to list
i want to talk about
streams of
payment i suppose someone
he has a contract promises to pay
each period over a number of years
we have formulas for these
present values
and these formulas
are well known is going to go through them and quickly here
the simplest thing is something called a console
in perpetuity
we have a perpetuity is
is a
as or a contract pays a fixed amount of money
each time period
we call the consuls because in the early seventies hundreds
the british government issued
what they called councils are consolidated debt of the british crown
that paid a certain amount of pounds sterling
he was every six months forever
and you may say
what audacity for the british government the promise to pay anything forever will be around
you know as far as you're concerned is good enough has forever right
maybe someday
the british
uk united kingdom well
something will happen to it will fall apart change but that's so
this in the future what we
we can disregard that so will take that as forever
anyway the government might buy them back to and so
who cares if it is inference
this just talk about it forever
so let's say this thing pays
a period
what is the present value of that
well the first
each payment will call a coupon
OK so it pays one pound one year from now
but it's one year just to simplify things
it pays another pounds
two years from now
it pays another part three years from now
the present value
it is equal to
remember it starts one year from now
under assumption we we could do it differently but i'm assuming one year from the
present value is one of
one was are this one pound
over one plus are for the first year
for the second year it's one
over one class are
the third year is one
all of one class are
and that goes on forever
so that's an infinite series
and you know how to some that
i think anyway i tell you what it is
it's one of our
for the one pound or
if it pays c dollars for every period
he has value see overall
so that's the formula
for the present value
of a council
as from the most basic formalism finance
the interesting thing is it means that the value of the council move inversely to
the interest rate
the british government issued those consoles in the early seventeen hundreds
well they were refinanced in the late nineteenth century there still there
and if you want to go out and buy one
you can get on your laptop
right after this lecture and by one of them and you've got something that will
pay something forever
but you're going to know that the value of the market was opposite interest rates
of interest rates go down the value goes up
if interest rates go up the value of your investment goes down
another formula
it is one of the council
doesn't pay
well what i'm saying
the next thing
there is a growing problem
i'm tired to growing council
even though the british council's didn't grow
let's say that the british government didn't say that they pay one pound per year
but it will be one pound the first year
and then
growth rate g
and will eventually
be infinitely large
so you get
one pound first year
you get
one plus jeep and the second here
one has g squared
the third year
and so on
the present value of this
suppose it pays the same pace pounds
each year
so it would be c times this
alright one plus the BBC
pounds one close the cube thirty year et cetera
the the present value
is equal to c
all of these are minus g
that's the formula for the
the value of a growing council
g has to be less than our for this to make sense
because if g if it's growing faster than the rate of interest
so this infinite series will not converge
anything from some of the younger
and i know you're going to have
a set of functions h
OK which is one the a set of functions and you like an inner product
on the set of functions so that they are additive
so last g
it's going to be
f h
plus gh
the norm of any function in the space is then written as h h
just like linear spaces
and it's very normal the semi norm so that if this is equal to zero
that means h must be identically zero
which is it so
imagine everything that you know about vector spaces
on vector vectors
this is true
what i should say is i should give you one canonical example of infinite dimensional
hilbert space so that you see
the set of all this is little too which is the set of all sequences
in one
eight two
eighty three
and so on
a set of sequences an infinitely long sequence a
which you can then that you have to infinitely long sequences did not infinitely long
so these sequences must all have the property that this
where there less than infinity
so that they are nicely defined
and the inner product between a sequence in
and the sequence b
is then
some asian AI
the i
this is almost exactly like so if you take a finite set of numbers
you can add them and so on you can take the norm of those numbers
you can take the inner product of those numbers have no in rn
just generalized to this set that infinity ward that's
so that's only want
there's one more property that people like
and that will take us to reproducing kernel hilbert spaces
so probably demanded very little always said he would like to classify actions
which will have this hilbert space structure
and this property is the evaluation functionals should be bounded
so let me first motivate that from learning from the perspective of machine learning
suppose you have a data set d one
and your learning algorithm comes up with the classifier f of the one of the
function f of the one
and you have another data set d two
and the classifier and you are out and comes up with the function f of
the two
so then you would like you've f the one and f of the two which
are the two functions returned by learning algorithm one on data set d one in
one hundred seventy two
now obviously f of d one and f of the two boats it in this
hilbert space
the hilbert space has the norm on it you can measure distances between functions in
the hilbert space
and so
you take fifty one f of the two and measure the distance
and then you want to say
that if f of the one minus f of the two is small
then we would like f d one and if the tool to make similar predictions
so if i have a data set d one and i come up with the
function f of the one they decided to come up with the function f of
the two
and i can measure the distance between these two functions f one and f of
in the hilbert space and i find these functions are very near each other
so very similar somehow
i would like it to be the case that they also makes similar predictions i
don't want f of the one to be making widely different predictions from f of
because that would somehow
make me lose the ability to control
the behaviour of this learning how
so what does it mean to make similar predictions at each point x it means
that f of the one x minus seventy two x twenty one
we would like this property
a week
statement is this
well that depends on whether you want to do with uniformly or not
so consider the evaluation function
OK so what's the functional
it will basically take it could be a linear function of
so given
a set of functions
should take you from
two are
so it's a linear function so the l applied to a function should be only
the number
and linear in that area of f one class f two
should be equal to and
of f one
plus and
1 the 4th type of
secondary bonding is hydrogen bonding hydrogen bonding and occurs
that occurs between as the name implies hydrogen and only the most electronegative elements
and that's fluorine oxygen and nitrogen only to their high average valence electron energy
this something peculiar here about the combination of high average valence electron energy and the
lightest element
and here's what I want you 1st be reminded of I'm showing here the average
valence electron energy in order and we see fluorine is that the the highest of
the active neon has a higher but neon doesn't participate in in chemical reactions to
speak up so
that I know there are some subtle differences in electronegativity scales 1 of them has
fluorine 3 . 9 8 this hazard of 4 . 1 9 it's a self
consistent set
so when we see
here we're up at around 20 electron volts for average valence electron energy and then
it tapers off something magical happens around 18
electron volts
what happens
when we put hydrogen in the presence of something that is that strongly electronegative so
let's work with the most powerful example fluorine so hydrogen donates its electron to the
covalent bond flooring donates 1 of its 7 valence electrons and here the other 6
and we know because fluorine strongly electronegative this bond is very polar and we can
designate the flooring and delta negative and the hydrogen and has delta plus
and let's look at this and in greater detail when we start pulling hard on
the electron associated with hydrogen what's left is that
by a lot an Adam that has
it's protons in the nucleus in an hour and n minus 1 electrons in the
case of hydrogen we had 1 electron when you pull that electron hard which leaving
is something that's essentially approach
this is a hydrogen is is is the unit of its electron it is a
proton proton is very special the proton has a charge of plus 1 but it's
got a volume that's tiny tiny tiny
so the charge density is very very hot
so now let's bring up another feature
so here's a 2nd HF we know that dipole-dipole interactions happen and that was the
category number 1 so let's start with a simple dipole-dipole interaction the negative end of
over the last
HF molecule
sidles up to the positive and of the right HF molecule
then the magic happens you see this non bonding domains sitting here on the right
side those non bonding electrons and then we will a way out there and here's
this hydrogen over here and it's electron is being pulled so hard by the fluorine
on the right I mean this hydrogen hardly gets visitation rights to see this electron
OK so there's these 2 electrons sitting over here
and I was looking over there and I never again you have again any time
with with my electron but disease 2 lone pairs of electrons sitting there and so
can you imagine that there is a force that's set up between this lone pair
of electrons because this rate because it's got so many electrons it tends to neglect
its electrons it doesn't pay close attention you know if you can if you come
from a big family you don't get as much attention as if you're an only
child right so fluorine and it's got electrons already so if 2 come straight off
following doesn't care so that's what's happening here is hydrogen that doesn't have the full
impact of its single electron here's 2 electrons then way way out
this is a recipe for attraction and that's exactly what happens and so we forces
established between this non bonding pair
when grouped together they can make notes and was in
music record there might be several nodes so that's what this model represents and we
have this by attention to model of time varying amplitude and we have these omega
OK and which are the frequencies of the partials for each of the nodes and
we want to
this moment of peace and music can be able to extract the component
right so
we have seen last time
that we can very easy rider likelihood when it is written in the form
we have the many in the parameters some of which are
continuous parameters such as the amplitude and some of which are this critical component
the parameters such as the number of nodes the number of of
and so on
right we had applied bayesian
analysis and that by defining priors
so prefers amplitudes
priors for the frequencies
which may look like that
prof and the number of partials for each node x attracts
so i tried to explain you how to select with partial so as to
to respect some compromise solution between the
the physical phenomenon and the easiness of implementation
right so we had ended up with that
posterior distribution of the
of the process
which could be
written as
this shorter from where where we have marginalized out some of the parameters and we
could also have the conditional posterior distribution for some of the parameters
so this is a very nice thing because we can have
it's simply the inference from the frequency parameters and when we have then we can
have the other parameters so that's why we chose this priors which are conjugate priors
which enable analytical integration
right so we're in the middle of this is it now
as an example of how to use MCMC
i was describing the algorithm that could be applied to this problem
this is just some that's the that humans were ready
so right
this is the basic centers and so we have seen
four is the
and to pointer or something
OK we have in one's initilisation which consists of finding the first set of parameters
for the problem and then iterations
of the metropolis hastings algorithm when we
first generate a candidate according to some rule
thank you
so we first generated good candidate according to a proposal distribution which is
so it is a sample into our stochastic way and then this sample is tested
by computing this ratio
right and the cause to increase shareholder lectures you have seen that this ratio
and this algorithm needs to fulfill if you conditions so have to provide us with
a convenient markov chain in which
in distribution to the actual distribution
and with the metropolis hastings rule should be you can have your algorithm like that
then you will have to be convenient for markov chains
OK so
starting to explain
in our example so we had the initialisation part
which is fairly standard
right OK
now i was explaining how we can
a date
the nodes so
we have a piece of music we have a certain set of parameters that represent
the music at the sentence that
and we want to to from this we want to generate a candidate
which would be a bit different from the previous sample and which ones should represent
better music
OK so that's where i explained that
in this example for we have been
we have had to design special
reversible jumps
because the MCMC algorithm but what i wanted to emphasise is that in many practical
the move that you need to use it doesn't exist yet so you have to
design it yourself
and this was just an example how you can do it
right so
if this represents the frequency of the note for distributed ESB of a of a
musical signal is just one of the fundamental here and the different bottles and
possible way to generate a candidate which should represent the better it is for example
to had
a few powerful
another possibility is to remove the bottles
another one is to suppress one every to partial so as to avoid oktave
and to add in between voxels
the first thing that
in the lecture of his job he explained you that the chain has to have
some conditions due to converge and here you can notice that
for each move we have the reverse moves
if i had partial also have to remove portions move
and this is a very important condition if you want to encourage them to be
correct you have to design both smooth
OK and further divide
and multiply
it's exactly the same
you have a corresponding to move
just remarking
and to be able to suppress every other two bottles
you need to have an even number of partial
and in many cases
you don't necessarily have an even number of rules so there is that there is
some need to make
the special thing to make it reversible that is you might be able to put
go from any situation
to be able to perform this move
so that's why i try to explain it in a little more
with bit more details
OK so this is the divine moves as the divine movies
this one
we're dividing the fundamental frequency
by a factor of two
so that's why it's called divide and we are adding
partial in between so we're not only changing the parameter that we are also changing
the model because we are adding new particles
so the mother becomes bigger
this is the new number of four
OK this is the old one and this is
the candidate and as you can see
we do not only multiplied by two which would end up with an even number
is that one
start if i know
now it's marginalized
this to me
usually a function
the particular point where to me
again this
it's just because have to go also
as well
the predictive probability
not just by taking the
distribution of the latent function
just saying well what prediction was that give rise to
this is just like that i would like to
and again we have in world
it this very happy situation because just two things
and i
i don't really think compare for the
the same on ground order to just
these assumptions about
what's happening
because the
what year
more describing the
when the patients in the region
if we
among them
voices of signal
that's fine
but as far as it
just think what the structure of the
we may not be
in the end
you know
thank you
you can also be
and to become a lot less
OK so the now just go quickly through the two
two things you can so be
now in the previous slide
observations by
ask me
the nomination
o point
with was somewhere here we'll all be
nomination by this person
of the original
which looks like this
i don't understand especially
so the question here is the
the area between x
star excites
this is the prior variance
not at all what's going to happen
for the first
that is just thing
in in great
not very easy
this is higher
and then very slowly
predictions here
posted here
this to tell you how much the training points
told you you
this is i
that's why it works
i should draw
on the prior
o point five functions
you can draw or
and a number of stations
national here
distribution b
and also wrong
we see that night when far away from the ones that to
so the thing which is important is the
much like u
you can use the most likely to choose
my life
what we actually want to do it also
the model
it is
to do this
and this is the
by uniform
well you know
these beautiful
the standard model
for practical purposes is not
and model selection and this
again we use that term was a normalizing constant
the school i
the science case gases four
and they get looks like this
and now back to the original question
but the terms
the expression for the last
except for one term is that
how well the vision
if it discusses
has programs in the the range
the second here
doesn't depend
on the observation that was going to
croquet in my garden we weren't satisfied with the segmentation so we went in and
made some additional constraints
and the constraints consist of marking pix els as being background pixels
and hitting those pixels to the you know associating them irrevocably with the sick
the x equals zero state
and actually will be kind of nice if
when you make this modification which is quite localised you have to kind of go
right back to the beginning and solve the optimisation problem all over again and you
could do that and it works really well and you know the optimum that you
get is guaranteed to be a global optimum
so it doesn't make any difference whether you sort of solve the problem incrementally or
ab initio is not the solution but because it will make a solution difference to
the efficiency of the of the city so
it turns out there is a rather neat way
are doing graphcut dynamically where you know it when you add constraints
you only have to do a little bit of extra work to implement those constraints
the idea is
having solved the first problem
and you know read off the maximum flow rate of the configuration and so on
we actually were smart enough school
the maximum flow that we obtain that for the flow i just keep the graph
is still there keep the flow
on the graph what about restarting
optimisation problem with the new
with the new
modify problem but starting with the old flow
it might be a good thing to do anything
because they all flow into a lot of work to establish that flow and you
know this editing
this editing operations any changed in small part of the graph most of it is
in fact so surely the old flow
it's going to be good
so what do you think should we start with the old flow proceed from there
good idea or not
my friend this why not
you know i was looking at the guy who didn't give a good idea to
do that
you want to tell us why not
right i think i understand you saying which is that you know in changing the
graph i was free to change the capacities of links the way how i want
and maybe i reduce the capacity of some links
maybe i reduce the capacity of one of the
the level of flow that was previously playing
previously that flow within the last thing but now it is
and i'm thinking at the moment just about these these unitary links the
the values will get onto the binary things because actually for this problem every labelling
rheory labeling in the reapplying constraints in the segmentation problem
the it's enough to modify your railings all i need to do is you put
an infinite cost let's say
on one of these
links and actually we might be worried about putting infinite cost something
you might worry
my one like you are
no termination because you know we could be said to me you know so far
prove termination such as it was relied on the fact that all links and cost
maybe there's another prexamination the required
could be more liberal so far slightly worrying but it turns out actually infinity can
be set to a finite value in other words you can find a bound
for a given problem such that if you set the cost of that value it
has exactly the same effect setting it infinity
that's kind of interesting so we never actually have to do that so anyway supposing
on a particular
it turns out that yes the flow has exceeded the capacity on that link
on the edge by saying amount delta
so what can i do about that well we go back to our old friend
the re parameterisation
and simply add delta on both of these
cost the that's the
cost linking the k note to the source and the one link indicates the sink
and so now the problem is isn't change because have the consider the energy as
and might a wasteful because we've had to add
capacity onto this link as well as of this link so you know we've created
some residual capacity that will have to be dealt with in eventually but at least
it so it's the problem is about the problem is right it still correct problem
we want to solve and we've got now valid flow in the sense that the
flow doesn't exceed capacity anyway so now you can start that from that flow and
start searching again a residual residual flows and so on and they are written before
we can see what
you can't OK question is can i just sort of take the offending flow but
it is zero
you can't just take one piece of flow
well defined one edge
but it is zero at least you should worry about that because now
you've changed the balance
a flows have particular note now it's sort of physically impossible flow if you like
in the sense that you've got the sum of the flow at any node is
not be zero as
what was selected four
if it was not
a complicated noble algorithm for doing things
arithmetical problems
which i can't believe
what it was i think
this consciousness
you see
i would argue
the consciousness which has many manifestations
passive things quality
perception and the color red appreciation for
melody are
so four four active free will all these things
also was here which have to do with consciousness and when we know the pain love prior determination
intelligence discussed such such a our country on one word at understanding
and also only understanding in a very specific context
namely the one which used to
arrive with thee
validity geneva
and the fact that can be derived from a
in fact i'm gonna give you this argument later on so
way forward
that's the hardest part of what i mean say blog alchemy the argument
so it's not something which is not difficult
and that gives an outline
and it the basic point is understanding what you're doing
and you can't it seems to me formalize understanding in terms of a purely computational system
and here is the issue i see is a computer computer controlled control robot capable
genuine understanding with this other questions come up here
and whether you could test for understanding is one question
and that's
relates during tests they can you see well can you ask your computer or person which averages
a question which requires understanding in the response
hand that's the sort of thing that computer center lack
in fact you see i would say that
how we use computers and most things if you wanted to solve some
simulate some
problem about how stars behavior something and you have
calculation you want to perform the see what is going to do
well your supply understanding
the computer that's the calculation is a symbiotic relation we have computers that's fine i have no problem with that
but it doesn't seem to be okay the answer that the computer produces it has
the remotest idea what it is what is four
you have to supply the understanding the system really understanding is what the computer doesn't
and now we have three words here
how can i not going define understanding
i don't know how define understanding
three other was i don't have define other intelligence is one and awareness is another
what i'm saying is that they seem to depend
based intelligence whatever it is
well i would think depends on understanding because i would like to say on entity
it is intelligent
it doesn't possess understand
that's certainly seems to be a natural use the words
i would hesitate to say that an entity
possesses understanding
if it doesn't possess awareness
so it is related to this consciousness is when this is an aspect of consciousness
it seems to be so as i said this doesn't say that computers can have it
it's just saying that the interrelated in this kind of way
so if i understand it can be shown to be on computation and that's a
the argument just been trying to present you with
and intelligence is not a matter of computation moreover system
if aspects of awareness and perhaps all of
beyond computational so so that's the my position here
is that
these things are
beyond computation
now i wanna get slightly more technical and i hope you'll bear with me here
because i want to give a proof
of the statement i
giving you before
one this here
and today just wonder introduce
a few
first civil just
there's a thing called a pi one sentence that's actually one of the simplest types
of mathematical statement you can make
which can be extremely difficult to prove
and one of the most famous
is he
famous famous last theorem was proved by andrew wiles
a few years ago
the famous gold box conjecture as a out fellows last summer what you've probably heard
the go by conjectures that every
even number greater than two
is the sum of two prime numbers is still unproved
and there's the lagrange theorem that every
natural number is the sum of four squares natural numbers well large prove that's it is a theorem
but these are all examples of what are called taiwan sentences and they can all be phrased
in the following form you can say
there is a computation
that's this a turing machine action
if it
goes on forever
that's saying this by one sentence is true
if it stops at some stage
that's the say is false
so you set it
looking four
let's say they go by one you said set looking far
even numbers which are not the sum of two primes but not too sure about four
so far this use of the word blog site which is the unofficial apple weblog
is a community block saying
so first of all the study of the differences between active and influential bloggers
so in the chart on the left side you see
most active bloggers which are listed on this blog site
and on the right side you see
most influential bloggers which is generated by more
the names in italics are the ones which are common to both lists
so based on these lists you can identify that there are some differences between active
intervention dollars
and then you can also identify four different categories of bloggers like the ones active
there are some inactive but influential bloggers and active but they are not as influential
and it is fourth that each which is an active and non engine
but you don't have them because the summary ourselves this in some blog posts and
moreover these are very influential
so next we study of without any parameters on of these are the formats which
we considered
is relevant or not
the formalism study
we generate
different lists for these influential bloggers by taking out one
but i mean each day
so we see c five contributions on the x axis
the first one is not things which is basically considering only the three parameters not
the openings and then no comments which is of the three founders except the commons
in the blog post length and then doing things and then the fifth one is
all in basically you have although
parameters in the model
they can see you have are
different countries have different arrangements for
these bloggers
so none of these two configurations have similar rankings so
this means that
including different parameters
these changes in these are the traditional owners
we also some of the correlation studies between these different parameters so what we did
was we
did a lot of
you know pairwise coalition for these different parameters so far these four parameters with the
solution to be found or one of these beers are actually correct
you have to use all these with parameters
and then
he also
initially there are some of the parameters
which can be used to find influential bloggers so we used the rate of convergence
is one of the possible it
so the number assumption would be like if you get a spiky comments reaction then
that post is really influential as compared to flat comments reaction but what we found
was different because
these two are available french force and
the they
exactly what kind of reaction so discussing the fact that despite the fact that we
are dealing with this
inflation of course not
so far you try to understand the influential bloggers hold they are different from active
bloggers different types of influential bloggers
and there temporal patterns
and more and more parameters
this one is basically gives you the
temporal patterns of influential bloggers and the
the heat map is arranged in such a way that all the
give you a different
or this blog site
and the columns gives you the bloggers which have been influential
at some point of time
the kind of media gives you the of
level of
influence they had so the darker the colour is the more influential
they were at that time
so so far we have not right
at the first one is the substitutional impurity and then if you flip over on
the back side and I have a copy of this cartoons and so here's a
substitutional impurity atoms its we've seen this already when we put phosphorus and the silicon
1 example it occupies a normal lattice site occupies a normal lattice site so there
is the door open that we've seen before and also you towards the end of
the lecture hall boron and dined substitution actually sits at the normal our carbon lattice
site there also alloying elements such as magnesium and aluminum there very few medals they're
used in commerce in pure for most metals are used in the form of allies
that is to say solid solutions so for example this aluminum cans is dominantly aluminum
contains a certain amount of magnesium and a certain amount of silicon and this is
designed given the properties that it needs 1 of the main properties that we need
and this can start is the ability to have a very very rapid delight of
the atoms this if you look carefully there's no seem on the bottom of the
this is made of a single sheet of
and so the sheet moves over a Die Presse punches down up down and forms
the u-shaped right circular cylinder and then a 2nd pieces crimped onto the top you
can imagine the high speed at which the atoms of gliding over 1 another and
part of what gives us the ability to the is the allies magnesium is isn't
is purposely added to aluminum we've seen color goals and this is 1 example is
nickel going into gold which will turn from its very buttery almost buttery ductility into
something that's got a little bit of strength to mean wondering that if you put
it down on the on the dresser at 1st to form so we have to
give some strength and in this case we can alter its colors so this is
a nickel Adam sitting on the SEC site normally occupied by gold again substitutional impurity
here's the last 1 we learn about 7 up in the lithium citrate 7 suppose
your on colander administering sailing in the in the hospital and as follows me 5
% sodium chloride in water but if there a lithium impurities substituting for sodium in
the sodium chloride lattice
is gonna dissolve and if you got some sodium deficient patient medium some lithium chloride
it's gonna be a bad day at the office so you know substitutional impurities can
have deleterious effects so those were examples of substitutional impurities the 2nd type is the
ins interstitial impurities in it occupies the position between lattice sites and you go to
the cartoons you'll see this highlighted and the interstitial impurity obviously this Adams small it
has to fit into the void space between the atoms so we did the calculations
we know that close-packed FCC lattice is
74 %
and 26 per cent of all i'd like 26 % voice is not just randomly
distributed it is there nothing in between the atoms so I could take all the
atoms away and I could give you a lattice comprising the interstitial sites you understand
the concept of lattices simply points in space so instead of putting gold atoms there
let's put the space between the golden imagine what we can do so here's an
example of an interstitial atoms small and it's obviously impurity because it's different from the
composition of the parent of material and so there are desirable and undesirable so an
example of a desirable and element is carbon in iron carbonyl iron is the basis
for steel without
carbon iron we wouldn't have steel and
the interesting thing about carbon irony is that the
radius the radius of the carbon atoms is actually greater than the radius of the
interstitial site in iron
greater than the radius of the interstitial site in prior so therefore when the carbon
goes into that interstitial site it actually distorts the lattice suppresses back on the parents
iron ladders and through this distortion of strengthens the material
another example is hydrogen and lantern nickel five it goes into the interstices in this
compound lantern nickel five
voids that are large enough to accommodate hydrogen and hydrogen can go in this axis
sponging hydrogen at peak loading
can go at this level
we have a huge amount of hydrogen going in here the density of hydrogen 11
medical firemen saturation is greater than liquid hydrogen itself and this materials under investigation along
it is great
i use partial derivatives because i'm not changing x
that's the justification for the articles
now again he this the first thing that
i'm going to write for this
and the fact
now you get
delta x
no i
doing something that mathematicians would never do i'm going to find out
don't tell u eighteen or whatever people that i did that
so now what you have
is that unified by t
thanks to the tall white square
on some value of x
it is now
x squared
and believe it or not
this is a big moment in our life
you view differential equation
of y which is a function of x and t
i will buy you take the derivative time and you take the robot double derivative
what is a possible solution to this differential equation
you can just see it
by looking at it you immediately see what the solution must be
any function
value function
you can come up with anyone i don't care which one any single valued function
or fax
one minus
once the times t
well satisfied difference just look at it
you can see it works
i think the second derivative in time
he gets his career out you get the second derivative of the function
take the seventh second derivative next you only get the
second derivative of the function and that's all
so all it requires is
that c
is the square root
but you know
that year month salary that any single valued function will satisfy this difference
one of them in you that c
one dimensional that c
beats per second is the velocity
if i have apples here
i was also there
this can only be in policy
as the dimension of the velocity
so therefore
you might as well write this
as part minus fifty
UML model right before here
the velocity
and we might as well change now
this differential equation in a way more
more uniform way
which is what i'm going to do do now
which is one of these script
ninety two y
calls to y
x squared
this equation
generally called
the wave equation
it will be with us until the end of the course
to death
do us part
it is really a big moment
because you're going to see this equation
many times
for many different systems
but now you have seen it
being derived for this
very specific case
let's now evaluate
the meaning of the v
if i have a
and i think just a function
could be assigned to the cosine i think one way more imaginative i think this
that's my function
it is to be single valued can
must be singled out
that's my function
so that's my function as
time t
let's take for free
always the positive number for simplicity
i'm going to call it even
he is always positive right
and i want to know
final comment later in time when there a minus sign here what that function looks
so it equal zero i gave it to you
what would it look like
a little bit later in time
if there's a minus sign
any suggestions
making it smaller
i'm beginning to see the dark
the lines are the diffraction which is taking over
look at this and the maximum
right there
it's getting lighter
getting wider
and i make this slip narrower getting wider
it's getting wider the club beautiful you see these destructive interferences
we're like was like his darkness
while right now it is at least ten times wider than it was before
now it twenty times wider
and get very faint of course it gets very faint because if i make this
very narrow not much like go through is nothing i can do about it
incredibly impressive this is how white
that sounds maximum becomes
that is very characteristic for the fraction
this leads the wider
diffraction pattern at the center maximum
now it is in monochromatic lights monochromatic light means that you
have practically only one wavelength
that's the way
that i can make you see this
from your own seats
that is what we're going to do
with the
with the cars that you have
so if you can get the cards out now
we did this
in one color right green lights almost one called almost monochromatic so you see a
beautiful pattern you're very well defined guidelines
you now can use this little slide that you have
born in front of your i
and i'm going to make you see this white flight
using all the features that you're supposed to see
but it's even more interesting in white light
with white light you have little red you have little blue you have a little
and so these minimum
will fall
at different locations of course
so you don't see it as beautiful as i showed you as this thing as
i showed you in green but you seem very distinctly the center maximum you see
dark lines
on either side
the main reason why i want you to see this is
if you manage to manipulate
the size of the slits
the size of a
if you manage to manipulate that when you make it narrower
notice that the diffraction pattern gets brawler
and not the other way around
so first make sure that you get it you begin to see the dark areas
and and then try to make it a little narrower
and then you see it opens up
this is precisely what i did
with the variable split here
so given the benefit of find help me that actually you don't have to pull
it open project you can
move one piece of the car behind the other cards
so you want to go to the back in europe
your found comes forward that works very well for me
o can see clearly the diffraction pattern
very good thank the card with you impress your parents
and look at home that very bright street lights
you will still see the same
diffraction pattern although not as ideal
as you see it here because our sources online source and that helps of course
if you split is vertical
if i don't have a
so that's as an opening but if i have a circular opening then
the pattern that you would expect
is the same that you see here which you have to
rotated about this line because you know actual symmetry
so you don't have a long slit but you have a circular opening
and indeed that is approximately correct
if you had a circular opening
you would see is centre maximum which would be very bright
and they would say rings around its of zero
so if i tried to make you see it
this would be
center maximum
it would be a ring around here
complete darkness
and then
again a little bit of light
not very much
because remember
this maximum is only four and a half percent of that one
and then you would see again ring
this complete darkness and so on
so you have a little pinhole
this is the image that you get on the screen
from the pinhole
you would think now that this
from here to here
state equals zero
and we call that state of
this is the state of always you first
you would think that islam that divided by a if a is the diameter of
european all
well it's almost that it is a little larger because the pinhole circular geometry is
different from the line
and so take my word for it that it comes not at all level that
divided by a but it comes roughly one point two level and divided by a
you want to be picky it's really one point two two
i'm that divided by a and this of course is in radians again i work
in terms of gradients small angle approximation
and so this raises the issue
of what we call in physics angular resolution
suppose i have the pinhole
and i look
at the images of two light sources
one light comes in from there
and you comes in from there could be the headlights of the car
could be two stars in the sky
well each one of them will give the diffraction pattern that's non-negotiable you can never
bypass the fraction so one star will give the diffraction pattern here one headlight any
other will give the diffraction pattern here
you would have no problem
to say we are the all the two light sources there's one star and there
is another story
now make the angle between the two sources smaller and smaller and and smaller and
and smaller sorted these two diffraction patterns come closer and closer and closer and closer
how close can you know bring them so did we
you and i will still say
still two sources
we call that angular resolution
and so how we define angular resolution is that both light sources have exactly the
same strength and that's assume for now for simplicity that the monochromatic so that there
is only one wavelength that they
then the criterion that is generally accepted
so that we can still
the site that there are two light sources
that this one
the centre of this one
it is not closer
then the location
gamma does not
if there is no
very from gamma
this time
is not
the with an arbitrary valid sequent and trying to find out
proof of it
i'm going to start arbitrary is not provable and construct model the future
that way around
it's easier
i'm going to simplify further
taking the a over to the site
right the sequence with two right hands tied to
not a entails
the bad guy
tales everything
it's going to follow usual practice by writing that with an empty right hand side
so gamma delta is to
gamma not a
is not satisfiable
the not a here might as well be a member of gamma
right i mean it's not doing anything now
for all gamma
is inconsistent
then gamma
it is
is a syntactic notion has to do with the deduction it means there is a
derivation of contradiction
because there's nothing to do with
tautologies and it is
OK gamma
from gamma you can derive a contradiction
if the fans
then gamma is unsatisfiable
and i hope i've
just the doctrine of steps
that you now believe
to do
since the doing work
might as well
the for all gamma holds in particular for gamma would not sign
this is going to be the technique
twenty minutes
left of negations
all this is being captured for posterity here slowness screws up
now we're happy
left office
a stroke here
right if gamma
one of the forced to use it does not entail a contradiction
then it's not
it's not unsatisfiable that is satisfiable
so i'm going to suppose
that there is no
all contradictions
from gamma
and show
that is satisfiable
and i'm going to do it by cooking up
domain and interpretation and uation
for the evaluation
will get
for smoothing we can create a lot we can use a lot of algorithms and
actually to be
topic how to small language models
but in
all practice when
creating greater when we are creating real operations usually people tend to use the simplest
algorithms and the simplest is classes using
it's interesting that actually applies to thinking about this formula defines you
try to answer
a very important question
what is the probability of
the next sunrise
every morning we see that the sun rises
the question is what this probability that it
the domesday
the last day of the universe and we not see
on the next day
and basic based on this philosophical questions
he came to form
two some form
of the probability of the next day
but for us it's more interesting probability of unseen words and
we usually four or unseen growth we can say something like this person and number
of seeing words in our collection
another problem is that
even for big fat
and use using big says to him
precise estimation
always had some
some the station in statistics and all a lot of different problems based on this
fact that
there are there and we don't have a lot of statistics for this work
and if you have a virus or
for example you have a collection of medium documents
and some words
four times
and in other words in the same collection
two times
does it mean that this is the first work is twice more probable than the
second one
i think that's from the intuition that can say no it is not true
it simply because
we have one document that uses this around the world
and we don't have
more documents with the first part of something like this
usually we need some additional smoothing tool
compensate this effect
and i don't want to talk a lot about it and if you really need
this and if you really want to
avoid this situation you need to
but need to do a special research in this area or to use
well known models
by the way that just
language models
initial development of them
the biggest progress
was done in speech recognition
because when doing speech recognition is very real
previous work
and we want to predict the next
also you can look at this language models as one of the simplest variant of
markov models and it is actually a markov model the simplest
and of course you can
use something more sophisticated
trying to
keep all our ideas very simple and durable in
one day of programming
OK so
how we can present this data in our memory in our program
so we have
we can have by the way i forgot to say that
we can have
this an
can be different ways
so it can be a unigram model
this is simply distribution of words by probability how probable problems arise
it can be by gram
when you have probability of two work
and so far
and the a country this this a good thing that's not
how they can prevent this data in memory of our computers
the simplest approach is
use any of the
serious structure
that we discussed on OWL
second lecture
and since work
for all combinations of words for background model is the key
and the probability is when
this is
the simplest
presentation of this information in memory
it's pretty obvious
so if you want to estimate some probability based on these models
you can simply
do a search in this model find it and get this probability
if you want to get probability for background
three grand you simply doing the same search but you're
the key is
combination of two or three words
how we can build this model
OK using our infrastructure that we already have
the o four hours
doris search engine
so we have some linear decision process
creates a sequence of words was attribute
and we simply
using some sliding window or this
four that getting from innovation
and size of the windows one forward
unigram model
so in getting every word
from our streams
searching in our
yes structure for this work
look into
count how many times this so this work
as infantry this counter by what are every time and we see this right
background models simply looking for towards creating this key
searching in our
index structure
by this new key
and well you can't
so it's pretty simple really
talking about the amount of memory for all four
during in innovation
they have some constant amount of
memory for this
the problem is that
actually don't have constant amount of
memory for all n gram models
because it can be actually huge
that's smart enough
you know how to handle this situation
the remember when we were building inverted index and we decided that
we cannot
keep it in memory it can fit into all memory because
four-year-old we need to understand the rates and mechanisms of reactions
so this is going to competitiveness it's linked to resource utilization efficient use of materials
and energy
we know how to
process things effectively the second thing is environment number of you've come to me after
on different occasions spoken of you're interested in environmental matters one of the simplest things
one can do to minimize adverse environmental impact of chemical processes is to be efficient
so understanding how reactions proceed is critical in
minimizing the adverse
environmental impact
so productivity issues
secondly environmental issues
and thirdly
societal issues societal issues
you're here at MIT want to get an analytical education
and you want to go and do some
o thing in the world
and one of the things that can happen if you understand your chemistry and understand
the kinetics is you can keep
a plant operative you can keep people working so there societal implications for
failure to understand kinetics
a process becomes
obsolete you go out of business and people going to work so for these and
many other reasons
we want to study kinetics
and economics
it takes place over a very wide range that's why i played this song about
that's what this is about it's about time
we have at the one extreme very slow chemical processes and at the other extreme
very fast chemical processes slow we have things that take place so on geological or
even cosmic time scales very very slow processes
on the other extreme we have
such things as explosions
explosions and explosions are necessarily
for example in the airbag that operates in automobile
it operates thanks to the fast kinetics of the gas solid reaction there is no
is no pump that can inflate an airbag an acceptably high rate to do you
any good in an automobile crash what happens here is the kinetics of a reaction
between two solid what we have is basically solid solid goes to gas
and as you know the volume of the gas is thousands of times the volume
of the solid and in particular
it's the reaction of sodium a side with
potassium nitrate and one of the products nitrogen gas in huge quantities
so you accelerometer accelerometer decides that you're decelerating iterate that alarmingly high
probably not healthy occasion
tiny current a tiny current electric current flows through a wire which acts as the
trigger for this reaction once the reaction goes
you can inflate the airbag in a matter of millisecond so
what we want to do is understand some of the basic cells
of chemical kinetics and so let's start and we're looking at a a general reaction
the general reaction to understand how first of all to characterize chemical reactions let's characterize
the rate of a chemical reaction so
want write a little a is
stoichiometry and big a is some chemical identity so a models a plus b models
react to form little little-seen moles of c
plus little the moles of d
that sort of
prototypical reaction kinetics
the kinetics
accounts for
the rate of convergence
the rate of conversion
that's what we want to know
how quickly our we consuming are
how quickly our we consuming our reactance how quickly are we
generating our products
so that's what we're interested in understanding so
we have first of all simple thing we have conservation of mass operating which we've
seen from early part of the real line one that
the rate of consumption
the rate of consumption of all of the reactants
the rate of consumption of all of the reactants must equal the rate of production
of all of products
there's no sources are six we have no wormholes hear everything that goes into the
plant has to come out of the plant in some other way
and specifically we can even get into looking at the rate of disappearance of a
single reactor so for example the stoichiometry would dictate that
the rate at which i consume
a this is one over a this is the
three multiplayer times the change in the concentration i apologize for
the multiple faster this case little c represents the
stoichiometry in this case this represents concentration of
the rate of change of concentration of a rate of its disappearance
when is normalized from all number would be the same as the rate of appearance
of the
so the by dt of the concentration of these so we have these individual
relationship so this is simply conservation
conservation of of mass
conservation of mass so we have that
now comes the
o point of kinetic theory we can theory says is that there's is a relationship
i think this is an example of a productive all-nighter and
also this is this is an example of when it's the right choice the blow
your homework if anyone wishes to do things like this and be as productive you
are certainly entitled to blow up the homework here too so
but to bring in good data like this when you're done
anyway this notion is the genetic map
it was totally abstract concept much like mentals abstract concepts that there were even genes
now we're going further saying whatever genes are we still don't know their DNA et
cetera et cetera whatever they are they live online and they behave as if they
live on online and they undergo recombination cetera and when i see a recombination rate
recombination frequency recombination rate
it must mean the genes are very close together
if i see a recombination rate very very close never recombine recombination rates
well i don't know maybe ten percent or something well there's some distance between
and if they further and further and further away or in totally different chromosomes what
would be the recombination rate here
for two different chromosomes
half of these are non parental types so when i get up to recombination rate
of fifty percent
then it means that they live on
they are so-called unlinked to each other
either they're on different chromosomes entirely
or i suppose it's possible in fact it is possible that they are so far
on the same chromosome
the probability of crossovers occurring is so high
that there'd correlated from each other and i can't observe any recombination rate less than
fifty percent it turns out many chromosomes are sufficiently big that lots of crossovers can
occur and you can actually detect linkages the two ends of the chromosome but if
you string together some genes in between you can see that this is linked to
this linked to this is like this is linked to this system to this
OK alright
so started it is another one of my heroes because he comes up with this
utterly abstract model here of chromosomes of genetic maps
what's meant to get that point
see some of the
so can
well first of all
you take
section four
this begins to provide a fairly convincing evidence for the chromosomal theory because it made
a whole lot of pretty wacky predictions and they pretty much holed up
here's another thing that provide a lot of good evidence for
and that
was sex linkage
also in morgan's law
which was a very productive play so much that
folks wondering about the fact that chromosomes although they almost always occurred
in pairs
the lined up with each other perfectly
in many species there was one
odd couple
a pair of chromosomes
always paired up with each other
but they didn't look the same
this one looks like an axe
this one kind of how the shape of y
and hence they got the names the x and y chromosomes
here was something very interesting
in front flies it was always the males had next one
in females it was always in x
what does that tell us
about these chromosomes and what they do
well what you believe to true
just correlated with gender females have these two funny chromosomes
males have as a human females of these two axes males seven x and y
it doesn't have to mean that they determine gender
maybe gender determines them
maybe what happens is that in female cells
you get both chromosomes but in male cells some some enzyme comes along and inches
off the end of the chromosome
yeah i mean this some physiological state
of the chromosomes why why were you so ready to leap to the conclusion that
the chromosomes determine sex rather than gender than the gender terms come
because you know the answer you've been told all this et cetera but i again
invite you to take apart what support you have and ask how would you know
right all these things you get told that you know how to now and there
was great argument about what is this really the case
how could you convince people
but this was true
it's not obvious to know which way it would go
the most convincing evidence not the only the most convincing evidence came from a single
they had been isolated morgan's lab and have zero fly
they had the very interesting property that instead of the normal red drosophila eyes this
basically it pays off only certain
of a certain type of problems in certain scale so for small things like counting course sorting
probably could do would be good idea although technically you can do this
no it's
and so on
this is the idea itself
not as much
on the level of functional logic or procedural
it's more like how you split how you will reformulate your problem
in the way they are so you have input data
and you try to solve something
now the point is
the dual first that that's why it's called mapreduce
first you'll met these data are
basically split the data into
many chunks
all smaller problems
and then you'll well reduce the solutions
the particular solution simple
the final solution so
in old fashioned way which almost nobody
using this term anymore in this context is this dividing can conquer
paradigm of
programming i mean this is the underlying intuition
is that it's nice nicely
are nicely these paradigms nicely mapped into these distributed processing platform
let's see
gotta do this if it's
processing conferences and
are data mining car talked with guys so usually they would have standard algorithms
reformulated in this fashion so this would be that difficult paradigm
usually wouldn't get new algorithms just that all the algorithms reformulated in this way and then they
and discover uh
among some data
another level in this pipeline we set so
how to store the data so high-performance schema-free database is the so-called
no ask classical databases these are the ones which
got quite popular in the last couple of years and now what are the typical characteristics of this
very can add something to this
the first
the idea is to support large amounts of data
most of them can really support large amounts of data then
why they're called the west quite because mostly they have this ground interface although
this is even changing all this i think that
so here you can see mongol be basically the use jason
simple enough so nobody they care to know spend like three days writing proper passes over the edges
jason pazis so
this is my understanding why the hinges
and jason is simple enough
then they operate in distributed infrastructures like on top of hadoop
based on these key value pairs so there's no pre-defined schema which is
of course suitable far linked open data which i'm sure you've heard these days about
so that no pre-defined schema means that no
you've no extra wear hats one later on when you're changing the
when changing the problems are adapting the problem
the flexible and fast
you have plenty of implementations
well here i forgot to mention the
over them
plentiful implementation new new ones are coming i would say so here's an example of
session with mongol be
around mungo
for instance with this statement you save name peaks warden
i ze blue
drop in hand with the next sentence
i say find me something with
peter ward and and you get back dobj
this is pretty much the whole the whole
paradigm so
everything is the same as it used to be that works fine fast
distributed fashion
and so
not many services are extra analytics services and so on are on the top of
let's say and tools like all the elements so one would have
more like this lightweight reasoning on top of it which is already
more sophisticated and many of those
but i get the new ones are coming which will have even even more
so i've already shown you this example before
and i also shown this
also if we now substitute
this thing
this upper bound of the growth function and growth function remember was almost the same
up to the door and has the shattering coefficient so remember all that we derive
the shattering coefficient
we can
now all the shattering coefficient in terms of the VC dimension in the balkans like
which should be what i showed you before in my my powerpoint slides
it tells us
test correspondent from both the training error plus
this complexity to
depending on the VC dimension
so it's
one interesting thing about all this businesses
that originally about in germany started by
studying the consistency of empirical risk minimisation
so here is some limitations first me one of which may be the simplest induction
principle that you can imagine just minimize the training error
it is natural to ask the question does this work or not
this shows us that if the VC dimension is finite
it this goes to infinity this quantity goes to zero so then in the limit
for all functions of the
learning machine test are in training are all the same
in probability
so they found out that this is consistent empirical risk minimization but actually
by doing so since everything that did was valid also for finite sample sizes it's
just not just an asymptotic theory
they they actually came up with something that you could also
used to improve
in the finite sample case so to actually
come up with different adaptive principle minimize the training error minimize something that involves the
training error and at the same time tries to control the complexity
one of the learning machine
it's called
structural risk minimisation
and it's something that people usually don't do in practice people often come up with
arguments a well this three something like structures decision to support vector machine is example
of that
but in the in the showcase you would have a nested set of functions
if you move to the right set of functions gets larger
therefore also the VC dimension gets larger because if you can show a set of
points so if you can classify a set of points in all possible ways
using this set of functions then you can also do it using this of functions
because every function that's in here is also here
but you might be able to still do it for larger sets of points with
the function space is large so the VC dimension increases the right
at the same time this capacity term in my bones the square root
it had on the right-hand side will increase with the VC dimension
and the bound which is the sum of this training our capacity to when they
behave like this
so as i move to the right i will always pick the best function from
the corresponding set
we see dimension increases
training error will probably decrease because if i that this function from largest that i
can potentially find better function
so there will be some kind of trade and at some point you will have
the smallest possible upper bounding the risk and the
you could you could say
let's go with this
we don't know the risk but least we have an upper bound
was the message from all this
if you think about this pond again
you want to generalize so what's important to you want to generalize you should be
working with the function class which has small capacity
for instance measured by VC dimension
yet at the same time the function class should be able
to explain the given training data
these are two conflicting goals and and probably you can only do this if someone
can guess something about your problem if you have some prior knowledge
so if you can choose some
functions that you think are reasonable for they could be smooth functions if you think
the problem move
then you might be able to get away with the small function class
small VC dimension at the same time
as being able to explain the data if you can do this in your business
so it's all about choosing good function classes
which is the same as choosing priors essentially
so for instance if we go back to this
linear classifiers of separating
but in
r two that we step three
in our and VC dimension n plus one
in high dimensional feature space they would have large VC dimension but as i mentioned
already before
if they induce large margin of separation they have
small capacity actually what should be measuring them using the VC dimension but i want
to introduce the capacity measures now
and that's the basis of support vector machines and other kernel machines
and it's a little bit but actually i could stop at this point and
we can have some discussion of some questions
it's time for you know
so thank you very much for your attention so far
so don't be shy