in the direction of k
and this line happens to be the line where the field at this moment in
time is the maximum and pointing
in new directions
so it is crests
in e
the mountain coming out of the board maximum value
i draw not aligned perpendicular to are
so you can build are
the dot product is zero
are is perpendicular to k
for this point
i will also assume that the effect here
is the maximum pointing a new direction and then there is one here
OK there are here
is therefore by
and cables are used for
because this now represents a wave
this is the form e
of the wave where he is maximum
new direction is the maximum new direction is maximum you interaction
in other words this here
is by definition
of labor
and this whole thing moves out
in space was
speed c
so you see the lines can build are perpendicular to k
the maximum of the effect this
a moment in time and all that starts to move out
now you go to the
the third dimension
then came the world are is constant i now no longer lines but they are
perpendicular to the vector k
and this whole plane perpendicular to the vector k
in the whole plane at the moment in time the vector is everywhere the same
what it is linearly polarized whether this surgery polarized when it's elliptical polarized is irrelevant
it's everywhere the same
and the whole plane then moved out which this speed of light
in that direction
of k
so can build are in three dimensions i all
planes perpendicular to the the vector
so if you stand anywhere in space
and you look in the direction where the radiation is coming from
that in any plane that is perpendicular to k
go to infinity there there to there
at any moment in time the vector is the same and the vector is the
and i said that is linearly polarized weighty issues or circular or elliptical
is a different matter it could be
either one of those
so this is the best way that you can think of the
forum of a
the vector going in
three dimensions
these and in planes perpendicular to the direction of propagation
in our first case
which is also very simple
because i wanted to warm you up slowly
OK are
it became simply casey
o OK x will zero
OK while zero
because it was only going in the direction casey was the only one which was
not zero which was k
so my dot product k delta are collapses into a casey
and so the wavelength lambda is two pi divided by this case
but if of course if you have a three-dimensional case the the situation
is a little bit more complicated
because then k
it is the
square root
as you see here
of xkx scrapers carey's purpose cases career
so our first case
to make it simple for you
this is the right moment to stop
after the
break we can
look at some
demonstrations also
so you have to relax a little to digest all this
this is not easy
so let's start handing out this many quiz
to make you feel good about yourself made it easy this time
don't start yet
you start handing out
i put here on the blackboard
x y
this is an electromagnetic wave
going in this direction perpendicular to the direction of k
so this is
definition of wavelengths
this is where e is the maximum in your direction and this is where the
maximum in your direction
and so this is the wavelength
now look
at the intersection
of these wave
in the y axis
this wave
and it intersects there
so the distance from here to here
is l y
which is way larger than life
and the same is true for the distance in the x direction is also larger
than that
and in the z direction in general it would also
the larger than lambda
now it is wave moves with the speed of c
and and when it has moved
the distance
in the UK direction
this crest
is here
how far has moved in the y direction
all the way from here
two there
so it's a brief in the y direction is larger than c
so that's been which we call the face
the phase velocity
in the y direction
it's very simple is l
divided by lab
time sink
and that is larger than c
it follows immediately from the geometry
because this angle here is the same as this angle there
this is also OK
divided by KY
five c
it's not only larger than c
but it can be
when larger than c
two pi
divided by l of y
i refuse to call and of y
let the y
i don't want to have to think in terms of the wavelength this direction wavelength
in this direction and of the wavelength in that direction for me
there is only one wavelength and that wavelength is two pi divided by k
so i refuse to call this labor of y
the k lies two pi divided by that of y
and you can do the same of course in the x in this he direction
and you will find
that the phase velocity
in the same direction
divided by
kx time c
and the phase direction
in the same direction
in this case
divided by k
c five c
and what is the phase direction phase velocity in the direction k
that is k
divided by k
time c
that is c
it is
on the wall
one of the
before that
this is something
you get what you have
a one of
three of these
you know nothing
one of them
o thirty five
one of these different
that's why
so the government
on the way to
all of
you know
cancer patients of different stages right so
we might
interested in summarizing data so we might use the hierarchical clustering as a way of
finding the clusters in the data
and that is still representing the data itself
we simply
represent each data by which cluster it belongs to
so we don't really sometimes they don't really care about the
i love the detailed information about
about the data
about the data points by simply where it is in generally space
the reason why why why we might be interesting hierarchical clustering is
that we don't believe that
they come came from some sort of hierarchical
underlying tree structure
and we
actually want to we actually interested in recovering what is
the underlying tree structure which give rise to the data so this is
this is an example
examples of this things like
the the language tree example and phylogenetic tree
oh by the way if there's any questions to
ask questions
so this
a number of
jet that's of
so there are many different types of hierarchical clustering algorithms
and they can generally be split into a different sort of approaches they could this
described in terms of different dimensions
to describe the algorithms so one dimension is in terms of how you construct your
that's true
general approach is one is the top down approach
and one is the bottom up approach
in the top down approach we start off by saying that all of data points
belong to one single cluster
and then we're gonna
we consider recursively split this cluster into smaller and smaller clusters until we decide
until we did decide to stop
the in the bottom-up approach which is
also called agglomerative
we start off with one
cluster for every data point so we start with the clusters
and we iteratively find two clusters too much
and we can't keep on merging the clusters until we get one big cluster for
the whole data
the whole dataset
so it turns out to the
dominant approach is bottom one
because it turns out to be much easier to construct to find good trees
when you start off with the bottom-up rather than top-down
i guess one way to think about this is that
when you start off with one big cluster
and you want to
two split into two smaller clusters
without knowing the internal structure of the clusters is very hard to decide how to
split that one the cluster into smaller clusters
another way of looking at is as follows if you have one cluster with an
data points
to find the optimal split into two sub clusters
you need to search through
how many
how many possible splits things exponential
two today and number of possible splits
one cluster into two smaller clusters
but in the
OK so
the bottom-up approach
if you have an clusters and you want to decide which two cluster too much
there's only a quadratic number of them so is much easier
it's much easier to search for the
locally optimal health clusters too much
then to search for
the locally optimal
it's split of one cluster into two
yes i will come to that in fact you could
many of the self agglomerative
clustering approaches
the way they differ is in terms of what distance measure used
and how you define distances on clusters
given distances on data points
it doesn't have to be split one to two but could be split one into
choosing the number is
well defence still so many different ways
so choosing the i guess you could
if you are bayesian like me then you use things like dirichlet process mixtures
when you
split data point to multiple clusters and you don't use
some penalty for me if you have more clusters than in the sense you have
more use more parameters to describe the data
and if you don't use something some sort of penalty to penalize for a larger
number of
of clusters then
the best way of
describing the data is simply to every data point being its on cost
so then that's that's different ways of of
for the number of parameters they've gotten one way is to
these businesses
i think tomorrow
maybe was so soon
it called some
good so much for linguistic values variables and because can of course now only want
to model those types of membership functions in in the computer in some sense system
that derives them automatically from data we want to manipulate them using some clever algorithms
usually don't want to model arbitrary functions of arbitrary shape so the couple of classical
examples that people often use the most commonly used is the so-called property which is
defined by four numbers so all you need to do is to store these four
numbers ABC which sort of the left
left corner office repetetive the degree of membership starts being larger than zero then be
used there are sort of the area starts where the degree of membership is one
and then it declines until c and then it declines it's going to property it
that's nice it's very easy to manipulate it's enormously easy to calculate
degrees of membership but if you wanted to use algorithms i'll get back to that
later but if you wanted to modify these things sort of fit data that a
little bit like the ones i just mentioned networks of for example using something like
gradient descent they need to compute a derivative this is really not it would made
to model things so you may want to do something like that goes costs bell-shaped
curves they you model the degree of membership using such for fear of being standard
the to sort of describe rates it's a wider this and you could actually use
compute derivatives do is sort a gradient descent try to minimise are so in cases
where you want to use sort of mathematical optimisation methods this may be a better
still reasonably easy to compute a special case of the property it will get come
back to that when we talk about fuzzy numbers are the ones that have no
plateau but just the peak you have eighty indians it's sort of like property price
and then of course we have the case singletons instead of just talking about the
degree of membership of one particular that it's like that with a belonging
to this set to a degree of one just listing sort of the the elements
and how much what kind of degree of membership to have don't usually use that
if you don't have a continuous domain
OK so this are some of the most commonly used methods to model fuzzy membership
if you wanted to manipulate them including to invent anything yourself of course
OK just a few definitions because it will pop up more often later they are
two things how you can describe the membership function
are very peaks and so the very fact about which are the support of the
core the support of all elements having non-zero degree of membership the support essentially all
the way from here
so if you like that sort of elements all the elements that belong just beat
to the set are in this the core of the sets of elements that actually
have a degree of one so they need to be some and you lose all
the elements that we definitely belong to that set and then things like alpha cuts
which are all elements that have a degree of membership at least alpha above all
subsequent sort of define an alpha somewhere here and then literally cut through that's the
biggest name comes from and then the
all the elements would be all the elements on this line and then the height
which is the maximum degree of membership for this particular fuzzy sets fuzzy sets don't
need to necessarily have elements that belong to this question
i want to you could also imagine the separatists' all the elements that have the
two but none really belongs to to a degree of one so the height doesn't
necessarily have to be
so i'll be talking about support and cornell did more so the question is to
draw the traditional dress remembering
in the core disappeared from alpha cuts specific alpha
and then of course the height is in this case it's one that could be
and he OK so now the interesting question is if you have fuzzy sets a
fuzzy set that describes old people who has has describes tall people and the trying
to figure out so
an element that has a degree of membership to the set of old people of
point seven and has a degree of the same element has a degree of membership
to the government to the set of tall people to a degree of five what's
the degree of membership to the set of old and tall people were trying to
do things like conjunctions fuzzy distractions normal set operators so what would that be i
mean you can of course
some rule of thumb say well i mean in that case maybe sort of the
average point six may make sense
then you can all point six cents successfully and so it should be higher than
any of these little
degrees of membership probably selection from not be not more than point five percent of
advice you add constraints you want not only
the tall people but if you want to talk and all people in the seventies
with belong to the degree to the set of old and tall people to a
goes to zero
as you approach
this is for you to be bold
you can see it
now actually as opposed to zero of the square the gradient
it becomes more shallow it into multiplying
if you want to play by the gradient it means that as because emergence the
green gives zero here because the average degree does not zero
so just from the properties of optimizing it is easier to optimize the
squared error screen descent than absolute here
great usually women are absolute area use something we use a linear programming solver or
use specialized algorithms that can actually handle the up there
i year
it is the problem here but it's just it's it's
it's just that the
the gradient can only be larger you want to close to the out there more
the range is because here because you can you get more
so convergence was still a lot less
here which is good because if you're if you if you're running online you you
don't want to
jump around with values too much
yes purely for come purely for the competition properties do we use these square
i should point out if you know anything about
least recent literature in regression classification
one of the absolute error
it has a nice properties with respect to the sparsity of the solution so if
you use an error function like this you get many more zero weight
in your status and so if you want an explanatory explanatory solution this is just
the basis functions matter
then you actually are given will give you that solution whereas in square almost every
will be non-zero
but for simplicity
we we use greater
OK so
i think it is explained by
very well in the book if you want to know how you ppl ability to
to the
function approximation case
you can check therefore for for better justification but the idea is simply showing that
this update
it's exactly that the previous update under the exact
function blocks on under the exact same thing
OK so now we have to keep out we keep eligibility is on each parameter
and we update
with the land
the air times the old parameter to be updated
OK so before we had the of states in the states now we have two
with better there'll there'll ability NASA way to implement very efficiently in a few lines
in the gradient sense
for td lambda
are covered the
a bit too detailed i think for what i want to go into that but
that this more information slide actually use the stuff
OK now you have to use
functions again
which are relevant to predicting value
so you might example limiting factor and imagine that processing of my life functions
being in a state
each feature fi is there's an island box one or next box
so i had exactly
i see
i went solo
a really bad
really that we do this would be to have
twenty seven features i think
twenty seven boeing features
which would be
o and acts or mt
positions one what one nine nine to towards three properties here was here
twenty seven features
let's say there's decision one
there's an exhibition nine years in division three and so on
now if you know tic-tac-toe
can someone explain why
this value function approximation
o limit although maybe making sense would never learned the opera policy
think about what values
that this method can can can approximate
so it it all a
i can value this
and i can tell you see next year
but only ever looks at the at each feature individually
what really matters to that are not the individual features and no matter how it
together that i have an axe here and now here
or an exit i i've outlined three axis here
clearly you need that to represent
so weighting these sorts of pages individually
doesn't mean anything about the global picture what you really need
are conjunctions of market positions
i have
features such as
two axes in
two cases where there are two axes in the world
by features like this and we do better in
in tic-tac-toe
but so people often use the nearby from approximations
they're upset when they don't work but i think the reason that work because you
didn't use expressed feature set
one way around this
is that
you can add in
you start with simple features and if you have a function not going well and
more complex features to start to conjoin
cases in your initial features
if you know things like decision trees
decision trees would be a good i functionapproximator here or a regression tree
the biggest trees again here we take into account conjunctions of features
so you may not seem decision trees you have
thank you for example
so we want a century you say
there's an axe in
true false
maybe there is
annexin a
true or false
some point
you get them to leave any say OK i write this has value three point
here i i had two axes are are probably saying high somewhere else another better
here each point
will we
give me
high probability for
one of the faces of my dice
and zero probability for the other each each point of this channel
very very close to what we had in the in the precise this one
if i gave a really little value for alpha
that we make that
i have the chance of falling in one of history
but it's like i'm saying
the chances that i see one of the faces of any of these it's really
low so indian one we
falls but
we don't know which one
if AC one is that having no prior with a uniform prior over the tree
of the
tree possible faces of my days
and if i
could be
four the tree
so far it's like having saying that
they're all
equiprobable they have the same
it is in the middle of the tree
and of course
the classical distributions to caution distribution that we all know
was parameters nu and sigma
which generalizes to the very caution distribution
in which
this time
it's not i don't have here this colour value but a victory
so the the mean is also picture and the
the variance of my question distribution is symmetric
a square matrix
and this distribution it's really important in
in statistics
because of the central limit theorem most of the time
because if i have
a set of random variables
which are
i i d
which i'm going to to define after but what i mean is that they all
have the same distribution
and very
independence between each for each other's
and so the the distribution of this the mean
of these variables
then the words a gaussian distribution
so any time you considering the sum of random variables if
you always in the output is is that if you have enough data
you will have in fact a gaussian distribution
so here is these these central limit theorem is initiated by
by these histograms well what is shown is that imagine they have a uniform distribution
so the
between zero and one the so the probability of having one value between zero and
one is the same for each of these values
and i repeat i have made the
i repeat i draw
somevaluesfrom this uniform distribution
and then computed histogram of these repeated experiment
when i have only one
random variable
we have
our uniform distribution between zero and one of the probability of having each of these
it's quite the same but if i have
if they have two variables
and i take to mean
so we see that now
we have a greater probability two
the sum
the mean is
one half
and if
i have
and search
variables and i take them in
we so we see what's the characteristic form of gaussian distribution can appear
he is the same for me
well for me that's that's something
one is defined as as
the ones like the samples
the the
examples for this
you can give me so that's
and also this and is the same as this
should have
had this in addition
no it's so i take
one sample for example in this in this case i think one sample
of my
uniform distribution
i take one hundred
sample but that's for only one variable
what what ten c
let's say for two because once it's misleading
no i take two
one sample one of one of the other thing to me
one of one variable one after the viability to me and i i d do
that kind of thing
so that that's the mean of two
of taking twice
the uniform
so that's what you call center
always it's one that's what
in one it's the standards
all that was
let's consider
let's consider the
probabilities is that it's usually use in and statistics
statistic it's
more specific around what's the random sample
so a random sample is the number of independent observations taken
well if i have another view with the mother
which is not observed
then i have some additional information
right OK
let's assume that the nodes
the same
clearly is independent
this is information here completely blocks
a user of knowing information about these violent or confer bishop
so there are conditionally independent
a position-by-position
now let's see if they are
we are all of the world will assume that
in the air conditioning panel c let's see if you obtain factorizations
let's just assume that is conditions can all be given c
i assume this is true
so we assume this is true
because this means
just write the joint
as p of the given c of c
and now we know that p of a b and c
is that thing
full we just something these times you see
isn't that precisely
the factorisation of these graphs
you see
you see all sorts of things that i mean we're not talking about the same
things we're over talk about different things
and we are proving that
something that happening in the domain of the graph is implied something
we're proving some
some some mappings
the universe of the probability distribution
in the universe of the graph
when you're interpreting just by looking at the graph
you reading
the set of conditional independence statements and there
factorisation of the distribution
so what this means so far we need to check still for the
and of course you to make an induction argument for everyone but if these equivalence
really hold
in general
what does this tell you
is that
we may completely forget about the universal
o ja break representation in our minds and complete think about
graphical objects
of course and we implemented in the computer will be writing
i mean
behind everything there
probability of course
working with graphs is much easier for
if we have this direct mapping between the universe
you can just work with the graph
and not everything that will be applied
in the real
will be completely under control
so we need to prove this and that is the
there's one
graph left
which is the graph where we have
and c
so we have two parents and one child
now the same question
this a and b
in the independent
OK if is said to have an observation i just
i'm just asking whether a and b independent we have seen the previous UK is
the business does not hold
so let's check if this is true so basically
i feel a b
is equal to some oversea of p of the BBC
but what's the factorisation of the ground
his appeal for a b
and p of the given name
well feel faintly of constant force
we can pull them all
and they only have someone seal you'll see you
and how is how much is the someone still feels he given a b
it's one
so the result here is p of three times p of the
and this is p of b
so look what's happening here
we just proven that can be is
the random variables in the act and the
there is that here
connecting to survive
both the mistaken
that does not mean
the electorate and then
they are actually independent
so this is the
different type of
let's atomic bayesian network that has different
i guess in cracked
we have no observations and this two
it actually makes a lot of sense to me
if this work and to have a child i mean
mary someone i mean it's independent women computing the pelican area
and then if i hope
chicken but
i mean
i'm doing this
let's assume subset the subset of
and it's independence in
now let's see
if i hope so
the child
if we observe the child
if i see something about the track
now the question is will factorizations imply conditional independence
we've seen previously that has been applied math
so a lot let's assume justin factorizations p of a few p of seeing a
conditional independence will
happen if we have that p of the given c
is it good to p of a difference if p of the given c so
let's just what is true
so have here the joint right to join us in
but suddenly we're stuck because
we're looking for these
quality p of the given c of the given c
so two factors in each factor has two terms there's no way you're going to
get to read
there's no way
you're going to get rid of these three
you can make toy model universes which are definitely not computable
even though they're completely deterministic and one way of doing it
is depend on
timing properties of
of what a called polyominoes as squares glued together and if they tile plane or don't
they if it does one thing the universe is one thing if it doesn't other
and then this happens to be one of these non computable
this is tower playing these examples which do
here's another example which doesn't
the fact that is a difficult problem you can see from the example because it's
pretty difficult to see how that tiles the plane
even though doesn't actually extend to infinity but let me not waste time on here the
other things i would say
i just want to show that they are perfectly
but not physically plausible but mathematically plausible models of toy universes
which are not computable which you can not simulate on the computer
so it's only a genuine question that's one thing
that that could be non sit
possible not possible to simulate
but i do want to work on mechanics
because as we saw during himself already
but quantum mechanics might have have relevance
so i have to tell you something about quantum mechanics
in the last remaining minutes that have which is not really enough time
this have occurred
here i have to
idealized experiments
which illustrates he
conflict the basic concepts in quantum mechanics
between particle-like behavior
and wave-like behavior
so here we have a laser so which is the source of photons
do we have what's called eh
beamsplitter or a half-silvered mirror
and half the light goes through it
after this detector over here
the other half figures reflected
the detector
now for a single photon what you find is for an idealized experiment is either
because this way all the way
it's an exclusive if this is registered this world if this
doesn't register
the stars and vice versa on the other one
it's an exclusive or
this all this but not both or neither
that's a very particle-like behavior
but you could slightly modify this property to problem areas here
having now other beings for the
and all these path lengths equal
detectors here and here and then miraculously find every time the photon comes along because
this way and never that way
if these particles like what we are trying to do here
then it might go this way like this way because this way like this with
this way because this would make with respect to it's equally likely to come here
but you don't find
we find that the possibilities
coming here
in some mysterious way cancel each other out
so now this is more like a wavelike behavior
this is particle-like its wave-like
and the way we
make sense that's introducing
the formalism of quantum mechanics and we're gonna tell you too much about it
the crucial point is
that you've these things cause states
hand that alternatives
in superposition so they can happen at once
so let's go back to this case here
it means that the photon
my do this forum i do this
and you have to understand that in a sense it actually does both once
otherwise you couldn't get interference which stops going this way
the photon fields at least both groups
it goes both ways ones
so today is one of the alternative is either
and you have to consider that they both happen once
it's even more mysterious
because we have weighting functions for put weighting factors here
you might think these probabilities
not these are complex numbers
yeah i got
complex plane complex means involves the square root of minus one
you can plot those numbers on the plane
and these numbers w and z
two different numbers in this complex play
well thought corpus for this one hundred and his going twelve
now i was on the selection committee and forty one
there's and also won the award selection committee in each of the images
it is very independent i ask because of his oldest and record what does and
he was selected twice for
this site and also one piece of information i found old since i
i came here to this conference is his academic
you moment OK and everyone knows that he has been running the data mining companies
is microsoft is chief error is now you
and also too small data mining companies
probably not a small data mining companies here
what could be and actually has also extensive and then these experiences
this different universities who was an
gender professor anthony it was still southern california
for several years and his in
and adjunct professor at the university of technology in sicily
and he is also an adjunct professor at the hong kong polytechnic university
OK most part model from the mold after i saw his prison just lies on
sunday had some academic on and i was wondering what colleagues used OK
given his
researcher called and also he has been a great speaker for
many countries is i actually want him to ICDM o three when i was one
of the program committee chair for ICT also in florida and eventually you two cells
and industry
we had two formulations for any security
so what and one was somerfield OK and the other was myself
and then when i heard that i was cover feature was the use of and
i told my mother say that you've always if i was allowed to vote i
would vote for someone as well as for his land at that time i if
his name was given on a one
that would seem to me to need a lot more attractive and the union he
won the silver so what in the two thousand three and i want to use
it so what informally which which is two thousand four
and it's less
one competition story and after any competition so now
we actually that colleagues as i mentioned earlier in his agenda professor at the hong
kong polytechnic university i haven't been able to you spend my sabbatical in the same
university for one year so we actually working together for the now not enough although
two delays that's
welcome to some of the other four
because they want to together
thank you very much for her
very kind introduction
for me that was almost lost control the first two two-minute limit
but i was conflicted
given time
i think i'll skip the first part of my talk
what i wanted to
this talk more about the technical challenges but then
this morning i decided to
focus more on the
on the
and really
more and
what's new here because i think there plenty of data mining
opportunity cost
to be you start thinking about this whole area of social media people interacting with
each other on the web
i'll explain what i mean by that so with
skim i like challenges and
we sort of covered
time and i apologize for not going into the technical side
let me
no i will start with a generic introduction
the goal is to sort of walking for some reason i went through as i
all of the internet advertising business search so forth and show you how to shift
to strategy
and then i'm going to do something completely different which is
should he start talking about some of these very fundamental very important
extremely poorly understood and tell you about research why we formed
and its mission
so i don't need say much about the internet
it's growing fast
thing to be about million users online
happens to be
the number one destination on the internet reaching seventy percent of the US population actually
about seventy percent of the world
for more than five hundred million users to thirteen million users
it offers a lot of properties
by properties things like male
when new finance i am
first of all sorts of
functions that would like to do
one which actually attracts lots of
people keep coming back
and that brings the project
as well as research on the things that makes up the opportunity to
to serve advertising which is how the model is one
i mentioned
we get at the moment the
the term inside looks like just longer
you fix science some reference density
and i'm only interested in the max of this is zero so only
he effects on given theta
it is less than my reference density
when i see something here
otherwise the term will vanish
let's say this is lace and that expression here
and this term will be less than one
so the negative log is going to be
greater than zero
so that his appears
so therefore only if i'm in a low density region
here there are
well actually see something happening
that's what the maps
is good for
for the next thing
so each other over there will be some reference density but actually i want to
get rid of this normalization
just to pay in the wrong place and doesn't really help so
let's just some subtract that the normalisation automatically
it doesn't really change my estimation procedure
it just makes it easier
and then
if you actually what makes the exponential families modelling two p of x given theta
will get this expression here
now this is something you should know from bernard
that's exactly the same same class
the classification will see the first noted addiction
loss function that not was talking about
it was probably talking in terms of slack variables and constraints but if you
go through the math it's the exact same thing
there two
key advantages for it
i don't care about the normalisation so even if g if theta is
impossible to compute
or really expensive
i don't need it
i don't need to do particularly well so i don't need to waste lot of
capacity on the high density regions
if i just care about normal observations this is where you should try getting a
fairly actually density estimate and for the rest they just need to ensure that it's
either in whatever threshold might want to pick
so this is fairly complicated optimisation problem here
which is some general convex programs now becomes the simple quadratic programme
possibly quite a bit here are
so one in several regards it's easy to compute it does what i want allows
me to do so even in situations where otherwise it couldn't do it
and this is probably what you've seen from finite the geometric interpretation
trying to find one perhaps play
that has the maximum distance from the origin yet it's still closer to the origin
than the observations
you guys in the dual optimisation problem to sing the classes being
seen it
who hasn't seen it
so but i didn't cover that
OK so
similar to our entropy
proud promise to minimize
one half the data square some of the slack variables
the condition that theta delta x
six i
and just
i'm using the non-credible version at the moment just because otherwise notation gets messier was
one sequence here
thanks i critical in here
so what we do is
in order to
compute the dual problem similar to the maximum entropy notation we have to get telegrams
by subtracting the constraints multiplied grande multipliers
from the from the objective function
and then
get rid of the problem variables
we need to compute the saddle point
then i can express the problem is that the saddle point in terms of the
deal one's negative dual optimisation problem
again the advances but to go from a possibly infinite dimensional space
one of the proverb into finite dimensional all but
probably high dimensional but
five dimensional space non the less the dual variables
how do we do
well it's just like a risk we take the problem objective function
write it down
lagrange multiplier times constraint
also the green constraint there just here
constraints so that
in the office and the test because the french multipliers have two great equals europe
extend match
and and then what you do is you take the derivative with respect to theta
new soulful
you get another problem
what comes out of it is what you then might be able to solve directly
the seat of a
gives me this expression here
to get the data is some of our colleagues or
remember similar to the kernel expansion had before the representer theorem so i had before
some theta equals some of alpha i y phi alpha x i and y
OK i would have thought topics i here if they want to the kind of
way but at the same time expansion
dix i have
gives me this expression here
see myself one minus the title sierra
now i know that the does it tell a great sequence here
that means it out twice in this interval
you can get rid of the test
and then i go
these things but expressions back into the ground function centre this beast
basically a plug all the values for theta
thanks i
and from what i had
and this allows me to eliminate all the primal variables
and get this dual problem
this is probative seen before
and convexity ensures
at the minimum value
this unique
it does not guarantee
that the minimise itself is unique just the minimum value is unique
something that often people confuse
the problem is that well depending on how we choose the margin rho
we might get more or fewer novel observations began picking some arbitrary threshold for those
no observations and it doesn't really mean much
so i would like to get something that's slightly more meaningful
which hopefully you can calculate
more precisely
because it can express is quite neat expression for the
generating function of the degree
in terms of that
he began
and we can we can we actually
drive quite quite quite a lot from that fact
in particular one thing to note is that is that became more constant and i
was actually wasn't random at all so they know to be doesn't depend on location
at all
then you actually end up with a degree structure in the degree distribution which is
possibly the same as described
now that doesn't mean that the network is structurally equivalent to register a new network
with other statistics may not be same particular things like clustering all clustering coefficient degree
correlations are not going to be necessary it seems to have just read the model
one one interesting conclusion is that
if your space is very symmetric homogeneous meaning that you can basically some symmetry which
takes any point to any other things i think it's something like the surface of
the sphere for instance
and in addition you're your to create your network
note placement x is
it's actually uniform in your space the the outcome will be constants and you will
have a process of
nineteen ninety degree
one consequence of
that is quite nice example of a very strong constraining effect of in this case
the spatial symmetry on on the actual structure of the network structure
the other thing you can say is that the decrease distribution of the scale free
if the moments of the random variable fail to exist for some
essentially the government
the game itself follows some kind of power law
the meaning that in fact if you had this fully symmetric space and uniform distribution
you cannot have scale free networks will not be scale free
now it all says that it's not too hard to into kind of an engineer
scale free networks by appropriate choice of
no distribution x as in that had one model which we saw earlier that's precisely
what they do
this artificial pos people come to that
interesting statistics is a statistic is the variance of that
one of the big and which may not exist in a particular may not exist
in the in the scale free case
it measures if you like the departure from the kind of course on this of
the degree structure
statistics clustering coefficient and degree correlations and so on
as i say in principle
computable cult calculator all that you can express terms kind of higher
higher moments if you like so long so this these variants of connectivity
technically difficult to calculate because you end up with this on riemannian manifold you end
up with some very nasty integral
how do we calculate things like component sizes phase transitions and so on well there's
a problem with using the generating function formalism which is how you might want to
do it because
that's very powerful technique unfortunately this model does violate
some of the assumptions of the model which is that the degree distributions at individual
nodes on not identically distributed not independent what you can do is you can you
can come up with some kind of if you like statistical mechanics is called the
mean field approximation which is actually to ignore the fluctuations correlations of node degree
five model
i try this it doesn't work too well as you might expect is that there
is a lot of variance autocorrelation amongst the degrees with a very
the simple bunched up
spatial distributions for instance
in the mean field approximation you actually find small world scale again that may not
is it is only an approximation
this shouldn't be too surprising as i say in fact the original inclination was to
call this model the small world spatially embedded model i decided not to go on
the grounds that
this in fact may not and what you may not be the the case that
you can fly apply kind of exact version of the generating function for the formalism
by telling it to you have to do is go through several stages of of
of averaging of conditioning first on the given node placement so the technical
and that's difficult in fact probably intractable
it's about this a bit better than that
possibly can be done so we could be looking at and practices
sometimes perturbation of the mean field approximation which again is one statistical
physicists would be inclined to
i'm not of statistical physicists to get some sleep problems for anyway
so now another side effects point is we saw in the i israeli model it's
quite it's quite clear how you're going to scale the connection probability has you
network increases in size
not clear how to do it for this model because your connection probability is is
that hold k functions now
so how you actually going to scale so well
the shape of the like is significant so you might want to scale like this
is my camera this to is how
connection probability tales of distance
now i can just kind of squash that i
or perhaps
this way perhaps to squash the whole thing down
this corresponds more to kind of just read time just simply scaled
uniformly scale whole probability across the entire distance this one corresponds more to if you
have the truncation
can squashing up truncation
i would make the distances which connections happens more and more that those things turn
out to be
to make a rather crucial difference to the statistical properties of the network so
it's again it's not clear how one should do that necessarily
so here's some pictures them anyway
what might look like this is this is a uniform this the space is uniform
discontinued dimensions the k
his thresholds so basically
nodes are connected if less than a certain distance is probably something like that
so like these are not connected to too far apart
let's continue to look like
the you can spatial distribution of nodes kind of radially exponential
so now it's much more likely to appear near the origin
and and also the connection probability drops off exponentially with distance to get very dense
conductivity structure close to the origin
and it gets much more sparsity move away from the origin
it will
and here is
he was
you mean
let me
you i it
can anyone
and in began
know we
so get
given that
i mean
thank you
on the limits of zeros for the
for the point in the family
all right so how does this apply to our case OK so far this polynomial
family identify
with i kept by the set of all polynomials that appear here that are nonzero
and we will denote by m
the cardinal of this matrix
this will be the minimum recurrence degree you can prove that
OK then the linear recurrence
it can be written like that and we can actually compute
what these polynomials are
and we note that the recurrence
doesn't depend at all on
on the actual
the values of the actual court polynomials that appear here only on the set of
those that are zero
now the characteristic equation
can be the like that but for these fjz problem here
the characteristic equation looks exactly
like here so x
appears to all the power that having this is in i
and these are all the routes OK these are the london
OK and to compare the absolute values of the land as this just to comparing
it is easy to some power different parts OK and we see here why the
the unit circle is so important so if you have
routes that are equally model that means
that c has to belong to the unit circle
if one of them is dominating the others
then that has to that xe has to be outside
and of course that will be
x to the largest element in i which is exactly
if there are
limits of zeros outside the unit circle they can only be roots of this polynomial
and again if there are millions of zero inside only the roots of the sport
all right so this character is completely characterizes completely the
the limits of zero and therefore
the spectrum of the
polynomial transform that we are designed so we are free to choose
these AK polynomials anyway we like
we only need to be careful that the roots of the first and the last
in the first
and we done a week we get a polynomial transform
that approximates the escape africa
so just show you some examples of how does this
how do these routes
approximate the unit circle
OK so here is the classic example that i've had throughout the talk
xn minus one we see the periodic boundary conditions
for n equal twenty
well sample units are going to call of places the
influence of unity
for and equal fifty the units finally grew eighty
again you could almost see that
this article is completely covered almost
OK for
another polynomial
this one here
routes that
i have
the same
experiments that have the same argument and they look like that
and as you increase
the degree
they get closer and closer
to each other
and of course they will sample
they will get two
sample the
orientation space
finer and finer
OK so it fits
our goal
OK some more interesting examples
for instance a polynomial here that
he has
the freedom
and so
how would we use this in the natural system
well i kind of like in stevens analysis by synthesis models
well basically lattice rescoring his so but
the problem here is is that this
model here we've got these multi dimensional articulatory
the models themselves will be obtained
as the cartesian product
of each articulator dimension and this results in enormous computational complexity during search
well so what do we do we we sort of punt actually decoding and this
to me
punters in we
we we kick the ball in
something else
well we can do though
we can start with our our our
our article acoustic features we could generate some hypothesized phonetic transcriptions from our generic off-the-shelf
is our system
and so
we will assume that we've got these hypothesized transcriptions here from some generic off-the-shelf system
articulatory model then
we ask that to generate these hypothesized acoustics
for each different hypothesise phone segmentation will generate different set of hypothesized acoustics
acoustic sequence
and they will choose the best phonetictranscription
as that which gives us that which is most plausible according to
i take the tree model
here in the acoustic space
i would like to
defined some kind of distance between are
will call these are target acoustic features and the hypothesis ones and will pick the
sequence as that which is somehow generates the acoustics is closest to the original
and we've
seen as i mentioned before we see in the number of different efforts to that
the bark is himself to model these these dynamics
the design some basically this empirically designs and fire filters
john riedl
so looked at using
deterministic a deterministic hidden dynamic model
explored this vocal tract resonance dynamics both of these are these last two are something
like common filters and you like like you would expect some
something that
describe the dynamics here of
given that we've we've made some assumptions about the form of our model we can
describe its dynamics in terms of something like a call cells are
the the acoustic articulatory to acoustic mapping
has generally been in the form of some sort of a of a static mapping
radial basis function
classifiers multilayer perceptron
most of the evaluations of these have been mostly sort of anecdotal utterances and so
you have your say we're live on these handful of utterances i'm seeing reasonable acoustics
they really are my hypotheses and reasonable way but they not these have not
we've we've got plenty of time right
it's fact
it's OK if you're approaching the table there are thirty
to be the next the second speaker who
four so
right so again this is another technique that but this is the holy grail if
you could come up with a
an accurate and robust model like this you could use it for so much
and you could use it for sentences you could use it for recognition and and
it's not quite there
but it's a but it's quite a fascinating research topic you can find
people were when i was about lads we had people who are doing collaborative projects
with the group at general dynamics to try and actually use their their wind tunnels
you might come up with full
completes articulatory dynamic models which incorporated the airflow and everything else
and it's those kinds of people that are
taking on the tough problems like this
finally the so
to conclude our time our sort of second thing here and how our exploiting speech
of the individual weight vectors if you want to think about it in these terms
because it's all stick together
and you add a term for the slack variables OK there should be actually see
year like usual you can you can wait this differently
and the margin constraint the way you would be funded knows he would just say
OK i want to minimize that with regard to w excited such that the margin
that obtain on a particular example is at least one or whatever
i've chosen the slack variables to be lower the modern it right so in the
in the
the separable case right where you wouldn't have a soft margin this would go away
here and then this would go away you would actually require the gamma i has
to be great equal to one as one of the constraints and then in the
soft margin case you expect variables that need to be nonnegative and you have a
penalty term here
so this is not a this is not a quadratic programme
and that becomes important
not so much for multiclass problem but it will become much more important when we
talk about structured classification structured prediction is that if we look at this now here
right this constraint is actually
constraint that involves a maximum right because we had defined the constrained in the way
that we said on this score of the correct class and what is the score
of the second best sorry the
the one that gets the highest score among the incorrect one
right and so we had this maximum but we can basically expand this right so
this one constraint
because basically as we've already seen if we get the
you get a certain margin
right separation margin between the correct one and the
best incorrect one then clearly we get at least as much and also for the
other incorrect ones right because by definition right they are not the ones among the
incorrect one that get the highest score so basically we can just expand it follows
that the difference between that we simply require that the difference between the score we
are getting for correct class and what we were getting for any y that is
different from the correct class that that difference in score needs to be at least
one or one minus something that we subtract using this library books i can
so is this equivalence is that you
so if we you know basically if we go to this picture here
right just basically means that now we saying OK we want the difference in score
between these two to be greater equal one and these two in these two
and these two right and we have many more than we get any more
the creation so the thing is that here
you know we just have one equation that's not nonlinear because it involves the max
we can just
and rolled this maximum and then we get lots of linear constraints namely we get
as many constraints as we have classes basically minus one and then we get this
constraint here so the total number of constraints
that we would be getting in our in our pocket drastic program in the end
would be and the number of samples that we have times the cardinality of the
OK so
if we have a relatively small number of classes then
we might be able to handle this if it
the cardinality of wire several ten thousand or so as you know could be in
in the problem with large taxonomy then already this becomes a bit nasty to deal
so now
i'd like to
move from multiclass classification two
really the core of this talk which is too strong to do structured prediction and
the reason why i talked about multiclass classification in the first place is as i
said before that it can be you can think of as an evil way of
you can decide to one dish ten days of two thousand images something
you really picks them up
and subsequent customer
subsequent customer that comes in the customer i
we will have two things to do
among the dishes that previous customers has tried
so let's say dish k customer i will try dish k with probability and k
divided by i where mk is the number of previous customers that have tried dish
so at this stage is very popular has been tried by lots of different customers
in the past the next customer will will
we want to try the dish as well as the popular dish
and in addition to that
the customer will also try
cross on alfalfa i shows that no other customers have tried
so in this case customer one decides to try six dishes
and out of the six dishes customer two
i will try each of this fish with probability one over
because is one and i is two
right so
with probability half the second customer we try each of the six dishes
and then this customer we also try a so the number of dishes that customer
one has tried before
so in this case because the two decided to try treat issues the customer one
did not try
and similarly customer tree
comes i will try each dish with probability
so we tried dish
we tried this tree with probability one over tree
we tried dish full with probability to the tree
and this goes on to fish like
and if a customer will also try
at a number of dishes that previous customers did not like before
and this can repeats itself
and we can
in fact derive this from this model where k goes to infinity and you can
kind of see this because
let's look at the first customer right the first customer we try each
the che
with probability
me OK but if we integrate me OK this probability is going to work out
to be alfalfa k
the book divided by one plus of of wiki
so this is this to privatise normalized
and that's basically going to be more or less equal to alpha over k
if k is very large
the customer will try each of this vicious independently so this is kind of input
and independence
a set of independent the new lease each with probability that approaches zero and you
can can work out that
the number of the new release
goes to infinity this the number of that picked by the customer is this can
be passed on distributed and the parameter was set to be puzzle
for some of alpha
anyway so it's kind of the exercise two to
to derive distinct from the previous page
know small all forms
this thing actually has
except for this of
representation it doesn't really have a close connection to dirichlet process it does have some
connections to the judicial process as we'll will see later but it doesn't have that
much of a connection
so it turns out that the IBP as described here is also infinitely exchangeable and
we can now see that it has to be infinitely exchangeable because this finite model
is infinitely exchangeable right we're treating each customer
independence given our
parameters mu
we can permute the customers around and it actually doesn't affect the probability
you can also show that this process is also affiliation but the tricky bit here
is that we cannot have to forget about the ordering of the
like if you look at this one it will always be tried by customer one
well unless customer one decided not to try any additional
do which is to use what's called a log linear model
in the new models that represent the probability of the state as a product of
potential functions we represent as an exponentiated so
and of terms which after all they can always convert from one to the other
so we still have the normalisation constant now we have have the exponentially some of
is a sign of a set of features times the weights
now in one extreme i can just have one feature for each state as each
clique and so i can we implement any potential function model in this way
the nice thing though is that
i could have
many fewer features than there are states of the potential functions
if i have a very large fleet with a huge number of states but i
know that there's only ten important features
then i can just represent those and their weights
so my model stay compact even
if the potential function with be very large and we're going to take full advantage
of this
for example the potential function that we saw before
could be represented simply by one feature
of the smoking cancer which is one if you don't have cancer and zero otherwise
and if you give one point five weights to that teacher you get exact potential
function that we saw
so there's famous mysterious in markov networks called the hammersley clifford theorem
which is the following
suppose we have a distribution
there is always nonnegative so there's always strictly positive
and graph encodes conditional independences
in your in your domain then
the distribution is a product the potentials of the cliques of the graph
so is that i i told me two things here may know a proof that
they were equivalent it turns out that they are equivalent the conditional independencies and the
potential for functions as long as every state has non-zero probability and the inverse of
this is also true
it's as its successful also a lot easier to prove
and you can think of this theorem in in in short form as a markov
network is the same as it gives distribution
it gives distribution is is this thing that i just showed here
young statisticians call it along models physicists call it gives distribution and what the hammersley
clifford theorem and even say is the the markov network meaning the graph with the
conditional independencies i described in the gibbs distribution are in the in effect the same
OK so we know we can we can use one or the other as as
appropriate and that's we're taking advantage
so how the markov networks compared to bayesian networks
they both have the same for both in the form of products potential so that
they are very similar
the big difference is that in markov networks the potentials are arbitrary functions
the bayes nets the potentials are forced to be only conditional probabilities of some variables
given this
so in this way markov networks are better than bayes nets because the more flexible
also in bayes nets
we allow cycles
whereas in india is not so can tell cycles a cycle in in in the
a directed graph does not correspond to any distribution and this lexical is gonna come
in very handy when you try to model relational domains
to offset these two advantages of markov networks the disadvantage that that they have is
that the partition function z the normalising constant can be very hard to compute whereas
in bayes networks is completely trivial to compute is just one
in fact if you say
i'm going to have a lot linear model the partition function is one where you
end up with necessarily going to be a bayesian network OK so those are the
pros and cons
here are some more interesting differences how the czech independence in markov networks just grab
in bayes nets the separation so much more complicated criteria
you know i was the graph basically you know says what it seems to be
saying was in bayesian networks the graph is actually somewhat misleading tonight is the lack
of medicine business are incomparable in the sense that each one of them can represent
the graph can represent some independence properties that the other one count
so some things are called markov network with a lot of competition network and vice
however the most important thing to remember is that the mathematical form of log linear
models be contacted either case
so if we can represent as a log linear things you know anything that's compact
bayesian networks is a compact linear model and anything that compact markov network is a
compact linear models
and now
lastly how do you do inference well we're going to look more that shortly followed
governments this things like markov chain monte carlo belief propagation and others for bees and
so i want
this property
to be true and i want to be in this set
and this corresponds to
the fat
the time could talking about so why
will represent the best
the good one
so what i want is that if i mean this that one needs be true
and i also want
let me
i try to explain so
i have way
to be really here
so actually this is not the type
this is
the nodes
along this path
with the whole
OK and as i have infinitely often b
this why is set which is infinitely long
so while represents the set
of nodes along this path
will be holds
so and so
the now
and i mean is that i mean i mean the sets of those nodes along
this very person talking about the one supposed to
so i'm along this path them on on the position along this path will be
i'm still in the past but
i mean i know where i promise you that in the future
i would which
some position would be whole
i will be in way
let me show you
this time formula
so here what have
if i forget this one
so how would you first compute this one you have to do iterations
two things have one which says me OK i take a set of nodes
and the associated to it
this thing here
this the definition
i want to compute the greatest fix point of this one
so how have to iterate
from the entire set
however this descending change
but it's time i have to compute so i start with these are zero one
so star
i have to compute this so let me give the name to this thing here
that we call f of a
so i have to compute f of
but what is the f of ten
if n is at least fixpoint of somebody
f of
to compute this one has to iterate for
the empty set
and now to compute
this thing here
which is
of n
and said
and set
and so on
so this set
will be
so the set of nodes so the this is the empty set so you replace
by the end to set
and and
and and y is replaced it is replaced by y
well it's always replaced by and so it means that
the empty set so either i mean the empty set
unable so sorry
i don't have the success of which is in the empty set
or have a successor which is
label baby
this is the thing
i keep iterating to get the least fixpoint
so first of all what do a catch on the first set
i catch
note that the labelled data
the second step of the
computation of this looks six point
i have a success
was able b
the success
was labelled by b
on the scene and
what i have
is that basically in one step
this convergence
and i have
computation of this f of n which is the set of nodes
we're not the full than today right
after iterations here sorry should have told me that this and is my iteration of
my greatest fixpoint here
this and is
zero and stuff
here i see that my but still because it's getting very difficult to understand OK
so i will not do it on the board what you need to do is
that i have
greatest fixpoint to compute
and it's time
so my greatest fixpoint is computed on the basis of some iterations
at each iteration
the meaning of this great the meaning of my function
is itself
so the way to compute this one
the computation of least fixpoint
so you would put it on your
on your paper here with the
you penn and you will remain quietly
what was done
for just one
fixpoint operator
but what you have to do is that for each iteration of the greatest fix
point you have to iterate
but this fix point until civilization when the stabilisers you you you have achieved the
computation of this
the right hand side and since there epsilon and over two of the probability is
to the minimize epsilon two that's basically
but now we're really the case so this is the kind of thing we like
an exponential decay in probability
with the sample size
OK this is looking
pretty good and so now what we can do is set this equal to
delta over two BH two and
which was
come from we're now back to putting the whole thing together effectively
that to be achieved two and is here
what we want to do is to make this less than delta
so going to make this quantity less than delta divided by two h
then we can invert
to give a bound on epsilon
if you
i want to spend just
two minutes trying to do that so just said this is equal to that and
where we know what is the age of two enemies from sours lemma
just got that down
OK that sounds like
this cells
so h and is less than or equal to this quantity
these dimension d
so you can plug that in
in place of this
i said that equal to
that and solve for
and so on
this could be too
well it's the expectation of the other probability so that's why you say anything
is that it's the thing i'm not sure is the right
i mean that was
i mean that's essentially this
this thing here right OK
i mean
yes because i mean this is just another way of writing this essentially it's not
as a means to notation is just saying
what we're doing is working at the probability
i mean it's the expectation of
here here
can you
i don't see i do
so the question was can you go directly from here to
two here right was
or rather
from here to here
useful technique which allows you to simultaneously diagonalizable matrix a
and you here's an orthogonal matrix x
is this just a set of vectors
which has some special properties
and then c is again diagonalized the ratio alpha to gamma those are what's called
the generalized singular values they come up in lots of different applications and that's what
i've done here is shown the manipulations
that the as new goes to infinity then you get convergence so it's really a
nice way of the
approaching this problem if you have one piece of software for solving least squares problem
then you can
convert to a problem where you have constrained by just adding in these constraints in
the simple way
but the techniques and we just mentioned this is the final method
and i like this approach
because it reduces the dimensionality of the problem
so here again we have minimize say x and we have linear constraint and now
we have what we do with QR factorizations of the matrix c member c transpose
is that
a lot
matrix or i mean rectangular matrix with more roles and more columns and rows if
you do now the QR factorizations aunts
you get an upper triangular matrix p by p
from from the
we transform a
the same killer was applied to a so we have a one and a two
and we transform x by the same transformation q only this time from the left
and lo and behold well will do this
transformation being minus a one y
mine is a to see what we've done is just
stuck in q transposing killing two in between a and x
alright minimizes so that are transpose y equals zero
in other words we have
b-minus a to z equals the minimum
and then you can use any method you want to sign this least squares problem
and here this gives the solution to the
constrained least squares problem
if you can and if the data structures from that there is a good idea
to eliminate the constraints that makes the problem better conditions
you can prove easily in this matrix a two
it is at least as well conditioned as the original problem and often
the original problem may be singular imposing the constraints may be make it non singular
so if you can use the constraints it's a good idea
now what about quadratic constraints
and that comes up very often
there lots of different applications
i mean does anybody hear ever see that kind of problem i know you see
regularisation problems
has anybody seen quadratic constraints OK thank so here's the quadratic constraint again we use
the grounds multipliers
and you see
you get the system
which statisticians sometimes called ridge regression this problem here only now
the mu is determined from this constraint on the length of the solution the length
of the solution must be equal to the square
if you substitute in what x is equal into this equation to here you get
what i call the secular equation
so it's a new is this unknown quantity here
it's actually the hardest part of this holy squares problem is finding new correctly
you don't need to know muta fifteen significant places was and south square
could be
one point one or one point o one or o point nine six
he really as we say in america
we just want a ballpark estimate of mu
if you use that expression at all ballpark breast cancer ballpark estimate that we need
so but this was not always in these equations
the south
if you use the singular value decomposition then you can die analyse your matrix a
and you have this equation to some
there are at least two there are two n
possible solutions to this but there's a particular one that we need to solve for
and then once you sign up for the new year on the way
another idea is the following
you have this problem here
i'm just rewriting this as a new matrix problem and if you eliminate
you know
you get the equation i wrote about
but if you eliminate c
you get this equation here
so this equation this is the square of the matrix
a transfer is a plus mu i square
minus one over alpha square and the matrix of rank one
and what you need to do is find a particular value of this quadratic i
value problems so
the lagrange multiplier is equivalent
to solving a certain quadratic i can be a problem if you can solve the
quadratic i can be a problem then you have the lagrange multiplier and then you
can sort of once you have a large multiply that is easy enough to to
solve for the solution
so the parameter mu is generally positive but not always
so this is something that's been of interest to me
and let me just mention how this can be done
so we need to solve this equation here
and earlier using the singular value decomposition
i wrote that in this fashion here
that is after i diagonalizes a and of course if you have a some
of non negative quantities you can think of this as the still choose integral
so computing f of mu
this matrix equation here
which is really a quadratic equation quadratic form is equivalent to computing integrals
can we don't know what this distribution function is because that depends upon the singular
vectors of a
for a
any time you see a quadratic forms think in terms of an integral
so this integral may be officially bounded by applying what is called the land shows
and then there's
the gauss rather quadrature rule i won't go into all the details but the interesting
thing is you can
making approximation to this integral by using was called ln shows scheme and it has
a certain side benefit not only do you get a good estimate of this parameter
but in the use of the land shows algorithm you construct and not vectors
so that you can actually that approximate the solution so like getting a free lunch
you get not only the regularisation parameter out of the whole process but you also
get an approximation to the solution and there is an algorithm that's very effective for
solving sparse least squares problems
it's based in part on this line shows the algorithm
and it it was it's called LSQR
so method devised by
chris page and mike saunders is freely available so if you have sparse least squares