very high he likely
back means i'm saying it's hard w time will be low and saying i'm saying
yes if you can think that's a great i like that line right so your
prior in some sense only a distribution over these models some reflects
the regularizer and you can actually make these very very precise and several of us
have done this analysis and in terms of trying
the results and then eventually guarantees and future performance by doing this kind of analysis
so so this is the important message and u may not be
using labs so you may be using is vehemently we'll be using something else make
sure your model is regularized don't only look at your training set performance right
and in the morning breakaway people often do cross validation and that's a reasonable approach
to do this or bootstrap and things so that's sort
those are all trying to capture this thing i'm not going to trust my performance
on the training set entirely right so because i may be doing hundred percent accuracy
on the phoenix
so this is a very important sort of thing to remember as you're building models
which are eventually going to be deployed and they're going be running on real data
i have not yet touched on nonlinear models
that that nonlinear models in machine learning is that one the popular
peaks is is what is called the kernel trick it's not a trick it's a very nice mathematical
essentially what it does is that it if if this is your classification problem right
so so this is one of the other class
there is just no way you can come up with a straight line which separates the two point two classes
if you actually map to a higher dimensions which depends on x one square next to square
right some some some second order polynomial six months when x quite x one x
then in the higher dimensional space they become very separate
right so they become they become perfectly separated so that's essentially the essence of the
kernel trick is that even tho
this is going to be nonlinear you're going to need a non-linear separating the low dimensional space
if you actually take it to hire him and we are not talking dimension reduction
using if you take it to a high dimensional space
a linear separator would work
so so these are what we call the corners which you know
they are product in high dimensional spaces the coronal
and there is a very nice
sort of unity behind this is in the prison garnered but spaces so if you
if you like mathematics you're going to like the construction that goes on the theory
that goes behind these constructions in practice they walk
one of the big success areas but these have been employed in computational biology
there are extensively used and people have developed all kinds of corners far for comparing
similarities between two extremely complicated things
in this is something you already know data itself is a vector in two dimensions
right when i'm talking about something like computational biology
you know you're talking about combining to proteins or something of that sort i'm not
which but they they are not finite dimensional vectors right they have
something very complicated
maybe it's a tree maybe maybe it's a graph may has a three-tier structure to
it and as long as you can define a common among two things
this this trick can be pulled up
you're you're pushing it a hilbert space marine products can be computed and new should
be able to pull this off
this literature is very stable there been books written on this you know you can
just go anywhere and look for books on kernel methods in machine learning
kernelized classification regression dimension reduction has been used
how learn the kernel for a given domain might current learning and commissioned called extensively
developed and it's still actively started but this is a very much urea
this is one way to capture nonlinearity and this is
there are other problems some of district doesn't work and we started looking at some climate data where the nonlinearities
and we're still not sure where they will be able to pull off this idea in the context
so so the last several mainstream
team i'm going to talk about the notion of ensembles
so what ensembles do
is bad
they actually do market
from the raw data
maybe by slightly modifying the auditory strike
it may be picking some features may be waiting that are doing some little modification
on the data that you have
and then you are cooking up a whole bunch of classifiers like that's and in
the end you come up with a way to listen to all of those classifiers
have their opinion on the new data point
you're listening to all of them with a suitable weighted combination of consensus function right hand
and this is actually one of the
so so what people have shown
in terms of the theory
it is about
we talked about regularization right if you are building like five hundred such classifiers maybe
cooking on one extremely complicated classifier
so if you've been one decision tree instead if you are building temples decision trees
online alleviated versions of the same dataset you may think of the fact that are
w regression don't really go through the rules
the theory that was developed in this to quite some time to understand why doing so well empirically
is that this combination actually uses
the loss
but it does not increase the complexity in a very precise sense
right so
so it is okay if you'd been what
jim decision trees on minority weighted versions of the data
and then i have all of them vote and do a weighted combination success stories
to some extent and boosting and random forests which which have been extremely widely used
and i i think you know we we may actually has some speakers maybe tomorrow
day after talking about some of these ensemble methods are used in google
and they can be scaled up to that level in order to do this and
they walk phenomenally well right so
and so initially for a small dataset they may look completely crazy man this is your
randomly building some decision trees and combine their outputs
if you're really working with large scale data these things start walking phenomenally well and
we have some level of theoretical understanding of why that happens
again you know these are things you will probably find in standard statistical software like we got another pieces
and then they they have different ways of combining these got creating as well as
coal mining these classifiers but these are methods that we like they are stable we
understand when they walk in the don't work
okay so i'm going to wrap up this section
by getting into an area that's that's several of us have gotten into and we are realizing
that we don't have methods
so far
high dimensional problems what we mean by that
yeah this district is it minus
x some land
abide by their
z is in the
my sex
on lambda
and you can do the integral
it's not hard
that is lambda
in nineteen on land
minus minus you
and lambda
i really want to emphasise how easy and straightforward and simple this is
it's just a few lines of computer code because all we need now put into your computer
is this statement here which defines
x given lambda
it depends on z
and then you put in this one which defines how that depends on lambda
and now you've done it just makes that says
you can infer lambda
by just multiplying together
all these things here so you have
hole-in-one z s and of them
hand loaded minus signs
z is a function of lambda
the country
and this here is a function of lambda
it depends on x so it is lambda dependence his land in here
and just multiplying together
and that's there is your all likelihood as we are always
the lambda
you either by whatever about lambda beforehand
andy normalize
and this is we uninteresting normalizing constant you don't care about if we want to do is
compare alternative theories about lambda
so let's look at the meeting this the data-dependent bit
and this is where it you first time you see this it
i find it just thrilling to
observe what just automatically happens
if you take this function
um stick with the lines
here's the code units right down
written it in
the report which is a language that you can use to define functions
and portland
well defined function peopple ex ante el which is
this function here x and lambda lambda as turned out on both
so the top line defined
the second line defined z
i've defined z slightly different output one over all into the pier
but it's it's equivalent
we define eight we define be
and then
we can plot these as a function of x which is the normal way of plotting these things so you
six lambda
any plot
yeah that's given lambda
as a function of x and it looks like and that's all very normal
so that's what it looks like a three different values of lambda
and if you have a very small value of lambda is
or constraint on left
big value lambda
you more uniform distribution
and everyone these probability densities over x integrates to one
and it's all very normal and this is one
and the area under
the green curve
also one
that's all very standard and very simple and just exponential
and then based theorem says okay now you want to know lambda given x will
just what the same function but look at it
as a function of lambda
so take these innocent exponential functions and look the other way around
andy this is what they look like so this is
the probability of x
sorry is not
this is a
andy i obviously do this we need to fix x to a particular value so
i'm showing these three different outcomes for three different possible axis x could be for
example three
could be five three twelve
and this is what effective lambda looks like for three the light blue curve
five it's the blue one
and for twelve it's the purple one
and the amazing thing is just one of those functions
take one
if we fix x three and then plot events given lambda as a function of lambda
i'm showing lambda on the horizontal axis here
and i put on a log scale
it's got a peak
so a single data point
is not giving you this nice peaky function and saying
just one data point that happened to arrive at
x equals three
one data point now tells you
tells use and opinions you will have a different values of lambda
extremely small values of lambda close to zero
are essentially ruled out by
values are laminated to also
are perfectly happy they did a good job of predicting
and larger values
of slightly rule them but not very much just slightly penalized compared to
is to also
so just one data point
i can tell you something about what language should be
and as you piling more and more data points
you multiply these functions by
the special case the data points out beyond the midpoint
gives you the purple line here
which is saying okay we can definitely rule out tiny values of lambda there's no
way land that could be point one o point three or something like that
you get a point at a twelve that's crazy so that's ruled out
but all values of lambda
from ten twenty thirty hundred they are all equally probable
rather they predicted this data point equally well
because they all predate essentially uniform distributions so they're all
equally unsurprised by seeing a value at twelve
okay so we multiply these together
and when you multiply those functions together
i have multiplied the functions imagining that there are just three data points at three
OK morning
the loss of you guys think
they're coming
so far you refer
a bunch of matter solving a bunch of problems which are sort of
now in the area of reinforcement learning
and you start to wonder maybe or hopefully i mean how all these things together
i mean this is just one of these
thousands and more and more methods
applied to
problems where you
you have to learn from data or something or some underlying principle underlying principles
a few
rules or
we sort of hold everything together
and in the next three hours
i will present the
statistical and computational foundations of machine learning
unfortunately i mean three houses
not too much
i cannot really flesh out all the connections to all the other talks you've heard
but i mean you will
see here and there where the connections are
especially the job talk in reinforcement learning
we defer last week
OK so one slide sort of one slide summary of my three hours today
at the end of the target the same slide and you know then you can
put it sort of in context
the that of the economy
like maybe we can
can you see that OK or
i would consider
sequential data
so that means essentially non IID data is the sequence of state data for instance
i mean
because metadata or stock market data or or other time series x one x two
x three optics and
and you want to predict xn plus one
most of the talk later come to the agent framework and reinforcement learning and
of course this general setup
includes idea of a special case
and actually even predicting
i think i mentioned already you could ask me why should we care about prediction
the ultimate goal is to do something with these predictions and to maximise your profits
if you're capitalist or
model to capture maximize utility function or
minimize loss if you
takenaka picture but that's just a minus sign
OK so
nearly all approaches what you do it
you start with the class of models or hypothesis
regulator could come from
then you can try to find
ideally the true hypothesis of the true hypothesis about
it's hard to tell what the true the ground truth is
let's talk about good hypothesis whatever good means in detail
and one classical estimators the maximum likelihood estimator so
you have
the local point of
take this likelihood function
this is sort of defining what the hypothesis mean what this age i mean for
this hypothesis and the policies that you a probability distribution over
o we we're sample space
so in the maximum likelihood estimator just take the hypothesis which has a maximum likelihood
the argument is
it's like very low
then it's very exceptional that all this data but this all this data so it
should not be too exceptional
and if the likelihood is high
you can expect the state and they happen so
it sort of seems to come from the hypothesis and over the arguments and in
any case i would not consider the maximum likelihood
and further
because it has some problems if the class is too large
it leads to overfitting
so in the bayesian approach what you do is you consider the first year which
is a much cleaner interpretations of what you want
one the probability
the degree of belief in a hypothesis after seeing the data
and luckily you can compute it from the likelihood
times prior
so what we additionally and now is the prior
the question is whether this prior come from and there are several principles but this
actually only one principal with general enough to cover really i mean
all of machine learning
and it is actually occam's razor they combined with the core principle
so what you should do it we should have a high prior for simple models
and i will quantify that
so you quantify simplicity of complexity with kolmogorov complexity
or solomonoff induction scheme
and then you have everything you need
the orient to wikileaks
in very general generic
i tell you
that all these works
if you true hypothesis when your data is sampled from is in the model class
very rough statement about
now it's sort of like that
so this is cover the prediction case and
i developed
actually element of that but i mean showing here a universal way of doing prediction
in any kind of domain
and the last step is to
to generalise the to the reinforcement learning setup
big decisions influenced by environment
so the generally accepted
OK so that was
for instance if m is the class of or polynomial
all degrees
and then you have a few data points
and then the best fitting polynomials of the maximum likelihood polynomial i mean if you
gaussian noise and then
maximum likelihood is just minimising
this screen
and then you get a polynomial perfectly fits the data
which isn't
is what
i contains everything site contains sort of all degree one polynomials of degree two polynomial
according to of three fully answers the union
for instance
so i think again this definition already
learn some stuff tried it out learn some more stuff tried it out and it built up
there is an enormous literature and education that says that's exactly how we always learn everything
and so that's the way this courses focus what we'll do is just for example
for today will learn a little bit about software engineering
then we'll do to lab sessions where you actually try to use the things that we talk about
then we'll come back to like have some more theory
about how you would do programming
and then you go back to do more stuff
and the hope is that by
by this tangible context
you have a deeper appreciation and the ideas that we're trying to convey
let me tell you a little bit about the four modules that we've chosen
the course is gonna be organised on four modules
each module will take about one-fourth of the course first thing look at software engineering
as i said we don't have time to focus on or even survei
the big idea all the big ideas in software engineering is far too big
so really focused narrowly on water two things
we'd like you to know
about abstraction and modularity
because that's such an important idea
in the construction of big systems
so that's gonna be our focus will begin in today's lecture
will begin talking about
i modularity and abstraction
at a small scale
how's it affect the things you type
has instructions to a computer
but by next week we're going be talking about whole bigger scale
by next week we're gonna talk about
constructing software modules
at a much higher level in particular will talk about something that will cost state machine
a state machine is of saying
networks in steps
on every step
the state machine get a new input
then based on any input and it's memory of what's come before r the state
machine decides to do something that generates an output
and then the process repeats
we will see that that's kind an abstraction state machines
has there's a way to think about state machines there is compositional
but you can
i think of it as
just as you can think of
low level hierarchies within a language also a lot more about that today
so the idea would be that once you've composed a state machine
you'll be able to join to state machines and have behavior look just like one state machine
that's a way to get a more complicated behavior
by constructing to simply behaviors that's what we want we wanna learn tools that lets
us compose complex behaviors out of simple behaviors and the tangible model will be the
we will see how to write a program that controls a robot
a state machine
that's certainly not the only way you can control the robot
and it's probably not the way you would first think of it if u
it took one course in programming and somebody said u go program the robot to do something
what we will see is that it's a very powerful way to think about it
for exactly this reason have modularity
the bigger point that we will make in thinking about this first module is the idea
how do you make systems modular r how do you use abstraction simplified the design task and in particular
we will focus on something that will call peak at
when you think about a system we will always think about in terms of what are the primitives
how do you combine them
how do you abstract
other bigger behavior
from those smaller behaviors
and what are the patterns that are important to capture
so the bigger point is this idea of peak at which we will then revisit it every subsequent model
okay second modules on signals and systems
that's also an enormous area
so we only have time to do one thing the thing that we will do is
we will think about discrete time
how do you make a system that's cognizant
and what is done
so that's in the future can do things with awareness
i've how it got there
a good example is robotics hearing
so the idea is going to be
okay i think about what you do when you're driving a car
and think about how you would tell a robot to do exact same thing
here's a naive driving algorithm
i don't recommend it but is widely used in boston apparently
i find myself to the right where i would like to be
so what should i do
turn left
i'm still to the right where like to be what should i do
o i'm exactly right should be
what should i do
go straight ahead
that's a bad idea
and what see is that perfectly innocent looking algorithms can have whole renders performance
what will do
is try to make abstraction about will try to make a model
will try to capture batman map so that we don't need to build the to see the bad behavior
will make a model
we use the model to predict the bad algorithms stinks
but more importantly we use the model
the figure out algorithm that work better
in fact will even be able to come up with balance
on how well
such a controller could possibly work
so the focus in this model is going to be
how do you make a model to predict behavior how do you analyse the model
so that you can design a better system
and then how do you use the modeling analysis to
stood to make it i am well behave system
the third modules on circuits
again circus is huge
we don't have time to talk about all circuits will do very simple things
we will focus our attention
on how you would add sensory capability
to an already complicated system
the idea is going to be start with the robot is is brighter start with our robots
and design eight head
for the robot
the robot comes from the factory
with sonar sensors that are sensitive these things that eight of them
they tell you how far away
something that reflects the e ultrasonic wave
actually come from the factory robots can sense light
what you do is add light sensors
the goal
is to make a system
the modify the robot so that the robot tracks light
the very simple ball
and we we do then
is to augment the robot with a simple sensor here showed a little more magnified here
the idea is
this is logo motor
it is rather different
in both cases
so practically
in the medical domain used to
you can values and false discovery rates to give to that
but practically trust models because the vision
however they give you a slightly different information
because the force is correct and he values his some idea about the fraction of
bad guys you have in your
selected features
whereas the classification results you more sense about how predictive your feature set is and
you may
include a large
fraction of garbage
features in your feature set and yet get very good predictive values for example if
if you use support vector machines on the packages
you may get
as good results with respect to the features set or even better results even though
you have tons of garbage features
in the challenges that i've organised have introduced purposely some garbage which is so i
knew for a fact that they were going to choose
and people have obtained you know
top ranking performances without performing any feature selection
you basically need both
aspects depending on what the emphasis is
all right if you care about
the features that you selected for example in medical applications you care about really understanding
which features are predicted
knowing that to get good prediction performance and preservation maybe not enough
in which case
you need to resort to computing for discovery
i have
the question
that's correct
scherzo a forward selection backward elimination methods do not yield the same type of features
that set at all
backward elimination you may end up with a set of complementary features and as you
removing features then you have to get softer degradation at some point at some point
will be only one feature such that you know all the remaining features on not
predictive together anymore
you don't see that in forward selection because the first feature selectors predictive but then
you run at risk of selecting first feature that is predicted by itself
but then you miss eventually power features the together would have been more
predictive than than that single feature the select first
enforce selection you tend to get very compact sets of subsets of features
and which may be an advantage or disadvantage
because someone redundancy helps to give give give better performance on the test set
there is no you know one method that should be recommended
depends on what you want to achieve
sometimes it's important that you will be able to trade number of features or accuracy
this is an advantage in that case to do forward selection because you can smoothly
move you're number of features without having this catastrophic degradation and sometimes you really want
to have an optimal
each subset of complementary features in which case back ruminations
maybe an advantage
so had joined but two other questions one of them was with this
you know
the laplacian i can maps
which is the spectral algorithm
and by special meaning can compute the i can decomposition at some point something
introduced by mister belkin partha niyogi
where you define the same neighborhood in the data space and then define the adjacency matrix where
he data development
it's only nonzero if i and j are neighbours
now the idea is that good
one dimensional embedding is one where the latent points
minimize this cost function
so this cost function is dependent on the latent points and basically if two points are neighbors
this applies
otherwise it doesn't so two points need to be close
if the neighbours
annotation been at distance in latent space so we'll just right now delta i j
so there is a slight problem with a cost function house is minimized
by putting all the data points on top of each other
it doesn't matter whether adjacent or not
what we do is we also have a constraint that they should be inflated and
that will come in in a moment but we can write this thing in matrix
form has this trace so i as i say i like writing things in matrix
o any land and i'm gonna do this trick again a bit somebody quick now
and maybe slower later if this time
that means that we can say that adjacency matrix multiplied by these distances
if we introduce something called the laplacian
we have a degree matrix and this degree matrix is the diagonal matrix
where the diagonal elements are the sum of the adjacency for the elements basically the
number of neighbors if these adjacencies a constant is the number of neighbors for each
data point
sometimes you can set these adjacencies constant but it's then just the sum of those weights
the laplacian is written in this form so
it's a defined thing for a graph that is the degree matrix minus the adjacency matrix
using the is this is the trick
which as i say i think i may have more details on later that allows
us to go from this squared distance is the same trick actually
as we've been using without centering matrix this is the squared distance matrix
and this is an inner product matrix
the reason you can pop between these two
is because
try and show
this matrix delta
is a distance matrix so it has zeros along the values on the diagonal yeah
all along the diagonal
taking the trace two matrices
the multiplied together is equivalent to
the matlab dot times old multiplication
followed by some some that's the way that don't ever multiply two matrices together and
then take the trace that's extremely slow
element-by-element multiply them and then some
both directions that's much much faster once cubic once quadratic
there is the distance matrix delta and that's being dot times by any which is this adjacency matrix
so it is a sparse so you've got this delta
times this past form which has solidified and let's call them once but it could be anything it's symmetric
everything's symmetric neighbour and zeros everywhere else
so are not terribly
okay so because the zeros down the diagonal it doesn't matter what the diagonal elevators
you can set angle they anyway you like
so what this is saying is set
with de-mining saying where d is a diagonal matrix
call at al
so if you know
it also has the characteristic because j is the sum of the rose
el times one is equal to zero it's got this null space
now that means that we multiply held by a distance matrix
what happens
this overrepresentation hair
we get these terms canceling
and you get just this x x transpose appearing so in rough sketch
that's a nice trick
it's also used in spring systems which will mention
a bit later
so turned what was the next uh
function in terms of a distance matrix into a function in terms of inner product matrix
and this thing
turns out to be
quite straightforward to minimize
the actually has this affect
making insensitive translations in this form
if you have this matrix here having a null space in the i can value one
then means that's it doesn't matter what x is
i mean is
it's it's insensitive to translations
that's minimized by placing all points on top of one another so what we do
is we add a constraint and this is the constraint they choose which is
that the inner product between each data point and the degree matrix is the
so that each state feature and the degree matrix should be one you could choose
a constraint where that's is just x kernel i transpose x can i is equal
to one without the dean they happened to this constraint
it is slightly annoying because it leads to a generalized eigen value problem rather than
a standard eigen value problem that we've seen if they not chosen a constrained they
just chosen the covariance the the embedding should be one which is the normal constraints
you would get
and i can value problem here
but i think you know you're splitting hairs sister
i think that's not really making much difference in means is not quite minimizing error functions we talked about before
or when we see it in this more general framework it won't be
so the smallest igon value this laplacian is zero because it's got
a zero
constant i can vector which is
zero igon value
and that's typically thrown away and then you retain the next q i can values for embedding
and you're minimizing as i say this subjective here under the constraint that the variance of axes
in fact
deep the covariance effects
now they tend be parameterized
even by setting it took on a constant i convert constant values which they call the simple-minded approach
all according to distance between two data points
so this is the adjacency
element hear that they will sometimes set and it's again it's not related why i mean this function appears everywhere
there's no specific reason why they should be related in this case the obvious for
being talked about talking about before
they motivated by analogy between discrete graph laplacian and class beltrami operator
which continuous diffusion equations
which they're saying the graph compression is discrete approximation to
i haven't played a lot with this so i don't know how sensitive
these algorithms are to the setting up this length scale here
and how you set these adjacency weights but it's something
you know people do when they do this
so you can do those two
the smallest igon values and then you see embeddings like this this one's picked up
the fact that the start of the run is different but then hasn't quite got
i how do put the coin that was the entire amount of think tanks so
skip lists are randomized structure
and in another adjective here
and just
and this also and simple
really quite so we have a simple efficient dynamic random search structure
all those things together
and so it's sort of like trees and that the bound is only
a randomized them but today we're going to see a much stronger bound expectation about
some particular skip lists all running order log and expected time
so the running time for each operation will be able to log in expectation
we're going to prove a much stronger results that there were large and with high
so this is a very strong
and that means
that the running time of each operation
the running time of every operations or log and almost always
in a certain sense
one i foreshadowing
so something like
the probability that order log n is at least one minus one over some polynomial
in n and you get to set the polynomial however large you like
so what this
basically means is that almost all the time you take taken skip list you do
a polynomial number operations on because presumably running a polynomial time algorithms using this data
structure polynomial members of inserts deletes searches
every single one of them will take or log n time
almost guarantee
so this is a really strong down on the tail of the distribution the mean
is or login that's not so exciting and the fact that almost all the weight
of this probability distributions right around like in this tiny little abseil ones
very very tiny probabilities you can be
bigger than again
so that's
we're going
this is the a data structure by
in nineteen nine so this is the most recent
as actually a trip somewhere recent they're like
ninety three or so
but fairly recent data structure
just insert delete search
and it's very simple
you can derive it if you don't know anything about the structure
almost nothing
now analyse analyzing the performance is lower than that of course takes are sophistication but
the structure itself is very simple
we're going to start from scratch
suppose you don't know
what a red black tree is don't know what the tree is
because you don't even know what the tree is
what is the simplest data structure
restoring a bunch of items
restoring dynamics
o west
link list
now i'm going to suppose this sorted linked lists are going to be a little
bit and
so if you have a linked list of items is
maybe on a doubly linked just for kicks
how long does it take to search in assorted blinklist
again is one answer
and the other answer which illustrates and is the right answer so even though it's
sorted we can do binary search because we don't have random access to linguist
so i suppose and i'm only giving a pointer to the head
otherwise i'm assuming it's an array and the sorted array construction log sort of like
west-eastern kind scan through the time
and worst case search not so good but
we just try to improve it a little bit we will discover skip lists automatically
this is our starting point sorted linked lists
date and time and i'm not going to think too much about insertions deletions for
the moment was just
get search better
and we were brought to this
updates so we're randomisation come in search
pretty easy idea so how can we make a linguist
suppose all we know about our linkclus
what can i do to make it faster
this is where you need a little bit of innovation
so creativity
four links that's a good idea
so i could try maybe i don't know and pointers to
a couple steps ahead if i had a log and pointers i could do all
powers of two and that's a pretty good search structures people is that
like some peer to peer networks is that idea
but that's a little too fancy for me
you could try to build the tree on this linear
structure that's essentially where we're going
you could try to
put pointers to maybe like the middle of the list from the root so you
search between either here
you point to the median so you can compare against the median with the sugar
in the first half the second half that's
definitely on the right track also a bit too sophisticated
another list yes
good we're is to listen to that sort of the next simplest thing you could
and as you suggested we could maybe have pointers between them so maybe we have
elements down here are some of the elements up here we want to have a
point between the lists and gets a little bit crazy and how exactly
we might do that but somehow this feels good so this is one like with
one this is another linked list l two and to give you some inspiration
i want to give you
so this play and
the game is what is the secret
so causes fourteen if you know the answer
we one you
have a small class so i hope someone knows the answer
two years earlier
just come
and the joint distribution of all of the hidden variables on all the observed variables
can be written as the probability of the first
valuable times probability first observed variable given the first variable
the probability of
invaluable given its
they are able
and the probability of each observed variable given the corresponding
in the
so this graph
corresponds to this factorizations which is true for hmms and state space models
the only difference between HMM is in state space models is that nature and the
states are assumed to be discrete whereas in linear gaps in state space models the
states are assumed to be real valued calcium vectors
and now
the interesting thing is that
the belief propagation
and factor graph propagation algorithms that just briefly describe are actually
generalizations of
the forward backward algorithm which is an algorithm for doing inference in hidden markov models
and the common smoothing algorithm which is an algorithm for doing inference in state space
when i was a grad student i took full
the term
the term long course uncommon filtering
we spent the entire term on common filtering and i was really bored at the
end of it now i know why i was so bored that was because
you could learn about belief propagation
and then common filtering is the special case
they didn't so know it at the time called filtering is special case you can
describe it in
a couple of slides as being a special case and then you can say oh
oh by the way belief propagation can be applied to hidden markov models and all
these other graphs as well
that's just an aside now what do you do with monthly connected
the graphs
so we talked about singly connected graphs but
the real world isn't always singly connected and so we have a few options
so there's an exact algorithm called the junction tree algorithm which i will describe but
i have in the appendix here i have actually the description of the algorithm
in subsequent slides the junction tree algorithm takes
your multiple connected graph logs a bunch of variables together
until it can form a singly connected graph
on the super variables these several variables are variables that you take by grouping together
a bunch of variables in your original graph
and then it runs basically belief propagation on the supergraph
which is called the junction tree
now the problem with this algorithm is that it's an exact algorithm it will give
exactly the probability want but
if you have multiple connected graph you have no guarantee that you're
supernodes that you form are going to have a small number of states so for
if you have a bunch of binary variables
a new lian
twenty binary variables together if you force along twenty binary variables together then that supernode
can take on a million different states
and you have to actually enumerate all of those states to run this algorithm
so the junction tree algorithm is exact but it can be exponentially slow
and it turns out there's no way of doing
inference in a general graph
where you're guaranteed always two
p polynomial time in the number of nodes because it's not possible
a general graph can involve a full conditional probability full probability table
involving exponentially many states so it's not possible to do so
that's what you get for the junction tree algorithm
another thing you can do is called cutset conditioning
essentially you take your multiply connected graph and you take some variables and you say
what if
i said this variable to this value
and then you run
we propagation on the rest of the graph and then you say what if i
said it to this other value et cetera so you
sometimes called reasoning by assumptions because you assume different possible states for viability having observed
and then u
then you
combined together the probabilities that you got from these different settings
now you can only do this if you find a set of variables that renders
the rest of the graph
to be singly connected
so they need to
take graph and surgically
remove a bunch of notes until you get the rest to be singly connected
so this doesn't always work
very efficiently either
and this is exact as well
and the third thing you can do is you can take your mostly connected graph
and you can simply run belief propagation on that'll fully connected graph they can take
let's lecture
first of all
i am i put a little bit of a reference list
on a web page
you know i'm not alone
just basic reading
for you
to to be at this point the war
understandably more of the
so you can
from my web page
you can go to the
and and the
two thousand seven link
and then you find it's actually link to another wikipedia article
my mission is to find mister right
and to me
the message you need some if you're curious about them
or not
if you want more of that
then a little
apologies there was a little bit in the
number denoted
you always very careful
somebody noticed that it was a little mistake in the reduction from nonseparable powerful analysis
so you just go back and fix
the way you
wait you're primary
is constructed
and this is constructed by an operator and the whole thing is
but because fixed but
course makes the difference analysis where you have to add that the labels
multiply the label
being held
the labels needed because
we need to cancel the other labels the counts the same level the camps when
your computer martin for you right
if you go there and see that there is a little
we state that in the competition the market because level of
but then when
going compute the normal view
the square is normal
the label has been go away
what about that big
now i would like to to
finish up the argument i thought that the last part of the class
in the
conclude that this analysis is the quality of the ones
so let me recap quickly
so we had this argument in one
which was
we find the the weight of the part the
i mean
the value of
the weight
we had lost the
where i come from that that's why
x the
beginning one minus
and xt because
and these are fixed gone because there
that is kept constant broadly
this is the policy is but i
so we saw that solving these
you end up with an update
with the usual form of the up to WP but WP my one like it
that he
why the next meal with simple
and the
in this case it takes the form because of the box constraints arising
from the use of the
like variables
let's say
and then l
the of that mind
well i
call it what you will see this is one is one
she changes on its one
so this many many of these
right to decide what to do this so the french for this one where
the prince one of for those of know that
and lines around
so it's very easy for
three move in the sun
it has its own rules as well as this very
it's force
the school chain
so what do we have to reason
i think we can get
these or what
all cast
we have shown by a number of things cells
when user group is itself is not world
intersection is one thousand
one of these cells the too
and the number is the number it is zero
so this is the largest
so so this this
we use it through
so that can was the one
in the music was
as these things
this is one of the first set
e two
the intersection of two surfaces
in some places so this
this is
this section of the four hundred but this is too
so in
so each is
the reason this no
there are no in the nineteen sixty three
until they
these but we you
the number of sections
one hundred section is something like
some of these
so the
it's so
right at the degree of
we can there that was a number
so solutions such that the
for i two d
that's probably because you have to use as well as the results of what we
three revert also in
the potatoes are a little bit salted and also stopped biting and the sold will
sink a N I can imagine we don't know what they are and will be
maybe he was restaurants in was that by the way already unfortunately already for 2
years but the habit states
and here we have committed on and cross
which of creating cap which are already using supporters in order to extract all kinds
of weather warnings and cut fearless but they can get to and this is the
and the hour aspect of this behavior that the loan not all of this behavior
is like some hospital alone and that it when they don't have the right to
work if they are given for example wires straight wireless by the experiment and with
the strike where they can't get into a big band that they make them into
very clever and here we have some very ahead inheritance in humans and a little
bit of variation on the theme and the ability to get over changes the song
and we don't know what the fate of the current will be probably not very
good but some bargains to survive
and that already said bore culture that we know so well this isn't the way
we can think about things
and this is the world in which we move this hour symbolic landscape something that
is so fundamental to us which is into which is saying which is part of
everything in fact we do and are
so is carrying find what did you do
why do we need this perspective on the pollution and inheritance what why is important
for us book is on all kinds of ways of transmitted the probation fined salt
so let's think so we have to give an account of why a quiet wife
of interest so far as to call it an important was a study of hereditary
if we're saying hereditary condition and population with no longer have to wait we can't
just assume that differences in jeans that make the difference may be at the that
the genetic differences that make the difference that will want to do something about it
would better knows something about otherwise
we should be misled so
but it's also important because you see we we have to realize that we have
clonal plants a lot of invasive plants are either all day because they start from
very very few individuals no more or less the same genetically identical genetically so when
we think of pig the 1 we have real should because it's up your lines
that genetically identical but this is not the case if at the inheritance appear as
if the environment continues at the genetic variation than the candidate selection into lines and
would better now that this is the agricultural ecological last week as well as the
hereditary and it makes a difference to the way that we think about the promotion
and I hope I have some kind of
and it makes a difference to the way we think about medicine problem
the minister
sell half what can we say so I said 1st 1st already with the example
that they gave you the exam with be prior we saw that there can be
selection and evolution on that genetic access
this this is he's were identical genetically there were different only whether or not they
have a prime and the frequency of crime containing and no prime containing so changed
as a result of selection so this is 1 thing that many other aspects are
really concentrate only on those of foreign like
so here we have Arabidopsis and we will see are different manipulation happen among 96
of Arabidopsis occupied what we think of the occupants here and it's like right in
this this year of the genes that we're looking and what we see is that
when we're looking at the population of Arabidopsis plans we see a lot of oration
indifferent ecological conditions now we don't know in this particular study whether this at the
genetic variations are inherited but we know from other studies that about 50 cent between
about 50 % immoral as head the plants at the genetic variations are inherited for
something like a generations
so if this is the case
group theory and field theory and so forth
it's an interesting there are all sorts of other great properties
of this kind of
this kind of man
the main thing and how this turns out not to be true if m is
not prime
so can somebody think of let's imagine we're doing something model ten
somebody think number that doesn't have an inverse mod ten
another one is
OK turns out the divisors
OK in
in fact actually
more generally
something that is not relatively prime
OK meaning that is no common factors that UCD is not one between that number
and the modulus
OK those numbers do not have
in inverse
but it's prime every number is relatively prime
to the modules and that's the property that we're taking advantage
so this is our fact
and so in this case what i'm after
i want to divide
phi x zero minus y zero
that's what i want to do it this point
OK but i can't do that
if x is zero
first of all if the amazon prime
OK i can't necessarily do that i might be able to but can necessarily
but i m is prime i can definitely divide by ax reminds wiser can find
that inverse
and the other thing i have to do is make sure zero minds wiser was
they would be zero if these two are equal but our supposition was their equal
and once again
just bring it back to the without loss of generality if it were some other
a position that we were off
i really doing exactly the same thing with that position
OK so now we're going to be able to divide so we continue with our
continue with our proof
since x is zero
it is not equal to y zero
there exists an inverse
director minus wiser
and that implies just continue on from over there
it is zero
is congruent there for two minus
some of i want to or
of AI
x y
minus y i
x zero minus y zero
so what
so let's just
go back to the beginning of our proof and see what we've derived
we're saying we have two distinct keys
we picked
all of these a i
OK and we're saying that these two distinct he's hash to the same place
if there has to the same place
it says that
o zero
i had to have a particular value
as a function of the other AI
because in others one side picked
each of these a i from one to o are them in that order for
that i don't have a choice for how i pick a zero to make it
exactly one value allows it to collide namely the value of a zero given by
by fifty different value of a zero
they wouldn't collide
OK let me write that down thus
why you think about it
so for each choice
of these i was exactly one
of the n possible choices of a zero that cause a collision
and for all the other choices i might make of a zero there's no collision
so it's essentially i don't have if they're going to collide
i've reduced essentially the number of degrees of freedom of my randomness
by a factor of m so far count up the number of a AJ's
x and y
that's equal to
others m choices just using the product rule again m choices for a one
times m choices for a two
after m choices for a are
and they're only one choice
for a zero
this is
choices for
eighty one
they are
only one choice for a zero if they're going to collide not going to collide
it got more choices frazier but by one collide there's only one value i can
this value
OK that's the only value for which i can i will pick
in this sense
all training points we look at the whole training points
based on that
which was the basis functions function the basic things the they had had the lowest
error is
so this is the function that depends on all the x i y i
so this function
the function depending on x i y i
therefore even if x i y i independent
six one is the public school and so on
this function f depends on both
one x two
the discs i i swear will no longer be
so mathematically speaking
we are no longer situation where we have independently financed
so in such a situation where this function has seen all the training points we
its own people
so what do we do
so that's where the whole
complexity comes from one
so let's start with two observations
so let's say that before the minimizer of our we denoted by of
the of optimal the function
we knew
test error
the function of the distribution
you know minimizer is characterized by
in particular we know that
these two inequalities hold true
because of minimize this function are
so he has
is smaller than any other country
in particular
likewise if my this function are all the functional
the function of functions
and minimize this quantity therefore
this inequality holds
characteristic n is smaller than the characteristic any other function in particular
these two inequalities hold true
and in know a way what we would like for consistency
consistency is before statistical them and roughly speaking is that in the limit of infinity
many observations
we get the right results or limited in the observation patients period is
all of to by all principal crystallisation
will converge to is expected
the expected values
so for consistency we would like this kind of uniform convergence
and we would like the left side of the inequalities to converge to zero
so in a way
it was he has been many observations this if we change function chosen from the
training points
chosen by minimizing the training error will change and we would like to change that
it's risk
we get arbitrarily close to the optimal risk
we know that this is always allowed to do there
we would actually like to converge
so these quantities we would actually like both the zero
both negative
one way to show that they both conditions
show that some of them is zero
compute the sum of these two things
here we've got some
first of all i just rearranged in terms of
this were one over here
the i can of on this thing here
he was so we here would end up in the way of an f of
we have this thing over here as it is this thing here
we will bond
why the supremum
maximum with one speaking over the whole country class
of this quantity
OK so the supremum
born on whatever you it by substituting one specific function here some
so this is an upper bound
let's take a a look at the whole thing we would like this whole thing
to go to zero
first of all the second half here
f of is fixed function is we don't know this function
the function that minimizes the
the true risk
but independent of the training examples that we see
so from the point of view of language inequality we find
six function so we can just
by the time of the quality of the law of large numbers and this tells
in probability
this was converges towards this actually soliciting was this one will find this thing go
to zero
already question whether the whole some would go to zero sufficient condition for this to
work for the that this thing supposed to zero
the supremum over
i rephrased this year against the first half
district inside the zero for this is the case
then we would have these two inequalities
in this case statistically speaking one would say that the principle of empirical risk minimization
is consistent
so the question is now when does this thing
this is where uniform convergence can informally so the to
the necessary sufficient for a certain type of nontrivial consistency not much
he careful
on nontrivial consistency
it's actually sort of interesting issues you do theory
this is the definition of this is the
if we define crisis in this way they get the necessary and sufficient
but they tend to exhibit very keen on
but not everybody is defined consistency this way but let's leave that aside
so from
necessary sufficient causes disease
one side of uniform convergence
here is actually
so this is exactly
o thing
i had here
it's about turning proved that
this thing here is necessary and sufficient for consistency so
roughly speaking what i argued on the previous slides was
but if we have this convergence
that's you want to listen to
optimized from the picture
one of the problems
above all suspicion
i don't know about you actually
from all
there is only one peak is one of the think
so i
so what native
but going than that to trust the model to try to become law
but the
politician equal to the
joke or a checking
an introduction so just so index indexes what a problem with dense
well as much of
the vision but also some of the interesting
the parameters of the problem in water to this is what i want
by the way is
only parameters of the model which is what
OK put them on the input which
the the problem of the water sensor networks
one of the most
that is connected to the middle between zero
the first is the programs to promote
but then the model is that
because the problem
it was like that it's the largest opinion
so perhaps
one of the most of the novel out edge
my own research
the political blog discipline was trying parker
small signal and some action group
what is the is although we should just become
but then or on support text from this component in the course of the
only one
but what i would call
she is not
below the surface
what is it
i suppose it refers to to
and i have a little bit more
you want to know what are the ones
this is the largest
one of the larger
or the whale
so does
so sort
it doesn't what you think
what we want
also some of the largest manual solution because the sounds
in the seventies policy with them
four months
it's a small child the political will
it has been decided to the solve quantum mechanics properties
so problem that because we don't have possible
the past according to
what we're want
in this higher
can give you problems with so many
which i mentioned the so
i would like to give two computational problems
you might have
very efficiently compute the similarity between two objects in such high time
and in fact
we call this could
so good
it's actually
similarity computation
between the object
some features
so in talk
have rather between two objects we first the object to some high
and in that time she is we think
but it's good that can be
you can just use any similarity function
to compute the in problem
you could have to be subject to
it has to be
so that could be seen
could be fixed by it must be positive
the which
if you go to the web is called the gram matrix or kernel matrix
which is actually
the matrix that
given the similarity
between each
the training examples
that is the gram matrix is positive things that know not so you can make
what do we
in the
in the three
we can play a role here by
we have
to use and also
in the
the decision when you
we can play
well we can play in the world
now just
a few
support vector machine and then i come back to that could function
that we can use information extraction
support vector machines i
to be a little too many noisy features
so you do do not need appealing feature selection
but of course you might know
in the trade
when you have to optimize it should be one
presentation so
it could be used
to have feature selection
after the
i have i will
so the discriminant function the i'm not
only used in the
the support vector machine
they are also used in your neighborhood
well well well
your data
we in
these only memory based learning when you compare an object with all with the vector
with all the other objects you
i call people about group
that can be used
in information extraction
so people coconuts are
well for text classification are here as i said
ninety six categories
categories like
sports politics
you might also be useful in long island new york times
you could also exploit the structure
natural language and neutral
to my mind told some i will be more
about structure
in natural language
and the structure learning the structure
he also well because could not be used as similarity functions operate
actually i already proved by
so if we look at some kernel and granka convolution kernel
and also some trees which
an example of course you could not so
which can be used to structured data such as sequences
you might
similar to the art
you can think of sequence of compact
you might want to measure the similarity
as the number of common ground
where and is defined as a lot of energy can from the
and it contains a an integer parameter n which starts at one so one two
three and this is called the number of degrees of freedom in some sort of
analogy with the mechanical system i suppose
and it contains zero power law term z to the and over two minus one
an exponential term e to the minus the number two and that that complicated term
there just serves to
normalize the PDF to unit area
OK so the expectation value of the were distributed variables is equal to the number
of degrees of freedom
and the variance
is equal to two times the number of degrees of freedom
so why is it useful i just made this to this definition and quoted these
these properties but why is that useful it's useful because if you consider a gas
in distributed random variable or rather some set of independent calcium distributed variables x sub
with mean values URI
and variances sigma i square
now let me take the following combination
x i minus mu i squared
divided by sigma i squared and summed over all of my variables
so that's the kind of combination it actually comes up all the time because what
i'm doing here is i'm comparing XI to its mean value
dividing that by some measure of its with
squaring and summing it up so that's that's that's the type of thing that comes
up in connection
with the method of least squares for example
OK fine so i do that and then ask the question
how is that guy distributed
if i were to make a histogram of z
what would it look like the answer is it would follow consequent distribution
so so that's that's somehow the origin of the importance of the consequent distribution and
we'll revisit that when we talk about the method of least squares
kochi distribution i skip the landau distribution skip
OK so now i have
we started
five minutes late so go another twelve minutes
right this network
well so far we get we can always continue to the next
so let me talk now about the monte carlo method
i know a lot of you have probably been working with with monte carlo data
simulated data for the LHC experiments but i want to take a step back now
and just talk about the basic mathematics of this procedure
so at an abstract level with the monte carlo method is
it is a numerical technique for calculating
probabilities are things that can be related to probabilities
by using sequences of random numbers
and you can break this procedure down into us a certain number of steps the
usual steps would be first to generate a sequence or one r two
up to some are m
values that are uniformly distributed
between zero and one so remember we just discussed this uniform pdf
so a uniform distribution between zero and one
in the second step would be to use that sequence
to produce
a second sequence of numbers
x one x two
and so forth up to x and
the length of the second sequence may
or may not be the same as the length of the image initial sequence
but from the second sequence of numbers i well
it should follow
some other PDF f of x that i'm interested in
so i have some other PDF f of x that i'm interested in exploring its
properties and so i use that first sequence of random numbers to produce
the second sequence of random numbers such that it follows
f of x
and once i have that second sequence of random numbers i can use it the
the x values to estimate some property of f of f of x so for
if i simply look at the sequence of x values and count the fraction of
them the line between any two limits say between a and b
what is that that's the probability to find x between a and b so therefore
that's the integral from a to b
of the five xtx
so by doing by simply counting the fraction of x values that that lie between
given limits have effectively done an integral and monte carlo calculation is at least always
formally equivalent to doing an integral
we don't have to actually think of it that way and very often we can
think of these x values as simply simulated data and then we can treat them
as if they were real data and we can use them to then test our
statistical procedures into design the detector and to see what type of outcome you would
you would obtain
assuming a certain hypotheses for the underlying probability densities
so let me now look at each of those three steps in a little bit
more detail
so first we need to do is to generate a sequence of random variables values
uniformly distributed between zero and one
in this sort of early days of monte carlo which somehow originated with the atomic
bomb project during the war
to figure out what is the the case
this is this essentially something that you have to
to enforce it is
these have has to sum to one
ah yes their probabilities
well they are defined as being positive things always
in the case of potentials they will be positive in the case of
are you know that's no you're right
i think i'm tired
yes so basically these things through all the positive by definition
now that the
we're not enforcing these anywhere because we are working with the function here
so we need the explicit this this constraints
these things are not
sum to one
you learn something negative values because
i will be
the negative logarithm of the number between zero and one that's only positive
oh yes yes yes
notice that these
quantities that we have here
because i haven't specified is being a linear function here
well specified as being in in the function
so i'll have as will actually be a linear function of
and peter of some function of x and theta
so essentially
there is some of his life
because which should be
anyway into a you check is like maybe there is some sort of something
but anyway let's put this otherwise all make progress
but the key message here is that we have to
times the size of s equations and even each one of them is independent of
the other
why because for every pair of equations is called
every click
we solve this equation independently of every click because these theatres
on these as prime the only involve items in that click the order
the other equation of pairs of equation only will by using the other clique
and so on
so basically we can have
very nice result in bayesian networks which is
we solve
the maximum likelihood problem
separately it completely decouples over cliques so if i have very big big network it
doesn't matter
because you only have to solve the max likelihood problem independently
it every click
there's we thing about learning bayesian networks
it's move
we wikipedia
in my car and feel how much like estimation well the same general idea is
just in this case these normalisation he doesn't go to zero
in general
the function of
on the other hand you don't have to enforce the constraints of that's what you
the problem is that these scenes is the function that couples all the teeth as
in the party
these are exactly the equations the couple
you don't have these the coupling that you had previously because he had the task
you have to test prior
everything is separated from every as prime
whereas here you have to
and this is actually the concatenation of all the prime factors so for everybody every
question here you have
every equation
so in order to solve that would be complex in general can be any complex
yes more complicated
OK now we are going to make it all these more simple
we are going to assume that function f of x and theta is actually a
linear function
on peter
that makes things really what simple
however it will be
this only text into believing that on some feature of x multicore sufficient statistics of
and that's the expression that we have
they called exponential families
if we assume that the probability distribution has this form
essentially we have with the con exponential family
p of facts is what we call sufficient statistics theta is the natural parameter and
g of people in this particular case
so what they call the log partition function
so this is not going to give you the idea and then i'm going to
i'm going to agree that the formula but
just forget about the following just remember the idea here have a graph
now imagine that should count
i don't know the number of path of length three that you have here
that if you can't count these number and you do this is the trick of
removing all the nodes that have that don't have the same color imagine that just
having that in mind you have removed
OK you have chosen different colors here color that are very similar to hear that
is blue blue dark blue one
the light blue it's cetera
you have those colors here so i mean that here you can you will have
if these is darwin diseased with these nodes made of those two knows is going
to to to stay and if it's
light blue and dark blue the combination of the two want to make a new
so imagine that
i know it's difficult but then you have a different number of parts here and
computing the number of paths of length three in this graph
it is precisely equivalent to
computing the number of paths of length three in this graph in this graph that
exactly how the same label
we're happy
OK i see i see one the theoretical part again
i understand that
so you have this graph in this graph
you the the product of those two refs
and then you compute
the number of of of path of length three that you have been described
and this corresponds to the number of length of a path of length three that
you have here
and here that have exactly the same labels along the path
trust me
if don't care OK
so here is the kernel i was happy to show you that because it's very
elegant but probably should i remember the first time i saw the lecture and these
it took one hour
so maybe in
in seven minutes it's a bit short
but we should look at this paper it's is very interesting you have a lot
of different kernels for graphs that can be
computed just using the
the i just matrices in the
label matrices
and the final type of graph
i wanted to graphical that i wanted to talk to you about it was when
when you have a space that is defined by a graph
this is something that is very common that you can see when first if you
want to
two to work with the web pages you want to do classification then web pages
are are connected by by links
and you can imagine that there is a web page that those are the connection
and you imagine that when you have outgoing link from x two to x one
you also have the same thing
the other way around
it's just simplifies things and that's the question that you may ask is
it is how you can define a kernel between those those those points just using
the structure of the graph that connects all the data
and there is a very simple thing i'm not going to have to spend much
time these which is called the diffusion kernel it's really nice again
it just say that you take the adjacency matrix a
again you see that
x one is connected to x two here you have one between the first rule
and the second kind
x one k which is connected to x five
so the first line in the five con you have one
if the what's i
in addition
they're on the conditionals regressions in the you know that each node has come very
simple idea technology and but simple often good
this this graphical models you know it's really hard to write and marginal likelihood to
go uphill and it just runs really grounds it might be a good idea and
really large graphical model to do something extremely simple try to prove something about it
so you know you're not doing something ridiculous
and then do various problem
good good developing literature
had this is know has been
this literature on graphical model
model selection but there's lots kind of toy example would precious few real
the real life applications of it and and successful examples of algorithms that scale to
real life scale problems of this kind of a different way and see if we
can get closer to reality
the lives of
the things
i mean this papers all theories so b we personally have been looking like it
the way you know whatever questions a huge field in which there
there are lots of tons of applications of it and
it is
clearly of benefit to do multivariate regression compared regression and i don't have lists of
applications in my in my head but there was a big literature on it for
good reason
so we discriminate theoretical contribution here i i mean i i k i mean i
can i can speculate there tons of i know biology examples where i can think
you can clearly think it's appropriate but you know we're going to follow up with
more problems stuff and we did this in a nested datasets and we show that
it was better you know and so on and that the mean that much to
i guess it was kind of interest in this dataset which we have very few
number of examples of each of the digits and
it was better than doing independent ridge regression to find the right features for each
of the classification better than
doing separately
but i'll leave it here creative thinker problematic it's not hard to think of joint
features like for feature selection and you want to borrow strength across multiple features like
i can't believe that's widely applicable
OK let's take a really short break is permitted to stand up and stretch if
you don't mind because i would like to finish a little chunk of the last
part of my talk
OK so i'll bigger indulgences the last talk in the last part of is about
to happen all that so you can try to skip over quickly here but i
think it will be of interest to many of you this issue with independence and
conditional independence thing especially as filthy and summary of the audience as the very deep
topic in which people are believed to be a great deal in this kind of
a has no conditional independence story that i think is kind of interesting so relate
to what you've learned
the during the past two weeks another talks
the reason i bring this up at this point is that there are again it's
going to be an algorithm that does something and we want to give an analysis
of it and this is by the hardest example is the real kind kernel methods
hard problem machinery is not the second order cone problem or the SDP which is
somehow simple analyses hard so we really need to a real serious tool here so
we use empirical process theory get
good results in this case just consistency but i can give you a hint of
how that kind of harder argument goes and why we want to face because independence
is a very important concept basically
OK this is a joint work with kenji fukumizu inferences block
OK so it's kind of skipped kind quickly a little bit so
this is the topic that i is mainly exist in the state literature mainly in
the annals of statistics and its kind surprising machine learning also worked on some people
may have you see more and more of this kind of thing but it's basically
regression where you have XY pairs the coverage is high dimensional
and you want to find a projection of the homes recovery it onto a subspace
as just like you were doing PCA
this one has to take into account the response
the PCA doesn't take into account the response
OK so i discriminant analysis is an example of this kind classically for classification
we try to find some space allows you to do good separation
this is the regression version of that and it's meant to be nonparametric so we're
going to do this with the words the buzz so my parametrically ie the disturbed
the regression of y on x is allowed to be arbitrary i mean i a
we want to estimate now will call the parameter as it's the subspace it has
the finite dimensional object so it's really a parameter estimate that
under any arbitrary regression of
x y and x
OK so that's the problem cos some i parametric because we have a nonparametric component
which is really a nuisance parameter for this problem trying to estimate the regression
i'm just trying to get SOS is the primary ever nonparametric nuisance parameters usually called
semiparametric problem
OK so the main is just to hear the main approach to this literature which
is called sufficient dimension reduction
trying to find a subspace s
has done by inverse regression so it turns the problem around tries to try to
go from x to y where x is really high dimensional y is low dimensional
turnaround why might be one-dimensional
and go from y to x
because of white's one-dimensional you from wide access to the curve in the x space
OK so you could think about estimating that and then maybe doing PCA or something
to find the subspace woodpecker flies
and then turning around saying well that occur in which the data line that relevant
to y
because i was able to regression from y to x
for this kind of relationship and maybe i'll recover a reasonable subspace there so it's
kind of an intuition and that's so that's been done but what to do this
to an inverse regression from y to x now x is acting as the response
in regression you have to probabilistic assumptions in the response you don't put on the
covariance put spots
nine i'm not looking
twenty one point three six
twenty one point
in round of four if you want to
you see that the agreement is spectacular
within the uncertainty of my measurements
comes out amazingly well you could have removed this too of course
because if you have an uncertainty of point two here a little silly
you have little to hanging there
you see
indeed this spring is very close to an ideal spring it obeys hooks law
and it is also
here's the pendulum
here's the mass
offset at angle theta
the length of the pendulum is l
the length of the string
there's gravity here
and the other force on the
the only other force is the tension t
don't confuse that with period t this tension senators
was the only two forces there's nothing else
the thing is going to arc around
like this
and going to also made
i call this the y direction
and i call this
x direction and here x equals zero
well i'm going to decompose the
tension into
the wired into the
x direction as we have
done before
this is going to be the y component
x component
so this is why component
calls t
cosine theta
the x component
equals qi
find things
and now i'm going to write down the differential equations of motion
x erection
second newton's second law
he calls
this is the only force in the x direction
it's a restoring force just like with the spring and if we have to give
it a minus sign
he calls minus
ten times
the sign of the
he itself could easily be a function of data so i have to allow for
the sign of theta
he calls x if it's here at position x
divided by l
so can i can write for this minus p which may be a function of
theta and x defined by l
that's my differential equation
in the x direction and i prefer always forty is eight right down
o double bond
now the y direction
in one direction i have
why double dot
this is what plug direction so i have the cosine fade-out
minus mg
this equation one
and this equation two
so now we have to solve
coupled differential equations which is
hopeless tasks it looks like issue
and it is it
and now we're going to make
some approximations
and the approximations and we'll make which you often see
in physics
when something oscillates
is what we call
the small angle
small angle we will not allow theta
two become
two large
the qualitative
what i mean by two large
when fate which is in radians equals much much less than one we call that
a small angle
if that's the case the cosine of theta
is very close to what
you will say well what apply close to one o k five degrees
the cosine is o point nine
nine six
that's close to one
ten degrees
the cosine is o point nine eight five
that's only one and a half percent different from one
even the ten degrees doing extremely well
so this is
consequence number one
of the small angle approximation
a second consequence
look at the extrusion that this object made from equilibrium
in fact direction that this big
look at the excursion makes in the y direction is this small
and where a smaller
then the excursion in the x direction provided the two angle is small
i give you an example
at five degrees
this excursion
is only four percent of this excursions
ten degrees
this excursion is only nine percent
of these excursions
and since the excursion in the y direction is so much smaller than the x
we say that the acceleration in the y direction
can be approximated
to be
roughly zero
there is almost no acceleration in
the y direction
with these two
conclusions which follow from the small angle approximation
i go back
the migration number two
and i find zero
which could be a function of theta
cosine data is one
and g
so i find
equals and g
notice it's no longer even the function of the data
so i simply have in my small angle approximation
but i can
make t
the same as mg
it's approximately i feel put an equals sign
i substituted back in my equations number one
so now i get
x double dot
and now bring it on the other side
he's now and g
and g
x divided by l
equals zero
comes the wonderful results x double dot
please g of l
times x
equals zero
and this is such a beautiful results
it almost makes me cry
a simple
harmonic oscillations
this equation
like a carbon copy
of the one
but we there
here we have k over n
we have g overall that's all
other than that
there is no difference
so you can write down immediately solution
two this differential equation
will be some amplitude
times the cosine
of omega t plus five just as we had before
and omega
i will now be the square root
of g of l
so the period of the pendulum
will be two pi
times square root of l
of the gene
just falls into our lab because we did all the work
i want you to realize that these results for pendulum
have their restrictions small angles and we discussed qualitatively how small you would like to
and also
the mass has to be exclusively in here and not in the string we call