hit rates and then we just
the magic transforming it
OK so prior distribution so we similar prior distributions to what i used in the
simple analysis it slightly different because we're doing this induced prior by using the
arc sin transformation
but not informative prior just allows it to be anything so someone says i have
no clue
can be anything so we just put it
than informative prior and you know real numbers
and again you was meaning dark side transformed
p is a weakly informative priors are like the open minded one so we use
the median p is point two five and ninety five percent and ninety percent sure
that falls between point one two o point four one and the reason for the
odds are nonsymmetric interval around point two five because we're actually putting the prior to
signing the arcs and transformed
the believers prior again we use the median point three three and ninety percent sure
that falls between point three o twenty six and the skeptics prior medium point two
first ninety percent sure
that median is between o point two four five point two five five
and i don't expect to reduce the only reason is here
is because and well up with this on my website and so if anyone wants
to go look at the results and details can do so but i have summarized
some of them for you
OK so here some summary of the results so remember what we're doing is we're
trying to get distribution for the possibilities for the medium
and so the distribution of possibilities has its own
fifty percent cut off its own medium
and it has the first two point five percent nineteen ninety seven point five percent
and and so on
so here's what they are so
basically what you can see is
that we also frequentist analysis using maximum likelihood so in all these cases the median
comes out about point three three
the lower and the two point five percent happens at about point three and the
other one about three six
the believers still comes out about the same place in the middle
as well
maybe is slightly narrower book but the skeptics
comes out still not convinced
so point two five one is left shifted slightly but not by much
if we try to look at the range for individual p so that was for
the medium
range for individual p is gets quite why the non informative prior one nine point
four nine open-minded point one seven five one so very similar to the next likelihood
estimate point one eight point five
but then we get slightly narrower intervals for the believer especially for the skeptic by
the way there's a typo in the proceedings for this just this very last one
this is what should be doesn't say that proceedings
what we found actually is suppose under the frequentist analysis and bayesian analysis of the
data do indicate that there's is variation from study to study
the difference in her right so just a binomial model may not be appropriate except
for the null hypothesis under the null hypothesis
so it looks like this five right here
so comparing bayesian frequentist results results under frequentist bayesian noninformative and weakly informative open minded
priors are actually pretty similar
so the ninety five percent probability of median basically ranges from o point three o
point three six
but the bayesian analysis under informative priors
is quite sensitive to the prior to the skeptics prior gives ninety five percent probability
interval for median p is point two five hundred twenty six two
the believers prior gives ninety five percent probability interval for median
from point three o eight two o point three four five
so can conclusions from the analyses the average rate for the population
in other words hit rates if you look at possibly different rates for different studies
it seems to be slightly above thirty percent whatever method is used except the skeptics
binomial model with fixed p is too simple hit rates actually may change based on
the number of factors
so statistical models actually need to incorporate this additional information and variability may be put
in information about participants
conditions of the experiment the experimenter was and so on and for doing that bayesian
approach actually like the most reasonable
so teaching activities if you wanted to do this in your class what would you
do well it's actually hate to tell you very difficult to do methodologically sound experiment
in this area because you really do have to figure out how to rule out
ordinary communication possible cheating
if i wanted to say OK you're OK do an experiment
i randomly selected target i want you to describe the show you four choices and
you have to pick which one you think it is
those independent sessions
i think the same target for all of you
and so the pair psychologists call this the stacking effect basically it's the non independence
results from the fact that suppose i say you OK
i have a picture drawn from national geographic picture randomly selected from national geographic possible
pool target
drop you think it is most of you are probably just something similar
you would probably draw something i don't know with maybe an ocean trees or whatever
what you've seen in national geographic magazine
so when i have the right answer if it happens to be something
the matches what you're most likely to draw
you're all going to do really well if i have something that happens to not
that we're all pretty likely to draw you into a simpler way to see this
if i say OK randomly selected a number from one to ten
because most of you picture yourself
that happens to be a you'll do well if it doesn't you want so
it's the not independent called the stacking effect so it's really hard to do this
and ask for the the class
i it's easier to assign projects for outside of class where individual sessions can be
used actually did i understand our davis of four unit honors seminar
it was called testing psychic claims from say answers to statistics and i trace the
history of research in this area from when they used to use the sciences
the more sophisticated statistical methods are are used and i had the students work in
teams to do project
and one of the team's actually did i dream study
where they had people in their teens
so when i an assistant and she would randomly selected target
any given night and they would all try to dream about it
in the morning they will be shown four choices and they would get together and
try to figure out which of the four traces was and they actually did pretty
well they had a signet statistically significant study at the end and so we published
twenty percent of the data is missing and you can reconstruct cascades when you have
even around ninety percent of the missing data so the idea is that even though
you went online and collected incomplete data you can use some kind of model based
techniques actually
connected disconnected pieces of cascades and really reason about how the complete data would look
like it's just something you have in mind when you do this kind of analysis
this is the first way to trace information tracing hyperlinks a second way of tracing
information with which is very popular lately is to use it right so it is
an information and each user generates a stream of bits of sort of the hundred
forty characters long messages and then also to the users can subscribe to follow streams
of others and that sort of three ways how to track information flow in so
the first way is to trace the spread of what is called hashtags i'll explain
what hashtags are the second the next thing is similar to hashtags is particularly URL's
and last option is sort explicit way how people can for interesting pieces of information
through the mechanism called the tweets that i also described so the first what do
i mean by hashtags right so here is about so i was preparing this slides
i i sort of focused on the on the
crisis or revolution in egypt right the things about the bottom right of the president
right so the idea is that when people who about something they can put this
hashtag infront of a particular keyword and now becomes like a bag for that for
that for that for the person or something like somebody here used to hashtags one
is cash obama the other cashmore barack right so many times discussion tags mean particular
people sometimes they are very sort of culturally specific so for example the one of
the most popular hashtags in january two thousand eleven was need new boyfriend right and
the idea was that sort of people with exchanges sort of stories about their ex-boyfriends
and they would that this kind of stories know you need what new boyfriend type
of hashtag or there is another one that was called he grocery striking this is
sort of a joke but instead of having a grocery list of things of i
buy in a store you'd have a list of hip-hop artists and again right so
we have this cash that could keep up groceries that people would put next to
next to the streets right so this hashtags what is really about them is that
they emerge naturally from inside the network so now we can place how they spread
through the network right so the idea the way you can do this is to
say hard because they had underlying network who follows home and if i make the
assumption that hashtags only emerge through the inside the network then i can trace how
information spreads right so so if b follows a and mentions cash the maximum product
of a and b we mention it tomorrow and because b follows a i could
make this assumption that this information about the product spread from a to to so
that is the first way how we can do things the second way that is
similar is because is you have tried so many times which contains URL school interesting
articles that people want to talk about that so here is an example of
of what that has a particular shortened URL in right so so now what we
can do again we can use the same thing with betrays the appearances of this
in the streets and in this way we can start making assumptions and starting to
see how how this usage of these you as flows through the network one important
thing would be to do what else is that this URL hash that shortened so
that services like twitter because his own one that is it is popular already put
in a long URL and to give you a very short URL and many times
the short actually the cached versions of URL personalized so if i can show you
what i get a different hash code if you had the URL so we can
only then attribute who was the person that was spreading the URL through the network
and sometimes of course that can also not be the case so these are two
things that people have done a lot of studies about how information refuses to distributed
through by studying adoption of hashtags or something adoption of
u s
and the second thing that is explicit about information is is a mechanism called it's
he looks slightly perkier than you did
yesterday because you're only halfway through the hours last time three quarters
so this is what we were talking about last time
markov model here remember defined over
the graph of pixels with the simplest conductivity north south east and west
and we were we had it in from your probabilistic form as as product of
factors and then just for convenience i also wrote down in this form as the
sum of
the logs of those factors
the negative log and
that's convenient and you remember the kind of
the business end of the of this prior distribution is this little expression here which
in energy terms that is it or in probabilistic terms reduces the probability every time
there's a pair of adjacent pixels with different labelings zero and the y and then
we also
is that aside about you know when you stop and think about it that actually
equivalent to having a prior which
many which says that
the outline of the object is the more probable
the shorter line is which is bizarre because it has become completely the truth because
then the most probable outline would be you know
vanishingly small so
if we were really to sit down and construct exactly the prior we wanted that
probably wouldn't be it on the other hand you know it's great to have tractable
priors that do something for you
and this prior we're going to see is is very tractable
i did the thing that does do for us is that it
it argues in favour of the smooth outline rather than a weekly outlining more or
less the same place so you given two outlines that include the same more or
less the same pixels as data the weekly one is going to have a lot
a lot more length and so that's going to be down
that's going to be
get less probability in this in this prize
so that's where we got to this parameter gamma which in energy terms is the
penalty that levied for
one unit of parameter length
and so the problem is
how do you maximise this
and how do maximizing energy of this form some of the sum of terms expressed
over this
graph and that's what you know that's what this lecture is going to be all
and i should this
picture which was you kind of tease that i'm sure been keeping you awake at
which was that
you know if we do apply this penalty falling in
manhattan distance then you tend to get these sorts of manhattan artifacts
you know
that's what you deserve
measuring distance so crude
and i wonder any of you have any
and the great ideas what you might do to sort of
make this work better any thoughts
that sounds like a generically good thing to do i don't know what exactly him
yes yes
he was a lot more
it's a good idea i mean the like yes i mean if weighted towards the
likelihood we would certainly weight away from the prior it seems to be the prime
doing the damage so i that's quite a good insight on the other hand if
we if we wait all the way to the likelihood
you know will be back in that's making individual decisions about pixels state and we
know we don't want that so
you know maybe there's a kind of a nice valley in between those two undesirable
three years
physical excel afterwards
you think i think i do that
but that's
to hack that
to good OK
so not about idea
any other thoughts before i
what about you know what about attacking the root cause of the problem
i think that's an excellent idea
the man says diagonal connections so you know if we if we can have
just increase the order of this markov random field to allow not only north south
east west north east etcetera then
effectively you be able to
compose your
instead of manhattan distance it will be barcelona distance
you've been to barcelona you know have always have all those squares then they with
the corners cut off diagonal if you noticed a sort of barcelona
the barcelona thing to do this rather pretty improves the sight lines that they have
the junction so it's been considered to be architecturally great thing to do so yes
barcelona distance we could we could presumably get that if if we
if we do that that's a very good idea people do that and you can
even have high conductivity
and that and that certainly helps
another thing you can do
which is perhaps more
you know it is picking up to your
this rather weird thing where we take the
the icing term here here's the penalty as usual
and we abated by term that depends on the data
at this point you probably thinking a little bit dizzy and sick because you know
this was supposed to be the prime
part of the of the
the model now somehow it's started depending on the data so that really is a
little bit a little with you just suspend your your feelings and also just to
have a little look at this
this term what you see you see what's happening is that across the same pair
of pixels where you're looking at the labels to see if the labels were different
we are now
looking at at the actual colors of the pixels and treating this
penalty differently if the colour of the pixels across the boundary are also very different
supposing i and j th pixel have very different colours so there
the euclidean squared euclidean distance there is large compared with some mean that euclidean distance
then what tends to happen is that this term get switched off this whole bracket
will become something small
and so
the penalty will get abated
so what that means is you pay a penalty in the new model everywhere there
is a change of label except where this high contrast in the image
because this difference of colours that there's going to the place where the contrast is
high so it kind of you know he says OK you don't need to pay
penalty here because the evidence is so strong it's a little strange this because it's
sort of
in a way double counting of evidence you might think we already said what the
the term was going to be and that that's where all of the dependence on
zee the data should be
and now we kind of somehow
cheated by
bringing data into what was the prior to say for sure this is no longer
and that's
that's a little bit of something
you know more hybrid enterprise and you might think well we actually don't have any
decomposition into likelihood and prior and there kind of two
attitudes to that one is to say well
they you know that we have to have one it's just going to declare that
this is the form of the posterior and if i have some free parameters in
perhaps the biggest opportunities to learn the values of free parameters is not completely a
god-given posterior
and so that's that's the
conditional random field idea which is a markov random field doesn't partition in any obvious
this curve here
and we have used for a variety
solid wire so let's look at the top here this is hydrogen
and you can see that the
conductivity of excuse me diffusivity of hydrogen increases with temperature up to the temperature at
which i and converts from BCC FCC and there's is an abrupt drop in the
diffusivity of
hydrogen what's happening
what's happening what's the void fraction of BCC versus the void fraction of FCC
FCC is more tightly packed so we see an abrupt for
here's carbon same thing
the diffusivity rises up to the transformation temperature falls then continues to rise and not
the difference in this small
the slope of carbon and BCC lions is gentler than the slope of carbon in
FCC i what's that mean it means that the slope in FCC ion is this
upper value the slope and BCCI's lower value of the pay for the formation of
vacancies here's self diffusion of iron ion luca drops two orders of magnitude when it
moves from BCC FCC
and just to make the point this is carbon in graphite this self diffusion of
carbon in graphite
what's the problem
where would we see that its operation
well we said the delta h vacancy formation is related to one
so you're here you see the comparison between metallic bonding which is what you have
an ion source of diffusion of iron i to project this curve up to this
temperature so we can compare
at the same temperature we see
seven eight orders of magnitude difference between self diffusion of iron iron that some metals
intermetallic crystal versus carbon in graphite which is
carbon in a covalent crystals so
big difference in performance
there are other ways of looking at let's look the facts how do other defects
affect so here's a cartoon showing the diffusion of some solitude into a material only
this real material to polycrystalline materials so there's a grain boundary
and as you know grain boundaries have
the more openness
they have the ones the grain boundary have fewer nearest neighbours
well if you what you're trying to do is to jump through that little narrow
saddle point waiting for those atoms to policy
going back of the way
the answer four-under-par
so this is like the difference between having to drive down an expressway
drive down the narrow city streets you got
got a much easier time moving quickly down expressway
right so we can see what the cartoonist trying to show is that
up at the top we see the rate of increase of the you
through the ball or we say it's lattice diffusion
classical lattice diffusion
down the grain boundary
at the same time we see a much deeper penetration because the material is able
to move
with less constrained
well on the surface it can move very rough surface diffusion is very very rapidly
here's some data
these are three different investigations of diffusion of silver
diffusion of self self diffusion
OK this is silver diffusing through silver
so this is classical what they call volume diffusion is what we would call letters
diffusion or walk diffusion single crystal silver moving through silver how would you make these
was the only way you could
identify once silver from another
after use radio tracer
OK so using radio tracer there are able to get some diffusion coefficient and you
see what they've done is the flip this around this is very wimpy this is
this is so when we look at what they don't these people the people the
plot of this are sold
this axis is you know
do you have any trouble figuring out the temperature is increasing in this direction and
you can think in one over t space this is how i feel comfortable when
i look an arrhenius plot i one negative slope in a straight line and what
they did is look at the numbers see the numbers they're sending from right to
because they were there so checking that they are afraid to have temperature rising from
right to left so what they do is they planted
the diffusion coefficient natural log diffusion coefficient but they've got one over t
rising from
right to left so that get positive looking slopes lines
very girly and like this
i don't like this
OK so
look at this here we have it first of all a very steep slope
very steep slope so that indicates a higher activation energy because we have a higher
lattice energy which would with which we have to deal
here's the grain boundary the grain boundary first of all it several orders of magnitude
higher and the slope is gentler indicating that we have less constrained and finally up
at the top we have the surface diffusion which has
i draw your attention to the values
we're down around ten to the minus a ten to the minus nine ten minus
in units of centimetres squared per second look at this surface diffusion
ten to the minus five ten to the minus four
here's diffusion in molten ferrous alloys ten to the minus five ten to the minus
four so what we've got here is a diffusion across the surface
it is on a par with diffusion in a liquid
so it gives you a very
a vivid demonstration of how a relationship between
the physical constraints of the lattice and
the diffusion coefficients so we can capture that by saying that the
activation energy for
what i've been calling both diffusion or lattice diffusion
this is a classical vacancy stuff OK
vacancy mechanism
OK via vacancy
this activation energy is much greater than the activation energy for diffusion along grain boundaries
which is much greater than the activation energy across the free surface
so what we see the trend in moving from left to right is
decrease in coordination number
decrease in coordination number which means
more freedom
as q goes down
the value of the goes up so all other things being equal this is for
let's compare apples to apples this for self diffusion
silver and silver ion
what have you the diffusion coefficient for
what it is today
i might say
this using machine learning
on pattern recognition and image analysis computer vision problem
my background is is on electrical engineering
searching physics
and i is being
computer science
the gradient structured background sometimes
make sure
bring together the different
the idea is entirely real ways but
but that's
that's basically what we are going to present day some all you can
use ideas from
ideas that have been floating around in in physics four hundred years
how can use those ideas to
solve pattern recognition problem
more specifically getting into the
the main topic of the long before
the basic
the theme of this talk
is called
i would call
structural pattern recognition
what some people call strong but the information
usually when you are concerned about pattern recognition problems
the basic
is to classify
some input
image better some put pattern or whatever
and you have
into some class so the idea is basically labeling
problem you want to assign labels
two different parts
so this is traditional pattern recognition problem
there are however
some particular types of problems especially in computer vision image analysis image understanding image processing
where this is not quite enough
it's not sufficient
to give the labels to a given path
what you actually need
is to tell
which part of this spot
corresponds to each part
another one
so for example
you have a face person can classify that as either the
or not
if i have for example
one face of one person in one image
one face of one person to another image
i can ask the question
whether these two faces come from the sum same person one
is the typical
pattern recognition question which is the traditional question that you would ask
but you can ask a stronger question this stronger question can ask is the full
here i have the left eye of this person
what is the left eye the other person how we find the correspondent
from every part of the first
to for every part of the second part
you might be wondering why this is important well try to convince you that there
are some
problem is important problems
in image analysis and processing computers where this is not only important
but this is actually essential
you can actually solve the problem
if you only give unlabelled
you need action
if you wish to give label
which party
of the body
you need to give to each part of the face a label in the order
in which which is
which kind of the other face
this part corresponds
so some people call this
the strong pattern recognition problem because
it's more difficult in the sense that you also want to perform some classification
but you have an inherently combinatorial problem to solve
because he's your partners are not
single part in the
now understood as being set collection
of small pieces of pottery
you need to find
correct sign
between this spaces in one part
the piece is in your court
so you introduce
a complex problem which is a combinatorial problem
and what will be talking today is exactly how
you can approach this combinatorial problem
in such a way that makes it you can
have your cake and eat it at the same time
in other words used to can solve the problem
without having
hypothesis so other three might be negative and then maybe the third generation you might
choose the second hypothesis again and so we have something to this up to two
so just i mean trivial
OK and then in the end you can compute but when you don t iterations
you can compute all the weights for four
four of us i mean all the others in the company
just this formula
let's assume i mean we always assume the base learner somehow minimizes this weighted training
OK so let's assume that maximizes that this was equivalent to the rates and operators
plus minus one
OK so it maximizes this ex
so it turns out that this is actually equivalent to finding the
the hypothesis which has the maximum gradient
OK so
the maximum gradient so the derivative of g with respect to alpha so this is
the gradient with respect to that direction
is simply this one here
so this is some so the the current d so the current waiting times hjx
and so this is exactly the
the edge of that hypothesis
OK so when you select the hypothesis which has a smaller and smaller training and
has the largest set that is actually the direction which has the largest creating component
this is exactly what postings doing whatever she was doing
gauss southwell method
OK we somehow uses based on this kind of article
to generate gradient directions
so in that of course also works when you have enough i mean huge posse
sets something like decision trees to tries to find one one hypothesis it hypothesis which
has a small training error and finds the gradient
we can
we go in that direction
OK so
i have to make the charts so
OK so in the general from the minimizer we minimize function and that function somehow
depends on on these hypotheses on the process rates and they maybe on some linear
terms so this is the most general setting going over here very quickly and essentially
would like to understand when these algorithms converge so maybe there's some conditions on the
on the function g here and maybe also some conditions on on the selection so
we would like to prove something
showing the convergence of that leveraging
we only consider the finite hypothesis sets
OK so
i find some conditions you i go over that essentially the base learner doesn't need
to produce
the hypothesis which has the smallest to largest edge but maybe something which is related
not so from not much worse than the largest at OK so
maybe let's say a
the largest which is this maximum here so it is
it's taking the maximum over all hypotheses in the hypothesis that so and it is
sufficient if the base learner adjacent iteration is just
i mean not much smaller than the largest edge OK so then that is OK
this condition is satisfied don't optimality
then we have this theory
given a training set of sample s and a
five percent have which is computation close the plus and minus have forces and then
if the gene function is strictly
strictly convex
and i can values are bounded from below
then we can actually show that this leveraging i with converges to the optimal solution
you know that
all of the
o thing going on
i mean you know
well need
as the
at all
o hold
i mean sure
i have
we are
what i mean
right right
right or
i mean
one i wrote here
if you look at this potentially this theorem is minimized on the circle where i
squared plus square is fixed the square of energy but there is a small lifting
of this circle degeneracy and the twelve IQ our one phi is plus or minus
hanover square giochi zero shot has to like you and you can write down the
kink solution
that goes from one to the other and it has this particular form it doesn't
matter so much more explicit form is but if you look at this field phi
it goes from one vacuum
crosses over to the second viking from left to right through the domain wall in
this case is separating two
now the important thing is that the we
of this kind of object is basically determined by the inverse minus of the elementary
quantum interference which one of them here
but the tension of the mass is much higher at weak coupling if you computed
here it's over g if g is small the coupling is small this is very
suppose you have one of these solitons and you try to think about low-energy excitations
in the background of this king
what part of these first of all you have the field can i remember the
phil kaye or you don't remember but you can see from the previous
transparency the field guy had no my s if you put phi the vacuum
this terms kill each other a exactly and there are only a guide to the
four terms interaction terms but enormous surprise the massless field induced by and therefore if
you to excite the system at very low energy you can of course
excited the field guide far from
this the main wall
but there is a second kind of massless low-energy excitation namely you can take the
king and moving very slowly or deform the domain wall had very long wavelengths and
this is also arbitrarily low in energy so if you think about the systems you
know they are at very low energies looking like the following thing some massless fields
in the bulk of running around some muscle is very low energy excitations localized this
domain wall and everything else is massive
actually and cheating a bit here because if you really do the analysis in this
particular model you will also find it acllon fields localized in the brain this corresponds
to the fact that there is a lot of tension more stable domain wall it
was a bit too complicated to write down that's why they're doing
but it's something here but nine it's the brain by q of that can be
curated by just stating the correct solution so
the effective low energy action has a very simple form if you compute here it
is some bulk massless field and some brain degrees of freedom here simply transverse fluctuations
of the brain they may have some potential in which also the bulk fields and
very few computed and plus everything else which is very massive
now in this simple example if you really want to do it as an exercise
you can of course do everything completely honestly you can just take the original field
theory was started with everything derives from there
sort of or write it in terms of diagonalized modes
of the quadratic operator in the background of the king and then think of this
as the new fields the you know i have to solve the equation for the
according to hearing eigen modes of the quadratic operator that there is only longitudinal coordinate
dependent remaining in the coefficients think of this as new fields do correctly you're expansion
and you find exactly what you expect me this
instinct theory unfortunately we don't know how to do this we don't have the analogue
of this very simple starting point if only
not but there but in lagrangian description of string field theory
nevertheless it is consistent
in every way people have checked to think of the closed and the open strings
as the bulk and brane localized modes in the presence of fish
and that's what will be doing in the next two lectures
in particular the low energy excitations of additional brain described by open strings of very
low minus
let's finally nothing by thinking about what these are
trying to automate the identification of this building on the right here has been born
this is very difficult actually in three dimensions to two
the pattern recognition
but there's a change detection here
it's much easier from higher up because you've got a problem of parallax
so the satellite the camera on the satellite is not exactly the same position in
the two pictures so you need to do a three d pattern match before you
can pay say that change
detection in the image
and here we got the lead at the airport in beirut
this is much easier to detect the bomb site
it just shows how accurate the israeli bombing was because there
hit every single intersection on the runway
OK now
before we get into the web mining techniques and so on i thought it would
like to review
the web
now i think he will think we understand the internet
but it's
it's incredible when you realize just how
new it is
if you think of communication
this is the diversion for about fifteen minutes
in the nineteen twenties they in the phone was invented
it basically it's still the case today people don't have phones
the mobile phone revolution was the one brought phones into africa
the the phone to
a very long time before it was
brought before it his adopted but worldwide
and he has a particular thing it's a point-to-point connection it's basically you can talk
to somebody at the distance that's all it is
the next big revolution will be saved broadcasting
radio before the war the radio not television radio
i took off the slow way
television came
from the nineteen sixties and now everyone is television but it took let's say for
forty years before diffused out into
every home
again the way to tell if it is important to realize the difference the way
we communicate
in fact we have a it's point-to-point connection were broadcasting
one person decides the content
and we'll sit there passively and look at it
and this is a very good easy to control the government can control what is
allowed on television et cetera et cetera
and so the if you think of before the way
it was very easy for governments to control what their people learned about it was
it's very
and for those who was easy to tap phone if you if you didn't if
you mistrusted someone it was quite easy to get together for
the web changed all that
i remember
seeing the web for the first time i think at the end of ninety two
somebody downloaded mosaic from NC CSA's website
and we looked at it and the impact of that first view
was incredible i knew you saw immediately that there was something completely new
and the the whole model of communication changed overnight so now
it was possible for you to publish information
and we had a situation where many people to publish information and there's a lot
of other people who
looked at it
so around nineteen ninety three
the web started to grow
i knew it would happen when i saw URL london bus
that was about two two years later before that was
basically just university researchers in in the in the internet
again it was basically a passive things web surfing the term web server with basically
people looking at other people's content few people publishing
then the say the commerce the dot dot net the dot com boom and bust
they actually had already got most of the technology
for e-commerce running
but why did it all go bust
the real reason was because they didn't have the band
now we talk about this new buzzword thing web two
what is it and you can read papers on the internet which will tell you
OK web two is all about social networking it's all about
it's say this new
technology which is actually just javascript it was nothing new at all hx four special
clients like google maps the and so on
and easy syndication RSS there are three things that they kind of
get lumped together in this web two
connection which is a social network sites are assessed and hx
all these things are nice
but really what changed is
what really changed was the widespread deployment of broadband
because it only became possible at that moment for you to really get involved and
published yourself so user
user interaction on the internet only really became feasible when broadband was it's in everyone's
today there about a billion users of the internet
and then
eighty percent got broadband
so now
is the that's why now this sudden boom in the in the web again
an interesting fact there was a survey done in february this year and
to estimate how much data is on the line
and we came up with this this estimate which was done
basically by sampling various sites and doing a rough estimate was came up with this
figure one point six times ten to twenty bytes
which is i believe one point six x but it's about a thousand million thousand
it's about a billion
it sounds huge number but if you if you think about avocados numbers
which is
three orders of magnitude bigger
is the number of molecules in one gram of hydrogen
it puts things in perspective because if you wanted to know if you wanted to
the volume is
i could play the song accounts were
well i expose about
synthetic bird to
those stimuli
using the sort of hierarchy that are just
yes yes it does yeah it sounds like it's very
famous sitting in the morning my garden but you sometimes hear these birds out there
is you know it's quite compelling
it is easy to actually just to freeze the right range and any
so reasonably
which normally counting
dynamics will will actually sort produced one or vulnerable strata
i would whistleblower the nervous about this right i did the
so it's not quite the
so this
well done here is just plot the variables namely these prediction errors and come poster predictions as functions
first this time
after the president or during the presentation of the stimulus at different levels in this hierarchy
at the top of the hierarchy must first furthest removed from these sensory input we
have these representations in the hidden causes and the true hidden causes
grey lines here some basically switching on the chair
by inflating attractor it cycles away generates frequencies and amplitudes from point attracted to
chaotic attractor here with true control parameters and the inferred control parameters are
the blue and the green here with ninety percent confidence intervals and they are formed by
the best explanation that minimizes the prediction error about the flow
of hidden states of the lorenz attractor
so this is the best explanation before all they accumulated changes in the flow of
the hidden states and the blastula hidden states when where they
called expectations about these flowers come from what they are
the best explanation informed by prediction errors
all of these actual dynamics of to those hidden states which are very
the amplitude and the frequency the sensory input so we have this recursive message passing
the has this separation temple scales has faster going on
showing these fluctuations in expectation and we get a higher level at the very
hierarchy here basically things we've lost the dynamics michaelmas perceptual categorization here
the one
this is the only one here
this is a standard chaotic system
there's a vast literature
which i don't know deeply that people to so many articles from time-to-time modelling both
these particular differential equations that show deterministic chaos at the level of these
the steering she's the voice boxes lots of work in a very fast time-scale tr
about the speech production but there's also a lot of interesting work in the high
and they actually see the high vocal center of songbirds
looking at sort of winner-take-all all sorts of
yes you could get
yeah there's nothing really special about that you know there's nothing really important about editors
deterministic chaos is just more it's more produce more realistic stimuli
the differential equations that seem to arise from
the competitive dynamics between the
distinct populations and high vocal center syncytia to show deterministic
but now it's just for fun
you could just use a and also switch on and off with this frequency and amplitude too
two properties
this is not
it is exactly a very good point so i you know so this is using
the grading the generalized bayesian filtering that presented in the first slide
the in the special case in which would be
kalman filtering
pound interestingly if
we replace block form of york of fewer of yours
and particle filter
with a single
guassian distribution
it would be i that this will be identical to what you're just as well
because only have one particle must be anyone me
expectation for having an arbitrary example from your point-of-view but mathematically we have a very similar form i think
yeah so this is basically filtering based deconvolution predictive coding
yeah yeah you
so is coming is generalized bayesian filtering bayesian deconvolution
this is predicated on the linear predictive coding device and he coding that have a
direct mapping to message passing in the brain it's they're all the same thing
absolutely so yeah what so this notion of all the helm the brain being helmholtz machine
could be articulated as simply saying the brain is doing a bayesian deconvolution bayesian filtering
all sensory input
what have to do that we have to minimize these
the difference between the free energy and surprise was happy about what has to
it has to be able to mean price to minimize its special states what is
actually about well because you have status
in this
all the
well it was a good question
it's your question
there's your question so how does the brain do do do you know
probability quasar i approximate bayesian inference on
problems such as weather forecasting all markets that
that's true
you know
you will well yes so there are two very good points first will how do
you know and is the experiment and in fact
i when looking attended my presentation but what i would have shown
is that one can regard action has performing experiments to optimize the model
i will speed through the slide show you about the
but was was the case that we don't have time to do but the the the idea is that
in order so so let me ask the first question and then i will explain why
you can regard
living as an experiment
to optimize your model
the best model
is the one that has the most evidence as like bayesian model selection so usually when you got some data
you want to
compare different models of how u hypothesize of all those data are caused so you
know if it was and whether forecasting could be deemed model with multiple you know
with lots of
hierarchical structure very simple you may want to bit sums variables
carbon dioxide made by their or not and then compare models
so the problem normally reduces all of statistics in terms of empirical data analysis reduces
to one problem it's the comparison of different models or hypotheses that the same data
those models are scored with the marginal likelihood of the basic model imprecise bayesian model selection
because free energy bands
the model evidence or marginal likelihood in ninety nine point nine a practical applications one
cannot and does not use the marginal likelihood of the evidence one uses the variational
free energy bound
so what you do is use choral compare different models
but may have a different form a different number of nodes and the number of
edges for example in graphical models
using these free energy
so this is the schedule for my part of the spring school so just the
first five days i don't know what's happening with
it too when when you divide
and some of you do biomolecular organisation and some of you do complex data analysis
i think one group remains here of one group there's another lecture theatre that you
but i'm not sure of the details
so i think almost everyone is
did everyone manage to eat some lunch
OK so one of the things that i mentioned
in the previous lecture fees
i sort of referred to the the degree to which we can take inspiration from
natural complex systems in our efforts to understand
complexity but also to exploit complexity in engineering
i like to here
the end of is israeli to give you a sort of whistlestop tour
through some of the more
impressive feats of natural complexity
and to talk a little bit about to what extent we can
what it means to draw inspiration from
so there are some
complex systems
by the way tomorrow we start to get to grips with what i'm meaning when
i say words like complex so don't worry
but i'm using them a sense today
there are some things that people might think complex systems in nature to you gotta
marine ecosystem species of fish and coral and plants here you've got a swarm of
insects i believe they're locusts of some kind
so you've got an image of the human brain
got developing foetus
here you've got a three to sort of physiological engineering
here you've got a special kind of ornamental cauliflower
about that well it was on the first page of things that you get when
you talk complex natural systems into google images that i thought it was quite pretty
it obviously sort of exhibit some kind of fractal results similar structure so
i mean these systems are very very different
i mean we're looking at different scales
and in the case this is an organ within an organism this is an organism
developing this is another organism this is the single organism but this is an ecosystem
this is the agglomeration of organisms
we're looking at very simple
creatures looking at much more complicated creatures
but we see
complexity what we would
i think of as complexity
almost everywhere you look in nature
i'm gonna concentrate on just a few examples and i'm going to that a bit
of rough ordering over them which i'll try to make it clear as as we
go on so for example the first example is gonna be termite mounds
so guy in africa and he is the man and made of mud by a
colony of termites
and he said
you know the more you think about these structures the more fearsome they look so
and and you can't really make sense of them to start comparing them to
the kind of structures that humans create
nothing human has formed a group of humans has built
approaches this would these i make the the large the the largest cathedrals built by
humans were built over many generations they weren't built over hundreds of generations by millions
of builders
working together by comparison to the size of the termite build a man like this
this is taller than is four times taller than the tallest building that humans
successfully erected and they're not just i mean you can see that they're structured you
can see that there are these veins running up and down the that structures just
incidental or attractive there's lots of stuff going on inside these mounds and the structure
of the mound is acutely involved in the ability of these mounds to the brain
regulate so the temperature inside areas of the mound is kept within working limits for
the termites the live there they also act as defence they practise some kind of
horticulture within them so there are chambers where they grow fungi fungi
they have to control not just the temperature but the climates within those chambers the
humidity there is very important in order to grow this fungi that they organise their
their young in crashes graveyards where they store the dead bodies or they move that
is and there's even some evidence so if you if you go up to one
of these termite mounds that's in use when you punch a hole in the outside
i've actually a termite will arrive or maybe there will be termites there anyway and
the first few of them instead of instead of trying to rebuild
so instead of rushing away to warn the others what they do is they get
when they but i think they detect it with because the the change in air
pressure and they start banging their heads from the termite mound
OK but it's been you know the sort of like wailing despair
but really what they're doing is alerting other termites to the fact that there's been
a breach in the wall of the and other termites are recruited to that area
and very rapidly you'll see swarms of termites and they do all of the building
there's even some evidence to suggest that the
material properties and the organisational structure of the mound has to had to be optimized
for its acoustic properties
supporting this kind of alarm signal
and then you look at the size of these tiny tiny little guys crazy
there are able to do this said
so there's not a lot of stuff that didn't make it into david attenborough's programme
which i think is quite interesting so that just got some pictures here that i
got from rupert's
web page
i mean
the undertaking that
the data got was pretty formidable i think they got
to six tonnes of plaster of paris shipped from south south africa to namibia for
free by some freight company that we've got some publicity out of that they had
to hire
you know tens of people on site to
a wrecked this
scanning and slicing machine
i mean it was it was a huge undertaking from what they ended up with
so that they revealed this three d structure obviously they there's the resolution there the
plaster of paris couldn't they couldn't recover the very very fine tunnels for the termites
use and they ended up with this CAD model
of reconstructed from slices of this that they took away
and really this structure is far too complicated for them to do anything with and
that's the problem they can't simulate
convection currents in it they can't explore its acoustic properties it's just too
and you can also play soccer
and these pages i got from the default is guy has countless animations and his
i definitely recommend you look at this so you know particles represent the position of
the ball in the position of the robot the robot to learning
i wish
trying to locate itself and marketable
and more impressive publication also beta
is the particle filter with the particle here represent an estimate of what the person
is in the city of seattle
i believe
and then the particle filter also represents another state which is
what it believes the person is guided to set to hierarchical setting with you know
what the person goes it helps you with the tracking
and then there's the sort of particles following the person and this detail was using
to actually help people with
some forms of dimensions on because you want to make sure to track them and
have an idea of what they're doing and detective there
maybe quarter on bus so that you can then intervene on the system
it is sort of one intervene all the time because they can be very annoying
and so you
you need to get good estimates of what's going on
and the type of model the that data has
is this something that looks more like this where you have some observations that evolve
over time
there's some discrete states the purpose and the unknown location and then there's this sort
of meta variable that indicates what the planets where this person trying to reach
and this type of factor representations have been used a lot with
particle filtering they use and also industrial set out in the negation
one important thing is when you have structure in the graph
should exploit structure as much as possible
and you should do analytical computations as much as possible
don't do monte carlo if you don't need to do it it's really and last
and indeed when we exploit structure these algorithms in terms of paris do incredibly better
the methods that are and will discuss
also applied to set perhaps in which number of nodes is changing over time
particle filters are very good for that they are able to estimate
the so called partition functions normalisation constant so we can do model selection relatively easy
compared to
how it's done with traditional methods like MCMC
the method is the real one really goes back to
the first paper of metropolis and column in nineteen twenty nine
it's like a four paper has so much and it was really worth reading every
sentence a few times
and of course there were interested in this kind of problems two
a lot of things
and this is the picture of the NES and the programs of the time
this kind of has changed over time
and and for moment actually
i needed someone to
according to algorithm invented importance sampling action is more later
she writes a note to someone and he says i believe one their computer should
be able to understand
these steps and inputs like line numbers and so on in the program
so some later he invented you know the architecture for these things
our computers
and many people have been involved with this starting with enrico fermi
for nine months or the metropolis who is actually the around metropolis with the code
that they
a young physicist they got the common cold is machine
and then became the famous metropolis in physics
a lot of them actually spend the rest of their lives campaigning for peace
and next
will start to the many people have worked on this matter and there's been incredible
amounts of work this in physics and in the world of phylogenetic trees in artificial
intelligence is really huge
the russians were too there is some of the redskins on the amazing things
over the last ten years artist and a lot of work in this manner
of the finally obtained dismayed feats can integrate which suggests that integration is part of
a unit did so is the ideal stimulus to keep an extension of the point
Delaney Clause space which is scored into the judge Jose Guillen and space where you
complex metrics although machinery parties with each additional missiles is you have to use updated
UHA which is something to hold so areas of as the state of symmetric matrices
so to an end mattresses on this and that he will produce a metrics and
other dimension to end on which the ways this relation and possible GM and is
equal to g with D which is due in the next
on the other are equivalent to the uh disease mattresses simply teach a week of
its 4 nation on in fact disease space is in value
by the loss of vision which is the fact that an extension of the modest
possible pitfalls of plant spaces uses it also may issue was 1 1 case of
gin artist will discuss permission that ABC on the hour Maddox on the longer Oscar
their value us all as he did last holds that exist literature is evaluated by
the fossil missions like just holds that also issuing on remove LZZ equipped groups relying
solely should stick to its but was able meanwhile is required to pay a housing
exactly is
she is not in fact Saluto makes is a party to offer case also this
of preach causes even if a white very interesting because you when you up is
to do everything E. Bush until that we reserve the only enough
pursuant to different was the role of general and factory ideas to Duke's disease can
be complex matrices on news expression of Yuan told computing is the distance between the
2 complex mattresses so we wouldn't get integrated they can you obtain Mr. result just
being operated by doing as well you also lose summation of the regarded logistic mission
where where are ads are in fact they begin value of this course facial his
club I should only older metrics said 1 the to computer again value on the
situation is a distant so when you have million notional a room in which is
different to you can said so again computers everyone on
you can compute the distance between the 2 which ignited the Xinhua that is there
is no room which is not there
so it is also which is scored a victory dormitory that would explain afterward we
use of Howie uses
this is a circuit on the that affect the symmetry could be deduced from deviation
of functions which is put on show in which is called the ghetto potential in
funding factories closing Quezon to showed that potential which are introduced direction of geometry aren't
you all cases we will use put on a show that in fact there's a
date most data winner of the metrics which is exactly is still Peters was position
who give idea is to give you can also use it as an extension of
the credit to transform the gods based extend the unity of injury he by register
for example if also point out that souls of more delegates which means a unique
ID and by its excretion fact Uganda take put on show at use log of
wouldn't to dig this would ensure and that you could do to help about 2
years the to put demanding which he is exactly the issue and the potential
please excuse to be the same case for the the property
so mystic space the branch of so lessons very simply do training that also called
on retrieve for example the local we aren't you from the complete with space so
near the use of the space of the symmetry visited the dignitaries is our citizens
distance is defined by December nation that you have a real introduced on all sorts
of ready space the complicated based on that verifies this certainly nominal
so inequality is pleased that I would just like to distance food as being produced
in 1972 by your country
I'll be displayed the bombs still owns the silly but still the dialog on the
suggested by the land will say is that fact the square are also died and
questions to devote all of innings most of
honors are demanding that educators and analyzes 123 colon
when it should be a magnitude to read 2 books
it's also from objects all former university but he's still the false 1 in English
with regard anyone and I want go oldest when 1 of is literal among must
only true written by strong and that these historical duty on the fact you have
closed in relation to all of during the course of because in fact out money
there is some loser could have predicted if democracy to be used in different amid
saloon number 2 reads was like what you know to really statistics and physics Stallings
a book of trouble you can see that work which is designed to use role
the following the chapter of include uses the characteristic function of according to cool in
the mind of missions so that you can use our opinions space at the university
said to be local entities speaks belongs to see on the numbers but you know
that makes didn't so it introduced a characteristic function which is this expirations which cheesy
and they were address space of 6 export not sure where are you know operates
but we at the end sort joint optimisation problem
when can find a consensus on the world is really sorry
part of the so that the final result is not only locally but also
it's a gaussian noise in the sky
with the pick survive
but i mean you can analyse what we want is always nice
bit more technically so
graphical models are essentially what call multi by probabilistic models why motivated because there are
many viable
in the case of the physics example i gave the many rivals were the many
atoms present in the material for every out have there's been was one or more
than one
in the case of an image
there are many variables are the many pixels are present in the image and they
interact in some way
but there is
that there is a structure in the dependency of these
of these variables
and this structure is given
in terms of article conditional independence they will see what conditional independence
morning formerly essentially the graphical model is
these are model that represents the system
it's part
and the possible relations
these but
in the probabilistic
in terms of which questions we would like to us when we have a repetition
there essentially four
at least four interesting question we would like to
two s
the first question is
usually will have a probabilistic model to get to the details later this they just
want to call it the big picture
will have a probabilistic model which will have some parameters like a statistical model with
and the goal one goal will be to estimate the parameters
we also
we collect from
real experience from real sense
real images that you think are real
gene expression
or real music
we want to estimate the parameters of far
this called the learning problem
the second question is interesting is that once we have these model how we all
things samples from that
i want to sample from model
well sampled from an image model is an image of sample from music
what is new is the song
sample from
a model basically is able to generate example
the dark side that it's actually model
thirteen that you would like to do is compute probabilities of particular outcomes
if you have a model that represents
how the weather
facing camera or
are useful wales region
you may be one question i would like to ask is what's the probability that
it will rain in camera and
will have
some into
so maybe you have created you have
you have once we have a probabilistic model of think of big databases
of probabilities
and then you can provide clear is that if are probabilistic and well you have
probability eighty percent of having trained camera
and so on
the type of of question that you may be interested in is find the most
likely outcome
again i can ask what's most likely to happen today
cloudy day
or sunny day
or rain what's the most likely
nothing to sing the probabilities i just want to know what the most likely
that's another type of query is
we want to
to perform
likewise in the case of the image denoising i have haven't noisy magical this was
the most likely
the noisy image
right because we want the only one
in which we want to see one corrected image and corrupted in
we could make sense maybe
i have a graphical model that represents the noisy versions of an image and that
we chose building noise the first thing is that the best noise version
that particular edge
also this fits into this find the most likely outcome
this is because of the four questions we are going to
mostly be interested when they have graphical up
i would just
make the connection with a very simple type one
and i will try to address those four questions
four a very simple kind of model which is not a graphical model or graph
which has a single line so it's not the multiply i
of facts
it doesn't
typical definition of graph
and is the model
this is
girl distribution
so this is a unified gaussian distribution
normalized means you don't have to
these expressions that you can see
it's basically the
expression for this function
you can see in the graph
you can
as those four question mentioned before for this particular very simple for
probably solution that you can estimate
for example
the mean
and the standard deviation
given the number of observations
if you know that the given process
the given to behave as function one viable
and you will attain
that process you can estimate mu
and sigma
and by the way you can do that is
some of you may remember how to do that actually that
estimate of
but i mean
is the maximum likelihood estimate for example mean
i think the smallest school and i wanted to be
so here for example
the black ones has to be wrong
and one
it should be clear that has nothing to do with who the position belongs to
it's completely out of the
colored by one
and like one
right so the question is
zero one circus
that's it
what this means it means that
so that whatever the other one
so is that
the choice
i don't know what you
will be made
but what about the MAP for young on
plus he so i want to play tool went to be system because it is
that the graffiti of analysis that the least one is even
this would question
if i take the columns
i think that this one either it's odd or even
know if it's even if they
zero who
i forgot sorry so
how the winner played
play one is
when the play
he says that the core or a is so that says that the least one
is even
that's the way
otherwise the play
it's not like this is also
players play one with
which we
so let's see what we have
here we go
so i feel
the phoenicians even on the slide
for the talk
you say OK so
i showed it to
partition will tell you more about this in the solution of the game being the
if i take for example
is set of nodes
i mean this set of
start from can choose any position
i have given you hear from so-called
a way to play
so when i'm here
my try to this
on this with the previous
so that's why it's so solid
i was OK
i have chosen be here and you have no interest
and here so i decided to go here
that's it
now you can check that
so from it
w zero
region four players zero
well we start
if i play
you know which is conformal to the strategy is small lanes world
have to check then you can trust me saying we started to come here
and then if he comes here
i come here
yes would be stupid to stick to this choice here
because i mean infinitely often the black
positions which is the one
so players you will win so player one
tourist play here so from time to time is a all over the place here
for a if you place here
it's easy for me to do
make of t plus
larger than fifty two mio by some margin
and we're going to train that by stochastic gradient descent try just
doing gradient updates with a given learning great for sampling triples around
i mentioned some prior work
using well actually using support vector machines perceptrons and even neural networks by chris burgess
and and co-workers where the user
hand coded features
in contrast here we're focusing just on using words and trying to find this representation
is also
several works on optimizing different loss functions like mean average precision in our CNN NDCG
and we're not looking at that here but you could train these models and presumably
with any kind of loss function
there's also other workers similar to this by a bengio called pami for retrieving images
we use
basically percent margin ranking perceptrons
with degree two features and they don't easily rank models
and there's also something called hash kernels more recently where
again the kind of degree two features are taken but they didn't into a smaller
set of features so things scalable
we can compare to that as well
this follows some experiments comparing some of these things we can use wikipedia so is
around two million documents and twenty five million links and this is what we're going
to use is going to pick a random document as a query
and then rank the other documents
and the documents the hyperlink to it should be highly ranked
so we're going to split the data into training and test
using that kind of preference relation can take two setups one where the whole document
is used as a query and one where phi ten or twenty words at random
from from the document used as a query to mimic keyword search
so here are some results on
document document ranking first first we limited our dictionary size to thirty thousand words so
that we can train the margin ranking perceptron on the degree to features because otherwise
the things too big to fit in memory
and you can see there are several types of error rate reported here but if
i just concentrate on the ranking loss
which is the percentage
of times that the preference relation
is the wrong way round a d minus is above the plus the test on
the test set of preference relations that we can see that the output TFIDF this
is this is like the cosine similarity
and then we have a list sorry
and the site where you add
where you don't just have the embedding space also the cosine similarity to in these
things are all inferior to supervised learning on this task so
the last two races of the
degree two degrees three neural network models but i showed and they
perform a little bit the margin ranking perceptron and
they also use much less parameters
so you can see
these are in like two hundred dimensional
embedding space
so that's the difference in the number of parameters
and then if we look at
training on
all the words in the dictionary two point five million
we can use the margin ranking perceptron any more but we do use hash kernel
approach and we get the same kind of
the results
and then we look at query document ranking this is where we picked either five
ten or twenty
keep k keywords at random
we have compared to everything there
but you can see what we get the same kind of
kind of observations
so it's not because we use the whole documents as the query
and then finally we have in our experiment in wikipedia you have lots of languages
actually so we thought it could be found to take silver cross language retrieval task
so you take a japanese query and then you trying to retrieve english documents that
should be relevant for that query if you had translated it well
so the the
the method has to do somehow implicit translate either explicit or implicit translation
so if you do explicit translation using
so good good good tall
and then the cosine similarity you get like four point seven percent
ranking loss on this task and there's a method called which is developed specifically for
this task has around three percent and then we have two versions of neural network
that we took from the slides before
it was trained actually just on the english
document english query task and we just use the translation tool and then and then
and then apply the function and is already better than the other methods but if
and they can over the observation
and now we have the decision problem
over an extended state which includes
the physical state transition counts
and the observation count
and so
we can set up a full
upon the model based on this
i have my extended state space
physical state counts
the other accounts
action observation
stay the same neck and define the joint observation action function which is defined in
a certain state
because certain actions as certain observation with my next state
the reward function stays the same
it's just another part of the problem where the goal is to maximize the return
under partial observability of my state
there's nothing different
in terms of formulating the model
is a little bit of the complication compared to the MDP state
so what's the complication
you have an infinite state MDP because my counts
the very big with a known model
you have an infinite state
MDP with a known model state is defined over the state of the finer over
in this case i every time step my state is observable
and my count phi is is updated and the party at every time step
this is not observable
so my counts are not observable
i don't know which state i went from two
so i don't know which count to update
that makes things a little bit tricky not in terms of the model the model
is super clean
but in terms of using this in practice we need to deal with that little
bit of complication
which is how can we be these counters how do we know
where to get the credit for certain transition
all we know is what action was taken on what observation was perceived but we
don't know the states
and i dirichlet distributions are defined based on the state
not to worry this is the classical problem for upon this is the reason learning
in palm piece is so much harder than learning in mdps and one lord of
the focus so far in the literature has been strictly on planning for the part
of the case
will just
turn out upon the machinery here instead of having a belief state only over the
original state space but also have initial counts
and we also use some
a way of monitoring the belief
and the belief now will be expressed over the states and over the counts
now to define the beliefs over these counts we need to sort of hypothesized that
when i see this
it could be because
this count needs to be updated in this case needs to be updated so we
need is a mixture of dirichlet models which tells you all of the different jewish
those which could happen
and that gives us the way to
update this
upon the model using standard bayesian inference
from a practical point of view maintaining that mixture is a little bit difficult because
the number of components in the mixture
grows quickly the more things you do
the more different ways your account could be updated so it doesn't clearly very elegantly
here t is you're planning horizon
so a little bit problematic in terms of
planning horizon
before i tell you
how we can make this tractable
i'll just mentioned two quick theoretical results that come with this probability model
this is the slide with a lot of complicated math
it's not really complicated result that slide says
assume that you are interested in estimating the value function for specific physical state
specific count vectors
and you want to compare to the same value function that same physical state but
slightly different count vectors
can you bound the error in the estimation of this difference
now here comes the complicated expression but those four parts to that complicated expressions
the first part says that
difference really depends on
expected value of the two count vectors
so i have my to dirichlet distribution
phi and phi prime in expectation are going to be a little bit different
that term an expectation the size are going to be a little bit different
and these two terms just says well that's all fine and dandy but in some
cases phi and phi prime are the same in expectation
but the magnitude of the number of counts is different and so that term just
deals with the uncertainty in the dirichlet distribution over the transition in certain in the
dirichlet distribution over the observations the estimates you have to have you as you have
more and more counts
this starts going away but for small numbers of counts you still need to put
that into play
so this is over the value function
so this is the first theoretical result this is something we can measure it seems
big complicated into
expression which isn't very useful
it turns out that expression
comes at the core of one of the approximation methods we use and being able
to bound the difference really helps us figure out how to approximate the mixture of
two more slide
the second theoretical result that comes with this framework is the following one
so so far i've told you that i can bound the difference in value function
when the physical state is the same
but the accounts are different
what i'm telling you here is
given that i have some
value function
at some state
count how different is that in terms of
the correct value function
and i've thrown in some projection operator here if you want a formal definition that
you can go in the paper the point here is that this is the case
where the counts are going to be bounded to some opera value
so we're interested in say
what five down my counts to sum up value
i compared to the case why don't the counts
because in the infinity for the counter and outfielder really well
practice you might not want to do that you minus one to stop early so
so it's a worthwhile for
asked to produce a white paper specifically talking about vocabulary mapping and
so stop
i wanted to show
as an example of the sort of coverage that you get some random called tag
decide terms not
not disambiguate bombers might mean submarine sandwich for example somewhere
but also might mean one plane which does
so now
large is going to
so you're better about how you represent this in
so it's meant to refer to as
this is not
it's not
it is
so that
but think
it is
it's like that
in some areas
you can get
it's something fairly
fairly wide coverage that had
the areas which are more didn't see there there are a few areas which has
no coverage whatsoever
but there are certainly areas which are densely covered in the areas where the first
part of it because we never
really had an opportunity to do something like that for
two and ingram list sorted by water and representatives that you know i would like
to have an opportunity to do that i would dearly like one of you to
take on the task
doing that would be very useful thing to do community
so it is very useful for
and means in wins
because of need to for was very it's kind and it's difficult to imagine
what need that's sold
because was not and you that's
that will be because
he then went
not show how the
content on the at page codes
the available as our or for some of us
one the things
if you go to
o was i got was that the org
and you would search for a left-handed person responsible for left-handed person this is the
page you get
it looks like
normal HTML page
but if you check the source
you would actually that's idea
with some
this formation applied to transform it into art
the whole thing
but as shown obvious how we go through this hard source actually look like
just to give some context so the page is about left the person
which is this personalisation of homo sapiens
an instance of
left-handed person is a human who favours
his or her left and so this would be
now if you open but
if you go to the internet in and out of the page
this is what you
so one
the works
OK so this is what you get if you go to the web page and
see the source of the left-handed person
that page
so what we do is we have that each concept in opencyc is assigned a
unique IP
so this would be
so this would be this
everything here
this is a unique idea
for this concept
OK so far and this is
was this song
the first to have some assertion about
it's an ontology from
so to cyc ontology concept
external ideas on
so what does so
this concept is a class
this thing so this is a left-handed person
and if you check the content
you see that it's has the labour left-handed common human
this is the common to the data before loudly
so that its
all instances of this personalisation homo sapiens is also this is just for humans
then have an increased level this would be the predictive text so before
it's a subclass of the thing as check what this thing actually is this
is a new idea of the
concept as concepts
many of these
and here we have links to other ontologies the same as
this concept in
number and
open circuit
it's the kind of also link it to
the total number
two side that come to wikipedia and so on so
this would be different
here are some more
transcripts of this can be set so it can be left
we live in a person
and then if you go down here
some more assertions about this
which is similar to
vocal that we're talking about and can is that these are the primary
representational channels each of us
has a preference it's only a preference we have all of them
we have a preference for one so
some of us
are visual
we have a preference for the visual sort of thinking some of us or auditory
where pressure or preference for sort of sounds
and some of us are can is that if we have a preference for feeling
i mean just take you through some of these
and then how you can use this when you communicating with people
so these are the three
that we're going to talk about three weaponisation channels visual auditory and can setting
if you're talking to a visual person
you should be using visual types of words
because this is how they think
so use words like well you see what i mean
does this look right
can you just picture this imagine
do you see what i'm going with this
if i'm talking to you in your visual
it will make more sense
and if i talked to another way now for those of you who chose number
one of course
in your preferences probably visual
because if you look at the description
how houches house is picturesque you can see that a lot of focus
has been put on the colourful paths in the garden area it a lot of
window space so you can enjoy the view is clearly
i've purposely injected a lot of visual words in there so if that was your
it's probably likely that you're visual sort of think you have the others as well
but this is probably your preference instead and then if you have a very strong
one two three
you have a strong preference here
right so you are number one and you have a very strong preference was this
is good this is a good for you to understand that you're probably strongly preference
to visual
if you're talking to an auditory person you want to be using
sound type the words
so does this sound right
the strike chord with does this resonate
we on the same wavelength
i'm very old tree
i was going to say this sounds right this
this makes more sense to me when someone says all we on the same wavelength
when someone says can you see where we're going
with this
that doesn't resonate with me
these these words to
so if you chose number two you'll probably
strongly preference toward auditory
the house is very soundly constructed
and situated isn't such a quiet area that all you here
when you walk outside of the sounds of the birds singing it's a story book
in terry tells us so much character you probably find yourself asking
how you could pass ever passed by
did anyone have a very strong preference for number two
a lot of not very strong but maybe a little bit so my mind would
have been mind would have been strong for the number and then the third disc
so this sort of words you be using when you're communicating took anesthetic person
i just feel for this does is describe
can you get a handle on this
to feel what
and if you chose number three
you probably
recently candes that because of the words i use the house has a really special
feel to it
it's not often you come into contact with the place that touches
on so many important features is spacious enough you to really feel like you can
move around freely and yet cosy enough that you want where
yourself and taking care of it
did anyone have a very strong preference for number three
not a lot of particularly i added OK
have a look at this picture
what strikes you
what strikes about this picture
she reckoned
and our friend bush
same gestures
they look as if they could be talking in same time what can't tell but
it does look
if you if you had to say yes or no
would you say that these two guys in this picture
look as though they have rapport
so if you look at the face
it doesn't look so i mean sure and looks a little bit
bush laughing is
it's not like hierarchies series and bushes laughing
there but slightly leaning slightly leaning towards each other
which is an interesting
interesting position to be in and of course the hands both of them are using
their hands
body language is important so
so far we've discussed is it's important to
the subject you're talking about is important
to have something in common
so if i were to
things like emcee see epee variational methods
and even another new
inference algorithms can be used on the same model
so you really need to have the toolbox of
four your models the understand and are comfortable with like calcium distribution plus on distribution are you know
an infinite mixture whatever components in your toolbox of components
you put them together in a way that makes sense fourier application
and then you say how do i do inference in this and then you go to
we are separate toolbox of inference methods and if one of them doesn't work try a different one
and i think it's sort of important to make this distinction just because sometimes
analyzing something is much more complicated if u mesh together the model and the algorithm
so you know i'll just get some points for discussion
so the first few points are
just kind-of
you know
my personal
views on some myths and misconceptions about bayesian methods
i don't wanna rant about this too long but i think it's useful to kind of
have them on the slide to be able to talk about them
one of them is that
you know i sometimes see people who are
mean perhaps a bit naive about modelling say something like i really like not comfortable
with bayesian methods because you're making all these assumptions i want methods that don't make
and i here this surprisingly often
and i mean the answer there is on methods make assumptions
in order to do anything
that involves predicting you have to make some sort of assumptions
if you don't make assumptions the only thing you can do
you get your dataset and you spit it back
you know you the identity map you know these
the same data
you say is it all up to you what my model is i saw this data
that's my model that's the only thing that doesn't make any assumptions okay
so without assumptions is impossible to predict with a bayesian
framework does is it forces
you know
almost obsessive
transparency in your assumptions you've to write down all the assumptions
in the language a probability theory
what that means is that then people look at it and your assumptions are so obvious they start questioning them
actually i think that's a good thing
right if if everybody had to be forced to write down their assumptions
common language then we could all question each other's assumptions
and that you know you would get different answers given the same data that's because people make different assumptions
so whenever i see a message that i don't understand i try to figure out
what are the assumptions that went into the math that what behavior with this meant
that have
and so on
okay here is the second misconception
which is something like if you know i don't it comes in the following form
and really like bayesian methods because i worry i don't have the right prior
if i don't have the right prior
you know
i want to very well
and it's certainly true that you can really badly abused bayesian methods
by putting in ridiculous priors but this and there's no such thing is the right
prior from a subjective bayesian point of view
certainly a poor model
any kind whether it's the prior part of likely apart whatever
aspect of your model if it's a bad model
then it's gonna make lousy predictions
so the point is how do we guard against their
the model
all components over the prior and likelihood
should capture a reasonable range a possibilities
and you can only
do that's perhaps by some introspection some
intuition about what these distributions are
and then some maybe sampling from your pryr
when in doubt
you can choose vague priors
it shouldn't stop you just because
you don't know
something you should stop you from saying was a reasonable range i'm sure you can
come up to a point where we say on that's unreasonable
i don't want to know
range from minus
ten million to ten plus ten million that's just silly
so at some point you will be able to
specify a range
here is another misconception a lot of people
associate bayesian methods with maximum a posteriori
so map is similar to regularisation
but really offers no particular bayesian advantages
in fact i would rather do regularization then map
because regularisation at least i can analyse within a nice
thinking about regularization
kind of unfortunate
aspect that u
might actually think that i'm trying to do something bayesians
in fact what they
troubling things about maximum posterior is the following
maximum likelihood
is invariant to re-parameterization okay if i take
maximum likelihood fit more calcium
and i say
instead of parameterizing it is mean and variance i'm gonna prime traded prime prime tries it mean
and log of standard deviation
the maximum likelihood fit
is still exactly the same it's it's invariant a re-parametrization
map is not invariant to re-parametrization
so whether i call that the variance or standard deviation log-variance actually matters when i do map
that's just seems terrible
right that's totally irrelevant information it shouldn't matter
in fact
give me
any simple problem
and any value for the parameter
and i can really re-parameterizes
the problem so that the map lies at that point
the way you do that's by the way if you try to think about it
is you re-parameterized in a nonlinear way
so you squeeze
the privatisation around point so you density your your your prior will have to go
up and your posterior will go up around the point and you stretch it out
everywhere else
and then my map now will be point
so this just seems perverse and you know for that reason we should be careful about map
and the importantly from a practical perspective it doesn't offer the advantages averaging over here uncertainty
o people don't seem to like bayesian methods because most bayesian papers
i don't have a lot of theorems and proofs that he ended them
therefore look like
i ran the same ciency and then i did this and then here's a plot
it just doesn't feel as hardcore math here whatever