so these these we want to have a monitoring system which will take the CPU
measurements for everybody the network measurements from everybody and try to find anomalies and outliers
and forecast potential problems so that we can pull out this
this unit
so this is the problem and the motivation
two subproblem similarity search and data mining so let's see the first problem how do
we do similar to search through indexing and feature extraction let's see the index first
so we have here's the problem given a set of multimedia objects and let's focus
on time sequences for illustration
right we want to find the ones that are similar to a desirable query remember
we have the stocks this is not microsoft stock so that we don't laugh and
and this is another part right and want to find everything that is within ten
dollars away from
from the red part
we have to figure out what a good distance function how to measure similarity between
time series how how do you measure similarity
these are all the same length three sixty five sixty five right
it turns out of the best of the fest until it comes to your mind
he is actually correct and probably the first time series
the euclidean distance right some of different some of the differences squared right so the
euclidean distance makes alot of sense
other distances exist like some of absolute value differences and so on but there are
performing about the same there's also the time warping distance
which says that you can accelerate and decelerate but the the the query patterns
but for stock prices this is not
this makes no sense for voice it doesn't make sense to accelerate and decelerate so
some expert gives the distance function and usually the euclidean distance and want to solve
the problem
the problem is so well defined right if we want everything within ten dollars distance
away that we could even solve with sequential scan right take the first
the first sequence compute the difference between the partners it below ten dollars yes OK
print it is it above ignore continue right so this is a well defined problem
how could do faster right if we have one million time sequences each of them
being three thousand time ticks along this might take a lot of time right how
could we do faster than that
and the idea is
but we could extract a few features
instead of keeping all three sixty five days for overstock we could have a quick
and dirty description of every time sequence so we could of one set of features
not necessarily the best but good for the station is to take the over and
the standard deviation if those stocks have completely different operators and completely different sound vision
there's no way that would not
mike stock is average five you actual stock has other one thousand
there's no way they could be within ten dollars from each other so this a
once we had a few features taliban other deviation every stock price becomes appointing two-dimensional
space are quickly becomes another point in two dimensional space remember the queries are in
query want everything was in ten dollars away support this aquarium and right so then
we are we have transformed the problem into an geographic problem special problem find all
the city is about ten kilometres away from my favourite city right
and the good news is that there are a lot of reasons which will help
us understand the geographic which is so here is the outline of the
the methodology whenever we have in multimedia
similarity search problem what we can do we can extract we can sit down and
i o thing can't extract a few features two three four five features
right numbers that will describe our in our stock prices images video clips someone
by once we have done that then every in munster stock price we took it
becomes appointing two three four five dimensional space then we can use off the shelf
spatial access methods sams as they called
to find the qualifying images there's a footnote here we may have false alarms but
we can always discard false alarms right
using the exact the euclidean distance or whatever the domain experts said the correct distance
the method has been used for time sequences and the features that were extracted was
the discrete fourier transform it was used for modifications to the euclidean distance were offered
by like his and his colleagues and then back to mendelssohn and the woodruff and
so on the method has been used for images of the cubic project of IBM
which will see later again two more like stage four video clips showing for media
for automobile parts shapes in germany
kriegel from university munich and his colleagues and so on and so forth so let's
a little bit about special xmas because this is one of the
a wonderful methods that can withstand that withstood the test of time so they deal
special xmas methods we have a collection of cities
right and we want to spend money on state of the united states and want
and define recursively as so that that's an easy definition there
there are more general ones but this one is that the easy one
where that that that man is seen as a sum plus or minus one
the the elements of the first line times are the minor
of the matrices of the metrics with that these minor is
is the metrics without a line and without
rope without row without for example here
for tree by tree matteris you see here we have first element
then this minor second element and the matrix form by this vector
and this one thirdelement and so on and so on
so what's interesting about determinants
is it's air related to inverse matrices so i go to inverse matrices
so inverse much is our define so as much as a is called
non-singular ought evert invertible if there exists
a matrix b such that the product of these two metres give
the identity and if these b exists so
the inverse of our is not i'm in one needs to be
so what is interesting is that if the determinant of my matrix
is non zero then i know that my matters is invertible
which give me
if i have n equations with n unknowns
give me the solution of my in equation by inverting
the matrix so if i have no one hundred by one hundred metrics
equation problem i take the metric say look if he's determinant
is nonzero if is non zero i directly have g here the solution
of my my in equation so let's let's go back to the
to the geometrical view and in which the determinant in fact it's
at that the surface form by the two column vectors of my metrics
in that to dimension of course introd and nations cated and
so yeah and it's easy to verify if you if you go to for our
polar are called coordinates
what you see is if if my two vectors are calling yeah as a so
before the determinant would be zero because the surface
it's a completely flatten so just to to verify that what we were
saying before held for that it's ok so what happened when that
that was when metrics a is a is a square it's easy we take the inverse
but what happened with it's easy to is rectangular
we take the pseudo-inverse scald so the inverse
and yeah so that's health for any and matrix
providing that's eighty times a is invertible course
i'm talking about rectangular trees there is one which is really
interesting which is a bit already talk about today
which is the metrics where i take where each line
is one of my examples and that are
the so as i said before that scalar product is something which
are really interested in because it is
related to the distance between our
vectors so one matrix which is also of interest is the gram matrix
where each component it's that the the component
i j is the scarpa looked of the vector of the example a i t
times the vector the day example j
also or something which you always reading books
which is the the metrics i'm considering must be positive difference
if needs which on means in fact that the
billionaire form which when i'm taking a vector and non zero vector
and i a which plate left side and right side
my metrics it must be a positive or zero
and gram matrices are always positive semidefinite so that's one
one thing you always do you there's a lot of theorem that holds
if matrices positive semidefinite and
we we we want often machine learning top plate to gram matrices
which hopefully are positive semidefinite so
no the only person to think about it
ok so for example this metrics we sometimes want to
raise it to the poer to see what would be the distance or something
created the distance not between two vectors but
between these vector and so one passing true though me once so the
distance the path to go from one to the other
in tree in treaty times so it's interesting to to be able to raise
to the to the to our and for that matrix degradation is really
is is really something you want to do
so and eigenvector of matrix a is a solution
a non-zero solution of this equation
which cannot see it can also be seen as
in fact i want to find the environments kind of the invariants
of my application a so that if i look at the metrics as an
as a linear transformation what happened to these eigenvectors dane
fact are just striation stretch but not
they don't change direction honest stritch so
it's close to invariants idea so of course these it's equivalent
to these with i being the identity matrix
an eigenvector has associated eigenvalue so for solving that you
first go to the view through the the cursor sick polynomial
and solve this which is yeah the support
about supervised i
like the fisher discriminant i support vector machine that supervised by
so in these are good admitted that are available for a lot of examples and
their associated correct answer
i want to find the idea of learning is to find anybody sh drawn from
an opportunity for space
i'm sorry but so the idea of learning is to find i know but this
is a draw from mine portland point based such that it performs well on the
training but also to construct the well known as the labelled from y
from a new test sample x
in the traditional supervised learning setting this is the function is a map from an
input space from two n out space
the regression the output space is simply there is a set of real numbers can
be binary classification
the output space is set plus one minus one of labour's plus one minus one
in multiclass classification
the output space is the set one
we have k classes
what is structured output learning from the output learning contd
it uses the same idea to learn map h from input space to an output
space but consensus considering more complex output spaces then they once considered by regression classification
why structured output learning well there is the need of structured output learning
because because many problems are in many application requires dealing with structured data
that can be represented by sequence of by graph or was simply by images
and these happen in many fields like computational biology computer vision natural language processing
structured output learning framework has been developed to cope with this problem in a principled
and and know to be able to to
three the director there
probably without losing the information about
this tract
i give some example of structure and named entity recognition NE one example we have
for example in this case the sentence
spanish sentence and we want to find for each word in the sentence at time
and that indicate for example name of location organisation
and since then we you can approach this problem as simple multiclass classification problems where
where we have
a set of four percent of the value of but that there are the war
and we have set that the the top
we can
we can compute to each label for each one severity
but it will be you will be
but if we can compute the all the label of sentence together in order to
take into account the interaction between ideas and not others and
problem can be somehow addressed the sequence labelling problem we are given an input sequence
x i want to stress that the set labels of equal length
in this supervised learning framework what want to do is given a training set of
correct phase of sentences and their associated that we want to learn to assign new
and it is from a new sentence
another example of structured output problem either biological sequence alignment when we have to see
sequences the biological humans i want to deter mine dissimilarity between them
and bioinformatics given to see when is a global alignment is an assignment of gaps
such as to line up each letter in one sequence it with a gap or
a letter in the other
this is an example of two two sequences and an associated alignment what we have
for example you know that the match between the two sequences
through the gaps and green there
i means that
in general be given to see when we have an exponential number of possible alignments
can be represented in a compact way as but into a graph
it is usually referred to as the alignment graph by the possible alignment correspond to
part from the upper left corner to the lower right corner
from unsupervised learning point of view what we want to do is given a sequence
where we want to be able to predict the correct sequence of alignment operations so
the currency was of matches mismatches gaps
the that example is for RNA secondary structure prediction
and given any sequence and want to be able to predict the most likely sequence
that is that there is that there is some of the funding of the sequence
on itself due to either it in my
this problem is can be approach has a sequence parting problem so given an input
sequence x one to deter mined in society part the y
having defined an appropriate context free grammars
can't speak either
he invented a set of
know that you seem like a set of nineteen model and the set of rules
and the starting symbol for example on
and given the sequence x y is an example of possible
from the point of view also provides
we want to address the problem or any secondary structure prediction in this way
given a training set of correct RNA secondary structure we want to learn the might
be able to extract the most likely secondary structure for the new
any sequence
i do address this problem in a principled way
we extend this supervised classification does to want to be able so this time again
a training set of input output
but this time in the out put the it's multilabel it's complex
again we want to find out you like but this is a page that is
the market from people input space from two outer space
such that it performs well on the training set and is also able to
construct the optimal level of the optimal output for a new test sample x
usually is
started out with the old people do is to define a scoring function that is
a linear function
of some features phi
the defeat of some
mapping joint parking of input output five
w again the vector of parameters that we want to
and the predictions e
given new
right and frankly we tried this model and it wasn't working very well for us
and sometimes people call these models do doing harmoniums
so we need to go beyond so what we're doing here is we're using a
class of models called deep boltzmann machines
from edible which you can think of them as just markov random fields
u half
latent variables but you're introducing dependencies between hidden variables
right so what changed from the previous model is that you having these two additional
terms and these terms and modeling dependencies within each one image to image to image
did so explicitly
putting dependencies between latent variables and all connections undirected and in this case it's a
much more expressive model than the simple are began
but also it's a little bit more complicated because hidden variables become dependent even when
you conditionally so it will play
a little bit of when we start learning these models it becomes a little bit
more challenging to fit these models but again
they much more expressive so now what we can do in terms of building a model
is we can use
does not be an essential to model do
that's real valued image features we can use replicated softmax all what count data and
we can build ourselves a hierarchical model here
okay one nice thing about these deep boltzmann machines
in this case multimodal tables machines is that there is a very natural notion of bottom-up and top-down
right so information can flow from the low-level features of words all the way
down to the low level feature representation of images
right so it's it's unlike some of the other models like deep belief networks and neural nets type of
type of models
now in terms of learning let me just give you a preview of how learning
is being done with these models
we can
do approximate maximum likelihood learning if you look at the negative log probability with respect
parameters in this model it comes down to being the difference between two expected terms
so it's expected sufficient statistics driven by the data minus expected sufficient statistics driven by
the model
in this particular case unfortunately even expected that is sufficient statistics driven by the data
you cannot compute in closed form
because you've dependencies between hidden variables but there are ways of life fitting these models
and effectively so using mean field approximation set of expectations and we using markov chain
monte carlo
all what's called stochastic approximation algorithm to approximate the second set of expectations
and i'm not gonna get into much in the theory behind it but you can
show almost sure convergence guarantees under certain conditions of all of this learning rule to
as particle asymptotically stable point of the variational lower bound so some nice theory behind
these algorithms and and you can prove
certain properties about them
but now the question is how well does that doesn't do right so here's again some a few images
this is condition on images generating text from those images
and most of the cases it doesn't capture
meaningful structure right so that's capture what
what you see and there is always a bias towards canada
right because this model was created in canada
in any case there are also some feelers right so the model is not perfect and here's some
daily examples
if you're looking at this slide things as it is just basically
women soldiers right and now impression of that's because this is the flickr dataset most of the time people
post pictures of
themselves and follows as opposed to pictures of animals right
i also like the second one
you confuse it with barack obama election in politics and
my student convinced me that it's is because
you know
obama signs typically carry blue and white
science also it's making a mistake here
but i have a different theta i think if you just keep looking at this
picture for long enough you would you start seeing hope and change in
and obviously the model that's the right the right choice here
you can also do
the other way around so this is the case where we can
it because it's a generative model again we can sample from one delta conditional another
modality and again the model he's initialize the completely random state so here we're gonna
be generating cars and auto mobiles and such
you know it
one interesting thing about these kinds of walls notice how fast the markov chain mixes between different modes
right and jumps between pictures that are very different from each other
and sometimes it gets stuck for a few iterations but then it doesn't move around
quite quickly so there is a conceptual wisdom market chain monte carlo methods are very
in this case it doesn't seem to be the case
right so that's that's the reasonable job
right and that's
well that's not in terms of some of the examples given some text these images
that the model is generating retrieving
in some cases again the failure modes here if you look at the very last
wrote in in the query he was chocolate cake so it retrieves
even though again i would argue these cannot look like chocolate cakes right always you can make stuff up
but now
one other thing about this model is at
and if anything about this model is that
we can
leverage large volumes of unlabelled data to train these models and there will be crucial
in our applications so we can train these different e pathways separately
now in terms of just let me give you a couple of
examples and give you some quantitative evaluation of this model
this was done using a my we dataset you have about one million images
with users assign tags so we have images and text sometimes they meaningful sometimes they're not
in terms of the kind of architecture using
we have a multimodal dibble's machine with about twelve million parameters
and about six million latent variables hidden variables
in terms of features we using just joseph impact of about four thousand five dimensional
image features we use in two thousand
constitutes the instance level
defining the tee box as well as the a box areas
languages have been standardized so
the original language is
the language of description logics
i mean i think now for say five years the world has discussed the web
ontology language the recent version is OWL two and fall to various sublanguages has been
defined that are suited to different application areas
as you may have seen it is useful to also
holds about particular instances concerning
the relationships
of the classes and relations of instances between classes so
also we need a query and manipulation language we might want to interactively modify
the relations between individuals right
in the
ontology community there are various standards for querying and manipulating these instance or terminological searching
such as dick one two l API or reason standard that is called a link
having defined an ontology consisting of terminological as well as a search knowledge
we would like to have all queries answered and this is then formalised as a
set of decision problems so for instance we might query whether the ontology might make
sense at all so if we impose restrictions on the meaning of the primitives that
we have chosen then it might turn out that they are contradictory in the sense
we defined restrictions such that we determine there is the concept that is a sub
concept more specialized concept and another concept this is usually known as subsumption
might also be able to find implicit facts about what we have said for particular
instances as you see
solving these incidents
these decision problems we need
reasoning engines and so usually there are reasoning services for the
class level for the t box as well as for the
a box
projects deal with how to make this
effective and how to provide for
scalability i will not talk too much about the details about the reasoning engines
i will talk about
way ontologies are used such that to get an impression what can be done in
your local area of expertise with the technology
usually one doesn't write down
ontologies is using a textual language one could do so
in an editor but usually one uses
ontology editors and
one of the most well-known editor is the protege editor and i have
opened the main protege window here so you can assume that i uploaded
some university ontology into the system and then i can use the produce facilities to
add some axioms
there are many people
in the world the just defined the model
and our
not really aware of that the model might be
unsatisfiable that is to say it doesn't make much sense or their implicit things that
machines could to dig out so many people use ontologies without ever exploiting reasoning facilities
i mean usually
given the
expressiveness we will study this later of the languages it is
not unlikely that there are implicit things being said so one
should press
but in that reveals implicit things
i think some of you are already familiar with the classification service that uses a
find implicit information in the t box level and as you can see here this
is assumed to be a display of the asserted hierarchy and uris within the machine
has computed the inferred hierarchy
and this it i think to
get some information that for instance the chair concept has moved from an explicit set
concept of person to an explicit sub concept of professor i don't want to dig
out now all the details why is the case this will be done later the
message going to make here is that using the reasoning facilities
during ontology definition time
really is really helpful
and in many cases also reveals concepts whose death was definition doesn't make much sense
with respect to the whole ontology
OK we have been talking about
class level
relations between the instances the concept
the relations between the instances of these are
declared either textually or with the editor that you see here and
now we use reasoning facilities to dig out the implicit things and the idea of
this way to define ontology is to do it in the top down
so one first defines the concept presses the button classify and checks out whether the
reveal implicit things the implicit things may be unwanted
things it might not be
intended to have chair as the concept of professor right and then
it is
apparent that the model must somehow be revised and it won the ontology is defined
people of the ontology is defined we can use this
i have a clear is and said about individuals so i call this the top
ge ze
the first
in some mining heterogeneous information networks
because for this conference so many
workshops are going
after our struggle
which says everyone
which is true
this is one way of thinking about this is not just
overview of the introductory material
this one is going to be
down to the
most of them regardless of pain
is the last two or three years
in sense it's quite up to date
it is not hard to understand it's quite important information network analysis
so either way
and to give this tutorial
so the tutorial on their
and so
it was the
of his life he wants to make it easier to and she just married you
work workshop just the you
last time
on one of the things
he goes
you know
assistant professor at UC santa barbara
he said he was idea for many years
chairman of the
no it had to be useful
we call this
four slots
fall the things we want to partition one is on the motivation and here is
where the stream into parts
one is a song by australian a
at some point in search
the first one on my talk page or discovery
founded in the world
so we first got this one
our you for social network communication network which never quite
the first question one task is
what are information networks or what whether they have the same or
they very different from social networks
or some other networks
so the information for the general definition is
we get lost in all
and also some kind of the information
it could be
person like social network could where the research paper
conference so
and it is
and we lists need to get
and also the fact that
professor supervises student can teachers students you can collaborate with sister schools
but there are ways you conferences
conference of
i don't know
but that doesn't mean that i think it's
one thing need to touch the things we want to discuss this
first is homogeneous
one of the homogeneous what the
homogeneous means
think of time
time is one
for example
you say france like facebook friends with friends
well the link friends don't see this kind of of
yeah it's
all we know to know
so so you
link this also kind of objects in
these we call
o to
the web page for example you look at the same pace
so when there are many different pages i don't
these are used
you know some things you want to on so the was
you can see this one homogeneous network as well
but in real life
we found that many many words to produce these
martin high one
this gives is for example
american men
we patients doctors hospitals treatments
prescription all the things emailing about was patients
he was patients are probably with the third carried against me
you may say
the doctor
the prescription
that's not the person to link with the hospital
these are different things including together
they played
so that one
these we have to understand the homogeneity
and the different types of e
the same thing that we use these objects
the last
we have a conference aspect e
we also have attendees these
we have
a paper may terms
no they are going to get
but these are typically
heterogeneous information
what this talk
understanding is we are not
on the australian prime prime minister
the heart
and because the very strong australian
and so what happened is that
it passed in
something as a stray alien
but he went to say well australian
important speech recogniser not the local conditions
this was actually at the time when he was talking a lot of about illegal
aliens there was particular
novelty detection
so what can you do that
well you might want to decide whether points news
the network is
and with digital belong to that respect
let's say you're system
you need to make sure that universe universe trying
and all the sudden something strange happened
you don't really know what it is but you basically know they're getting more losses
immediately you think something is wrong
even though you might be able to to
he might not have seen exactly that situation before
even though you might not know exactly what is wrong but you will probably say
something wrong
now was systems are expensive
and you don't always get the really skilled one
we have another problem is that the moment but anyway
what you want to do is you want to program that
give him hand in telling him well this is unusual in that one is
or handwritten digit you want to just really we'd have to really badly written on
the maybe have a human tried to to stop them
or a lot of sense
so if you have a car alarm in his car
not many people are OK
if you have a car alarm on your car in the parking lot fresco by
and at some point i mean most of us will have serious noise by random
car alarms going off night
black and of course the only isn't that is like a car with the kind
of the concept of sanction so what happened basic the sensitivity of the car alarm
was just
way to finally
on the other hand what you also don't want to happen is that well the
alarm is just just so widely that it knocked the wind
and that's the breaks in
it can run away with that
so what you would actually
rather we want to have a system that automatically correct
for that you want automatic notification
and what a lot of ways i can consider things not
basically problem in the one of the breaks apart
by the way how much fun to play
here this is it i i have the right
OK so i think a lot of time i'll go very quickly
OK well i
let hear it so that what isn't especially
try this on a mac using
escape exporter
i tried to model the maximum
it's quite may quite amusing in the first two three car races actually make a
lot of things
but then you realize
also the brain doesn't work
so what i'll be talking about
after burn next lecture make explicit the lectures is about that is the probability theory
you know it's a bit of a shame that i cannot do that before i
basically this learning the language about how to deal with event
that would help
OK good so
well basically the series you want to
find out the probability
that well
certain things how you all know the basic axioms of probability theory namely that the
probability of being has be here in one
the probability that something happens to one
and if all the events of the joint being
over all of that is the probability of the joint
the event
and that of course means that
the probability of the events happening which are not necessarily chime in with probability one
the intersection
and here's the proof
this happens that happens
that's probably that both at
and so
the joint
just think but that
well this
but that one that
you could have more than one variable
and well
i mean if x and y are independent i can actually write
the probability that he of x y
what is an application
let's say you want pregnant you want to find out player
you go to the drug
and let's assume that the marginal probability that getting boys and girls i library at
twenty five was a
but the case that you have a point of
this starts goes because this crystal ball in the back room come back i know
it's going to be able to write
and how find that of the other one
what people would realise this guy always is out of oil
so the expected o point six percent change in radius
and so the two thirty eight will end up here
i exaggerate very highly and the two thirty five
o and p two thirty eight has a larger radius because it has a larger
you see that here
there's no change in b
no change in human there's no change in capital v
we accelerate them over the same
potential difference
and so if the radius
for instance where one meter
of this mass spectrometer
then the difference here
remember this is two are
the difference will come out to be about one point two centimetres and so you
have a collective here
you can lecture two thirty eight
adams and u u
collected thirty five and that's the idea
a mass spectrometer
why did i choose this particular example
well this example
changed our world
and it made history
you're eighteen to thirty five
i was needed by the americans
to build an atomic bomb
o and the second world war
this is
this was done under the
famous manhattan project
and ernest lawrence of berkeley
built mass spectrometers
which were able to separate uranium two thirty five to thirty eight
in the beginning it went very slowly about one hundred micrograms per day
but a few kilogrammes was required for an atomic bomb
they finally managed to get up to one gram per day
and in combination with other separation techniques such as the gas diffusion techniques
which i will not discuss you know
they managed to get a few kilogrammes
and they dropped the bomb and they rush him on august six nineteen forty five
and three days later
the bomb was dropped on
japanese surrender
it was the end
of world war two
it's a good thing that there are many peaceful applications nowadays of mass spectrometers
particularly in the medical area
people sometimes require radiation
and the need radiation from a particular radioactive isotope
but you don't want
the other isotopes from the same element and so
two separate them then
with a mass
the whole industry
very important industry
and i would like to address the issue have you
extremely high speeds almost approaching
the speed of light
and that
there's also something for which
ernest lawrence is credited
in early days it was done in a cyclotron
which i will describe to you know
which is called a d
this is one d
and here's another the
conducting chambers
look from the side
would look like so
this is the left chamber
this is the right chamber and all of this in vacuum
and let's assume
that we have a magnetic field coming out of the board
like so
that's really visit our one MTV proton
suppose i release in this chamber here
one MTV protons
and i know the speed with which it comes out because the one in the
had be you still see their one point four times ten two seven meters per
we also noted in one test field let's make this one test well
that the really is is going to be fifteen centimeters using it up there
so what is this proton going to do
it's going to do this
but when it gets there
potential difference is introduced between these two
so that this is low or high potential and this is the local council
and so
you're going to get an electric field now
in this gap
in this direction
so this proton is being accelerated that suppose
that's the difference
is twenty kilowatts
this program will in
electric in kinetic energy it will gain kinetic energy twenty
kill o electron volts that's the way control is is defined
and so
you start off with one anything
so when it has
cross this gap
it is now
one point o two and
twenty kv
the rate is now is larger
if capital v
two percent higher and i go to this equation
the radius
is one percent higher
and so
when it comes out here
and it makes the circle
the rate is now is one percent higher than fifteen centimeters
but when it gets to this
part of the
this potential difference is reversed
and so the electric field
again in this direction in the direction of the proton and so it is accelerated
again by twenty
general electric now to radius of course is even larger
so very gradually
every time that reaches the gap
the potential differences change in direction to accelerate protons
and so it gradually
spirals out and
to the largest radius
that you have so doing one full rotation
it gains twenty kilogram volt one thousand twenty kilogram full price
so against forty kilo electron volts
and so the electric field
i doing the work they accelerate the particles magnetic fields cannot accelerate
magnetic fields can change the direction that they can do no work on the particle
so the magnetic fields confine the particles
let's assume we go
twelve hundred
and twenty five
four locations
during each rotation
kinetic energy increased by forty kv
so if you multiply the two
and you see now that
kinetic energy of the proton
increased by forty nine
million electron volts
because it went twelve hundred and
twenty five times all the way around
so now you have
forty nine NTV plus the one two started with
so now you have a fifty
i mean
you the second line there
there we have that fifty and the proton
but i discussed the issue here
in one test field
now the radius is one meter
like for NHS some some come on there is part which is conserved among the
the twenty minutes is this is about is used to make the things but you
are and what you
the specific part which is different the twenty minutes is so you can have be
all small businesses are going to have a positive charge and negative charge density are
so you have to differences
and typically
all the proteins
are something come which is the consequence of businesses and what the difference is the
ordering of the is used so you can think of the states within india but
and when you write your data different sequences the new different parties with different functions
and what i mean
problem is that fact proteins can have a huge variety of functions they can
many of them for instance are called enzymes because they they act as catalysts configurations
many of them are used to make the structure of the cells of the organism
so we want to make a membrane we want to make glue between things these
many of them are used to carry information
for instance when i can take information between cells are so the is incredible hall
however was able to use this common framework to produce and to give the assumptions
so something i universities is how you will find in two
the proteins that
four letters so there is a sequence of four photos i said that are and
is very similar to what could be
DNA into RNA with the transcription you could be want what appears there is a
difference which is that instead of a t c g university by u
OK this is what people are named after DNA
but this is the and a second a here is that there are so you
want to one directors of our of DNA editors of RNA
but then properties of about twenty eight hours twenty amino acids
so this is where the agency called comes in because the actual decided that one
of the the
many ways to to make a computer science state sequence of RNA into a sequence
of proteins
in fact there was a debate at some point what is or how much is
that in fact it shows very simple scheme which is that it changes to what
the sequence of foreign a it was it took two
to search by
three so they all sequences of three letters in the middle of forehead sort like
a because each sequence of three are in a
is associated one amino acids
so this is already done because as you can see you when you have four
letters and three parameters is you for full-time for which is sixty four
what spoken and sixty four and this is what is now this is the falconer's
some up to the twenty amino acids so you have the time that the sentiment
as it
OK so what i mean the president of three nucleotides nucleotides and for the basis
of DNA
it's called the
yes so i know it has been studied a lot and i know that before
it was discovered there were people doing speculations about it because before it was discovered
we knew that there was another
proteins were
were made of amino acid so there were many speculations and what could be discovered
that i am not aware of any from results i don't think it's three optimal
in terms of doing something
but surely i don't know
anything that has been done
OK so it's to to the human genome project now
what you want to sell the chromosomes DNA DNA used to make proteins
and so despite in in the system was discovered quite a few decades ago you
see that it is so i the central was the main idea of what's biology
and so if i go back to the central dogma
is it becomes interesting
to look at DNA because it's very little looks like a program and this is
the same is the string matching the constant that trees to putting so there is
a simple idea which is that if i was able to know all the DNA
and if i give you the
the genome of an organism and if i give it to clever tricks anti-social to
the guys don't necessarily consistent is by far the genome then probably i could because
the more i know i know that because i know part of how
imagine a world
well fortified if i the DNA i should be able to understand how it works
OK there is the idea that the brain to find the group then i have
a good chances to reconstruct how it works so
since the eighties there are several
the other sequences technology was developed sequencing means reading the letters of DNA
it's not easy but it's possible and after a successful sequencing of of simple organisms
was decided in two in nineteen ninety start project of sequencing the human genome
so first we can assume that these are the spiciness of course you know that
we are all different all the events of different so when i talk about the
there is not one single
six sources unit test
describe all the humans because we all have different DNA is what's called dimension of
insight is that each side of the species like in human you operations among individuals
but the vibrations the alterations there are many variations
but among the
among the six billion it
roughly speaking six million version six million liters for human so the rights of variations
among individuals is one to one thousand
OK development project was to sequence
an average human society several people were sequence
there were five two competitive projects
recall that but need several people like all the other ten to twenty people were
sequence and so the was to discover the ninety
nine the nine point nine percent of commentators because all the dimensions and also to
discover the
o point one percent of partitions humans
so that is
the time spent
in communication and taken from the computation is to all that like the communication with
the computation
so while for if we use asynchronous communication means that the
let's define synchronous communication and asynchronous communication in synchronous communication
when decide to send the message to another
he stops the execution of their
they start sending the message to deal with the end of of the communication process
will not every pattern to this sequence of instructions
these are synchronous communication that advantage is that when we read from
the communication operation
we actually one hundred percent sure that the destination machine has received our data our
we can assume
in our called
in asynchronous communication what we do we started their communication operations sending a message
and then we ask the operating system
to complete the operation so
we can agree that what we call
continue executing at the instruction computation
but in this case it's not guaranteed in our called during the execution of expression
our called it's not guaranteed that the machine has received the message not yet at
with take longer
so it's treaty
because we may assume that the emotions know something it's not too
not yet true
overlapping with asynchronous communication can
increase the along to the performance
but it's more complex
so let's say a few words about how we evaluate how green speed up everybody
you should know something about speed up
but the let's define
the speed up
is defined as the that's answer
between there
time taken by the fastest
known sequential algorithm
not anyone
no they were not the one we have finalized but the fastest known sequential algorithm
for this problem
over the time taken by our talent how algorithm
so it's not fair to to compare the parallel algorithm with the is lost when
in this case
we can define
in the algorithm we are paralyzing we can let's say we let's assume we are
we are using the same
sequential algorithm here
and we know that we use
for the part of so we take one out we analyse the system is
in this case
we can look into the outcome and recognise that these maybe
part of the which is sequential
it cannot be executed in more than one machine
and then it about which is part of life
so we can paralyze the only despite
the result will be that we have
only one process of BC at the beginning
and then after they finish the sequential component
the other can contribute to
in the parallel combined
so we have part fraction the sequential fraction then the speedup can be expressed in
terms of these
two fractions
when we look at the chart
what we need to keep in mind is that
linear speedup which is the
the maximum daily collaspe be that we can reach
if we use
eight machine the best we can do we can imagine to do
his driver's the speed up of data
in this case the entire program
has been
divided in eight five
and each processor executes one eighth of the entire problem
sublinear it what usually happens because we have the communication overhead we've had a parallel
overheads so we do more work than the sequential called it
we will get to sublinear speedup
in some rare cases
we can get super linear speedup
the article point of view formerly it's formally it's impossible if you see is super
linear speedup you can conclude that the
we didn't use the fastest known sequential language
so it's wrong results you can reject the paper
but there are two cases when this man in
one is
due to the memory you can we were discussing before because we are not using
it to the machine we are using real machines
and the memory yes he
produces phenomena
which may introduce opinions
because now
a big problem which doesn't fit
in the first level education second location is global the
memory to the around
now if we split it in several parts we get a smaller problem which may
feature in the case
so it will be executed faster
then the sequential
in this case we can
find out
if we simulate the department called
in a sequential machine
if we do that
again we will get here better performance from the sequential called
what we thought was the super linear speedup becomes
linear assembly
the second is exceptions
and search algorithms
because of search algorithms
let's say we are looking for a solution we don't know what the solution is
in the domain and the search space
and if we use the sequential algorithm
we have to sequentially
trying one by one the solutions and
if we are like we get the solution
before of we unlike we get it at the end if we have enough processing
we can look at several solution in parallel
from a statistical point of view we analyse the it's likely we get to the
solution faster than the sequential
that's why for set out
can up and then we have superlinear speedup
the speed up
not only
OK occasionally nested these references
but there is the and that's law which says that that we have the maximum
speed up to
when we increase the number of processing elements
let's say we two
do we get
is there a limit for this
we keep
increasing increasing
there no this just the one before
if we increase the
processing elements does this does increase
it's not possible because any program has fry fraction sequential fraction
sequential importance
so i'm law
he's talking about these sequential component when we have the sequential component which is not
even if it smaller
we can say if we
increased and see the number of
processing elements the maximum speed up
and i can show on the screen this light that comes back i'll see the following
will see red on the outside
and then i will see
something that's bluish but maybe not perfect blue
and then i will see inside here
white light
and he will see no light
because phi cannot be larger than forty two degrees
so no light will strike the board here
she read
gradually other callers come in
and then
you will see white light
and that's
at the heart of understanding of these
the rainbow
gonna put you out on the field
u i
i'm going to make it rain
the grading
we don't want a son anymore at the horizon because it's too special case so we're gonna put on
the eye on the sky
the put son
then this guy
okay you're standing there so is there what you see
you see a shadow
and here is your head
the shadow
and here is your body
and he
that's just the way it is that shadows right
just happened to be looking in this section of the sky
we'll get the rain there
there's a raindrop years a range of new orders
thousands of raindrops in that direction
it's one of these raindrops
is returning to the sun
called light
and that call
is red on the outside
and the rest we know
i'm only going to draw you
the red column
and you'll get this report
and this one this one this one this
what do you see what is the colour of the rainbow
it's not read
not looking at this red light all because the red light is
only hour
part of the common what color you see
you see white light
because you're looking somewhere here
we've seen all the colors you see that very small angle so you see registry greasy
so you see white light
thank you very much you see white light
that's the white light it is returned
in the range of interaction of the sun
well you also looking in this direction
looking way higher up in the sky
and so you raindrops
direction of sun
and so
it's one of those raindrops
they don't know any better
throwback the sun
forty two degree angle
the cone of light
what is the color that raindrop
you don't see it there is no light coming back to outside come
no light
so you're looking at interaction that is forbidden
if i cannot be larger than forty two degrees and if you would see light coming back
would be larger than forty two degrees
or if you're very good
we're going to look
in a very special direction
going to look in a very special direction
i'm looking to disarray
and this angle now
i have chosen to be forty two degrees
notice is forty two degrees away from the direction the sun
it's one of those raindrops going to
throw at me
forty two degrees
the direction the sun
and it's going to throw back nice cold in the sky
what is the color that raindrop
because i'm exactly looking at the right conditions
but i'm just seeing
this part of the code
so now
you've almost created for yourself
because remember it's completely actual symmetric so you can rotate the whole thing about this axis
it is you write the rate
so now it going to see it forty two degrees away in this guy is
going to see only read every raindrop that is forty two degrees away from this
is only read
if you go inside
the ball will be right
outside there will be no light and gradually as you approach the white
it will become
and so you're going to see
something like this
let's assume
sons of degrees
above the rise and
so that this angle
forty two degrees
there you will see the outside of the ball
inside the ball
white light
you may never have seen
sixteen bright sometimes we very bright white it's dark
don't means that you see the clouds
it means no light coming back from the water
and the clouds normally dark when it is raining so that's why i said are you see right
you see the clouds and then
you will also see
gradually other colors come in
so he inside and
you have a blue appearance and there you see
the formation
of the rainbow
if you go through a similar sequence of geometry
which are used elsewhere on
actually also used for now falls
it's tell you about intensity it's a little bit more complicated
then you can also demonstrate
that is the second ball
call that the second that this is called the primary bright wonderful
there's a secondary which is not at a forty degree angle
from the direction away from the sun
what is higher in the skies about ten degrees higher than the fifty two degrees and the colors rivers
many of you may never have seen it and the reason why you may not
have seen it is that the primary so much brighter than the second day that
you pay no attention the secondary
but it almost always there are provided to support that water drops
at that's fifty degrees
i'd like now to
look at a few slides
first before we attempt
to answer
the questions
so let's look
at slight number one
normalized when no
OK let me show you this more
carefully in this important cases
the weight vector updated
vector is
the euclidean distance squared to the old guy
plus the hinge loss
and then
if you differentiate is
you end up with this
this fancy delta rule
but the gradient of the future
is used here
the approximate gradient and now
this is the normal perceptron algorithm
the perceptron algorithm doesn't update when
when you're correct so when this is the same
you don't have to date only when you're wrong
this is slope becomes one and you add in eight times x
and that corresponds to sort of
when you correctly on this site
you conservatives you don't do it it
but when you the wrong side
you slope this one
and you get an update
similarly you can get the normalized winnow
now you just a
the bregman divergence
to be
for the parameters to be the relative entropy
and over here
they lost again which is another bregman divergence
if you
differentiate is an approximate
the gradient
you're in
with this kind of
this is
normalized winnow algorithm
so it's the same situation
except use the different parameters versions
the overall scheme is
trade between two
the parameters
which measures how far you move in parameter space
and sort of the loss divergence
how much you moving to los space
and online learning algorithm is
trade off between the two
this divergence measures this distance in parameter space to this one this is in
what distance divergence in in labeling space trade off the two
and minimize my w
he this the online setting
we're take this then there the last class
loss of just the last instance
i can also immediately get bashed out within spitting distance to the divergence
and then the loss is summed over all examples
they get back problems
if you do this
then your day always has the following form
it is
link function applied to the old
weight vector
eight times the gradient
which now has a simple form
hw t-minus
the next few months like this sort of the this is the y
this was the prediction y t
minus twenty
and this is known as the delta rule
you know it's sort of
from the network lingo
the generalized rule because you have this meaning function if you do know networks they
only and always did this
when the link function
the identity function
but now we do this also when the link functions for instance the log
then you would get lot w e to the
and that
back in the field
because new zero times i
times and divided by l accepted this and divided by l no
the number of windings of my current wire and this is the length of my
soul don't confuse it with the one we had there that was on an atomic
this is on the macroscopic scale many windings
could be where you had a big one year in class twenty eight hundred windings
sixty centimetres long
so that's what this number is all about
so the moment that i
i know what the current system i sort of i need to know what my
vacuum field this one-to-one correspondence
and now i'm going to matter inside the ferromagnetic materials but i stick in the
solenoid and measure the magnetic field
what's going to happen now
first of all i can not at all
love this curve
on the one scale
the reason being
cap of four ferromagnetic materials
is so large
that was done for now number of one thousand say
o could be largely that's a kappa
is one thousand
that means that if the
magnetic fields
in terms of
this big
one centimeter in the length of the factory
the field inside
ferromagnetic materials a thousand times higher
this is one centimeter in length a thousand times higher is ten meters
so this is the length of the vector of the magnetic field inside the ferromagnetic
that's why i cannot do it or scale
so when i draw the line here
among the if i didn't screw
if i did but i can't
the tangent of all
recap of of
which in this case we can do
so this angle of find something like eighty nine point nine something degrees
so i cannot do it or can keep that in mind
in the beginning i get a nice linear curve
but now slowly i'm beginning to reach saturation
that all these dipoles are going to be aligned
what you're going to see is that this curve
hands over ends of events over
and the
magnetic field that you finally achieved here
is is the famous two point three which i calculated for that imaginary material
the fact
two point three
is not the field
i will call b prime
this is the field that is the result of the alignment of all those dipole
and so when i increase the vacuum field this goes into saturation
and several for two point three and can no longer increase because i've aligned magnetic
and so
if you
vacuum field is strong
and this field is no longer a thousand times stronger than the vacuum field is
no longer in the linear part
so you also think of it the kappa have been smaller than
several way
you prefer is fine
but it's no longer
two the value of
one thousand
if the temperature is lower of the material
it's easier to align them so you achieve saturation earlier
so you could go like this curve is also a function of temperature
so this is
if temperature is low
relative this one
but his car depend on on temperatures well below what temperature the easier it is
to align the
if i read this point here
when i b prime goes into saturation
i can only increase the field
the field in the material
by increasing the vacuum field
b prime is not going to go up again
and so i can only get a higher field
by increasing this current so that this is a vacuum goes up and that goes
very slowly because this huge magnification factor one thousand
is gone now
so to slow is very slow to growth
that's why you see that i would like this
that it
increases very slowly but
plot is not to scale any
now i want to discuss the issue
what happened was the material
once i have driven it into saturation
what happens
if no i changed the current
and i make my
vacuum field zero again
now you get a very unusual behaviour
let me do you on the blackboard
so i make new drawing i could have continued with that one but let me
make one
so i'm going to
do the following experiment in my head
i have a solenoid
and i currently that sort of knowledge
and if the current
it is in a clockwise direction
my vacuum field
will be in this direction
and the current in counterclockwise direction
i will assume that my
vacuum is in disarray ferromagnetic material
if the current flows in a clockwise direction effective field direction
running counter-clockwise direction
the fact that the right
he was going to be my vacuum fields
easy for me to know whether this because if i know the current my solenoid
this equation will immediately tell me what the vacuum field is so i've never any
problem with the vacuum field
i think appropriate here
and i measure the magnetic field inside the material how we do that is not
so easy we can do
two things that
i can tell you this is one
so here is the magnetic field inside the material
all right so there we start
we do the same thing that we did here
we approaches saturation now and i'm here
i am reducing the current single back to zero
remember that when we hear all these domains that we discussed last time have all
in the direction of the vacuum
huddersfield is enormous but now i a current go back to zero
and what happens now is
i end up here
at this point here
the current now is zero
there is no current going through the solenoid notice the vacuum field is zero i
can take the material out the ferromagnetic materials the material itself is no magnetic
and you see
there is magnetic field inside
why is there because some of those domains remain aligned they don't go back
but the experience and experiment so you could can in principle
think of thinking and behaving brain
that's quite
people in computational neuroscience
OK so just
to start with some
seminole invasive BCI work
he would have a monkey that sits on the chair
that's that's due to an equally cynical
and you with
the monkey has
is the surgery and there's some metal electrodes in his brain
and then
these brain signals there typically air raise no show you how they what they look
like later
and so
the data is required and then you need to
transform it into the code
the brain signals and
the intention of the monkey
what is doing
and one wants the the idea was here was that the monkey had to do
the task control
a robot arm
whoops with that
so the monkeys to control the robot arm
and what he's doing that they recorded
the motor cortex premotor cortex ever neurons there
they get some
spike trains
from that
so this is the hand position
the monkey
the idea is to learn the mapping
so to say the spike trains to the robot position robot arm position trajectory
so this would be the training
in the testing
would be
that you
turn off the i mean that you you keep the the monkey on fixed
and you just use the brain signals
to control the robot
this is very similar
set up from andy schwartz see is the fixation of the data
of the monkey army
you see that the monkey
so can
it's actually sitting quite comfortable and in fact most people don't know that that
if you
i have a monkey that
that is not feeling well it is not doing any work so you cannot use
them for experiments so some of the monkeys that
schwartz was was working with the
they actually
after many many years of work in the lab they are now
and so to say retired and they went to the zoo
there are now older than than typical monkeys living in the outside world and in
they can take they are now subject to aged studies on monkeys
so i just in tokyo there was an element in the short and he was
telling me this didn't know before
OK so so here's
to say that two see part
see these are typically electrode arrays
you see here
this is the a brain and you see how it this now
starting to get planted see here how these these
put into parts of the brain and you see that there's a a lot of
them in the brain
stuck into the brain and motor area
premotor area and so on and so
the new this is sealed and
you to the signals and you can try to control robot arms with
so in fact it's from the signal processing offer even from the title technological point
of view this is quite advanced because you have to deal with a lot of
you have to amplify quite a lot of signals in rather robust manner
so that they are measuring the width of the order thousand electrodes so that's that's
quite a lot
to sample from
so maybe the most impressive
resolved that that i think is around is due to
this is a video of of
and the short from andy schwartz left
and you see that
the monkey this is
o thing is so it's not the monkey arms
stuck into this so the monkey on the somewhere here
it's fixated
and you
you see that
well you will see
that by my intending
by thinking the monkeys moving the arm
and there's
attached to the so the monkey will close the group
and get some
food from
stuff it into his mouth
sorry i don't see anything i see it here
the sun
is that
you seem
one more try
o thing to toss of highway driving
so all of us part of the reason why drivers and what we try to
be automatically trade many different desiderata values of the with other cars and you really
don't want to hit other pedestrians and we don't suggestions maybe you want to maintain
reasonable speed you don't have separate or break too much useful they want to sell
the blind spot that big truck on the kind of what i don't like tonight's
the curb the matching the curve is not is that it's a pedestrian and you
like to maintain a resource fees early seventies thereafter so
if you think about how you teach six-year-olds to drive what you do not do
is sitting down and say you know he kids this is the reward function go
maximize that what you do instead see that washoe drive for a while and somehow
by this process of washing drive that they somehow figure out maybe what could they
somehow learn to drive for themselves on and so
to me one question is on if you given out of the demonstration of driving
this is peter driving that car is it possible seven out of figure out how
drive by itself
OK and i think the fact is even though all of us are pretty decent
drivers is very hard for us to sit down and write out the mathematical equation
saying well this are what function for driving is much more natural to demonstrate driving
in the urban to what can
there's lots of work on a
learning from from from demonstrations goes on in the imitation learning learning by watching a
few of the names of the major work has has to focus on trying to
predict and express actions as a function of the states and on a lot of
success is i think it often lacks performance guarantees what we do is just described
different approach those really do the peer review for instance was sphere and those on
something called inverse reinforcement learning and what you can prove is that this approach that
can learn a control policy with performance is as good as he expect because it's
the demonstrators holes
what you going to evaluate performance according to the expected reward function which by the
way you is actually impossible to figure out based demonstration
it turns out to be impossible to figure out what he expects what function is
but none the less the unknown and unknowable what function you think of our fuzzy
improve would do well on that one function
this may be almost this promotional most technical father to talk but his the idea
of informal you can about having a two thousand justice two things one is you
guess what experts try to guess what the expose reward function
and the intuition is to try to find reward function that makes what we saw
the expertise to the really good and tries to make anything that we manage to
do ourselves the really bad day and then you can formalise this is maximum margin
problem as a quadratic programme next as of the mathematically equivalent to support vector machines
but the idea is key finding a reward function that explains dx this behaviour makes
of cells pretty that makes explicitly
you take the reward function guests and you pretend to write what function the use
of the our problem using this reward function you just guess and then you right
we can prove is that under mild conditions a small number of iterations is our
of open policy that all forms nearly as well as the expert as evaluated on
the experts
the especially some examples
on the left is the video that is actually exactly the same video the soldiers
now of peter demonstrating you know driving the car
and with no reward function specifies the input the only input the our atmosphere driving
twenty driving that
you know that
this would be more cool three d computer graphics
so just kind of fun examples on the video left in each of these examples
and that's the panel shows the driving demonstrations and right panel shows the learned behavior
when only the left panel demonstrations given as input and so this is PD demonstrating
driving style which he crashes into as many cars as possible
and when you do that
i think these behaviors that may be somewhat visible but challenging to specify mathematically get
on the just and demonstration that's peter stay staying in the right meaning veering off
and for some more
or one
one of these
we are in
it it
four of
this work
three or five
we were
are sure
the game
four years
there are
he throws it will be on
the thing
for each
and even
all kinds of
so all the first time
very very old
he's not
over the
this room you must have done OK right
having said that
i have discovered that saying that is misleading and the reason it's misleading is cast
your mind back to ninth grade nine grade math is hard
OK i remember in particular were problems are hard and you remember were problems this
is where you drive from here to cleveland and you fill your tank up with
gas and the gas cost so much per gallon the question is what is your
shoe size or something and you are but but the way one approaches that is
through kind of common sense approach which involves the fact that many of us have
been in a car driving from city a city b perhaps not cleveland but somewhere
else and so you have a kind of intuition to fall back when you do
the math problems that are logically the same but applied to astrophysical systems for which
you have absolutely no common sense to back you up then you have to reason
purely from the internal logic of problem and that's hard to do it's a skill
that can be learned
it's a skill that's worth learning it's a skill that i'm sure many of you
already have to a large extent but it isn't an easy thing and so the
fact that the level of the math is low doesn't mean that the problems are
and we do have a lot of help mechanisms which are described perhaps on thursday
to keep you to keep you up to to speed if you start having trouble
with these things
OK so i should say something about course requirements here let's see
we have sections in this class these sections are not just problem solving sections these
are actually required the fact that we're dealing in topics for which the answer is
not fully known means that one can actually have discussion sections unlike many science courses
so we're going to do that and so the structure of the courses like history
course two lectures which was required section and so ten percent of your great comes
from sections a large fraction of that is just showing up but they will also
be something in terms of you know saying something intelligent what you get there
that's ten percent of the course thirty percent of the courses problem sets we'll have
these things at once a week the first problem set will show up on thursday
and if you have any question about whether this course is appropriate for you the
right thing to do is to look at that problem set and ask yourself is
this reasonable i will say
the students on their evaluation to pointed out that it does the course does get
harder it's not the math gets more complicated but the situations get more complicated and
so if you have serious trouble with the first problems that that's probably a warning
sign as i say that will be handed out on thursday these things come about
once week thirty percent of the great also more about problems sets later on thursday
the thirty percent come from two mid-term exams the way we do this is the
one where you get the better score counts twenty percent one that you get the
worst score counts ten percent so they give you a little bit of a break
and then there will be a final exam that's the last thirty percent of the
there is also an optional paper if you choose to do that that will count
fifteen percent of your great and what it will do is it will d-wade whichever
the worst of you're thirty percent part of your grade are back down to fifteen
percent so if you're a word person rather than a number person you get this
opportunity to to augment your score and d d-wade
some other part of the class in which you may have done well as well
all this stuff is on the classes server i should say that the syllabus that
i put out here is just a direct copy of what's on the classes server
so feel free to to take that but all the information and actually more information
is is online
let me
oppose now ask whether there are questions about the course and the course procedures
no no this class is going to be now
i'll have to check and see what you were thinking of but it may be
that what that was referring to was section times actually this is something that i
have mentioned sections are required they're all going to be on mondays we're going to
have a wide range of times all of them on mondays from twelve thirty two
i think eighty nine but you do have to sign up for section let me
also say
i've i've mentioned here i don't think this is actually looking at the number of
people here i think we're going to be able to accommodate everyone including including juniors
and seniors but i did set up in such a way that freshmen and sophomores
get first crack the way that can work is set this section the online section
form opens up on mondays on monday
and juniors and seniors won't be allowed to officially register for the class until tuesday
so the freshmen sophomores get to fill up the sections first my guess is again
looking at the number of people here today that we want to have any problem
and then if you're junior senior
you'll you'll get on just fine
and so will be picking sections through the through what is now the standard online
times the dimension times the rank
and input to be extremely precisely two times dimension mind answering time the rank but
the point is that if n is one million and the rank stand for example
the number of degrees of freedom
of the matrix of rank ten in dimension one million is something like twenty million
not one trillion
which is an square
and so of course the matrix of rank r depends on the number of degrees
of freedom which is much smaller than n square which is the ambient dimension
and so this ask begs the question was well if this matrix depends on the
small number of degrees of freedom
you i really need to see everything two
recovers the matrix exactly
and the question is not as easy as it seems
so here's an example of the very simple matrix of rank one
as you can see
this matrix is based by multiplying the
basis vector was the last that symmetric which is full of zero except that there's
the one in some corner right
and if suppose
i show i'm going use gray says
if you don't mind
if i show fifty percent of the entries to grace at random fifty percent of
the time she will see zero
and so when you see zero is no way for you to tell me that
this matrix is not zero matrix
so you have an example of a matrix are very low rank
and even if you look at a few i given a ninety percent of the
entries ten percent of the time just zero and you will never guess there's one
right here
and these matrices cannot be recovered from one percent of the entries or even ninety
percent of the entries just not possible
OK but this matrix is a little bit peculiar and certainly the netflix matrix does
not look like this because images fixed images look like this i would say
there's one guy that likes one movie and everybody else dislikes
then on the other hand you have also to be careful with what i decided
to show you
so suppose we have a rank one matrix which is simply an outer product between
two vectors x and y
then the entries of m is simply excite times y j
and suppose that i should grace everything except
roy manual so let's say this is
again the netflix database and she gets to see everything the preferences of all users
for all movies except she knows nothing about man
well how can she predicting that she doesn't even know how it looks like OK
of course if i forget
if i don't sample row or column even if you have the same press matrix
a matrix of rank one
matrix completion is not possible
so of course these are very peculiar sample set so we can assume that way
the set of entries that you get to see example at random not because i
believe in probability but i'm interested in describing what happens most of the time and
not in the worst possible case
so now
we arrive at an interesting point which is that if the matrix is not adversarial
with the one in accordance are everywhere else
is something said is random that is it's not constructed in the village way perhaps
there is one low rank matrix which is completed which is consistent with the sampled
right so perhaps there is one only one low rank matrix that fits the data
and this is the case then i would recovery by just
minimizing the rank of the matrix subject to the constraints
but i want to say that this point that it's just i hope that we
don't know whether there is only one rank matrix and even if i were to
give you data and i say how many matrices of rank seventeen are consistent with
this data
then to decide this is already already NP complete
but we could dream and say well you know we have enough data
and the data is not adversarial
so maybe this is just one or a matrix that is consistent with this data
and which cases will work
the problem with this is that minimizing the rank subject to linear equality constraints is
NP hard and in fact
yesterday we talked about the hardness of minimising zero zero norm
well if you think the minimising of the one norm is hard
then i have news for you that minimizing the rank is much harder
and to the best of my knowledge i think the best are reason we know
to minimize the rank
is as the complexity which is doubly exponential in n that is we can do
is n equals five maybe
but cannot do any calls eight
all right
so even if this made sense there's is no way we can do it in
the computer
so instead we're going to do is we get
so the convex guy so we can relax this problem it is something that we
can solve
i'd like to introduce the nuclear norm
and the nuclear norm is simply the sum of the singular values is the nuclear
norm of a matrix is very simple definition
it is the sum of the singular values of the matrix it's not clear that
it's the norm example is not clear that it obeys the triangular inequality busy day
so now i'm going to replace
rank functional by the nuclear norm phenomena as to minimize the nuclear norm subjective data
constraints because i have norm then the objective function or becomes convex and the
and the
and and since i have convex constraints and looking at the convex optimisation problem
and in fact it's just not any convex optimisation problem it's a problem that is
kind of
closely related to the rank in the sense that it is the tightest convex approximation
two the rank optimisation problems
and so
the way we should understand the one norm minimisation is this which is that if
i look at
i hope you can see this picture if i can look if i look at
all the vectors that have one nonzero components
of size plus or minus one
so the signal that i extremely sparse
then they are on this
and what the l one ball is it's essentially is the convex hull of this
point that it is the smallest convex bodies
that contains extremely sparse vectors
and there is no smaller
convex bodies it contains
this very sparse vectors and just the same now i cannot draw a picture but
just the same
if you look at the simplest object according to the rank well this will be
wink one matrices
OK and now suppose to normalize them such that their spectral norm is one and
you ask what is the convex
how of all this point that is what is the smallest convex set that contains
rank one matrices we use
as a precise balance on the spectral norm and that happens to be the nuclear
norm since sense just as the l one ball nor is the tightest relaxation the
tightest convex approximation to the l one norm
i see zero preceded by one
many times i see a one preceded by
a one and so on you do all those counts and he
maximized by
so those a simple
markov models which just correspond to changes
in space
and you can make these models in the same way you meant to say a
density estimation model to turn it into a classification model you can that these models
with imports
so instead of having
just this chain of models
the go like this you can also have some inputs
in each of these nodes
get what you get
for features
what this says is that says about of this note here
doesn't just on its parents but also on some input from the world
so you can think of these things may be labels
OK so in a sentence so that each one of these corresponds to words in
these are
part of speech tags this is the noun verb or some kind of function words
like predicates something
and this is one model can be used to do part of speech tagging and
sentence and the assumption here is that
when you're in and a verb or predicate it depends on what the previous work
was because he has this very strong
but it also depends on something some observation make locally like maybe the morphology of
the words or
some other aspects of the the sentence that you want as input
so maybe if the word ends in e g
that might be signal that you're you know very likely to be observed
so that would be an example of some bottom-up inputs and you also have this
the level of of markovian models
so this structure here
is called a maximum entropy markov model
and anything using a lot of sequential labeling tasks including information extraction and part of
speech tagging and labeling images and things like that
so you can think of this model in two ways you can think this model
is a markov model
where we had up bottom up there
it features the bias the markov model
or you can think of it as a classification model
where we have a temporal dependencies between the classes
classification of i give the inputs and you have the class
and it is making decision at each
o point independently but here in the class the you decide four point two
depends on the class size for data point one you can think of it as
a classification model
query string
you can also
you can also consider an undirected version of this model which is called a conditional
random field
i conditional random fields
this is different from the maximum entropy model and the fact that the normalisation of
these distributions is global and local
and you can look at this and figure out that have to do with pairs
adjacent labels and pairs of inputs so
this is another kind of all that can be used to to model changes when
you have some labels at the top and some the inputs
of all
OK so change is a very simple
kind of model which extends these two models to a richer structure
and in the next step beyond change
party considered directed tree models
so i directed trees are basically graphical models
in which each variable has exactly one other variable as parents
except a special node called the root which has no
intuitively remind you can think of trees as that is
with no explaining away
remember explaining away occurs when you have a single node that has more than one
and then when observe this
these parents become couple in the inference
but it really we explicitly said so every node has exactly one parent and so
there never any explaining away
and that lack of explaining away next morning please very very
so the trees are sort of the next logical step up from assuming independence between
the nodes
so you have a huge number of nodes in the graphical model
and ask you
what these are the most
factorized something you could make it independent no links at all the graph each node
is just as distribution
and as you what the next most general thing you could do
the next month's general thing may be changed
pick an one ordering of the random variables and arrange them change the really you
should think of it as the truth that reconsiders the variables as parents
instead of just in isolation in
each pairwise
all of
so that
well you know
the end of the
on the boat