so first question is to do any technical works and consumers must be quiet
the person
well i find that i have to do technical work to same so i i
do programming from that point of view but also
i find that there's some
ideas which really you can explore and and and sometimes only explain to people by
writing code itself
that's why for example i started doing some
last year i started doing some hx coding for making to make it RDF browser
because i wanted to show the sort of
things i meant by an RDF browser
and it's been a lot of fun should students over the summer of two for
a whole lot more work into it
and so that's why i always like to try to find time to get back
to it we also have various projects it's not quite large pieces i have lying
around need need attention
so they brought
and we still using those and of course we using those in some cases systems
which we use from day data
so the lives so to keep this going
very interesting to hear what about the people around the w three c that they
all come competent in the same way
so the culture
who's the culture thanking i'm not everybody is a program but but but a lot
of people are
people tend to result make their own systems for
i want to get any worse than the number of people who have made for
example system for tracking time system for tracking
the issues working group for steve reich who has
the web browser he's produced a system for building slides in each making slideshows html
and this of course is all kinds of things the validation which made by assistant
team this part of the w three C's
and so on
now the question since you kind of consider this godfather
that and so on so you must be trekking come from different sites o
since everything is changing fast
so that that
two point zero semantic web
kind of buzz words which might be quite difficult to track for the external communities
so as a and the web itself changes the life quite a lot of our
sociologist able to cope with these changes
you must be
having some contexts
in this direction
by sociologists able to cope well
one of the things that we realize and one of the reasons with that we've
learned launch this web science research initiative is it really when you look at the
way we have to use of sociology and big economics and better computer science and
mathematics and to some extent all mixed in together because these things come together so
i think that one
each discipline has got something to
offer and in fact we have to put together the
abilities of people in many different fields in order to really be able to build
a better weapon understand how we have this one works
so that's a
the question the same line so sure that we all agree that changed life in
but the aspects and very much positive side so everything got accessible and so on
but also that's sort of like being tractable
anonymity because getting lost here and there and so on can you comment on this
whole probably see more of this from your site and how to tackle this kind
of well
the point of view of the work we do at MIT
are some sample images from the dataset but it for each image to the right
of the image into four regions and two two
in training set in the testing so there is no for each of these
classes than b
with some somebody so not only from the actually don't publications or size of the
features example some regions and then compute the covariance matrices
the previous descriptive nine features a little bit that i shouldn't
and the kind of
recognition algorithm to compute the distance between the sample and the rules of classes and
minimum distance
well was some published results of this is our method throughout this is the performance
of the the random covariance
and what you see is a combination of thirty eight on is the tropic and
is the topic if for despite being and malik
the being competition it takes hours
our method can is seconds
the first round
and this is the best performing arts rather than arts and
maybe less than one percent of the competition commission about
i wanted to there's in the data set is the example that i wanted to
kind of a fine the correct class and this is the support of the training
sample so
wrote some things that all
you should be similar to this but i find the other thing so this problem
the other thing to solve difficult dataset is but this is in a different class
activities are completely different images so the
as it should be actually it is looks more similar than this to what i
mean by that is
these are not that significant on its own kind of kind of understood that we
can compute distances on the manifold
and you can outsource for this kind search operations that
this ograms because you cannot
some structure on the representation is available
mention of representation
i'm going to discuss about some clustering applications so the crossing is despite the balls
in this in a given distribution
can find these kind of different types of
of images
the first example is a three d motion estimation in this example we only know
the future points at that some
i we don't know how many different notion exists
there are there are three different motions
all differently but you know
they are rigid body so is three of motion and because of that it is
the structure and the class of the correct matches and the walls are of lives
so that the correspondences are correct significant amount of into the example of going to
estimate the number of different motions at the same time find the transformation is so
very difficult problem you don't know how i mean all objects in the scene at
the of the motion one to compete with them
this analysis people by the
the standard approach is some form
the snowball
forensic or something like
so seeking most thinking but it does this it our distribution in in euclidean space
i'm going to start at this point i'm going to compute a density
and then i will take the mean of the density and i should like john
means local neighborhood then i'm going to repeat myself until become
the model
any more in the long
so for each point the same thing that you end up with a different
because in points and combine those and see those are the mall's and this is
what we do with desertification
four since we want to compute the group is to take being three point correspondences
and some of them are owned by the because there are no is that there
is an element of lives we generate emotion hypotheses and the generic enough tools and
in the samples from the multiple motion distribution or animals because i mean you don't
was of the same object even if they are coming back so number of significant
loss of the number of motion groups and the
the motion parameters and this how it looks like
that means
OK i'm not going to do it on the manifold so these are my points
the motion hypothesis but do not multiply it points say this point a and point
of task performance transfers two
identity and points on the manifold are mapped to the tangent space of the points
i mean identical next to zero of and the points in the neighbourhood of the
and it's is meant to zero since this hobby of being the identity in the
first place so this is the first iteration i do now i mean the indian
space in the space i can go compute in means
but it seems that call big project the mean on the manifold and we know
after today
the stars again
and the kind of explanation although operators that i mention a so some
this is the
motion and
these traits ourselves until
she doesn't become a very small
it's usually takes maybe four or five iterations in this example and here are the
so a
to two point correspondences less than half the
there are no outliers that are objects this but i'm trying to say and for
each object may be rightmost two in correspondences so these are two images like these
certain domains like medical imaging and other other cases where asuming that this different this
nice itself and i is caution is not appropriate and again
this is very standard integer genomes parts of most of the standard packages statistical packages
that you find and you just quality element to fit the model four you just
need to specify what kind of warning you're trying to fit
just like in the case of classification there are two primary considerations one is optimization
how do i figure out how to estimate w's
and what kinds of statistical guarantees
we can give
the literature on least squares and ridge regression is more standard it's it's very old
you can find it standard statistics books what kind of guarantees in terms of
the bias variance analysis you can give
this is people are working on this right now actively several of us are actively
working on building the statistical guarantees far sparse regression models the optimization that is almost
this is the statistical guarantees for sparse regression it's getting we are working on it
and i'm going to show you some examples
nonlinear models often don't make the clock right so if you're doing a linear classification and here regression
so so the second level of complexity that people put in and this was not in that order
is is is hierarchical linear models and and people
started looking at hierarchical linear models in the seventies eighties definitely
no decision trees neural networks and all these kinds of things came came into being
and we now look back and we have a much better understanding of how those developments fitting the bigger picture
but you know this is essentially wetlands
you know decision tree this is the canonical example
at any point you are just trying to make a single decision which can be considered as a linear model
and then you have a hierarchy of them in this particular case it's it's it's
a decision tree you can go with a neural network are related models as well
classification regression trees are extremely popular and they are widely used in the industry for
various purposes u u break your big problem into smaller chunks which are more tractable
using a linear model
so they are actually
you know very nice packages for doing these kinds of things
my perceptrons are
there are very popular there still are used in many many different applications
there were some
some initial shortcomings that people realized in the nineties which have been fixed
and these are the belief networks are more modern versions of some of these things
they are also hierarchical models and data capture this systems at every level you have
a simple model but you're building a hierarchy of them which led to capture something
much more complicated
has been and as i said before you know
doing the learning and optimization and the statistical analysis for this class of models gets
a little bit more difficult because quite simply because you have a hierarchy and the
overall model has become a little bit more complicated
this is i think both of these are very much ongoing there are good there
are standard learning algorithms and optimization algorithms for each one of these things
decision trees regression trees and so on
the statistical guarantees we in some cases we we can see certain things about the
performance of these methods particularly for decision trees we we do know what can we
say about these methods
but but it's it's in anything more difficult problem but the good news is that
we are very well in practice in many many applications
so so we love this class of models this is u u u like your
linear models this is just really hierarchies of linear models by property mixing
the outputs of individual layers of linear models
this is an important slide
right so because each one of us working on a different problem there has to
be some guiding principle as to how you were about doing things
the question is not whether
you know cubic explains is better than linear regression or is it better than some
conditional random fields or something like that's there has to be some guiding principle as to how you're doing things
so this is an important slide because i'm going to try to illustrate an overview
of of what the guiding principle is and if there is one big lesson we
have learned in machine learning over the last maybe you twenty twenty five years
and and you see that is exactly constricted tight constraints
yeah that was a good idea to change the number should I change
it is and different just solve the problem once more
so let me go back to 14 here and that may change a few other
numbers on the increases 1 2 3 and just doing this at random and reduce
that to do all 1 and this 9 2 6 OK is it clear enough
can you see what those numbers are
that's still 1 of our I'm asking you to solve a problem on the fly
here but then using 12 is now the minimum and which well where's the cut
this 7th
all right through down here through that 1 through that etc.
through that too and that 1
so 2 1 1 7 2 1
and the effects of minimal cut then I can get 12
the policy with this kind of money can get through 1 and 1 1 8
1 3 1 1 0 I did I leave no I increase that yet so
14 was that all of that but now I by reducing reducing
reducing some of these others I would some other cut of
12 which so that the theorem which says
it and we don't see immediately how but with a little patience we would figure
out a way to send 12 through that's really we consider more than 12 that's
for sure because you've identified cut with capacity 12 and then we got something so
we wouldn't we certainly know then we we got 2nd full amount across the cut
we've got send you know we gotta start on the answer because we know that
we have to send 7 that way and so forth and so on and you
know off we know what all these points should be and then we can fix
the others to supply them where there's extra
that's a beautiful thing and it would follow from some general duality theorem of linear
programming but then there would also be some special
argument like holes
conditions that would apply and and maybe I mentioned that this maxflow mincut is associated
with forward and focus where the student can editorial
identified that the
problems so yes so that there would be right yes so the book which speak
about that but I think we can look at the 1 way and say you
I could write the whole thing is a linear programming uses simplex method
but then somehow the simplex method should specialise to this problem and and
that in your there was called because those corners and so on should have a
specific meaning in terms of flows and that's yeah yeah this right yes
well now think that I I'm out oil-and-gas uninsured portion of the previous incarnations yeah
cause all yet got I'm getting natural gas off the goal of the Gulf of
Mexico market pipelines going into the mainland and I've got refineries there with capacities
and those pipelines a real network of pipes in yes yeah that's sending electricity believe
what I mean by completely mapped is you would like all the ties, all the friendships to be observed and traditionally
what social sociologists meant went for were the were the last two bullets, right, their their social networks were realistic they were completely mapped, right, they really spent time with people and inter interviewed them, so they had very rich knowledge about each particular node
but they were not large-scale and now or today with, I don't know, emergence of web and all the social networking booksites and social networking websites, we can sort of approach having all three of these points and what I mean by that is for example we have logs of like myspace, facebook right has, myspace, I think has like seventy-five millions of users, facebook has like ten millions of users, we also have logs of like email, blogging, electronic markets, instant messaging and so on
so we want to analyse large networks, the reason for that is that
once we have enough of data, properties will start to emerge, right, statistics will start to work but there's also
some some things one needs to be careful about, so what I show here is, for example, different scales of social networks like, for example, we ha here here I am showing like a five hundred node network of email ex email exchange in our corporate research lab, then, for example, a bit larger network is a similar email exchange over two years at some large university, right, that was almost like fifty thousand nodes for example
if you look at the
network of friendships on a large blogging community, you come to four four point four millions of nodes, but, for example, if you look at all the communication over the microsoft instant messenger, then you're working with basically the whole world, you're working with two hundred forty million people
talking every, day exchanging more than a billion conversations a day and so on and this is something that I'll I'll talk about later, so
how how does the this massive network data that I was just showing compare to like small small-scale studies, right, how does it compare to the karate club little network as we saw and there are we get more and we get less of something, right, we get more in a sense that we can observe glo global phenomena that are genuine and actually
wouldn't be wouldn't be visible at when studying smaller networks, so this is what we get more right we can observe something with higher confidence or we can observe things that we wouldn't be able to observe when we would have too small too small network or too small number of people that we are observing, what we get less of is that we don't really know
what the node or link means, right, we just see its strays ,right, we didn't really go and spend time with these people to really know the story of each one of them, so
it's very easy to measure things, but it's very hard to que ask the right questions
and what is the goal is to find some point where these two lines of research would meet, right, where we can have
some of these good things of
large networks and also we would like to know things about node and links in the network, so that
we can make inference
there are two things one can or at least two things one what what what one can think of when working with networks, so
and this is also, how my tutorial will be structured, we can we can think about structure and there are many properties of the structure and for now
there're just a lot of them and I'll explain them later and the other thing what one can think about is also the processes and dynamics of the network, what I mean, a process would be something that spreads over the graph or a changes a graph in some way and this would be like epidemics cascades, viral marketing is going on I don't know on social networks and so on
for the structure of networks what we're interested in
is what is the structure that the network has, I don't know, a network like this and how did it become to have to have such structure or why is this really there and then for diffusion, what we are interested is
the spread of things over the network and, for example, here I have a picture of one of them is a product recommendations and the other one is the spread of tuberculosis and
there we are interested in the properties of the network that, I don't know, will tell us whether the wireless will die or survive in in the network
so here is what I'll talk about today
so so this is the plan for the first hour and a half is to go through the structure and models of the networks, so basically, first we'll see what are the properties of large graphs and why do we care about them and then the second part will show, how do we model them and how do we think about them, then after the lunch I think, this will come will be, I'll talk about the dynamics of networks, which means is, how do things propagate the networks, how the viruses spread, how does the information spread, how do we detect viruses effectively and so on
how do we model them and also and then the last part will be case studies, where I'll be talking about this microsoft ins instant messenger network and also
how does the web look like, how do we find bad people on ebay and so on
so okay, this is the first part now
and again, the first part will have three parts
so, and then I'll stop so I won't go deeper, so there will be like structure, models and how do we fit models to the data
so okay, the structure
let me so I I think i made this point clear already that traditionally
we were
we were analyzing, I don't know, networks of hundred nodes and if you ha take a traditional social networks book, there will be there will be appendix say that there will be table with the data and you would go
type in type that data in your computer and start doing research on it right
as the networks as we are interested in
or the networks that are available today, obviously wouldn't fit in a single book so
that's that's not something that that's
appropriate, the other thing is that I also want to emphasise here is that the question types of questions we're asking changes a bit right, in traditional settings we would ask things like, what happens if a node is removed from the network, so we would really do like a node-centric type of analysis if you like, what we would ask today is like what percentage of nodes needs to be removed from the network, I don't know, to disconnect it so what num what number of computers do I need to remove from the internet to to break the network
and as I said
we are having these three goals where we have statistical properties, models that can help us understand and think about them and then
ultimately what we'd like is to do some kind of predict behaviour, generate models, generate realistic synthetic graphs and so on
the basic question that we'll be asking in the first part is how does the graph look like and how could we generate it and so
let's think of what is the simplest way to generate a graph, right, and in this is called a random graph model or in erdos-renyi or poisson random graph model, so this was all developed in sixties and it's very nice and rich mathematical theory and let's think of it this way, so let's say that somebody gives us N nodes and the way we'll create a graph is that we'll we'll connect each pair of nodes
independently with some probability P right, so we have a we put nodes on the table, now we pick two nodes at random and connect them and we keep doing this, until we added some number of edges in the network
the question to ask is are real networks like this, so now let's see how real networks are like
thing that is observed with graphs is they call it
get approximate first of all by
something on unit balls
could do better on the half intervals
down a little
stop when
and then i can do better
four rules i would approach
the limit is the scale gets finer and finer get the function
i have to be integers
OK should be in which all integers
my infinity
one minus one plus or minus two
i'm working on the whole
line here are not to far from my functions
no i think
i would have to take a look at its
can i could write it as two
two times
so you could say that this could be one
right let me just drop of two t minus one distribution
so two t-minus here's what we're allowing the free of to belong which i belong
draw from
two t
minus one is that's it
just so we see one one
at first glance looks like we're shifting in the unit interval
but because it's too t minus one
where does the two demons once
i'm claiming it's it's right here
right next
it's a shift because you see when
two years i have
it seems to be zero and not the function be starting twenty years
this will be one of the functional began being so sold
so yes
this is not by here
this guy
so it comes out right
well welcome to i find point for finite point yes
maybe i should allow infinite combinations
but it's
but but if you keep them with finite energy so the
taylor fred infinity
it's of course our entire focus is sort of function
on a finite interval
but if we want
these spaces get all these functions on the whole line and probably better
that there be
inflammation combinations
if lim many
kernel combination
you've hit on the central question that that's the key
but it so that this sort of loneliness here
the same year should be contained in the one but it was since the key
to everything
because it means
the first guy
in particular fifty which are like champion
member of the zero
all the other just shifts of it the first guy
also in the one
of all places on particular are
person has to be one of
what it remains is supposed to be a combination of these guys so that's the
key so that these are only one
it leads to
leads immediately to
the fact that have to be
it's supposed to be the one want to be one
with some coefficients column each of k
the basis functions
for a while
i'm jumping the gun you could say
or leading the way whatever
by using
notation h for the coefficients in fact old you going for all the major are
OK so you have no doubt that
those so is a link between
set up
bunch of spaces
with the basis
the previous
discussion of
particularly h
so the answer is definitely yes
in this
this is what you could say the classical way
in two thousand
in two thousand one new century there's like
you might try to us
you might find this somewhat
and you might be trying to create wavelets on spheres because you wanted to represent
the geopotential is the combination of wavelet
or wavelets on surfaces because
he worked for pixar in there
same toy story or other
that's become of
application out of
computer-aided geometry and
the surfaces are all but that's like second generation
this is the
place to start
equation to start with
it's the function or functions here is the combination of
we have two t-minus k and of course you saw what happened here
and the coefficients one one and one
coefficients were the full box
is which is somewhere here
it's obviously one of the works was one of the largest the coefficients or one
and one in in particular example
that's the easiest example
so this is the of two t fifty
i don't think raising
for equation
three members of box fifty is sensitive to t
and in length
i don't think it is
i want you to think about why that is not correct
look carefully where that al comes into my differential equation and you will probably come
up with the right answer
and i claim that the actual l that we should have taken
is a little bit larger i don't know how much larger but it's a little
bit larger so that also
make the observed period
become larger than the predicted
so i'm not too optimistic that we will go
and it is
the way we want to hear it but that's good because that's where the physical
eyes that you see
there are other factors that have to be taken into account
i'll turn this
one of at all no
make it completely dark in the classroom
because you're going to see on the right you can see the liquid
you see the liquid now
i see these equations two
it's zero
so let me try to
this is a
the string
large swing then so enormously that
i really want to get a very large swing
that's nice
not bad
twelve point one eight
a little bit of light
so observed
ten t
twelve point one eight
OK my reaction time o point one
so t observed
is one point
let's make it too
wasn't mine is o point o one sec
that's not bad
it actually has an overlap if you have this one here you get one to
and if you should check you could also want one
so it's not that i expected it to be a little higher but
close enough to be happy
think about why l should have been taken with the words
one more
very interesting
portional opened
so while they are two-and-a-half meter steel wire
hanging something on the bottom which we're going to offset
and that's going to oscillate back and forth
it's called torsion opened
and we're going to calculate the period of oscillation they have wonderful properties
there are no way like a spring
like a one-dimensional spring
remember the one-dimensional string
that we have
period which was independent of the
well within reason of course
make the amplitude too large
and you get permanent deformation of the spring
we never had to make any small angle approximation was the
spring as we had to do with the pendulum
here is the dependent
portion opened
is obama
and it is the weight here in this way weighty i tell you more about
that later
hanging from the ceiling has a certain length l
this is point
we're going to twist it
and then we'll all going to let it oscillate
this bar in the horizontal plane
when you look from above
you will see the bar here
o point here
and then
we can offset over an angle theta
and then it will oscillate back and forth
the port
a relative to point b
not very similar to what we had was a sprain
we have a minus sign
then that
illustrates it is restoring instead of a
OK now we have a cap
which is what we call the portion of spring constants
and now we have an angle
which we call
so we generally taught
which is proportional
angle very similar to the linear spring whereby we generate force
which is proportional to the linear displacement
now you generate torque which is
linearly proportional to the angle
and this is
the moment of inertia about point p
kinds of five of five stated about
so we're going to get that data double dots
cross cap
time theta
divided by of p
equals zero
captured by the way
so we have a differential equation
clearly that going to see a simple harmonic oscillation
this is a constant
three going to get theta
you people will say to maximum
omega was five getting boring
angular frequency
and the frequency
and angular frequency histogram
of kappa
cited by
the moment of inertia
about point p
and therefore the period
which is by divided by omega
close to pi
i'm going to ask this question
why are we here
that is to say
you know we all of us
you want to study the ancient greeks
i think it's reasonable
four people
who are considering
the study of a particular subject college courses
that's why they should
what is it about
the ancient greeks between the years that i mentioned two
it deserves the attention of people in the twenty first century
i think
the answer is to be found or these one it's the truth is there are
many edges and some of them is it's just terribly interesting
but that's very much of a
but somewhere along the opposite of object
subjective observations by me
so i would say are less subjective one is that i believe
that it comes from their position that is to say the position of the greeks
at the moment and the most significant starting point of western civilization
which is the culture that most powerfully shapes not only the west
but most of the world today
it seems to me the evidence that whatever its other characteristics
the west has created
of government and law
that provide unprecedented freedoms
for its people
it's also invented a body of natural scientific knowledge and technological achievements that together make
possible a level
of health
and material prosperity
on dreamed of
in earlier times
and i know
outside the west and those places that have been influenced by the way
i think the nobel prize laureate VS naipaul
a man born in trinidad
in paris
i was right
when he spoke of the modern world as
universal civilization
shape chiefly
by the way
most people around the world who know knows
i want to benefit from the achievements of western science and technology
many of them also want to participate in its political freedoms
moreover experience suggests that a society cannot achieve the full benefits of western science and
without a commitment to reason and objectivity
as essential to knowledge
and to the political freedom that sustains the
and helps us to move forward
the primacy of reason and the pursuit of objectivity therefore
both characteristics
of the western experience
it seemed to me to be essential for the achievement of the desired goals
almost anywhere in the world
the civilization of the west however
was not the result of some inevitable process
through which other cultures will automatically pass
it emerged from a unique history
in which chance
an accident
often played a vital part
the institutions and the idea is therefore that provide for freedom
an improvement in the material conditions of life
cannot take root and flourish
without an understanding of how they came about
and what challenges they have had to surmount
non-western peoples who wish to share the things that characterizes modernity
you will need to study the ideas and history of western civilization to achieve what
they want
and westerners i would argue
who wish to preserve these things
must be the same
the many civilizations adopted by the human race
have shared basic characteristics
have tended towards cultural uniformity
and stability
the reason although it was employed for all sorts of practical and intellectual purposes in
some of these cultures
it still lacked independence from religion
and like the highest data to challenge the most basic received ideas
standard form of government
has been monarch
outside the west republics
i have been on and
have been thought to be divided or appointed spokesman for divinity
religious and political institutions and beliefs have been thoroughly intertwined
as a mutually supportive unified structures
government has not been subject to secular reasoned analysis
it is rested on religious authority tradition and power
it represents what i think the problem since working data is most likely to be
so given a training set s
in the so the bayesian procedure we would
have made the probability the posterior probability of by parameters given my training set
hands on
francis and export so my posterior
well my parameters given my training set by bayes rule is proportional to the
right so the by bayes rule
holocaust here
and this
the distribution of represents my police about what data is often seen that
and when i want to make a new prediction in the presence of new holes
a new input x
i would say that while the distribution over the possible housing prices for the for
you for new housing trying with the price of say given the size of the
house the features of the house x and the training set had previously
it's going to be given by
and integral over different states of y given x commentator
and times the
perceive distribution of data given the truth
in particular one year prediction
to be the expected value
on y given
input x and training set
you would say integrate
over y
tons of hysteria
you take an expectation of what i respect your posterior distribution
and you know that when i was writing this down to what the bayesian formulation
announced that you right here y given x common data because this formula now is
the value of y conditioned on the values of the random variables x and data
some no longer writing semicolons data rates commentator because i'm not treating theta on
as a random variable
this is somewhat abstract this on
and it turns out the circle of questions about this
this this stable concrete it turns out that
for many problems of
both of these steps in the computational difficult because of your hatred and this one
dimensional vectors and this one dimensional parameter vector
and this is an integral over inverse one-dimensional
one of our employees one
and this numerically very difficult to compute integrals over all of a very high dimensional
spaces so
usually this integral usually is hard to compute the posterior one theta and also hard
to compute this in the ground state is very high dimensional
on a few exceptions
always this can be done in closed form for main many learning algorithms
the bayesian logistic regression this this is hard to do
and so was coming done is to take the posterior distribution
and instead of actually computing the full posterior distributions here theta given us on
well instead
take this quantity on the right-hand side
and just maximize discounted the right hand side so register
and so on
commonly instead of computing the full posterior distributions
we will choose the following
which is the was called the MAP estimate on the maximum posse or e
as the data which is the most likely value of data most probable value of
data on the posterior distribution and that this
here theta
and then we need to make a prediction
you just predict
using your usual hypothesis on and using using this map the value of data
in place of this as as the front affected choose
carbons on either side of that would be designated as follows or you want to
see http
two dots and this is called manfully
this is called this the methylene radical
and the only other one that i really care about in the
is the one that comes from
FAC two h six is
so the radical from this would be c two
h five and this is called the full
radical one will come across some compounds
one that
we need socially is ethyl alcohol we put the
alcohol functional group on the
and of the full
so that gives you an introduction to alkanes so now let's go back and look
at the next
colin that's the l keynes
so now we look at unsaturated
hydrocarbons and the first example is the
now keynes and these are characterized by SP two
hybridisation so that means at least in one place
it only takes one released in one place in the molecule there's the carbon carbon
o double bond
and that will give you far we have is this one
carbon carbon double bond
it will give us
the chemical formula c ten h two and
and clearly and must be
greater than equal to
greater than or equal to two so the simplest one is
c two h four which we've seen already
we talked about
sigma pi bonding this is ethylene
and hydrogens here we have sp
two hybridisation so we have one sigma bond and one pi bond so the carbons
and the hydrogens line playing
this is one hundred twenty degrees
we've seen all four
the ethylene is the common name for it but the the
the name that's
were regulated by the international union of pure and applied chemistry is following this
nomenclature we take the
ETH because seed numbers two and we have a and e so the formal name
for this is FAC
not ethylene but
you can use either one was going to
very agitated about it and then for n greater than two
for n greater than two
the position of the double bond is not fixed
position o double bond
not fit
so we can show
examples of that let's look at here's one beauty
c four
h a
so one has to put the double bond very and
so i just got one double bond and
there's one hundred twenty degrees hydrogen hydrogen now one two three four
one two three four one two three four so this is c four h eight
and this is called one
eugene because the double bond is off of the
the first carbon
or we can put
the double bond somewhere along the line so we can do this
so the double bond is not at the very end
o five methyl group at the end
one two three four one two three four
so this would then be called two
two beauty
two beauty indicating the double bond comes off
number two
one beauty into beauty
turn out to be constitutional isomers because they got the same chemical formula but they
have a different mix of
constituent groups so let's label this is constitutional
these are both constitutional
i some
but we can zoom in a little bit more on two beauty and introduced yet
this is this is only the total probability of these passes only the probability that
i that set frames but given that i that sort of ice creams were interested
in which of these powers was the best way of explaining that happens to be
so if we want to know
whether i am sorry whether the second it was hot weather we ended up at
this stage
so we can look at the total probability of all paths that go through here
which will be very small because it's them explains the entire diary
with the additional
requirements that
the second ever called
and we look at the total probability of all of these
also very small explains the whole diary with the additional requirement the second bihar and
maybe this is the total probability powers that go through here
as a hundred times greater
the total probability has it go through their so that it would be
the probability
the second being how would be
a hundred times as great
as the second a being called
all right
how can we do this efficiently well i've given you a little head
with the numbers that we've written here
the basic idea is that if we want to know how many
pads come through here let's start out by looking at the total probability of all
paths that come to the
actually let's look over here the probability of we've got more stuff to the left
look so we want to know the total probability all has come through come to
where every every path
every path probabilities the productivity arcs
there's two ways that you can get it right
you can you can take flight through here applied through their
there's only two rounds
well of course to get here there are four ways to do two is to
do it and get here there are two ways to do it
but let's put that offer moment
if we
once we get here
the total probability of all paths here the total probability pounds coming through here
will call that alpha
times the cost of getting from here to here
right so that's all paths they get to here via the
so it's out of this state total probability of all paths
to hear time's point five six
the total probability of all paths to hear that come through here
which is alpha here times point o seven
clear enough so the idea is we can get out of here if we know
the office here and here
how do we get over here
by knowing the office from here to here how do we get out of here
well that is OK because really coming from start so this is our base case
total probability of all paths serious point of one
similarly over here that alpha is point one now let's work forward
over here we go
probability of getting here is point of one
o point o one
times the cost of the story let's start over here point one the south
total probability has here times point seven that's this
plus this point one
time point five six
the pads coming from here and that's point o six three
and similarly
total probability will pass there is point oh
now we also have at this stage
we want to know the total probability of all patterns here
we take that point o nine and we multiply by point seven
and we take this point o six three so the total the sum of those
two pounds
this one
and that one is point o six three
we multiply by o point five six we get that and so we find point
to point o three six
so let's see how we actually computer this on the spreadsheet because we used to
to compute the
to compute the graph before
so here we have
OK so here the alpha numbers for the cold states
we have a point o one point o nine point o o one three five
and you saw this size these are exactly the numbers you saw on the diagram
a moment ago and what's happening to these numbers as we go down
again much much smaller how come
well multiplying which makes things more but we're also adding i mean we're adding a
lot of paths together so it's not obvious
right away the
they should get smaller
it's gonna get smaller right but remember that every stage not only were multiplying but
we're also adding
so you know there's
you have the thing from the cold state anything from heart
OK how come
OK but we're we're in some sense for not choosing between hot and cold right
because we're adding those possibilities together
that i think is the same answer i just give monica
so over here
when we ask about BLP here
we're considering both the hot and cold possibilities here
we consider going through here and going through here
so the numbers are getting smaller we are making some choice for not choosing the
the animation of the body that that argument if it doesn't work but now we've
got a new one
you need the soul in order to explain free will
when we come back to that argument later to good arguments as that are well
worth taking seriously let's come back to later first let's run through some other things
that might be appealed to as candidates for feature
suppose somebody said look you know it's true
we don't need to appeal to solve in order to explain why bodies move around
and non random fashion but
i have a very special ability and so the argument goes that mere bodies couldn't
have physical can explain that the ability
to think
it's the ability
two reasons
people have beliefs
and desires
and based on their beliefs about how to
to fill their desires
they they play they make plans to have strategies the reason about what to do
this this this tightly connected set of facts about us
beliefs desires reasoning
strategizing planning
you need to appeal to so the argument goes you need to appeal to us all
to explain that
mere machine
could believe
no mere machine
has desires
no mere machine could reason
easy to see why you might think that sort of thing when you stick to
sort of simple machines
it's pretty clear that there are lots of machine that doesn't seem natural to ascribe
beliefs desires or goals are reason
my lawn mower for example
it doesn't
to cut the grass
even though it does cut the grass doesn't have the desire it doesn't think to
itself how shall i get that laid that's of graph has been eluding me
so it's easy to see why we might be tempted to say
mere machine
could think or reason why have beliefs or desires
that argument is much less compelling nowadays
i think it would have been twenty
forty years ago
in an era of
it seems with quite sophisticated computer programs it seems at least at the very least
to talk about
and reasoning and strategizing so suppose for example
we've got a chess playing computer
my computer at home i got a program that allows my chest to play computer
i myself
i think that just this
this program can be me made know blind
i move
my bishop
the computer moves its queens
what we say
about the computer why did the computer move its queen or virtual queen why computer
move queen
well the natural thing to say is
it's worried about the fact that the king is exposed
and it's trying to block me
by capturing my fisher
that is what we say
about computer playing programmes
think about what we're doing
worst driving
desires to the programme
we're saying
it's got an ultimate desire to win the game certain subsidiary desires to protect its
king capture my king certain other subsidiaries are out to protect its various other pieces
along the way
it's got beliefs about how to do that by blocking certain patterns
or by
exposing make other pieces on my side vulnerable it's got beliefs about how to achieve
its goals
and then it's
puts those
combinations of beliefs and desires into action by moving in a way that a rational
to my move
it looks as though
the natural thing to say about the chess playing computer is it does have beliefs
it does have desires it does have intentions it does have goals it does reason
it does all of this it
to this
limited extent only able to play chess but to that extent it's doing all these
things and yet
we're not tempted to say are we that are
computer has a non-physical part
we can explain how the computer does all this in strictly physical terms
and of course once you start thinking about this way it's natural to talk this
way and
because of course the right across a variety of
things that the computer maybe trying to do
now because it's perfectly open to you as jules to respond by saying
although we
the computer
we treat it as though it was the person
as we know it had beliefs
and desires and so forth
coming back to the stuff we're talking about before with structured output
the undirected ones actually got more commonly used than directed one so for example
ground this thing into
c natural language or some kind of
it's sequences in bioinformatics same label
introns exons
one thousand miles in HMM right i have state variables
generating some kind of observations so let's call these
why is why
no one x one
y two
thanks to
so by the way the variable elimination algorithm
will correspond to
if you eliminate
this way something like
four it you need to backward if you want to get everything else back but
i look forward backward or itterby algorithms will be exactly the
instantiation of information about that but this is
direct version of this there's a much more popular version of for doing this kind
of tasks that one so you building watson intron exon centre or enabling things like
part of speech or named entity recognition or whatever in natural language
so more common models of this year conditional random fields
that's the thing i talked about
in the first hour so you can think of it more as like that
right it's basically undirected edges these my my y max is very different but what
happens is we can
very subtle
i have different where we can learn this thing conditional to be conditional distribution which
is this p of y given x as opposed to the gay which stressed model
x come why both of them
and this is the standard of discriminative versus generative trade-off in
in supervised learning to compare something like bayes against the CMC
it doesn't do so well maybe by the way
just to be clear
its main base we have some class variable
and generates features
so it's one of the simplest bayes nets
and there is
so this doesn't do as well from when you have an opinion of data as
well as an SVM or something that's essentially
you pointing to on the other way
so these things are posterior estimates that the
kind of structured output stuff
built upon
OK so
directed models that are actually might be useful
in a lot of situations where we have
unlabelled data so we need since the generative models
in order to complete
complete hidden variables have a latent latent structure that we're trying to kind of used
to explain the data
in directed models are usually the best thing that
OK so
right so moralisation it's the term kind old-fashioned term what that means is basically
we're taking our business turning it into kind of an equivalent markov networks because of
the inference algorithms work on
markov networks so
five to here there is no
there's no question what to do in this district translates into this
we can basically take
this conditional probability table in color factor
you know there's some to anything
to factor factor to to
comes have
these structures
basically what's what's called american parents right so so you have to this that are
not connected OK so now i'm factor here that's over three variables x y and
z ratified just introduced too far too wise e and
x z
canada was reason full correlation between what i need is a factor over x y
and hands what we do is take this thing and map into market networks we
introduced edges
between unmarried and that's called moralisation
very simple things that allows you now makes clique there and then we can put
it we can kind of comedy are
cpt the conditional probability table
from the business science
this fact
OK so
is an example so here's our graphical model here
we have mary on the parents that that line vendor ones
OK and then once everything is moralize we just drop the direction
that's it so that's kind of one of preparation for
so now we have to be talking just mapped everything into undirected models now let's
look back at that variable elimination thing we did without any reference to graph structure
all we need needed there was conditional independencies right we do it without any definitions
of business or market that you can do it now
and this is my first sense in terms of graph OK so there are
this intermediate factors there are being created when you
eliminate things and they
essentially correspond to to
factors in reduced graphical model
so you can think of variable elimination as the way to
take a model
and then kind of some of one variable a time
you some
time what might happen is introduced
new correlation between the remaining variables
and so
that's exactly what we're not elimination is essentially variable elimination but just to conceive graphically
so you know and then you create mission clique which means you take
all of its neighbors
and and you know make the cliques so you connect all the neighbors ahead of
also an example basically all the neighbours of this node i'm not going to be
interconnected to whoever
things but i'm going to put my strongly entrenched things at the top
OK now as i said what entrenchment is essentially an ordering over the formulas in
if you remember back to the rationality properties that we had at the outset one
of the rationality properties so that if we got
a preference between any two formulas
you have to give one i prefer to give up the least preferred to the
most profound
so he was going to say that we're going to try and give up the
least entrenched over the most entrenched
i can as actually what this ordering looks like is as follows
the most important stuff
so the most deeply entrenched
which is the it is the top
the tautologies
things that are always true
then we've got
all of these levels
at the very bottom
i got all the formulas by
such that is not order
so these are all the non
can we got this entrenchment
between forms
so at the outset we said that you know in this belief change problem we
can use logical criteria line so essentially what we're going to do is we're going
to add to our logic
epistemic entrenchment this relation over formulas
which tells us how important performers are relative importance of one
OK so formally the
this relation
has the following properties
the first is that satisfies transitivity
you know
yes i should draw this this
one x
to be
do this in one x
even more important
so if x is more important than why why is more important than that of
course exist
transitivity holes
the second one says that
if size the conclusion of five follows from five
then size more important five
say what you think
OK why
why is that the case
let's put it this way that if
if i if i
and i want to remove side
do i have to refine
so a five three sign i one
is finding
and better not be because if it is
from the five precise going to get it back
so if i do retain five
when i want to give up so i was going to get syed back because
phi tells simon remember that came minus five deductively closed for us
so if i want to so i have to give up five i can not
give up five because it violated there's going entail
on the other hand if i want to give five
but there's no reason for me to give up side
can retain sci-fi really want to
OK so that tells me that size is going to be at least as important
as far
i have to i have to always give up five
but in some cases
can retain i can retain side
OK now is the second possible tells us that we know that phi
and so i
tells phi
that also entails psi
so by this first
this image is what are the dominant orientation so the picture
so the jews what they call the manhattan greedy assumption is many human images that
contain only basically two dominant axis and the only thing that you want to know
is what is the invention of the camera relative to the axis
so here
all the parameters that you need to know is what is the the elevation of
the ground
and then what is the relative orientation of the camera with respect to the
to the great
and because that's very limited is very few information that you need to collect the
very few parameters that define the camera you can do that but you've obviously from
the image so this information that you can get very is from the picture
and once you've done that then you can label different edges in the image as
belonging to one of the dominant orientation in this great
which is basically all you need to start getting some simple for
so here the new images receiving in-depth are marked in red and then vertical lines
are marked in blue
but alas the camera in green
another thing that they can do then is once you had these you can try
to see which of just violate great which have just outside of the manhattan great
so here is an example in which they had this scene and it is this
bicycle here and edges of the bicycle don't aligned with the great so they are
able to pop out this bicycle some parts of the bicycle has been something that
violates the manhattan greedy assumptions
also the three here seems to imagine that
there is this interesting paper about community c and system and all single view metrology
which is an interesting read if you want to know about most of the things
that you need to know in order to solve a simple geometric problems from single
and of course you can also just stereo vision
but you monocular images is also very interesting because many of the images on the
web are always going to be monocular
and also most of the time even for humans you are using monocular cues most
of the time stereo is good for short range things but as soon as things
get far away stereo become so weak real monocular cues are dominant
and so there is this work OK thank you and
there is this this this work by
and there are k first anniversary in which they also very simple geometric information about
the scene in order to provide context information from detections so in this case again
they company image if you know what the camera is i you know what the
ground plane is you know what i suspected sizes of objects in the picture you
also know what should be the relative locations with respect to the ground plane
so for instance here if you have all these just here and you know that
all discussion of this people they are sitting on the ground therefore they should be
aligned with the right online
and you can infer with ISO online is by just looking at this very simple
perspective patterns from image
so once you have that information can be like a book review of this image
and once hundred detections you can know what are the three locations of objects in
image and this is all done from a single view there's no stereo images here
so here is an example of how you can use this to improve detection so
this will be the actions don without integrating any information about geometry so here you
we have a bit of detectors can detect errors
if you have also just happened st and there are some false alarms over there
two was you know what the ground plane is
and you know that i online is here that can help you to remove most
of the false alarm so all the false alarms that were on top of the
building are
then the detections that were maybe two weeks before now become more confidence and i
do know that all these are all pedestrians
there are so many false alarms that like this one here the
there is not really understand or here
but again it's detection of what's cooking with context i got hands
so in this in this case that using an explicit representation of the information but
is very simple
three the information is just the actual line
it's is very very basic human need to have a full three d reconstruction of
the image
there's another piece of work also do seem for the information in this case they
also introduced earlier
and they have a car driving on the street and the goal is to reconstruct
the straight into indentified or just within so again you can have a kind of
shows the many false alarms
one is integrated information to get rid of most of the four times and you
can even put a small for the cubes around just to have detected
and you can also have a more restricted eighty three d representation not just the
ground plane and but try to actually get a moral discourse representation of what the
three d of the picture is
so there is a bunch of water that now have appeared on the community but
have recently
trying to give a single image get simple representation of the three the picture is
and that representation can be something like joe's into names with the ground plane and
if you were to planes that percent like buildings and so on and so there
is this work again by of in which given an image
the first segment the image and now
it's segment you have to decide if it is some segment or a vertical segment
and you can do that quite reliably again because general trying to do very fine
you know attracted to the sum directors for example
it's not a joke i
at the end
i would like to share
is much more much astronomy the
for real
hi temple
the long tail to be brought to the didn't have before
the creation those are much stronger
did on sets of the nodes that have been changed
so is it was more swing
more string and the input so all these are
decisions taken by the system and actually implement
i don't understand what
the is lower frequency than
and how you can not just tool
noticeable and
slower tempo will always much more
the just OK so
now a few words about the tempoexpress one lesson we learned from this exit system
is that the effect of the temple
on this facility was crucial was extremely extremely important
then with its leader the church search and we found several papers and we have
to our surprise
we found that there was some controversy about the effect of of temple in music
for example there is a well known well cited worldwide
he says that uniform time stretching is enough
to change from one template to another temple uniform time stretching means that for example
if you have two hundred and ninety bpm
this discriminative temple two hundred so increase by twenty percent
well you you just what you have to do
want to the temple after the duration decreases by twenty five percent
one divided by zero point eight
there are other people however publish papers
again is that because the human contributions
that uniform time stretching may work in some particular situations but in general is not
used up to that in works so you lose you lose lots of musicality of
musical quality maybe not sound quality different sound quality can be very good but musical
quality not
music qualities is more associated with specific so very well known people and peter hunting
from kth or undigested back
they provide counter evidence on some cases and
on the other hand said the listeners are capable to distinguish above chance level between
a recording of a performance that has been uniformly time restriction to temple from my
system but i know the original recording of the target temple
and this formation by peter hunting is that expressivity is a result of the conception
of the music by the performer and this conception changes with tempo
when you are told to play of the of even tempo
you do
you some expressive resources and when you multiply it another temple
if it is
of course significant difference
construction is different in your play
this is only in terms of a specific so what we did is let's see
well actually uses this shows an example of how the onset
the onset of the nodes drastically changes from a slower tempo too fast temple for
faster temple much more nodes are anticipated than slower tempo for the saying the same
this is the same happens with all the other
although expressive services like ornamentation consolidations implementations of nodes that was you know what
so many things change as a function of temple so what we did was the
goal is to
i said that was should the selfless
how to automatically change the temple
of the performance
preserving expressivity or adopting this specifically so that at the target tempo
that's still does in meet the
the musicality of the performances
it is
at least as good as the source temple
and i was in the context of jazz standards not only just ballots success maybe
i didn't say that but just sex is limited right now to jazz ballads it
to just
and this has a very interesting application by the way and we had to we
had contact with with with new post processing company the software company
my nose the manly
is done mainly in commercial farming TV commercials
the commercial how limited the very limited number of seconds
the commercial very expensive right and then the video constrains the only
maybe you have a beautiful view that google very well with this story with these
images but it is a slightly longer do you don't want just look at it
like this drastically you would like to know to stretch it or to make it
shorter or longer depending on the on the original temple OK
so that it will fit the the fifteenth second order and the second iteration of
the commercial so these instead of being done manually takes hours and hours
with the
tempoexpress it can take minutes following
that the city and again if that fraction is relatively high then it turns out
i can actually compute the probability
barcelona's city based on the tax one important caveat is when we do these counts
it's important to do those over independent sentences often write sentences are repeated over the
web other quoted and we don't want to count we have a variety of ways
of determining that two sentences are likely to be independent of each other in this
work that doug downey did we actually formalise this very specifically just to show you
know we don't just build systems we actually as the precise question if an extraction
x appears k times in a set of n distinct sentences what is the probability
that x is a member a particular class classier particular relation are
and it turns out that we were able to derive using combinatorial model a closed
form solution for for exactly this this probability and this closed form solution was fifteen
times as accurate as
previous work so it turns out that using combinatorial techniques we can actually formalise a
lot of what's going on in these extraction processes and what's happening with with redundancy
so so here the key ideas in textrunner first of all open a over the
web is actually possible we can take arbitrary sentences and extract in english and extracting
meaningful information from that secondly
we've been able to identify a tractable subset of english it's not the case that
we can take any arbitrary english sentence and find meaningful extraction from an but we've
been able to identify tractable subset of english which is interesting in and of itself
and lastly where we have a bunch of ideas that i just quickly alluded to
of using macro reading of using redundancy over literally
hundreds of millions and billions of sentences to help us identify errors and to help
us quantify the probability that are extractions are correct
so the next thing we did
is in error analysis of textrunner relations and again even with the mechanism described there
are plenty of errors and operating over the entire web here are some examples of
incoherent relations that we found the sentence for example the guide contains that links and
amid sites in in the CRF labeling process it decided that the relation here's contains
a minutes remember has no domain specific no relation specific knowledge and we actually found
out about thirteen percent of the time this was occurring so that's pretty significant we
also found that
about seventy percent of the time textrunner was extracting uninformative relations would
extract is as the relation between two entities were really the relation was is an
album by or is the author of or is a city and and really problematic
right because it might extract something like barcelona is spain as opposed to barcelona is
a city in spain
that's not what we want so the next system we build which is just coming
out we have a paper in the proceedings describes and also tony fader is the
paper to appear shortly in EMNLP was called reverb and it said for identifying relations
from river from from birds and the remarkable thing about reverb is it's incredibly incredibly
OK and actually to to do a quick great to one of my pet peeves
we actually have a hard time publishing this work because we were semantic offers people
say well you've got very nice results reverb actually the area under the precision precision
recall curve for river is two hundred percent higher than for textrunner right so it's
easily doable and people said give various empirical but this is so simple right we
cannot accept this and say no no when there's a problem and somebody had a
complex mechanism and we come up with something incredibly simple that's interesting
so if you're one of the reviewers of the paper please come and see me
after the talk we need to have some some words here but i i really
think it's important and i urge all of you except simple papers right if they
have demonstrated what what they're trying to show you because that's one of the ways
that the field advances not always this by creating more complicated mechanism
so we describe to this ridiculously simple mechanism the first step is you find the
longest phrase well we assign parts of speech to the sentence right using a part
of speech tagger that standard NLP technology right so we know what the verbs and
nouns and so on are but then we find the longest phrase matching a simple
syntactic constraint system regular expression that has three parts either we have ever
or we have the verb followed by a particle which is typically proposition or we
have ever followed by maybe noun adjective adverb pronoun and then by particle
that's it
that is are syntactic model of relations and this is based on empirical analysis of
text we've had a
virtually all the binary relations actually map to this form so why do we just
look for it explicitly it's the bias for the learning system the one refinement that
we had to have because we're looking for the maximum phrases that length sometimes phrases
grow out of control so we get relations like is offering only modest greenhouse gas
reductions at
that's that's not an appropriate relations so we add one more statistical constraint over the
corpus we said OK if you have something explaining to bear relation to make sure
that you see distinct argument pairs for this relation more than k times in case
the parameter of the algorithm we could learn and we just set to twenty by
hand work great a large corpus that's
these two constraints essentially some small twiddles but essentially are river
OK and we get relations like
inhibits tones tumor growth and voted in favor of mastered the art of
wrote the book on its centre a huge variety of relations across all domains and
if you look at how the richness compares to previous systems you see the previous
systems the number relations was in the in the hundreds even learning systems like no
on the order of five and relations some manual efforts go up to the few
thousands text writer had maybe on the order of one hundred thousand reverb has easily
more than one point five million
of of these relations is really a former successful if we look at the precision
recall curve now at low levels of recall we're approaching point nine or even you
and that's essentially variational bayesian model comparison
so that you're acquired data through experiments so that you can actually score your model with reference to the data
and then you can adjudicate very complex models are very sophisticated models and very simple
models and sometimes with noisy data the simple models with
you know there's no point in trying explain and they cannot be explained
that's how you actually practically do it
the question then is why
well and the then the new asked you know
do you need to experiments and in the sense that if the objective of the brain is to
optimise its model
that has defined a model with the highest evidence or the lowest free energy
which means it has to go out there and acquired data
the confirmed its hypotheses
so the very
the way that we behave could be construed as the way that we explore basically
the way that we did our lines has is curious balance of trying to maintain
a home eustace is
was the same time exploring model spaces to evaluate the evidence or the free energy
and then choosing
those are choosing data
that will confirm or disconfirm
your particular model hypotheses and then elect lecting together with those models i have the greatest free energy
so you have
this fine
and i often find more interesting than of
well they you well that's
well what i just just go to what i would have said
so you know you you know you're missing or you're what she was missing and
then we will recover conversation what i would then done is
give you an example of action
just in terms of cued reaching western trying to work at solver using optimal control
control theory in the conventional sense i we just created
a model in which agents believe that there
fingers are attached to a target with an invisible elastic band and then when the
when the chalk it changes colour
be elastic band becomes stiff
given those police i would have predictions both about what i would see my hand
doing and what feel my hands during which my reflexes would fulfill
hand basically what it would look like it was
what we call
cued reaching
in in in in your neuroscience so that i can simulate simply by giving an
agent's prior beliefs very much like
bayesian thermostat again here
i can prescribe movement
simply by prescribing prior beliefs about
what about movement should feel like and the sensory consequences
and if i
i can
take neural dynamics
i can prescribe those prior beliefs i've using point attractors four
using the rent attractors or itinerant attractors produce not only
reached the target
but also values
that's prior beliefs that have an itinerant wandering form with carefully chosen
the biologically plausible when this competition
i actually visited succession apart unstable point attractors i can prescribe behaviors that look
very much like handwriting i can then go on
and examine those used plants classical experiments
looking at the movement cause i believe by myself and
then cutting
movements sensations and examine in terms that watching somebody else move
and then finally what we would have talked about it this is the sort of notion that's
why why do i explore where do i expect to look on the coming back
to to to your point about
the harvesting sensory information
essentially being conceived of has perception experiments that are there to to optimize my internal model of the world
and this can be formalized
in terms of so where do i look
you can actually formalize quite easily
in terms of
suppressing the joint
entropy of sensory inputs on the hidden causes and all requires you to do is
to supplement the minimization of all maximization marginal likelihood on minimization of surprise here
with minimizing your uncertainty
the sensory inputs all the hidden causes of the sensory inputs
which means i can absorb accidentally
free energy minimization
just by having the belief
but i will go and sample data that confirm my hypotheses
and if you plug that into
one those predictive coding schemes that simulations such as before
you can then produce
quite realistic well this is the architecture i would have used
you can produce quite realistic you can't you see this book
the movie was shown
after categorized the exploring visual input on the basis of
but now we can this is actually what
this is purely deterministic as randomness is a deterministic exploration of a static visual field
this projection here of x two on on your eye plain is exactly
what is it exactly
so the the projection
of x
on onto your hyperplane xy is exactly x
the projection on on your talk not which is
of dimension one
so it's for action only on the wall and the y coordinate
so if you have hyperplane
computing the projection on the vector of vector on that is very easy because you
just have to compute the projection on its
on excessive promontory
which is which is here the do
the y axis and you have only once carrier product compute right what if i
was to give you think about it if you were in
if you if i want to give you only two vector this and that's sandy
a propane here that that span displaying you have to
the products to compute their to find its projection
if you're in r and then the hyperplanes of dimension and minus one you may
find the basis vector that's of that is of legs and minus one but then
you have and minus one the products to compute
to compute the projection of x on the hyperplane
it's easier to go to the supplementary which is of dimension only one and compute
only one the product
to compute the projection
on top of it you can see that because you have this nice property that
the square of the norm two
do some up
then the distance
of x so my approach in h
it is squared
plus the product of its
on the y coordinate square
is exactly the norm of x squared
now if i want to find distance
i just think in all of us and i and minus the
square of the coefficient of the orthogonal subspaces
and the last to do
the last thing that is written this transparency which is actually the first thing is
because it when it is in the pain then
using its supplementary you may find an equation of of h which is really easy
just said that
any victories in eight is the vector that is orthogonal
two you
when you
is the vector that spans the supplementary of g i be right
it's actually more
it's actually more difficult to say that that
two c
if you if you are in there are two and you're a hyperplane is
the line that is orthogonal to the vector u
then you have this equation of therefore the hyperplane
the the distance
actually that that was really wrong
if you said yes but that it was really
OK so come back to that and you know it this distance of it's your
hyperplane exists that given by the absolute value of the dot product of x with
x was you and the projection is this one
actually this would be the norm of the projection
of x
on hyperplane there
and the distance of
so you are the hyperplane is easily
this this distance there right so
here in my in my drawing there
this is the projection
the projection of x
unmarried poor pain
and that would be the distance
and the time
this ranks here is the edit distance of x to my hyperplane which is exactly
the length of this is the product of the projection on the y axis right
now if you have
now we go from from subspaces two linear set of equations matrices
so let's assume that you have
several hyperplanes and you want to find the index section of these these places
then you end up with that so you have an hyperplanes then you have an
so x is in the intersection if those in the equations of true at the
same time so it gives you a sense of and and the linear equation
with the unknowns which are you dx one x two x
and the set of linear equations may be written as matrix vector product
which is right here
if you forget about a hyperplane then you just have a set of linear equations
you may have a single here which yields a non-zero vector
so the main matrices matrices are
with the rules in the core of the columns
it is an array of numbers of real numbers it's actually an array may made
and we vectors or equivalently the
the column vectors
and you can can see matrix vector product
the demanded objects industry namely faces cars digits letters and we have not getting to
these details since the focus of today's lecture is about graphical models not about surveying
the entire computer vision literature for this but actually here in CMU we should be
very proud some of the best algorithms for these for these
categorisation come from CMU for example schneiderman is face recognition and
and we have a in one
i think a TNT bell as you could propose one of the best to do
recognition systems and so on
we want to go back to this problem
we want to instead of nose nose algorithms that categorize faces or digits are cars
tend to
tend to be very domain specific
and the designer has pumped into a lot of
human knowledge about the specific class of object but now that we want to actually
look at
the other side of the problem is generic object recognition had only
how do we find some kind of expression that we could hope
to begin to learn now hundreds of thousands of classes of objects
and on top of that
we may even want to put them into a meaningful hierarchy objects do have taxonomy
in nature we have animals that comes into families and groups species and so the
question is goes beyond just classifying individuals groups of objects we may even want to
put them together in some meaningful way or
there are there are context of in certain contexts that object recognition requires actually contextual
knowledge for example
what is the
a blob
but now
you probably have an idea what this object is we would for the first top
the image it might be
a wine bottle were plate for here in my b shoes so sometimes can recognition
and classification of objects are facilitated by the global recognition more our understanding of the
scene context so
OK let me just give this so
OK so i hope have basically
illustrated or or given to give a very brief introduction introduction about what is the
question of object categorisation
and then i've shown you some of the challenges of object categorisation and then they
went briefly over the history of object categorisation now let's put this language into us
to statistical will viewpoint so what is the task of object categorisation here we can
we can write down the probability
or write down this
this task in the following way
given an image
we want to understand
whether it contains
and in particular class
of object or not in this case we use zebra as an example
so this classification task becomes
a comparison between two
probability scores basically the first one is given the image
it was the probability of having the zebra the second one is given an image
what's the probability of not having
and as emperor
everybody is familiar with bayes rule
we are here to setting up some terminology here let's take one equation o well
one number here
probability of image given a given image probability of zebra
it can be expanded into probably the probability of
image given zebra
times the probability of zebra
over some normalisation factor
and now the same thing goes for this
and we also can expand this
here so here is the terminology this is called post-imperial ratio
this is called the likelihood ratio of this term is very important limit to elaborate
one more time the likelihood means given some kind of model
of the object class what is low likelihood of this particular instance
and this is the prior ratio so you'll see there's quite a bit in computer
vision papers dealing with this problem domain
OK so i rewrote what we've just seen here
so there are two big class if you want to
really and put them in groups of techniques that people are using
right now to solve this problem of object categorization and we we love them into
discriminative methods or generative methods
discriminative methods tend to do look at the poster directly and try to find boundaries
between these two classes or or
and classes well as generative methods try to go from models that could describe
or or even better generate images
the hero i'm going to repeat again it's in the more visual way that discriminative
missus look at
the direct boundary between the posterior probability of a given an image to we have
as above or not
generative methods really look at the likelihood probability
the likelihood probability if given the model
how likely is that image so in this case let's suppose
we have what we have in mind here is a model of zebra and what
we have in mind is