i mean look at things we going through you know the actual
know i was reading one of the articles in time magazine i think
this had only five people destroyed destroying the whole world
all of them came from harvard business school
and one of them is george bush and i'm surprised how the hell you could
go to
however to do MBA
somebody told me that there is a rule
if your father if your parents went to how would you can go to how
and is all you need is your mum and dad to be lower than you
make sure that happens
what kind of property that but for that's why because his father into howard so
you could go to any couldn't get any without mission
and they get some time in all of the hard work and all of them
to the economy either making the regulations very easy or
you know
straightforward corruption
i agree
so anyway the comes to these intrusion detection very small number of things to do
that and you have to catch them know these are like all players if you
think about it if you put of all this data together intrusion could be seen
as the player so the idea here is that many times outlier detections are very
difficult because you don't have enough sufficient statistics for building them in obvious way is
much harder
click-through data sets are also raised
so what we have done is CART quite simple and what you do is that
first of all your mind congress patterns
and then use these things as like seeds
you know for example you can apply your favorite
you know genetic algorithms you sees these patterns
and then you do do the crossing
instead of mutations
what you do is you look at some of the dominant features and the new
and the mean to these things and that's all we did it
and we were able to show that
i can build much robust classifiers like decision trees and other things using these rate
cancer dataset so here is an example
i know you're given
emerging patterns e one e two e three
you do some kind of combinations of these
and then let's say
we we know that value for is very
a high growth rate for the attribute for then you we synthesised entirely new sets
of points by using u one u two u three and therefore you generate these
things you can use very clever
you know some kind of genetic
hybrid icing
and cross
breeding or whatever you can do that and you build them new patterns and once
you feel this pattern make sure that doesn't contradict your positive instances so that means
you build an instance and it is too close to one of the positive instances
you might try this because it could be
correcting information so to make sure that the instance is created
not contradict with the
the major class
so the idea what i told you is the
decision trees the weighted decision trees based on emerging patterns is basically
you give weights that is how important these instances
in a in a in a strange way
what we're doing is we're doing it kind of classification already
because we are finding school
but what we're doing is instead entirely relying on that we are basically telling how
significant it is in terms of confidence because if the scores are very close to
both sides may be should not play a role in the decision tree building and
that's what the underlying model was and this is given as a very good results
and his father then KNN because can looks at all the features that is this
one looks set subspaces and that's why it's very very practical
and one more thing is that can only looks at the k nearest ones because
you do the sub-surface projection
you can see many more instances rather than just the neighborhood
thank you
i will be
so he's trying to say goodbye to
he didn't want to do publicly
so k nearest neighbour
you know probably have non you know you try to find the distance between two
points and typically you do they all the features
so here we can actually selectively project based on emerging patterns only those values were
looking at and that's where the
the strength comes for for these things
so maybe we won't have time to this one that you sign up for those
people who
work in databases
the red lines i really surfaces this three-dimensional you have to rotate the whole thing
about the vertical
these surfaces
and the red ones are positive potential services and the blue one's negative potential services
that is not important but the green lines of field lines
and notice if i take for instance this field lines
perpendicular view to read perpendicular there perpendicular there perpendicular there perpendicular year perpendicular here coming
in a perpendicular perpendicular perpendicular
everywhere you look on this graph you'll see
the field lines
are perpendicular
to the
the potential
and that is something that we now
i fully understand
the situation
means then that if you release a charge
at zero speed
that would always start to move perpendicular
uniquely potential surface because it always starts to move in the direction of the field
plus charge in the direction of the field line minor charge in the opposite direction
so if you in space
you release it charted zero screen it always takes off perpendicular to its potential
we have something similar
with gravity
if you
look at maps of mountaineers
contours of equal
people height
if you started skiing
he studied at that point
you started with zero speed
you would always take off
the potentials
this is the direction in which start
well if you start off with zero
and i want to give you some
feeling of the connection between potential
and electric fields
and i want you to follow me
very closely
it's that
but i make one two
follow me
i am
somewhere in space at position
at that position p there is a potential one unique potential
the offspring
to give them
and there is an electric field that
location where i am
and now what i'm going to do
i'm going to make an extremely small step only in the x direction
more wine lynsey only in the x direction
if i measure no change in the potential
over that little step
it means that the
component of the electric field in the direction x
is zero
if i do measure the difference in potential
the components
the x component of the
electric fields
the magnitude of that
it would be that little sites
step that i have made x
it will be the potential difference that i measure
divided by the total sites there
and i keep y
and the constant
and these are magnitudes
that's why put vertical bars here
equally if i made small sidestepping the y direction
and i measure a potential difference delta v
being x and z constant
that would then be
of the electric field
in the wider
earlier we wrote down for me as a unit new note newtons coulomb
from now on we almost always will write down
forty unit of electric fields
volt meter
it exactly the same thing as new kinds of cornwall there's no difference
this gives you a little bit more inside
you're making little sidestep
in metres
you measure how much the potential changes its faults
i mean this
is it a potential change
over the distance
so now i can write down the connection between
electric field and potential
in cartesian coordinates
it looks
much more scary
the nice
weighted i could write it down there
when i had
a function of
systems are
and so in cartesian coordinates we now get the
equals minus the minus sign we discussed at length
now we get
the dx
times x roof
because the
and why
would be
i do
and what you see here in first term here
including of course the minus sign
that is e
of x
and this term
including the minus sign
of y and so on
and the fact that you see these
girls these partial derivatives
that means when you do this derivative you keep xeon why constant when you do
this derivative
you do actually constant and so on
and so this is the
four which in eighteen o two
you will learn or maybe you already have learned
we would write it e equals minus
the gradient of this is a vector function
this is a scalar function and this is just as a different notation
just a amount of words
for this mathematical
you get that was eighteen eighteen o two
and now the
these are the parameters of the estimation just
there is a big random parameters
from one division
the because random the parameters
we look at the point in a a cluster
and then we compute the likelihood is product of public land paper that
the former
OK in the likelihood of the parameters
and so it and then we multiply this
like function would is
with the right
so basically modulate the likelihood function to towards
and this is not normalized probabilities of together through
probably because we have normalize and this is the function from which we sample the
distribution of the sample
it's called the posterior distribution of
one of the parameters given the data and last
now how you how hard it is depends on the form of these from users
sometimes you have to the monte carlo because you can sample from the distribution
so it's really easy and for example in the case where f and g lugosi
and the public before any number of nodes is still a gaussian distribution so
it's really easy to get the new sample from the distribution
generalized case of the girls is what's called conjugate priors
so for certain functions
you can choose the two zero so that all resistance
and that's called conjugate priors
and so if you have to
if the
you know the conjugate has actually is actually acceptable for
the kind of data that you have with the kind of problem that you then
the sampling is very
in this case it's just
closed for example
of course in any case if you some from the posterior given the data
so you get new parameters for cluster
o back can you find the points and so on
and you're on this algorithm four
for a few thousand iterations
and then you start looking at what kind of people of european cluster cluster labels
have been and so on
and it's actually two
how do you get what you want really is one class
in in our case of clustering so it's not
quite a simple problem to get one clustering from this you are going to get
the last some bad some good
but before we discussed this
i just want to mention one thing about the posterior
some of you know it i'm sure
but if you don't know it it is worth to mention
what happens here you're multiplying one function with
with the product
so if there are
usually this is more a citizen what led functions so it doesn't have a strong
preference for
many of press should have a strong preference for the parameter because actually it has
be that this are in the next to the centre of the data so they
are but better be close to the data and not far away
so if you have
only one point in one class and then they will be somewhere near that point
but not all
but one of randomly around the
but if you have many points in one cluster solution of large clusters
o point close together
then these are the close together very strongly to the
and so because there are many this this prior to be almost wiped out
these it
russians behind the agreement
we call this
i find myself
the which that if we don't do it if
the fundamental reform is doesn't it
and we say that
i find myself
is good if
this about one these
and the net
we're fine
because o the thing
but this good money for
and it is known that such
the connection
well in description in the project to be from
casual this proposal for user
fundamental structural equations of
a bus facility
the the city
the manifold is simply connected
and doing well actually
the predictive throughout day
it of course it up
i find myself which disease
well that this government with being white space
the naked let us define contrast function
five muscle is known it on the clear
they don't the like
artist of input iceland
vector space of
or in breslau
the brain
but it is going go bed with these vector spaces
then we can define the
the bottom up
i famous
they really
one them up
is a lot of money
no no picked over the
and player
doesn't assume
the majority
all that the space
the model is
called the moment
and we can define
the function that by this function
this formula
so if
the statistical manifold is about
in this case
the geometric divergence point and we
the canonical divergence
but if want a
but the soul
and one for that is about this good morning there
o thing
potential function
in this case
his final match
is one point three
six six
so p two
one point three six sixty five one now this page
is an overpressure gauge therefore
you're not going to see this number but you're going to see the difference was
one atmosphere
so what the gates will show was
is o point three
six six
times one atmosphere
and since it is calibrated in
pounds per square inch
is o point three six six
i'm fifty
on the screen
and that's about something like five point four
that's what i predict
and we'll see how close we get
you're going to see this
it all works well
there is
one is said to the light situation a little better for you
i can even make it
little dog
this gauge
as noted is zero even noticing
i swore i opened this valve is opened
so it is zero because it measures only of pressure
now we're going to close this fell
now there is now closed
we're going to
i think it here is this
object that is the volume
like the bathroom floated mean toilet flush that's what is probably
and now goes into boiling water
now look at pressure and go free
three and a half
all the pressure in pounds per square inch
four and a half
is given a little bit more time
take a while of course because gases are very good
insulators so
may take awhile for the gas in the
in the copper bowl two
so really close to five
we don't have to wait of course for the thing to become
all the way five point five
five point four
but it will probably go up if we wait
now five
not much sense in waiting
what i want you to
i realize what happens or i want to ask you actually what happens if open
the valve now
so if i open developed in one atmosphere
some of the high-pressure stuff
that's out
one atmosphere settles inside
so since this one is a
overpressure gates it will be zero
so i know
that's fine with me that's very close that was in a percent
is class we had five point three but we were a little bit more patient
i will often develop now
and watch what happens
goes back to zero
some animals that out because the pressure inside
was higher than
so we see the tests
reasonable test
the first application of
the ideal gas law
can turn into a liquid and the liquid can become solid
that depends entirely
on the
kind of substance the temperature
the pressure
that we have
and this brings us to the
field of what we call
based on the ground
i'll show you first commerical of phase diagram which is also on the web
user interface that very
in two it is pressure
imagine that we have a similar
and we put gas in that seven that we put the person on top
and we push it down
slowly pushing it down
so we started with gas
and in particular temperature which we're not going to change
and we slowly pushed the piston down
in this trajectory the ideal gas law would hold
the temperature remains constant
if you look at the gas law
if e
remains constant that's called OIL is low by the way that the product of
pressure and volume remains constant
so the pressure in the gas goes up the volume goes down pressure goes up
volume goes down pressure goes up
until i had this point
and now
liquid is going to be four
the depression is not high enough
this temperature to form liquid
if i push further
the pressure will not go up
all the gas will first turn into liquid all of it until the last
and not until everything has become liquid
can i pushed even further on liquid
to increase the pressure on the liquid may be silly thing to do but i
could do that
you're not going to
compress it very much which you can try
and in some cases
if you put a tremendous pressure on it you may turn the liquid into solid
and then you read this domain
where you have a solid
what is much less intuitive
that if you did it at a lower temperature
and you squeeze the volume the pressure will go up
but you may now reached the point here in this phase diagram by no liquid
is formed
no condensation of liquid but you get immediate the formation of crystals
so you go from the gas phase immediately into the solid phase
if you push further down the piston
the pressure will not go up
to all the gas has become
and then i will continue
to go further
suppose this one atmosphere here
and i took some ice we can take a piece of iron one atmosphere
and it's a very low temperature solid
and i started reading it up and keep
the pressure one atmosphere
the solid still the solid
at this point it begins to melt
this will be the melting point
and when i keep eating its temperature will not go up until all the solid
has been melted
in two liquid
then i can increase the temperature
then the liquid will get hotter
until you reach this line
and when you read this line
some of the liquid will turn into gas
one of the few you'll see it boils
you can increase the temperature
if you do want to stay on the degrees centigrade there's nothing you can do
until all the liquid has become gas
we call it one of a
then after that
the temperature can be further increased
so this point point will be melting point four
i see war
and this would be the boarding point
at one atmosphere so that's the idea
behind the phase diagram
and we're going to use them
today for some of our
i have here
i i
just like that because there's only one thing the gamma function only comes in when
you have multiple
it would be the same thing but this is this is this is this is
fine and that's pretty cheap
these slides
o by overly confused you by correcting my equations variant
so in this case actually i think this is not more expensive than the other
one this will be cheap
so this better
OK so good habit is to assess the convergence of the chain and one way
to do that is to monitor the log probability of the state and observations for
example by plotting autocorrelation
and know that when you exponentially that quantity that is proportional to the posterior so
even though you don't have access to the normalizing constant of the posterior you do
have access to something proportional to it and you can monitor that to see where
chain is on the surface of the posterior
and so for example
with the the
with the collapse
gibbs sampler
here i took a document from cora
and i ran the collapsed gibbs sampler and here i plotted the log probability of
the hidden and observed variables as a function of iteration and you can see that
we started here and we climbed inclined inclined
up to their actually this including the topics this is the whole core dataset but
it's the same principle it's the same score and we are
climbing in the posterior and then flattening out somewhere
and if you zoom in on
i iteration i think two hundred on the five hundred you can see that we're
kind of jumping all around the posterior and it's more or less flat
this is not an exact science i know there are
other heuristics that you can use more computational heuristics to assess convergence but the point
is that it's a good habit to do something rather than just to run for
some number of iterations
and stop there
just say no
slides are mass this
this is the collapsed gibbs sampler with this equation gone this and this the collapsed
gibbs sampling
when i was thinking
OK so
the next thing i want to talk about is variational inference for LDA
any remaining questions about gibbs sampling
now this is the borders right
the board i love the board i hate the slots
get this is fine
well so there is so in the collapse good question the change is just the
so if you want to estimate of theta
for particular state of the chain then what you do is you take the disease
and you look at the post your seriously given those is
and that gives you are
oppose the an estimate of the distribution of data given that state the chain
thanks sense
you do whatever you want with that distribution you can take the map you take
the mean
other questions it's good question
yes we will learning data
yeah i'll talk about that
OK so variational methods variational methods are a deterministic alternative to MCMC and you've seen
them already so in general if we have x the observations and zeevi any latent
variables our goal is to compute this posterior and this is not easy to compute
OK so
but for the test data they do tell you the annexe
and they're going to tell you the annexe at test time as well the training
time then why bother learning anything about the axis
i think
i think i think the short answer your question is yes
so let me let me to explain a little bit so you know imagine that
so we talk about supervised learning so we think of x being the input is
being the output and so your input x might be english sentence on the output
y might be a french sentence
this action is of so
let me
the scenario
it's actually cause english sentence
y equals french sentence
you have training
you have x y pairs
and then for test
you have
x given
why and
and what you want to
you need a function
probability of y given x
and then in principle you could do translation by choosing
the nice o output
why that is
p of y given x
now what's the language model
i think
a language model
is a
the problem is
i guess technically polymaths functions
that p of y
and so if y is french sentences then this would be a probability function that
tells you which french sentence is unlikely
which would be correct sentences and then which french sentence is unlikely that would be
incorrect sentences and they would have low probability and more when you're choosing a y
to be your output
if you really wanted to satisfy two criteria you wanted to
i have a high probability given the input english sentence and he also wanted to
be a good french sentence
so language models
so language models actually used to
to tell you the probability of the output sentence being good sentence
in the output language and if i have this formula so this is just a
simple formula probability theory and i can also write it
p of y
times p of x given y
well then actually the statistical approach to machine translation
building a language model somehow
which is
a model of p of y
and then really building an inverse
well you could call an inverse
translation model
which is the probability of the english sentence given the french sentence
i guess some
and there are reasons why
they do it this way
rather than doing it this way
and more
i think you know we if you did it this way
then you have people doing all your eggs in one basket you need to learn
of very good morning p of y given x and if you do it this
way your from
it said it to divide and conquer approach to the problem you can try to
make this model good you can also separate try to make this model could but
i'm not an expert on
must statistical
because it would seem weird they were before my data points are completely independent then
i'm not going to learn anything so i think the noise being i think so
if we make this IID assumption that noise is coming independently each time then we
can write down
independence allows us to write the joint distribution of y is just the product of
the marginals so we can write that down in apple and that's the standard sort
assumption for a regression problem and that means that we have the likelihood of this
so the likelihood is the joint distribution of these counts things now what we're going
to do is click through here
we're going look at that and say
OK this time but it's not depend on these parameters that i was fifteen before
so i'm going to ignore it and i'm just going to say this is proportional
to that that was the constant proportionality to keep this kind of one so i'm
going to drop
now look at the product and say well i can pull up look inside the
exponential productivity exponentials is the same as the exponential of the sum
so i'm going do that
then i'm going to look at the exponential and say well i can remove that
by putting the logarithm on the other side
so now i've got something of this form
by constant proportionality
now becomes an additive constant here
now look at that and say well OK
a scalable
that is equal to the error function i defined before
we were minimizing the error function
but now we can see that our function is equivalent to a negative
OK negative so if i minimize
something and then take negative by maximizing the negative so in fact if i minimize
the error function on maximizing the log likelihood
many important thing about the log is a monotonic function i never got that power
to deny
well i draw them
if i think that the log is a monotonic function
so you've got a monotonic function
if you maximize something
and then you might and then you put it through monotonic function
it doesn't change the ordering of things so if i you can think about that
in the discrete case
if i take the logarithm of a discrete set of numbers and then i want
to find the function so i have something
not explained very well
because is a monotonic function if i maximize the
log this i'm also maximizing that itself
so i can take the negative log likelihood i can minimise the negative log likelihood
on effectively maximizing the like
so the probabilistic interpretation of the error function is the negative log likelihood
and minimize the error function is equivalent to maximizing the log likelihood to maximize the
log likelihood is equivalent to maximizing the likelihood because log is monotonic so
the this is the probabilistic interpretation of the error function
it's basically there
minimize the error function is equivalent to maximizing likelihood with respect the
so this is called max what
so everything we saw before
can be reinterpreted in that way now there was a question in
the break after spoke last time is it true that every error functions
can be interpreted as
and maximum likelihood and the answer is no
because you can imagine error functions the you can't normalize and if you can't see
when you take the exponential
the error function
you can't actually normalized result and if that's the case you can't think of is
maximal likelihood
because we don't have this property of the probability distribution so normalisation is vital for
to find something
but most things that people are using typically
can be treated that way i the example that was given was an example model
but the most sort of standard things people using is error functions you can interpret
as likely
if the data was really generated according to model we specify that like you really
had calcium noise plus that
a weighted linear some of basis functions then what you can say is that the
current parameters will be converted in the limit as n goes to infinity personally this
is you know the a consistency proof
i don't remember the last time someone gave me infinite data so i'm not sure
how much i care about these proofs personally it's not missing is the rate of
convergence is actually quite important
but in some sense i really am interested in very low data rate areas so
it's true you know i a lot of what's a google are doing with very
large datasets is relying on this you know got limited number of parameters lot of
data and things work really well in that region and you can prove that this
is the case by and using the law of large numbers and i'm showing that
what you're doing is is more minimizing what's called the kullback lieber divergence between the
true distribution and your approximation and this is like a mainstay of classical statistics although
i is credited to fisher law i'd really read the papers but you know you
can go back to gases explanation of least squares what i've described to you in
this error function is least squares and i think it talking gases so we explanation
what the squares was because he didn't invent it then you're going back to something
like eighteen ten
the physicists were doing this so this is why i keep looking up is is
something of a little bit ahead of machine learning people they just didn't have the
computer so they that was their interpretation that was gases interpretation and claims that he
found that planet series or whatever it's called the dwarf planet he re found where
it was through applying this
basically in the fact that he made that claim in order to justify he invented
least squares for so that might be a bit dodgy
the germans and french
well there is is that it
so this is the likelihood the the regression and the suggestion is to maximize its
with respect to w that's what we've been doing in the last time that can
be done with a gradient based optimisation of the log likelihood
there's an alternative approach and this is the bayesian approach to the alternative approach is
not two optimizes w
but to integrate it out
and this is where the controversy starts
what we can do is effectively considered the expected values of all the likelihood under
range of potential w that we believe so when i was talking before about
prior knowledge of functions this effectively how in this model year introduced prior knowledge is
i'm going to have a distribution
for w
so i purposefully right
my parameters is conditioning as if they are random variables
and that means i can think of p w and then use some rule to
integrate and that's what goes on in the bayesian approach
we can use bayes rule to implement bayes approach
but bayesian is not named after bayes rule is very common confusion if you don't
use bayes rule
two inverse probability you're just wrong you're not being frequentist
bayesian refers
to something different
what they refers to is this thing that i'm doing here treating the parameters of
algorithms for training that have this adaptive learning rate
property but a basic thing to do which tends to work well
is to have a schedule which works as follows
so use set the learning rate maybe to be fairly large initially
to make big steps and train fairly rapidly initially say zero
point one and then you keep track on the validation set
what is the error what's the performance
when it stops improving then you divide the learning rate by to
continue training but also encourage if possible to go back
to the point before it you know became worse
and that's schedule i found works pretty well in practice
yeah so so i guess you question is you know there is working optimization
that would suggests sort of metrics to keep track of
to determine schedule yeah i think might be used by some people
for sure but i found much like early stopping for some reason is
very effective of getting rid of the regularizer
again validation set performance tracking is very useful
signal for knowing when you learning rates to high
so there might be things that are slightly better but this is just
like impressively you know effective procedure yes
yes so as i guess the question is you know you mentioned that
sometimes even if the error gets worse on the validation set
might become better later on for instance we know that the optimization
problem when training neural that is really in nonconvex optimization
problem so it is possible to draw a line in in non-convex function
and where you would go up but then goal down
lower later on because you were in a local minimum and maybe later
on each other better local maybe global optimum
that this is a that is not like that can happen
because of this like you can deftly construct cases where
this happens but it's hard to i don't have any good advice to like
when should you then ignored validation set for a while
look ahead can play this role bits so you can say ok i'm actually
going to weight you know just not if the if it if it gets worse
the next step actually like the x ten steps
maybe goes back down and then you just you're back to as if you
didn't stop and this is partly why i tend to use a look ahead of
a few iterations so this will partially addressed this like it
doesn't matter if it goes up if it eventually goes down better lower
number than which found so far before the look ahead you've given
you're training procedure you will cover that situation
maybe one rk yeah let's go yeah good
yes so so yes so the question is mentioning this
result that states that stochastic gradient descent
will converge if the sum of the learning rates using a schedule
eventually actually divergence
to infinity but the sum of the square of the learning rate
actually converges is convergence some that are in the
early called result in terms of converging over the training problem
again the big advantage of using the validation set it's not
just to measure its indirectly measure are good you're doing optimising
but it's mostly measure good you're doing generalizing
and that is like it's big value so so i think this
this result essentially just guarantees convergence not to sell
the fass converge like it has a complexity associated with that
this statement here about this know decay
schedule is something that in practice been found to
work really well and i don't know how much
theory there is behind like this schedule just in practice it's
very effective
i mean that's yes so the question is about new normalizing
does always work i guess so there might be better normalization
so for instance you can do that ca whitening
removing also second orders correlations between the dimensions
and i can also help
because depends who you mean by word
to avoid possible misunderstandings
my lectures start nine thirty eastern standard time which is different
from lobby seven times you may have noticed
o the clock and will be seventy seven minutes long
today we're going to cover coupled oscillators
this is a big part in eight three
though we leave out them in order to afford major complications
that i have
thanks al mass and
and have
also mass and
the length l
and i connect
the spring
three dimensions see there
spring constant k
imagine our time t equals zero
that i
if this object which i call object number one and this is object number two
given a certain position
given a certain velocity so i e four choices
and that the system go
what you're going to see is something extremely chaotic
on our task today is
to predict
what the position of this one is at any moment in time
what the position the position of that one is at any moment in time
to show you how chaotic that motion is
i'll just
so it is
so i take this one
this displace it from a colombian i displays this one from equilibrium at time t
equals zero i'll give the one
my left hand just as a certain velocity
and if you look at the
position of the individual objects
it would
see nearly impossible
to come with a analytic solution
which tells you what these motions are you will see it amplitudes build up
of certain ones amplitude goes down this one is hardly moving at all now not
speaking up again
so our task today is
to work on with
what is by no means obvious but i'll show that to you
that any motion
no matter how you started off
it's going to be the superposition
of two
normal mode solutions
anyway you started
can always be written
the superposition of two normal mode solutions what is a normal mode and normal mode
is in this case that both objects
i have exactly the same frequency
it is fundamental to normal mode
that they either in phase with each other or out of phase with each other
nothing in between
because there's no damping so it's either in phase or out of phase
that is the normal mode
in other words if i call
one of those frequencies omega minus minus means it is the lowest frequency there are
two frequencies in this system because the two objects
omega minor cycle that
the lowest frequency
then it would mean
if they are
in freeze was it's over the two
that country will hold the same moment in time
that means in phase and in the same direction
so to come to all the same moment in time
in the same direction and they have the same frequency
if then i have another frequency which is higher
there are two normal modes because we have two objects we have three objects there
are three normal modes
if we go to
higher normal motor higher frequency
they have the same frequency
but they are on the eighty degrees out of phase
so when one comes to a whole year
other one comes to the whole there
that's what it means on the eighty degrees out of phase
i can excite
and i will excite
this system into its normal modes only i can excite
this normal mode along and this normal modes along if i choose the correct initial
so for any
randomly chosen
initial condition
the motion of each object
can be written as a linear
combination of these two modes
if you take
my work for that for now but of course i will demonstrate you and i
will prove that to you
it would mean that
o channel time
can then be written as having some kind of an amplitude x zero i give
you the minus sign because it's related to that the normal mode frequencies
times the cosine
of omega minus
class some five minus
some of the amplitude which i call x zero plus
which is going to be related to this frequency
times of science
of omega class
five class
let's look
let's try to see through this what this means
it means
if i know my initial conditions
i can determine
this amplitude i can determine
this phase i can from this amplitude that i can determine this for
there have to be four
constant because i have the choice between the positions at the zero and the velocity
so there must be four
what you see is that all we good minus
and omega plus
which ideas normal mode frequencies are independent of the initial conditions
and i'm going to write down
the position in time for object number two
functions it wouldn't
it is meaningful to many of you i wish watershed intuition another sort of you
know sort of reason to switch to state action values versus of was the state
value the following even if i give you state values
even if i give you the star just to compute the optimal action model
well if i give you q star
then to compute the optimal action i don't need more
the reason
if you like
switch to state action values
so this seemingly simple notational switch from state values state action values
was critical in allowing us to develop a direct methods for the optimal control problem
which one of them
four pride prior to this
seemingly very simple switch were putting values not on
nodes but the edges
like in this in that sense really made me distinctive OK swap back to how
was any questions
where you have to do is not to be
i used to listen to compute the
not sure the question but let me try to answer it anyway
we live me answer by summarizing where we
so you still have questions
stepping back define two things define the policy evaluation problem and the optimal control problem
in the context of markov processes
the planning version of these algorithms problems and the learning version of
and find the optimality equation for these two problems
the planning case
we've given the transition probability what functions you know
solving this problem solving systems of equations
there are many many different ways of solving systems of equations and perhaps what you
are alluding to
is that why not some other way of solving the system of equations
and there will be just fine
we just fine in fact i'm not going to talk about these things but there
are also things like policy iteration methods for solving the system of equations and in
the case of policy evaluation is actually a linear system of equations
so can use matrix inversion
to solve for the value function for a fixed policy
it's worth writing this
so the the
and making hard time to the current this by the way
is this right
i don't want to
your permanent marker
OK so the
recall the development the
but policy evaluation problem the system equations was like this right for all pilots or
pilots gamma
some more or less prime p
as prime given as high as
the highest price right
you can solve this equation how you want
one way to solve it is the matrix inversion for
which is or enqueued event the number of states
operation to solve the system of equations and value iteration is or m squared each
depending how large n is how many iterations you have to do you want to
value iteration so
you know there are many different ways of solving
the policy evaluation from the optimal control problem the non-linear system of equations because the
max in there
and that
makes it for much fewer much
smaller choice of algorithms and value iteration is the outcome of choice
for solving for the optimal control
off policy that that's your question
let me
let me now
basically covered the very foundations the very basics of reinforcement so i'm about to die
would do more interesting and
sort of more new material so
let me just might not be apparent you why
why q learning is advance what real way is in advance so let me spend
a little bit of time
talking about that
the first observation to make is
q learning doesn't learn more what i mean models or m squared quantities right the
map from state actions the next state so states number is the number of states
and the roughly order and square quantities
you're trying to learn something or in square
value function of the other in order and
so q learning by the learner and squared quantity by indirect methods do
so you might think that
therefore q learning can be much more efficient
try to find learn more directly nor insert a newly less data as you might
think that learning is actually more efficient than the indirect method as a result that
that's one into the way of saying why q learning is is the p is
let me give you another intuition as to why q is purely think back to
the planning out what were we doing we were sweeping through the state space
at each iteration updating every stage
q learning runs around the world
and update state as you've seen
it leads to really important obvious simple point which is that
q learning in a sense
automatically focuses
updates on things that happened
on things that
hopefully means hopefully that means on things that matter
drive home the point a little bit you know in a more elaborate way but
reinforcement learning has nice property
that's because your learning from experience rather than to our model
in some sense experience is more immediately relevant
then learning to simulation model because
these are driven by
my experience that this is very vague and fuzzy and make this a bit more
how to current
cover image from the
six and
well in the in the
sender and actually we use the is quite a simple IQ linear strategy two
rather than to here
pixel colours
it's basically falstaff
firstly we start with this
just random draw
pixel labels
that we will build up
semi supervised learning model
and the value of the prediction results because in the
in there is
centre and we do have access to the truth
that we stop meets certain criteria
that is the sort of thing so how vigorously with some
catalytic example some some pollen
several in europe and
rather than simply so
labels from the pixels
then we can go through
step two and the totally
so basically
that's that's all i was in for the
sender around
so the implementation
a bit further technicality we actually we workings
luminance and chrominance space so
one space
and so says
the colours are
well the
three tunnels are more
then the and in RGB space and the we predict the colour
channels such that is you into the battles independently
and also we build the feature graph building some sliding windows
tamara the
to measure the similarity of clothing is
we all the
yes in our value
which is quite standard in image compression
in the following i'm going to show several
in the example the first example is
assume we we how
this is a different site in a similar way how
only access to the
risk image and the force
pixels here
some lines we help cell to the color labels
given this tool
by multi only the
from that
receiver on the algorithm caltech something like this
which is actually
quite the visual can pleasing
so this is just example to show
it actually works
well so let me explain
this is the second example
in this setting we go back to the compression and the
from the centre
he how exactly the ground force which is a colour image
then he signed the
illness china which is the way it handled
as well as
four so this middle column this example
he signed over
human annotated labels
the receiver on the other hand the internet actually can recover something like this
your using the current algorithm
but so here
basically the how some those selected
picked by
which means that the pixel picked i could never love
i can't see this
the algorithm this understanding with scale as well as this
this the the receiver actually can our something which is quite close to the
ground truth
to the original source data
so here also shows the look as well as the
number of a
labeled pixels
and still the image compression setting
sanders how this and he sent
well the
intended in
as well as this column is
hume is actually we draw a random sample
around close to switzerland
this column labels that actually
of ten this result and if we to learn you actually can focus hard part
the image and will ten
so that the
receiver and actually can recover something like this
it is the number the test bed clothes but actually if you look closely can
for the face
the official color
this line is quite different as well as for the
especially for the
a long time since i did not you
before moving on to the panama about this is most likely to have generated discussion
have more
finally glacially one at the end but so some of the teachers requested me
to have a place to small amount of like for this week already because some
of them will not be here for the next friday and the
you know if you want to give lectures units some feedback of what's going on
and to what extent do really communicating
so i would like to go one by one through
well events and ask you for come show
a lot
questions so went for questions are fairly well question
i would like to ask you for to choose one of the three and for
whether you are profiting for each course maybe not so much maybe yes
maybe i like
and then for school
that two things were not so much
i would like to know whether it
because it is the maybe the level is too high for the above-ground maybe just
allow for the environment therefore you are not perfect of it because you know it
already or maybe subevent onto something else
so and this is essentially an excuse to try to happen
any one of main know anything
and now it's easier to show hands and then just start speaking so maybe if
we start by showing and somebody will also speak but if you have a if
you have anything to say
this is a moment for it
who would show hands for a lot of profit for recording scores
four how many would say
it's very simple because it is a the interaction mrna
the court held many would say it's not so much
the reason is the level was too high level was too low you new everything
how to make a last lectures
a lot of profit
if it is about profit from it
and maybe not so much
and then do a lot with them while you knew it already
now we want to know whether it so from now on just answer about
however the seven score
a lot of profit
thank you
yes profit
so only one left for not so much
thank you
a lot of profit from parking structure
some benefit from lecture
enough of it
not so much
and then there's this material that some of you know and let me ask jointly
the four supposedly for the laps on spider and a bit of a slap shot
because they were
such a heavy but the deficit to have different
feeling with the rest of course it was it was it put face in this
way the you think that it was so where they have have the laps
and i said to complement the
which is mapping
from what to what
states and actions to
some real valued
one zero ten one hundred point one
native hundred
to define model you should know the six things secondly you should know whether these
are known or unknown
actually the transition function activation function the reward function
OK what you've done this you've done
sixty percent of the problem
it's formalising formalise problem at the right level of abstraction
it is often quite hard
what you have done that
then you can characterizes the solution to these problems officially find them in you're luck
because most the colour models and solutions are known
this is just a matter of getting the problem into the right model
so for example for every other application i discussed is already full model with known
ways to derive solution and properties of that solution so clearly the problem here is
model the problem
now recently gave the talk i i i i do a lot of things in
my job one of the recent research projects
is on city traffic control
and i received talk and i realize
people really care lot traffic
it was great i mean i had this discussion to search took on its own
is life and i just saw some back
i didn't talk much people really people really care about traffic you really care about
how long you wait stop lights
and so on so it might be nice to quickly formalise what traffic control problem
would look like
and again if you've got a piece of paper or the placing notes things to
help you
with the rest lecture
traffic control
OK let's
let's sum for simplicity let's assume that she was stoplights
in here
but this is
these are one-way roads
that's three roads here
OK so every intersection is going to have
two stop lights went retraction
what the state
i said look like
thank you
it's like this orange light coming late
for the embers well
we have what the state of to stop quite right
so we have
the cross product twice
by one one three points
if i see square then you publish and i mean this
right now
as part of the state
get more stiffness that
what you care about
say that a simple problem
is the thing OK get
but does more seats the problem in this does more see upon what you want
to conditioning your actions
so how had in this stuff like really work
percent state
actually these inductive loop brain
actually actually right
OK good OK and so that destroyed text the presence or absence of the car
OK so i think the current state of the state would be
OK let's
i call this
that's what i'm sorry
q one
you think you can really make use
q two
q three
and q four
and with the current traffic centers either no
weather traffic is on that sense or not
now it's actually you can do more than that for example in sydney
they use the rate of traffic flow sensors to try to invite capabilities let let's
think the pretty simple
OK so i have four here i'm just going to have a boy in state
space is true or false to four
p ten p times b and b
this will be a very simple problem
this is really cool so one thing this is is doing now is the mounting
traffic cameras on top of every stop
and he showed his vision is to build hard problem but when when when you
when the camera one traffic
OK and you know really markings are you know the geometry
seven earthquakes
the jump doesn't change
there's actually
fairly soul vision tasks to say there are these cars this linear system any we've
got bias we've got so on
and so actually so the next generation challenge you will see into the next ten
years are sensors that can say there's bussiness later buses were forty people
is worth forty cars
or twenty cars
so i'm going to give priority to this past to go through
so the problem can be a lot more complex if you allow things like that
and this is what we're actually we're we're looking at our research
but right now
two thousand nine
we just have centers saying there is a car here is prior OK so how
many distinct states do we have based on this model
three times three
times how many states here
sixteen to the fourth
nine time sixteen accounting enough we had a one
o forty four the
so the size of the state space is one hundred forty four states
this problem
now imagine we have twenty traffic lights three lanes in each direction two-way traffic
we know whether buses in queue lengths
lower OK
clearly how model state really influences how to solve the problem is very simple
what's the action space
precup control
so let's assume
OK so so for traffic there are minimum time delay can be in the cycle
there are issues about how on one last few red one x like can green
with respect
the target density the idea
OK i want to sample from p
come to the nearest to the distribution
check with this racial here
OK if we increase
we have a high value here
and if we have decreased the most probably have
low value
this is just a correction to take into account
density we use to sample
and there are probably things
the reason for that
got the candidates is going to be accepted or rejected
it is going to be at you
this one is larger than the one we always accept
and if it's more than one
with what
we accepted or rejected
it is high that is a good improvement
then very probably will as new can
but this is know
is change in any way we
but we must probably be rejected
and then we iterate
OK so
now to have
and so this is a very generic categories and we want to apply it to
the problem of harmony kind
so i
present you i we can build the MCMC algorithm for this page
OK so
we have different levels
at the level of individual powerful we have
the amplitude frequency of the possible
at the level of nodes node is composed of fundamental frequency and the bottles
we have a structure parameter which is the number of partials
so we want to estimate
and the overall scale we have the music
one node to another
and i have a
see additive noise variance
so we have three
three different
in this case
for the problem
and a very important thing about
the dimension of the
is varying with the parameters so that's why we implement
and so i think all the time
lecture about anyway
and the problem
OK so
this is very very
because this is the theory
we want to estimate the parameters of the music by designing a markov chain
so the problem when you want to apply
how long is it going to take
it's not finished in one million years it was
so under the constraint is that we need to implement the first
this is why we need to very carefully
think about the markov condition cannot which is used to build a markov chain fast
and i would be the most
and think most important constraint problem
now let's see how it
it can be
so we have unionization
we have to be a piece of music
and we have a model we use
some notes
we cannot accept
we want to
initialize the things we want to
they select an initial number of nodes and initial number of each node and initial
because that we do we here
we sample say
we don't know anything about it
so we're going to say well
it's not for
we already know the number of nodes here to simplify
and for each of possible
from from initial frequency
so we can
have a look at that
just look at this picture from we might have some frequencies that uses to sample
unusual set frequencies
we need also
initial value for the variance parameter
right so
it's somewhat unusual value for that
and it's very nice because we have the conditional posterior
so as have already sampled from this
we can
have the
imagine any
connection to machine learning and nonparametric
i simply summarized the sum
phenomena for a product of random variables
which is essentially a prize peak was
or any
as our or any financial product
i will use and much more
maybe i already assumed
sequences of three vector
but the process i only assume
that the or the multidimensional distribution of the process
is invariant under the time she any
time if you look at the segment of the
market process
then the distribution we are not depend on the actual location of the
the fact that
i will show you
very important
previously all one is the
nonparametric regression estimate
and the other one is from actually learning for machine learning
how to aggregate estimates
died that it could be costly for very general market price
so that
the party is is very similar
two wednesday
the main difference is that year i love that you
training data you're in each day
in the morning when i
fix the actual portfolio that are
the portfolio vector may depend on the path
return vector
in the first day had no history of the for the first day
the portfolio vector can be arbitrary
and maybe remember that if there is the initial that for initial capital
for the first day
at the end of the day
the the amount of money what i have is the product of the
initial capital and the the inner product of the first portfolio over or under four
returned back
so the next day
for the second day
one is the new initial capital here
he has or at very
well the by the way the first the return vector for the portfolio vector may
depend on the first the return vector
and then
back at the end of the second day
the amount of money
it is the product of
and at the day and
the story is the plot the return vector so on your mind one
but the portfolio vector or
can be an arbitrary function of that part the reason that source
in this case the amount of money what i have is the
product of the
initial capital and the product of in inner product
at the i
the portfolio vector may depend on the preview the return vector
maybe remember that on wednesday afternoon i mentioned that is that of looking at died
at the and then it is reasonable to to look at
average growth rate
the rate the exponent which shows how fast these there
captain goes to infinity the what is the time and the
in the exponent it is
the average
of course
log there is
and this will be the
quantity which is on the one hand can be handled
and on the other hand characterizes the
a growth rate of our investment strategy
in contrast to one of the afternoon here i assume that the sequence of three
is stationary
and regarding
but the process if you don't know what would it means never mind i will
not use
just remember that stationary means that the thickness visionary award the institutions are invariant under
the banshee
and then the good portfolio vector
if the sequence of three vectorw is not independent identically distributed then
choosing values of x and then evaluating this green curve which is a sinusoidal function
and then adding guassian
zero mean gas noise to get the data points the data points are sort of
noisy observations from this green sinusoidal curves
and let's model is a simple linear model
so we can use a model
children by y of x parametrized by w which is going to be linear in
the parameters of the linear combination of some fixed functions of x these functions could
be non-linear but the fixed we call this the linear model is linear in the
unknown parameters
distribution for t then is the gas distribution whose mean is this function y of
and it has some inverse
some variants beta inverse beta the precision of the noise
the likelihood function is the product of these evaluated of the observations
so here's an example of the choice of basis functions is some fixed knowledge base
function in this case the polynomial
so this is x the power one that x squared and so on so it
sitting model which is an expansion in powers of x
now want to introduce a conjugate prior is unknown parameters in the conjugate prior is
going to be a guassian because y is linear in x
and so the mean of this distribution is linear in w
the functional form of this with respect to w is e to the minus the
quadratic function of w
so the conjugate prior for that is against you
so we define gas in w which is zero mean controlled by some parameter alpha
and so we multiply
the likelihood function by the prior because its conjugate again we get gas distribution and
if you work it out it's takes this form this is the mean and the
covariance s is the covariance
this the multivariate gamma distribution
and capital phi here system matrix
of observations to the NJ elements of this matrix
it is the j th basis function evaluated for the and observation details don't really
matter the point is this is a gas distribution
let's suppose will have look at a really simple case of a special case of
this let's imagine that is the moment instead of the sinusoidal source the data we
just a straight line
so let's generate some data from a straight line a plus b x
and will add some guassian noise to the observations
and somebody kindly told us that this is a straight line so we know what
to fit going to fit
this simple model which is linear in in w and linear x that is the
two parameter model w nor plus w one x so the goal is to
find w norton w one given some observations
so we have against him prior distribution this is now to the prior for this
is the two parameter space w norton w one of the two
parameters that we're trying to learn
and this is the prior distribution guassian centered on the origin and we can
we can visualize this by drawing samples so if we draw samples from this prior
distribution each sample is the value of w or w one therefore defines a straight
line to import that in data space this is why this is x so each
it is a pair of parameters which define a straight line if you draw samples
from the prior we can see we got a whole bunch of straight lines that's
quite a nice way sometimes of gaining insight into your into your prior assumptions is
to draw
draw fictitious data points to see what they actually look like and see if there
are reasonable
so the prior now let's observe one data point
so just observe this data point here
so we can compute its likelihood function and this is the
the likelihood function for that one data point and so its highest in the middle
so so the dark red is is a high value falls off to the blue
which is close to zero
what i want to hear white cross that white cross there is the true
value for w norton w one which of course we don't know
a straight line effectively
so a single data point constraints provides one constraint on the straight line so there
are there is a whole continues straight lines which pass through one data point because
we know the data point is noisy so it's sort of soft constraint
so the likelihood function has the strong correlation points
points and this is the parameter space w w one points along here
all correspond to straight lines that go close to the state point points out here
straight lines that miss the data points
we take this likelihood function and we
multiplied by this poster multiply by that posterior distribution by this likelihood function the normalized
and you can see we get this elongated gas this correlated down
and if we draw samples from this posterior distribution
and plot we see that indeed they are straight lines and they all
pass close to
this data point
close to is defined by that beta noise
so that's the effect of observing one data point and course bayesian learning is sequential
so this is now a prior distribution preserving the second data point is the second
data point
his it's likelihood function so it two defines the soft relationship between w norton w
this form
and so we take this likelihood function
multiplied by this prior
and we get this posterior distribution again guesstimates it's time much more compact because two
data points two points define line these noisy data points but nevertheless it constrains them
in this software so we now have quite compact posterior distribution and if we draw
samples from this distribution we say they are indeed all straight lines of going close
to those two data points
and that if we observe twenty data points
the this is the likelihood function for the twentieth data point we solve all of
those likelihood functions the
mister dispute
distribution is becoming more and more compact is the same
less and less uncertain and if we were to observe an infinite number of data
points this eventually would become delta function centred on the true value
because all models are correct model
hidden layers
and of course
we know that these are not convex optimization problems but for the more it looks
like it gets worse as we have more like
so the traditional approach to train neural nets is with random initial parameters and then
choose tune the parameters with stochastic gradient descent
what happens when if we don't really know
training doesn't progress with me well
the gradient is small
it means you either in a local minimum or you are in fact
there are some units that seem to be
trainable even if there are deep in the code convolutional nets and i'm going to
say much more about that but
but again we don't really understand why these are exceptions to these are specialized vision
two thousand six something happened
hinton osindero and ten published
calls asking for deep belief nets
and there's an idea in there which
it turns out to be useful for other types of deep networks
he is trying to do network radio two
user kind of greedy approach
so i'm going to try to find an unsupervised network which he sees the input
training layer by layer
adding one layer on top of each other
each layer is going to be restricted boltzmann machine which is something i'm not going
explain but it's
it's a kind of nonlinear PCA or ICA or whatever which are in representation of
its input is part of the learning process
unlike PCA and ICA the representation can have more components than the actual input
there's no constraint whether it doesn't have to be bigger or smaller
so when you try
you get a
both model of the inputs and way transformed input and the newer presentation
actually we don't really have a clear idea of why this decision should be better
than the original one but when we use this representation instead of the original one
input features for SC SVM or nearest neighbour got process we find usually we get
better classification
so what you do is you add layer by layer like this
and the and put on a supervised learning
your preferred classifier or whatever you want to do regression and this is a pretty
good but then you can get even better by taking this
i think that and
and the whole thing
by gradient descent on the supervised cost so you can find this big networks
and what happens is basically means used this device layerwise really thing as a very
sophisticated initialisation for
are being that
why is this working i'll say more about that but at least one thing that's
clear is that when we do this initialisation we the optimisation is done
locally within each layer so we try all these weights and they don't have to
look at what's happening above essentially below there are no interactions we know that training
a small model is
presumably easier than the big ones for the and also it looks like that education
completion of gradients when you do so many years introduce something that makes the gradient
less useful so in nineteen twenty one layer at a time
maybe it's easier
so now i'm going to say something about online learning
can you give me time
thirty four minutes twenty five i got
my friend leon bottou
the nice piece of work the online learning among those
something that is important for me because i'm interested in learning
very large scale problems
this paper with you can NIPS two-thousand three
that brings an argument which
on the face of it is obvious
when you training with abundant training data and they symbolically with the amount of data
is infinity
online learning
asymptotically outperforms batch learning simply because
that's something we have to eat right multiple times through the data
and while i was writing the second third and ten times the online learning could
have looked at more data as
and those
larger and larger that advantage in terms of generalization becomes bigger now it's not totally
obvious because one converges faster to to the optimal training error and the other and
there are some trade to be study and
this year's paper continues on the same track
look centralization here which is usually
studied in terms of the trade off between approximation error because we have a cost
function it's too restricted to small
and estimation error variance because the closest large
and we don't have enough data
that night introduces third which is the effect due to the optimisation because optimisation is
not perfect
usually we stop optimizing when we find that are close enough to a local minimum
but what is the effect of this
and basically needed to study it introduces a very nice idea which is
we have to
constraints to consider when we trained learning
one is how much
we have and the other is how many examples we can afford
the objects to be clustered
the edges represent similarity
relations and the weights on the edges represent the similarity
wanted to simply to
so we have
technically speaking
atleast this part of the talk we have an undirected weighted graph and we we
assume that the weights are nonnegative
but then are equal to c
a common way to represent
and directed weighted graph edge weighted graph is by using this weighted adjacency matrix
this is an n by n matrix where n is the number of vertices in
the graph
and at the intersection of the rule number i and column j
just find similarity
between i and j
we assume that the that the main diagonal of this
memetics is zero
OK so let's start from a very simple and realistic scenario
let's try to answer our original question what is the cluster
when the similarities between the objects are binary
so in this case
we have just that two objects are either similar
or the similarly we are not allowing intermediate values of similarity
in other words
the graph
is it in a weighted graph is an undirected weighted and the adjacent semantics is
just the zero one matrix so let's ask yourself
of what is the sort of structure in this graph that satisfies two criteria the
internal and external
the answer is very classical notion in graph theory
the notion of a maximal clique yesterday
we had talked richard hardly talk about the notion of the week
from different
but what i can just
nine what is really what is the maximum
give you a graph
example this one
OK so it's c
it's just a subset of mutually adjacent but
then we have the notion of the maximum
maximal clique is a clique which is not contained in any larger so for example
this is why
physically of course
and is also max
this one also we
and is also the maximum
this one is a clique
but is not maximum because it is contained a large
well it's not written that we have fight the notion
the notion of the maximum clique
to distinguish it from the notion of the maximal cliques and maximal clique is a
clique having largest garden
there is no large so in this case
there is only one maximal clique and this is one
this is this one is maximum
and it's not max
of course any maximal clique is also maximal
but the opposite is not true for example in this case
the maximum clique which is max
we also have a notion which
can't believe
it's called the
strictly maximum we just mentioned
because strictly
this is a clique which has the following property
if this is a maximal clique
all that is outside it
can we have
more than two edges
incidentally those because
if this verdict here which is outside the clique
it has three edges incident to this one
this will not be m
this gave me the world
to get to my note so it it's fully characterizes the note OK
so for example here
the outliers if you like the address of this nodes
so i finite words
over the alphabet
zero one
so i give you
a finite ordered here it gives me a node in the tree
so the support to carry out an not
carry on something
frame the frame
of the tree and well anyway you the tree would say
it is composed of nodes but simply given by the address
and how do i move from one node to its chinese i simply at the
end of this adversely either you if one the left
one effect on the right shape
that's that's tree very simple
and if i have made no move
from the top
the MT what is epsilon and that's the root of the tree
so it's written like this
that means that the sequence of the other one
is the empty word and it's the address of the root of the tree
now if i wanted to decorate my
information michael sigma of the set of information that i'm using
and in general see mistaken finite
but of course i mean there are few is that extends
trees of infinite alphabets but we
we don't need it here
so i will
label my notes with sigma
elements of sigma and the
trees sigma of the definition the full binary trees
labels on those that are elements of c OK
so in general
what people would take this is what i have explained to you here
if you want
to come from programs propositions about the labels of each node would be as the
subset of propositions that toward state
so remember that you
a given node
may correspond i mean several nodes in the tree may correspond to the same
current state in the problem
because look at this the way of unravelled this thing here
i mean in this notes the current state here is as two
here's is as one
so here as well
what is also very important that we really do not exploit
here in in this setting is that in the tree when i choose an note
and if this node corresponds to
note is the tree corresponds to an unraveling of some famous structure operational structure
in this have information of the current state
but there's have also information about the past
which tells me we have reached this state
so here and both them in both cases i mean state one s one
but here
after this instruction which maybe i don't know maybe to increment survival in my problem
whatever two
to ask the user to give me another value of you can see that here
i mean the state where i asked the guy i mean one
to give me the value of primitive ones and he had twice
so the trees very very powerful
regarding the
execu shows of the problem
so now we enter the logic the mu calculus
just to start to define itself it's you you fed for the first lecture at
this with the main objective
what is important to note to remember
although we will not really
c will have elements
see why i claim that this logic is so powerful but actually bit
is that
the formalism i give you will subsume i mean
the temple logics
you can think of volume you may
you may
and countering your
scientific life
it's it's assumed
all the possible logic you can think of
actually it has exactly the same power as monadic second order logic
very very powerful
other the trees
this is x half of the lecture but you should remember that the mu calculus
that they present you
whatever you can you would be able to
on the full binary tree
with monadic second order logic so you have second quantification it's alot lot
whatever you may be able to express in this logic
this can also be told in the new calculus but only
on tree structures
if i take more complicated things like greets
that things that they can express the MSO monadic second order logic that will not
be able to
express the mu calculus
for the good reason that the mu calculus
is it logical talk about etiquette executions and future of the execution so it means
that can make a difference between the great or some unravelling of the weight as
the tree
so the logical gonna use is insensitive to unravelling
so whereas monadic second order logic is it is undecidable reads
you can because when we made decidable because actually doesn't talk about read
it talks about
the tree that underlies
the operational model it is described by green
OK so it's really
it's not for that that and so what if i choose my models as trees
it's as powerful as this
what is nice for the mu calculus is that you can
you have you can build in
your favourite modality
so let me explain
just to introduce fixed points because it is based on fixed point
i just consider
the city formula actually that is a city cell formula but i could sit cl
because it it's in well known fragments
cgn which is a bit simpler
so the constraints and
siegel r
well the chicken is
polynomial time city sorry peace be peace space-time be space
the space time the space
so the city is a very nice gentle logic people like
and that's mostly what you find in checkers like
news and the whatever
all the tools that have been developed this last twenty years which would which have
led me
edmund clark and the MSO amounts to the civic is to have the
during award last year
you know is only is in between
and we and what's that
OK so CTL
is can that you can tell something that existed before eventually
proposition p holds
this is fine you
that means that from the roots of military