discoveries during the early years of x-rays astronomy we
discovered five no
x-ray sources so we double the the number of
sources that were are known from
rocket flights before us
and some of these sources that we saw from balloons
highly variable
we noticed
an x-ray flare
x-ray intensity went up by a factor of three or four
on a little time is ten minutes and that was completely new in those days
and that could not have been discovered from rockets because the rockers themselves only five
minutes above the earth's atmosphere
and they're not looking at one source all the time
they are scanning the sky because their objective was to find as many x-ray sources
as they could
but we're up sometimes twenty six hours so we have plenty of time to look
at one portion of the sky
for a long time for hours on
and so it was not an accident that we discovered these
flaring events
this lasted up to ten minutes longer
we also discovered an object which we called gx one plus four
the number has to do is we're this in the sky
and we noticed much to our surprise that the x-rays seemed to fluctuate in a
periodic fashion
two point three minutes
at the time we had no clue what that meant
but later as you will see very shortly
it became clear
that was the rotation period
of a neutron star
so the big question was in the early days what i these objects
and this is something that we have discussed
in a one
and i will go over it very briefly again but we discuss it in you
even at some
homework problems on it
these objects are
x-ray binaries
whereby by one object is very compact
which could be a neutron star
or in some cases even the black hole
and the other object other star
is a normal
nuclear burning star something like our sun and they're very close to get
they're so close together
the matter
which is here
is attracted by the neutron star stronger than that is attracted by
the star itself
and so it starts to find its way to the neutron star is a binary
so to go around each other
this metric and not just
going radially
but it was filed
slowly and find its way to the neutron star strangely enough
but we still don't understand
how it makes it but it does make it ultimately the neutron star and this
is that what we call
the accretion disk
this is the of pretoria
and this is the donor
donor provides the fuel
that finds its way
the the neutron star
and if you take a little bit
you drop that on the neutron star a neutron star has mass capital and say
and raise capital are
then the kinetic energy that is released that impact is something that all of you
should be able to do next monday
that is
g provided by or
equals one half
the career
this is the gravitational potential energy that becomes available an object of mass m
crashes onto the star
the surface of the star has a radius capitol are
the mass of the stars capital and that is converted to kinetic energy which is
one half MV squared so this is the speed at impact
of course is always independent of the land
and so you can calculate that speed and that speed is horrendous for neutron star
the reason being
that the radius of the neutron star is so absurdly small is only ten kilometres
it is roughly a hundred thousand times smaller than the radius of our sun
the mass of the neutron star is comparable to that of our sun a little
larger but it's comparable but it is the radius which is so small
and that's why you get speed at impact which is about one third of the
speed of light
and this kinetic energy is converted to heat
for the same reason that when we drop something here on the floor
the kinetic energy ultimately goes into heat
and so it it's up the surface layers
of the neutron star
and the temperature becomes horrendously high ten to seven ten thirty eight degrees ten million
hundred million degrees
and that very high temperature
almost all the energy almost all
electromagnetic radiation comes out in in the form of x-rays
the song
as the temperature of only six thousand degrees most of it comes out in the
form of optical light but when you go to ten million degrees that's no longer
the case the spectrum shifts in favour of the
the amount of energy that is released is
horrendous to give you some feeling for that
if you take a marshmallow
you throw marshmallow from a large distance onto the neutron star
the energy that is released
which is this an idea
it's comparable
so the energy that was released
the atomic bomb that was thrown hiroshima
and nagasaki that tells you something about
gravitational forces that i at work
on the surface of a
neutron star
no now what these systems on the evidence is overwhelming
we have observed the
rotation of the neutron stars the two point three minutes that we found we now
know is the rotation of the neutron star
neutron stars have strong magnetic field
and the metadata that creates onto the neutron star
reaches the magnetic poles
o eight o two you will see
you will learn why
this last mile which is highly ionized
but it cannot just reach the neutron star anywhere
but it is forced to
only enter
the neutron star need magnetic poles
and if the neutron star rotates than the magnetic poles can rotate like this and
the new owners you see x-rays x-rays x-ray no x-rays x-ray so you see positions
so these positions have been seen from any neutron stars now many of these binary
it's very clear that it's a binary system
if you are in the plane or near the plane
of the orbits of the two stars
then the neutron star
and go behind the donor
then you don't see any x-rays because the x-rays are then absorbed by the donor
and there you see an x-ray eclipse only x-rays vanish
so you would see
people solutions
strong x-ray signal and all of a sudden boom it's gone
and then a few hours later it starts up again
when the neutron star
reappears re-emerges from the donor star
but that picture is all
but i don't want to show you
at least
of what we think such a system
and you actually
well the most relevant document
actually like with high
is the probability of any
in the first and entity
and this
this probability is considered to be
proportional to its value
you have all the probability
of course system entity text
it just copies the data
so we UK
initially you can
the don't
please note
initial probabilities
and then
used to perform this
you go out
of system
and this is a the probability of going from one page
and next page
taking into account the page according to rank probability p
of the of the p that you come
but we're by the probability
that you actually that the
that link
so is it is often
computer and this transition is often computed uniformly
five outgoing links
of each
the show
so you get twenty percent chance of going
two serve to the next page
and considering
on the beach
that point
two of new page
so the point h
o point for age
you can of course one line also
just actually
randomly to another entity text
which is considered here
the same page
these probabilities
the user decides to make sure not to follow outgoing
any more
and not
all the models
if you that more
and i know that because
i think it's also
to look at smaller
because today we have various
well we have a u
technology here
for making in the network
for information retrieval
i have not yet been explored
nineteen ninety two turtle and cross
published quite famous information
the true model
as the propagation of probabilities
in in the network
so you have
consider that we the network
where you have to note
in graph theory
a directed acyclic graph
and you have to know which are present that they are you model
the causal relationship between parents and children of which you can see also the condition
all the world to which i don't
you have also moved in in such a network which will can give
we find that retrieval
the building
they built a document network
which is the already for document collection
as a directed acyclic graph
and the document
prior probabilities
usually these are uniformly
find of document collection
but you can give a higher probability priors to
some some set of documents if you have
so i think this would be competing models
and the documents in this model of to
a document generation after
have a certain concept
i have here
the strength of the things being the conditions
probability that child
generate give your
and also for the way
to ten
directed acyclic graph
but now use that kind of upside down the find certain concept
that generates the query terms
and the craters again for
this particular class
document retrieval then is seen as the propagation of
probabilities into the network
so that each document you can compute
system probability
of earliest c
by putting so by putting all the other documents in a not active
you can one by
computer propagation of probabilities until you reach to query
so you can do this for each document and then think
and source document
by the end of the
probability of that you have compute
for query
at each node
you can use
these types of
i didn't make too many mistakes it didn't kick me out but i'm moving on
two two boolean which sort of implies me
there was a question of when
when should we have a break those suggestion having one half an hour break after
one and a half hours is that
sort of okay with everybody
make it yes
right so i'm going to talk about something which is
the sort of a bit
due to what john was talking about john try to explain how to
detector spot patterns
in data
so you try to find dependency in data using
several types of algorithms and i would like to
teach you a different point of view which is also very popular now in the
area of machine learning so we have
some things in machine learning and other things and the other things that i'm talking
about is probabilistic modeling so the idea is now
you try to come up with models
how the data are generated and of course there's a lot of uncertainty in there
so it must be
a model that involves probabilities
and these models are usually adaptive they have a lot of little things to tune
and you can tune them
by training them on data
and once you have the model then somehow the algorithm at least the ideal algorithm
depending on your philosophy will automatically pop out so you don't start with an algorithm
looking at the data you start with your ideas
how these data are generated and then the algorithm comes
more or less from
ideas from statistics so let me see if i can make this running display pictures
so yes
as i said we're trying to bases models on
the way
we generate the data so-called called generative models
i have adaptive parameters
and then
we can see
it's going on
and then we have statistical methods for learning these parameters from the training data
and in a sense if you have a good model of course i mean that
depends on your knowledge of model assumptions then
well in some sense these algorithms are in some sense optimal and we are going
to discuss in what sense they might be optimal
and some interesting point is also
it seems you can you could even try to generate new data or similar data
and see
how well how similar they would be too
the original data so i have a very simple example o
i got even an overview
you never know what i have here so what i do in the beginning is
i talk about very simple
probabilistic models and maybe i should just before i do anything
we have already e
a bit of knowledge sort of in probability
but in statistics
well some you know just elementary probability
coins and sting
and from time to time again assumed density or something like that OK let's go
so well i mean
so this is why i love this kind of stuff it's always you know you
should not expect that everybody likes to say way i like it right so i
i start with a couple of simple probabilistic models and then
talk about so-called maximum likelihood estimation for the parameter of these models and also explain linear regression
related to gaussians
and then i'll just talk about some more advanced examples coming up with a model
called ICA at least a probabilistic version of well
maximum likelihood version of it and then i'll talk about bayes estimation
right so the first thing is the simplest model is
well very primitive not so
not so interesting in fact but is always start with something simpler and then build
conformal complicated things so this is a biased coin what i mean by a biased
coin there can be two possible outcomes zero and one of the head and to
well he we even think that all these data are generated independently
and we believe since it's a biased coin zero and one are not equally probable
but it's not one have but there is a certain parameter theta which is the
being one
so we're interested in the question what's the probability of an entire sequence of we
have a sequence x one two x ten and these are zeros and ones and
can show reshaping or assumptions which way that we get to the right eventually
OK but what we have here is that
kernel machines can approximate anything we want
or even the two layer neural nets for that matter can approximate any see what
do we do but those here and say absolutely nothing about the efficiency of the
representation with which the efficiency with which we can represent
of those
you know any function with
with those things
and for example there are there is a very good theoretical evidence that shallow architectures
you can really implement things like very visual recognition efficiently
so i'm going to just show flash a couple examples to use so that the
you know some of the resulting this actually for a few here
and you know some of the models of the some of them are shallow
but you know i'm expect to kind of at this but basically the one that
works best the points
and not so work best actually train faster and faster to run at the end
OK i'm going to show you a slightly more specific example that in a minute
so here is the slightly more example of that and should this example queries goes
well but merely here so let's say you want to recognise objects images that are
roughly hundred hundred pixels
you actually get to them because it's there which is plugged into a linear classifier
to get thirty percent error on the test set OK with the test and so
this is the training
yes it is there and for each of those images you have multiple images of
each each object so it's kind of event recognition problem i also thirty percent for
our classifier are
eighty to ninety percent fourteen years never something like eleven percent for the
five hundred percent for commercial that's nice and comparison of course because the SVM has
no idea what we know it's looking at images
but still the difference here is between sort of show and deep
there are differences as well of course you can always on the cards but then
you know
if should on the kernel you again you have a deep deep
it gets worse if you look at the time it takes to train the system
of odes to audition going from the screen so
the new point if one is OK
so this works so if you look at the time it takes to transport information
to get to eleven point six percent takes four hundred eighty
minutes on a sort of virtual when vigorous machine
so that's kind of a long time to get the same accuracy comes from that
you need sixty four
i mean gigahertz
on the same thing data so it's basically a times faster
OK know put the convergence snowbound no
you know whether that's the this of original bands
nonconvexity certainly
but it's faster it works better
and if you the training for the same length of time and support vector machine
you get happier right
the test is even worse is about three times faster to test
comes from that is here
this is considerably smaller
OK so changing the architecture
makes a huge difference and if you have to for a convexity for this fine
it gets even
works are
if you take those images that are sort of club versions of the previous ones
truancy and we get some kind of get forty three percent error basically it doesn't
work you know pretty much all the points are support vectors and it's not clear
that the there was any convergence to speak of here but essentially the best implementation
we had at the time of support vector machine which was one of actually was
one of implementation was
hospital aggressive because it implementation on parallel machine you can get a on that level
commercial net five foot nine percent error
that's actually amount of the sort of raw commercial that is less than a percent
and the training time or even worse into something worse
to can actually ten thousand minutes seconds to give us the wrong answer
in about half the time the commercial against point
enormous differences
and with the non convex you know
not particularly well justified theoretically methods
so you have to be careful with
you know with with things like that
OK so one of the things that has become pretty clear over the last few
years including for things like SVM and search is that people have been writing in
terms of papers on various optimisation algorithms
four is the and you know in the in
but still there is as yet no one that's and those of the learning machine
CRF on but which came out of the you know the controls work in the
over to his work and some of some work in the in the past is
basically a simple stochastic gradient descent beats everything by a factor of ten one hundred
or sometimes thousands
discover knowing because you come up with all those really sophisticated optimization methods to the
into its and you compare it to the right method you different and it's but
you might as well not comparative methods
so in fact i can wasted time my life and i was in toronto suppose
that actually implementing those optimisation algorithms like stories yes and yes yes and
you know all kinds of cuisine using that conjugate gradient comparing them with stochastic gradient
after six months and was this time with the time i figured which is you
stochastic gradient surfaces shopkeeper then when you read and
the my life and
you know we can have to be just we discovered this and get some data
on new learning algorithms to get convince people that that's the case
so one problem is that
let me see
we want to go here
so that's an argument for why why
deep architectures are more efficient than the this and what kind of of you know
however the head really too far down the
in applying so OK so are still several strategies that people can sort of use
in machine learning to kind of to taxes i problem or cancel the sort general
problems this is sort of philosophical and so recycling an argument that geoff hinton has
written in his review papers
so it's slightly different but it's kind of paraphrasing what he said
so one possibility to this defeatism since there is no good proposition for kind of
really complex functions of you know we should stick to kind of
building or feature set by hand and stick convex classifier on top and then for
each new problem will just find a new set of features or new kernel and
you know
the happy with that i will keep drugs
the second deduces is denial no correlations can approximate you want and the VC bounds
if feature based representations
is forty objects we are dealing with is not easy to obtain
maybe the classical example is when the objects to be described to be cut to
are represented in terms of graphs
namely the objects can be decomposed into parts
and parts
do not happen without any relation so there is some relation between the parts and
this means that the objects
can be described in terms of the graph
now once you have the graph representation for another this is
very difficult to obtain the color presentation
it's quite impossible to
start from the ground which is actually
by dimensional structure relational structure and to match
this structure into a point in the future
in this case it is quite difficult to obtain feature based representation
on the other hand and this is the good news
there are ways for computing similarities between graphs
compute similarity between arbitrary graphs may be
a difficult problem is NP hard in general case
but for some instances of graphs for example trees
the similarities between trees can be computed in polynomial time
so in this case and lacking
a feature space representation i can use k means for example or any other central
but nevertheless i'm able to obtain similarities between the so what i get a similar
OK that's the other situations where actually it is difficult to obtain a pictorial representation
back on the other hand you may obtain quite easily
a similarity between the objects you want to cluster
so pairwise algorithms so that was framework does apply exactly in these cases it is
a pairwise clustering algorithm accepts as input magics of similarities
it doesn't it doesn't accept it doesn't know anything about
the the way in which we are representing the objects
they need they like the graphs or vector or whatever it just accepts as input
matrix of
and starting from from the similarities with try
to partition the data according to certain coherence
so in one sense
pairwise clustering is more general than central class because he
we need to know
something essential about the way in which we are represented
that we also need that the object be represented in terms of vectors here
we just forget about
in representation is OK
provided that i have the means to compute similarities
in this talk be talking about it was classical problem
we accept the pairwise clustering problem algorithm accepts as input a set of n objects
and then find a matrix of pairwise similarities and the idea of course is to
input data into objects into maximally
coherent groups
so you are a very simple example we have
i mean we can
see there are four clusters
so for someone
in this case
the by the objects are represented in terms of point in the plane
and the distance maybe can be euclidean distance and of course we want is the
output level
and i said
OK otherwise
so we have four groups but of course
this is a very simple case
because there are there can be very different situations for example
here we have a situation where four clusters
different size
there we have also for clusters but the difference between the second case and the
first one is the clusters
you have a very arbitrary shape they did not come clusters in the final example
both with complex classes and we have an arbitrary shape so
the problem is quite challenging and actually it's the main problem in unsupervised learning actually
supervised learning machines
that class
so the problem of clustering objects into groups into coherent groups find applications in a
number of different domains from image processing computer vision bioinformatics information retrieval and so on
and so forth it's a very
important problems
so now we have
so just start from the from the beginning
ask a very simple question what is the cluster
because this would be the starting point from this
from this framework
let me also say that
they what clustering algorithms exist solely to start from a different question
they basically what i'm thinking for example
the number in which actually encounter later called
example normalized cut
and capt
and right
ectodysplasin algorithm cells
quite popular i think so
kind of algorithms actually start from a different question
i give you a set of objects give you similarities between objects and then the
question is how can i partition
the input data the best possible way in such a way that the classes are
maximally coherent
so the starting question is not what is a cluster and the i to find
a cluster and then i go ahead by defining partition
starting from the notion
there is that how can i partition the data and vesicles so usually what is
known is that one defines an objective function among
all possible partitions of data and so the idea is just
to find
the optimal partition according to the the objective facts
so now we start from a different question just write one so technically this question
what is the cluster
there is no
universally accepted definition of plaster
i mean formerly
but at least we can say that everybody will confer
a cluster whatever it means must satisfy these two informal criteria
internal criterion and the next most important
before defining the notion
the internal criterion says that
a set of objects
is the cluster if all the objects inside the the cluster are similar to each
this is not enough for defining the notion of the cluster because for example if
i take
in this way
if i think
for example this cluster here
plus here
OK so if i think it's i strict subset proper subset of this class and
say this one
this is not a classification
because it is included in the a larger coherence
this satisfies internal criterion
it doesn't satisfy the external criterion so in order
four class forty four set of objects to be defined the cluster we also have
to ask that
all objects outside the cluster should be highly similar to the one
the support of these two criteria actually would be
the the basic starting point from the definition of the dominant
so usually when we deal with the pairwise clustering problem we represent the data the
objects to be clustered in terms of the graph
were the vertices of the graph represents the
the products have the property that this is negative but we don't know that yet
so what are we going to do
well we're going to do is we use the fact that this f is an
element of all space so we can write this function
in this form we know there are some
coefficients such that the function can be written like this
OK so we don't know
what this function is but we know we can write it like this
and we also know that this thing is symmetric bilinear forms and now we can
use the linear linearity again and take the sums over the of five out
of this spelling from again
if we take them out
we get this thing here
and now
so now we have the product between two individual kernels
and the good thing is we know what this dot product is because by construction
we just look at how this thing was defined
now this is equal
because this was what i call the reproducing kernel property before
so we know this is equal to i phi i phi j with the kernel
matrix here
and since we have started with the positive definite kernel and that's the first page
where we're going to use the fact that the kernel is positive definite we know
that this is lower bounded by zero
so therefore we also know that this is bounded from below by zero
therefore we know that this thing with the angular brackets that have called asymmetric piling
up form so far this thing is a positive definite kernel
OK so that's the next thing know we have some additional tools because we have
proven certain properties of positive definite kernels and we're going to
let them loose on this problem
we're almost there
this is not movable
we have
so now we have two
can we know it's a positive definite kernel nice we know it's by linear but
for for this thing to be at the product we have to show that it
strictly positive definite strictly define it in the sense that
whenever the dot product we have to show
whenever this thing of function with itself itself is zero then the function must be
equal to zero so only the zero function
has this property that the dot product with itself is zero
that's what's left to show
well the rest we already know we know it's symmetric it's palinites nonnegative and so
on and so very actually nonnegative it doesn't have to be
so we have to show this thing
and how do we show this
OK we're going to use some of the properties that we had before
so in order to show the function is zero we have to show that is
zero at every point
let's actually square this thing because then we can use the cushy schwartz inequality
OK so the first thing is
we're going to rewrite this
the kernel between
o point into to the next
and the function
so that's a special case of of the dot product definition that we had before
so if you
look up here
so let's let's turn that say this is the function f that
cut out some of tasks and only evaluated one specific points so we take the
dot product between a function f and one individual kernel also so we remove this
and the bit is also removed here
OK here will
right OK so when starting
so i'm so are
so my
my field of
researches on logic not only
it's mainly on what were former methods faustus software
and logic the is very very important to them because it is used as the
specification language to describe the properties that you want to the to verify and assist
so that
the lecture here is about on
very expressive and the gene which is the mu calculus
can work yes
and the connection well the way too
let's say
handle muc whose
in the automated manner because this is the
the purpose of form verification is two
we cannot derive automatic
automated methods
to verify the properties on objects that are programs
so you have to think you have do not make it to the you know
the programs that are
i mean described in programming language and we extract programs to derive operational models you've
already seen some of them i believe new lectures like key conspirators for example
and we've seen a lot of the trees
when you have the models and you have the specification language given the logic
you have to connect both
nine does the model that they have here
satisfies for example
the formula that even in this language all
the idea is to have
a mathematical clean mathematical setting
to deal with these things
so now
what does he wants this one
the problem is that it's
so you're lucky because i cannot start
for the better this when the
it's common
great hope now the
which is the
this morning when i read it was finally
so here we are
right so now we can start so the
title of the of the lecture
it is about them in the connection that one can do between logic
these are intimidated tools that enable to handle the
manipulate logical formulas
how to reason the to matter
by using
two was OK
so feel free to interact of course
ask questions i have
keep more precise precise details on
what i'm telling you
so the
that line would be very simple we briefly
i mean
i to remember hollywood use logic for programs
then we will have to focus on a particular logic the most expressive one one
can think of in the way for
operational aspects of programs so that's new calculus
then we'll will see
as tools really connected
so it will not be clear at the beginning how to model connected to this
logic but that would be the purpose of
the last part here when we go from the mu calculus the alternating parity tree
automata special kind of automata
vice versa
and in between between ultimate that we can use the ideas of objects too
accept language of models
you already know but finite state automata
it except the finite set of finite words
you can have automaton that accepts
sets of trees finitary is infinite trees this was seen
the tools that one would be use
to answer questions
o automaton like membership of non emptiness of the language so that's the
that's the main part of the
so let me tell you about model checking which is the main motivation for us
to use logic programs
so one checking
is a very mean
well known problem problem now we will mean and you say established program
well the
whatever kind of mathematical framework use
you have some
system which is represented in the model
so for example for problems you can have the set of executions the
sequences of even the problem can perform
finite or infinite depending on what you want to talk about
and you have also language
four specification that's what i've explained
and the model checking
is to decide
so you have some compute computation computational less aspects there and this problem is to
decide whether this system satisfies the specification
so everything should be obviously given the clear mathematical setting both the models and the
specification language
deciding what to do
may know should know
is to know whether there is an automated message or an algorithm
to answer this
so obviously if you want to make things i mean
you may use able
in reality in the real world
the same thing doesn't mean only that you you have to
to know whether you this problem is decidable or not
but you also very interested in its complexity because you have to know the problem
is tractable
so this is the
general picture
and so here is an example that i will tell you how we naturally derive
some models
from programs
so it's a bit of a little introductory example where you start from something which
reasonably looks like problem
and i will take you to mathematical model the that we call
operational ones
well things are based on say
and so the point is that in this case the racing line is given and
it's all about how he would try and managed to stay
with the car on the racing line and
he was one the very small model of how you could go about that you
could represent the state at any given point in time as the angular difference in
the heading
of of your car with respect to the to the ideal line that you're trying
to follow and ideally you have had purchased a description of course and then you
as a result he will you want a mapping from states to actions policy and
and find an appropriate steering angle for fractionation achieving this being on on the racing
line and here is the
the training data and you're essentially fit the curve and and thereby learn the particular
controller that the human is using now this is
can you know a very boring model because the racing line is already given
following up on on what sam lectured about the latent variables the more interesting problem
that people are working on is to observe someone's driving
and now
using latent variable model the latent variable being the racing line and this person is
trying to follow
which then produces the
together with the policy for following it the particular steering actions that the person is
is taking and then the job of course of learning is not only to infer
the control policy but also to infer what the intended racing line may may have
and so that would be more elaborate model for this particular example but it turns
out to be quite hard to two
actually work with these games that may be an interesting point
in order to do some of these experiments we
i went to the game producers and ask them could you give us the code
base of
recently released game or something and they did but in
game software development is very special for you if you like because they are fixed
release dates and these games are never really finished there's this
at some point development stopped and then testing periods started and then there's this french
period where all the arrows have to be eliminated from the cold and this results
in the code beings become extremely ugly if you have some are there and there's
only one way one day two to go to the to release or something then
you have to do hacks and it's quite amazing how many dirty hacks finding these
codebase is you know usually these if
very specific condition occurs then do this very specific strange thing and it makes coding
within these codebase extremely hard once the game has gone gone through this transition period
it also has to do with the fact by the way that these games are
not revise for a second version something they once they are done the codebase is
essentially discarded and for the next version of the game people start new in in
that respect the games industry is a rather immature software development and
is a very poor culture in that respect because reusability isn't really used to its
it's a lot like newspapers the right
but these games can make money
so this is then
if these were the true control actions then these are the the ones that the
the neural network would do in this particular example
this was an example in driving games and another great challenge comes from first-person shooters
so first in half-life two the one i showed is a first-person shooter they the
terminology is relatively simple you see
the world from the first-person perspective
so that's first-person shooter comes from holding the gun in your hand so
in this role creating non-playing characters that behave like humans
is one of the great gold
and anyone who creates such game essentially ask themselves the question should incorporate current parts
which looks pretty stupid but at least provide something or should we just leave it
and so for example in halo two which is one of the most successful first-person
shooters ever they just left it out because they figured the state of the art
is so bad we'd rather have no bots then stupid bot which i think was
pretty good decisions
so one idea for creating bots is of course to learn the behavior from from
humans because there's a lot of potential training data around you wouldn't believe how many
kids you can get for generating data if you just provide them with
as yet unreleased game or you know
something that's amazing you can really data collection is not hard task in this particular
business but the problem of course is that you have
and what you want is tactical behavior in a very complex and more importantly in
a hostile environment
so let me give you an example of of
what this involves this is the skin game halo two that i was talking about
and i'll show you a a little bit how people play online in multiplayer game
there's no bots involved in these are humans but i want to show you what
kind of behavior is required here
you see i think i'll just do this idea trick again
so what you see here
but if you like
so what you see here is very rich world with various vehicles i i don't
know if you could see that the tank
you have
you rocks it's the big valley with trees there's other people involved there and the
goal of this particular game is to capture the flag
this is the red guy
it interacts the longer it stays in equilibrium and the lower will be its freeze out of abundance
sofor a coldthermal relic the more weakly interacting it is the larger it`s abundance
so the week shall inherit the universe they`re not going inherit the earth that's
clear but they will inherit the universe you can you can solve the Boltzmann
equation of the rate equations and calculate a freeze out temperature and the mass over
the freeze out temperature depends upon the mass of the particle the plant maps which
determines the expansion rate and this cross section sigmazerobut it only depends logarithmically
on those and you can calculate the freeze out abundance of the particle relative to
the entropy densityor if you wish the photon density and as the mass over the temp
freeze out temperature to some power and one over the masstimesa plug mass
time sigma zero now if you want to know the contribution to omega you multiply the number
density times the mass in here you see that this mass cancels this mass so except for the
logarithmic dependence of them out of the mass of the freeze out temperature this this
is independent of the mass of the particle it only depends upon the scale of the
annihilation cross section of course in the particle physics model the scale of the annihilation
cross section can depend upon the mask but it only depends on the annihilation cross
section one over the annihilation cross section and is not depend upon the mass
so that`s the general result of course it's not quite so clean when you dig into
the details you have to ask whether it's s-wave or p-wave annihilation or
you talking about annihilation of scattering cross-sections are also possibilities that the particle interact with
different strength with different other particles in the the thermal bath about this is known as
co-annihiliationand this sub-leading dependences on the results of dependences on the mass at
the number of degrees of freedom etc. so it's not quite so clean but that
gives you a good ideathe gross features of what goes on
so a cold thermalrelic has the following really remarkable and beautiful relations if you know
omega we want omega omega H squared to be point one two nine
you know we know very well what omega is for the dark matter then this
tells us for a cold thermal relic whatthe annihilation cross section is it has to
annihilate into light particles let's imagine it in it annihilates in the quarks so we know
something about this matrix elementwe know something about the value of the matrix element
we don't have to know whether it's supersymmetryorsupergravity or the Tooth Fairy it doesn't
matter we know something about this matrix elementso if we know something about that
process by crossing we also know something about the scattering cross section of the dark
matter particle with thequarkand if we know this we can work a little
harder and get the scattering cross section with a proton and nucleon or nucleus and
we also would know the production cross section at least we know the matrix element
that enters in this production cross-section so just by knowing omega in the particle you
know something about the annihilation cross section the scattering cross section of the production
cross-sectionyou don't know the mass so the reason cold thermal relics are so incredibly popular
in the Oran object a particular veneration is it leads to very rich possibilities
in experimental physics and astronomy so we could detect we know the scattering cross-section if
you go through the details it's a little bit weaker than weak but it's scattering
cross-section may be large enough to detect indirect detection experiments and sensitive underground experiments that
are run by people who of lost their had it looks like and you know here
I'm not gonna go into this because people here are very familiar with these ideas
in the subjective setting for example
hierarchical priors it's just this notion there
i may have a prior
over some complicated parameter space
uh i don't know how to specify the pryr so i write down some distributions
and they have some other parameters alpha
and say okay well you specify a prior over the parameters alpha
and those parameters alpha maybe are specified there's distributions with some other parameters beta
so then i need to specify a prior over the data and so on
okay now
people often look at this and they say
o with this goes infinitely up and that's completely ridiculous okay this only goes up
to the point where r
what's the point of these hyperparameters these hyperparameters here there are tying together parameters at lower levels
once you get single hyperparameters at the top
you just put down some distribution over them
and there's no point having extra layers above the
because you can marginalize out all those extra layers above it just get some other distribution
o ver say
beta here
so this a hierarchical process doesn't stop
at some point
ah wear you just have single hyperparameters that you just need to put some distributions over
and then empirical bayes
is this idea that
i write down prior are often in the form of a hierarchical priors on hyperparameters
i don't know how to that the hyperparameters so somehow learned more optimize and from my data
this is
an approximation to
what do we do if you actually averaging them
get any questions about their
let's talk a little bit about some of these different frameworks
so subjective priors
the idea is that priors capture our beliefs as well as possible
you know what's the point
now how do we know our beliefs
you know
it really depends on the problem domain
so if i'm trying to solve a particular problem i think about the problem domain
try to come up with some
don't be too scared about the notion of beliefs
i think a bit more has
not ridiculous ranges fourier parameters
all you really trying to do in your prior is specify ranges for your parameters
the spread out probability mass
so you can capture what's actually going on that's sort asymptotic
you know convergence idea
so you wanna spend all your probability mass but maybe don't spread out to ridiculously
because are making very silly predictions about what possible data
you could have been
in your model
how do you evaluate your prior well
one way to do it is if your model is fully specified
then you can generate data from your model
right that's what it means so you can generate data and you can look at the data you can say
is there what i expect
for example if i had a prior on
attributes of human beings
i generated from it and it is shown me there
people's heights with varying from
you know minus one meter seven meters i would say that's that's wrong i messed up
okay people's heights don't go negative and no and no human will never be seven meters tall
okay so i change my prior
so that i can actually generate something more reasonable
even very vague priors can be useful since the data
that's all very quickly exponentially concentrate its mass or unreasonable models
and as i mentioned before the key ingredient is the idea is is not the
prime here is the idea of averaging over the different possibilities
now empirical priors
here's a slide for
imagine you have a hierarchical model with some hyperparameters alpha
and what you can do is you can estimate those hyperparameters from the data
this is called level two
for type two maximum likelihood you optimize these hyperparameters while integrating out these parameters theta
and then for prediction
use sneak in
these optimise hyperparameters and the data in you do this for prediction
now clearly we have
we've broken the sum and product rule here
but there are some advantages
kennedy advantages are this is actually quite robust
your are allowing yourself to fit
alpha to the data
and so if your data was something that you totally wouldn't have expected
then your uroplakin can go fit somehow anyway
so overcome some limitations of mis specification of the prior
the problem is that you're double counting the data in the sense that you're counting the data once here
and once also in your estimation of alpha
but if you are only estimating a few hyperparameters then usually
there there will result in a lot of it it will be very very minimal you'll never notice it
questions about their
level one maximum likelihood is just a regular old max likelihood where you are optimise the status
so level to just says integrate out the status optimise the office
days later on
opportunities are
it is
three of
i like
the anchor
get ready
right four
we can
rather a lot of the people
in which the
in the
this is for
last is
you know it
well let me to
as you know right
one of them
but this
i talk about today
not so much tomorrow but today will be for these for a very generic state
space stochastic models
so would like to be able to estimate hidden process online i think i said
all this i don't need to go through any more because there's just a handful
of applications that we move on
people these all go online people could people can read that that stuff afterwards so
what i talk about today
well i guess most people will be familiar with
quite a lot of this list actually especially i guess the first one so i
just established the bayes theorem form that we need for today
i was talking a little bit about monte carlo methods i know that marries a
nice tutorial already i wasn't here that's exactly what he's covered of the artists survey
if few bits monte carlo methods that that we need
defined the framework wherein so we pose these things using state space model stochastic state
space models and the estimation tasks that were interested in particular filtering which is basically
learning about the state of the current time as the data evolves so as soon
as you see the data you want to learn about the posterior distribution for the
state at that time
then if you want to give you or alternatively if you want to give you
a bit of self-image retrospective look awful forward look through the data to get more
reliable estimates out of the data we can we may do smoothing that's statistical smoothing
one of the main building blocks for sequential estimation
and indeed
a building block for some of the particle filtering algorithms see tomorrow is the kalman
filter so i'm going to go through the analytic updating formerly
the kalman filter the extended kalman filter which works for non linear
models under certain conditions but consider the color filter in a rather neat probabilistic framework
some of you would have seen this before it's available in various textbooks already for
example i first saw it in the textbook by colman but there are also not
common common doesn't like the probabilistic interpretation of the color filter it also we had
to belong to those
we have
and to belongs to a workshop on particle filtering in cambridge of you in nineteen
ninety in two thousand six and he pretty well disagreed with the whole foundation the
whole workshop but he gave us a couple of nights someone else there was great
as long but he doesn't really agree and doesn't really agree that stochastic processes even
exist so physically not in the mathematical sense
so but i will talk about the colour filter from the probabilistic point viewpoint bayesian
updating of probability densities for me the need derivation of the of the common fields
shows a lot of light on this type of particle filtering area
then moving to monte carlo filtering area to just oppose it generally how you do
monte carlo filtering filtering that doesn't quite solve the problem doesn't give you the sequential
updating that you need with the particle filter or at least not completely tractable form
so then i'll talk about the basic way of doing that
the sequential monte carlo bootstrap
that's the view i've that's what i call the vanilla version of particle filters the
simplest version then i'll talk about the journal version that that allows you to deal
with harlem models using few particles through the choice of appropriate important functions
tomorrow we'll move on to other types of particle filtering also talk about some applications
that we've worked on things like using particle filter smoothing particle filters the rare blackwellized
particle filter a very important area at the moment MCMC
with particle filters so they can be coupled and very powerful ways
but bayesian inference well expect we do about this but i'm going to be talking
about marginal inference we have some observations y
quantity of interest let's say that x
and we have some nuisance parameters in the model call those things
but we can form if you like a sensor model tells us what's the probability
of observations conditional on all of those are
required texts and the nuisance parameters theta formulate the joint posterior probability for all of
the unknowns in terms of that the likelihood function
and the prior distribution
jointly over all the unknown this features and of course on the bottom line of
bayes theorem we have this effectively constant is constant for any given model and data
set y so that there is
as well as in many bayesian calculation is going to be neglected as constant in
each step of the particle filtering algorithm and we do the bayesian updating
and of course if we want to model inference for the quantity of interest we
will integrate out x using the more the marginalization identity from probability theory and that
thing would be the thing if it's just sex were interested in that's the that's
the quantity was used to do
the inference and of the joint
monte carlo methods
so this is actually an output from one of the particle filters are two dimensional
particle filter out a particular
two is two-dimensional state vector overtake particular time and it comes from a nonlinear model
is that very simple model is used a lot as benchmark test model in particle
filtering and this was one of the posterior pdfs that came out of that particular
time is the kernelized density estimates obtained for it and we obtain that instead of
trying to solve this very intractable density is certainly multimodal is probably not galaxy in
the story doesn't look
calcium doesn't really look like a mixture of gaussians not not a convenient number of
components anyway so we represented instead using monte carlo representation
that simply means that ideally we like independent random draws from this PDF instead of
the density well represented directly in terms of number of randomly sampled points from this
PDF montecarlo representation and that's very convenient representation in particular for calculating difficult expectations
so let's suppose we want to
work out expectations with respect to some highly complex probability density p of x so
this one then the expectations
we may require in general be some functional h of the state variable the integral
with respect to
the probability density p
as i said with the that with monte carlo
thereby by generating random samples from p of x in the notation are used random
samples throughout is a superscript so if i have the example of a large collection
of n random samples and label that x superscripts i for the life of those
informally it's quite nice to think about that
it monte carlo approximation to the density function itself
and using direct functions
the probability theorist like it's very much but it's it certainly gives you the right
answers and it's a nice intuitive way of thinking about monte carlo representation so once
we've got a random set of samples for a large number
of samples and all drawn from the probability density function p that somehow and said
i would generate with thinking were approximating p of x
as a lot of point masses basically because these are all the samples independent samples
from p of x the there is an unweighted samples so we have one over
and just to normalise the approximation to pdx
and then using this into intuitive interpretation
we can easily see how things like
approximations to expectations drop out of the formula because we're going to take the expectation
you can see the tree
or you can use all the iterative algorithm to continue current you can appear to
be some kind of
expectation maximisation
so that for your
the first classification model
but for the information extraction i will not speak a lot about in the course
because it can cause because our proposals for the experiment on semantic role labeling
it very hard to language
two weeks later by the
because we have so many real natural language for you
you have
certain combinations of words syntactical structures that occur the
you can do it because you have many of the language you have usually very
long so you have many many exceptions
many many real situation which
you're my because just more
so this may be weakly supervised
the reason why they are especially for information extraction
quite a good job
but in the early nineties
and i think people will be less than in this area
quite quite well for many many years
it was studied
information extraction we're not quite well go back to
actually we heard coming
it goes back to the night
i think the really people of artificial intelligence community where by hand back to refer
in fact
i mean that sense with for very limited domains because if you have a hand
crafted rules and the you doing that
it a lot
a lot of human to end there are many domains languages so there that you
have so many things that you would have to
so you can only do so for now
x subject
later on in the his career people start started see in the core
also we think that supervised learning
so using machine learning techniques
in the that would
that's how this problem of manual
the manual work people
of course you have to and think you have to annotate labelled the
in your country
but usually
well it is usually done by top to them in summer time high hired is
in the time domain the document collection and competed at her less tedious
along the coast
right so that y
but of course there are
people now look into it seems like lot thinking
i have a few more like general and then you can go into
the first real action symbolic techniques
you you might
but really this type of semantically labeling related if we see the name of person
or if we look at an image and have heard or here we have someone
are we there angry
where do we get the play
you can even ask yourself the question do need label
but if we use the name in the classification within class
we can define why don't you
i think
i also had like references only some symmetry for to another dimension that like bill
clinton to younger brother
we want to make it
and that you can perform
on the other hand suppose you're working in biomedical domain
you know very specific
in chemistry and biochemistry for instance that might
i have that is name or they only over that particular
when you try to extract the creation
the becoming my head writer of
you can also exploit when you're
in your
you can exploit
this much higher
and you know binary
and of course many people speak about ontologies
when you really
find a certain domain
by number of concepts and relationships can be called
so these ontologies
they are used to provide
certain words that have
they have
basically parliament image processing algorithm to obtain an efficient algorithm on essentially there's no black
box with to OK so obviously basically it's going to be you are going to
put a lot of work for you MCMC algorithm to work OK so all
it's very similar advice metropolis to gibbs sampler if you update the stuff the valuable
at the time either i dependent on the target is not going to work well
if you try to design basically to update a lot of highly correlated variables simultaneously
it's very difficult to model we see away
two abate simultaneously like one the correlated viable using kind of mixture of particle methods
on elm MCMC but still no methods actually quite complicated tune on design
OK so one way that has been proposed which are was supposed to talk about
but i actually decided not to because i wanted to talk particle one way you
can essentially tried to
black box with some of try to import basically you MCMC type degrees is to
build an adaptive MCMC type algorithm so those guys libraries which i don't discuss how
we put some slide on my webpage and you can have a look at them
if you will
and after MCMC algorithm what they try to do the tried to basically
use the output of the markov chains that use simulated so as to tune the
parameters of the proposal k on that so as to optimize in some respects some
cretan it's way to impose some or all of MCMC algorithm of basically the naive
it's all right
he so the so the the answer is you don't actually is true there's no
actually not for any kind of realistic modelled that essentially no results yet so what
people do
on this in the important particles typically from a particle point of view going after
us some empirically was the algorithm works well not so one thing people are doing
is typically that they're gonna run obviously
many alisation wntn secularism starting from some are very diffuse distribution so you're not starting
all the markov chain from the same same state obviously you can
use like value essentially nasalisation of the of the markov chain or one of markov
chain algorithm on t essentially few these degrees are converging towards the same
the same the same essentially mode explored due the same estimate OK so that obviously
that's not to pull it off
a bulletproof guarantee that you have conventional attire distribution but at least that you've explored
actually interesting same so like local node of the target distribution of things you can
do to kind of SS was
you algorithms that list even if it's within the model whether it's essentially exploring properly
this mode is essentially once again generates basically
your your your market chains so you can have sequence of parliament to six i
on one thing you can do is basically compute the autocorrelation function
of this of this marker markov chain to give you an idea of essentially all
dependent the on you generate all depend on the sample you generates OK so you
do see
you compute the autocorrelation say
of the
simulated sequence for one parameter on you see that is of the correlation function becomes
extremely slowly towards zero then it means that actually algorithm is not working with a
talk because essentially you're part during the successive values are generated i e dependent one
from each other so it's the kind of indication that the algorithm is mixing extremely
slowly but there is no bulletproof so there are some diagnostic you can use obviously
to kind of onshore always the idea of the kind of work and not but
really that's just know
i mean i agree some maturity called justification for complex problem is very empirical what
is done in the literature
so that's the limitation of ncnc you have to accept it i that's serious limitation
commonly were
there's the technical report in the paper
by gelman genetics
although it appeared applied point between nineteen ninety five something like that eats
the poor and so for this thing became extremely popular
the portal is actually a of the of the
what i the same is only valid extremely strong conditions
which are essentially they're dealing with high dimensional target
OK to distribution
which factorized so the component is an independent
they are i i d
OK on the problem the solution either on the more that factorizes century
on the components of i i d on by basically that limiting arguement they show
that's the thing to do when they try to come to optimize their thing is
what i thought tried forgot forgotten thing where they tried to optimize the try to
maximize the thing was back to the to the scaling of the on the mortgage
the expectation
of this the
the square of distance between x and plus one xn OK so to try to
maximize to estimate these distances are maximal as possible
you've got this magic zero or two forty four that get comes out there should
be already in that makes that's based on the stupa strong assumptions so it's very
interesting results this is like
but it's
the and i am not quite convinced this is so useful particularly because the assumption
actually never satisfied
but is it before
what we could do
OK let's try to pull the whether discuss
he is to use those
went into type techniques like that i will discuss it at the MCMC is really
you use the pages don't put up the simulated markov chain on relatively you try
to tune essentially the parameter of the algorithm so as to satisfy the given criteria
so for example you can try to tune it so that the acceptance rate of
your metropolises o point two four fall on you try to tune it so i
basically what are they doing that trying to basically goes to maximize the distance between
the squared distance between two two successive state of himachal chain you can almost OK
so you can do that on only section called related technically to stochastic approximation literature
skip so what people doing well so
people nodes pollinators and well like quite well on complex point four four
for a long time to do active our for fifty years OK
most of the techniques that have been developed to try to come
we with some more to bypass the limitation of still MCMC agrees
he is only we see this is exactly the same thing in the context
of particle method they tried to modify the initial something problem by essentially adding some
kind of oxygen are volleyball on CD target solutions we try to modify the original
problem so that the something that's easy
o is really something which i think policy very disturbing for people working saying optimisation
of kind of learning theory where people have tried to do like sampled bones they're
trying to come up with a grenade grenade essentially this is very
so let's look at this i would have been proposed based on what like an
intrusion on basically is as i say always very difficult to obtain some kind of
theoretical reason for that sort of the same reason that the cities like we the
theoretical justification for that it's more basically people have intrusions going increase empolis beating the
mixing of the markov chain on basically might have been able to put it on
speech he he is is that he take
clark was text corpus domain specific problem which is kind of a lot of things
which is example our domain which is monday and then
problems and put all the information
try to capture the information and put them
into ontology so we concentrate in this in this content on the text content and
try to bring the content into ontology and model the ontology sold except for this
but this ontology learning
the first step is that we try to capture the terms and the problem of
this is that we have a lot of terms which are located in
the was but it must find out the meaning to be we can use the
to to find a lot of the terms to continue if in this weekend's called
yes i have and what is known from the university part of speech tracking and
so on so we can find out what's going on in a certain way and
what's the problem can give them something but in the end the user must decide
what is big shock probability and how you arrange them in the hierarchy and so
on so but try to find out how to get to him is list of
which out in the second step for instance we tried to some relations between this
concept he captured in the first step to be taken to determine put concept into
the ontology arrange them in the right way and now we try to capture this
taxonomic is is relation between the different concepts the next step would be to find
some non-toxic and also fifteen users on his some data-mining techniques and is that i
i mean if you in the next slide a little bit more
details about this that and because of the time constraints sitting steps
maybe you can download some
it just goes down the last point i want mentioned is the index is a
lot of resources for instance but it's quite large and not only focused following the
domain if you are interested in what they really want to hold about the site
of the whole english information that you need some steps forward under the under certain
domain and for this we developed some pruning technique also some of the things i
find to be talking about in this problems in that to do lots of ontology
and we think also the we have no basis to start modelling a smaller basis
to start so
that's coming towards semantics and regulations which is one of the ontology learning from this
for an ontology from the semantic web so we have on the right side a
small ontology
and an example of ontology which is about events areas fishing and so on and
on the left but we have some website which we can take
that's important what was to derive some further information goal is to find out which
relation exists between some concepts and for this we apply
some of the station woods
which i hope is very very knowing and what we made is the
he capture some relations of the terms in these documents and we count if often
occur together for instance the
it's an area which concepts of the ontology and you can have a lot of
terms from this document to this concept
how often then there must be a relation between
this the concepts the drive an relation an accommodation for for instance relations
i'm not only did she has to
this is located in a certain area and
the problem is that you know already
that's the accommodation and
gary are related to each other but we you don't know how they related to
one of the problem we have we can only present the user data relation but
we don't know which relation and this one that is that you can do we
can try to find out how they are related you can use some grass it's
normally gives some people to
how you rate but it's the next step so it's one of the example that
i want to show you another
now it's it's the next step maybe have and what or ontology which is given
to us and the problem the next problem is that we need some instances to
fill up this ontology can be can only
brokerage this ontology if you have some instances of that have some ideas to bring
the instances automatically automatically into the ontology
according to our knowledge base
so we have on the top of his life and example from ontology and we
had this
that aside i presented last slide and now we are interested in find some
in fact
between one into the ontology and he can do something nice from the information is
one example
where you can actually solve problems
by running the junction tree our or belief propagation
and not all
every triangulation
i will give you the same marginals
i mean these are with them is an exact power no approximation
it's just making things convenient in the sense that
it's very structured our from that creates these nice but the structure
when you first compile
computation that you can we compute everything you can precompute
so that the query time you just use exactly
the minimum of information create time
everything will be equal
approximate computational
OK so just illustration of some practical examples that you can solve the graphical models
i mean he just illustrate
first of all let's assume you want to solve that some
well probably very large cluster very complex pattern recognition problems
which is matching structure
we do this all the time right when we are recognising people in recognizing faces
recognising objects
and particularly fusion but also text of every every recombination activity involves
some sort of matching between your model
that you have in your brain
the observation
and if that model
if that match score
is higher than the given value then you classify something as belonging to some classes
i mean
its population is very very complex problem i mean
you can model this pattern recognition problems as a graphical model why because graphical models
are very natural things to model for example
geometric constraints
distances relative distances can be modeled as pairwise potential
between also fire
angles can be modelled as
potentials involve at triple the fire
by using
for example you can enforce
region matching by matching distances
you just defined distances of being potential
of pairs of fire
you can do
even more offensive stuff for example you do so a fine
matching what
u one to match
it happens that are different by find transformation what you find the information is is
but the most general linear transformation that you have something of these five
so you can actually stretched according to scale the
and translator
have constant here so they can translate this thing
and you have access
and they have this is major fear of coefficients
a one one one two two one and two two that basically definable the scale
of your path
and you can in called these in a graphical models
in this way
this is an example some work done in the past
so for example if you have
o point correspondences of this time
you need three point correspondences to uniquely
because this system here this is the general linear transformation in the plane
it's a system of two equations
you have six via
in order to solve the system i you
three of these
pairs of equation
so if i have three correspondences
like this
i'm able to give
three sets of these equations for x and y
i can solve this system that uniquely determine the final transformation
well it turns out that they can
use a graph of this type of graphical model of this talk
working every clique of size three for example i called one possible if i'm transformation
by running the junction tree our here
i force
i can enforce it every
the trouble is that get something
is you can have serious rejection sampling as a component in those
so let's move on now
and talk about the metropolis and
so the methods we've looked at so far
much elements
the blindfold
i was told to go to a random place and look there
you start and maybe some other information you want
moving around
every move is independent
the previous so the new location we said to just rules into every time you
above something which
now the metropolis that
it's going to be an example of a markov chain
what elements
which means that instead of asking
you go to a new location
it's completely independent where he's been or
there's going to be a dependence on where he is at the moment so when he is now
going to move into a new location
that depends on the current location
why should help is not at all clear that why we want to be
dependence on
but i want it
so now you have two of
this is
the next location
and this is
the current location
and this assumption is going to be
we can draw from q
so q can be something simple like a gas in distribution or something then points
and we're going to assume that we can evaluate you
so we have an acid solution
you read
is nothing
look like
this example if
this is the current location
hand if
this is an application
the right
and maybe you might look like
that's the sort of concept we have maybe
was just distribution is centered on the current location and the things that
it can be any distribution like
as long as you can draw from it and you can evaluate it so you
can think of this as being completely general
you can draw from this is the sort of thing that you it is a small large state
or perhaps a bit much you could use very broadcasting want
or any distribution that you can draw from
so it's okay
which should to be
something to emphasise their
it's okay
look like it
importance sampling
rejection sampling
this work really well if q looks just like he presented
it's like
if you can make that looks like an
draw from it
and that means you can solve the original problem the
some of
in the metropolis it's okay
but it's there classical logic it isn't there or not
but it's not a lot nicer having this adding
distribution in a primitive
because it's just ugly doing that i mean just saying blk all got these rules
for the connectives and that's what we mean by the connectives but i yeah there's
one two
and you say where does that come from all comes from the river and talked
about the cleanest proofs you've got a
model theory and you got proof theory it's nice to see the match up because
they both seem into it
well here is that really matchups we got patch
we can throw in another arxiv o now the match
well is it with a new proof theory wasn't doing the job giving
a real understanding
proof in the system is this is just say oh yeah distribution which is going
to throw it and in fact the interesting belnap systems original ones and i'm not
having go them i'm not saying there are a bunch of tricks or anything like
this now they were they are very smart but they were doing this sort of
you know after hope they did their ground-breaking work a lot of other people thought
about it
and eventually rose came up with this
which is as i say quite elegant and easy
and very intuitive because you say OK well this is what the proof by cases
it we're going to take a look at in parallel what happens
to each of these things
and instead here we did
was we introduced a new subscript
right and that's why
we had a conjunction here we had to say see here
and we could also are d vere you see here we could
bringing in here
why because it this is discovered different subscript right for conjunction
introduction we eat the same subscript
that was the that's what ruins that having this and script restriction four
the conjunction is what makes things difficult
i have the distribution true for classical logic for it
it's thirteen lines long
list what i came up with
and i think that's probably about it
but you but also says why it fails and with relevant logic
but this pretty systems were much
as i said before and
ross has a
if you come to read his writing materials as this is difficult stuff and all
you have to read it a few times because what he's dealing with this very
hard in some ways but you can see beneath the surface is very elegant and
intuitions and is very good mathematical logician
is proven a lot of really standing
things one of which will talk about in the last half
we have plenty of time OK negation
the negation in relevant logic
looked at properly
my way
it is i think quite a bit like negation intuitionist logic and classical logic
and the key to this
is again false
but the falsum here is going to be an interesting thing
remember i told you
that in relevant logics
a or b
is this is called the variable sharing property that we talked about
a erobi
is going to be a theory
however out of tracks
only have a and b share least one propositional variables
that's too
make them in some sense relevant one of the only thing i think makes rather
i think the notion of real use a premises in introduction is what really defines
is something interesting has an interesting property and i think it's important property the one
thing reasons why
it's interesting
it is because of the treatment of contradiction server we saw in
intuitionist logic as it's normally construed by the BHK interpretation
the notion of contradiction
it doesn't include the notion negation can because it used to define negation
and we don't want to circular definitions
relevant laundry
the notion of contradiction isn't
we need national contradiction actually it's very well
develop notion yet
relevant logic isn't that new goes back to nineteen fifties are actually the very first
relevant logic was developed in nineteen twenty eight by a guy named ivan or love
and we know nothing about him apart this one
paper he wrote maybe now people know that more about them but i think
use user action he wrote this paper in russian it wasn't rediscovered until the nineteen
our lady it is by cost division whose serbian but also happens to regression and
he revealed to the world translated as quite nice paper but
but all of that he was
giving after broward intuitions mathematics people want to come up with intuitionist logic and and
height eventually is one who came up with what we call intuitions logic now but
so there this very common
reduction in the book being concerned about which is multiclass
two binary classification
so as the first thing i'm going to talk about
the next thing
his cousins the classification the classification
the cool thing ideas about this
is that so general
as a classification problem
and you can think of every classification sort of problem is
cousins defuzzification
the idea is that later
OK so multiclass classification
it is the same as binary classification
except we have more labels
seventeen zero one you predict one two k
any classifier to predict one get
and then
given your multiclass datasets
you define a multiclass classifier
with small areas so that means that
you know
the probability predict around from d
once again i'm not going to be
throughout everything i'm assuming that
examples are actually drawn from d
it's not going to be the now
OK so this should be straightforward is using binary classification
just smart labels
and then
you want do but you want you to solve multiclass to binary
so there's is this technique
first by
in bacteria
what is this
pretty nice actually
it says
suppose you by binding learning our rules
and you can solve multiclass classification the following way
for every
you can create a weighted binary problems
which are distinguishing between a subset labels in those subset cells
first by many problems here
and the correct prediction is one
it is the label is one or two things which predict one
in three or four users predict zero
and then you can create another minor problem which is here
it's one of its one three thinking about a problem which is
one of its water for
and then
at classification time with you want to try to predict
what is the right
multi class
you can run it if you want classifiers
you can get some predictions like for example in
in this case it is clear that
oppose it looks pretty clear
it is the right
multi class label predict
we have a look at least one error no matter where we are
and the possibilities of one are
one three or four
so maybe randomize over this
and then
you can have a very strange
it's two areas where you
are now is one are here
the way you do this you define some sort of set of labels
the binary training data
you just x
the indicator function of with not the actual labels in the set
that is how you do it for each of these
and then finally the way to make a prediction is you just find the closest
in hamming distance anschluss
there was a very nice
simple analysis
plessy reduction step analysis
so we're going to use that one test classifier trick so we can take all
these different binary problems
and we can embed
the name of the set
into the feature space
the nice think about having any classifier
OK so
but you see that one but classifier
i think about
this is
the multiclass distribution
is the induced distribution in the binary
one by the classifier
and the claim is that for every
number of multi class labels