so now i'm gonna take those two measurements the measurement that happened seven measure happened
in number represent the in a slightly different way
so this is the same data got four data forty four pairs numbers is the
same data i just indexed by time now
so you see that the one the one red point we're looking up a force
pair numbers seven and eight am
is now is now put there on that axis it's seven am four data points still
so the natural thing you want to do next
it was okay what if i measured at nine am
what if i measure which what if i measure are rate ten am
and so on
what this is getting at is
if we want to measure at seven and we use the by very similar to that again nine use
i three-dimensional gas in four-dimensional guassian five dimensional gas
but really what we're getting out what we care about are are what we might
be interested in is inferring the entire function over time
and that's that's how we get to gaussianprocess intuitively
so rather than having some finite set of galaxies that we have to measure strictly from
we have if you will infinite gasses and that's that's what function is
here's how we're gonna represent that's throughout
throughout the course so
each of these feature this function curves and color is gonna be a single draw
from that gaussianprocess as a function
with the way we represent the areas represent the prior distribution is with this this
means which this gray line here
and this on the left this around which is two standard deviations around so what
this is saying is that we imagine that's
the average draw is gonna be something like that and we have some some distribution
that will surround inside an envelope
what this allows us to do and this is this is this is really one
of the key features of the gas in processes the remember before we talk about
measuring rigidly at those hourly times
but now if we've got this nice infinite dimensional object we can measure really at
any time we want and we'll get in all the mathematical reasons
for for why we're able to do this
so i can measure at this particular time
and you can see what's happened
is that measured data point at about ten thirty
and what that's done is that's taken my prior in the same way that we do in
in that fixed dimensional case that's taken my prior
it's said actually is refined into a posterior r and this is actually i believe
that my function is not quite flat anymore but rather close the data points and
you can see that around the data point that i measured and i have no
have increased confidence
we can then take another measure
more measurements still and you see what's happening as we go through this process
as we get more and more data
were striving out
this regression function this nice smooth underlying function
and we're getting more and more confident about the envelope around
okay so
that's into a summary is is is is as follows
when we are taking
when we're taking measurements single measurements at seven am we are getting
real valued variables so as being a very gas a nice distribution over real valued variables
we move at the pairs or triplets or what have you that the multi very guessing allowed do there
and now when we want infinite numbers are real valued variables in other words functions
are real valued variables that's what a guassian process allows us do
if you take nothing else away from from this lecture take take better way that
this is something that allows us
the gaza processes effectively something that allows us to have a gas in distribution over infinite numbers of variables
and what that drivers to
is this notion of regression
so let's look a regression real quick and talk about a few reminders of what regression task force
i put this up again so here we've got all these blue data points belief
that we've observed and we believe that there are some smooth underlying function
that's really what the descriptionof
what the date is doing
so one of one things regression is quite good force just at which is denoising and smoothing
so we want we don't wanna follow
every little wiggle these data points but rather but rather come up with some
good description of a v what is noise and what is true signal
we also want to prediction and forecasting stock collected all this data that's great but now i wanna know
what my heart rate might be
OK let's continue so what i covered so far worse
introduction to machine translation also
but more in machine translation evaluation
i told you how to use a phrase based models to be according to find
the best translation
not to fill the missing gap in the middle that to tell you actually how
do you learn these models when you actually
require all these probabilistic models
and after that
there are
two other topics that about one is that the translation model
and the other one is this kind of training
the third time the slide
i think that now you know the sentence
so you
you take the input you break it up into phrases you translate
each phrase you can see that the most important thing is to learn here
is the phrase translation table you know for each
input phrase one of the possible translations
but you get that from before that
i usually avoid having too many formulas talks but
it is after this one so this is kind of mathematical way you can discuss
this model so
you you look for the best english translation e for foreign sentences so that this
argmax e
the probability e f so there might be all kinds of english sentences
and you look for the one in this sentence has the highest probability
the first thing you do is you apply bayes rule
that allows the main purpose of that is it allows you to introduce the language
models if the probability of english
it flips around the translation model so you suddenly have an the
translation model the foreign given english so that the system mathematical reformulation
and then you kind of expanded of the translation model is
so the translation model here consists of a phrase translation models used for sale the
and then we also have
distance based reordering model
it's technically part of the translation model so you
and for each word you have some kind of sense of how much distance is
that between the end of the phrase in the
because between the beginning of the phrase in the end of the previous phrase and
that's the consider that reordering model
so the presentation model
both of these two models must break down on on this phrase aligned so you
have to sum up of all the you if you
in fact of all the phrases that are
but use symmetrisation here stands for each phrase to use your phrase translation probability
and you have reordering probability it gets a bit more complicated like that than that
but for now that's kind of
the working assumption we have some sense of translating phrase time you ignore the context
wanted to say the phrase
in the context kind of comes back in the language model
so as i said the important thing to learn to see the phrase translation probabilities
o processes pitch why is it good models
this is kind of ways by translate phrases not just individual words
so the nice thing about phrases you have more data you have the more likely
you in big chunks of text
see if you can do many to many translation
so these things that are usually very hard to do magic phrases like kick the
bucket or bite the dust artist
the future
really hard to explain berber translation basis you know he just like the phrase so
as long as two years you just learn phrases
so that allows you to have a little more local context a lot of words
that are very ambiguous good example this
for instance interest to very ambiguous words classical example association and you also works like
the rate
i'll ambiguous could mean all kinds of things but if you put them together interest
that has a very clear meaning has very clear translation so it's often better to
use the local context in translation as
and the other stories that more and more data you have
the longer phrases can be learned so
you might even see entire sentences
if you have enough training data into some say that's the crazy
so this is an example of early on these festivals look like you
you all possible for sensationalist huge tail at the end
and then each of the first session of the probability
on the way to get them from
well we start actually already
one step ahead we start with the word alignment
and i'm not talking all about how to get the word alignment so that
there are the original IBM models
that had a very good story how word alignments occur alignment itself is huge research
problems several papers published in the how to get a better alignment
i think for this purpose so i want to say to someone well-defined task but
not really
so if you look at that word alignment matrix do there
OK maria mary
OK these are the two words there should be trusted to have a nice matrix
the block so that's a good translation the same thing with notion that the
that means green just you know hardly
any argument about that gets a bit fishy with function words
so if you look at the where did he wanted to with the way did
i said it aligned with the no
why did i do that
well because whenever you have been no in spanish
i don't know that refers to work then you have did not in english and
english can just say not the obvious that we did not
a couple of things you can do that you could say well it's just a
fun english words it doesn't mean anything and you don't have to be dispassionate shouldn't
be aligned to anything to just throw away
so should so this technology and the point all
the third argument you can make say well actually contain some valuable information it contains
the past tense of the verb
if there wouldn't be did but there will be do then
you know the spanish were whatever it is and i have no device special
and would be that has so maybe that should be aligned to the tablet there
so this makes it possible thanks
you can do with function words not examples actually the
proposition spanish proposition
so you have i love prove
well in english you don't have a prepositional phrase that you just regular noun phrase
so what he did with the proposition
well he said words kind of the same thing as the
kind of
part of the beginning of the no
introduces that noun phrase
but you could also say it's not aligned to anything
or you could say
you have a prepositional there because that particular
spanish verb phrase requires the prepositional phrases objects so maybe it should be produced together
with the work for
alignment of persian words is not entirely clear
OK you are going to worry about that we we just got basically assume that
some visual world we know that kind of probability
at the end
what we observe it just the document and the visual world and we discovered the
that the latent topics
since this
one composer
written the first row
we can use the marginalisation rule
april the rule of
the joint probability
probably observing words and documents
and we can
by using these three
the probability of serving awards given documents
written this way
and is like mixture
topic so
an image can be seen
as a lecture topics for instance and the object
this can be seen also online
so like
i'm optics the composition
taking care
normalisation of the model
what we want to do
we want to
recall that the probability of visual world
given a topic and the probability of their
topic given the documents
and to do this we must make
mark maximize
they're like like likelihood functions
using a model one
and after that we can use them outside the universe
of the image
or we can
use that
distribution over topics
the image
as important
for discriminative classifiers
this this is going to have to aspire to get the file
this tool
it is one of the most powerful
for scene classification pretty stunned
and here we have some results where
obtained by bush
we we have
just the probabilistic latent semantic analysis
the probabilistic semantic analysis by taking into account the partial
light of the image
and just above the visual word
with special you
and SVM
so we can see that
using latin topics and also information on partial
relationship between this topics
results increase
this small that being used also for
object categorisation
in this case
the health effects
one hundred
four hundred one object that have been using
and the result is quite nice
take into account the large ability of this
this stops
again this picture is the time you see this
this is the main framework
and what we have done
we have
i propose we propose to model represent images
it is similar to
the more the using text
and we have to build
this model to build their problem which were more than we use but the recognition
in order to infer which is the best
and after that
we can build a representation of our images
and we can use but the punisher going to classify
together they decided to categorize images
before i finish i want to give you
a very brief examples of occupation the man with the bag of visual model being
we briefly discuss the problem of
simple categorization classification and object recognition
and this
it is likely to domain
and given an image we want recognise the context of the image
for instance for robot navigation
or we want to recognise the also objects inside
the scene
of course
there are works where
we combine these two things because context that have been
when i object for instance here
you and
really understand what is
one of these objects are
since the same object with
the difference of
but if you
take context
the scene
you can
large cliques have to specify you know you know the negation the negative and positive
cases literal
there's actually piece of syntax in alchemy that makes it easier which is asterisk if
you write a clause in alchemy with asterisk instead of negation in front of the
literal what that means is created both versions of the class with the negation and
without the negation
so if for example you put asterisks in front of all the little this creates
all the possible groundings which is what are meant to
of course you don't have to search for large cliques are things will not get
out hand
but again it's very easy to translate and i'm an internally
finally what about bayesian logic
well the logic is i said has a pretty complicated syntax so you know i'm
not going to bore you with the details of that here
but the key thing that vision logic buys you is the ability to talk about
objects that you don't seem so how would you do that in markov logic
well an object
is really a cluster of similar or related observations again think of the example what
is an aircraft
and the graph this is the thing that gave rise to that sequence of dots
on the screen
so what you want to be able to do is you want you want to
have two types of constants
observation constants that represent the blips on the radar
and ordered constance to represent the aircraft
or observation consist the represent the records in the database
an object consists that represent the actual objects that you know like the paper or
the person that those records refer to k
and now
what we need to have these predicates like instance of observation object that says this
observation is an instance of this object
this blue is an instance of this aircraft
OK now we want to have clauses relating the two so causes using this predicate
is something and something then this observation is the distance of this object otherwise is
an instance of an object
now when you write out of model like this in the inference over it it
will infer which observations correspond to which objects and maybe even regularities relating those objects
maybe more often if you know something about the properties of the objects you can
write that down and that will influence i was signed objects observations to objects
in fact you can go even further and you can have relations in addition to
unknown objects by having second order markov logic
what i mean by that
when you're doing information extraction or for example when using schema matching in databases you
actually need to resolve attributes and predicates
for example contacting one database might mean the same thing as telephone in the other
or you know the phrase
and her friend bob and who's friends with bob you know and his friend bob
these are all different but they all represent the simulation so you actually show is
unknown relations i want to be able to cluster those as well
we can do the markov logic very simply by using this approach that we have
here with one addition which is we need to allow
predicates that range over variables that range over predicates
as those variables that range over objects
now conceptually this is not a big extension because what happens is that you just
about the markov logic network by grounding the predicate variables the same way that you
ground the observation variables
and i can write something much more content like for example in the citation matching
the main i don't need to have in one rule for you know authors model
for venues in one of publications for titles for publishers et cetera and if tomorrow
i have more fields
the same and also work
the details of this are in this paper that just came out in ICML two
thousand seven
OK we almost at the end before we conclude let me just mention some practical
ponte piece of and also
he he there's some small probability he can change his mind changes goal any time
and you may not notice that you don't have any outward sign or direct and
that except how having use the space so that these these strong switches and goals
are explained this actually this here is not actually upon p it's more of an
MDP because we assume that the both the observer and age have full knowledge but
if we really wanted do to theory of mind big draw inferences about agent's beliefs
which could be false or could be incomplete because maybe they haven't seen the whole
environment then we that takes us to upon the people and so here's some recent
work i should say that this is all the work of chris baker
we're we're
we're actually doing joint inference about
basically tracking in belief space and also inference about an agent's preferences so the domain
we study this is similar to the ones seen we call it the food truck
domain so you can see over here on the left is a little scenario we
have some grad student on
hypothetical college campus
very small college campus here every day he gets lunch one of the food trucks
there's three food trucks the korean k the lebanese l and the mexican and but
there's only two parking spots on any one day and most two and sometimes only
one of these trucks is present on the campus so you see harold start over
get my cursor so harold starts here and goes like this ten ten ten ten
ten ten ten one here
more slowly goes here
remember he can hear sort of line of sight axis so we can now see
was on the side of the wall and he goes back to k so the
question is
this k over here this l here what's his favorite food truck KL around
interesting because there isn't any were present in the scene you know it can be
there but
there is no direct perceptual evidence there's nothing like is headed towards me just interpret
the fact that he was looking for and then was may be disappointed he didn't
see it so he went to what his next favourite and that's what you can
see here is both people in the models and is the best then k and
l and they also make a kind of corresponding belief inference he must have actually
thought was likely to be there that's what you see here on this part otherwise
he wouldn't have gone to the trouble to go and look
and again across many different scenarios we get a pretty good correlation on both preferences
and beliefs not as good as in the simpler case the so pretty good you
know certainly by the standards of what until recently i mean really until this work
was only treaties qualitative different intuitionist theory of mind
on some some of the other things we've been doing along the same lines is
intuitive physics so you can
here's one more damage to close out it's it's fun and easy just look at
this table here with these red and yellow blocks and say if i bump the
table in one of the blocks falls off is more likely to be red or
yellow since you yell out so we can hear you
red or yellow
yeah OK so pretty much everybody agrees on those little variation how does that work
how did you do that
so our approach is to is to sort of take physics and and and seems
seriously so like a few other people in the community there is a really nice
poster from CMU on this yesterday you know we we think that you can understand
vision is actually inferring three d model it's really inverse graphics and the hypothesis space
and the forward mapping is basically picks and physics is physics so we've been building
these ideal observer models in which we assume people have a probabilistic version of newtonian
mechanics and they can run a little simulations not very accurate but little simulations to
reason about these things and we can test this for example in the simple case
we haven't on the red and yellow but for example we can show people these
towers of blocks and say is stable or not will fall over so these ones
look pretty stable this one
now right fall over this one probably unstable these ones are little more borderline and
three and we can get again very good correlations just with very rapid presentations between
what people how stable people think this is and the predictions of this model that
somehow assume that you're you know approximately inverting the graphics to come up with a
three d block description and running a little
brief noisy physics simulation to figure out what's going to happen
even the same kind of models can even apply in simple cases to infants and
be able to predict infants looking time which is the standard measure what inference no
but until recently has been related in any kind of
problem and kind of quantitative way to any model that learned probabilistic model
so just just to wrap up then all point to what i think is you
know on really on the AI side that technology that's that's going to allow these
little basically first model steps that we're building and others are building to really hopefully
try to capture something about human common sense and take that over and is the
idea of actually building a general tools the so called probabilistic programming languages which give
you a way to express all these models and generic inference tools you often some
kind of approximate inference a lot of them are using monte carlo but not all
of them and they basically probabilistic programming language built on logic like prolog and there
are a number of wanted to build more functional
or imperative programming styles like this for matlab and i want to go through any
of the details here but it's very exciting these technologies are there are certainly not
sure but there are under development and it's it's going to make it possible to
develop and work with these kinds of models and even to frame learning as what
you might call kind of programme induction cognitive development the kind of program synthesis ministers
far stuff i don't want to pretend this is easy or accessible in any really
satisfying rigorous way at this point but i would venture prediction that sooner or later
we're going to have to view learning this way because otherwise we just can't explain
how this kind of knowledge developed i think
and some of the work i showed you like the graph grammars stuff or other
work for doing with the handwritten characters for example brenden lake is doing some work
on actually what i think is one of the right model for handwritten characters is
actually inferring motor program if you look at how people actually draw those those characters
from one example all rather than pretty much the same way that they that they
don't just have a visual concept but it's actually of motor sequence concept
or there's a lot of really cool were going on in NLP modeling the acquisition
of language is basically synthesis of simple kinds programs
OK so i'll wrap up the big problem that we in this field of trying
to understand it's really a joint project with machine learning and AI is how does
the mind or anything like mind get so much from so little across all these
different domains we have the toolkit which builds on the core bayesian statisticians toolkit and
how it's been extended in ML with for example hierarchical nonparametric models but it's also
one has to draw i think on the computer scientist toolkit including but just interesting
data structures but probabilistic programming languages and to a cognitive scientist the value of this
is you know what i've shown here is things like one nice quantitative models but
even more and i think this is also true for free i tools for thinking
thinking little bit differently so instead of getting stuck in his usual debate's that have
racked both cognitive science in a i for decades is the mind should be understood
the line to logical probability in nature versus nurture is learned as wired and we
can really do you don't have to have those debates anymore because we can ask
me much more interesting questions like how can you actually learn real knowledge with some
about but let me spend a little bit more time on learning theory so
because not all of you might be familiar with the concept of uniform convergence so
there were several steps yesterday
politically and the first one was too
translate this issue of consistency into the question of uniform convergence
so i was showing you some
pictures i'm showing you a graph maybe i'll briefly go back to that one
and in this graph can see the test error or the expected risk and the
training error of empirical risk
regular morning test whether people are
of the training error and test error now i was telling you that due to
the law of large numbers
whenever we think one function f we evaluate the training error and test error on
this function
OK so
we have the training error and test error whenever we have a fixed function f
here then due to the law of large numbers the training error which will be
a function of the training examples that we've seen size and therefore in particular function
of the number of training example we've seen this empirical risk will converge towards the
actual risk in probability
the more training examples to see what the closer we are to the actual risk
point wise
this curve converges to the other one
but this does not imply that the minimum of this kind of
function that has the lowest training error will converge towards the minimum of the other
kernel based function of this possible risk that we could achieve
which is the actual goal in our learning
so this is just
like intuitive argument but this is formalised in this case theorem of learning theory
think in germany in case
the prove that it's necessary sufficient for certain types of consistency so consistency you think
of it as a success in the limit of the learning procedure
is necessary sufficient for this to have a certain type of uniform convergence over uniform
over all functions can be implemented by the learning machines so here for the worst
possible function of the machine where the sense that training error and test there are
markedly different
different for the worst possible functions
the probability that the training and test error
dv eight
by more than epsilon so goes to zero
so this is uniform convergence
you will note that normally when you talk about uniform convergence in mathematics you would
have modulus here
and here is where we just have parentheses it's actually a uniform one sided convergence
we don't care about deviations in one direction and in the other direction and this
is basically the case because we're interested in consistency of empirical risk minimization
not of empirical risk maximisation
so we don't care about whether the test are so much smaller than the training
error that's fine with us worried about cases where the test error might be a
lot bigger than the training error in which case the learning machine might look good
on the training set but that in the test set
so then we started looking at this quantity in more detail
so we want to cheque when does this thing go to zero so we have
to analyse the data
if we have only one function
we cannot directly give on this thing using channel found classical amount if we have
more than one function
we were using something called the union bound which gave us almost the same so
so there's the copper lines and brass you see the copper lines and you see
the inclines
so by this technique i could give i could give you an alloy
consisting of three elements
and you can see from where those lines are
what the elements must be that are present in the alloy
and the relative intensity
of the lines must be related to
the relative concentrations of this constituents that are present
this is so important
it's amazing
first let's look at the data
here's data this data from of
now remember this is what we're were expecting
and that's what we got so
there's something else going on here it looks as though
it looks as though what we have
it is
a combination of
looks like we've got a combination of this
so we've got this is this here is are
these are characteristic spectral all right
it's is the characteristic spectra
is imposed upon something else
and this something else is continuous right there's no there's no break in this curve
so this is a continuous spectrum
there is a continuous spectrum
there are various ways of describing the shape is certainly a symmetric but since we're
in new england we call this
quail shape
it's whale shaped
and it's going to very steep it's kind of vertical rise here
i want to know the shape it's not just arbitrarily drawn it steep vertical rise
and the asymptotic
the asymptotic tail
and of course a maximum skewed asymmetrically
so it's not quantized
not quantized
furthermore if you look at this figure carefully you'll see that there is a family
of these
there's a family of these and their in their enveloped in one another
they envelop one another as shown here
so that as the plate voltage increases as the plate voltage increases the height increases
and the
the minimum wavelength decreases so if this is
if this is wavelength increasing from
left to right this means that energy is increasing from right to left which makes
sense as you go to higher plate voltage
you go to
but what's going on here what's what's the physics of the spectra or by the
way in the highest one you see the k alpha k beta designation if you
don't know what they were just took that value of k alpha it looks like
it's around
about three-quarters of an extra
by my
eyeballing it it looks like it's about three-quarters of an extra and if you take
the calculation of most of these laws for lambda of molybdenum
o k alpha
you know that molybdenum z equals forty two for malik z equals forty two plug
that into again zero point seven two angstrom so that seems to be OK so
in other words mostly predicting the
and the people by the way is you know i'm drawing of a straight line
like this but in reality these pics have some finite with
because real materials are not perfect and so there's going to be
some variation in the
in the spacing and the energy
OK so what's going on here
how can we explain this what's the underlying physics here
well let's take a look
here's a body centered cubic
crystal as is molybdenum
so let's say
the plane of the table is the
and the electrons are zooming in from the cathode in the ceiling c electrons are
coming down
coming down or smashing into this and some things going on that causes the emission
of x-rays in all directions
and we've just seen what what's it's OK that's the good news cnn central board
there what those energy should be the discrete energies but let's see what else is
going on
when i zoom in it at the
every surface of the molybdenum
there's body centered cubic and the electrons are coming and also electrons coming in from
the top
and electrons charged negatively and we know that this is not neutral but
there's an electron cloud
start with zero everywhere
well i'd like say you can't you can't pick and choose edges and say i'm
going to go searching for zero
because that would violate the conservation of mass
i don't know you know you you have flow piling up to know if you
so you know if i change this one here i'm going to change a least
one of the one to balance the i change in work and the thing becomes
a problem in its own right but we've done here is avoided creating a new
search problem
and what about if we wanted to change the pairwise potentials so there other problems
not this one actually a lot of revising your you know user interaction with the
segmentation but the problem is that we will see one in a minute
where you want to change the horizontal links
the the the pairwise potentials
what do we do about that well it turns out that kohli and torr came
up with a neat
the solution to that
so supposing the same thing happened i got a link
here for pairwise potential
reusing the existing flow to one is exceeded that that link by delta and what
can i do
well if i just really you unilaterally reduce the flow on that
link by delta
then i'm in trouble because you know it just as we were discussing will pile
or or in deficit these nodes so
what i can do
take the the link back to the source and back to the sink a least
in the restricted problem that we have
and because we are dealing with a particular kind of graph this is not actually
fully general i confess the general version of this which they reported in the paper
but just the purpose of illustration what i can do is
to compensate for having reduced the flow in this direction i take this link to
the source and increase the flow
i exactly the same amount and the same year increase the flow by the same
answer the now the mass balance
at each of these two nodes is still
and now i've got about flow
to start with again i can you know do all this stuff but i do
so you know that's pretty close to what you would what you
and what is this good for well is
of it from the body and soul
paper suppose you want to do segmentation of video
so this is actually and we want to exploit the fact that successive frames of
the video is similar
so this is different from the problem that we were
talking about before
actually now that this count actually moved in between frames a little bit
and so you remember
the the capacities of the horizontal links we're using now
the modified ising model one is modified by contrast the contrast is moving along with
the count at least you know some parts of the contrast the long tail moving
along with the council now the costs on those are zontal links pairwise potential also
move along so there will be some changes in the pairwise potentials
we really do have to deal with that as well as changes in the unit
i'm just going to show you
two things to notice first of all that
you know this whole thing works that you get a segmentation this is the
first frame you'll see the segmentation of the entire movie into
the second
and secondly this diagram here is showing you the
flows at any one instant
so what you see is the flows are changing progressive as well so in other
words the flow for frame and t plus one
is the indeed very similar to the flow frame t really is worth exploiting the
similarity of flows the the efficiency of the
algorithm analysis
the figures area
OK moving along big segmented as it goes
with the
transport count to nirvana or somewhere else and
you can continue background and you see
coherent blows up and you can get really very considerable speed up more than one
order of magnitude speedup in this
from exploiting this regularity
OK what other application what question
the question is do you have to go take the maximum global delta globally under
the modifications using that no no this is all this is on
the edge by edge basis
so you take the current value of
flow the you know the one from the previous problem you mark all the edges
where the capacity is exceeded and then individually each time you say is a violation
of the capacity constraints and i'm going to transform the capacity that edge
and in itself
was uploaded to
neighbours and then you dealt with that one and then you go on to the
next one is it is not very simple
and picks up at that point
OK so another of another problem that uses where one of the things we're doing
in the microsoft lab is developing a new kind of webcam because we believe that
in due course all webcams will be stereoscopic there's absolutely no reason why not because
very little more
now there is to make a stereoscopic camera monocular one
and it turns out there's an awful lot you can do if you have that
but it's going up the teeny-weeny little electrical gradient
gets out there and what does it do the outside
makes more positive so the third potassium
makes it even more perfect positive and is more and more potassium is rush out
the outside becomes more positive
every potassium now
it has to do work
get up the electrical gradient
but of course it's the concentration gradient pushing it out
so they keep going forever
no they're going to balance each other
there will come a point
the concentration gradient the force driving test them out to the concentration gradient is all
by the electrical gradient pushing passing in
we're keeping potassium it
so what happens is
goes out
rushes out goes out leaks out the test in leaks out
which now
sets up
the electrical gradient
and what happens is the cell becomes more positive on the outside more negative on
the inside
an equilibrium potential is reached
equilibrium is reached
so in equilibrium electrical potential
is reached
the concentration gradients
exactly offsets
when it balances
the electrical gradients
any guesses to what that electrical concentration gradient is
minus seventy million books
that's where minus seventy million votes comes from
it comes because that's the
concentration gradient which potassium going up the gradient just offsets the yes
well because but does the electric potential must keep it in
the concentration wanted out the electrical wanted and that's why we have an equilibrium exactly
if those two balancing forces
very good
so our the passing by the way has the russia
the set this up it turns out the trivial amount
it turns out that about
ten to one part in ten to the six
of all the potassium ions
sets up the gradient
of about
mind about five million volts
minus five novels
one part in ten million of potassium ions will suffice to set up a concentration
gradient minus five novels
so i've got to do is set up about
less than well maybe about one part in ten to the fifth of all the
potassium ions leaving a tiny contribution of the of the concentration change in the concentration
by one part in ten to the fifth will get me minus fifteen ready
so it's very interesting is huge amounts of iron set up very big electrical gradients
and have no real effect on the concentration
but they have a big effect on the electrical gradients so when i say potassium
leaks out it only takes heed of potassium to leak out
in order to accomplish this
OK guys now
let's get ready to make an action potential
so here goes
the action potential but
we set up our
resting potential by transporters by this open channel
the first thing we have
a new kinds of
membrane channels we have a
voltage gated sodium channel
check this out
this guy here is the channel
that's close
it's close
so minus seventy million volts
it's closed
if i can transient we depolarized the cell to minus fifty million volts
it opens
and it admits
so t
so when i get minus fifty
it opens
now what will sodium doing that door opens
let's see
o electrically what would sodium what would
sodium do
so what we have a concentration from the point of view concentration with so what
they just trying to
forget layer
the electric what sodium like to do
would like to comment wouldn't because negative inside positive
but for a concentration gradient what would like to do
coming also
so what's happening
we've got that i am that i would like to come in electrically and would
like to come in from the point of view concentration so what happens
it comes in
and it comes rushing
now what happens
as it comes rushing in
what what do to our electrical potential from minus seventy
we got to translate up to minus fifty
and as it comes in what is electrical gradients
brings in positive charge
the electrical gradient goes towards zero
does it stop it zero
no because
even if the cell becomes positive opinions in the interior
sodium still wants to keep coming in because of its concentration gradient
now has to do some work against electrical gradient set up
but it keeps going and going and going is gone forever
no because eventually reaches the point where the electrical gradient positive now now inside the
cell offset the concentration gradient and it'll stop
and a region new equilibrium potential
which turns out to be about plus fifty
amazing opens the door so to control rushing in dallas castration natural gradient shifts the
electoral gradient from being negative to positive and eventually it slows itself down because it's
summarized in these books
there are quantities that you need to calculate things like interplay space things
tables are available there so this is a handy thing primarily for fraction
volume three
it's called physical tables
and this is where you find things like absorption coefficients for x reason for neutrons
it's where you find the latest values
absorption coefficient neutron scattering banks since these things are derived experimentally the values improvement change
from time to time so this is where you find the most up-to-date values of
physical constants and items that are necessary for diffraction
it never ceases to amaze me and how somebody who
has the good fortune of having to use diffraction for thesis will
labour carefully over making the measurements and reducing the data and then when it comes
to using
a wavelength which is
how the final numbers will be determined goes to an appendix of a book on
the fraction that was published twenty years ago
and that's not the most up-to-date value scattering powers of x-rays by the electrons in
the atom or
calculated from wavefunctions which constantly get better from year to year and the value of
the scattering powers as the function of angle it's better from year to year so
this is where you want to do if you need any of physical data and
finally volume four
it's not it's title but it's essentially an update of the physical
tables giving later values which came out of that ten years later
OK had this
the series was getting out of hand so
the bend my knees to use two hands when picked up this one this is
a continuation of the series essentially but this one is called international tables for crystallography
period no x-rays because neutrons and electrons are just as important today for doing scattering
and so the international tables
four crystallographic
no x-ray mirror
and there are now something like six volumes out
they're not called one two three and four but they're called b
and c to avoid confusion in volume a is
one called space group symmetry
and then there are a whole series of other ones as i said i think
there are six of them that the physical data and all sorts of useful guides
i had next feelings about the new series
you will see that
it is about
three times as large
and three times as heavy
which means it's nine times as expensive
to me it's almost the case for most people
of the situation where if it wasn't broke you should fix
and what they found is that they put in all sorts of esoteric
which probably is going to be an interesting use two
perhaps five percent of the readers but nevertheless if you wanted to find there which
is something that could not be said before they've added a few things which are
useful but a lot of
additional information which you don't really need and you pay for that whether you want
it or not
nevertheless it's been done you can buy the old volumes any longer have to abide
by its
so anyway this is what you find in library now maybe they do they do
still have the old volumes one through four
we will make reference to in the course of the term i will give you
copies of certain pages and here's handouts when we need them for purposes of illustration
or for use
i spent the last five minutes just to make you aware of the existence of
these books and these are really the penultimate source of information and numerical
quantities that will be
used in diffraction one of the principal applications of crystallography
i think i have just enough by i to start things off have the
syllabus for the course
he is in very dense for exactly what we will be covering this term
and i would like to read you by the hand through this
what we will be doing
in the first half of the term is something that is
known as crystallography
OK the meaning of the word is almost self-explanatory the first part is crystal
we're going to be dealing with the crystalline state of matter
to me
amorphous materials so they may although may be important to have all the interest of
a piece of state before it's been cooked
the atoms in amorphous materials or find that they really get interesting when they organise
themselves into an orderly fashion
so the name is self-explanatory the first part crystals
it means we're going to deal with the crystal and state
what does the graphene mean
that means mapping or geometry
and let me give you an example of a few other words that have the
same sort of structure geo
the earth
followed by
the graph the geography
is that the mapping of the earth and there are many other terms that involve
is two separate parts
crystallography though it is
very often subdivided into
different flavours
there's something well defined called x-ray crystallography
this is the experimental determination of
the crystallography of material using diffraction
usually x-rays because they are relatively inexpensive and widely available but increasingly neutron scattering or
the probability that every pixel in the image is completely independent of all other words
another way if i give you one hundred by one hundred so part of the
image and ask you to predict the central pixel
that would be
easier than predicting random clubbing scene and he
clearly falls but it's a very strong assumptions so the independence assumptions to show what
we want to do is we want to have some intermediate family of functions between
this assumption
which is like the most
so you can make
and this assumption which is the most general
or you could in is clearly intractable
when try and tell you about the rest of today
is a family of assumptions you can make
we see
we interpolate some sense between this which is crazy
and this was also
so this is great because it's too general and if you don't make any assumptions
can learn anything and everything to have enough data
how our to deal with making
and this is crazy because it's such a ridiculous region aggressive assumption that it's like
four years
how can we proceed with basically over
so what mean
so what we do instead of making complete factorizations marginal independence assumptions are going to
conditional independence assumption
notation i'm right
x is conditionally independent of b is
the he given axes
very occasionally go back to where the probability of traditional
competition the definitions she says
variables x inexperience conditionally independent given a third xc the joint distribution between a and
b given c
so this is informally
once you know c
it doesn't really tell you anything more about b or b doesn't really tell you
anything more a then you already knew from c
it doesn't say a and b are unrelated
it just once i tell you see
there's no more information they can tell between themselves
beyond here
and think it's going to
thing is that the conditional distribution of a given both b and c is exactly
the the same your beliefs about a question
both b and c
it's exactly the same as you believe that this should be c
so only a subset very small subset of all distributions in the world respect respects
some conditional independence assumptions like this
when you make conditional independence assumption you're basically throwing away a huge set of joint
distributions which no longer are appropriate because know that some and that's going to remember
like all of the public distribution
the world chart way to get rid that can work with that
so this is set of distributions respect all of the conditional
assumptions we make is going to be the family of distributions is
office is that of course can be
and probabilistic graphical models are a powerful and simple way to specify
so what is the probability graph was model is a way
representing large joint distributions compactly using a set of local relationships as a graph
the policy
all is nothing more than a match for language
which is the fast way for me to tell you know alex smola or john
or any one of you this is a particular family of distributions which to consider
so there's no way of writing the picture i show you this picture you instantly
know what a family of joint distributions
OK so it's convenient macro language for talking to each other conditional independence assumptions are
only about subset of distributions are going to consider the conditional independence assumptions to
and the way you do this
her language is that each random variable model is a node in the graph so
there is no x one corresponds to the random variable x one might be pixel
one that the directed or undirected although in this section on the talk
directed there are direct edges between the nodes which tell us something about the factorisation
of the joint probability and although you can see it on this picture you open
this up here
inside there is a quantitative function know which tells us the details of the pieces
which the distribution factor
OK so graphical models like you know
this famous criminal goes under many names for that
also known as bayesian networks
bayesian belief networks belief networks
you know
it is permutation this so you people like belief nets business or bayesian belief networks
are all the same thing problems that just this matter language for that conditional sentences
so we're going to focus on directed graphical models and here is the
we ask actually
what should we do the time
should i just go on our way to the nearest or or should
OK so we're going to consider directed graphical models and focus on this subset of
graphs which are directed acyclic graphs so there's no directed cycles
OK each node in such a graph has a possibly empty but has said parents
which are of high
and each node stores inside of functions
and that she is the conditional
the distribution probability x given its parents
so really the factorisation of the joint distribution here is in terms of local conditional
probability for example and when i write this picture
what i really telling you is
that gives a rare glimpse into
the lines of the ninety nine percent
this video that i'm going to show
it is distressing to witness and i want to remind you that my goal here
today is not distress u but to raise awareness
and to do that i have to make invisible
i spend a lot of time selecting material that i felt was sufficient to inform without actually traumatizing
and i also wanted just remind you to
the focus of this presentation is ultimately solution right we explored the problem only in
so far as they can help us explore ways to transform and transcend the problem
i want to encourage you
to push a comfort zone and bear witness to this form in video clip because
i do believe that the few second discomfort will be well worth the empowerment
but awareness ultimately brings in this feedback that i consistently get from people who attended my
but i also want to encourage you to win yourself hand if it's too much
for you to close your eyes and play areas for a few minutes and i'll
try to keep the sound blowing to
block get out
and that show you an undercover footage and animal factories
you the new
you can
so you
only four minutes and it feels like a lot longer
i know good
good job i know how hard is to
witness i know
i've seen this
and videos like this so many times and never get
never get anything for me either
i wanted just remind you that much of what you've seen here are
standard industry practices that apply to so called organic
and free range facilities
as well
whenever people
but it's like this they always ask me
melanie how is this
how is this legal
and i replied that not only is the legal there's an entire industrial complex organised around this kind of violence
in water
animal agribusiness is a hundred and twenty five billion dollars per year industry in the
united states alone multiply billion dollar industry around the world they are
countless companies like this one
selling emasculate has castrated as though it were a nail clipper r
but if you wanted to buy your own you could even
find one on
we that are not
which is where i bought mine
now before you make assumptions about what kind
so i am
what kind of woman i am
because i have a castrated my person
i arm
i know it's not good for my love life
i travel on the second year speaking national speaking tour in the united states speak
presenting my slides showing card and so i want playing a lot
and i can bring anything sharp
and i can't bring anything too big so i had to get castor
so what i wanted to bring to my talk but i'm afraid i'm going to keep
forget my first one day and
be on a day or something not good
but i'm happy to show you later if you want this is
this is what it looks like
we animals staying ideally four-hour carnism
but as i mentioned animals and not only in the victims
system another group of invisible victims are the meat packers at slaughterhouse workers
who have to work in a highly dangerous death saturated environment and not surprisingly have high rates of post-traumatic stress
in addictions i'm initially refused to just three titles
occupational safety and hazard accident reports from the united states to just give you a
sense what people have to contend with
can you say in the
two small rivers
employee hospitalized before neck lacerations from flying
employees i injured when struck by hanging hook
employed decapitated by chain of hide color machine
in fact in two thousand five for the first time however human rights watch issued
a report criticizing single u industry
the meat industry
for working conditions so calling it violates basic human rights
and d are environment is an invisible victim criticism according to the united nations animal
culture is one of the most significant contributors are some of the most serious
environmental problems facing the world today
and finally
are the invisible victims carnism
we paper are concerned with the help
eating animal food has been linked with the weeding diseases in the western world today
this is why the academy of nutrition and dietetics used to be called the american dietetic association
issued a statement saying that not only are pure begin diet nutrition only adequate but
they are actually beneficial in the prevention and treatment of disease
we also paper currency with taxes billions of dollars per year millions i believe here
in the united states and billions of dollars fearing need subsidies
subsidies that have been criticized across the political spectrum is one of the most egregious corporate welfare programs
in the history of the world
in terms of course
we pay
four hour carnism
with our hearts
and with our minds
because they need the body of another essentially being we have to block are awareness
and shut down are empathy
empathy and awareness are integral to our senses itself
we paper currency with the gap
in our consciousness
so we talked a lot about denial expressed through invisibility is the primary sense
the primary defensive carnism but
i think about it is invisibility alone really enough to maintain the system
do you think invisibility alone can maintain the entire system
now of course not
hints about the truth surround seeing being in the drumstick
be pig on a spit at the company barbecue
you can guess the dinner parties and an endless array of dead animals everywhere return
in the form of meat
so when invisibility inevitably falters the system needs a backup
we need to be able to justify
eating animals
the way that we learn to justify eating animals is by learning to believe that the methodsof meat
more complex prediction tasks so
one of the ones is receiving a lot of attention
his group detection
you want to figure out
nodes in a graph cluster
so who is in the same research group
who is in the same social circles so a lot of the work and social
network analysis and group detection and here
there's approaches that are based simply on
along to just clustering and then there's the question of
do you
this in the there non overlapping groups are dual to allow overlapping groups
and then there's the ones that are based only on the structure
you say OK if the clique
in this social network then it's group or if it's almost clique then all the
nodes that are in there together
are in the same group but it's interesting to be able to kind of combined
together both
attribute similarity and structural similarity in order to find groups
and you can kind of
one way of viewing the group detection is that there's a a hidden variable
that you're trying to
entity resolution is closely related task
this is something that actually recently i've done a lot of work on
entity resolution
the solution is the problem i have a bunch of
i have a bunch of references to people in my database have john smith j
smith jonathan smith and so on and i'm trying to figure out well
those references which one's really
are referring to the same underlying individual verses which ones are distinct
this is
he studied under
a lot of different names to record linkage identity uncertainty
object uncertainty and so on
and it's very important problem
studied also in the database community under deduplication
and the interesting thing that you can do with as all techniques is you can
make use of not just attribute information so the similarity of name and so on
but make use of
the relational similarity
so the most obvious one to make use of is
the current for example and say OK with j smith john smith are more likely
to be the same person if they published with
you know
some jones and each jones and so on and
again you get into the same kind of thing that happened with the collective classification
you get this dependence as i figure out that
john smith j smith
refer to the same individual that gives me additional information that helps me figure out
terry jones and h jones are the same and i can do all that if
i have the appropriate framework for keeping track and doing this kind of reasoning
another really important kind of prediction task is kind of getting up to a little
bit more meta level where we need to do predicate invention so coming up with
a new useful
link or feature two years
from existing had
proposed the concept of adviser
from the fact that i have these relationships co-author
and financial support
then it's very easy
and this tells you how to do so we can easily compute the joint pairwise
distribution for any pair of connected nodes exciting x and to do that if you
just put your finger on the the trigger i j
you take the product of the messages coming into
the messages coming into j
and you multiply those two products about the potential between these nodes and renormalizable
business OK so
this is just what over here on the slide you take the product the messages
coming into each of the nodes i except the message from j of course the
messages coming into j
except the message from my i
and the potential that exist between so that might be if if the graphical model
has a relationship you x i given next year xj given x i or if
it's an undirected model to some potential on this two you multiply all these things
together in the normalized that and that's the poster
so the joint pairwise posteriors over the maximal cliques these these pairwise things cover all
the maximal cliques in the tree
and so by definition these are all we need to do
richey asked what if you query involves more than one and given the sort of
have an answer i said well if you could involve more than one node in
the adjacent it's easy
in a sort of try to motivated by saying and if you're doing is learning
these are the only ones you'll ever need you never need
the joint posterior between this guy and this guy
to do mundo
because there's no part in the parameters which care about this guy in the kind
the parameters only care about the cliques however there applications in which you want the
joint probability of this kind this guy given the evidence and you can get the
pairwise marginals or higher order marginals from these things but
they doing some legitimate extra work it's not just reading the article did from BP
you need to do some extra work and and like in particular need to call
some asian you have to do some extra work
but that's a very good question
OK the
the last thing i wanted to point out here before returning to the HMM example
is that this equation
which i wrote up here
it is equal
in the case of maximisation
something you want to know is
elimination belief propagation both summed over all possible values
of the other nodes that we were interested in what we want to maximize
over all of the
non query non evidence nodes to find the probability of the
the best settings of the nodes that are consistent with the current evidence so this
often comes up in like planning constraint satisfaction where you have this probabilistic notion that
you're trying to some of the things and get marginals
find a single configuration about the
the marginal of all the nodes in the model that are consistent with some side
constraints some observations and maximize some utility objective function and so this is not in
the probability thing as the maximum a posterior e or MAP configuration and internet on
trees we can use an algorithm that's exactly identical
two belief propagation to solve this to solve this problem right
and has to do with this
so we have this equation here which is this
semantics of a b
and as i've written up there
that's just eight times the max
a b and c
so again it looks like it requires two multiplications to compute this maximization but in
fact you can just pull this out and see work so that has to do
with the fact that
yeah sorry
i should change that and i think you
so they has to do with the fact that he has product
former field
in here
max and some form of feel they have the same distribution properties in fact you
can any pair of operations that you generically one to call
you know plus and on the other hand the distributive property you can be efficiently
solved for you
so the these things i guess are formally called semi commutative semirings and it just
has to do with this property are the max sum pairs also a semiring so
the algorithms are not in the in the engineering literature by various names but the
most famous is viterbi decoding
so in the future be created this algorithm which in the case of chain graphs
spines the single best configuration before the general with the non it's very similar to
dynamic programming and he used it for decoding
CDMA correcting codes and then formed a company called com
so you have to have some hope that if you have a good algorithm guided
computer science you could become unimaginably rich as a cell phone
the main gate OK
so this is another detail about this max product algorithm it's exactly the same you
pass messages from the from the lead back up to the trees but now the
messages that you pass involved this this maximisation and this true in the max product
are disjoint
so a particular variable will only appear in one of these factors
again sort of a thirty minute maybe an hour
exercise to generalize to the case where i have intersecting sets so that some variables
can appear in different factors it's more complex cases original model but will will admit
that case for the purposes of the tutorial
OK so what we're going to do now
it is we're going to use calculus of variations again
two more
all possible factorized distributions
and in fact the way we're going to do it if your heads up is
that we're going to
consider one of these factors leave all the others fixed and just take one of
them and will maximize the lower bound with respect to particular facts let's say qj
keeping all the others fixed all attain analytical solution for qj
given the other guys
so we'll end up with a set of coupled equations which will then iterate the
thing we actually code dot is the iteration of the carbon equation
derive them
so the lower bound is the integral
he said
he said data
the qz
he z
and we going assume that qz
is the products
however some factors
if you are right
which depends only on a subset of variables that i
so the first will into here
control products online
q i
log p
p seventy
lord q
which is the sum on i
long queue line
he z
just substitute this in here
three witnesses like
now we're going to do is we're going to focus on one of those factors
let's say factor q j
a particular index j
so i'm going to do is i'm going to rewrite it slightly system a huge
a explicit
so this is what the factor q j
and i've got the products
i not equal to j
u i
i haven't rule here
alright like this dz are not equal to j simple of always itself to j
then i have to use it
j put square brackets around
so that this
this term here
if the entropy of q and the entropy of a product is the sum of
the entropy is if you're not familiar with that then we can
we can see that from here
consider one of the terms in this sum
in the product here
consider the term long qj
all the q distribution
other than qj
well i integrate over all of their z variables just give me one
so it's something like this imagine it's intergral
q one of z one is a simple example q two z two
times log
q two z two
he z one dz two
and i could
because this doesn't depend upon z one i can do the integral over z one
when i left with is in the integral
q two
lord q two
he z two
just the entropy of z two
after a minus sign
so in in this in this expression here
however some of my and all the other terms disappear
in other words this is just
to admire facts and logic and argument
to analyse and criticize and judge
almost from the opposition
what we should do is to create value
and to look
four worked
you know this is our way of thinking i right you are wrong i think
this is good think this is bad
and this much more productive is to explore the thing first
i like it
and you dont but still
you will explore what's good about it
i like it you don't but still i will explore what's bad about it
it will broaden my horizons
i will not
use my time
four conflicts
and then
if we are all focused on doing one
i think the time
we don't hide things to friends you know what arguments when you have no other
sarah thinking
he always as much as formation
as it is good for your case because the arguments you are making a case
and your friends are making the case against you
in such a way when they're all doing what i think at the time we
all share the information
or for example we all
when we all generate ideas we just generated the US
as simple as that
we all explore the thing from one angle the same and of course
it's much more productive
and now we are getting to six
in the last five minutes eight minutes
you will flow slowly ix
i understand why had
because there is an english expression called the thinking that what you're thinking hat on
you know like let's do something about it
so the body didn't this is not his expression he used expression
i just realized that this can be tools and this tool
is let's think about information let's think about feelings let's think about everything that positive
about it
let's think about everything that's negative about it
let's think of ideas let's do one thing at a time
i can't juggle six vols
but an excellent in jordan in one
that's how it is we all as the group do one thing at the same
it is the thinking tool
it's not about categories it's not
it has nothing to do with character sort of horoscopes we can all do
all this
i will skip this
so we can all
so imagine you have a meeting
this is
ideal group is the group six to eight people
somebody is the moderator of it
the facilitator
this someone is having the blue hat on
rule as the sky
as the control above us all the time
and this little hat
was very careful about
what kind of what is the focus what exactly are we going to think about
so that we all understand it
so all our minds go
think about one focus
and the blue
that is telling us how much time we are going to spend on it
people need to know
what's going what will happen with their
even if this short time future
they are much more comfortable if they know how the meeting is going to look
and the third thing
the blue had is giving cars is the discipline
one of the techniques
if people know that
at this meeting now we are going to share all the information and then we
are going to
generate ds and then we are going to see what's positive about it and then
we are going to see what's negative about it
you know can easily focus on ideas
because the amount of the judgement will come as well so they do what i
think it's time know
they they can structure
it's much easier
much better than unless you come to the meeting and you don't know what i'm
want to talk about how long it's going to take what i was going to
you're just
and you know that when it comes to the bubbling actually
blue had is in charge of this at the beginning and the end asking for
conclusions and for the next step
if this is the meeting
we have to agree very strongly about very concrete next steps who is going to
now this political
something has to be done
but you would call these one you will go there you from there
like this
in the meantime look at is the control had facilitated the meeting
it just paying attention to it
we don't know go out of focus which happens at meetings very after all we
don't spend too much time which is my danger right now
when we share information we say the reporter
what is the white piece of paper
when you read the black-and-white something
that's what you write facts what exactly do you know all all the facts all
the information that this knowledge
what do you know
what you don't know
and very can get the missing information
this is very important to know what you don't know and it's good to know
also one thing happens in
bruhat it's called the o pv
other people feel
very important to know how other people who are important for this thing
feeling about it or thinking about it
when we talk about your feelings there's the red hat
but when you talk about the feeling
of somebody who is important for the project that's an information for you
that you need to put into context as well
red hat it's red as valentine's
you know
read as love this is when we all share how we feel about it very
thank you alex on
i first one to summarize why you didn't need to come to that for the last fifteen years
it turned out that the reason backprop didn't win everything back in the nineteen eighties
is because computers were fast enough and datasets were big enough
and what's happened since then
is computers got faster datasets got bigger the labelled once especially in speech
ant we find a better way to initialize the weights but that's a sort a rather minor thing
so the question now is is anything these big deep can't do
because they're winning acoustic models for speech there winning four
object recognition there winning for predicting activity molecules
one thing it seems hard to do with the big neural net
is to average many models
and that's because each takes a long time to train even if you google
at test time in particular we don't want to have to run lots and large nets
now we want to average models
because everyone who wins the competition does it by averaging models
from which you can refer to any competition average models probably
the model so seem to best oppressive averaging
are decision trees
so random forest do very well lots of things
and that's because decision trees are very fast training and also very fast at test time
so you can afford to average loss decision trees called random forests and to make
a different decision trees do different things by giving them different training data
i guess you'll know about
now there's two ways to average models
if you have a model and model and they predict class probabilities
i could take a mixture of them
and i can say the class probabilities i got by just averaging individual person equally weighted mixture
all i could take a product what the model say
so i just multiply the probabilities together
take the square root if i'm taking geometric mean
and then i get some numbers don't add up to one side divide by the sum these numbers
so this is the geometric mean
and this is an arithmetic mean
and you can do either lighter than work pretty well
i'm gonna do
geometric means
because at drops out the math that i'm gonna talk about
so here's how you can use lots of different nor neural nets
and average what they say
and not pay a price at test time
let's start with a net with one hidden layer
what we do when we training it is when we present a training case
we randomly omit
each hidden unit with a probability of no point five
we got no point five by solving the equation
x equals one minus x
if you do that's
each time you given input
and then what happens is you're using a different architecture i've evacuation units is to
to the edge different architectures so that's a lot of models
thus many more models anybody else to model averaging uses
each model moreover only overseas one training case because one stage is large and never
going repeat the same pattern here
and if you go through the data many times it's important each time we see
the same training is again to use a different pattern drop
the reason you can fit only seeing one training case model
is that we tied weights together
so a given hidden units when is used always has the same weights to be important in which the output
so that's a very good regularizer because what you're saying is instead putting the weights toward zero
like a one rule to
you're pulling the weights towards what other models want them to be
and that's presumably something but this here
so we can think of this as a way to model averaging have to to the age models
with all this sharing
managed to fit these models even though most models are actually never used it all
in training
what we'd like to do now is a test time
the obvious thing to do is do this random drop out and do many many different times and average
and i maybe what the brain does but it takes time to do
so a nice property this
it's important is especially when you work on real world problem problems of large scale
you not only think about how accurate you can be but also how much time
it takes to be accurate and there is a tradeoff that you can also formalized
this is
well you can probably just read the slide one i will put them online there's
nothing really
maybe just
jump to the conclusion then opened decision for
that's just from discussion about prior to let's go to the messages
OK so now i will just you know
restate all the messages that would really want you to keep in mind for the
rest of your phd flash carrier
and of course here
i more than welcome to criticize or comment or react on this thing and i
mean i already
i mentioned that in the previous lecture but i just wonder if they then
the most important thing we're trying to the induction here not reduction the we can't
justify induction
which means the only thing we can do is your prior is use priors they
are needed but we can't justify but this is really really important
the only thing where you we can get some control like you know i was
going three bomb
true versus empirical
and to answer classifier versus the best classifier and the last one was
error classifier with respect to the best in that
the last one is what i call maximum regret where you compare your performance some
reference that
and that's the only
thing that you can control in the completely
assumption three or distribution free
i think
and you will see that again in the inequality lecture
the shape of the bound that you that you should have in mind one of
our screwed-up and that's being
if you have a finite class you can just use the size as i mean
the logarithm of the size of the public sector
then if you use
bernstein what then it might be refined bounds for the
the binomial tail you can make the variance and the bound
and have you know the empirical error with this streak of inverting the bound
and enter here
these are
o three
kind of
i think that you should always
having been lying somewhere
and the last thing is you know how does the geometric structure plays include bound
by in replacing these firm size by
a bit more complicated but
that captures how well i mean how close the functions are in the space
the one thing i should mention is
and i should write that typically
if you are
in dimension d if you xis are in
you know
subset of rd
like in the ball rt
the x is contained in
maybe even like
argue size one whatever the matter
then the kind of bermuda things square of
over and
the complexity
i display classifiers or
a large class of
different classifiers that work in this space
typical behavior is of the form
if you
i mean for those of you who noted that everything is dimension
i'm sorry i did not mention the in the lecture but that would be potential
because i think it's not easy to relate this i mean it's a very very
combinatorial notion but it's not easy to really these two
the metric structure of the place and i think it's more important to understand that
what matters is how the functions are related to understand the special case in a
way which
you now we restricted to
classification of mammals
but OK so for those of you who have heard about this
the whole by that would have been with the VC dimension also is one where
do you is defeated images we have a class
a function which as we see them into the
little things like that
and just to note
your right
so we that been a lot of discussion about the financial crisis i will continue
on this point
trying to offer
data and some insight that we have gathered over the years
without group here
and i would say this is
shooting at
fundamental bias of mine which is to look at big things
like a big earthquakes big catastrophes
big crashes and so on because they believe as announcing the feeling that to the
the young younger fraction of the audience
by looking at the big things that's one systems
reveal themselves much more
then one they are most stable
because big forces are basically balance
one the events occur
they may reveal some very interesting black swans or dragons but that's another story
the center stage
first i should stress that when you look at the mystery of economics
and i'm here borrowing from a very very important in very interesting story by iranian
art and the world of
who looked at almost two hundred years of financial
and economic crisis in the whole world
what happened in these different countries different time different epochs
we found that the present crisis is not really special in many ways
when you look i mean
i have to go very fast or this very rich data but when you look
at them
of countries which is here sixty percent fifty percent twenty percent which has some kind
of problem
thank you for a restructuring of that
finally if something like anywhere between twenty to fifty percent at the time of the
last two hundred years
being in crisis is a kind of common phenomenon and when you don't have time
to show the data of but when you look at which time countries were involved
not just thinking of latin america
i was speaking of
not in europe one of the you know solid economic and social speaking of of
course us many times in the nineteenth century
and even twenty century
just being europe speaking is you is you are fantastic full of example of crisis
and they are even broader
cycle i would say we could we could say that in the modern era the
two last centuries we are in the
so the big
and we have tipped this cycle and that we are
going down the slope this is the cycle of globalization and financial
gross you see here data flowing
basically a measure of the share of the percentage of countries in some banking crisis
the from of time to get from nineteen eighteenth century to the present time
connected with some measure
macroeconomic measure of globalization in terms of captains capital mobility
some time when i teach this to my students they are amazed
i realize that actually the lover of globalization
will is by many measures larger
at the end of the nineteenth century to the twentieth century that is now
you it is very important to think these brought a picture that not so it's
not so
many new things are occurring now compared with what was happening in the past and
very interestingly
the share of crisis were
it was also correlated with the kind of globalization leakage networks france
as we use today
to describe this kind of
jumping ahead immediately at the level of the present crisis just two
i have a few evidence of the severity
of course when you look at the data set
this is an economist who are very interested in looking at the past and we
hear look at fifty years of data car
many such time series they just took some which are really dramatic in
showing the amplitude of the present
earthquakes are conspicuously the number of reserves of depository institutions in the US
fifty years or data on
for this case enormous down hundreds of billions of dollars
just simply to capture what is going on now
so you don't see much situation there are lots of an interesting situation you look
at the distribution and so on but the point is that you completely would miss
that would complement the prediction of the possibility of search
huge enormous change of regime right so this is an example of what what is
and in now likely to drag and nowadays is that they do not only the
young any statistical fluctuation that if you
similarly for other measures like
tax received for example the dismal state of that that that's we see for example
in california in the US of
in terms just to motivate
the question going to ask which is how to understand the crisis which
you can take as a kind of photo was maybe most more features small cartoons
and talk of inredis morning basically on the same pace
to put the
perspective and ask what
this slide
summarize some estimation of what will be intimately the cost of the present crisis
so here i contrast to estimations but they are a bit heavy but the number
that is interesting here is ten
ten trillion so we have to learn to speak about this big numbers trillions of
two a billion and a thousand billions of dollars that this is this is this
is to measure the total cost of the crisis according to the IMF
OK president estimation
if we look at the estimation by the same guy
i was referring to these study strictly
they look at this cross-section of all the prizes in the last two hundred years
and they look at the best case scenario
i think that what sometimes some
OK to go and the worst case scenario and in the middle of the average
you can play all this quantile what could be the the spread of
severity if you just look at the statistics
we find that the in the best case
the cost would be about forty percent of of GDP
which is significantly worse than the IMF estimate which is this ten trillion is about
twenty seven
the question is what can we do nearly as well as the best of these
in hindsight
OK so if one of them so none of them really good
we don't have to do very well but if one of them ends up actually
being quite good then we want to do nearly as well as it
OK and so just emphasise an expert here
doesn't mean someone who knows anything just means some with an opinion
OK it's just
that's why i like financial
some of the opinion and we don't know in advance of any of them really
good one of them turns out to be good we wanna do nearly as well
OK so that's the problem we can look at
i guess what i can easier version of this first just to get their feet
wet so
here's a simple question
we even experts
suppose we are told one of them is
never make mistakes
we just don't know which one
and we think of the strategy would make up
log and stakes
OK got an expert every day making predictions
and then you get to see their predictions make your own
and your promise that one of them is perfect you don't know which
might think of a strategy for combining their opinion
exactly just take majority vote
then throw away the ones made mistakes
and that guarantees that every time you made a mistake
there you least the you cut down the set of available expert by lisa factor
if you're lucky you may even cut down the set we want making it but
for sure every time you make a mistake means at least half of the experts
there were left predicted incorrectly assumed to cut down by these factors
now they can be anything at all so so you've got you've got your expert
in making predictions and you just taking majority vote two hundred experts fifty seven say
up forty three say down to say if you're wrong means the majority experts were
because you went with the majority and then you in every step you throughout out
the ones that
the made mistakes
promised one of them is perfect so we can throw out make
state that guarantees every time
we get it wrong at least half of the ones left so so very mistake
which optimally factor two
we make making most log base two of n
yes over the simpler version was for the simpler version of assume one of them
this is the simpler version before we get to the real
that's so
so we can do that
if i can be just to make the site
we're not going to be going in the structure but making side if we had
a prior
which we thought was more likely to be the good ones we can take a
majority vote we can wait them by the prior
and then everybody can make mistakes at least half the probability mass goes away
and if the best expert expert i
with probability say some p i p i support prior expert i
for chopping at least half probability mass to make the most log one over
p i think
this logan's kind of like
if your prior is uniform
when you log one and here
we're not going
so we going away
OK so
sure we can solve this way we take majority vote of the experts have been
correct so far each x mistake at number available by factor two
which is great because i mean it's OK for and to be very large making
so this is called having to get
all right so let's now the the the the more general question one if none
of them
can we still do nearly as well as the best of them in hindsight
well here's the strategy one strategy we could just repeat that out so do the
same thing as before the ones we've crossed of everybody we say
we crossed everyone that too bad everyone made mistakes restart from the beginning
we could do that if we did that then
if the best expert makes up optimistic the optimal expert then we make logan mistakes
for every time it makes one
and then we restart making a log in the second time makes one is make
logan times more in the paper
that's something we could
it's a great thing to do
this is kind of wasteful out it's constantly forgetting what is learned and restarting from
that's going over that
and you can
so we need to do
well it's is it's not doing that great because it just makes a mistake one
time and we make logan states when we crossed everybody
then we restart from scratch and it makes one more mistakes we make another logan
mistakes we cross everybody
so we're making times more mistakes and that's why this is not a great
it is a fact
i am more kind of every time we just restart from scratch we forgot we
were in the last time does not the
best thing to do
here's better thing to do very natural strategy
the point here is that you know when you make a mistake it doesn't completely
eliminate you from possibilities because we even the best ones to make mistakes so so
crossing it off well just cut its weight down
some particular cases the following so we'll start with all the experts having a weight
of one
and then we'll project based on the weighted majority vote plain
beginning to play majority vote in that will penalize mistakes not by eliminating them but
just by cutting the weights now
seems like a reasonable thing to do
so we got weight
so the weights one may be the first time step three of them critically as
one predicts now
we take majority vote but if yes is the correct answer these guys say the
same way one this guy's wages cut in half
now the predictions are yes no no yes is the way to one one half
on as we go up now
if the right answer is yes then we penalize these two in there with cut
so we just
make mistakes is cut the weights
so this turns out to actually give a pretty nice
and go through the so i so he
so i'm i'm
here the theoretician come here appears science and so
no i do like algorithms that actually works great and i even like i like
nice theorems i really like per
that's a really
sites so this is a very nice person
so we're going to show that this algorithm actually does nearly as well as the
best expert in hindsight
and then we'll improve make it even that
so they analyse this to now
the bad
look at three things
we're going to look at capital in which is number of mistakes we are algorithm
made so far
we're going to look at little and the number of mistakes the best expert has
made so far are look at one more thing which is the total weight the
system the total weight the system we start everybody with weight one
so the total weight is an experts the total weight is kappa is an