those topics from boy and two which is the
focused lot in there plans to bananas italian also by with which is a bit
more related to analysis so those are all good books
now to get more into this topic
so for let's start the simple things first when you have an end to rise
so you have the same the same term ever on the table now
the square the square of the internet on this is the square of the norm
so now this is a differentiable problem if l is differentiable with respect to the
second viable
you can compute the gradient surfaces with the gradient descent for the loss close to
gradient for the for the regularizer and of course to be optimal just said the
gradient equal to zero
in the case of the square loss so we can parameterized it is a loss
well why just vector always all values of y are subject of an in depth
x is the design matrix which is times be where all
of the observations are stacked rule by
so this loss function this
some of the losses over all the points where this is the losses
the square square is simply can be done with a simple formula
so if you take the derivative of that while the gradient you get this value
in your to get the usual normal equations
this is what life is easy
and we have as well as in square regularizer so if you remember one thing
about the tutorial
this is this one because the one norm is known
it is not differentiable so if you try to compute the gradient is bound to
fail at one point k
so the good tools to do that
you have two sets of tools
with the one of them is to consider the directional derivatives
which i looked at this tutorial
you may use subgradient so you can go back and forth between those two
it's simpler to to present national eighties which have been doing in this line so
never try to compute the gradient does anyone know
you can always go got some stuff when w is far from zero but that's
you always kind of problematic
so what you need to do
is to consider in fact the natives along all possible directions OK so you look
at direction that i know of being and you take stuff from w and go
along this direction and see the rate of change along the direction which is exactly
it's actually is that these things and this is exactly what people call the directional
derivative in the direction of of
the good thing when j is convex continues
is that it always there always exists and why do we need to consider that
essentially in a nonsmooth optimization you need to be able to consider all possible directions
and not only
p different once the gradient is essentially
looking at the different directions with nonsmooth optimization you need to look at all possible
ones and in one d it means looking at two OK left and right
of course when j is differentiable
then you have
strong link between directional derivatives in regions namely that the directional derivative is a linear
function of fuel
so now i how decide whether you people are not physicists imposes just the rate
of change in direction that if two or more of these height of ten should
be going
i unconstrained minimisation your optimal if only all directions you meaning that you locally good
meaning that the
the directional derivative is positive whatever actions
OK first if the function is smooth it does reduce to the to the silk
road condition because having only now function being positive be zero and so this is
just a safety check if we get back to gradient forecast from intimidation one go
it is just for reference
so now i look like for for the one on so this is one of
the few slides with we did it improves but i think this is what is
but importantly to get that when you get most of it
this not only true but
the truth OK so this is the last place along that time so i can
arise are so i call and capital and of the value the loss
which is the sum of all the points and you need to go so this
one i would assume differentiable
OK so when you need to compute the derivative the first is simply the gradient
steps that are not the norm to compute the rate of change the change along
direction that you immediately immediately see that you have to
make a distinction between j index in this is for which the village is zero
and this is for which it is nonzero
so when it is zero essentially far away from zero your function is linear OK
behaves like the likelihood function
but i had zero when wj zero
then if you always get
is the positive terminal so when you divide by zero and then the limit you
will get
nine after of the data
just motivated and which is happening here
so now if you mix is and one on which is a differentiable part together
survivors some sort of all possible j j goes from one to the
he differentiable part on the left for which jwj is nonzero
and you have the non differential apart and when the is
OK so now how do we get approximate conditions
that would be optimal if this is positive for all possible sources you have
since this is separable in that i j
for all j
after all you need all those terms to be to be positive
so for this way means that it is zero because this is enough function which
is positive on if it is always equal to zero
and you get this one
this has to be positive and this essentially require that this term is less than
in absolute value y because if it is
let's armed then this is a this is always positive because it is always bigger
one minus the value
if the value is bigger than yours and mine is that you get the positive
OK this is a so if you think about it if you have two months
ago and we see that you need
the absolute value of the gradient to be less than under
and this is what you get them
you get your optimum
if you are the gradient of of the last-place lambda times cited wj zero
but it's incremental
and it can provide results
with the learning phase beginning at the beginning of the stream and based on the
host tree
for most methods
you have to adapt the method if it's not incremental
so i'm going to
a present some work on decision trees to make incremental
if you have
sliding window
is a good case
which are
additive met if you have additive methods
it's OK
you can
is only
apply the algorithm to a sliding window i'm going to show how
with the example of PCA
and if you want to apply to any portion of the stream
it's going to more that is going to be more difficult
you will have to be temporal
and i we give an example with clustering
four decision trees
there have been some work
in two thousand
with the construction of very fast decision trees yes he he
from some work from domingos and
so these are standard decision trees
you have
variables to predict which are either discrete or continuous
and values to predict
despite that attribute
and elements of the stream are
with element containing i both variable predictors and the to
so we assume here
we have
g of x
which is the measure
you use it
to choose the splits
so far
a given set of elements
you which is the variable
and the cat forgetting
on this variable which
g of
so the idea is very simple
and the algorithm
it's quite basic but i think it's interesting
it's called the hoeffding trees
the idea is that it's not necessary to wait for example
to choose a split
so the output is this
so there are several
assumptions in this work
and one assumption
is that the distribution of data expression a very important
so the output is this is about
the measure for
converges to an average measure
and then if you
the hoeffding inequality
you can say that
by observing
and dating
measure of
you can say that variable or j is better than j prime
if the different
it is greater than the
born to the probability
having the
variable choosing the wrong
the algorithm is the following
is that
is maintained
or variables
first the vagaries and waits for a minimum number of examples
and it takes
the two variables with the highest value of j
and when the difference of JAPE obvious to high use
values variables
it is greater than epsilon
it decides
the split
on their board
alright so i'm going to introduced this will one move from delta g
into thinking about the relationship between delta g and k
equilibrium constants
so basically the point to remember about equilibrium
that it is a dynamic process so not reaction has
when it reaches equilibrium
reactions are still going
the rate of the reaction
and the rate of the
reaction are equal
so there is no net change in the composition of the material
reactions are still growing
there's no no no no change
so let's take a look
an example
of what that means
so if we take the reaction
h two
going to
reaction with delta g
minus thirty two
o point nine
withdrawals from all
we consider what happened
when the reaction starts
we we'll concentration
of the reactants and products
over time
at the beginning of the reaction
we're only going to have to react
so you would have hydrogen which would start
it would react to the concentration will change and decrease
and all
the same will happen
nitrogen reactive
o started a higher level and the concentration of
and the rule of law
and there will be no problem in the beginning
but the prior concentration will come out
and allow
so i want to make a point from lecture notes i spent i can't tell
you how long trying to make the core and powerpoints and once we got it
wrong one powerpoint
sometimes like it's not really going on in our powerpoint
what is the issue
and another in general discourse
in terms of the ability to walk things they are
the standard by parts of exams and green light for the final thing to draw
as well as i draw so this is an extremely or
in terms of drawing and you know you know when i went to college to
art is not on the way
so i apologize for some
nineteen occur
during this course
right but the point here
is that with the have first running at higher concentrations
are being can
they make product product is coming up
why how and what that means the equilibrium has been reached
the reaction is still going on it's going more reactions
there is going forward and backward
there is no net change the concentrations are level all
right before reaction
this is equal to the rate of the reverse reaction
so we can think about this in a different way
what's going on here
in terms of free energy
so if we think about wanting free energy
first forces
the rest of the reaction
free energy
delta g
sources progress
the reaction
in the beginning
you would have sure reactive
this point
delta g
it's going to be less than zero it be negative
so your reaction
the four
here you would
o come down
we have delta g
less than zero
the comes out
as the
both sides
we used this work comes out of the one on the right through two
run this one backward which is the same remove heat from cold behind
of right hand
to run cleft hand
why not
we need work to come in we might as well get it from here
the total work that we can get out
must be zero out of the hold some of them right after overtaking the output
work that we get from arriving using it all the driver
so that means
the line is double prime must equal w
w is greater than zero that is
in this one we have the environment doing work on the system
now we have assumed that
epsilon prime
is greater than epsilon
so we can just write out
but those are minus
w prime over q one prime is greater than mine w
over q one
but we know the miners w prime is the same thing is w
so w over q one prime
is greater than minus w
over q one
which is the same thing just
a little bit
maybe pedantic as
w over
minus q one
the only reason i'm writing that to
illustrate that this is the q one must be less than
q one prime
he one
is less than zero
this one's running back pumping here
one prime is greater than zero which running as an as an engine it's taking
heat from the core the hot reservoir
that's interesting
that says that minus
q one prime plus q one
is greater than zero
it's a pretty interesting result
there is no work being done on
out of the whole thing right
this is providing work being used in europe
if you take
the whole outside of the surroundings and
this whole thing is the system
no network
these things cancel each other
and yet
he's going up
how that happens
it happened because we clearly must have a faulty assumption underlying what we've just done
right this can't possibly be true
this is impossible
what this says is the efficiency of any reversible engine has to be one minus
the through
over t one
it's not a result that specific to the ones cycle that we put up
and you know
you could have a reversible engine with lots and lots of steps
but you can always break them down into some sequence
of the vatican isothermal step so you're cycle
you could have a whole complicated sequence on TV
diagram of steps
going back as long as it's reversible
you know what the efficiency has to be
and in principle you could break it down into a bunch of steps that is
isothermal in eighty about it they might have to be formulated in very small steps
in order to do that you could
what this has to
so this result
that we found
now of course
that's are
in a row
it is zero
its general right
entropy as
is a state function
now remember we went through before we just a function but calculate you need to
find irreversible path along which
you can
figure this out
but the fact is that the state function
in general way
good morning everybody can you do me a favor played
so i noticed that it's sometimes hard to understand the biggest in the last row
in the rows in the back
i'll try speaking loudly but i'm not quite sure whether it be loud enough
so if you could please do the following
if you stop understanding it was maybe at some point it will
rick is the volume of my speaking or whatever start waving your hands wildly
i mean that we can't fall asleep i mean
i mean i prefer if you wait to hand but for the first lecture is
going to be very very very elementary
in other words if you've ever the machine learning this will probably
too boring for you OK so that's not much for trying to motivate the audience
i'd say
so but if you have not done machine learning before only very little this might
actually be useful i mean the most challenging thing will be in the first place
in the first lectures is bayes rule and we'll look at independent random variables but
that's about it otherwise that the laser pointer some stick or something
but i could use
the really great
are you
it looks like
it's OK
it's much better
i mean that one looks like straight out of that was but we have the
OK so
let's get started the lectures all covering lectures just one point and fix the first
one is going to be really simple namely just really what machine learning at least
some parts of machine learning are
i mean there's no way i can really recover it all
at least i hope i'll be able to give you a flavour of it
so i will look at the article
classification regression novelty detection
probability theory bayes rule
that kind of stuff
election number five has been support vector machines so this a classical treatment would have
seen any
what the book and again you know about support vectors you might choose to give
that lecture
lecture number six is probably going to be slightly more interesting this this one will
talk about to this nation
this will actually contain some news but
this is like state-of-the-art nineteen forty that they are probably the two thousand
that's pretty much they you are what you will seeing here
so depending on your background you might not fall asleep so you emails whatever
you have a linear
good let's get going
what do we do in machine learning well
one thing that
or if you think about it what kind of WBC
text images pictures graphs and of course the collection of all the thing is by
no means complete but i hope you'll be able to give you
a useful
of course something that you might encounter
the point is that
quite often for instance when you download something like the UCI datasets
it's just getting a collection of it
and so you think that all of machine learning and they were convicted wrong
and this is really just to remind you that
while maybe at the end of the day you might be encountering also
and as a matter of fact when i will be talking about it we all
sorts of things in a hilbert space which is just a really bad civic spaces
usually you actually need to to do something to get your problem into that shape
the other thing to think about is well walking actually do with machine learning
and i be
giving you a couple of examples of what might what you might want to do
it again this list is by no means complete it's just to give you a
a flavor
is quite often when you think machine learning think OK well filling up from oranges
for binary classification on victoria park
and this is really just the tiny tiny fragments of what you really can do
so i will talk about the content of a page classification regression
time series nolte fictional that kind of stuff
i'll also briefly talk about what
you will to learn another thing
artificial intelligence always
in inference some people
i might have a very strong
a different view points there but
take it seriously disagree and then the end will actually do something practically useful namely
we look at bayes rule we look probabilities of being
dependence independence conditional probabilities
well we get to bayes rule
you'll get something useful out of this picture in terms of
take this out would go off and do something with it if you want to
let's start with that
later i will talk about that analysis
you can do but
so i want to get
you might have
they can be applicable doesn't mean that that if think that you might think
like the height weight blood pressure the age
if that's the case i mean
prince from medical applications out there might be missing
you might
i want to map categorical variables into victory
it's a very simple one medical record will female female OK
you will probably encounter this one here
that's not too bad but it's a i have bring
and having the property
the any given at any given y and z by summing over all values of
x i get one
OK that's that's what that's what that would be the discrete variables
if that big table of numbers has the property
when i conditional on z to apply slice of the table corresponding to a particular
value of z
and the value of x is the same for all the values of y
it doesn't depend upon the value of y then that conditional independence property holds
and there has to be true for every possible slice every possible value z
very simple
definition that's it that's all there is to it
and we'll see examples as we
until david introduced this notation x is independent of y given z
now we can write that in an equivalent form which is perhaps slightly more intuitive
supposing i look at the
joint distribution of x and y given z
using the product rule of probability
i can move one across the other side i get here that's given y times
p y
and they're both conditioned on z
so this is equivalent to this
and now i can i can make use of this property if i take this
apply to that there
the y disappears here that's given z times p
y given z
in other words
it factorizes conditioned on z p of x and y
factorized the p of x times PY
so the independent this statistically independent because the joint distribution is the product of the
marginals that's another equivalent definition
now while we
why are we going to all this trouble to discuss factorizations and discuss conditional independence
and the reason is that we want to build
models over many many variables and we can't work with the general joint distribution
over all of those variables for instance if you've got any binary variables two the
power was there are exponentially many configurations of those variables we don't want to have
to represent all store
well measure
although it's possible
so i went with joint distributions of many variables we need to work with simplified
models and the simplification can be expressed in terms of factorizations or in terms of
conditional independence or just
graphically which is gives us both of those properties
so the conditional independence property sometimes also called markov properties and
the question is can we determine the conditional independence properties directly from the graph
so if i draw the graph can you tell me what the conditional independence properties
will be for the for the
for the joint distribution
i should say for the family of joint distributions important idea
is that the graph doesn't described the distribution
despite the whole family of distributions
because i didn't tell you whether those variables were discrete or continuous with a guassian
whether they were gamma distributed or whatever so graph actually describe the properties of the
whole family of distributions
we'll talk about that later
so the answer is yes you can call
in the case of undirected graphs it's very easy in the case of directed graphs
there is one subtlety on very important
twist in the tale
so i guess we'll start with undirected graphs because that's the easy case
so prove any theorems here but i think this is sort of bordering on the
very easy to understand where this comes from so here is an undirected graph
now remember
an undirected graph specifies
the joint distribution is a product of functions over the cliques
it would be useful i guess to sort of identify the
cliques in this graph
so remember clearly
a set of nodes which are fully connected every node is connected to every other
node so we have
those three nodes are fully connected clearly transmitted to every other one
but there is no other node which i can include in the set which is
which is fully connected so i can't include this note
because there's no link from here to here
so those four nodes do not form a clique case that's one clique
and then here's another clique
here's another clique there's another clique and so on
so the joint distribution
he is just the product of functions over those
over those cliques
times normalisation factor
that's amazing i ask the question
let's consider these nodes here will call those two nodes x these two notable call
why those two letters will call z and we can ask the questions
is it the case that
like these
so we can check the frequency of these graph patterns
and the output  those frequent patterns and the discard those infrequent graph patterns and
sometimes we can put these frequent patterns of back into the pipeline and then run
it again and you can see that
with several iteration we will exhaust the graph pattern search space
all of these algorithms are different
in one step how to generate these K plus one edge graph pattern candidates from the
already discovered
k edge graph patern
before i introduce exact characteristics of their properties then just show you quickly about a
cost analysis to generate this is one of patterns
basically there are three components
which are related was expense to generate these graph patterns
the first part is graph pattern candidates
the second part is graph isomorphism checking so basically whenever you find a new candidates you
have to check
graph sub-isomorphism to change this pattern candidate and all of the graph in the database
the third component is the database size
you can see that for this part we cannot reduce database size but we
can reduce two things like this one and this one
that means in the in the first part
we would like to develop some mechanism so that we can generate a
those graph
pattern candidate s that are likely frequent
and and we would like to generate these graph patterns that are different from
the previously discovered patterns
and the second is
the graph isomorphism checking
that means because when we do that isomorphism checking you know that is that this
graph patterns are highly correlated can we use graph sub-graph isomorphism checking for
the previous graph patterns for the subgraph isomorphism checking for the newly discovered patterns
so OK so now let me summarise the design principles of all these graphs
pattern mining algorithms basically i summarise them into five factors
search order
generation of candidate patterns
discovery order of patterns
elimination of duplicate subgraphs
and support calculation
so this is very obvious for example search order some some algorithms adopt
breath first some algorithms adopt depth research
for the support calculations
actually there are two methods one is we can remember all of the graph sub
isomorphisms testing in the main memory for some algorithms, they cannot do this method
they just calculate the sub-graph
isomorphism from scratch each time when we check the frequency of our graph pattern candidates
in the next several slides i will focus on this three main properties on main
design principles of the existing graph pattern mining algorithms and you will see that season
difference of these atoms
so this is the first the main property of these algorithms is about to the
generation of candidate graph patterns
we can divide this algorithm into two groups one is apriori based approaches
the second is the pattern grows approach
in the apriori based approach you can see that
suppose we are they discovered k edge
graph patterns
and then we have to generate the k plus one
graph pattern candidates
so in apriori based approach what they are doing is
they tried to join two k edge graph patterns together to generate k plus one
graph pattern candidates. by doing so actually it can avoid the generation of infrequent a
lot of infrequent graph patterns because in each step you have to make sure
the pattern you generated the candidate you generate generate must contain two frequent
well in the pattern growth approach
does not do the similar thing
instead it directly generates
frequent graph pattern candidate from the previous discovered parted for example suppose we have k edge
graph pattern, we can
directly add one edge to this k-edge
graph pattern to generate k plus one edge
graph pattern candidates
about the lowest you could you could safely and you and you keep your live
vector is basically flight would fly the entire entry with you vector going away from
Europe and that maximizes you're range but you actually targeting entry
so that you have more energy than you need because it's a lot easier to
bleed off energy than somehow to get it back especially when you don't have the
engine so what you what you normally do it is
you will basically do the will be rolling so that your angle of attack with
respect to your velocity vectors is always 40 degrees but essentially you're rolling around the
velocity vector so you can now point you will over the side and therefore for
instance of if you didn't I have enough propellant when you were burning and so
now you're you actually have too much energy and what you can do you off
for instance if you have a lot of cross that you have to make up
you could spend your entire entry over on your side like this and in fact
there was even a case which we will simulate it if you're if you're entry
burns if you open under burning you know you have too much energy you have
to really get rid of a lot of energy you can actually role or 180
degrees and energy that would be pretty supported in given up
it simulated I don't know people what would be expected period coming in but but
but the point is we we try to ignore all while we have a basic
design that you're working with them then you try to develop operational procedures to make
the system work in as many contingencies as possible so anyway that's that's the deal
you basically are rolling around the velocity vector to control both your energy and you're
you cross until it's advantage that at 20 of Europe your elements that you're ones
actually get pitch effectively and so you you disable the pitch jets and both of
the pitch and the role
are controlled by the the ones the vertical stabilizer as you can see is in
the shadow and so actually you don't get your infectivity of the vertical stabilizer until
just about transonic and subsonic when you actually do the final pitch over to get
ready for the going into the having a wide circle and and that's why sometimes
if you've seen pictures of the shuttle
as it approaches the landing at Kennedy Space Center see plumes coming out the side
and that's the origin of your students with Austria switches still firing because it's still
supersonic when it when it gets over the space and you can actually if you're
on the ground you hear this double sonic boom which is which is pretty impressive
cool because you don't want from the from 1 from the back of the vehicle
source of all of this and the goes around so that's a good and and
then of course you're you're flying in you hit the atmosphere at mach 25 and
so you're going through this entire aerodynamic down to hide through hypersonic supersonic transonic subsonic
and I remember was backstage gave us a little talk about how the aerodynamic coefficients
you're talking about how we had together but they change at different lot numbers right
and so you know there was the and we mentioned this before you know why
you really need a fly-by-wire system on this vehicle because the control laws that you're
using to in order to do with the of maneuvered at at 15 are different
from the usual maneuvered market
of this program test inputs you can hardly see that you really didn't feel there
were just a couple of degrees you know that you would move the stick it
just little things but that collected enough data to to
get a much better determination of these coefficients very sensitive to things like you know
beta angle you know probably about 2 degrees you know if you called for more
than that that's actually
when you read the detailed description of the loss of Columbia you know when they
had penetration of the of the forward edge of the of the way that disturb
the airflow and so they were actually the control system was was fighting you know
really valiant fight to keep Columbia on target and added in other words they could
see that on the ground that there was there was more of aerodynamic surface activity
in the RCS jets kicked in
in the and of course you want out of control authority of
a new beliefs
OK so something else it's closed under action
so these are all functions but what we're gonna right winger write the meaning fixed
forms all right k plus five k minus five
OK so for
belief expansion let's try to look at what might be some intuitive properties of the
function class
which is the saying case expanded
in this case OK we can expand k by alpha
OK so the first form the first partially we might add is that
if i k
so please
it's called one stuff like that
the thing is it skips forward and then there why does
OK the first once says is so hopefully doesn't have started ten
then if i have a sentence alpha
and i have beliefs OK
cable selfish should also be implicit so that's our principle of categorial action
six months is that well if i expand k by operation into believing alpha alpha
is now resulting c
then one says well i should end up with some thing which is at least
as big as i started so that never end up giving up anything i should
end up with more
releases much possibly more stuff
the fourth one says well if i already believe k one then i should do
nothing minimal change so i don't know
the fifth one is the monotonicity property and again sort of try to capture the
notion of minimal change in it says well if i've got to believe that one's
at least because the other than when i expand
each of them i should in the relative expansion should be at least as being
and the last one
he says that for all believe sets
what you end up with should be the smallest set of formulas that satisfies the
properties above
this again this really directly
captures my change
perhaps surprisingly for some of you get
the amount of logic that you're familiar with not so surprising it turns out there's
only one function that satisfies these properties and it's the function the consequent function essentially
so if we just take our current beliefs that we have alpha closer to action
and we define k plus alpha in that way
that function is exactly
characterized by cables one to k six
so that tells us that function that you know expansion is a fairly straightforward operation
then it can be achieved by consequent question
so contraction revision things turned out to be less difficult
the other thing to keep in mind is that we all interested in is looking
at all of the
you know rational functions that satisfy these properties were not necessarily in telling you which
one to apply
this AGM approach is not prescriptive framework in which tells you how to do something
always trying to do is figure out of one of the class of rational functions
that are able to achieve the best belief change criteria
i believe contraction belief revision so
OK so let's just take a particular fairly simple example where got i explicitly told
you the following formulas are my beliefs
if it rains the grass gets which is currently reigning
if the shop is open
the sorry shop is currently up and the shop is open in the light in
the shop is on
now suppose we want to give up belief in the grasping with
i've given you sort of three possible options here
we've got to remove one of the two sentences
it is currently right
and then if it rains the across gets way
and we've got a choice between this and we said before that
in logical criteria line doesn't really help us
and i've given you three possibilities
the first one
is that we're the fact that currently
the second one i removed the fact that if it rains then the grass gets
and the third one i removed but
so the question to you is which option would you vote for is the most
intuitive option coming out of contraction
like option a or the fact that it's currently reigning would you go with option
the way you remove this sort rule
if you raised the grass gets way
or would you go with c
but there are
so everything side
OK guys
why i
it just seems like the choice right
beautiful great that's great thing that's a brilliant said just so the idea was it's
easy to get rid of a single piece of knowledge rather than
you know something more complex rules rules tend to be universally true like also like
then it uses certain person mister decision tree pruning technique
on the training set itself and it also has a way of transforming the decision
tree into a set of rules
and then pruning the rules
which means
putting away some attribute values from the description of the rules
so just to provide some intuition
you could estimate the error in a certain node of the decision tree
suppose we are only looking at the training set we don't have a separate validation
set and we estimate the error in this or not
when the n is the number of examples in the note of which he examples
are erroneously classified and then we have an certain upper limit to the standard deviation
of the error which assumes certain group probability distribution
moreover in the note
and then what is the backup power it looks at the
instances in the
well when you have split
the set of instances into subsets you look at the
are in the subset
two which came with a certain value of the attribute
and you have multiplied with the number of instances in that subset you have the
estimate of the error in the other subset
multiplying it with the number of instances leading
in the other subset and then you compare it the
and are static error is smaller than the error which would make after splitting then
obviously this painting is not such a good idea and you should better stop despite
OK the other approach would be that you convert the decision tree to the set
of rules
and then
you prune each of the rules separately but pruning of rules this part of the
chapter on ruler to talk about
rule pruning in that particular
in in in that chapter so another way when you stop for instance if we
will decide through the decision tree with the so-called pre pruning technique who one obviously
would be well
i will stop
decision to construction if the number of examples in the certain low
you know this too small
that's a less than thirty three percent of all the examples
that's one way of
to stop
six discourse structure or even the percentage of
values of one class let's say is higher
then ninety five percent
such heuristic approaches to deciding when to stop the construction of the decision tree but
it turns out that it's better to construct the entire decision tree and then say
well what would happen if i prove
here so i see how many examples would possibly be wrongly classified here
how many would be
with with such a decision tree or with the decision to see
with which i have
split this node further and and if the errors which would be made by a
large decision tree her
bigger than by smaller decision tree obviously you will be happy to build
smaller decision tree
there are different algorithms i have mentioned i disagree
which is the parent algorithm of for this family of decision tree learners
i can mention cart
that was an early decision tree learning algorithm which was developed in the early on
our colleagues to sneak bratko canonical copy and there were many for development of this
algorithm to be honest well
assistant assistant professional than many aggression tree learners and so on and so on
well known
algorithm developed from IDC is c four point five developed by queen
and also for the professional development c five
and one variant of simple twenty four point five is also implemented in the wake
of decision is in the wake of data mining workbench
so there are some other issues which such a learning algorithm has to do it
so what do do with unknown values
if in the table not all the values are present summer and we call them
unknown values or and there are some missing values
and then one option is simply to assign
the probabilistic distribution of different values
in that case and in the class classification you follow all the branches way with
winning so much of punctual into the tank from the attach point in the front
so much punch loads into the tank on the banking and S. R. B. and
we have all the gambling before forward on the flight performance calculations the wind shears
the wind gusts and we assure yourself that we don't violate any of the load
indicators but that does not say the vehicle save then genus fires that went through
that gives all those conditions that go structures people and they analyze a hand of
it OK they look at all the cracks and crevices and and if you got
people that don't have a cooperative spirit
it won't work
it just doesn't work
so you learn how to get along with the bodies over on the other side
and and don't know 5 tumor that you also begin you control your own destiny
because you don't
and we had a super group of people to work with and and to me
that's what really preliminary work centered on heating about way and they give us a
heating indicators and it was found judgmental more straightforward with gives accused of local sticking
out references and we that the through multitude references and we're given well-defined set of
trajectories and they would analyze it in detail
but it's
allocated the use a problem and I can work it like a piece of and
on this problem globally down to the center then go on in this space in
this space then work that way you start around the edges and a new Sakhalin
and finally get to read all about that but you
accomplish around the edges 1st and work out you bigger problems and then get them
this that the energy necessary for all
I wanted to find out what some of the things based on the same opportunities
part of the problem is that
that's a good thing if it was something that was that was previously this on
I think it was found that only we lost the increased drag a little bit
but not enough to to returning bank and a and then managed bother meaning that
nobody went down by 0 . 0 0 1 but not the fellas that will
find it and they they got in there and that the against go around the
heck and I'm still involved with an example here and there but all that all
that was done in a much more systems integration and you got include the crew
junaci system above them in eroded by the instructions about it but you still got
fly and documents and it will be that you don't want the pilots talking bad
Apache airplanes in the borders the of the of the it'll give you grew at
the head of the black death but dance you questions and no 1 not not
really to do
meet the requirements it's going pretty much the same way we find designed today you
know OK let's go by the same requirements now and you give me a difference
set requirement is not all going to same it something
I want you to think that
cannot that that's not a joke this right
at the origins of the members of the board of the graph
the beneficial . the parts that cannot cannot cycling and I give a picture moment
and increase my left
if it's only after the vehicle when I get a picture moment and decreased
also cannot wonderful but what can large do is it fouls up the flow over
all the rescue vehicle
and so I've got a total unsteady you back back to here I've got 1
configurations unsteady aerodynamics heating
this configuration cannot there now got
2 more configurations 3 more configurations for more far more sex more and
it is there's a lot of grief with Vortexes and stuff like that he had
added and you have to have it can't and have it OK so that in
the initial and it operates marginalize I wouldn't but cannot on if we had another
this year at the time of writing here instead question generally half of all
the raven must be black
so this thing
is then one
now we're trying to deal with these two expressions here
now for in order to resolve this we need to make an assumption and we'll
come back to that assumption later ends and maybe see if it's a good assumption
or not the assumption here is that being erased is independent of the truth value
of this hypothesis so the probability that a is the raven
given that the but this is not true
is the same as the probability that something is or even given that it is
well this
i don't think about it i think it's a pretty good one
i mean i don't really have a fundamental problem with that but it's not absolute
right it's really an assumption that we make so for example i think about the
case that there was only a limited amount of black
available to collaborate
in our universe
would then still be true
good assumption i think but
can be attacked fundamental philosophical level
let's continue this so this
this racial was one and this thing was one so this was using this assumption
and this is pretty clear that this is one so what remains is this expression
and that's what we have here and that's called that eta one this probability here
and it represents all believe that given raven
is black and the assumption that not all ravens are black so this year but
is not all ravens are black
you have to understand that this hypothesis compact compatible with a lot of things for
example no right from could be like
almost all ravens could be blank
right that's compatible with this with this negated hypotheses here
so now we just like in this eta one into our plausibility measure this is
were formerly this ratio was and i just like the one here and we see
that we can get good confirmation from this measure this measure can become greater than
obviously becomes greater than one if the denominator is smaller than one
so confirmation is greatest if initially we don't have too strong belief into the hypothesis
and more importantly evidence dependent if this eta one is less than one or even
much less the smaller it is the more confirmation we can get here and it's
really quite unbounded i mean if
if this probability if if we assume this probability to be very small then we
can get a lot of confirmation in this theory from observing black ravens into our
belief that all ravens are black
so that's
pretty good that's what we want to write it was one of the conditions to
resolve the paradox of theory has to somehow explain why if we observed ravens and
and the hypothesis doesn't get refuted but we believe somewhat more in that
so now let's consider the second type of evidence non-black non ravens
this observation is an object that is
another reason and that is not black so again we consider this racial here which
is the crucial data dependent quantity in our measure of confirmation we just like in
this expression here for two and here three two and now again
we use the trick of taking that apart by writing the probability of this and
of our is the probability of are given b b you just have to consider
this whole thing has
as an expression and then it's just the the old rule we know you know
that in the numerator and the denominator
now we try to use the same
trick or a set of tricks that we did before now
the hypothesis is that all non-black objects are not to ravens
this is just equivalent to the original hypothesis that every race this black so we
if we believe in this hypothesis here in something is not black then it cannot
be erased
so this expression here is one again
so we got rid of it remains to analyse this pair here and again we
would like to argue that this thing is equal to this thing and
so written spelled out that would be the probability that something is not black given
that we don't believe in the hypothesis is the same as the probability of something
is not like given that we believe in the hypothesis is essentially the same game
the same type of assumption that we made earlier with being ravens depending on not
depending on the hypothesis
so if we believe this assumption and these two are equal
this thing is one and what remains this expression here
so i've just taken that out against our racial here is now this probability here
and i find that to be one minus along so
the probability of are given this stuff is
epsilon and that's what's written here so epsilon is the probability of of
a being erased from given that it's not a black and we don't believe the
and now we would like to to show that this quantity is very small
because if it's very small then there's very little confirmation
now do we do that first of all we express
this conditional probability again using the basic rules as the joint probability of it being
erased from and it not being black
divided by the probability that it's not a black standard probability
calculus here
and now
what we can do is we can upper bound this quantity by just dropping this
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help a mighty
opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free to make a donation or
view additional materials from hundreds the mighty courses visit mighty opencourseware does he w diamide
he died he
hello and welcome to six o one
i'm denny freeman intellectual
one thing you should know about today is that there is a single handout you
should picked up on the way and the availability the two doors
what i wanna do today
in this first lecture
is mostly focus on contact
but before i do there
since excel one is a little bit of an unusual course give you a little
bit of an overview and tell you a little bit about the administration the course
six o one
is it
about modes reasoning
what we would like you to get out of this course is ways to think about engineering
we want to talk about how you design how do you build how do you construct how do you debug
complicated systems
that's what engineers do
and we are very good at it
and now we wanna make very good at it
we are very good at it and you know that's from your common everyday experience laptops are incredible
as we go through the course you're gonna see
the laptops incorporated things from the tiniest tiniest level
things so small that you can see that the microscopic individual transistors are not things that you can see
we develop special tools for ryu even to be able to visualize
and yet we conglomerates billions of them into a system that works relatively reliable and
i realized going out on a limb
because you when you say things like i think always fail but
i'll go out on a limb and say for the most part
the systems that we construct are very reliable
we'd like you to know
how you think about making such a complicated system and making it reliable
we want to tell you about how you would model things
how do you gain insight how do you get predictability how do you figure out
how something will work before you've built it
if you are limited to try out
how things work by actually constructing
you spend a lot time constructing things never make it
we want to avoid back
why where we can
making a model analyzing the model making a prediction from the model
and you using the prediction
can build a better system on the first try
we want to tell you about how
to augment the physical behavior of the system by putting computation and it
that's a very
a powerful technique that is increasingly common in anything from a microwave to a refrigerator
we'd like you to know the principles by which you do there
and we like you'd to be able to build systems that are robust a failure
that's a new idea
it's something that people are very good at
if we try to do something and we make a mistake we know how to fix it
and often the fix works
were less good at doing back in constructing artificial systems in engineering systems and we'd
like to talk about principles by which we can do that
so the goal of six o one is then really to convey
i distinct perspective
about how we engineered systems
now having said back
this is not a philosophy course
we are not going to make lists of things to do if you wanted to be robust
we're going to learn to do things by actually making systems this is an introductory
engineering course and so you're gonna build things
the idea is going to be that in constructing these things we would be exercises
so that some of those important themes become transparent
so we the idea is this is introductory engineering you're all make things
you'll get things to work
and in the process of doing the act learn something about the bigger view
our quality engineering happens
so the cell
despite the fact that we really about motive reasoning
that's would be grounded in contact
we selected the content very broadly from across easy yes yes is an enormous endeavor
we cannot possibly introduce everything about easy yes in one subject that's ridiculous
however we wanted to give you a variety we wanted to give you a sense
with a variety of tasks that you can use
the you can add that you can apply the same techniques to all so we
want to introduce motive reasoning and show you explicitly
how you can use those modes of reasoning in a variety of contexts
so we've chosen forum we organised a course around four modules
first modular software engineering signals and systems and circus and probability and planning
even so
even having chosen just forum vast number of things we could have chosen there's no
way we can tell u adequately
it we can give an adequate introduction any those things easier
what we've chosen to do instead
is focus on key concepts
represented by asterisks
the idea is going to be we choose one or two things
and really focus on those deeply so you get a thorough understanding not only
how fits within for example in the context of software engineering but also
how the concept ratifies in other areas notice that i chose i tried to choose
the stars so they hit multiple circles
that's what we're trying to do we're trying not only introduce an idea to yield
but also show you how it connects
the other ideas
so the idea then is to focus on a few
we hope very well chosen applications that will demonstrate
a variety of powerful techniques
are born track
the way we intend to go about teaching this stuff
is practice
there's any norm is educational literature that says
whether you like it or not
people learn better when they're doing things
you have a lot of experience with a lot of experience on the other side to
i'll try to forget the other side released right away from you your brain momentarily
the focus on your more fundamental modes of learning
when you were a kid and you are learning a first language
you can learn all the rules of grammar first you can learn all the letters
in the alphabet first you didn't learn about conjugating verbs first
you've learned a little bit about language you started using iranian problems you learn a little more about language
you learned can get to go from words like feed me
higher level concepts like it was written
are so the idea is
that you've learned it in an iterative process where r u
and made the
by depriving for the for
for about twelve hours
and and then the little foot
at the end of each of these are it's the a topic chips
and i would put in the eyes of
if i had good working memory
well first of all what we're just going one to one one
try to fix
but it but you had to be members if you build he remembers that he
already been this
when he got back to the media that is not what it really well
so he wants to go new
so we have an opportunity here
no along with the i and more than ninety percent efficiency of the some training
of basic training
make only one billion to hear all eight ships
so the tips the three
the summit and on my heart specific problem
this type of
so this is the standard miles
but still working memory it says so history still working memory
it's easier than that
then the what models is going to do but nevertheless
so instead of try to remember that the models has to be there
leo goals this the standard miles
it's a mistake
the is still
well yes
second best school couldn't remember that
now i show you another your it's not a name it is that this is
a good thing and then called the sharing
and again it's on only the part of the brain in part of the brain
causing arranging if it is deleted
it's not about
let's see
if we would
if you know this thing
it's like this the ipod is easy because any of these
because one more difficult than they were to make mistake here is that making mistakes
another mistake
the mistake that
make lots of mistakes
in the past government
difficult one more difficult
well the cross
the was actually this is what be speed up in the experiment the each feature
because we have a few seconds of
the holding models in the central area in little that's so that was would not
take the city and strategy
one of the next
they can do that and that the strategy canvas independent
o to see that i missed it
all right so
i was just a
the there bit about the memory thing because
this is the research we would
in this kind of signaling enzymes it's enzyme which put the phosphate group into some
and we were interested in the occurrence of this particular gene for the study of
i can see
mechanism for working memory but it can't
this led to the the new project
mechanism for schizophrenia
they ask suffering patients are known to be
in working memory
and that we knew
then one of my possible to you should be to continue continued this miles
well i do other tasks
o two pest
the features
article fools impairment recognizing the human suffering patients such as a patients
social interactions
in the fall and the kind of these models
it had amazing
this similarity
in terms of deficit in the features
and we believe this is a very good model
animal model horse for schizophrenia in fact that we were all one step further and
corroborated with
prof there someone and the rockefeller university with the very large set of tasks of
humans pretty near
patient the DNA
and we did the so-called associated genetic association studies of this kind of thinking
and we have very good evidence that at least
this team
contribute significantly
increase the sensitivity of schizophrenia in human
so this is not technology it's very good
powerful in understanding basic mechanism but also can contribute
one more try areas by providing
identifying more accurate target
the of of the of the drugs
we we we we plan to extend this study
possible development of new set up
have they identified the so the total size of working memory from
the size of working memory could be sixteen or policy
it is
this has not been done
it will become more technically difficult to do that
the you know what they will not do
in all animals with mixing up
i will give a short demo short presentation about extracting sentiment
sentiment on financial objects such as stocks
from twitter posts
most a few i guess you know what we do is
it's about platform for sending short messages
kind of like guess a mess
but the difference is that has a mess is one to one more like a channel and then twitter is
in kind of channel
this is a typical to the page it's actually our project page where we
where we would advertised events we would point out some
interesting stuff that we find on the web
and so we would
talk about our research programs
and a lot of people are tweeting so
it's estimated that
there is
two hundred
i two hundred twenty million users
and in two thousand ten
they have added one hundred million accounts right so these are big numbers
and all these people produce roughly sixty five million tweets everyday
we do is accessible from practically anywhere
obviously from your computer
right from your smartphone
minister bit phone
from a space station
and so on right
give you an idea
how much traffic is generated on twitter
when michael jackson died right
a four hundred and fifty
roughly four hundred and fifty tweets per second were generated about this event
when steve jobs died
ten thousand tweets were generated by this event
and there's this record's
twenty five
thousand tweets per second
when in japan they were screening cartoon called
i guess so in the sky
so these are some
to give you
an idea of
how much traffic is there
of course you know this traffic
there's also a lot of people talking talking about finance about stock trading about companies and about
four x and so on
they would use something called
dollars signed dollar sign convention
i would
just gives here's some examples so
so there's this one user here saying that apple is making an announcement at nine am on what
what it plans to do with scale with its cash right
when the user says apple he doesn't say apple but it puts a dollar sign inputs the
stock ticker symbol right
so this is very good because we can
from from all these masses of tweets we can extract
tweets talking about stock trading and companies
by searching
by searching for these
kind of
dollar signs
so what we do is we acquire roughly thirteen thousand tweets every weekday
and this is on roughly one hundred and one thousand eight hundred stocks like google
he very yahoo and so on
and we can analyse the
vocabulary in streets
to determine the sentiment whether it's positive
are negative
so i would like to know shoyu
the two them as
and the first one
i have it in detail
the reader has call-outs you know these bubbles
with text but i will basically them to you so you don't have to
these are comes
this system that we have developed in the user expresses his interest
in this case it's about europe again you can see this
he uses the dollar sign convention here
so the
tweets about iraq are returned so that beta is credited for tweets about europe
and the results and then the vocabulary is analyzed in the results
are presented to the user
so she see that we have collected one hundred twenty in total
and we have
thrown out
roughly half of them
they were near duplicates and non-english tweets so we remove those
and we are left with roughly fifty five percent of negative weights
and forty five percent of positive
if we look at some concrete examples
there's one saying that
euro versus the dollar closed below weekly what i guess this is some stock
in this tweets uh
what happens is that we have some function here
i'm going from one to o which depends on the y and y one
the data that
OK just write about in that way
i think it might depends on why i depends on y that what we get
the maximum
well we want to maximize the otherwise
this summer all
well i can just say well i think maximize the y two up y o
and the first
and things all the terms except for the first one don't really depend on y
to y one i can push the maximisation over y one slide here
they knew what the value of y two was i could just work out what
the optimal value y one
i'm going to to trust
compute for all possible values of y two
but the optimal value of this is with respect to y one
i'm going to
called the functionality of what
is not eliminated why what
nine to write the function
instance you want to write about the more
and i'm going to war
why one would have chosen
for any of the what
i mean i'm going to push y two into this optimisation
i'm going to get to of the y two
if y two y three
and you have to apply to
and now i can play the same game for y two is is what they
i'm going to do
the a function of y three would paint
with many
immediately incorporate the optimal value of what
they can do it why
y three y four and so on
but have recursion
at the end of the recursion will want to have
perhaps the optimal value of it
which is kind of cool but useless otherwise
but i also know what the last term in the sequence has to be
and now i can do the following can just work my way back work
it's just like when you terrible piece of
fabric and you
remove the last trading you just
unravel it
so this is really what's happening we now know the last time we can work
out the second last for that is a simple table look-up india
so what you really doing is
viterbi algorithm forward backward part and that's it
it question so that the moment
they have a a very complicated now
exactly so
let me repeat the question
i am looking for the most violated constraint
and if so
both in that he incorporated the l one
the copyright and that i was trying to make the equations because simple
so first of all
if you look at the o one loss
this can be written out
as a function of basic is some of the
the differences between why i and y i brought
these are functions that depend just on a single variable
so regardless of whether i want to do the prediction
at this time with i want to find the most violated constraint
i will still get some function which depend on y and y one
but if you want to make this substitution
the problem is identical
and all of that is that just switch
the rock to make things look a little bit into yes
you have to solve slightly different dynamic programming problem
for both training and it's on
but it's only very slightly different and
the system looks the same
all this slide is great regardless of the
thanks very much so has be paid very little attention back slot
the question
if i have
interest around here
in other words will be designing for functions which depend not on y i y
but maybe also why i
they would have become interaction
how could i do it then
they would have an idea
actually whatever it is i will get some of those functions while i was one
i could write about like that
and now
in my dynamic programming
well i could still maximize y one
but this would then be a function of y two and y three
the data what if ten and y two and y three
the three with depend on y three y four and so on and so on
in way the optimisation problem looks exactly the same except that they have brought
because we before ali had this or what if
the next variable has a value of one zero
i no need to score what if the next and the next pair
had the values once you like it
wet rice
if it depends on who are
we need to store two to the three choices
let's assume that otherwise would only be serious ones but maybe
at ten different
then the simple dynamic programming
because we can
o operations rate
every step
one may have to take into account cost we can square the content the three
so what you can see is that one
crystallography fraser mathematicians would call the periodic repetition
that is
this is a translation vector in one direction here's one direction and the translation vector
in the set the direction here is that translation vector so that if you took
a small cut out of this you could literally stamp out this whole thing just
with repeated translations in those two directions
here's another another one that he did
and this captures several things not only the regular repetition but also notice the duality
here for every black fish use of long pointy nose black fish and here's a
little shorter ones much like the ones we had a moment ago there is a
corresponding right
in fact
this is again this figure out
if you could somehow list of all the black fish
and leave the white fish
each one of those would be perfect replicas of the other figure and ground
well exactly the same
you have you can think of them as two layers you have a black layer
and the white layer that exactly perfect images of each other
that they actually are fit together in this jigsaw manner
and i'd like to take a a small
it's not really a detour but rather a
if have the actual followed with regard to regular repetition
mathematicians and and crystallography for c as
regular repetition
and to begin the
one of the first show you
a baseline
page of mathematical paper
that was written in nineteen twenty three by the mathematician george polio
this particular paper which appeared in sight refer crystallography
brought to
anxious attention by his half-brother
who was a professor of geology
at the university of lausanne
actually the time it was nineteen thirty seven when asher learned of this session was
trying to make translations
he had already been twice to the alhambra
and copy out of those beautiful mosaics in the alhambra and from those here clean
some inkling some idea
some of the geometric rules to follow
and made about a dozen
test relations
he wanted his tiles to look like something not just be geometric
but then he got stuck he had no idea that there were any general rules
or if there were other
ways that
tiles interlock then the other ways in which he had observed that the alhambra
and so his
half said you know there might be some mathematical papers with pictures
that would give you some help
and this one but was actually an announcement in nineteen twenty three
the whole you had proved that there are exactly seventeen
plane crystallographic groups
what that means is that if you classify
interlocking tile patterns
o that have periodicity that is that have translation symmetry
if you classify them according to
which other
isometry is that it's translations of rotations or glide reflections
which of these if they act on them
leave tiling invariant looking exactly the same so every thailand's on another tile
if you classify
periodic plane translations
according to
that is isometry is that leave them invariant there only seventeen classes where there are
only seventeen symmetry groups and paul
so we said make a picture
whenever u explaining anything mathematical if you can make the picture
and he was true to his own words
in the paper
he made this picture the display is one translation
for each of the seventeen symmetry groups
many of these are taken from well-known sources this one for example in this one
of the on this is an obvious but apparently obvious roof pattern but some others
he had makeup
this one is original this one is original
and as you can't beat all of these
study in very hard
he didn't care at all about symmetry groups
and he never did anything with groups
he did study these for the ways in which the tiles with interlocked to try
to understand the isometry is governed by the interlocking of these tiles
and then he set out for himself
the idea
of making
the whole system at
for himself
how can i make the tile
so that i know little interlocked with copies of itself
and i will know exactly in which way is it will interlock
with copies of itself to make a complete isolation
definition that he took
four what he called regular division of the plane
was taken from another mathematician
this mathematician
was called
as hard
and interestingly enough his paper was also written in nineteen twenty three actually copied this
word for word
i translated it to english it was originally in german
the regular divisions of the plane
consist of congruent said convex polygon tiles joined together
the arrangement by which the tiles join each other is the same throughout
in other words
asher was looking for ways in which to make tiles
that every time
in the test asian was surrounded in exactly the same way
this says nothing about symmetry groups
when you talk about symmetry groups
you have to the cancellation looks like
because you acting on the whole thing
when you're making it escalation
you take one tile and then use around it and then around that and so
on and so forth
this is the definition he took this as a criterion for regularity
every tile is surrounded the same way
and yet
that's not the way it is today let me just illustrate with
a nice cancellation
let me try
straighten this up here that's a little bit better
OK but
the bottom line and the butterfly
and superimpose lips
looks like i want to
do this
that's a super impose this on
the butterfly
the surrounding exactly the same way as one butterfly surrounded if i move this one
to show you
this is one butterfly surrounded by butterflies
if i move this to a different position
so put this on red butterfly
again it exactly matches and so on
mine and I can choose to charge them an upfront cost monthly cost don't necessarily
recommended to do but we let you do that and then they start taking running
it pay 20 cents an hour
when we collect the 20 cents what we do is we keep the 10 cents
for the underlying image and we send the different in this case another 10 cents
minus the commission to you
so it's actually that's why Satan new kinds offers service and have everything I'm talking
about this evening I think that this is probably the biggest opportunity out there that
if you want to know if you want to start a business and sell it
for you know there's no boundaries national boundaries and go to such a really good
afternoon we also make the same pricing model available with the Amazon is 3 so
you're able to mark up to data storage in much the same
there's derivative images size was available
the couple 64 bit among spending time here other than to say that Frederick themselves
for instance in 80 cents per hour that recent
that's an awful lot of energy
a little trivia fact that's actually quite worthless but it did
but think about
1 electrolyte images is equivalent to anyone remember well like you're beyond that 25 years
ago the Commodore 64 with the state-of-the-art for somebody who's 250 thousand Commodore 64 per
cent of all along that
the show you how far we've come in industry observers are questions about that but
after years of examples of how people are using this 1st one
it is a website that I found I called FCW its called that means Federal
Computer Week so this is just a magazine that covers the other federal and cover
the federal military computing know
the U.S. in this particular case the talking about agency inside the Pentagon Culdesac for
Defense Information Systems Agency
and what they do they're just basically the I T department so they were putting
together a prototype
where they needed according to the story here they needed 30 thousand dollars worth of
servers but more broadly they needed to get it approved in the 1st half of
the Pentagon's got really really best director for the person who was
trying to do the project and got tired of waiting for approval and got out
his credit card in Peru
and an easy to 10 years what the project cost
I'm sure he got in trouble for saving too much money pockets
but this is interested not think about it that
it on ice tea in a minute service providers very capital-intensive business to buy all
servers infrastructure for what started out as he
without any capital
what this company owned by moving people and not in Toronto Canada and what they've
done is they've launched an idea speed for writing traditional high-speed services on top of
Amazon's seemed so when he gets new customers you just buyers of new instances if
you give it customers go way he turned to mark its always always making money
and then of course he value he heads things we don't do we don't do
back up your system we don't do the typical call support helped in all for
lined with people call and ask for help
we doing it wasn't so he adds that value only made business
I thought
members talking about the meeting of minds offers a service
these are the 1st people to take advantage of the soul
maybe Red Hat Enterprise Linux available for at 15 cents per hour
but they do have a monthly fee in addition so instead of buying Red Hat
Linux for about that
I chairman exact price is little over 2000 here by U.S. you can just rented
by the hour and made a business out of this world
here's 1 my favorite to talk about
anyone here know about the new little algorithm called that produced
1 2 0 0
some of the book itself for the rest of of your what map reduces is
an algorithm that Theron decision take a big computing problems in chop it into pieces
and then you can operate on each of those pieces individual is independent of the
others and then you solve all these little answers getting a lot of little interest
in some of them into the final match of
it is the open-source implementation of that in the Dube was written by a guy
named undercutting the works for a young man of action
and what I'm showing a screenshot of the New York Times
was trying to convert old articles in the PDF files so what they had was
please convince yourself you have the time that this is the dimension one of the
second square has the right mention
the by the way whenever i uses throughout this lecture is never periods it is
always tension
i will stay away from the capital he
when we're dealing
it was a period
so i can divide
m out
and i can rewrite this
get an downstairs
so we now get y
of the
double that
what i'm going to do now i'm going to take the white here
and is it
and bring them to the left
however minus you never mind this year
so i get lost because credit
and while the
and then i'm going to win the peace minus one in going to bring the
plus one in
notice i have assigned here
so i got mine is omega zero square
plus one
and here i have a plus minus minus the plaster when i bring back get
minus but i really have the miners
so i can why
the minus one
and that now equals zero
the newton's second law
for particle p
x me
what is your problem
thank you very much
very good i appreciate it
this is true because you have to
one year
you have one
thank you
very ten
so now we have to do this for every single object so we have
capital and differential equations one
for each particle
the only thing
that we have to keep in in mind now when we solve
y zero which refers to that location zero there
i was always zero
and the why and was one
it's also
so if i made a sketch
so we have to warn you up to the idea
and i made a sketch for only two particles
so it is number one
there's number two
this is the text that this fixed
then you can sort of see that
the lowest normal mode
this is something like this
omega minds and is going to oscillate like this
but you can also imagine that in the
the second mode
the the highest one
that number one is up
and the number two is down
in this situation
and so they also made like this
just to make you see
i call this
l and r equals one
i call these people and equals two and referring
the moat
mode one
this and later on and this is then
mode number two and only two modes because only two particles
so that is now
with the equation that we have
and let's write down for this system
two differential equations
so look at this one
going to substitute
four b
first number one
which is this one
that's one differential equation then we're going to put in for the number two
get the second difference
if you're ready
we're going to get
why one double dot
plus two omega zero credit
by one
mine omega
zero credit
and then we get
y two
that's this particle
and then we get a plus
p minus one which is closer
y zero
which happens to be zero right away
because y zero is zero
now we go to the
this is zero
the second particle
so we get y two
double dot
two omega zero created
y two
omega zero grid
and now we get first people is one which is number three
which is why three
which happens to be zero
because y three
is this point
and that's it
in this specific case was only two objects
and then you get your plus
like minus one
and that is
i was wondering to that's why we
so this
these two coupled oscillators
i have to be solved
and in the normal mode situation
we are clearly going to
what this in as file function
we get
they must also made with the same frequency omega otherwise
we wouldn't be dealing
which is normal
so these are trial functions are we going to put in these equations
and we will put them in
number one
going to put in number two and then
we will put them in
particle number p
and then we can all the way go to an n is ten thousand after
i don't ten thousand different equations
i will take the rest
of the or
i'm going to number one year
so again why one which is a one
the second derivative always mind is only just created
is only
one i
that's the cosine omega t because each term the cosine we get
then they get cluster
because it was great
i'm able
and then i got my
omega zero grant
eight true
right because now
again get two
is zero
it happened to me
so i just put it there you will see shortly why i want to keep
i said that i didn't like average interval on so much
but i mean it's a good answer in the sense that typically quite safe answer
conservative on in this case a ninety nine percent two two two hundred percent i
mean it's a pretty robust answers the bad is
inferences are not often very very weak
so and if you goal is really to maximize utility
the interval approach is not the preferred approach
i mean you could have other goals for instance i mean you have
two doctors
into treatment
different treatments one guy dies and then this
and then you could say i can take so some modelling start with the following
that come to the conclusion that the decisions and
whenever any doctor chooses from this set of optimal decisions one decision then sort of
whatever happens i mean is theory of imprecise probabilities or confidence intervals so and i
think it's OK
four for maximizing utility
i i would not recommend that
here is another paradox
so i give you
two envelopes
the really
this money in the envelope
now scholarships call of
and in one and the love this twice the amount and the other one thousand
dollars in two thousand
five dollars ten dollars whatever
you choose one envelope
when you open it then you look at the money and then you have the
decision you can either keep the money or switch to the other envelope
so what would you do
o would keep the envelope with the money
a few hundred dollars and envelope
just pick some number
and on the the left in the half or double the amount of in
you were OK with which
who would keep it
i would say doesn't matter
OK are wrong
we should made it now
OK i mean those of you that it doesn't matter probably from symmetry arguement i
mean look i mean this is
completely symmetric situation i mean the end of shuffle
it doesn't even matter but i look at it or not i mean
i can switch or not
was ready to begin this
but if you do the computation
so with probability one half the other envelope contains them and then with probably one
half twice the amount
so let's compute expected value
and you so with probability one half w amount of it probably one of your
have so the expected value one point twenty five so again
twenty five percent in this case twenty five dollars in expectation switch
so because
i mean if you follow this rule is which always
i mean there's leaving point looking at them but if you take the envelope and
they say are
so maybe you can do that you know many times
it's more and more
so there was for fun but for the homework please compute the answer
the amount of course
and and then you will see
why all answers are wrong but you gave me
good what is life and what is small
it depends in america the only hundred dollar in real words
in european five hundred euro so