so for instance
if you have a case
we're all the wife
normally distributed
and you have
well a markov random field of not too long range interactions
you get a covariance matrix which is not too wide and you can actually just
two standard dynamic programming which in this case would just be gauss elimination through the
so common filters will be doing something a little bit like that
the main does not have to be finite in order to to allow you to
do your summation
but what it has to be
is it has to allow you to actually carry out the summation
having defined a small domain is sufficient condition
but not a necessary one
thank you
and in some cases i mean when you don't have to find the main like
or even you have five members just lot migrants images
you may have to resort to other clever tricks on how to restricted domain
one thing for instance you can do is i don't know who is
seem to be the work of course let's say a across from CMU
who's played around with the eliminate feature of
the market actually say eliminated and just sample from the background
in a way what he does is he
restricts the main
to a subset of packages from images that you've seen before
and then samples from that made in or to fill in the remainder
it's actually very simple
model where you restrict the domain
in a very clever way
basically without any optimisation
this is one way how you can cheat your way around
and intractably large domain
if you she cleverly enough it's just as good as well the real thing
i mean that you seem to wear a lot of the art in graphical models
papers comes in well how to deal cleverly with the main that first sight looks
that's the the
any other questions
if one
did which is what happens
i mean to the two thousand eight he watches carefully
so the first thing you can do it you can
use the subspace representer theorem
just expand in terms of all the terms they
and for some problems that may be good enough
so for instance if
the exists if that space is too large like a few thousand and if the
wiser only range over the set of
two three cardinality
and this may be perfectly fine
problem is much larger
then you will have to use some sparse approximate mean that onto which starts by
the project is solution onto
so that being just the standard problem of like what you will usually what happened
gaussianprocess thing as opposed to classification that you can solve the problem for large datasets
for you
iteratively expands into a subspace and solve the problem there
you will usually be able to go
good performance guarantees and how how far you away from an optimal solution
but you will
of course not get the optimal solution
so what you would do is we would then use
indications of how large your duality gap is and so on in order to get
any ideas on on how far you away from the optimal solution
roughly the idea
and again that's
an active area of research
and people are debating whether you should use the problem dual method for instance can
be has done a lot of great work on the problem is that in such
kind of problems
there is no i i don't know how much you'll be able to download this
recent pages but
a lot of work on the
source the paper made mangasarian on this but it doesn't talk about statistics at all
in the other places along those lines
let's just quickly connectors and compare it measurements
in a conditional random field what we did is we say well there that the
observation x
you want to annotate it by labels y
and this was essentially all dependencies structure in the white ivory dropped the dependencies and
it's because they don't really matter
so you would think oh and maximize p of y given x and theta
now in hidden markov model what you typically do if you would say well actually
this is hidden state why they want to infer
but i only seventy x radiation and talking
this is what you serving and this is what's going on in my mind and
you're trying to infer that
and what do they do is you were try to maximize
in some way
joint probability over this is unwise
and for some parameter theta so you would actually have to model how my state
of mind being
in influences what i'm going to produce sound
that has quite the big achilles heel in
actually your model
of what i'm saying needs to be pretty good in order to make any inference
you know what you are optimizing the wrong criteria
and so
if you just
try to to model both x and y
well i think a lot of capacity that in the past
on modeling the axis which are you know which you will never have to estimate
but you wasting a lot of your computation on doing something on working on trying
to answer the question that you will never be as
now actually it turns out that there is an equivalence theorem saying that well
here and hidden markov models
you seem to be
probability estimates
if you're trying to hidden markov models in discriminative fashion
and the set of functions is equally expressive
so how do prove this well
it just right after
before the series the one for the hidden markov models and you show that they
only differ in the normalisation
problem that can be solved that
suppose you want to minimize the maximum of linear functions of x the general piecewise
the function of x
then we already know that this is always convex because the maximum of family or
the a convex function of x each of these separately protect the i convex
so the maximum is convex
if you're just interested in knowing the context of the
the answer
if you want to solve it then
you have one difficulty that this problem is actually nondifferentiable
you can just use of it by two method for example because
because of the max it's not defensible
it's underconstrained something sensible
so the standard way of solving problems like this is to convert them into an
and you do that by introducing new variables t
scalar value would be
and then you minimize the subject to these inequality for each of these inequalities says
that he is an upper bound on the fact that he i
so altogether means that he is an upper bound on the maximum of the function
with a i
if you minimize the subject to
the constraint that is greater than the maximum that same minimizer
so if you have know this information and you have no peace over you very
efficiently solving
piecewise linear decision problem
another example is this but they completely described by inequalities
and i ask are trying to find the centre of the village
defined as the centre of the largest inscribed all inside the police
it's called chebyshev actually maximizes like this
two women and this is the boundary
and is sometimes used as the initialisation of the centre of the body
how do you
i find this well the first condition is supposed to look at one of the
neck the inequalities we just as the question is this given
the centre xc
and radius are
contained in the half space defined by one
pictures just one inequality for example
and the question is does this all lies on the correct side of the inequality
what if i know xy
centre and the radio
but if you look at the condition of it means that they i suppose x
must be less than b i put all points and all
the journal vol element in this all i can represent that exceed centre plus the
vector normalized and are
so the question is is this maximum overall
you've written on as an artist and b
this max something that they can work out easily get in the baltic sea
and i think they maximize the maximum of it with you
pro-eu bit normalized and are
but you
k two terms that's what c
the maximum of its both thank you
they take the maximum over all you with euclidean norm is an hour
that simple
the two normal the european on a high rate
so the condition for this borderline as space is at a specific c
this time euclidean norm a i b i
look at this issue it's a linear inequality in xy and are
use those variables at the midpoint of the year and radius
then i get a linear inequality index you are
and then i can find the maximum largest ball inscribed into politics by maximizing are
subject to m of the inequality
each of the inequality says that what lies on one of the as basis
but this
lp is an LP because your objective opinion on the variables are axioms are
this year
the conference here on
so the and the next example actually familiar for people in machine learning
but problem of separating two points by
these are the points here and there
invisible for other side
so i tried to find has been hyperplane that we already at find function that
separates the two sets so i want a sensible excited to be positive
four sets in exile point onset
and then it i suppose my ability to be negative with the other set
and as a consequence the conditional on x a and b
the parameters of the hyperplane that linear
sixteen the of inequality
and there is a small difference that we actually pulled the inequalities usually want non-stick
and we can actually
by noting that this this condition is homogeneous in a and b
a and b satisfy these conditions that can multiply a and b then any
number and they get
our solution
so can resolve scale everything so that the right hand side is greater than one
and there's an minus one or the other
and then you get this set of templates and linear inequalities in a b
and then so that's four
separate separable
that's acceptable then the set of inequalities has solution
if it's not try to find the
if not separable try to find a hyperplane that separates them as well as you
in one
o point
now i get o point
now i am very close
the maximum
this is very convincing
if you make your film
this thing
that it will look distinctly red
maybe not proof read the
i think the red color dominance
the blue
technically absence at all apart from the imbalance you may have
the four one zero
and the reports
the question that i have asked over the years at the final exam for a
two or three years
whether the thin-film interference
is the result of the difference
the three
the index of refraction
between the different colors and is absolutely not
the index of refraction i have taken the same for all for all practical purposes
that this does not explain caused colors explain
by the different path length divided by that that is why you see cause nothing
to do
with the index of refraction
you can see here
thin-film interference in soap
now try to demonstrate that you can see it in oil spills on the road
also unique example
then films
if you call
i think films do not give you cause
if you go through the exercise which i want to do
to make the
o point one million
which is
practical standard still very thin
you will not see
any cause
and the reason is
that if you
go to this equation
and you calculate
four which colors you will see
constructive that structure interference there are so many colours in the visible spectrum
four which you get constructive interference so many you'll see
your brains will tell you see white light
it is not one uncommon the
and values that you will need to buy
i going to be very high in the range five hundred two
seven hundred
huge values of and are necessary
in order to
that's what it called interference go through this exercise on your own
and you will see
very quickly that so many colors
constructively interfere
that the film little white
so the first thing that i want to do
prize not so easy
to make you see these callers was so we must have seen in fact if
you just take a shower you soak yourself in the bubbles themselves in reflection already
these collars
i'll try to make one
that is slightly larger in size do not always succeed
let's try that
so the idea is that one can see colours
well maybe did but the
there was a little quick
now using collars
so i wanted to say
he said no about again i was
i mean it want more
well easy
it's all right thank you
OK so so bubbles give these course
because they are exceedingly
it also gives you have to
really can be much bigger than a few times the wave lengths of light it
becomes much thicker moved to call the reason that i just mentioned you
that there are too many columns that constructive interference
don't see
now at demonstration which is
very tricky
it works most of the time but not all
going to make it so film
o eight
metal frame
we've done in this box
the metal frame
and we did but so
and so you get soap
and then gravity
will make the film in the fall and figure out the ball
so as you make a cross section through wear
the film
this is then so
i can make this sort of
is completely dark reflection that is what i promise you that d
it's not zero
but d divided by lambda
so small maybe one twenty years of one thirty is of the the wavelength of
it's all right
and as this
well suited doing
the plant will show you can
go through these phases of colors and then gets thinner and thinner and thinner
and then it turns black
i will show it to you upside down
don't get too has to do with the way the project
OK so
in the demo that i just did
whole is happening under the hood
because now there a sort of a joint inference process to be done why is
that well
it's because
we no longer have anything quite as rich as the try
so we have a by map if you like the what the user did said
there are some areas of the image with a very definitely background
covers our
go on
so when you when you try rectangle around an object
you've been explicit about what is in the background
michael was of maps
inside the square or you rectangle you said is
there's a mixture of foreground star not programs
so initially
you have some evidence of training data to learn the background colour distribution but you
have no
data for learning the foreground
four and mask
so actually
the now
the whole inference process becomes an expectation maximisation process
the maximisation is
one round of optimisation of the trying that problem he like you know if you
what the colour distributions were the foreground and background you could do a single shot
of optimisation as we did before we the trial
and get your inference but because we don't unambiguously no foreground and is
the inference of the foreground
the colour has to alternate with inference of the mask
separate foreground background
you know maximization step is the
that we can perform the expectations that was that the re estimates the colour mixture
components for the poor
and you see this happening before your very eyes here
with you initially in response that rectangle rather messy separation between foreground and background but
iterating through
sort of stable estimate the foreground and background colours
and so there are lots of examples of you know cases where it does work
in cases where it doesn't work
these are nice separable cases
you know it's not surprising that the
the segmentation comes at night he
here is here you know more difficult cases where
you know this is like the newsreader effect
i mean
say the the
and got these various bits of the background
you know the computer county telepathy as far as he's concerned
do you have been with in that means that we didn't tell the computer anything
about that not being the case that was not unreasonable thing around assuming
and so that's what it
you you can't expect miracles and system similar to the three here
out of all of this
transparent stuff going on you know really we would have needed to solve
the original problem
to make much headway with this this one is always going to be difficult
the binary
the segmentation problem
not everything that we can do
this can be fixed
there are low cost
by going in as a user has an oracle and saying they you
let me show you some of the things we got wrong
you've got this one wrong for example
and so you're going to use and
that one
OK the
this one
here is another one
which i have had a
and then try
a croquet player
or rather a like for you
after the picture you but i
the rectangle around there you have it
well first
it's got hole in that
well yes
we have
so as a user i can go in and put in actually what i'm doing
is putting in some hard constraints
and the hard constraints
get absorbed into the you know the optimisation is redone with the hard constraint actually
explain how
we make a small change like this the processing of the problem the optimisation can
be done incredibly efficient you don't have do nearly as much work
as you did it first time round and not just because of the
iterative nature of expectation maximisation amount of work done
when i make an edit is even less than one iteration
you know even less than one inference that
because of the
clever thing going on in the algorithm
and the issues well we probably want to
we are
might have got that shoot the price of issue
but we do
what to happen
i quite like that what you think
we could go on refining for example
you might be able to tell me what's going on here the interesting
actually sort of cutting corners in
why do you think that might be happening
what is known about the model that we have had
that you know you would lead users yet i i knew that would happen
the idea
while you're thinking about it
any other ideas
the email by the way one
now it is
is it because need do
somebody can tell me what it was like why does the
interpreted conformal like to call it again down here it is not is not free
that does have a bit of tendency to do
well you have to take it homework in the county
every search
and element skip list
cos or log in
that's it there
to define with high probability
so with high probability
and so we have a long phrase so
then we will and you can abbreviated w h p
if i had a random event and the random here is that every search
in an element skip list costs log n
i want to know what it means for the that events to occur with high
this definition
so the statement is if for any alpha
greater than or equal to one
there's a suitable choice of constant
for which
the event e
with this probability actually mentioning
the probability of least one minus
one over and so the alpha
so this is a
a bit imprecise but it will suffice for our purposes you want the really formal
definition you can read the lecture notes
the special election of for this
lecture on the
so side
is the powerpoint notes on some site
but this this is right there's a bit of subtlety and the choice of constance
there's the choice of this constant
and this the trace of this concept
these are related
and this
alpha which we get to say whatever we want but the bottom line is
we get to choose what probability we want this to be true
i wanted to be true with probability one minus one over into the hundreds
i can do that
i just said
alpha two hundred
and you know after to this will cost that's going to grow much slower
and and to the alpha
i get this i get the error probability so this thing is called the error
probability the probability that i fail
is polynomially small
any polynomial i want
is that with the same data structure to fix the data structure doesn't depend on
anything you want any alpha value want
this data structure
will take water log n time now this concert will depend on alpha
so you know you want
error probably one over and one hundred is probably going to be like a hundred
there is still stillorgan
this is a very strong
claim about the tail of the distribution of the running time the search
very strong
let me give you an idea how strong it is
how many people know
what fools inequality is
how many people know what the union bound in probability
in appendix c
maybe you know it by
there is going to know it by name so the linearity of expectation lot easier
to it to someone
linearity of expectation saying you know nothing more you sum up all the expectations of
things and that the expectation the some
what is are the same linearity of expectation
let me crazy when different
so if i take a bunch of events and i take the union this sort
either this happens or this happens or so on so this is the
inclusive or k events
and instead of looking at the probability the sum of the probabilities of those
easy question are these equal
unless there independent
what can i say anything about them
any relation
is less or equal to that
there should be intuitive to you
probability five here
and look at the textbook
very basic result
trivial result from almost
what does this tell us all suppose that he i
is some kind of error that we don't want to happen
and suppose
so if you make some letters here suppose i have a bunch of events which
occur with high probability
call those by complement so suppose
so this is the end of that segment the
with high probability
so then the probability of e i is very small
polynomially small water and the alpha for any of fireworks
now suppose i take a whole bunch of these events
and so that k is polynomial in
so i take a bunch of events which i'd like to happen they all occur
with high probability is only polynomially many of them so let's say
let me give this constant name let's call it c
so take into the sea such events
what's the probability the probability that all of those events occur together because they should
most of the time occur together
because they're each one occurs most of the time occurs with high probability
so i want to look at one bar intersect
each bar
and so on
each of these occurrences high probability was the chance that they all occurred
also with high probability
so when there a lot of
theoretical calculations
which are dealing with that and experiment also
all the experiments are related to ternary fission so you don't have to fragments but
you can handle so large light charged particles which is emitted also
and it's quite rare process
but they're not experiment expecially i ll
really understand this make any sense
what is looked also is sufficient fish for production of super heavy elements
everything which is related to neutron emission because it's very important for all the
applications so
what measurement suffolk returned from ten delayed neutrons
so now theoretical description so what are the progress has been made
so first
i will tell you that it's a real challenge to
to describe the fission process so first because it appears
as a large amplitude motion so what does it mean it means that you go
deformed ground state to very very elongated shapes so you have to deal with shapes
which are very far from equilibrium
so that's something which is difficult to
two constraint
also you have a very big role played by the shell effects and i can
explain that demonstrate that by two examples of the first example is quite old ones
so you have sufficiently of the fragments mass distribution
depending on the mass murder
so you
please look at this one first of
and just neutrons
so very
low energetic neutrons
so that means that the most probable fragmentation is around one hundred thirty five
the complementary fragments here
and you see that when you increase the energy of the projectile so then you
something like that so it's
very probable to have some fragments was two masses around one hundred twenty
so you just increase the energy of the neutron and then it really changed
this feature a mass distribution
another striking feature is related to these fission fragment mass and charge distributions
so this has been obtained energy side you have this
charles distribution for different fissioning system different act and i put that in your dialect
can you
and you see that for example you go from here to here
you change only one prototype
magenta and threatened then completely changed all the features of this charge distribution so it's
one proton among
around two hundred and forty details
on the one
it's same if you go from here to here nugent one neutron of the fissioning
system and you change all the features in one case you have two fragments with
the same mass
in the other case one big and one small
so that's really very important shell effects that has to be reproduced
all the problem is that we have to deal with different deformation at the same
time and we don't know which one of the gene for the patient process
and finally
as usual we have these interaction between entrance ticket citation where you have the citation
of the human clones
it was collective motion of that's all these vibrations
so that's because of all this reason that it's very difficult and challenging
for theory
that's why a lot of studies now undertaken two
make progress on these related to this equations
so i insist that because it's quite all process so why are we doing so
fission studies
of course of this fundamental questions but also because of all these new experimental results
i geo site so there is a lot of experiments new experiment where now you
have reasons for exotic nuclei efficient
offer super heavy
efficient so far different an engineer and so we no more restricted to the well
known uranium two hundred thirty six five and eight
and also because a lot of progress has been made these last decades
for description of
description sorry if structure so now we want to
to make the same progress for nuclear reaction to try to
they get data of all progress from the class structure
to put that in
time dependent mechanism
and it's also because of his new super calculators to flow so now we really
i can think of
new approaches
time consuming for CPU but that are now possible so that's really the reason why
something new
will be done concerning is now done will be done in the future concerning all
so the goal of all these studies is to happen
something which is as i mean this was possible
so we don't want to introduce parameters that we cannot just we want first c
what we obtain ways
the most ab initio calculation that can do
but also we want something that can be applicable to the different aspects of the
so we want we want to be able to describe the structure of the fissioning
system so these big actinides
the structure of the fragments
and the dynamical evolution in between
so we should be able to have something very clearly around for all these different
and then we want to have a quantitative results
the challenge at with experimental data
so that's why we have developed an approach which is career for all these properties
quantum mechanical microscopic time dependent
to describe also the structure and dynamics and the dynamics of the process
the question so
what are the progress that we have made so what was missing in this description
so far what was missing was a real
good description fully
friends and you know they they can then somebody to can actually capture that in
dodginess that
in some kind of simple
algorithmic way that allows nodes to create
these networks artificially give some understanding of how we can do this not just relying
on humans to
to come to to to
contribution to trust
a priori
i mean that could be useful for automatic peer-to-peer applications
now i skip
to something else
going back to the
this talk by another human
he there was talking in his brief peter p section about how you can create
effectively incentives for individuals to share things where they might not normally be incentives to
do so and by the way did that by introducing money
because when you introduce money that what you're doing effectively is then you have to
assume the individuals rationally trying to maximize money
you introduce money from outside the system need central payment system etcetera
there are other ways of doing
one of them is like by creating these changes will talk about it because the
recent thing
which is deployed peer-to-peer client which is based on bit torrent called tribal
and this user's bandwidth this currency as a way of creating the kinds of incentives
so you don't need necessary to import money into the system and and all that
and assume rational incentives you can use other kinds of incentive mechanism in the basic
idea is it's a bit like this kind of thing but instead of dollars you're
talking about bandwidth that you're prepared to lend to a friend and then you would
expect that to be reciprocated later
so he so the idea of tribal ways you build what they called tribes which
are essentially friendship networks
based on persistent i persistent ID's where each node records how much bandwidth they contribute
to their friend previously and balancing of the books of the time
so it's a kind of
kind of economy of bandwidth
but currently is limited to
disconnected tribes and again
you have to supply you have to say this is my friend and he will
help me download the file and i will help him so again this is why
exhau generously done
trying to learn
tribal it all
you can actually what's going on now so it bit promotion although and i've not
been involved in this but i am and moving to the place that are involved
in this there's is actually experiment i think still going on moment where you can
download two different versions and if you go to the website you click and you'll
get if it if experiment still running if you are still down to one of
two versions but i'm going to tell you what the idea of experiments because it
could it's your choice
OK so
basically what what i've been doing for a long time is looking at these new
if you if you saw karl sigmund stock plenary talk
he talked briefly about these new group selection models to create cooperation in evolutionary kinds
of economic situations what i've been trying to do
is get some of those models and get them into a network so that we
can create these kinds of trust
network spontaneously OK
all these recent group selection models and i'm going to rush through mound i have
OK so i'm going to go through quite quickly but the those references at the
bottom you can look up if you're interested always group selection models are not really
group selection in the traditional sense they're actually models of individual selection that create dynamically
social structures which look like groups then constrain individual selection to produce group group level
benefit benefits so said it did not the group itself is being reproduced of selected
is that the individuals have been reproduced cited to create groups that maybe it's silly
distinction ball
biologists can get very upset when you talk about group selection if you don't mention
OK the point about these models as they don't require reciprocity in this tit-for-tat
well they could play social structures the kind of reciprocity
i'll skip
there was a whole being a whole set of models based on this tag concept
by tag domain folksonomies can mean something totally different and tag models essentially create arbitrary
which evolve over time
eliminating free riders because groups have less free riders in them
tend to contract and groups have more good guys in intend to expand so what
you end up with this kind of dynamic ecology is groups in which individuals within
the predisposed to be incentivized if you like to be good guys too
to not to pay the debts owed to share bandwidth whatever application more recently there
has been some some work presented here by by those that there's been a network
rewiring approach
which is where you take note and effectively
really to put it
in its simplest form nodes move from the neighborhood doing they drop links if they're
not happy
OK doing some interaction with their neighbours if they're not happy they dropped links and
they moved to some of the random
region of the network so kind of simple learning process what you find there is
you get these groups of good guys forming bad guys
dissolve that group came under certain conditions right
the the more recent and different models
like group merging well group splitting models where when group SSN inside it splits
just another model so
we designed this with called slack which is it can be proposed this recipe to
be protocol but you can see as a simple mechanism that captures how you might
create these chains
that's basically algorithm
right so the basic idea here is that you each node periodically is performing some
activity which generates some utility this isn't not discussed it could be anything i'll show
you what we go by the prisoner's dilemma which is a classic going to test
cooperation but periodically nodes so random peer
if they can if they see that p has a high utility and then find
they dropped the current links they linked up here
and they copy its strategy it's behaviour is this is an evolutionary approach OK
now if you do algarve
go through all this if you do this
then in this case nodes are periodically playing the prisoner's dilemma with neighbours so that
would in in a quite a way to defection in the prisoner's dilemma would be
a bit like not paying your IOU's
the similar kind of thing
so the plan this hours to go back to static models dynamic models
and is that the model
there's a technique that works a lot better than
the importance sampling called markov chain monte carlo
and that's
what began to lag
by now
the closest of manifestation of MCMC to you life google
google is actually an example of a valid markov chain of
a markov chain kernel that is used to find
the probability vector over
everyone every web page
and how probable that thing is indicates how important
or how relevant the web pages
its surrounding integration you also have this
matrix of
essentially the web just you to think about this this agency matrix that says this
user points these other users and so on
and so the grids like kernel probabilistic
and so are the ones of
short fingers
this running of kernels
the first i can facts
of google gives you the pagerank which is importance of each web page
the second i can factor would tell you where the bottlenecks are on the web
of information and this one with allied to split the web to cluster
if you wanted to
and if you look at successive i can values you would be able to actually
find clusters on the web find some communities
likewise schrodinger's equation of surprised the first eigen value i can function is all possible
to its absolute value of the weight
an electron is the absolute value of the weight of probability
that's the model
when the like
and so the second one the second standing wave will have a negative
so it's like standing waves space
and what to compete standing waves
and that actually complicates things because the moment this particles with the negative weights negative
weight control positive weight you have be very careful in doing this
physicist about a lot of effort to solve the problem
it's called the sign problem in quantum
one of the columns quantum physics
if you can solve that that's also good phd
possibly in world
OK so
here's the quick i'm going to give you a quick tour of markov chains then
i'm going to introduce to you the most important algorithm which is the metropolis hastings
algorithm every other method that i know the MCMC can be derived
from metropolis hastings
if you understand metropolis hastings here that
the rest is just
variational bayes
including gibbs sampling government alone
it separates
these methods are very good
markov chain monte carlo methods are very good especially when you have
these graphical models
where you can decompose in order to this divide and conquer
this is a divide-and-conquer strategy
there are also the method of choice when you have no idea how to design
and any other algorithm to solve the problem
these methods are except that summer how nasty your problem is throwing this method that
your problem
it is usually easy
whereas if you try to come up with the variational approximations on that involves many
pages of for example several papers
and makes it hard for this features
very easy to get off the ground doesn't mean that doing that extra workers not
course might be to come up with approximation the work better than this
but this is sort of a cheap way
o doing something the methods of three generic
at the same time the very computationally intensive
so this is the sort of thing
you don't do this in the front end of the search engine for example you
would not be able to be running amok
so what markov chain is considered discrete state space it has only three possible states
one way to think of this as think of it as web pages web page
one web page two and page three
web page one
o point two web page
one hundred percent of the time then with say a hundred links
web page three points the web page one sixteen point six
in reality they only have one zero two or three legs but what the google
guys do is they have a small number and they everything by the sun so
that in the which you have these
probability estimates
that's how patron
and if you have this graph then you can construct the matrix
if you're building a search engine you don't construct matrix the matrix on the authorities
it will be mostly spas
and that's pretty much what amarkov
how markov chain gets constructing these are the elements
now the property of the markov chain is that the current value
of the state
only depends on the premise that it does not depend on the history
with particle filters by the way just in in
this a remark
they don't need to be markov they can depend on the previous history
the assumption is not needed
i made that assumption actually
because traditionally made but it's not
so here's some properties of markov chains
so t the matrix that we had before
i'm just going to call the matrix d
is the precision matrix the that
web page one point to web page two it doesn't point to itself and it
doesn't point to a page three from that graph together
the transition matrix t
he some properties
one of the make
this concept is an important periodicity
and irreducibility
a periodicity
of come to explain the next slides but they are
but if those conditions are set
and if you take any arbitrary vectors whose entries sums to one
then you multiply times the matrix many times
o times cup the times coupling thames cup of tea and you do at the
as t tends to infinity this multiplication
always gives you the same effect
that's why google works google starts with an arbitrary initial effect
one of the n one of in one of our friends
multiplies the
and the transition matrix
multiplies it again and again and again success of matrix multiplication
you end up with this
o thing
and that's the same thing is what's known as schrodinger's equation you apply to kernel
in other words you multiply by the time of the month multiple so we could
do this with the article
only to the particle filter if the matrix is like a gazillion by against million
entries because otherwise is much more efficient numerical techniques
so the argument applying the shopping your case
because the matrix is infinity pi infinity
but for finite matrices you can do it
i've done it myself
so i guess we'll get started
perhaps will begin despite recapping a bit what we did last a
it's probably a bit tougher to be inside day like today when the weather so
nice and sunny outside
thanks to all you for being here
so last time we spoke about graphical models we spoke about the basics of graphical
we spoke about undirected directed models factor graphs
and we sort of concluded that for the purposes of computation we can from now
on focus pretty much on on the undirected case
so we had a graph and
with undirected edges and we were interested in looking at factorizations of distributions
as products of functions on cliques in this graph so to be looking at graphical
models undirected ones that have this kind of form
and today going be shifting more on to approximate methods for
how to perform what's called inference how to compute things like local marginal distributions also
things like modes or most likely configurations
what we saw last time is the for trees things like chains and trees
all of these computations are actually very simple there are linear time algorithms you sum
product algorithm which we went over and also the max product algorithm which you mention
so today we sort of want to move beyond a bit the case of histories
and we'd like to focus on the following kinds of problems
one is actually just computing the normalisation constant this fuzzy or log see that sits
in front of the graphical model and makes it probability distribution
we'll see what important it might not seem obvious but it's actually very important for
instance in learning parameters model structure
we spoke for a bit about this problem of computing local marginal distributions
they will talk about that a bit more generally computing locals take statistics of some
but at bahrain i
some of the value and what the
the random variable is also
second moments
the you have to get numbers
so first one is you need to
it's not
not really
this is the first one is
these distribution e
if you look at the distribution is all
the second question
you know if you find these things that
as a concrete example of somebody told me that you had of one was equal
to one
and you had two is equal to two
aside about equal to two
are there any distributions satisfy those constraints
these are questions
what if you had of two is equal to minus two
would that be OK or not
right that would be OK because you're taking this function is always positive
we know where to get the expectation of something strictly not are nonnegative to be
minus two
so this is not possible
this is also not possible
the reason is because the variance has to be
there should be nonnegative
right so the point is if i was fire people like to come along and
give you pair choices you had for which there was no distribution network
but if you measuring things from real data in the world if you didn't have
some evil at doing this to the problems like that wouldn't happen you always have
something that satisfies these constraints
but that issue of whether or not the constraints can be satisfied whether these are
called moment constraints in general because there is looking at the first and second moments
this is going to be important later on so it's something to think about
the other thing to think about is even when one does exist
it's not in general going to be unique going to be many such distributions
because all you're doing is is sort of giving particular constraints on the distribution year
it's an underspecified problem in general
so what maximum entropy says it's actually a very simple way of stating the density
it's one that's quite controversial mainly for philosophical reasons for going to see that it
really just is maximum likelihood so it shouldn't really be so controversial
but what it says is that you should look at a certain kind of
property of distribution this is this is called entropy
and since the negative some of px log p of x
so many people have seen entropy in some context before
OK so a number of you might have seen in physics
you might see in information theory and chemistry as well would play a role
if you haven't seen it you just want to understand that this guy is in
some sense a measure of the uncertainty of how spread out the distribution is
it's like variance but it's it's a bit more refined
so the natural thing to do and you can think about this as many names
can think about is being faithful to your data while being otherwise as uncertain as
possible you try to maximize the entropy
imposing constraints that the data gives you given constraints from the data
but otherwise you want to be as uncertain as possible
so different names is called maximum entropy it's called the principle of least commitment
and there's a big literature on this
what's important for us is that if you go through a little argument with raj
multipliers how many people have seen lagrange multipliers before
OK let me ask about how many people have not seen lagrange multipliers before
you have to raise your hand once because you have to some
you either have really happened
OK so some of your shy
you don't want be a sea
especially if you slip into bags for your order of stuff and you want removed
the sea not get stuck in the middle i wanna be a bit you wanna
be it
the problem i'm i'm hip guys i did you take thing on southwestern i got
to be w i airport ninety five minutes before my flight because i was going
be in non gonna be
so i got to the southwest airline machine stuck in my visa card and i my ticket and it said
i sit side of this thing is fixed this is really this is worse than
las vegas there's no way i'm gonna be i'm here ninety five minutes before this
like there's no way i'm not really
when i got my son upon and stood in the back of the field
well i said there's stewing in the back with the beeline for an hour
and then they called the flight
and then i saw it
all that is
seem to be getting on
what looked to me like crumpled pieces of whitehall printer paper
has has though they had downloaded and printed out at home their own barcodes and
boarding passes at twelve or one am the night before are
well i don't know it's thanks that first convergence southwest airlines began a program
we're all the customers could download print out
their own boarding passes twelve or one am the night before all friends i looked at the next
o twentieth century
u are so globalization to point out i mean really
i think about globalization one point o there was a ticket age and we go
down the case street washington one number standard is a physical person stood in front
of you
then there was an e ticket machine
we thought school
and while you were sleeping
while you were sleeping in
southwest airlines may due to the individual
your own
an excuse me
now we look at it
southwest airlines made u they are employed
an excuse me one more time
if you value times the twelve one am the night before
u are paying southwest airlines to be their employed
and that's
made possible
what southwest airlines did
and what i haven't done was horizontal as
i was still
interacting with southwest airlines
i was the more on going up to the e ticket machine
not the person downloading the take home so next time around
next time around
i will go online twelve one in the form i will go to work for
southwest airlines i will download as an individual my own boarding pass and barcode
and i will arrive be w airport
thirty five minutes before the flight
ninety five and i will capture
sixty minutes of productivity
all the changes that will be involved in recapturing those sixty minutes
we are just at the beginning of a million changes in our habits and business processes
around but i call horizontal rising ourselves
that's the second convergence
say we just the beginning
the third convergence is very simple just when the world went flat this we created the platform
from multiple forms of sharing knowledge and work
just we started to adapt our business processes what happens
three huge economies called india china and the former soviet empire open up
and three billion people
who are not in the game
walk onto the playing field
and when they arrive
just one then flattened
and just when they can plug-and-play compete connect and collaborate
with your kids and mine
more efficiently cheaply and effectively the everbefore in the history of the planet
yes i know
ten percent of those only ten percent of those three billion you can really plug-and-play
ten percent three billion zero here the one that's three hundred million people
that's exactly twice the size of the american workforce
it's that simple argument this book
that's it is the convergence of these ten flatness with these new business processes with these three billion new players
that's gonna shake the brief history
the twenty first century
now beforehand
let me just point out one last thing
one less coincidence
huge event this what i this triple convergence which i think over time
is going to change
we're going from vertical to horizontal
i think this is gonna be seen in time and it will take time to play out
as the mother of all inflection points
this is gonna be as big as goldenberg end the printing press
and just when we reach this incredible
inflection point
it's completely disguised
by what i would call a political perfect storm
and the political perfect storm is nine eleven
enron and the dot com bust
nine eleven completely distracts is a country from the president on down to the reporters
world focus on worlds run made every sio guilty until proven innocent so who wants
of them little and think about what they might need to actually compete and collaborate
more effectively in this world but they might need by way of tax incentives to
different right and intellectual
property loss
of course the com bust made a lot of people really silly it made them think that globalization was over
but in fact it was just being turbocharged
so right when
the world cup flat
we are looking totally otherwise
so doing this work was really strange experience
because they go around and interview all these ceos and sitios ceos and
and then
like part people
they're like pod people in the science fiction movie
they all know the secret
they're doing it like crazy
they all know what's going on everything i learned i learned from them
they all know
what's going on
but nobody has told
can it's
nobody's told
the kids
so we just had an election
right in the middle this triple convergence
with the democrats were debating whether nafta was a good idea
and the republicans
put duct tape over the mouth chief white house economist greg making when he said outsourcing makes a lotta sense
and they stashed in india c chain is basement
never to be heard from again has anybody seen greg q
and creating perceive gravity down
i'm not going to accelerate its in this direction
i'm going to do shortly
in the classroom
i'm going to accelerate all of us in this direction and
resurrection of the apple go
in which direction will the blue and gold
what do you think
i will go in direction that it proceeds gravity
after we go like this
i'll go like this
i want to go like this
o city opposite direction of gravity
so really goes in this direction in fact what you're doing is you're building an
atmosphere pressure p one here will be higher than the pressure p
two there
and wants to go in this direction
pressure here
the higher than the pressure there
larger than zero
if there is no nowhere in there
we would all fall
he would fall
the model for apple would fall
and i would fall
i have here
and appl
on the street
in the closed compartments not like
what we have there
i can take you out
an area where we have no gravity
here a closed compartment
here's the apple
yes gravity in this direction
he wants to fall in the direction of gravity if i cut the y
now i'm going to accelerate in this direction
when i do that
i had a perceived component of gravity
in the opposite direction
so perceived component of gravity this direction
so this apple wants to fall down because of the gravity that cannot afford
and want to fall in this direction
so what will the string do
very clear
very intuitive no one has any problem with that
this string will do this
now i have blues here
yes gravity direction that's why they will want to go out
well is gravity
i'm going to accelerate the car in this direction
i introduced perceive gravity in this direction
what does the building want to do it wants to go up against gravity
i build up and you must be closed compartment
i must
build up the pressure differential
and i want to fall in this direction i build up pressure here which is
larger than the pressure there that's why it has to be close
well over here in england do
like that
that is very similar to what
i accelerate scholars i will do
apple will go back which is completely consistent with our intuition that helium balloons
we'll go forward
the first was the apple
is totally consistent with anyone's
make sure that the apple is not
we need to watch
only happens
during acceleration
so there's only during very short questions
but i accelerate that you see apple go back and then of course it starts
swing forget that part
so what's closely or even more that i accelerate will come this way
goes into direction extract component of supergravity
point almost hit this class
everyone could see that right
now we're going to do visible
take this one up
and now let's take one of our beautiful problems
the following year
be closed compartments so that
air can build up the
pressure differential
this problem is static charges on these
only have to accelerate the balloon going forward direction to accelerate in this direction
what you're going to see is really very little to do with every time i
see it
i said to myself i can reason it
do i understand
i don't know what is the difference in reasoning and understanding there we go
and when this way
you can do this
your car your parents
really fun to do it
have string was an apple or something else and every helium balloon
close the windows
don't have to be exact totally closed more or less
and as you that you want to slam the brakes
first to apply this principle component analysis
you compute the principal component
and for each test point compute its projection on these components so basically you're converting
this does data according to this transformed space
and they are taking the first two components
so using this
formerly here
and if
this some here is higher than some
we specify threshold
data record can be considered as anomalous
again this is taking the first
q principal components so assuming that this first q principal component scale can represent the
normal numbers here which is very well
another but the opposite idea is basically to observe
the last few principal components and to compute the similar stuff
and then anomalies that show high value
this book of for example if this is
of the curve
that is beginning some pre specified threshold that can be also observed as anomalies
so sometimes this may lead to good results sometimes this may lead could to to
could but the main idea behind is basically saying that anomalies
captain the
this smaller principal components
OK so
so the set of
as i said few top principal components capture the variability of normally but the assumption
is the smallest principal components would also
here constant values for normal data so they
not important for this normal here but
outliers so anomalous here variability in the smallest principal components and for that reason this
smallest principal components of the most important that the undertaking
the city is applied in this paper here for network intrusion detection using principal component
and basically for
every time is the
the basic components for the specific
they can be taken the first one
yes taking all principal components over time to form a matrix
then we have forming the matrix of all this principal components
and then we are trying to applying this single about the composition of the matrix
to capture the
b here and right now we have the new data record
twenty basically new t
the angle between the new principal component and the singular vector for this step
can give the degree of anomaly the higher the and that's probably the
there are more than of the same so basically this new data record
it is actually
deviates more from that's what we have so far so that's
what people use full degree of anomaly
depending on the applications many researchers use different visualization techniques school
local all observers anomaly and people use different visualization tools
it to detect anomalies or to help them to understand what anomalies
o two
show what the evidence showing that so and they usually seems to usually dealing with
high dimensional
the states dataset
they are using different alternative fuels
how to you today how to visualize the data
obvious this advantage is that you have to keep the human in the loop so
humans have to verify that that's real anomaly
some drawbacks that's
this obviously works
full dimensional data we have
hundreds of the dimensions
it's quite
impractical for humans to look to all this
need not be
visible just in one dimension so sometimes
you have to combine two or three
the measures in order to see
so this anomalous
so that's why it's
difficult for humans too
visually the vision is that because if you introduce this
combination of of the parents of all the attributes the significant includes the number of
views that you have to
the ticket to look at
and it's not suitable for real time anomaly detection when you have real
data streams
so i'll just give you one example of
as probability
plus two times that's one
so we we shift to estimate the probability up but it turns upside
can shift
the probability of some other
right direction we set the probability of the correct thing
down but tons of songs
most of the problems of the wrong thing
but it and so on
and the vote goes the wrong way
and we get the wrong thing
so that
but by two because we can see if both these same time
so it tells us
time steps on
and then the score it is just is this query
raag again
so it is there
this discourages from probing
by the classifier
four years from now setting things up and down
now slip factor two
which comes in from that
from the exact analysis
screening is
OK so he says that
it says that there
for every classifier for every multiclass prediction problem
the multiclass regret is bounded by the
four times was carried out the
binary regret
we have had to martin
she was also or something cool
which is that you get a bonus round
you can do probabilistic multi class
prediction as well
maybe it's obvious if you go back and we think about the exact case
because they can
said that the individual probabilistic predictions work at that quantity
and then we can just invert trying to figure
there's a lot of the way to do that in the next one
that's supposed to be a good publicity guesstimate
whenever are
binary predictors are accurate
this list
if it things
according to this output process
very classifier
urbina crossfire
every multiclass distribution
the squared
one of our the true
multiclass probability
to the
predicted the class probability
it is bounded by
four times
binary regret
we haven't tried experiment as well
and kind of weird about this by the way
which is that this formula
can go above
one and below zero
kind of unfortunate
it is even if you click
meaning you just make sure things are
in the interval zero or one
the theorem is still valid
you know
we're working with imperfect ones as well
right so this is perfect and that this is imperfect
here i was thinking about
how we disturb the some of the largest and that
let me tell you
one of the analysis which
we should not do for recruiting codes
what you should not do
it is assumed that the
individual areas are independent
and then
multiply probability is an appropriate way
to to try to predict the class
the reason why you shouldn't do that is because
it really is the case in practice
that these
the individual binary problems
kind of in and around so
our approach is to are for each of the individual binary problems
or at least for a lot of them
that that that dependence
is there in practice in a big way
so you must take that into account in your analysis
right so
you analyse the running time
no i did not explicitly
i will tell you that turns out the running time this is similar to
so you might think that because you ran probing many different times
the costs you know according to be different from the programme which is a little
this trick
the trick is
let's go back to this
the trick is that this sum
can be thought of as an integration
then you can do inference using exactly the same markov chain going upwards
and that'll get you asample from the posterior at every level,
and then learning should be easy
so in fact
if you remember the learning algorithm i had
for a directed belief net,let's think about learning a weight here
between unit j
in this layer,
and unit i in this layer.
the learning algorithmsays,
get yourself asample from the posterior.
well that's easy to do, we just go chunk.
and given a sample from the posterior
do learningthatsays, take the presynaptic activity
this guy
and multiply it by the difference between
what you actually had here
in the data,or the posteriorif it was a hidden layer,
that's this guy
and the probability
that this samplefrom theposterior would have turned this guy on.
well what's the probability
thatthis stuff would turn that guy on?
instead of computing the probability, we'regetting a sample with that probability,
so we can actually do an experiment. we're gonnatake this and say do you
want to turn on? let'ssample stochastically
and that's what i call this, right?
but notice we did that experiment already
because when we did inference for this layer,
we were exactly taking thissample
and going through the same weights the other way
and deciding whether this guy should be on or not.
this state here
is actually this the reconstruction right so the state here is actually
a sample
of this probability we need
so we can plug that stateininstead
so that the learning rule for this connection looks like
the difference between
the actual state of si
in the data,si0,
and the top-down prediction from this
posterior state here
which is si1.
so that's the learning rule foradirected belief net.
for this weight here
but of course this weightis tied to all these other weights
so we need to apply the learning rule here too
the learning rule there looks like this
and the learning rule here looks like this
and if you look at all these things
thatterm, sj0 si0, that stays. but this term
si1 shows up
against there--again there. sj0 si1, but with the opposite sign
so that cancels
and this cancels and this cancels, it all cancels until you get down to infinity here.
and so we
get the idea that
if you take this directed belief net
and figureoutthe learning
rule, the learning rule says you get all these derivatives here
and they all cancel out
and you end up with
the correlation that you get here and acorrelation you get at infinity there, and that's the boltzmann machine learning rule.
and then you can ask well what about that contrastive divergence approximation we were making,
when we didn'trun the chain for very long?
well suppose these weights were small.
this chain would mixrapidly
and if the chain mixes rapidly
then when you do inference, it's also mixing rapidly
so by the time you've gone through a few steps
then you'll be sampling from the distribution the model believes in.
now if you take a model
generate samples from the distribution it believes in, and you ask it, how would you like to change
your parameters
you're gonna say, i don't want change parameters. my parameters fit this data really well
so we know that
if the weights are small
all thesederivativesup here will add up to zero.
there'll be noise in them,
but they'llallcome to zeroonaverage,
so we can ignore them
we can say, let's ignoreall these small ones, andlet'sjust take this one and
this one
so we're taking the derivative here and the derivative here
so that gives us
just these first two terms here
which gives us
this correlation
si1 sj1.that's the contrastive divergence learning rule.
so it's equivalent to saying we're gonna learn this deep directed belief net by ignoring
the small derivatives you getupthere,
whichseems very sensible.
the best thing to do actually is, as the weightsget bigger,
go for a few more steps,so run the Markov chain a little bit longer
and you can actually monitor, because you can look at the size of these derivatives and see
whethertheonesyou're ignoring arevery small.
sothatsort of
explained the relation between
the directed learning algorithm, this algorithm
and the boltzmann machine learning algorithm
foranet where you have these same weights at every layer, and it's an infinite net.
now of course
what we can do is we can say why don'ti start off learning this
which is equivalent to learning
this. theseare the same model,
because these are all the same weights.
once i've learned that,
i'm nowgoing to freeze some weights
i'll freeze these weighs here.
i'll just keep this bit of the model.
i'll say, ok, now i have a model for how this stuff gets turned into that stuff
and i also know by using the weights the other way round, i can do accurate inference.
and now i'll take all these weights
untie them from these weights
so these weights arefrozen.
these weights
start off from where they werealready
so i've got the same model
this model is still the same as that model, the previous model, but now with
all these tied together i start learning these,
as a model of this stuff
so you can also think of this learning algorithm as, we're always going to have this
infintely deepdirected belief net
we'regonnastart off by learning all the weights at the same time, and all
layers at the same time
and gradually we're gonna untiethe higher-level weights from the already learned lower-level weights, to give
ourselves more parameters
and we're going to get a better and better model.
so that's another way to justify what's going on in this deeplearning. it's an
at least in principle is that they go
o all the all sets of five known so for example here's a set of
five nodes and ask OK what's it community score you know here's the school and
then i try some other set of nodes and you know this gives me
this gives you already have better scores of these school of point four and you
know if i now consider this set of five nodes you know this this has
absolutely best
this is absolutely the best
cluster of size five or on five nodes in this particular
right so the idea will be the idea is to find something that that we
the network community profile plot basically what i'm asking is for every k for every
size of the cluster was what is the score the conductance of
best such clustering the network
and then just putting k versus versus the school so the idea is the following
for example i fix k equal five i go over over all sets of five
nodes and i find the best
and now i increase my k
let's say go k equal seven and our goal sort of i go all possible
cuts in the network that cutaway seven nodes and i ask what is the best
one for example for seven notes this is the best one right now we're just
very can increase k
and you know i get i get this best best clusters of on k nodes
and this is the plot be creating
to show you a bit differently so here i am
the network
this is the size of the of the cluster the number of nodes in the
this is the quality of the cluster the conductance lower is better
basically every point here corresponds to a particular
cluster particular cut
this tells me how good is the cut in all of the interesting is how
does the quality of the cost of the cluster change with the size of the
so what i'm basically blocking is hard the
the score
the quality of the best cluster change as the cluster as the clusters get bigger
this calculating this is a bit tricky if i have time i'll go into why
is this the right i mean because in principle and basically going all possible subsets
one of four possible sizes and finding the best one
in reality not doing that
but i see that i have time to talk about that
so what's the idea that the idea is that by using the using this
approximation algorithms for NP hard problem of of graph partitioning
to somehow experimentally probe the structure of these networks and
there is a bunch of
different ways how to cook how to compute this these dots especially i can use
spectral methods
that have certain problems
basically they confuse long that's which sort of deep cuts i can use the flow
based IDS
in the past but have they have problems with expander graphs
i can use some heuristics that work really well like
i can use some post processing
to improve on the cards i can use this local spectral methods where i find
the cluster around a particular node and this is very scalable and this is basically
what i using
and i'll explain later what this means
so just to build some intuition what plotting you here is sort of the number
of nodes in the cluster which is the conductors the score lower is better
and here i'm showing
eight four different grades of different kinds of measures for the chain four greed like
two d mash for cube like a three d mesh and you can see so
what's the best way to cut agreed that the best way to come the to
cut the grid is exactly in the middle of the track i always have to
cut the same number of edges but as a move towards the half of the
grid getting more edges inside right so we find putting you sort of
the number of nodes in all in the smaller side of the bridge which is
the number of edges i have to cut the logarithmic scales then i'm getting the
surface to volume ratio so that's the reason why i get this straight lines
and the slope of the line is exactly one where the dimensionality of the great
OK and of course if i have a very dense random graph or clique
then all the cuts
very expensive so so
so i get this flat line
so what is the intuition here is that somehow if i have this nice geometric
things basically i get i get is downward curves where the
the slope of the curve somehow corresponds to the dimensionality of the object and cutting
OK that's the intuition
and for example if i take the road network in california
i see that the whole thing goes down
in the slope is
a bit more than two right and the reason why the slope is a bit
more than two is because we also have pages so this thing is not exactly
plane but it's almost plane
and if i continue for example if i think
like our hands they said that sort of
popular in manifold learning you know every
basically what i do is i think this every image of a hand is like
vector in
i think two hundred fifty five dimensional space and now is simply define the network
in this space to connect
pictures that are close
and if i try to partition such graph again i sort of see looks like
like great writers this nice structure where the best way to partition in half and
so on
so that's four like many for learning datasets
if i take OK again so i want you talk
so here is the
another little small social networks because it's nice clustering structure and if i blocked the
size of the cluster versus
the score of the cluster sort of the bigger the cluster the better and
this this letter here correspond to the clusters right so what he says is if
i cut away a
you know if i cut away this piece
this corresponds to hear support for example if i cut away the
this should be this piece
this is this is the score but if i combine c c and c together
i meaning if i put
this the together and got here you know this is the best of the best
way i can do it right so it says that if i i can sort
could put smaller clustering into bigger clusters and that pays off right because i sort
of get much more edges
inside and what they have to
to cut it away OK but again the observation is that again is downward shaping
similarly if i look at one of those
so this is this is the one we were looking before this is the hierarchical
random graphs right we have these hierarchically nested communities where for example the top level
i have the clusters and then each of these two clusters then internally is composed
of let's say you know kitty store is a few more and so on and
again if i do in partition such a network i get this downward downward slope
where is
bleeps basically correspond to cutting away clusters
right so for example this is the last one down here would correspond to cutting
the so i might get a lot of edges inside and i sort of got
just a few notes
just a few edges
and i know this one which probably corresponds to you know to cutting this
because here and many more edges and i get a smaller
so basically natural hypothesis now is that
when i when i taken at work i would get this
you could you just wave and if you want to speed up the that
don't be shy
the wave and if you want to slow down
and if you think this is about right
OK majority
many questions from what we have covered so far
it's took little bit about causality
if you go to the polls book
you will hear a lot about causality so the relationships and causality in directed graphs
to directed graphs rather good at expressing causal relationships and
it's often the case that we have
child variables which we are which we observe we want to infer the posterior distribution
of parent variables is a very common set up so something in the physical world
that we want to know about
we can't observe directly if we can probably solve the problem is we observed indirectly
via some other process and or some of the variables we we then condition on
the observed variable we want to find out about this this hidden variable so
a person may or may not have cancer we can't measure directly what they have
cancer or not precisely
we can do blood test
and the outcome of the blood test
will be related to have cancer but it may not be perfect test
it may be that the blood test is much more likely to be positive if
they have cancer than if they don't have cancer
nevertheless in idea stochastic relationship to observe blood test
outcome and then we want to find the posterior distribution of the have cancer condition
on that observed blood tests
as long as you take the trivial graph but will see similar structures in in
sort of a complicated graphs of practical interest
one might be tempted to go in the other direction one might be tempted to
try to infer causality from statistics you might observe that you know people have yellow
stains on fingers seem more likely to die of cancer
you might wonder whether
is it because they smoked cigarettes that's causing stains on fingers and smoking cigarettes causing
well all we have is the correlation between stained fingers and cancer
you know which is causing which and so you might be tempted to say well
we can we can try fitting different graphical models with is going in different directions
and try to see which fits best and then interpret that is causality that turns
out to be very subtle i don't consider myself an expert on it but it's
certainly not a trivial thing to do
it's extremely subtle really to get a good handle on causality you have to be
able to intervene in other words you have to be able to take the population
divided random and stop half of from you know stop people smoking cigarettes who otherwise
would have or wash their hands or something in order to find out what which
is causing which intervene you can infer causality but just correlation it's hard to get
so i mentioned it in passing i'm not going to say
a great deal about ability just show you
a little example which also illustrates another point which is to do with the ordering
of the variables and the fact that there an equivalent
so in the beginning we started off with the joint distribution of three variables completely
general one we wrote it very asymmetric way we have p of x p y
given x z given x and y and so there is an asymmetric relationship on
the right-hand side between these variables we could have done differently we could equally well
have written pz
and the y given z and p of x given y and z and that
would be different asymmetric relationship represented by different graphs still fully connected with the arrows
going in different directions so
this is to be lots of different ways of representing the same situation and here
are some graphs from a problem i may come from poles book it somewhere in
the in the literature from way back when
i won't go through the whole problem to boring these two graphs to illustrate this
particular point so there the problem to do with with your car will start or
not so
you know if your can't to start you have to have fuel
and battery has to be charged but you don't observe these unions of fuel gauge
the fuel gauge only works if electricity and it's a bit of an unreliable fuel
gauges well in this problem so these probabilistic relationships and and the engine maybe not
so binary variable five binary variables may the describe a joint probability distribution is the
table of numbers that add up to one that describe the all possible to the
power five
instantiations of those five binary variables
that the joint probability distribution is very special
lots of conditional independence properties things can be expressed in terms of the graph with
very few links and that's the graph
and that
the model is constructed to reflect this causal relationship we know that the
with the fuel gauge risk for empty
is determined by
whether the battery is charged a flat with the fuel tank is full or empty
so that those arrows represent the directions of causality we can equally well we decompose
the joint distribution into factors going in the direction we start with probability of start
me probably battery given start and so on
in this case the exact same joint distribution
is described by fully connected graph
so these are all equivalent to looking at that graph it tells you nothing
was that graph tells you a great deal because there are many missing links
so making two points here the first point is that if you change the ordering
of the variables
if you perfectly liberty to do that you end up with the different graph the
graph has a lot more links because a lot less useful
this is the absence of links that's the useful property of graphs
and the other point is that
the directions of the arrows
can reflect causality not necessarily but in situation where modeling the world in their causal
relationships the arrows follow the directions of causality
so up to now we've talked about graphs as expects as expressing the factorisation properties
of the joint distribution decomposing a probability distribution into a product of factors when i'm
going to talk about another
class and properties of joint distributions namely conditional independence properties
and then we'll see there an intimate relationship between conditional independence and factorisation of furthermore
that relationship can be understood graphically just by inspecting the diagram without having to grind
through lots of bayes theorem in mathematics
so the definition of this is the following imagine we've got
a joint probability distribution over three variables all three sets of variables x y and
z again this could be mixtures of combinations of discrete and continuous
then if the conditional distribution of x given y and z
doesn't depend on y
we say that the conditional independence property we say that
independent of y given z
so what that means that this whole for all possible choices the variable z so
imagine these with discrete variables should be just a big table of numbers giving the
value of p
for every possible
choice of the variables x y and z
one is used
so we have
it is this
good is that this
quite so to some discrete for this
and the question is how we do that
it's actually a lot
and i
which was
by far
by my actually was the first one was just simple a bright you
the students were well
human way to describe colors
we can think
the problem is that all line
we can say that you know if it is way you
also wish to
which is close to disagree with
because it's fun
after five color
so you want to make changes
transform which banned space
for example
but there is much more useful
in image processing because if we want
which is why we can somehow or other the known fact that we've just like
what i mean
so when we build this is the division one these we can make the
in the problem i mean
so here
just for the size of colors to choose a candidate for the
like like
so we have
x y and
because it is
this point
the most right
and the end the
describe the heel
o actually
they have different ways to calculate the amount
so four
but they
and the college
two crew
the last column
the thing
after the
this is called
it also
like called
the great using her
i for more actions
i think
and this is known to be
the most perception of colors
what does it mean
actually if you want to compare
two color
we want to be able to quickly because between columns and you want to use
correspond well to the human perception
for the you know
it's quite fast
the green line light quite close to each other so we need to
have a measure which this form of deception and then they
they are such
that means that euclidean distance in this space actually corresponds to
inputs for the because way to at go
it's not
but much more
one of our policies
it was proposed that the colors
like i
and the difference
a lot is the following
you can
that is like
you have to call the color me
criminal romantic
changes just
we need to
the guy who wrote the
you what are
if we
the point cloud
you may
just like
along this line again returned
let's try to colors
one of the problem
was situated about and actually we it
the human soul
if you measured usually by and the other o
the like x
if you think you can we just
if you do for the same
composition composite i'm thinking composing
what i mean is that i compose every function from the set here
with this fixed function here
where this fixed function means
essentially apply a try one
to the function
that information politics everyone happy with that
so this is just the application of rademacher complexity in our essentially to complete the
we need to get rid of this minus ones
we need to estimate this empirical value and we need to compute the rademacher complexity
and we done that's
let's let's do those steps
well the first thing to observe is that on the training set the
the value of this
threshold you know piecewise linear
approximation of the heaviside function
it's just the slack variable divided by gamma
one of the gamma comes from the slope
i is just the
the way we define psi i that's the way it comes out or other is
less than or equal to that it's it's in the region
less than zero then it's it's equal to that of course bigger than zero it
will keep going up straight so it's less than
so we can substitute that into here
and we get one of the m gamma something so i i
the minus ones from this one can the minus ones from this one so they
just go away
we just need the minus one
for you will see in a moment y
let me just go back
that minus one here which just spanish that minus one here because the expectations of
the sun
or the difference of two things is just expectations
that will just cancel this is just i over the empirical estimate this is just
XII over
so basically what we have is
of course i i some of the slack variables
which is the thing they were trying to minimize anyway
is one of the gamma
and this rademacher complexity
so it's all looking very good reason we had that minus one is that what
we're going to have to do to ban this rademacher complexity
is too
it is to appear
make general results about the composition of functions with a fixed function the function class
with a fixed function
and that will rely on the fact that the
function satisfies the effort of zero
is equal to zero so we have to subtract one to make the true
so what want to do now i'm i think is
just sketch the
steps stages i mean i want to look a little bit rademacher complexity
and show you a little bit of what's involved in this proof now
i think this is
quite an interesting case
or when
OK so this this is the proof of this
is alluded to in the paper by
mandelson bartlett and
it's part of
general sort of
remember in which there are several properties the rademacher complexity listed
most of which are fairly straightforward actually this one
the first two books by the do around and is really quite
if you really want to try and follow through all the steps in the proof
you have to delve into this rather
difficult text and you know it's really quite a lot of detail and that you
have to master
i think
it was sort of nice to try and get a direct proof so
what i want done with
collaborator random alliances come up with the
if you like an elementary proof of this fact
i was going to go through it and i don't think i've got time but
i've got slides
so there are no on the wiki or in your notes are you able to
look through if you're interested in but i think it's it's nice to see that
something that you know
he just break it down step by step actually
there is a quite straightforward sort of elementary proof of this fact
but i just wanted to sort of illustrate the kind of things and just to
give you a flavor of the kind of things that you can do with rademacher
and that hopefully will set you up to the truth if you're interested
in looking at it in detail
just the kind of first example of things you can get if you've got a
real number and you multiply all the functions in the function class f by the
real numbers
the rademacher complexity goes up by
a factor
the modulus of that and that's follows from the fact that if i have is
the function achieving the suit for some sigma
then for f then it will that will be true if and only if f
which is the suit
for the function class and so it's just a very straightforward
looking at the way the
choice of f in that suit is chosen and it's clear that
and we will do the job for you
if we were interested in bounding
the rademacher complexity this composition of
functions from f with a fixed function l
where l
a function that satisfies this lipschitz condition
that is that the amount the output of the function changes is bounded by some
constant times the difference between the inputs
in our case
the function was this piecewise linear function
and the species was one of the gamma because that was the slope
that section went up from zero to one
just before this year so the l in our case will be one of the
and we're playing that function
all the functions in the function class
and we require this property that allows zero zero that's why we have a minus
one can become complicated
and basically what one can show is that there less than two times
the lipschitz constant times the rademacher complexity of the base class
so that actually is the result we need
because now we're in a position to put the
bound together
now as i said i
i think i haven't got time because i'd like to talk about kernel PCA and
prove more interesting is another application
the rest of the slides here
just going through breaking down the problem proving it step by step and
you'll see that actually each step is really quite straightforward
so i'll leave that out
so that's the end
so here's the final bound we get out
remember the rademacher complexity of the basic cost was two over times this square roots
and the ship
constant was
one over gamma and we had to add to two times lipschitz constant for the
m gamma
times this
so that's the final bound you get out the probability of misclassification
this is given by this quantity here
so we've got a very nice involvement to the two parameters that were optimizing in
in the optimisation that we're trying to solve for the SVM
we've got began come in
inverse so obviously want to minimize gamma
and so maximise gamma
and we've got this some of the slack variables which we're trying to optimize
as the second moment coming in so it's very clear motivation
the optimisation of trying to solve furthermore has this nice property that we
actually measuring the
which guarantees that other satisfied
otherwise i flip available that maximizes the number of satisfied clauses OK so this is
the greatest
and i find lucky at some point in this process i will have a solution
if i'm like you have a solution and the disadvantage of these types of messages
that i never know
there really is no solution i are just didn't find one in the time that
i have available
so if you really want that and so if you want the negative answer you
need to use the backtracking methods the this advantage of this method are that it
tend to be a lot faster
OK so scale to really large problems which is what we want here walksat to
be very good
OK so
finally let's look at inductive logic programming
so the question i like how do we learn
knowledge bases in first order logic from data
and probably the best way to introduce this is to start by looking at propositional
rule induction
so rule induction over single table
so we have a set of positive and negative examples of some concept let's say
spam no spam emails and non spam emails
each example is a is is the concept of class y
i'm going to so its bullion and a set of attributes again i'm going to
some its boolean so why would be spam nonspam and x
to what extent would be the presence of different words like the word free for
example is probably a very good indication of that something is spam
i still
so the goal in rule induction is to induce a set of rules that cover
all positive examples
but none of the negative one
and the rule is just
a body implies the heads
otherwise known as horn clause
so the body is a conjunction of tests
which can be literals
meaning in all these values or their negations and the head is the class
and i'm going to say the rule covers an example if example satisfies the body
of r
and in order to the learning i'm going to need some evaluation measure for a
rule like you know its accuracy information gain coverage support you can use different things
so the way the way rules you know there are many algorithms for this but
i like the most widely used one that looks like this
i'm going to learn a single rule one antecedent at time
and then you know the rules set by learning one related time
OK so how do i learn a single rule
i started out with the heading the class and then antibody meaning that everything matches
the rule
and then what i do is
i look at every literal
i try adding it to the rule evaluate with the results and then i have
the literal that gives me the best results i added little to the rule and
i can repeat and another little to the rule until no literally improves the evaluation
and then i returned the all that i found
OK this not plugs into the larger with
often known as separate and conquer
which goes like this i start with an empty rule set
and with with my set s
which is all the all the examples
and i repeat the following single rule
the way that i just described
i have a rule to the rule set
and then i delete from the same as the positive examples that i discovered by
separate them out
because those those are accounted for
now and then i'm going to try to learn another rule to cover the remainder
of the positive examples
and i i keep on doing this until hopefully actually this
it's not until the cities states until the set of all incoming no positive examples
left to come
he lenses and we were sitting with this idea the most likely cause
and five that that's actually and so the question here is like how this rule
is this is similar to boosting this is actually a lot older than boosting decades
but there's an interesting relationship to fact you can use boosting to learn rule sets
by taking a single rule as the model that you posted that can give good
so in boosting in this instance what happens is that i don't completely take examples
i just don't like the so yes there is an interesting relation between the two
as i said this is only the most basic of them it's not in know
the most sophisticated
so not only the first of the rule induction
right now instead of just these boolean attributes i have arbitrary predicates with arguments
you know
thing not very complicated the good news is that we can actually take the time
that we just saw
and transferred to this more powerful language with only a couple of changes
so now i y index i have predicates with arguments a wise ancestor x y
so we want you know to learn the rules that pretty consistent x y
from things like you know parent x y
so now what's going to happen is that
when i grew a rule what i'm trying on is not attributes its literals
and again i can try adding all literals in the language
with one caveat which is actually make the restriction that i can only add literals
that share least one variable
with the literals that are already in the rule
because if they don't then basically the neutral says nothing about the things that i
think that i'm interested in in so i think this is reasonable
restriction to make
and the other thing that we need to two
what about is that adding a literal actually changes the number of groundings of the
in propositional learning
the space of examples that was learning rules over was always the same
it was the set of objects
that i have in mind here it's a little more subtle notice suppose that i'm
building a rule for ancestor x y
what is the set of things of this with the set of pairs of people
such that one could be the ancestor of the other
but if i now have this little parents see why not simon being that rule
here because it has one common with this guy now the set ground possible landings
of this rule is the set of triples x y z
so not just suddenly you know greatly expanded myspace possibilities
so to be easy to fool myself that i'm doing very well because i'm just
creating a lot of positive groundings but that doesn't actually mean anything
so what i need to do is i need to change my evaluation function to
take this effect into account
and again there's many ways to do this but one simple heuristic one that works
fairly well is i just take a vow
and i multiplied by the number of positive groundings of the original rule there are
still covered after adding the
and the idea behind this heuristic is that well that's what i care about
if the total number of things has gone up but but the number of positive
groundings has gone down actually and you know i'm more interested in the latter
what we do
you mean the qn
all or are in
PM right OK whether it's the bayesian idea that there's some
you know
belief about the likelihood that different functions will arise in a particular scenario that you're
so if you knew which function was gonna rise of machine learning to learn so
you're done
if you don't then you may have some belief about what functions are likely or
more likely to occur
and that is what pn is giving you
of course you know there are various
philosophical interpretations of what that belief means you know because you can't repeat the experiment
in some sense
that that you know i i wouldn't
be able to give very informed views about that but
yes exactly but this is the sorry the the idea is that function
that distribution is defined before you see the training example before you know when you
arrive and you say
i'm going to study i don't know
biological networks
you know then i have some prior knowledge that tells me the likelihood of certain
functions arising
and i have to think of all that and put it out there
ahead of time
and then i get my training sample try and
find the best function
biased without prior probability
that's not to use it
the only way that
shown in the
but given
the probability of mean
i mean what you know
of course it is
i think the
the assumption is that you know very little
i mean the assumption there is only the relationship between x and y that you're
assuming you know something about not assuming anything about the distribution
of x
so there i guess is way
the original set of these
that we can go away
air force
well because
and when he is wrong
it is not to say that prior
the prior was
the mall
i think it's only a prior over the relationship between x and y that peaceful
will satisfy are not an assumption about the
distributions over the
the marginal distribution of x there an assumption made about that
he said mean i mean what you're doing is saying is i'm expecting these types
of functions to rise those functions will tell us given the next how to get
the y out
one tell you anything about the distribution over acts independently of one
i mean that's the same answer just a moment ago
the idea
we can talk about offline
not convinced like so you can move on if you come back
right so
OK i'm fortunate have this you know what i would need is the bound with
training error in here but imagine is term in here with the training error
plus this quantity here
so now if i have a particular choice of q i will minimize this combination
and one choice of q will bias me toward using the functions so maybe i
two functions the roughly equivalent in terms of training error
and in one of the choices of q
one is is preferred and in the other choice of q the others preferred
so it would change that
what i need
it is
the best way
exactly those are regularized all in
last algorithms
well in that case it would simply be minimizing an algorithm that would minimize this
together with the training error so would find the function in the class
that would have