the last ten years
having this
are we going to
absolutely not
theory of the
i mean turn
and my
at the time of
one year
it would be
make your
is all the more
we can already
so they can play
o five
all the here
it be or
we have
he is on a
might be
you are
early on
OK the world
that year
he will be
a lot
it is
there are
you know
the way
is not a clique so if you think there are two
nolte the that are not connected
otherwise it would be
so let's try to conditional independence according to graph separation between these two guys
we get exactly this because this is the lowest p
she was only the
p of x one cm x two
is equal to p of cx one times your sixty divided what you see
since we applied with this
so these red
equation holds
is true
what we do
we essentially compute
these in their expression
this expression is over
all the elements see that are hoping it be
and now
we can separate these some into four
which together
formed in times so you can you can see from this four parts
in the first part x one and x two are not in c
in the second part only extreme norms
only x
now this is
major just see
now this right
the way it's written is correct
we are going to perform this song
but we will
the set si not included
x one or x
we only include the notable right
if i put here only c
the set will be this i will
the range of this image will be all the seas
but do not include x one
and not include xb
now let's assume that they want to include x y
now i just take the union of x one with c
but they keep something over the same range
i want to include only x two
they include x two you would see but keep some of the same original range
of c which was not x one marks
and finally for wanting to both explain the extreme estimation
i some of the original set but they include x x
these exhaust all the possibilities for all the subsets
now the basic because the following
since the cardinality of the set
the party of these
the same as the party of physics one
but is the opposite of the parity of these exponent
these cardinality here
it is
well if this is all is even if is even this or rather because i'm
just adding one single line
since he had two elements
the fact of this expression is the same but your original expression because
i had to live
not one
forty five had two
six it's a which is still in effect
nine which is still which governments so busy
these kind is the same as
and this is the same
so i can suppress all these x one x two
and just change the signs
of these this expression
so i'll change
all suppressed is x one the mines here
suppressed physics to the mines here as suppressed x one x two and they put
two models that which was one
so there's
when you put all the missing evidence
i guess what you think you think exactly that expression
the side monday that
but side on the side here because of this
these things you know
basically things that will never be is not a clique
this is
so the final result we just our function or the entire set
will be just some of these
are cliques
these which represent leaks
that's decision proved
you can try to cool
we can to one of the most celebrated theorem
graph model
slide here is really important
y four
conditional independence statements are usually what you can see from problem
once we've gone through training period we're not going to make mistakes with high probability
we're not going to make big mistakes for any future things drawn from the distribution
f of the PAC guarantee holds so graphically i drew it this way imagine each
each row here is is another training example coming through
the first block of them are blue those training examples and after that it's a
bunch of things where we were the algorithm makes no mistakes it correctly classifies
four outputs
after the initial training period
OK so
that seems like a good kind of guarantee it seems like a useful thing to
have which you can imagine that the learner the robots scrambling around the world collecting
data about oh i tried this in this state i tried this in this state
building up the training set and then predicting things correctly after that point
that would be really great so here's the first thing that goes wrong building
putting the PAC learner as are transition function learner in reinforcement learning algorithm isn't going
to give us a PAC MDP guarantee and the reason for this is
i find it somewhat amusing the idea something that so critical for getting kind of
these classic results to go through a implies that the learner can improve
and changing anyway it's behaviour
right so these these examples
whereas the robot getting his examples from his wandering around the world and collecting them
it's what's the distribution of examples what is a function of how wanders around the
world so if it collects for a while and this is all about how things
work now start to behave differently the distribution changes
so really the only way they can use this great learning that it is that
it just it just it just made so it makes perfect predictions now and wanders
around the world the same way that it's always wanted the world saying you know
i know how i would have optimized that i know how would have optimise that
they can make use of that because the learner goes away
you can make accurate predictions anymore
so that's unfortunate OK so we have another model that there's a better on the
mistake bound model of of
computational learning theory says that we're not going to have any depends on the distribution
inputs are going to be presented online perhaps by an adversary and for each one
the learner is supposed to predict the output
if it makes a mistake get to observe with the correct label is
and it's not allowed over the course of its lifetime to make more than m
mistakes so it's sort of a victim of the adversary adversary can can not show
some example for arbitrarily long into the future
it when it gets an example might make a mistake on it but the whole
numbers takes over its lifetime has been found
so that seems good right we got rid of this notion of depending
desperately on the distribution of inputs
the problem with this one though if you stick it into a reinforcement learning algorithm
is again it's not PAC MDP and that's because it can make mistakes the predictor
of next state can make mistakes and as i showed in that little two by
two example that a mistake could mean that there's some place out there that has
high reward that are currently function predicts has low reward and therefore we're not going
to learn what i'm going to go visit when i can learn and we can
be permanently suboptimal so we will satisfy the PAC MDP guarantee
getting near optimal reward
after some number of mistakes so are so we said okay well maybe we can
get the best of both worlds here and we sort of
did we have developed
a learning framework to sound like paco quick
which stands for knows what it knows
so here's the basic idea
is the inputs are presented online like in the mistake bound model for each
the learner can actually predict the output but has to be accurate or it's allowed
to say i don't know right we can expect to be accurate with
learning anything so it's allowed to say i don't know and observe the label it's
not allowed to make mistakes
and up to that point it's actually really easy to do this right you just
say i don't know forever so we have to put it down on the total
number of times it's allowed to say i don't know
OK so that means it's allowed to get training examples it's allowed to be cool
is for little while but it can be closed forever so
graphically awaiting i didn't point the graphical representation the mistake bound k so let's take
the case it's getting examples some of them are wrong read and some of the
right green but the total number of red bars has to be found near the
top of the total number of blue bars was found this is now the quick
model the total number of blue bars is bounded so what's happening is it's it's
getting in input making prediction it
if at all but only if it's sure that's right
otherwise you can say i don't know and request an example
and the total number of blue bars has to be relatively small
so that's
quick quickly
and this this can we can plug this into reinforcement learning algorithm and we can
get our PAC MDP guarantee y
why why
the problem with
right worst mistake with the mistake bound algorithms do is if it's not sure
it just it gases
and some of the really affect mistake bound algorithms what they do is they not
playing the odds but they play the hypothesis space they say basically if more thing
many things in my hypothesis space agree on go with that and if i'm wrong
then i learn a lot and it makes very calm very dramatic progress towards learning
the real hypothesis but but the quick recovery can do that if it's not sure
it has to say i don't know
if it's too confident
o it's not allowed to be wrong
it's simply not OK well in its impact has the pack like has an epsilon
delta sort of thing so
a quick algorithm you can guarantee that any problem with any amount of stochasticity is
going to be a hundred percent guarantee correct so we have to hold out some
probability that the whole thing could just fail but when it's not failing it has
to be right
otherwise cyclic
little section on
so some practical details and
in the rest of the lecturing and get into sort of
some more
technical details of estimated to construct different sorts of markov chains harder problems so we
can solve so if at this point
things on claire good times questions
world class
one of the things that seems a bit unfortunate about one colour with that it's
a noisy i started off with this example of trying to compute pi and it's
embarrassing bad right when you can it's huge amount of work just to get a
few significant figures
when sometimes it's not true that all we can do is evaluate how distribution up
to a constant we've actually got some mathematical ability to
do some analytical work and maybe some things out exactly they would be nice if
sometimes we could use some of the mathematical ability to remove the noise from something
get better estimates
here's an example of the problem the
multicolored find very hard to imagine something from
distribution and you're interested in the tail probability just some extreme actually looking for that
red area
if you just draw samples then hardly any of them are going to fit
into the red area and taken as the variance is the sort of binomial thing
whether you end up in the air and then you can get very very noisy
estimates because you're going to be averaging a whole string is there is no i'm
not in that area with the old one is something necessary
so we like methods that can maybe do that one way is to just change
the distribution of sampling from that some sort of importance sampling trick where you actually
sample from something focused on that are
here's another way of reducing some noise so
imagine we are interested in
very simple problem what's the probability of a single binary variable being turned on
so we've got a big probability distribution which just interested in one of the variables
and whether it's turned onto its marginal probability and it might be that marginal probabilities
are small
if the standard thing you say well
this probability is
in expectation that's what we always do we write an expectation that you are on
drawn from the distribution and so you just average and your samples how many times
it was turned on doing the thing averaging together all these areas and the old
is the alternative
so you're doing gibbs sampling you've already computed
the conditional probability of it being turned on
given all the others because that's what you computed in order to resample it and
you get something algorithms
so we're going to rewrite the probability in a different way
this probability is just
the joint probability is the probability of all work
summed over all of the others
and now this is an average of the conditional probability
which we've already computed so we can have a free
average under
the samples of all the other variables
so what we can do is this
we're interested in one of the variables and none of the others
and the obvious thing to do was to sample from all of them and then
you look at this one
instead we cannot sample from all of them throw away the one we're interested in
and only look at the rest
and the rest are going to say
given out setting this is how much we think that one variable you're interested and
wants to be turned on that nice real number which could be the sort of
very small things close what we're estimating and we average a
so we're going to run exactly the same MCMC algorithm and we're going to be
processing samples in a different way is the whole the monte carlo estimator we just
played around with some of the
this thing is
called by a lot of statisticians around isation i have what can only be described
as ransom my thesis why that's stupid doesn't really apply but only that interested readers
is also
called waste recycling by some communities because
they generalize to other transition operators that imagine moving into the state you're interested in
so in this if you're doing something like metropolis and you're proposing lots state they
say makes states to propose the weight but we're going to recycle waste by looking
at the probability of going there there's lots of funky names out this very simple
trick which has been around for many decades
it's an example of a more general trick
involves this idea of you're interested in some variables and instead of keeping just a
being one feels the same amount attention
i mean one has its unit vector pointing in the opposite direction
i guess that's written here is the unit vector pointing from jade i is the
negative of the unit vector pointing from writer jay
but but the
under tension
and so the x
it doesn't get a negation
it's the same number but the unit vectors that give me the direction that is about these forces
are acting there opposite each other
and so this is the force on node to pulling it this way
this is the force i know to pulling up and to the left this is
the force on to pulling it straight up
i write down these equations and all the five nodes
that's fine vector equations my vectors are two-dimensional in this picture so it's ten equations
in a bunch of unknowns
just as a little bit of notation here we have a coordinate system
introduced say put a court according system like this may be
then we can give coordinates to these
nodes and if we don't know piece if i is the position vector with the court if you like
i've no died in the unit vectors u i jay
are just peachy my speech i divided by the length of the difference
so you have explicit the concrete formula here
and so in general and one specific one but in general are constraints look like this
this the sum
for each node i is the sum overall jay
such that i j's one these beams one arcs
the unit vector pointing from my deejay times the tension variable which i don't know
yet excideuil that's my optimization variable should be equal to
minus be survive
the force node
so it was really equal equations that have to be satisfied
and is written out in
and in matrix form for that particular example we've got one two three four five six seven
eight variables and we've got ten constraints
let's see here
but there are some redundancies in these constraints because as i said these forces have to add up to zero
so the x component these four set up after zero but why can the
vertical components these first attempt at a zero so there are
two k to redundancies actually there's a third redundancy that the talk
the total torque has to be zero so
well going into it because it would take us too far field there are three redundancies in this system here
and and so even though it looks like this is overdetermined it's actually underdetermined i
only have seven constraints and eight variables so this is an underdetermined system
by the way it
for those of you who know
network flow problems that looks a bit like a network flow problem because every column
has a plus one minus one
this that's what happens in network flow problems for those of you know
recall a plus one minus one
here every column has a unit vector
and the negative the unit vector
in two dimensions are if we did in three dimensions are being will unitary three vectors
this class problems is very similar network flows
and so you can see that if i add up all the columns
all right so we get zero equals zero
even if i ended up being
rose associate with the x variables you'll see with horizontal constraint
with the horizontal direction and force
i we get zero if i add up to be
even rose i would also get zero so the redundancies are clearer
okay was the optimization problem the optimization problem is
minimize the total weight of this structure because we're gonna put on some spacecraft and fly it to
end it's expensive and the hardest this thing is the more it costs in fuel to launch this thing
and so we wanna make this the lightest structure possible that will handle the forces
the forces that can be applied to it
and so on and minimize the weight
end now
this problem is
the original model you'd have to be a little more careful here but i put
something simple just make it easy to explain
the weights
is the sum over all arcs
the length of the article which are doing biology that's data
times the cross sectional area of the arc
and their cross sectional area
ought to be proportional to the tension or compression
he met
and so they had been is under tension or compression
a lot of it then i did a big number here and so put the absolute value x i jay
as my
measuring how
much cross sectional area i need for this being
and that's correct
and then this will give me the total
volume and the course
the way is just the density the material times by
so this is the optimization problem we want to solve the same constraints i showed
you in detail before r i just added this objective function here
but it's not a linear programming problem has written because these absolute value signs
there's a few common tricks and here's one of them and these tricks are good to know
when you're an absolute value signs you can often
reduce the problem to a linear programming
here's the trick
right x i jay is the difference to nonnegative variables
now these now nonnegative variables that's nice
so replace x i j with the difference of two variables
x i j plus oxygen minus
and all the next statement is not quite right
be absolute value is not
equal to the sum of these two variables
it would be equal to the sum of those two variables if i knew
this differences
written what and with the extra stipulation that one of these two must be equal to zero
positive number
if x i j was positive it would be just this act the positive one
effects idea was negative that would be just fact
and then the absolute value would be
e there just at or just at and there would be the correct thing
if the if they are both can have
can be positive at the same time then adding a little bit too much so
this is actually an upper bound
on the absolute value of the variable
it's an upper bound
but i'm trying to minimize this thing
and i would never leave the slack left over in both of these things
if i added three both these variables so that they can
on both zero also what so the positive
actually extra bass strings which were appointed by the challenge so you have to keep
that in mind
so much of which was same task quite complex task and
if you want to solve a complex task you have been told true the complex
so from is really two extreme choices to get a complex system
the first one is what i call love scale engineering
so i think we brainwashed you will get at the beginning about that
you basically like design
very good and christian features that you know
good for your for your task
and you see that two of very classical originally now simpler learning enterprise so that
actually works very well
but we're just not interested in that we prefer you know like
the only way
instead we use that simple features cities like features which are related to gently till
task like in know because it would be text
gently straight text and try to design this time quite complex system of this text
i mean the specs walls and
you hope that your system is going to implicitly down the right features
existing cure which processing system we tend to use like you know the first the
so the usually design and quality features and food
if you don't do like shallow classifier like this public television
sometimes because you got on top of something it's overnight
so far just like part of speech thinking
feature actually
usually quite simple it's like a combination of false unlabelled so i mean it's OK
but from the more complicated task
it tends to be
but meanwhile in particular for semantic role labeling
and actually
it's sometimes even more complicated than that
people tend to like cascade features so far semantic colorings will like first handcrafted features
get from is crafted features the part of speech tags
from this part of speech tags they would like to be in the posterior
and then from the sparse trees it would again handcrafted features
and if it gains features to a new classifier
and they would have been the tags are interested
we think that you know
trying to
i do like some task specific engineering really like limits the natural language processing so
called because it's time you have like a new task
you need again to find new features and as tasks tend to be more and
more complicated variables you need to
get you know
one more complicated features so instead we would like to find some kind of unified
hidden representations of text which
would you know
represent very well text on wood which would work for any kind of natural language
processing task which involves tagging
and as you see the presentation we would be able then to
build some kind of unified natural language processing architecture
without any
external and internal
so we want to work towards the actions
to achieve this goal
we like going to start from scratch will forget
most of the john which was a single knowledge
we're going to keep actually then that is the natural language processing benchmarks to see
if we do
and you know any good
but really
in this talk to remember all of the which is avoid
that's specific engineering
so we are doing the job was processing
we need some kind of
complicated systems
something which would scale because we have a lot of the
something which would like to find some out he then all preservation so i don't
know if
you know it's true it's about in your head but for me the obvious choice
and i let one
so maybe you forgot about knowledge work because it's quite old
but for me and i know it works just like a series of
metrics based on computations
followed by some some monday night
so in all cases we we use like a simple
i mean it's like the house version of the hyperbolic tangent but you can use
whatever you want
so you can you know stacks is layers
and basically at it's clear
you get
an increasing level of abstraction of your input data
the cool thing is
that's the
what we call the weights the parliament of each trails just trained and trained by
on something like gradient descent
it looks OK like that because we would legs and obtain like he did presentation
it's like you know what the main point here is
how can we fit you know text usually knowledge works sunlight just you know number
of so i can we find the text
it's actually quite simple you just like my simple
next two like a feature space you embed them into a feature space
so you want is that just like a fifty dimensional feature vector nothing else
but this feature that you know is going to be trained
well what happened before were
no no no no no as you might them to like feature space and you
trains you know by gradient descent you really like train them
she was trained this is an important point that train
the in the implementation is like you know empolis
basically i
a kind of lookup tables which has a lot of tasks like it's a big
metrics of the size and the
the size of the likelihood of feature size you want for
there was five hundred fifty
the number of false you have in the dictionary
and basically the lookup table just return for one one which is an index in
some dictionaries
it returns back the corresponding column in the big metrics but it
and train
you know
by gradient descent
so we have this kind of approach assuming that sigma had the gram matrix has
restricted l one i can value which is well behaved you get out fast convergence
rates and l one estimation error bound
OK so
isabelle said that maybe there journal seemingly papers and so
many people improve things but what's going on here also what
this whole framework is is you just make
the appropriate assumptions to prove what you would like to prove i mean it's a
bit exaggerated but this is not this is in way not that hard i mean
you just make the right definition to restrict the one i can value
and then you crank it out and it's not too much work in way of
course it took some time to see how this can be done but
in a way the real question for me is
how restrictive or such conditions how restrictive it is restricted to one i can condition
and here is one and more technical answer well it's actually weaker than what most
people use usually statistics so far
this is the restricted l two wagon value assumptions due to be queried of tsybakov
so this is what i just presented you before it is slightly weaker and here
is kind of more general picture
i don't know
one imposed that you understand that in detail but the picture should give somehow the
grand view of what's going on
so there's lots a huge literature in high dimensional statistical inference and you see in
this picture here are various assumptions and various implications k and there's a tendency from
the left to the right so the left or strong assumptions on the right are
the weak assumption just if you look at this graph right and way on the
left is the restricted isometry property this is come this time i mean this is
great work but it's very restrictive assumptions
OK this is in compressed sensing i think many people work with the restricted isometry
property but it's just much more restrictive than what people have worked out now for
the lasso in linear models your other assumptions representable welcomed assumptions and then way out
here is this compatibility restricted l one i can assumption
so it seems to be a weak assumption but nevertheless i mean that's not really
fully convincing you want to know i mean it's really what's going on in practice
does it hold
at least approximately in practice
and the first thing is it's not checkerboard it's impossible to check it you would
need to go
you would need to know your true active safety issue we can take the assumptions
in statistics i mean you cannot check with a linear model is correct or not
i mean some people quite interesting like you did skinnier offski to come up with
checkable assumptions is nice so you have the design matrix lexicon shake the assumptions are
fulfilled but
the checklist sumptions are substantially stronger non technical assumptions so there's is a trade-off here
and here is kind of justification why we think this restricted i one i value
assumption is kind of reasonable in practice and in the following scenario you say OK
you xis
in your matrix they have been sampled as i i d roads
so you say x one xn the rose in your matrix they are i i
have mean zero that's not the restriction to have the covariance structure sigma
so sick most of population covariance structure of you're IID sampling for the matrix
and now you assume
that the l one restricted i value holds for u sigma for the population covariance
that's an issue
but here the end has
the end is not the parent anymore this is there's no sample size involved in
this anymore
it's just the p
times p matrix so we don't know with high dimensional not the relation into pieces
lost it peter by p matrix and i just want to know whether it p
by p matrix is reasonable
and so we assume actually it has a well behaved restricted one i can values
the specic the population six
and that's OK i mean sometimes even you could and p matrix has well behaved
i can about is if you take it templates matrix
it has well behaved i can values even if p he goes to a million
if you take a correlation it has a well behaved i can so we kind
of thing it's not too unreasonable to say that the population sigma has reasonably behaved
restricted in one i could use
and then you need some moment conditions its for example including the gauss in case
and then again
the sparsity principle
if we assume that the number of
active variables in the linear model is in this regime not growing faster in square
over log p
then you can come up with this bound with high probability so then
you're empirical drama matrix has also well behaved restricted i one i can values it's
just loosing factor here
from my view this is maybe the best justification why this is restricted eigenvalue assumption
kind of holes in practice if you believe this kind of scenario in this part
of the regime
it holds with high probability
OK so this was kind of my theory block
a summary
for the last so
so for fixed design linear models
if you make known design assumptions and all they can as crazy as possible
and you have a mild assumption on your ear at it's long
you get
and if the slow rate of convergence for prediction so for prediction you can do
the job and you can actually get consistent prediction if it is sparse
the fact to murder property two is if discomfort ability conditional is restricted one idea
about condition holds
four year gram matrix
and mild assumption on here
that's really not a big issue
and you get fast rate for prediction
so i'm going to talk about
alternating direction method of multipliers and i just to give you a rough idea of
what you what
what i'm going to use the title what the talk is going to be
i'm going to kind of like a tutorial
it's going to be sort of the background i know there are people in this
room you know
actually way more than
what what i'm going to talk about
in this talk so i apologize to them
some of them
actually even came willingly i don't know why but there there are here
but not for the others is just supposed to be an introduction to
two one two one method for
for doing
distributed optimisation and we will get that now to show the simplest of all of
this is taken from something that's much longer but still kind of tutorial in nature
and it's one of these foundations and trends of booklets it's everything is available online
i mean including source code for every example you'll see and things like that
o and this is a joint work with with with the bunch of co-authors and
in fact i should say
this is mostly work from the seventies
and in fact it could be argued to have come from in front of you
could trace it to the fifties so so this is also
so what's the goal
the goal is i mean you really want to do something like arbitrary scale optimisation
so and you know the most of them in the most obvious example
certainly for everyone here is to do
machine learning and statistics with huge datasets i mean that's that's that's obvious
but actually there are many other applications so
not all optimisation problems are machine learning once an example of another one would be
dynamic optimisation on large scale network
to take one example
yes you can take of electricity dispatch i mean just to take one so in
maybe like thirty one hundred generators
the schedule in fifteen minute intervals for twenty four hours so
for generator you have to work out one hundred numbers
that's still that's not bad i don't know what we're up to that's like thirty
thousand variable it's it's still
i mean it it's not a small problem but it's not huge however all of
that has to happen over network with about five thousand nodes and maybe fifteen thousand
there are variables for the power flow every edge that network is capacity aided and
guess what now you have a really big problem
i mean bigger than in fact anyone can handle by the way the lights to
come on in california so you might ask how sets off in itself in an
ad-hoc way
they they alternate between going back and forth between sort of network optimization scheduling generators
and they go back and forth a couple of times and usually works and the
lights come on the next california so much mostly i should say OK
now the approach is going to be decentralised optimisation and so the idea is that
you have different devices processes agents workers threads whatever you want to call it different
entities computing entities
the according to solve large problem by passing relatively small messages in fact that's actually
an important point here is that this is this is not going to be something
like implementing stochastic gradient descent on
a data set or something like that where lots of data is flowing all over
the place
i mean
that these things are optimized for that so that's fine this is given this is
in contrast to the idea is to get a relatively small messages and a fair
amount of heavy lifting is going to be done at each worker node and relatively
small messages are gonna fly that's going to be the the idea and obviously this
it's gonna the math doesn't matter but it did operate at many levels right so
this could be
this could be something like this could just be
how to take you can have multiple threads and just take advantage of different causes
could be something operating data centre could be g seven you could target GP using
electric stuff now i i won't even talk about that but there are lots of
so here is the outline
so i'll go away back in history and actually the first two sections are history
well maybe history and helps a little bit this is just the set up for
the method we're going to talk about so it should be maybe review for most
OK so start with dual decomposition
that's that's what you want to solve this
convex optimisation really minimize the convex function subject to some equality constraints and see if
all the lagrangian
which basically says you're going to allow
the equality constraint to be violated and you have a residual
and you have dual vector price vector
and you can interpret this is something like a a payment either to or from
it either like a charge or subsidy depending on the sign
four what happy what happens if you violate the the constraints
if you minimize in this in this framework over x
not sure what you like yourself to violate the constraints but you either pay or
are paid for through this dual variable y to to get the dual function
you then i mean this is the dual function that's always concave and if you
maximize the dual function of all goes well the maximizer is in fact the solution
of this that they're like they're actually details there and not just little baby technical
details because in fact for some of the problems you might like to solve like
linear programs this scheme fails utterly
right so these are not just sort of little mathematical details the things that make
this not work but you with enough
assumptions you know one being like f is strong is you know has minimum
curvature something like that this method works
so how would you
how do you how to maximize the
the dual function
you reduce the gradient method
or in the case when differentiable be subgradient methods and so you would calculate gradient
and make a step in that direction these are positive steplengths well the gradient
of that
the dual function is nothing but the residual
so the algorithm that looks like this is called dual as and and this is
maybe if maybe from the sixties but probably people knew it in in moscow in
the fifties or something like that and
so i mean that's where all that's role this comes from and to the dual
ascent method looks like this and this should remember because you be seeing this for
the rest of us our OK so it looks like this you take this that
lagrangian you fix the price vector dual vector new minimize over x
the minimizer x you calculate the residual but if the residuals are you quit because
you your optimal you stop
OK if it's not zero you update the price the dual vector in fact by
some positive number times the residual and that's it
so that's it then it's got other names in economics you call this the like
attached on more procedure something like that or price adjustment procedure and the idea is
the a x equals b constraint there would be something like a market clearing
and then this is the price adjustment mechanism
and to that so it's got other names and long traditions in in lots of
fields OK
you first of you might ask you know why right why why should you solve
the dual instead of the prime or something like that
and the reason has to do with the composition so
and in a
at all
i mean
i mean it
you are
when you these
this way
right and i mean
and one can
and i
no no
well right
o are
you are you know
and you
i don't want to create a few things to say about single like one tools
of the expected avoid slide
well i agree
what they mean what they say they want to simulated nearly in instantly needing effectively
you just switch
one time
six times
in fact you do it according to some statistical
measure which surround not those around us
in the
what you need to
so-called cooling schedule supposed to simulate what happens when you need a piece of metal
but the theoretical result the simulated annealing always find the absolute optimal solutions
given enough
the words
time but in fact
it really does take a long time so it is not really work although it
it effectively will always
theoretically we always choose alpha expansion model which is similar to the recent rise well
for special better and in the sense
it is because
the following table idea
if you
you have
a bunch of pixels
and they all have some labels around
nine eight
like this one as well
users say OK this time this
pixels chance to sort of switch
so do you want to switch
maybe these all
wrongly labeled
they're all wrong labels together
right so
if you give this pixel chance to switch
people say well
i prefer stay where i am my friends are right
i don't see the film i have
that will be
in fact you increase the cost is one to to move
right because if you want to zero that a lot of weight between all these
functions right but
you know for expansion
these all have the opportunity
switching to get
the whole area of image
the terms that really has been wrongly
label then it'll switch in fact this which was released in the early stages after
large numbers of pixels tend to switch
just try to do them one by one they all held back
by the neighbouring pixels is only the
it's only the
in the process simulated annealing which allows to to give us is not really
very useful these days
final office
function computationally intensive graph cuts but that's not really too bad
after expansion the one pixel is doesn't get linear
the same is also such a thing called
which also doesn't work
taking well
yes it does because i mean you saw that the thing
the land in the image of the behavior of the lambda which is quite narrow
stuff after that
was sufficiently
background going
so he offered
simulated annealing nineteen hours
after expansion ninety six
the better results
what happened just
this for all time to make it
if you could use
cooling schedule wrong when they get
i think this is a million ways
you see that we see is that today was to be i layout
yes or something like
genetic out alternative to things
alpha expansion practice results depend on initialisation very much
this slide initialisation important practice not in theory
just one thing about this with simulated annealing with the cell alpha expansion rather
built for me
first in the middle
the people who did this dynamic graph cuts you can use dynamic graph cuts in
this world
right by
so let's have a look at this is an example of simulated annealing
this is an image which people use a lot
to segment of tree in the garden house
it is given labeled tree got house
it's not
the semantic meaning give to computer
the various steps to really offer
a lot of expansion
often only
one by one
if you do
if you do this often expansion then you're doing alpha alpha equals one two three
et cetera
you've got all these different graphs which is setting up every time
called one iteration through the
the next time you try to think particularly as you approaching final solution
graphs can be very similar
nothing much has changed from one hundred thirteen years techniques
reusing graphs
because they have to change such that
i don't believe that range expansion
and i also think recycle in iteration
so these type improvements to get
using that
more about that
but it does allow you
two years
the self expansion technique in close to real time
on things like the
i think they're getting about six
one frame
every sixty minutes seconds
so it's not like
the second from right
on on his browsing power this is not a very difficult problem browser can write
space a all these solid lines that was the lines
correspond to two things which are parallel to the plane so we have very high
plains here
in some feature space which is non linearly related to this in domain and this
solid lines
on the traces of these have constraints on the domain
so you can see in this situation
almost all the points become support vectors
five gave
there can be situations where even in high dimensional spaces the problem is not separable
and in situations where even if the problem is separable you don't want to understand
separate it precisely
so sometimes you don't want to
you want to a lot of possibilities use training error
so is that it allows the optimisation problem
and there are ways you should tell you about it because if you apply support
the tutorial program you are likely to use
how much he's to about and how it can be used
of the machine
so it is so much to protect the machine
if we a constrained
this can be satisfied so this
after this last year
the slide about the optimisation problem
suppose there is a point which no matter what we do we cannot correctly classified
as an economist correctly classified points
suppose that we cannot change such that this is avoided
this was all this is always negative that means the alpha i would actually increase
without bound so will go to infinity
so that's bad the optimisation problem does not converge
what do we do in this case a naive solution would be what and was
simply place upper bound on the phi just stop going to infinity it would sound
like cheap hack but it turns out that's one of the solutions
only that solution can be motivated slightly differently so you can motivate the solution as
follows you can modify the constraint it OK i can't satisfy this constraint
so i think the constrained limits simpler by subtracting something from the right hand side
this something is XIIA what people call a slack variable but then i don't want
to make excessive use of the slack variables and we want to use them which
is really necessary so i would penalize the slack variables in the objective function so
i will have to turn like this the some of all the slack variables
time some trade constant to the objective function
so it turns out if you
do this and you go through the whole culture value derive you do problems but
you end up with is exactly that you get an upper bound on this
o five variables and the upper bound will be this consistency here
so that's the just the bodies called the c support vector machine
that's the first soft margin SVM was proposed that a slightly more elegant way of
doing soft margin which is called the new support vector machines
in that case the parameter that we use for the trade off is called new
and it has some physical meaning that i'll tell you about
in that case the objective function so the sum of six II's it does not
into the objective function via multiplication of c
but it and has like this sort of like with a constant multiplier and in
addition we have this term here minus new times rule
where rho
it is the variable of the optimisation problem of the primal problem and rho also
enters the constraints in here
so i'll
probably come back to this a little bit later but first well i'll tell you
something more about this from ten new and later on try to explain why this
is the case of explained in the case of regression may lead to a tiny
bit easier to see
but effectively is the same property so what does this parameter new meaning
sorry man remember
we can we can define support vectors as points which have positive i
some being a little bit sloppy here
before i was saying support vectors of points that lines
supporters of points for which the constraints are met as equalities
and the consequent tucker conditions not tell us if a constraint is medicine inequality than
the phi can be nonzero but they can be
in principle that can be support vectors which exactly meet the constraint but which have
a zero five but that would be very coincidental situation
so anyway let's let's consider those points are support vectors from which we have positive
nk is
that is the number of customers
currently sitting at table k
and then the customer and will sit at a new table less labeled as k
plus one with probability
out proportional to alpha
so customer one comes in and says here customer two can either sit at the
first table with probability one of one class alpha all the second table with probability
alpha one class of
so in this case the second customer sits decides to sit with the first customer
and the customer comes in and can decide between sitting at the first table the
second table
and if a customer sits here both customers here fifty six seven eight nine and
so on and what this
yes this is the partitions of the integers one to nine
that simply says that one two and four belong to the same
five in tree belong to the same cluster six belong to its own cluster seven
belong to
to a cluster and line belong to its own cluster
so this basically corresponds to saying that
theta one theta two and three to four takes on the same value
the tree in figure five takes on the same value and so on
so this
this chinese restaurant process basically tells us the clustering structure
on the fetus
if you look at the clustering structure the chinese restaurant process it exhibits count two
properties i guess the first one is rich gets richer
in fact right because if you look at
a class the
that really has lots of
a table that has that really has lots of customers
then the chance that future customers
i will sit on a on the same table is much higher than table that
has very few customers so table that's rich gets richer
so so
what this effect is that there will be a few tables with lots of customers
and then
the the other tables we have
much fewer customers
the second effect is that
as the number of customers goes to infinity the number of tables that used by
customers also goes to infinity
in fact you can show that the expected number of clusters is going to be
on the order of alpha timeslot and
so of course as an goes to infinity and also goes to infinity so over
here we see that the concept the number of
the number of tables depends on the concentration parameter alpha
basically the the larger alpha is the more tables we expect to see
and this is of course
the result of of this thing right so
alpha here is basically
governs the probability that a new customers come in with the new tables and that's
going to create more tables if if alpha is larger
so the
sometimes people call
the the infinite mixture model
that we saw
on saturday a chinese restaurant process mixture model so basically
we can think of this
china the clustering
of the customers into
corresponding to
clustering of data items in two different clusters
in a mixture model and every table is going to correspond to a mixture component
in our model
any questions
it means that
i mean yes but
that there is a difference
a process called the pitman yor process we shall come to at the end of
this lecture where the scaling is not a lot and bus and to the
one parameter d which is between zero and one
we can see actually just use it is willing to use any so any probably
any scheme to sit customers at tables it has to satisfy a property called exchangeability
we shall come to in few slides
yes that's right it should be here less than or equal to n but typically
k is less than that because case on the other lot yes
this different interpretations actually lead to different
inference algorithms
and there are for example
gibbs sampling algorithms based on the chinese restaurant process is that so this is in
fact exactly the same give something other than that we derived last week
but there are also like gibbs something algorithms based on the stick breaking construction
once we have
written down each of the
parameters in g in the following way then we can just say let's forget about
g let's try to do inference where this is going to be are latent variables
and because of the different inference algorithms
can have different
so for example
with the stick stick breaking construction we can derive a variational inference algorithm pretty straightforwardly
by this
i don't know of anybody who has the right to variational inference camp for the
chinese restaurant process
i mean that
because we don't have a problem with people
for use by the way of understanding
the people who who say well this things don't actually give you a density for
the whole g i say features
if you just write down what the density of pi one until pi
OK and also we can also write down the density of the town
the test i want to use it
the test wiki we can write the density but as big k goes to infinity
the is simply gonna
go to what's
zero so
we can't actually read all those the four g itself because there this into objects
is infinite dimensional
six weeks
the polya urn scheme
in fact the first
the first successful MCMC schemes for the dirichlet process is based on the polya scheme
but nowadays people don't actually use it the problem is that it can have
mixes together
two things it makes together the clustering structure on the dirichlet process and the values
assigned to
to each cluster
and that can mixed inference slower so for both the chinese restaurant process and the
so the representation is going to be
and serves two questions one can ask in the world
so which questions what kinds of questions so here's
i mean make precise what's the question
so we can think about uncontrolled system to control systems i mean i think about
control systems for stop and think about controlled system the control system is one that
actually so a question
is essentially of this form
it's about what they use the word future some of the questions and the would
has still mean the same thing request the form action observation action observation action observation
action observation
the sequence of actions and observations
what an answer to a question the answer to the question is
the conditional probability
but you would see the sequence of observations and that question if you take the
sequence of actions in the question
so if i behave according to what the question asks me
what's the probability that see the actions in that
it is part of the question
that's the answer to a question
what i'm going to show you
as of this class of questions contains within it a subset
so define was and is sufficient to model the state of many many interesting dynamical
including the class system model of mdps and pomdps
that's where i'm going
so these questions are going to be entirely expression in observable terms i'm going to
show you that in fact
there is a small number of questions was answers are
a good representation of knowledge about the world
that's michael classes system i'm going to limit myself to the most of the talk
is going to be discrete time
the discrete observations
and finite action systems
MTV's comedy like system OK
so let me what to extract that and we define what i call the system
dynamics vector
so here's the system dynamics vector
basically it has
later on top
all possible questions
i can ask for dynamical system
king case is not clear why using the phrase dynamical system an agent environment interaction
is a dynamical system like it takes an action get an observation takes an action
get an observation of the dynamical system so it's fairly abstract general
what what i have the columns
as the
as the indices to this that there are questions so here's the length one question
all length one questions for bowling two questions for bowling three questions on infinity so
this is an infinite vector
and the answer to the question what are in effect this is the probability the
answer to question one and question to remember questions alternating sequence of actions and observations
so laid out
in this form in exhaustive
explicit conceptual form
all the answers to all questions about the dynamical system
it should be confused as hell of the point of this is the point you
ask me a question or two that i can try and address
so what i'm asserting is that
any dynamical system
will have answers to these questions or equivalently and answering this these filling in this
this conceptual vector specifies the dynamical system
right it's assigning a probability all possible futures
condition making actions
so this is a this is an exhaustive representation of
any discrete time every discrete time
finite action five observation system has this conceptual representations
any dynamical system there's no i'm not placing any constraint system other than finite observation
finite action discrete
any such system will have
and to these questions and i made an exhaustive listing here and it's a one-to-one
so the way the one-to-one mapping between these vectors and dynamical systems
why i am doing this is not going to be clear to a few more
OK so it's one of the make sure you understand what this vector is because
otherwise the next fifteen minutes will be meaningless
please ask me if this is not or actually whenever you feel confused about these
things so all possible futures they may be zero in here
lots of constraints on the entries i'd like to think that the sum to one
and so on
right this is a mathematical construct that IS the system not a model of the
system it is the system OK
or equivalently any exact model of the system should be able to produce or generate
the system dynamics
so what i'm going to do now is to show you a modelling this this
using a pretty representation of states which only one more if you would like to
develop now i'm going to make that into vector
in two infinity by affinity matrix
which goes like this
these are all possible futures
the answer is in the first row to the first row the that you already
seen in the vectors on the previous slide and the first row corresponds to the
number history or the initial conditions for all possible futures on the initial conditions
so what i'm gonna do
is expand this vector matrix by
making the rows all possible pasts
so future the columns
and past are the rose
or histories past history
what's the history history is just the trajectory of action observation that happened so far
right so they are both action observation sequences future and
OK now let me tell you to fill out this matrix
so here's the entry corresponding to the i future and the jet history
this is the
and so the following question what's the probability
of this future given this history
so let's
so the property of its future given the genetic history is probably conditional probability of
seeing the observation sequence in that future given that you take the action sequence in
that future from that history
notice that all the rows after the first or redundant in the sense that they
all computable from the first round by the first row is already a sufficient characterisation
of the dynamical system redundant information but i'm doing this for a very specific reason
that hopefully you'll see just two more slide thirty much like
OK so any dynamical system
and the corresponding system dynamics matrix
different features are different scales so if on
now if you take measures the people and so you know one one one feature
maybe the height another maybe the way to another maybe the strength another maybe
and how the age or whatever all of these you all these quantities are very
different scales and so on normally
norris the variance
sometimes if all the excise the called same type of thing on so for example
if you're taking your work with images and x ij is all the pixels of
different users are on the same scale because they're all pixel intensity values ranging from
zero to twenty five to get the way of this
so after preprocessing
let's talk about how we would find the main axes along which the data there
how we find the principal axes of
so to do that
let me just try to just go one specific example and we formalize the our
here's the training set comprising five examples and has roughly zero mean and variance on
the x one and x two axes of the same as the one
and so
it depends where axes the variation of the data is roughly the the positive forty
five it reacts
so like to do is have my out of can concluded this direction to draw
with arrow u
is this the best direction onto which the projected data so that the axis i
wish my data really varies
so let's think about how we formalise as well
one thing we want to look at is supposed to take axis
this is an easy access onto which i want to project on the quantock to
actually used to capture both the variational data
and which to training set and projected onto this line to get
that said points
you notice that those dots the projections of my training set on the this axis
has very large variance
in contrast if i were to choose on
a different direction let's this is really
falcon the worst direction onto west my data
if i project on my data trying to this access
right then i find that the projections of my data onto the
purple line and it is on the line has much smaller variance than my points
are clustered together much more tightly
one way to formalize this notion of finding the
that the main axis variations of data is a to find a vector you will
like to find a direction you
so that when i project my data into that direction
the projected points very as much as possible so in other words
find finer direction so the one project data onto it projections are
largely are widely spaced out lines
let's see
so i want to find the directions
and on this so reminder never have vector you often one
then the length of a vector x i
project well
the vector x i projected onto you
has length
of course transpose u is the
so the talk is some feature selection in machine learning
i give
basically overview of what's happening in there
and some reasons and so on so
why we do feature selection by dimensionality reduction in general
we can have different reasons we want to improve the performance
to improve the efficiency of the to provide faster predictors that request list information of
the original data which can really be important in some domains were obtaining features is
maybe medical demands so when you when you're getting new examples to test
you would maybe prefer to have less features than the complete set of features
maybe we want to do with dimensionality reduction in order to reduce reduce complexity
of the eleven results
enabling better understanding of what's happening behind there
OK so what are
the common approach is to
that means that reduction in machine learning what we do
we met the original feature space into some other
feature space
and how we get this other feature space in different ways
one way is to select simply select a subset of the original features
and this stock is name is talking about is just the beginning i give bigger
the other ways of course to construct new features
to replace the original features and we heard a lot about that yesterday
we can however also construct new features using some background knowledge
which can be
general background knowledge like no numeric data you can do some of the two features
you can do x or two features make apply some general functions
ignoring the domain of the problem
or you can use the background knowledge
which is connected to the domain
it can be possibly also provided by the user as a function you know saying
this is how the function works
or it can be domain specific for instance on text documents
what you can do is you know it's text you can use language parser talked
a noun phrases or some other kind of constructed features
or you can toward clustering
based on the data and then use clusters
as new features
and these new features constructed features
can be used either in this instead of the original features so just use that
or they can be used as additional features so you actually in larger feature set
and then of course
after that enlargement what you can do is apply feature subset selection averaging features generate
more features
then the feature subset selection
and hope
of the new features are going to get in this subset and helping
solving the problem
OK so a simple example
what we do with feature subset selection so the rest is about
feature subset selection
if we have a simple domain five will the features
and assume that
the classes correlated directly with the two
features is or f one or f two
and after three
feature trees negation of two
and the five thousand four also related by negation
so what would be the optimal feature subset if we do that
based on this knowledge which of course in real situations we don't have about the
we would say
optimal subsidies either f one f two
which completely describe the class or f one f three
since f threes negation of f two
so you can get an idea of the optimisation space for finding the feature subset
is actually
all the possible feature subsets
two IDF
and we have to search through the space is some clever way of course
this is an example if have more features our search space how it looks in
the movie between feature subsets when searching
and there are different approaches common approach is to search in the space
the most well-known two are either former called for selection start from an empty set
of features
and move
through the space
adding more features or backward elimination when you start with a complete set of features
then remove some features in hopefully smarter way
so for selection and there is the variant forward stepwise selection
well you move by adding or removing the feature one at the time so that
they are really going to miss
backward elimination
removing features
one at the time or you can also enable adding or removing at each step
and then random mutation that
you start with the random data set a random subset of feature actually from the
previous picture
and then
you make a random change or some other kind of adding removing features
and of course we move to the search space and evaluate
so that's the the big stories now how we about it
so there are again different approaches to evaluation
there is a
simple family of filters
use for feature subset selection
well developed asian function is independent of the learning algorithm that is going later to
use this feature subsets
there are so-called wrappers
thirty evaluations
the function of the feature subset is actually using the machine learning algorithm
that is
to evaluate the subset and and once we find
feature subset
it's going to be used by the same machine learning algorithm so it's kind of
taking machine learning group them into little wrapping around it
there are embedded approaches
have feature selection happening inside the learning algorithm during learning
and there is a variant of scene of lucas
which i called sympathy filters there's
the growth inhibitory factor
so an important growth inhibitory factor is for example tgfb
and teacher better works exactly the opposite
ptgs because it is the signal which is present extracellular space and tells the cell
it should stop proliferating
and therefore TGF beta if it's present in large amounts in this part of the
cell cycle
if the cell experiences in large amounts that will influence the cell not to move
through the restriction point conversely if it's absent then obviously ptgs can have the undiluted
tensions of the cell
and therefore what i'm trying to convey by this is to tell you that the
cell balances both its growth stimulate tree and growth inhibitory signals that is receiving from
extracellular space
decisions are weighed and finally down here
but still make the the binary decision to go ahead or not to go ahead
depending on historically how many of these factors it recruited in this specific window of
recall as we said last time that once a growth factor like pgf goes to
the plasma membrane it encounters a receptor on the surface
let's say we call the pgf receptor
and i'll just like this for the moment
it's a transmembrane proteins the extracellular domain is on the outside
and i'm trying to copy the EGF receptor here
for reasons that will become apparent in moment
and what happens is that ptgs which for example can be itself a dimer it
can be a dimeric growth factor so it has two distinct subunits in
they're both essentially equivalent to one another but it is time eric
and this dynamic structure PDF allows it to bind to growth factor receptors simultaneously
well why is that interesting
it's interesting for the following reasons
transmembrane pgf receptors like the ones i've indicated right here
there are anchored in the plasma membrane because there's a portion of their sequence writin
here in the transmembrane domain indicating here in the orange
which contains highly
hydrophobic amino acids
and those hydrophobic amino acids obviously love to be in this hydrophobic environment of the
lipid bilayer and they but they don't they have no effect at all on whether
pgf receptors can move can traverse in the plane of the plasma membrane so the
pgf receptors can move across the face of the plasma membrane these ones can move
to the right and left but they're not going to come in or out
because they anchored in this lipid bilayer by the structure of hydrophobic amino acids
now what happens interestingly
g the dimeric receptor binds to two of these pgf receptor molecules which as i
told you have lateral the freedom to translate lateral and clean the plasma membrane
what happens is that it will bind to these receptors and in so doing it
it will pull the two receptor molecules
next to one another previously they were just floating around the plane plasma membrane having
bound their ligand
recall that pdf is considered elegant for the pdf receptor
having it will cause these two
receptor molecules
two now becomes
the become very close to one another so read right now like this
now these two receptor molecules that look like this they're right the cheek-by-jowl
they're right next to one another
and this has an interesting consequences
of great interest here is the effect this has on the ability of the PD
jeff receptor to emit signals into the cytoplasm because we call that the endgame here
is always how to
how does the intracellular part of the cell know that this there's been an encounter
with the growth factors in the extracellular space
and this signal emitting power pdf receptor
comes from the fact that once
these two
domains are brought together
each of these two domains is able to modify the other and change the other
i e
so a modified subunit b
subunit b modify subunit in how is this modification achieves
for the for it is achieved in the following way
the this domain which i've been calling i've just writing like this is a rectangle
is actually a catalytic agent it's actually a tire seen
kind of certain enzymes
and the terracing kind is is an enzyme that takes the gamma phosphate from ATP
stress syndrome and if you talk to these guys when the lights go off they
think of you know i'm now
vulnerable back on my guard post and i don't know what's going to happen and
is much larger and people post-traumatic stress syndrome so he was the phenomenon that independent
condition the light was on for a very long time and the questioners will be
dependent on the image below the bed nucleus
the punchline is the for the first time we found the bed nucleus was critical
for this for now
so this is the most complicated slide you can see
there are three groups of animals they have little can so little tubes to allow
us to infuse drugs directly into the brain
and now we're looking at the magnitude of started going from the dark to the
light so that's the magnitude of light lighthouse startled the yellow curves are the control
condition and so the different groups of animals that have cameos in either the bayes
lateral amygdala projects to both the bed nucleus and the central the central nucleus or
the bed nucleus
and what we found is that in activation in the basal lateral block this light
enhanced are
to our amazement inactivation of the central nucleus had no effect and more to our
amazement when we activated the bed nucleus it totally blocked this effect
so we wondered well maybe they can also just in the wrong place so we
actually took the same animals and now we took a short light three second light
and we repair that with the shock
and we asked what happens when we activate them
and here is now fear potentiated startle that is the increase in starling the presence
versus the absence of the light that previously been paired with a shock to we
activate the bayes ll we block that like lesion work only activate the central nucleus
we block that but like deletion work and inactivated the bed nucleus we didn't so
we get this double dissociation between inactivation the central nucleus walking fear but not this
longer duration effect
and vice versa for the bed nucleus of the stretch miles
so this fact number one
fact number also
in this sort of schema than
we don't understand it at least at that time but the difference here
is we have very explicit q three second like here to diffuse q it's too
late some twenty minutes its long-term versus short-term it's on condition worsens condition and this
is sort of an inherently less predictable compared to highly predictable situations
well it turns out that there's a peptide called corticotropin releasing hormone that course is
known for activity in the hypothalamus pituitary axis but is also found in very high
concentrations in the amygdala the bed nucleus of the street remarks
and importantly if you confuse this directly into the brain it produces a whole constellation
of behaviors that look very much like fear anxiety so there's an increase in plasma
norepinephrine happen after an increase in heart rate blood pressure and respiration
they're angiogenic effects anxiety like effects in these animal tests
there's a decrease in feeding and sexual behavior pain sensitivity there's a big increase in
startle and other anxiety like effects so the question is is where CRF acting
so is a really important question because you have a single peptide that can produce
this whole pattern behaviors and the question is where active
and the punchline once again is attacked in the bed nucleus of the street from
mouse anatomy amygdala or least the way we've been doing these experiments technical point that
get into later on just one piece of evidence for groups of animals here
we implant them with the cannula to allow us to directly put this chemical into
the brain
and that we give them a pre-test so this is just start all amplitude there
now for example
atomic propositions
it is hard to do a or
it's going to rain tomorrow
and x less than zero x equals you and so on
now in propositional logic we
i don't really look at the particle individuals in state like it for example
so we not
formalise x
this is
we just take
the statement x
equal zero as
atomic state which we can analyse
that's why we're going to abstract abstract is
atomic propositions yes you
well that
so when i say property propositional variables i mean
it is an abstract and of an atomic propositional
now we what we really case just how
propositional composing how we calculate the truth value of the compass
basically problem logic is just starting
composite truth
i understand the logical
connect you have to standard
the called and for y and so on
and then
one of the important problems in
propositional logic is the so-called satisfiability problem
so if i gave you a complex formula
assign truth values to the atomic propositions are true
they composed an industry
so this is the
the language or
usually called the syntax of propositional logic
now we defined inductively
the class of all propositional
so we've seen that proposition five
this is an abstract in tonic statements
from that
and i will introduce
logical connectives
actually six come true and false
so there is another e connected true and false
the traditional symbol is as you you can see that it
shows symbolises called top part is called but
and and then you have this
wait symbol
three percent
the conjunction
and this is the symbol represents you know
its meaning is obvious in the
and then you have this arrow
three percent implication
and then the formula is just composed by
propositional variables and connected
on the context
so you are familiar with
he met notation of the
you probably learned
automata theory
i can just right
the inductive definition is one line which says that
after is the classifier that is the probability that two of negation
and or
legends always struggle with this to the concept of syntactic semantic
the syntactic
describe the form of state this is how write down
semantics describe to me
let's say you are interested in
know what can infer from the form of the state
so is valid in all possible patients
for example if i write
first two miles three
you probably understand immediately what is
so error
for most of you it's probably very obvious that describes the operation
there's really no
rule universal law that says you have to write this statement is
again for the same
represent a number
number of
alphabet a
one is free
in one and two is a two
so what
ladies tend to get syntax is very
relax we saw
particular symbols doesn't have fix
well apart from standard
thank you
unlike his investment
he died
right away i
so we'll see this
this is
two concepts
very often so soundness we're interested
this two questions cause soundness completeness sound just means that
you take the form of logical statements you do some operations at
you get another
logical state
for example i can confirm this
equation two
things like three three
by simply
this expression
how does this operation preserves the meaning that we suddenly assigned numbers
this is a sound
on the completeness is
semantically valid logical statements
the proof by just purely syntactic transformation this is
really at the heart of automated reasoning
found computer science
as i said earlier
we can assign for that two
complex formed by breaking down
the truth value of simple form
assuming that we know the truth value of atomic
rules so to compute the probability all the time
the marginal probability this
clock here are probably next so these quantities here
more generally
this is the
this calculation in which for the values of variables given that the prior is called
inference and when
many many variables inference can be called
which in itself requires an entire album to this misleading here is really just simple
o ratio using phrases just great britain but there's many many many things you're referring
the process of writing down is serious itself requires replication
so when we
talk about
in these cases we can solve it exactly
so let's go through the circle
example of gas mixtures as for piece of cake going to make specific
choices of gaussians and then you can see the responsibilities involved evaluating the density of
the point x under each models and compute the ratio of how likely is it
multi by how
so i think this model the mixture of gaussians as two separate things work
if you given data point
any way this marginal probability
don't want make sure that
i think is not going to
so here
in this picture i put it up here and knowledge is good
one of the best in sample data availability
here's what about minutes not
but you can also have a mixture of gaussians as a machine that converts data
points each point on the simplex
it data point two
distribution over clusters and in that case the posterior distribution is sort of like clustering
so the
i really like your
make sure that the engine converts that
four distribution which says nine on this
zero five boston to
his first
these models can be used in many ways one is to evaluate marginal probability that
in some sense often what's interesting about reading
this is serious problem later so the traditional view UN statistics is very important nuisance
and the only reason why it should be something that
in order to compute the relative margin that
but sometimes you actually care about variables
you want to do something like clusters
or for a copy like those so don't do
variables just irritating things is always want really should think about
model introduced intentionally because we
they like
and to assure that we will be true and where i some that cases really
want more
three cases reviewed university itself before so you should be looking for this is like
eating vegetables sometimes in the seventies
OK so just to continue in this example we can extend this to mixture of
linear regression experts
so here we have given y
we have an input x
n conditioned on x y has the distribution mixture of linear forms
you basically
in these mixing proportion of actually depends on x
so that means that which
component case select is a function of
the input variables x
you can think of this as
imagine that
a teacher for
and then the principal of the school in two thousand features
the teacher
i want to make it appear like classifiers
so what does it do well when principle as question the feature space
i with my students
you know the answer to that question
teachers college assume that they know the answer in this case audience
right so the teacher is playing the role of the scaling function l
the future works question which is input x and make a decision about the distribution
over students k
we're going to be able to get the right answer and
you one
and the reason that so cleverly select students
and here's the classes
the is
you know of anyone in
question think this is gating function is designed to select the expert that is best
suited for that
the scaling function
many many forms the simplest form is to just put in year just rational softmax
regression with
so the conditional
distribution is
you what the next mixture
and this is
this is of the k two
probability of getting closer to a given the input x which small has a log
linear on
so that's exactly
here this is just the start lines show
your probabilities of selecting model zero one max and in the one-dimensional case because it
this is what
for any given
so that you should really be using that
try and apply the machine learning for instead of using a box we should be
trying to get more information should be getting better registration and hopefully
a lot of stuff to talk about was for you guys to have a look
at that
so i'm moving on
another thing that really difficult is identical
so that in this is the real real top one it's called
we refer to this as the
generic one problem and essentially it's
it's very very difficult at the moment
i will discuss footfall which topped things when we just wanted all boxes that what
you can boxer interface you know pretty good job you can come to get good
job generically across crosses places like this guy alexander downer x
foreign minister yes and
and madeleine albright and then are more
but anyway so these are collected generic places and things and we can do a
good job sometimes box detectors but if we have something that's benson so something that
we can exhaustively search of already introduced this term it becomes a lot harder and
we've been actually a lot of research in this slightly and we've got all kind
of some really exciting results we can actually do a lot better now
city in from for the linear perspective there are two problems in registration
the first problem is essentially the length
so how do i learn an object model that satisfactorily discriminate between
the object and the image background so that's that's what this problem and of course
i mean you guys have been sitting through all these courses and a lot of
really interesting information you has been gathering as well
kind idea how to do that so far not to do that
why are you here and sometimes asked myself the same question but the with the
with the three things apart whatever this is an important part of how to effectively
evaluate the compliance across all possible warp
and as you come to go through
this question and this question is inherently tied together
so it seems to make some assumptions here
you constrain yourself here seems to make some assumptions here
we constrain yourself here so
being ignorant of one
or the other
severely limits you also severely limits research into and the idea is afford so
if anything else you think about registration that's what i want you to go because
the code come to go home with the basically winning everything are inherently hard and
i can't separate the two are going to consider both questions at the same time
we will come to cover the landing landing kind of going to go the feeding
because i think you guys have a lot of learning already will go back to
the learning is as i go through
in the end
you will
to that we will actually get challenge one was so happy we deal with all
the variations on an object can undergo a set lighting pose clusions and even now
i've been talking about pose lighting things this so all of the time in vs
video sequences people and not just going to talk places so
faces are coming to my heart but cushions happen all the time and other objects
like if you come to my talk on the whole
if you got someone walking in the walking behind the house things get it all
the time or for everyone knows my face gets included nuisance variables so things like
care like we're actually putting a a demo together for a face tracking system in
the just for japanese car
and it's it's weird because we were training at all these places of often online
database that we have
a different kind of his come back it's kind of like to talk about it
seems like the current histone japan is going to have people's here over the topic
and its playing havoc with the system because all these people what a like people
have this this coming over here you really have to kind of know how to
deal with this and have a good time to do this so but it's often
difficult to define the nuisance variables two so you have to have a good way
of generalizing things and also place of
if you have any questions if you guys something is unclear or from that this
makes sense to stop me
ask me
the more
and the challenge to use the fitting
i'm just going to show an example here so if you have a six forty
four eighty image and this so i'm just searching my what function this translation and
and i'm searching say different scales so far different scales here
one twenty four twenty four thirty six forty eight sixty seventy two
and sliding every pixel synonymous that every pixel i still just for single image need
to classify twenty four thousand subwindows to classify