of that have best benefit cost ratio
so this is the idea
this also won't work so optimizing this can also fail arbitrarily badly and here i
have an example
we can try to go through right so if we are given some budget and
we consider just locations right on one location has cost epsilon the other one has
the patient b
and we only have one cascade one of breaking news network right four one four
four placing a sensor that this one will get two epsilon award and first place
in the second location to get the reward we now if we compute the cost-benefit
ratios we get so the first one the concepts we have we have reworked two
and the second one
we have this cost benefit cost ratio of one so we select sensor one
and then we won't be able to afford sensitive to
and now we so we get reward to have some instead of instead of being
now we send exception to zero and we get arbitrarily bad or we got an
an arbitrary away from this optimal what we could get the fit in our model
this is again so it seems like a bad news but the question is now
what if we take best of both solutions
and so this is what we do
the idea is that we have resort music we had like two pairs greedy algorithm
solve two separate problems in the first we obtain one solution that just use the
benefit cost greedy the one i just introduced and then the second instance separately around
the unit cost greedy so we just we optimize as there is no cost to
the census but at end we the solution whatever we exhausted our much OK so
define solution just the best of both and what is good
or what they can ask now is how far is this from unknown or optimal
solution that we cannot compute right
what they show is that if one uses this type of algorithm we are we
are we lose one-half right so we have one half whatever had before away
from from documents so this is this is this is very good news so right
now we cannot guarantee that we can't fail to badly
OK so this is the first part of the good news and the second part
of the good news about that you know is how to scale up this how
to make it go faster
before i do that i just want to do something i want to believe the
talk about something else that i won't go into much so this traditional mound there's
us how far from optimal is we would going to be before even we see
the data around got right so you before and we know that there is at
most thirty three sixty thirty six percent away
from from this optimal solutions we don't know any questions can we do better and
in the paper we have this to we show that we can get a much
better estimate how far is our solution from the optimal solution
and the idea that the reason for the intuition that we exploit is that this
marginal gains are getting smaller and smaller with the placement size so given this you
can sort the first you can estimate how how good could the best possible solution
to this gives you in practice much much tighter bounds
what i mean by this is decreasing marginal gains is the following because this will
also help us in scaling up the god so this someone says submodularity property guarantees
as that this marginal benefits will decrease with the solution size and this means that
if we have a particular if we are considering placing particular stands me and this
is the reward people get sorted now
if we decide to place some other sensor and then again going to consider
says again what will happen is that this one can only get smaller
and this is this is known as a lazy evaluations and this is what we
explore exploit OK so here is here is what we do right so again we
have the same the the same network in the same year considering placing some set
of sensors and what we do is again the first going to evaluate rewards for
all the sense that we would get and we still degree right so we pick
the best one in place what we do now is
this this the rewards are now
invalid but what we do is we sort of our senses by by this rewards
or gained from previous timestep and we will go and evaluated evaluate them in this
order so
we go and evaluated the and again sort
we go
we evaluate the
now our new values reward
this is this new melody what is larger than the reward of the from the
previous step and we know that if you would go to evaluate it
the this area could only showing this means that we already have the best got
so we can go and place b again and this will now be right so
this may be saved a lot we have to go and i know you evaluate
all the marginal gains but at every step we only keeping evaluating them until we
should someone who who is invalid and instead has what is the what you already
OK in this way we can we can do this much much faster and show
some timings late
so OK this was the idea and now
i could go and show some experimental results so
it must be
i would say
we have
estimate how couples can become a hub can be estimated that was to come
that's that's a different so that's a different question so one question is how to
do this faster and the other questions how to how so i go around this
algorithm i know i don't get optimal can i get some kind of idea how
far am i from this
something that i can't even compute
and then we also have a way to do that gives much better estimate how
far away are you from from optimal than what was previously previously not because i
did not know i i don't want to go too much into
the i mean the the deal old deal the result basically even without looking at
the data they get the guarantee what we do is we look at the data
and this gives much better estimate in practice OK
OK so now i briefly about the experiments so we have two case studies one
is on basically it's all have for both of you have been need to find
the data set where we have real propagation data right so you don't need to
assume any monetary can just go and measure how the news propagate through the network
and here we have a blog network where we have we were growing books blocks
for one year and then we were identify how does information spread through the blogosphere
right some blogger says something and on other refer to it and this spreads and
we are asking
which which blogs should be in the second
cases this water distribution network
well we have again a real city water distribution network and some some way to
to compute how would the
however the disease spread through the network
and again the question is as i said where to place sensors to detect disease
outbreaks quicker
so first of all setting the context clearly
statistical learning theory is something i need to put in context with other attempts to
understand the system is so i spend most of this lecture looking at that
then move into the basic
pac ideas probably approximately correct i think what the acronym stands for
and the proof
and again here i will be looking at some of the detailed proof because i
don't want to
just to give you a series of results i want to try and show you
how those results
i arrived at where the proofs are instructive in themselves so it is my intention
to try and look approves and see how they work this the key ideas how
they work
so i'll be looking
at those little bit more detail
that will lead us to
the sort of the point at which
if you like learning theory was that when suddenly support vector machines broke on the
scene and were performing extremely well and the theory that was at that point developed
was completely
unable to explain their performance
and i think that was a critical moment where if you like theory and practice
were completely
with each other and i think that was very
challenged the theory community to try and
if you like agree that theory to match practice and that's what i'll talk about
next which is this idea of real valued function classes and the margin
that will
hopefully be the point i reach the end of today so that the for lectures
and then
starting tomorrow will look at more modern
two in statistical learning theory concentration and stability
and then rademacher complexity
and its main theorem
and on the some applications again i would hope to cover
the next slide guitar
sort of eighteen of
what i would hope consensus is just giving a re capitulation some extent of what
i said at the beginning that some thoughts on why
fearing what it can do for you
the basic techniques with some deference to history but not a strict
historical sequence
insights into the proof techniques and statistical learning approaches
tomorrow complete proof of the SVM
found using rather rademacher approach i think somehow taking you through the whole thing you
know it's like climbing everest something outside but it can give you an idea of
what the
different components that are needed in the proof
OK so that is what i'm hoping to do what i want to include it
is the most general results by any stretch
i certainly don't i certainly won't include a complete history
i will be looking at an analysis of bayesian inference
typically that is
you outside statistical learning theory until recently when
the development of the PAC bayes
which sort of links the two
but i came will be covering that
and i live in this case is giving the advanced section of this course
i will be looking at the PAC bayes results
and also had this idea of local rademacher complexity so developing on from the
rademacher stuff all be talking about tomorrow
OK so hopefully seen i would welcome you to
ask questions and gain give feedback about speed
and appropriateness of what i'm saying
so please just try your hand
you are trying to stop him
so i'm going to start with an attempt to
by the way is point that i can usefully
just that see
closer to some
mediterranean area they have problems with force for a lot of force have
this appears because of that
in one way to do this is to use the
sensor networks
to deploy them throughout the forest or some critical area
and detect
five when it's really starts
so that you can react quickly
you will you will lose probably a small portion of forest but not everything
and this is something that because there was a nice them what one or three
previous workshops with the
all the trees and grass and all the sensors and we had even by almost
started the
so that's the so there's of proof of concept is to show that OK yes
you can use of this technology is not a commercial product but if somebody
is really keen and see business case can
take that improve it and make it
commercial stuff
smart road monitoring that's a big area
so if you enable all the cars to interact with each other and talk to
each other so you can get information from the car in front of you what's
happening so you can stop before
you would stop otherwise or like just coming this morning there with myself and
one woman scratch my mica
because she was trying to squeeze between me and the end of the road and
it was not possible
so if you had some of these sensors maybe she would have stopped before going
luckily enough the scratches on this small so it's to be problem
then some of the
health care scenarios of fitness areas where people can where some of the ECG or
blood pressure or even
some sensors that can analyse your so at hand based on that they can do
certain things and conclude what's wrong with you are what you should do
and then you can use it while running doctor can monitor ECG and if you
are preparing to run the marathon
and actually to five kilometres your heart rate goes
twenty two hundred fifty or something and you get some heart disorder then they will
say OK
forget about what monotone go play chess or something
if you ever find there say OK just continue this way or this way and
then you will eventually you will be able to run
one of the colleges of always interesting thing and waste management is another application that's
of interest
but you can monitor all these waste dumps
and to monitor the
temperature inside them and to some of the chemicals that or some chemical processes happening
and then you can react and maybe
and do something about that if you notice that some chemical reactions will happen that
can cause some environmental pollution
more and more applications these are just a few examples and
we can i can probably stand here and talk about these are application for whole
you want examples complete list
so that's wireless sensor networks and some of the applications
and then when talking about what it says metrics you talk about
isolated system so you have to waste management application i put my says there
and in the summer in my house i monitor from IPC what's happening there
or i put some usages as on me and my doctor sees what's happening with
so that's
kind of
isolated systems
with the internet of things
the idea is to blend all these publications are all the systems so yes i
put those sensors in the waste
for the military ways but i want everybody to be able to discover those sensors
and to use that information or maybe some other purpose completely
maybe they have to pay me for using those sensors maybe they will have to
ask me first for some credentials yes
the idea is that you connect all these different devices smart devices that are called
and make them accessible by anybody who has a proper authorization to use them
and then to start building application services on top of that
so x has this fifty billion connections by twenty twenty vision saying that it's OK
not just sensors and actuators but there will be
fifty billion
connections to all sorts of different machines including coffee machines and refrigerators
temperature sensors and everything else
and the number of machines
is much higher than the
number of people living so obviously from the
and you need to check every path from here to here to see whether that
he's blocked
is separated out
yes true
it's head had so these will have a problem with
if we observed these and these and you need to ask whether these
two and the separation
we need to study every path from here to here
so this is one thing
this page is blocked
by x five
because it's head to tail node which is absurd
and the first condition is met
now this pattern here
it's another possible path from x three two x six
but this fact is also blocked
because x one is so
and this is the tail to tail nodes so is also
the first condition
now the remaining pair is this here
is this bad block
this but not working
because x y is in the conditioning set
but its head to head
so when i observed x five
i created connection between x two and x three remember the example i gave you
if i see a child with brown eyes i know that both parents can not
be able one
right so if i hope so this child immediately create some
dependency between these viable
this that becomes law
so x three and x six are not the separate when x one and x
five ir are sort
he is
so again
the previous example OK up
a block at that
note that the point is that
this pattern is is not one
this smart also
it's correct because
these head-to-head nodes
is not so
if there is one was not observed respect would be block
but he is absurd
defining a blog that
containing none of these two affirmations one of them
one of them is to be true
containing all
so basically in this case
only the first holes in this case is only the first hold
in this case non hold
it's not the separate i mean this concept a bit tricky but it's essential y
because the concept of the separation
turns out to be exactly
the concept of
independent in
directed graph
we will see
so basically
we will see some
it's interesting results which is basically
the problem we have is written
that's all i will need to read write it here
i have the following result
this is really important
this is the first of the two most important slides
of the course
the first is that there is that you can prove which is the following
factorisation implies conditional independence
so basically
the attention to detail
you have a probability distribution that factorises
according to a directed acyclic graph so it's not bayesian network probability distribution
factorizes according to
children given parents
and if you have
a b and c which are disjoint subsets of nodes such that a is d
separated from b by c
then that distribution satisfies the conditional independence a
independent given c
look at what this is saying
this is connecting a concert from
pure graph theoretical concept
with the concept of conditional independence
offer probability distribution OK
but this will get counted twice
in the feature vector
so we went
good good fun at the moment we're not talking and talking
and this method is designed for translational invariance
i'll come in in the second to deal with the fact that the car might
be rotated so the the moment there is this problem you mentioning because when the
model is learned one is recognised there is only one orientation
it will find this over here you say
they were only vote on these two positions for the moment because both tracking and
assume no rotation
yes what this is the last week of
this is not much publicity using its is awaiting on
this point
that's the whole point in the next
but i don't think it's so much geometric smearing though i think about this myself
but i think that these these links from
models are
a fictional very that in your voting
three to four
it's just that i mean there's is some gathering
here you can see that
this region here which lies inside as well as like adaptive half so there is
some smearing that's allowed because you you're saying all of these contribute some maximum and
that decide that the smearing depends on the size of the
square that you you you cluster
astro very
you you count votes over
the system parameters and that goes in the opposite model or not
OK so i'm going move on to one of model which is in one of
the method which is in this class
which is a policy norman method in two thousand two
now this is actually
it was designed for segmentation but more given as a recognition
apologies for six like this differs slightly in the way the parts i got some
of the details but for small they start off with segmented images in fact they
have an alpha mask for each image they know what's the foreground background
and they learn
these what they call fragments which are variable size rectangles from both the the
training positive examples and from the negative examples
and they decide which fragments are important using mutual information
this is slightly different and it is still the same idea is in the end
you and you have a set of segments which should capture the shape of the
the object of interest
the parts which occur in two interesting and their goal is to cover the objects
that's that's there
he will be some fragments they might learn from this particular training image
and then when they come to want to recognise horses and the test image
what these fragments try to cover
image with these fragments OK so when they come
the new image they don't know the segmentation but have alpha mask
so what i want to to assemble horse at all these fragments as they go
so you get something like this
OK so small
assembling a jigsaw
that's an ocean structure
so if you have a horse you stick on these various parts and when you
sticking on part
it has to be against and sticking on done by cross correlation must cross correlation
so you have to some agreement with the texture some agreement with the
foreground background
so it the part just sticking on
you know the segmentation of the image you don't
you end up all these parts being stuck on then
you have a constraint for whether or not the overlap of parts consistent so basically
if you used if you sticking on two parts the overlap
in terms of background and foreground must be
consistent and that's the only structure constraints going on here the two parts on both
of them have to agree on
background and foreground segmentation and that's all very very loose constraint and then you end
up with a covering like this
now in our implementations of this what we found is that this this constraint is
just too loose
is no explicit geometry justice
overlap constraint and in terms of the allies than the policy norman described a greedy
algorithm the weight if this is the first of all i find the best fit
in part to the image
the best we can just means normalized cross correlation so it can be the best
fitting part is the background and in the first part is on the background there's
no way of recovering there's no backtracking in the algorithm
so we found this was the weakest of the three methods
OK so long as about this method pieces is a very different way of doing
the geometry
any questions on this method
so this is a comparison for this part talk where parts are found first
these two methods she'll graph cluster from positive examples but one is a has a
slightly more sophisticated
he's mutual information to decide what the fragments use interest points
in terms of the structure
we've seen maybe she'll have simple voting on
and a lot more traditional classifier on very sparse vectors and then both norman this
jigsaw like overlap
so what we've seen so far
dealing with recognizing class insist on the image translation only
all the examples we seem to have had an implicit structure model to be made
we have no articulation so far
and the only dealt with one aspect
of the object side or rear of cars for example
now coming to the question about orientation
if we want to recognise cars rotated or even scaled we have to an exhaustive
and this is very familiar to people who do
face detection
so the idea is going over sliding windows into the active roster sliding window
each of these positions you want to decide if there's a face inside
this window
it's a convex faces a certain scale
so here smaller scale and then to deal with scale changes explicitly the images resizing
the pyramid and the same the same size window
moved over that's how scales we have
likewise the orientation have to rotate the image and then run the same
so in the training is one orientation in the testing you can rotate the image
a set amount of each time we run out with them because that's how
and scaling
is dealt with in this class about them
any more questions on this
so then i'm going to go on to
the which
instead of the parts being the most important this structure term is the most important
that's really what counts
and what you see here the two new ideas one is that the structure what
i'm Xifing Yan from IBM t j watson research center and the today
Karsten from university of cambridge and i are going to talk about a graph mining
we will talk about graph mining from two perspectives graph
pattern mining from data mining perspective and graph
a machine learning perspective
and i will talk about the first part of graph pattern mining and Karsten
will talk about the second part of graph kernels
between these two parts we will have fifteen minutes to break
between three fifteen to three thirty
so as we know that graphs and graphs applications
become more and more important and popular in both scientific and commercial domains actually every
day we experienced a lot of graph applications
here i show you some examples - graph examples
so the first figure is very commonly used in bioinformatics gene coexpression networks
derived from microarray datasets
the second is chemical compound dataset
protein structure
programme for all graphs extracted from program traces and a very popular one
social networks
so given this kind of graphs, there are many interesting research problems we can
for example suppose we are given a set of chemical compounds can we find some
interesting hiddden inside
protein chemicals
chemical components super-structures that are active to some virus
if we are given two sets of graphs we might ask the following question can
we view the graph classification model which can tells us the difference between these two
sets of graphs
so i will examine these questions from pattern discovery perspective
mainly focus on graph pattern mining so i will talk about frequent graph pattern mining
pattern summarization optimal pattern mining
and graph patten with constraints and approximate graph pattern
and the later i will show you the application of these graph patterns in a specific
scenario - graph classification i will show you how to use these patterns to build high quality graph classifiers
and then later i will
discuss a a little bit about the graph compression
however i have to mention this by no means this tutorial is comprehensive about graph
mining because there are so many interesting topics
and the some of
these topics are very hot recently for example how to model graphs
how to analyse graphs dynamics
how to do the social network analysis how to graph
visualisation summarisation and et cetera
so if you are interested in you are very welcome to join session tomorrow on
monday afternoon we will have a session titled graph mining
so the solutions to the previous question i mentioned the for example graph pattern mining,  graph
classification actually can find many many applications for example of
mine  about chemical structures to find those active chemical fragments
mine those protein interaction networks to find those biologically conserved networks across
different species
find the functional modules in gene coexpression networks
do the program flow analysis to find software bugs
and and the using graph analysis to find the intrusion network fingerprints i will
use show you two examples in the end of the talk
so when we talk about graph pattern mining there are actually two typical settings
in graph pattern mining in the first setting
one is given one set of graphs without any label
each circle represents class
in this setting we only given one set of graphs without any level of this
is very typical application scenario
in the second setting
one is given two sets of graphs always supportive label and the negative labels
for example we can do a set of four experiments to test the activity of
chemical compounds with respect to the activity to HIV virus for example and we
can put those those active
chemical compounds into the supportive set
and as those inactive chemical compounds to the negative set
so immediately it becomes very challenging and interesting problems
can we find some unique chemical substructures
which can tell us the difference between these two sets of graphs
actually we can combine these two settings into one setting for example if we are
according to Parliament jobs actually couldn't because faulty acquitted you we have a lot of
sources of some of all that done jumped to the judiciary but for the birth
of the acquittals you also we should very feisty situation
if we get a simplified because
the predicted all we use it for much of not to projects he said
To defined an extended to the high don't feel to call that of various central
also find expression in his race and and you can't Wyoming matchup in 5 couldn't
on the conveyor less than 10 iterations so are so you
you initiate your process we are happy to reopened judiciary Petraeus is only applies iterations
of the contest advice on also on mattresses which are given by you want to
be here and so you could of sales that falls advice on bills this exclusion
was equipped with you also fund equipped you want be used action
he's asked said the agency will also sell a lot of time John will not
be equipped with a wall push mattress to position of the marathon aren't what these
areas venture that is due to the new Getty section Camacho space very stable so
you can initiate your of film back and you with the addition of a mattress
on the between congestion due to the barracks and
but we have not complexity of the program so we have objected to don't walk
songs on the program because we have no but we have noted took steps to
also mattresses sold means fool between the contest between going to do with the defeat
meant proceeds by our ambition beautifully but was a vital don't really know how to
to the truth is we have only exist for both the Web easier wanted to
know if he is also we would like to fool to Congress to adopt a
pizza Kamyshin attitude shipment removed can make some inquiries the classical fully equation so this
is just a good for ya questioning include appeared in space just too is defined
by the abductions versions of some of the going regret faltered in space mission retired
so that actions
UK Yukon factors rights as a 48 equation basis situation contracted that he did all
of you use which is in fact adequately community which is increase 1 on the
the end use 1 of the great debate was his are being fall 48 integration
of the Allied victory
and the Indonesian further 21 hours the PGA in space
on the inside of the fuels the guidance for the fleeting decommissioning is flat fee
free medical burdened with Phil
the fact that you could define a gang of 4 unique equation falters face-off with
big red of where you could upset association has been replaced by biting factories pollution
are already exists this equation this feelings exactly as an extension of the slope of
the fleet equipped that we have great players adequately Camino afforded by the community but
his expression is exactly the same 6 which only ups to lose the geometric mean
of the cheapest to neighbor would mattress
and it could be extended for years Rifkind neutral when the suspects it is no
longer changes that did
Was there is some somewhat done by caliber of also on and he needs to
win to explain his approach on so we have extended flop but don't receive than
a complex of Toronto's models so seasons of complexity model is very simple and when
you have a time series in fact you get is to make each point by
the pass with a longer or with novel which is defined by the although also
the old competitors modems facilities everywhere in signal was seen diesel elated to eventual possibilities
of social bomb the pond it is it being pushed by the oddity seasons the
mode maximum for peace
its effects would be next and the social construction would be next and you guys
alluded to all these and in your answers to my questions
so first you might say well food is something that's found in nature
that humans have evolved to eat foods that are found in nature they're out there
you can gather them you can hunt them you can fish them or you can
grow them you can do something but it's out there in nature well that's one
possible definition of food
another is how much is processed
and how if you take things that started out as food like wheat or corn
and their process many different ways and things are added to them or done to
that change their chemical properties that affect whether we consider
its effect is recognised by the body can the body ingest this particular item
and deal with it in a reasonable way and not have internal have occurred
a when people are eating foods that are too high in fat and sugar
and they eat these foods consistently in hand have other bad nutrients like trans fats
like the bad things happen to them on the body cannot adapt
two of diet that has certain properties
so if food belongs to class
foods that control class of items that contributes to the internal metabolic capt
with that the reason to consider a non food
and the social construction of course
it is very important
do we think something with taste good and we define it as the food as
part of the culture
so if we go back to the cheetos in the cockroach
and we look at our different criteria
and we ask ourselves is it found in nature
well we get checked for the cockroach on that the only
his flaming hot cheetos are not found in nature
is it concocted well
the cockroaches pretty much its natural state
and you have all the ingredients and the other for recognised by the body
my guess is that eating cockroaches probably won't do internal damage eating too much food
like this certainly will
is it harmful well
i mean cockroach might be seen as being harmful because we consider the dirty disgusting
revolting insects and we don't define insects something we released our culture
and then finally do we find it is food well then we get checked for
the cheetos does it taste good we get it checked for the cheetos as well
but only because we're trained to believe that one taste good and the other one
doesn't because in different cultures it would be the reverse
so you see how these different properties of food affect whether we would even consider
so far
are interesting part of this
there was a time when people were very close to their food they were physically
close to it psychologically close to
the food was raised locally
usually think back to new haven in the nineteen fifties are forty or thirty
a lot of the food much more than is the case today was grown locally
and was sold in markets and so there might have been one person or one
that resided between you and your food and you might even see the farmers sometimes
who brought the food into market
that was certainly true in earlier days
and so
but but the distance to food has changed a lot
because food has come has to come in
from far greater distances than used to be the case and that's changed our relationship
with a lot into a distance rather than close relationship
here's an example that you highlighted
in the block there
the is a farm called fairview gardens
that's outside of los angeles in suburban los angeles
and so that's the bracketed part is the farm in nineteen fifty four
the next slide shows the
so far same farm and its surroundings
in nineteen ninety eight
so you can see that a lot has happened here
and so this means that all the areas surrounding at fairview gardens
it was mainly farmland back in the nineteen fifties all growing food
probably a fair amount of it being equal locally by people
but since it's all been pushed out of the way by development
that means the food has to get shipped in from larger and larger distances and
it means that people in los angeles who are eating their food a lot of
it shipped in from far away
have a distant relationship with her
there's also distance psychological relationship with because we just aren't is concerned this people used
to be about where it came from
but that's changing and more and more people do want to know the story of
and that story is something we'll talk about in the class
very similar
but it just gets a little bit more messy i wanted to try and give
you a flavour of what's going on here so i'm not going to go into
this at all with nonzero
training error but you can get similar type of result which says that the bound
on the generalisation is b
number of so you should be k and so some mistake k is the number
of training OK around so that's the empirical
training error
plus it looks very much like what we had before
except that now the square root
which makes it larger
and lucerne
and that comes from using a different bands only
probabilities but you need in the non zero training case in fact
the bayes bounds that are now being developed has sort of interpolate between these two
so you know you could expect that as you go towards low training area you
might actually get something better than the square root
the square root is needed definitely when you have training areas that have large
there's something that
goes between those two
we're going to see the square root come back in the rademacher complexity tomorrow when
we look at the pounds come out of the market complexity
so i wanted to just show you
white squares that because these things should be very much less than one if you
take the square root is something less than one it gets bigger
quite significantly so so it's not a good thing but but it's it's still
an interesting band
so that's the non-zero training error case
so now i want to sort of step back
and sort of review where we've got two and
in this sense
you know the good news is that
this looks like a really nice theory
it all ties together you've got lower and upper bounds is beautiful sort of proof
and so on the bad news is
doesn't seem to actually apply in practice so
it's an interesting case
the problem is that the
you can't criticize it as it stands is clearly correct you know we've got up
and lower bounds
but in it doesn't apply and this is a clear mismatch between the theory and
the practice and probably the best example of that is the support vector machine
so this is sort of
if you like the catastrophic failure of systemic failure of a
the PAC theory
so what is SVM as well
from sort of learning theory point of view all they are is applying linear functions
in very high dimensional
feature spaces
OK this is the kernel trick that you've learned about from from the song which
allows you to do this efficiently
but from the point of view of the learning theorist how you actually implement function
is irrelevant you're actually using a linear function of very high dimensional space
now we know that the VC dimension of an linear function space is
the dimension that space
so the VC dimension of these
svm spaces is is very high and there is no way
the theory will give anything like an indication of good bound i mean for instance
if you use the gas in kernel
the feature space is actually infinite dimension
so you you know you you actually into that town and clearly that's not going
to give you
anything non-trivial
so the PAC theories is completely failing to give any indication of why these
the function should work at all and if you just using the PAC theory to
guide you in your
you know investigation of learning
algorithms you would throw out SVM
and yet we all know that they actually very impressive performance
how they work and
what's happening you know and we need to
you know learning theory needs to sort of
wake up
i understand what's going on trying to analyse this so this is the state of
the game if you like in about ninety three four one
st anne's have been invented in learning theory was still
start with the PAC VC dimension
OK seems work in the following way they effectively the one norm SVM seeks to
minimize this
two norm of the weight vectors plus the one norm of the slack variables where
the slack variables measure how much the
the particular training example fails to be
margin one so it effectively is enforcing the margin one the actual geometrical margin is
is effectively maximized by minimizing the weight vector here and the slack variables allow allowed
individual points to fail to meet margin but it
it penalizes those
failures by adding in
this one norm of the slack variables to the to the minimisation
OK so that's how it it works
and the intuition behind svms so i mean they weren't invented just
arbitrary i mean there was very clear intuition of maximising the margin would make it
possible to change good generalisation despite heist these dimensions
and the phrase effective VC dimension was thrown around but was an imprecise
there was no precise definition of what that meant at the time
that need the
OK so how we getting around this lower bound i mean you know we've got
a lower and
you can't do that
the VC dimension what's happening but there is a critical difference between the upper bound
on the log
you have advances for every distribution
you can have better performance
the second the lower bound says there exist distributions
four which were forced to make this error
so one with
effectively using here is the fact that there are the distributions image in practice may
not be
as nasty
as the worst case distributions
looking for something if you like about nine distribution something about the distribution which is
serendipitous it's it's helping us nature is actually not against us it's it's helping us
learning the actual task that we're trying to learn
and in fact what we
find is the margin is in this sense
a measure of how lucky we are
in in
particular distribution we're looking at
the distribution is somehow luckily aligned with the
hyperplane that we need to separate the data and actually is if you like showing
us the solution and that is what is actually
occurring in order to
avoid the
difficulties of love
so we know a lot about what i yes if you use these high dimensional
space is there are distributions will
that's for sure
what we're saying is that the margin is telling us actually that we can measure
the the ninth the distribution as we do our training and we can
see that we're unlucky situation
so what i'm not going to do is is is sort of take the first
approach to proving the band's
for ESPN's which are based
on the margin
i will give a complete proof of these birds' out
given a fairly it follows very similar pattern to the proof for the that we've
seen so far for the VC dimension
but i want to give you a flavour of these ideas are translated across
i'm now leaving out of this notation because
this argmax here that i'm interested in its for specific x five minutes for a
specific data facts
much so i can leave it out of the notation
OK i guess that was the
and there
so this
this GI function if you
if you look back up here
the thing that we want to maximize
it is the sum of all feature functions or high level feature functions the need
high level feature function is the sum of the positions in the sequence so now
always said as we have some of the positions in the sequence
and then this g function is really the total contribution
a single position i in the sequence
so much so and noticed that
you know why i minus one
and why i
they belong to
look OK the set of tags
so if i have a hyphenation problem
then there are just two possible tax zero and one
and if i have a part of speech
problem then maybe there are twenty possible tax twenty possible
parts of speech
x but
and w but
i fixed
this function g i said member trying to derive an algorithm so algorithms depend on
data structures so
what data structure
can i use what's the simple data structure that can use to represent the function
g i
data structure
so set of tags we call this set t
with cardinality
so m is the number of different tags to five-nation twenty four part of speech
have the function g i and i'm going to need to evaluate it for every
combination of values while i minus one y i
and then i'm going to need to store this function so what data structure can
be used to store this function in
hash all actually i can use something even simpler
i can just use a two dimensional matrix
because there are just two different arguments and their and values which are used the
m squared
possible values
g i
is an m by n matrix
and so actually the first thing i algorithm
precompute these by functions
and is it
x bars fixed
and then for four equals one
i just computer some some of the jwj
the left j
of why i minus one y i for every possible pair of values y i
so it's GI is an m by n matrix
so so g to g one
it is an m by n matrix g two is an m by n matrix
g three is an m by n matrix
so then precompute all of these
so that's
it's and square squirt
and square and time
so there and these matrices
each one has got m squared entries
entry in the matrix is the sum of the room
little feature functions
so it's it's quadratic in and
but linear otherwise
and unfortunately don't have much room on the board
and now
this goal
almost all the protons are going to be zero
because the use the gammas of you are independent
so you only get contribution at the turn at the point where you're multiplying the
same termites are just turns out to be the interval
all the all the time as series except for these sort of diagonal terms
where you takes on the same value
that gives you an expression that look like this
and you can rearrange this expression
to get
well it's a it's actually gauss integral manually evaluate that goes into google you get
term that look like this
which is just a financial x minus ex-prime squared over two
this now
is the covariance function
we have been working on on the previous example
this is this
calcium or squared exponential growth
that means
doing inference
in the gas process
is equivalent
to doing inference
the set of functions
i have little galson pumps everywhere
notice that have gas improv everywhere not just on the training points
this turns out to be quite important
of course if you wanted to do
regression in your fashion way
then you get into trouble if you have infinite number one because that means that
you're just input vector you feature that will be the value
of of
of each of those bonds right but if there are infinitely many of those
and then of course
you wouldn't really be able to write down
what you can do the inference if you think of it as gospel
because in that case
the inference only involves the covariance matrix which is dimension and by i
here's the figure that tries to illustrate
why it's important that you have infinitely many got involved
so you could sort of say well
this other stuff is just using some fancy mathematics and use sort of infinity all
looks very neat but actually when it comes down to doing something practical practical
i don't care about us to
is the figure which had to why you want to care about that
here's an example
where we have
we have a model which has three months got right the centre
exactly at the location where he also training data three
the training data points
you have three girls in bonds
in other model
to do inference model you have to inference over the weights corresponding to the three
girls in
now when you do the bayes analysis you have to think about doing it into
over all the possible settings
of those different parameters you can sort of think of the little girls bumps
as jiggling around but they have to dig around such way
we all know that they always
almost exactly explains the data to the red curve here is some
other the values
for this setting about can sort of imagine under the posterior distribution
these are wiggle around and you can get you some distribution of this of the
underlying rate function
we could use this associated areas
to illustrate what that
what that inference what those
confidence intervals would be
now comes out just point test runs over here
so how do we do
what happens when we doing inference here in the model how the prediction here when
we look at
what is the model predicting
and then integrate over the posterior we look at what happened somewhere here
then we regard around the little bumps here under the posterior distribution
and what happens out here
OK the function is always zero
that means the predictive distribution is going to be gaussians centered around zero
with zero variance
OK the fact that the centre and zero is maybe not so bad because because
the truth is we don't know what's going on here so zero is as good
as guest as anyone has anything
but it has zero variance
this is a catastrophe
it's saying that it's absolutely sure that the values zero
that's the wrong answer
why why do we get the right answer here
we've got the wrong answer
because the prior was sort of city
the prior already said well we only entertain
hypothesis about what's going on that only allow functions that vary over here
of course seeing any amount of data you still only get functions that very over
so what was wrong about the prior
but thing that was wrong about the prior is that it that it excluded that
anything could happen over here even before we started
which is which is an unreasonable assumption usually
you wouldn't want to assume that kind of thing in some applications it might be
an appropriate assumptions right but in general it doesn't seem like such and such good
so you can get away from that kind of prior by having down syndrome everywhere
OK so in this example
well let's say we also have a gas and pop over here
now we do the inference
these things are jiggling around ever-so-slightly right because i have to agree with the data
in this thing
it's just going around
its posterior distribution equal to its prior distribution because the data doesn't have any opinion
about what's going on here
that means this is jiggling around wildly
which means that the error bar is going to be large and that's the right
OK so
so this a particular gaussianprocess which you can think of it that way
but that's just for a particular choice of the covariance function
what i wanna spend the last ten minutes on is going to talk about
different types of covariance functions
so the so i so the gas processes are somehow much which class depends on
what the covariance functions are
the other is in the information about what you can do here so before we
look at the squared exponential
covariance function discussed in great functions
in one dimension which had a single length scales
but if you have more if you have multiple dimensions then you might have a
length scale parameter for each of the dimensions the new covariance function would look like
and drawn
random functions for different settings of the length scale parameter
three and four four point inside this
the radius here
they define outliers
as data records
therefore every are they
you have to define this is the parameter
so basically this a the number and the idea of are significantly deviates from the
distribution of values pj of our so that means the from the neighbors here
a source the simple pj from from from the neighborhood so for example
if this is true
that means point BI i is the outer
so let's let's assume you so that
and b i are that means
all the points that are from point p i
this post
at least our
there are four points this one
four so and are four
it's here
so if you if you introduce new parameter alpha
so basically having small circle here
so in this case and p of our is one
so can construct similarly this value for
support points p one p two and p three
p one
circles the are three point in this that's three
p two
there are five points on the circle here
so and the two of five
will be three
there are two points in the circle so that's two
and i know you can put in this average value so basically
the i are of this is the average value of all the points
including this point this point this this and this
so these all the numbers to the computed so far
this is the average so basically computer use this average in this competition here
of course you compute the standard
the nation here
and then depending on parameter k
you can define is a certain value
seven data record is anomaly some this is simple they how to compute
of these the director
OK of they want to make a break five minutes or ten minutes or you
want me to continue
OK then
it's very
can we continue
OK so far recovered classification based on nearest neighbour based anomaly detection techniques to cover
some of the remaining ones
we'll talk briefly about this online distributed anomaly detection as well
let's go to
clustering based techniques so same clustering based anomaly detection techniques key assumption is that
normal data points belong to to
large and dense clusters while anomalies
they belong to
actually cannot belong to any cluster may belong to some very small clusters
so the general approaches to cluster data
in two thousand clusters and analyse data instances with respect to what is the closest
cluster and if the points belong to any cluster
so the points that correspond to analysis that can be
they do not belong to any of the clusters
the sell small clusters
some this clusters as well
and also
things that are far from other points within the same cluster so depends on the
class three able write code behind
so obvious advantages included this is again unsupervised approach does not require any labels
and existing clustering approaches can be plugged in an applied here
for the problem of anomaly detection
there are many drawbacks
if the data does not have the natural
clustering of
natural kind of grouping
this approach not able to find this clusters and then you know the the goal
of an action
they're also computationally expensive like the nearest neighbour reported because they are based on the
similar idea computing the distances
and a national time people are using
different index structures
to alleviate this problem
and again in high dimensional
spaces data is sparse
distances may not be meaningful the same problem with the nearest neighbour technique
i will present a few of this approach is what is actually what people what
kind of the things people
using to detect anomalies
this approach is called find out
it's by these people
and this is basically a by-product of
they cluster of making this growing interest in buffalo
so only buffalo and the main idea is to transform all data records into multidimensional
signals using the wavelet transformation
and then high frequency of the signals
correspond to data regions where is the rapid change of distribution
these are usually about this is because of the boundaries of the clusters we here
and low frequency parts correspond to regions where the data is
concentrated so basically this is here and here so basically when you remove all these
points what this approach does basically takes all remaining points out of this
you all are
no i
you want to go
o or one one
you are
we are all
all right
you can be your
also a
here you
this a
the case
of these
on the other
twenty four
the you know
o are more
he you are
what i do it is a simple example i agree but notice what i just
did it allow me to highlight is the code doing the right thing
spotted an i could have spotted it by running on different test sets and using
prince things another way doing about this idea of at least simulating and simple examples
lets you checked
a couple of important questions
in fact now let me ask those two questions about this piece of code
the first question is
for what values of integers
images overall values of x does this code terminate
the second question is
for what values of x doesn't give me back the right answer
first question
of eyes have access to terminate
it's in x is an integer
break it down into pieces suppose x is positive
does it terminates
because answer start so to zero
so answer squared is zero and each time through the loop answer is increasing
that means at some point in some finite number of steps answers squared is going
to get bigger than x is possible
so for positive integers it terminates
probably i think we can deduce to return to the right answer here
x is negative
x minus sixteen
does this code terminate
i feel like arnold schwarzenegger does this too many
thank you so does germany right
there's too far back to try
so far sorry come to one later if you can find it it starts at
the first step right let's look at it
it says if answer i imagine axes minus sixteen answer is zero is zero less
minus sixteen
so what does it do
prince of zero
that now answers my second question
it does terminate but does it give me the right answer
it gives me an answer imagine i'm using this somewhere else you know it's is
going to go off and say g these square root of minus sixteen is zero
really should be you know an imaginary number but this is not a valuable thing
to have come back
so that's the second thing i just highlighted here i now have the ability
to cheque
what does the right thing
those are two things that you'd like to do with every looping construct right you'd
like to be able to assure yourself that they will always terminate
in the second thing you'd like to do is to assure yourself that it does
give back to reasonable answer
we started to talk about ways to do the former is looking at the end
test is looking at the kinds of conditions you can put in
for the latter
this is the place for running test cases would do a good job of helping
with that
nonetheless having done that let's look at
better way to write this
which is
it is also i think on your she uncommon that
comment this one out
so let's look at this code for second
is what this does certainly the heart of right in here
it is still
the same thing
but notice what this does the first thing it does is it says let's check
and make sure x is greater than or equal to zero
if it isn't
this was going to happen under that block is going to get executed that's going
come down here print out a useful piece of information was assayed in a negative
i don't know how to do this
if it is in fact positive then we're going to go in here but now
notice what we're doing here there's the basic thing we did before i were checking
the intestine incrementing
actually was going i commented that for a reason you see in the second but
normally would keep the sum which would let me at each step see what it's
if i ran this it would print out each step helping me make sure that
increment in the right way
they want to get to the end of that what's going to do is going
to come down here and now
was that during
well i cheated when i started some some is given a perfect square looking for
the square root of
but suppose i gave this thing fifteen
and as to to run
it's to give me an answer it just wouldn't be the answer i'm looking for
so now in this case this code is going to what we get here check
if you haven't seen that strange thing explanation point in computer is called the bang
this is the answer star answer is not equal
what sets a says i've already got to the end of the loop on all
past where i wanted to be and i want to check to make sure that
in fact this really is a perfect square if it isn't
print out something says you gave me something that wasn't perfect square
and only
if that
is true
print out the answer
it's the same computation
but this is a nice way of writing it often called defensive program
and i think we have lots of variations on down on the drum what your
favourites for the definition of defensive programming for me it says
make sure that i'm going through all possible paths through the code
make sure and printing ordered or returning if you like useful information for each style
sorry for each pass through the code
make sure that for all possible inputs there is a path through the code or
way to get through the code does not cause an error an infinite loop
well for jadran john
i i will come back to this later in the term and talk it in
less work to solve perturbed version of the problem so that's what happens with the
segmentation problem where you you've got here
you want to get back gov heads
but you got a little bit more than the head i resisted the temptation to
make the cut through the area
letting with easier but
we didn't want to share so
market in for the show to the problem you have to solve is almost the
same as the original problem except with this extra annotation which comes into the which
is sort of brought into the the problem the boundary conditions so you actually take
some of the the XII values the hidden variables just tie them
two foreground background or maybe
encourage them to be in the foreground background by applying extra costs on the graph
and now you'd like to solve the new graph cut problem here it is the
offending bit has been removed but it should be much less work
so the question is can you reuse
the work that you did before well
what happens with the
the first version of the problem is you solve it and then you end up
with the flood
you know you because you saw the maximum flow and if you just keep that
alive is not the same as the as the graphical model but the actual network
graph you keep that graph don't right away
the the allocate all those variables whatever you might have done this key that graph
and when you revisit it
all you need to do is to just touch few the edges in the graph
and change the
the costs on those few edges
so now
if you change the course on on a few the edges most of the edges
have the same cost as before can we somehow use the flow well the worst
thing that could happen is that you have when you're doing this maximum flow
the one kind of grammar school the augmenting flow algorithm which is the more as
the kind described to you know in hand-waving terms one of the rules of augmenting
flow algorithms is they maintain valid flow at all times never allowed to have an
intermediate stage where the flow exceeds capacity there are other algorithms like push relabel
you are actually temporarily allowed to have invented flows with their own temporary eventually they'll
go away and the reason why you shouldn't do that but in the augmenting flow
algorithm you'd like the question is can we change the augmenting flow algorithm to work
with this modified perturbed problem and reusing the old flow or the west could happen
to you is that you
change the FIA and FIM zero here five one here and which are the capacities
and you've now got the capacity which is less
and the flow you inherited from the previous version of the problem so they are
in trouble you don't want to do
i mean the flow is you know what we like is to work on the
residual graph where the spare capacity and then push extra flow through this through the
spec capacity so if in fact i had the model the preservation i made was
increasing the values of costs and all of these ideas you'd be happy be able
to reuse the old flow the be you opened up some residual capacity by perturbing
the problem and you just do some more pushing to mop up residual capacity but
if you
if instead the modification the problem to reduce some of these costs now you may
be breaking the constraints and have some flowsin some pipes that exceed capacity this is
very upsetting i can see you're all very upset
what can you do that is well it's very easy with vertical
log likelihood arcs because all you have to do is that same re parameterisation trick
that we did before i add some constant to this are here enough to make
the capacity exceeds the flow again providing and the same capacity this arc than the
original problem is not changed
and so you can see easily that's going to work and i want to show
you what to do with the horizontal
links because that's a little bit more
complicated but take it from me the same kind of re parameterisation tricks that we
saw before work there as well and you can switch the
you can see you can reprogram tries the horizontal
capacity is to make sure they exceed this flow that you have to start with
so this was
he invented by code in talk
and they did so demonstrated rather nice
capabilities with it
so for example suppose you wanted a segment of video like we just work
and supposing it is the case the things in the video or not
changing radically fast this is a slow-moving cow
and so
one should be able to capitalize on
the state of the time t
you know in the same time the character t when trying to solve the problem
at time t plus one
so now
run the video and you see either the real time
and what you see here
is the residual flow
i teach at each time step that needed to be
what does and you see that you know nothing at all is happening over most
of the image none of the background is any work being done they will flow
is being pushed and in the interior and then we'll fly is being pushed the
only place the flow needs to be pushed is as you'd expect in around the
silhouette moving to the rest of the of the really is very neat trick and
that can you save may be a factor of twenty or something about aldrin in
practical settings with this kind of problem so that's actually a very nice discovery
don't be sorry
it's a
i mean it works with horses as well
well you know
green losses which are in short supply of the
that's the kind of camouflage problem isn't and so
you know we
we talked about that yes we agree the camouflage problem is hard of course is
hard than this one
and about then the the potts model and the ising model i mean the modified
ising model country or a because they you know bringing in prior or a data
modified prior
that you know
makes up for some of the ambiguity in the foreground background
there's no contributions here there is no contribution here
the electric field is only exist in that's my assumption
and so the whole thing here
is now the five
let's look at our results
and also by
and was i are square and
my cap actually non-zero
well i get i get new zero times i
that is truly amazing
so if i know that we
equals new zero times i
divided by two quite
which is exactly what we had before
hooray for mister maxwell
because now it doesn't matter anymore when you take the flat surface
what do you think the bags of
you know get the same answer
in one case there is no contribution
from the displacement
current term
and in that case there is no contribution from the first
the real current
make sure what i'm happy with my results
i think that's fine
we can also go one step further
and we can calculate
anywhere in between
the capacitor
what the
magnetic field is
make another drawing of the capacitor
right here
i have this feel that will not repeat that every time
you have my point p two now
which is inside
the capacitor
and radius there are
from the centre
and this is capital are
circular plates
i have here my close
the circle
radius there are
i apply now
the new law
i to buy are
there we go we have museo we have an absolute non-zero we have a cap
there is no current going through year so it's non-negotiable i plan is zero right
it's not even an issue
so we get new zero
actually non-zero
i get kappa
now the surface area
right here
it's not pi capital are square
where is an
changing electric fields but it is only by large square
take a flat surface now
so now we multiply this
but by the large screen
and then of course the genes in the same
so we get our
current i
divided by
by capital are created
divided by kappa actually non-zero
and now you again losing lots
you lose your actually non-zero
which are kept
the idea is that by
and i kind of little or you have
they are square there
now we're going to get the results
something that you may actually have anticipated
namely together
field inside the capacity is growing
we are
because i make up my balance
i get upstairs museo times i
but i get one little stations you are square you you are here
i get to my
and i get a
capitol are squared i believe that correct
the check my notes
yes i'm happy with that
and this is proportional was little are
falling off one of or
and so i can make a plot
of the magnetic field as a function of the heart
when i'm inside the capacitor plates
because the magnetic field
this is the radius of the capacitor plates
the straight line
to that point
and then it will fall as one of the are
you can do your own work and that that is very trivial
to calculate to demonstrate that value
go beyond the edge of the capacitor
then it falls off as one of our
in the same way that
o point one is doing
so now we have the tools to calculate the magnetic field even inside capacitors
well we were charging which we didn't have before
the strength here the maximum magnetic field here
you find by substituting in there
four that are capital are
and when you do that it becomes capital are
this becomes one of capitol are
if you substituted in year for the lower capital or you will find the same
this part
it's not kosher cannot be correct
and i cannot make it right for you
and the reason why that part cannot be kosher
it's because we have made this assumption which is wrong
there is no friends
so we have something of calculations
that the electric field is only here
and there but it's zero user there's nothing known each year no changing magnetic electric
flux and that's not true
so clearly
when you get close to the edge
this is not correct
there's no way i can correct for that because the french fields will be different
from capacity capacity
and those calculations support
very easy to make
maxwell had to introduced his displacement current term
a very smart man he predicted that as a consequence of that term
the radio waves should exists
it was the time that we denote radio waves exist
he predicted the existence
but not only did he predict the existence
he was able
to calculate what this means
it's going to be
recall that the speed of light
let's which you and now we
consider what happens if we take the view of
knowledge representation of ontologies
and we know what ontologies impose constraints on the data and the actual data that
we have may be incomplete or inconsistent with respect to these constraints
and the point is that you want to take into account constraints while answering queries
so we cannot forget about them as is done in databases
and so p answering is not anymore
the evaluation criterion corresponds to performing logical inference which is a much more computationally costly
and notice that this is possible by
this is headed by current system because people the size of data is not so
critical we don't have huge amounts of data
and also generally which is considered to be seen so simple class expressions not complex
queries that's why current systems able to deal with although i mean the technologies is
is advancing let's look again victoria this situation are now have left he mo an
ontology there been used to together with reason to design the largest schema
but now the opposed over the ontology and we want to answer these queries and
the point is that in order to answer queries we have to reason over the
whole amount of information that we have to reason with the scheme and the ontology
to reason also over the data the data comes into play when reasoning and that's
the that's the problematic issue in general
let's look at
take up again our over variational for simple example where we now have the
the ontology of view
again the faculties professors in colleges and faculties work for colleges but now
we assume that at query answering time we want to take into account the ontology
you have again information notice that now the data in
read in the in the relational table database may not be completely may be incompletely
specified and for some
class properties we may not even have a table for example is not a faculty
home can we just have you know the john except professors there may be additional
professors we don't know who but we know these two plot professors we know that
college encouraged apologies and we know that
john for college a methodist college b but there may be additional information that is
not explicitly represented
and now we are very simple query asking give me
the members of those that are faculty members
i notice there is no
data about faculty members now let's see what happens in this case in our system
so now
by enabling reasoning so we exploiting now the information that we haven't seen before
in the ontology to answer this query and i see
we get
some sort of page on marinade
now let's look at why we get john many here here we don't we were
asking for faculty members john many can not listed as faculty members why do we
any any any clue why we get these answers why do we get john
once once it
what do we get john
i was surprised and not surprised
no one is surprised look for these was easy you surprised
no OK we
so you have to ask
OK this is the usual thing so
and no exactly
let's see what we get john it's also difficult john is is listed the professor
the ontology these professors faculty member so if you ask faculty members we expect to
get john and the same funny
get john because of these reasons now
question is married is professor why do we get married
this is also seen but maybe not so immediate what we get now
once once
exactly works for is a relation is a property whose domains faculty so we know
that whoever is in the domain of the works for property should all be a
faculty member and mary by the way here so we should expect to get married
as a member of faculty and that's what our system actually that's so we see
we have works for
property whose domain is a faculty and that's why we get married announced
now let's look at a bit more interesting example a bit more complex
this is again omitted toys schema just illustrate the
the basic notions so we have an ontology that just talked about persons and each
person has a father who is again the person who gets what ontology expresses this
one he expresses that each person has a father
and then we know some persons and we know some father of
person father relation john
five is an economics finance tony and johnny cantoni persons now
we are asking for the bears
x and y such that x is father
such access father y
what do you expect to get here
let's see what the system here
so we get to top
you get john in economic and tony surprise surprise you get exactly what we had
asserted as
explicit information in our
in our database let's say OK now a box
the system in this case is not able to infer information to get this expresses
adopted but it cannot infer new information knowledge cl slightly different query query looks very
much similar but now we are not asking for the pairs x y just asking
for those persons x that have some father but not interested in the father of
now let's see what we get is an answer here
now we get three doctors care and you see now get also tony
as the first component of answer we didn't have to only before someone returned in
the pair why do we get only here
i mean it's similar to the argument that we had before we get only because
we know that every person
should have fathered by ontology has father although we don't know the father
of tony we know that since he is the person he will have someone who
is his father here and that's why he's returned as an answer to the query
now let
go on let's look at a bit more complex queries
we are now asking for persons for which we have a chain of ancestors
so x which show some wide it is that is the father of x
for some y one this part of x and y two years followed by one
well look
adds up to six
we found the submarine without which number sixty three
the computer was thinking of
and why come to such a beautiful random numbers
some special coincidence
what is it always happens well let's just
check reporter cancel this semester
this and the
this and this and this and this and this is the
and this
and this so the answer is always gonna come out once you've found
the submarine
a lot landscape
thank you
you know it makes
have no proof
but it's a nice little bit evidence that maybe this logo one over pete thing
which looked a bit strange at beginning
maybe that's the right way
to measure how much information you get
when something happens
do you want to play again
maybe not i think we got arrested any questions
so that's what
now let's do then collaborate
the question is the mafia boss tells you you
two but i tickets
the outcome is going be the stream
is obtained when the coin is tossed
one thousand times as the bent coin
raag heads and common tales was are very few ones
you can buy any that it is you want from the box office
if you
do we need it then you get exactly in pounds
and the mafia was forces you to buy
lotto the tickets and that have a ninety nine percent chance
and questions i'm going to ask you first if instead the rules you just being
forced by one ticket so got pound forced
to go and spend it which take it would you buy
have the best chance of winning
question two is gonna be having ninety nine percent and winning which tickets with you by
and how many tickets is back
and please express your form in your answer in the form to the power something okay
so that's the really questions for you
please contact with your neighbour
and so all of these questions
our what the world
okay let's start with a simple question
you're forced to buy one ticket from the shop
would you buy
they on
the only
and on wanted different ticket
one nine hundred zero
i one hundred one
i feel the
anne which one would you
would you buy
which these
you don't mind
that's all people employed
are you happy with this choice would you like a different one
so do you
you like most spread out again
will feel free space I call this the milk carton problem how many different shapes
of milk cartons could you make the dimethyl truck perfectly and he came up with
7 of
7 and a lot of getting ahead of myself there the 7 of them were
shown here this is in your in your notes and these are the labels for
the visit here is the basic unit so you have 3 lengths ABC and have
3 angles alpha beta and gamma and depending on which makes you choose for example
the Cuba's here a equals B equals 3 in edges all normal to 1 another
and then here's the author Robert they're not equal to each other and so
so 7 basic shapes
and here they are drawn for you and this is taken of the lecture notes
the archive lecture notes
this is analogous to the the tiling problem to drive home the point that you
wanted to the tiling problem how many distinct shapes of tiles
farther into space
so I think we can agree we can go with square tiles or we can
go with the entanglement tiles What other tiles we have
triangle triangle is actually it's not a basic unit because I can't it doesn't observe
translational symmetry but if I close the triangle like there's never 60 degrees and this
will become the basis repeat unit OK then there's a regular the parallel pipe where
this unit in angle rather is not equal to 60 degrees and this effect is
the basic unit the frank gary users in building is if you go over to
the the status that you will see that the basic unit that's used to make
those irregular shapes is this
was a space-filling and that all of these are labeled and so on this is
the clothing problem will how do you cut a two-dimensional piece of cloth to fit
over 3 dimensional shape nontrivial problem has worked was closed off that this is a
very simple fashion designers don't understand the simple geometry
and we have a we describe size and for for men at least take a
chastising size for women go she's 8 1 8 1 number and this is why
things don't forget you have to get down to the unit cell
here's 1 that will work at the Pentagon won't work and I'm not trying to
make a political statement simply saying
so here's what you can do is is if you here's what happens if you
try to filter space with the Pentagon you see disabled but up there's these white
gaps the reds touch the Reds but it will fail so this is how always
work in free space and determined that certain units will not bought up against 1
another and feel free space perfect
OK so we're click and things are going well but we still haven't got atomic
erasures all we got his milk cartons so far so now let's think about the
next the next step step came
about 50 years later
but 1848 which was an auspicious here and in Europe there was another frenchman was
and that he proved mathematically that there are 14 distinct ways to arrange points in
space and what do I mean by that there's a cartoon that shows a
the cube
we've agreed that the cubism cookie-cutter that will fill 3 space
but when I start putting atoms in the cube I have 3 distinguishable arrangements so
here on the left I have something where I put Adams only on the corners
and the 2nd 1 I . atoms on the corners and 1 in the center
nothing look at the 1 in the center that 1 of the centers sees 8
nearest neighbors each 1 of these sea
only 6 nearest neighbors so these atoms have a different
Adam arrangements a different Adam environment from the atoms and this arrangement so the last
1 is called simple cubic the center 1 is called body centered cubic because there's
an atom in the center and it doesn't matter I can arbitrarily shift the center
of discourse in this corner Random sees the same nearest neighbors in the same arrangement
relative to the center
there's a body centered cubic
choose any 1 of those if I sit here in the center of the 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 or I can go to this 1 over
here vertices 1 2 3 4 and you just keep going the same arrangement and
yet that's the cookie cutter that fill spaces the acute there's 1 other possibility and
that's face centered cubic face centered cubic is here where you have this this
the square face that atom in the center of each face
and that's distinguishable that's so
brother again frenchman steeped in math goes into the mathematics and ask how many different
ways can I put Adams into these 7 crystal systems that only has specified and
get distinguishable . environment and the answer is 14 the 14 14 ways to arrange
points in space
so now we're getting somewhere now we're getting somewhere by the way if you look
at this object here the 14 different brevity lattice as
and the shown this is also from the lecture notes and all putting here is
1 . and each lattice point but it doesn't have to be a adopted because
was showing a 2nd is I can put sets of atoms groups of atoms in
other words if I wanted to describe what the positions of every apple in orchard
what I could do is say that the bond that the brevity lattice is telling
me the planting of the trees
and then I can hang different for different types of Apple arrangements at each point
so that's what we're going to we're trying to break this down otherwise you're going
have a gazillion different atomic arrangements were able to do is confined everything to a
simple set of 14
so what I wanna do now is show that we can look at different sets
of elements that these at these points so it's good to see what happens if
we look at face centered cubic input different atomic groupings air at each point so
ultimately what I'm in search of is the crystal structure the crystal structure and the
crystal structure is the atomic arrangement in 3 space atomic arrangement and the crystal structure
is the sum of 2 components 1st is the brevity lattice gravity lattice what the
brevity lattices it's really just a point environment it's a point environment but not including
want the point including nothing American make this sequel John Cage penalties in just the
point arrests of different time signatures from time
you compare this with this it's not based upon sonnet 57 because 1 of only
57 this is really really good and I mean I would just give it because
he wrote assigned but there were some of the key points here you see in
mentioned smelting amazon extracted metallurgists that took the case make sense melting ice and you
guys so
I think this is something to
to think about the way before we go to the place OK so the contest
there is the prices are necktie's and as
starts with the they're they're very hot the black with a colored elements of the
periodic table so very nice level bring samples next day they're really look sharp very
sharp you know there's all kinds of gift-giving coming down the road you never know
when 1 of these could just do the trick but so don't fail to enter
and I will have office hours today uh starting both 330 to 431 tomorrow if
you want to see me by all means go during a recitation structure that as
well so last day we were looking at similarly but taxonomy and then on to
a little bit more about the interior of the atom we looked at the representation
of elements in the periodic table where we have the proton number z which is
equal to the number of electrons in the neutral atom and the atomic mass which
is the sum of the proton number and the neutron number we talked about isotopes
and and what today I want to continue so far we've been looking at static
elements but most people think of chemistry as involving reactions so let's look at the
dynamics reactions between chemicals and we describe chemical reaction what are the rules about the
1st thing you do is you write an equation the equation is subject to these
constraints 1st of all we involve Dalton's law we invoke Dalton's law of molar proportions
Dalton's law of small proportion
and secondly we write subject to conservation of mass conservation of matter I mean literally
mass not mall number analysts look this is probably best seen by example so it's
look at a simple 1 this is the calcination of
limestone limestone is calcium carbonate and about 900 degrees centigrade
calcium carbonate decomposes to give line for calcium oxide plus of carbon dioxide and this
is used as the 1st step for making a cement concrete and so on and
so when you think about how much cement concrete are consumed annually on the planet
this becomes a considerable source point source of greenhouse gas emissions is you know carbon
dioxide is implicated as greenhouse gas and there's a huge amount of
of C O 2 that comes from this process that is also used in steelmaking
and so so anything on the left side of the equation is called the reactant
anything on the right side of the equation is called the products of the products
react to give us reactants in distance shows some of the hitting a balance here
here we have 1 mole I don't put a 1 in front we just take
1 for granted so there's 1 mole of calcium carbonate that gives us 1 mole
of calcium oxide and 1 mole of carbon dioxide and so
here we have 2 moles and here we have 1 mole so what's the conservation
of mass if we divide by the atomic masses here we will get a 100
. 1 grams of calcium carbonate and then discovered that we have 56 . 1
grams of calcium oxide and 44 grams of carbon dioxide so clearly masses conserve not
numbers and if you have trouble balancing equations you can look in Section 2 .
1 1 in the text and they go through some
the mechanics but when without look at what happens when things are not in proper
proportion so in other words what happens if we put a bunch of other elements
compounds and reactor but they're not in the balanced amounts and so for that I
will look at the production of titanium by the crawl process and this involves the
reaction of titanium kept chloride with magnesium to form of magnesium chloride cluster containing this
was invented 19 37 by wj crawl while he was still in Luxembourg can just
before and just before World War Two broker-dealers United States and finished his career in
the Pacific Northwest where he held on make huge quantities of of titanium and this
is performed this reaction is performed giant batch type reactor in which you feed titanium
tougher chloride and magnesium and he to about 900 degrees as the reaction goes will
have some magnesium liquid sitting on top of magnesium chloride liquids and then chunks of
titanium solid forming at the bottom titanium chloride gas above and really clever reaction because
the change of records against so it's obviously buoyant magnesium liquid but it's less dense
than magnesium chloride so as these products for
they continue to fall out of the way they keep this interface opens the reaction
can keep going and the end of the reaction you have the right reactive power
consumed of 2 teams chloride magnesium you have salt on top and you have to
take him on the bottom and this is what the stuff looks like this is
earlier this summer I was on smelter in Japan the largest titanium smoke from the
planet and this is coming out of 1 of these reactors is about 3 meters
across 6 meters tall is titanium sponge comes on the bottom of this reactor that
subsequently remounted in a vacuum arc furnaces and these were generated ability of solid titania
winning tens of talking OK so let's say some young engineers on the job the
1st day and says OK let's put into 100 kilograms of tackle and let's put
about 25 kilograms of maggie using the typical terms only sister tania typical right it's
tackle this is mag undergraduate student answers of brilliant PhD student of mine and she
had 2 dogs is parenthetical and she and she loved metallurgic has idea and she