in general
here the idea is
so i just think how much risk is our economic well being when i make
a decision i'm taking some risk
i want to take a decision about by my my
job career taking the really risky decision
if i want to be an academic economist and started do a phd and not
able to know now if you i will be able to secede the finish my
phd thesis
hi i'm not able to know if i'm going to sit in finding a good
in a good university and so i'm taking lot of risks
is it possible to diversify its risks
maybe yes maybe not
is it possible that the market for the classification of this
well it depends
on the distribution of the risks
if this risks our lady stable distributed with an awful lot one the market will
not work
if there the shots of distributed with an offer higher one while the market could
so it's a it's a tremendous deal tremendously important to two to understand this factor
to apply this theory to to this to this type of of literature well the
main idea is the following one maybe it's a it's something which
it's not when we have something do thinking about it very very
frequently our wealth
our present our wealth now
can be defined by the some of the discounted present discounted
the value of r wealth coming from financial markets so dividends
interest rates discounted to now
from here to the end of my life
the present discounted value of like human capital what i will able to
to gain working and this depends on my choices
depends on what choices in terms of career
and also on illiquid assets income
for example the value of the house
then i'm going to buy
in twenty years
all the value of the house that in which i live
and this is liquid it's not easy to sell the house
the problem is that the first one
can be diversified financial markets
this one
is not of this find function one
we are learning all these three
the idea is is it possible to diversify summer of love
this risk
using financial markets to make
well for policies for example
this is idea of showing one the main point is that in terms of wealth
this council ten percent discount format so there is a huge scope for diversification in
this case
well what about these shocks
i have some
summers lies about some possible implementation and i'm going out of time so i'm going
to just to present some results i think i was skip theoretical results but i
don't have time enough so what about it
once again for the united states there is a huge amount of food available as
regard for the average highly wage
four occupations of the four-digit level
and we have data from two thousand one to two thousand three to five thousand
six the the number of data points is quite high for economics
so we can try to reason with this data
this is an idea of how much you gaining if you work in some position
position means that we have data for a supply manager working in the automotive sector
and supply manager working in the food sector
so we have data for different positions in different sectors it doesn't matter
since we have data for different years and we can try to
of wages
over time some
i know that i sample is very small but these are the
we have about about this position so we are forced to use them
so if you calculate the cumulative growth rates
cumulative growth rates which means that you
abstract from a mere increases in prices
so if you are clear
and you consider just the real wage
the number of
fan which is that you can eat in five years for example
independently of the
price of sandwiches in for years
you have a distribution
which is basically an abortion
this is the cumulative growth rates
if five years
for all these industries
if you take occupational majors
you have these special majors
and if you take
the community growth rates of
are basically
upper bound this by a sum of probabilities now I have one probability for each of these terms
and is a sum of a calligraphic N such probabilities and then I can use a general thought
for each term
so this is this second form of the Chernoff bound that was referring
to empirical quantities how far they deviate from each other
if I plug this in and then what I get is
I have this shattering coefficient
I also have a sum that goes over this number of terms and for each term
I get something like this and
if I put this together I get this kind of bound what does this tell us
this tells us that if the shattering coefficient
if it's somehow is well-behaved in particular if it doesn't grow exponentially in M then this second
term will always win
because this the case is exponentially fast
so in that case the right inside will go to zero whether I'm speaking differently now
maybe I'm getting too emotional that the bound is close this is the so-called Vapnik Chervonenkis
time unequality so this is a a
people call this a tail bound in statistics and maybe just to discuss it little bit so
there are two types of randomness in here one is that
this P over here refers to drawing training examples we are drawing training examples from our unknown
underlined probability distribution so this is this tells us how likely is it that we
get a training set for which this is the case
and the second randomness is that here on the
these risks
and these are an expectation over the same probability distribution well okay this one is a product measure so
products of this distributions this is the distribution itself so here we also have
we are using this probability distribution when we compute this expectation and here of course this is a risk so its
expectation over the whole distribution in other words we think of this as a test
and we can also rewrite this bound if we want so now here in this form the bound
tells us that is very unlikely for training error and test error to be very
different upsilon different it's very unlikely this term will be small for large training set sizes we can rewrite this
by specifying the probability with which we want the risks to be close to the
training error and then solving for upsilon maybe this is a nice exercise
if you want to play around with with it and we can then rewrite this
bound in two lines
in that case the bound will tell us that with the probability of at least
one minus delta
this test error is upper bounded by the training error plus some quantity that
depends on this shattering coefficient
here you can also see this thing here will go to zero as M goes to
infinity and if this
shattering coefficient does not grow exponentially in M then this thing here will always win against
this because here we have a a logarithm
and this bound is this is now a typical learning theory bound
it's kind of surprising that something like this is true it tells independent of the
functions so this holds uniform over the whole function class in particular it holds for the function minimizing
the risk so if we choose
all function by minimizing some kind of training error then this bound still holds because it
holds for all functions and maybe let's see maybe I should discuss this a little bit actually but actually let's
first talk a bit more about capacity concepts and I think in the end I will have I will state
something like this bound again so this is not the best possible bound you can give
people have looked at constants and so on in detail and more sophisticated ways of doing things
that's one comment the other comment we can minimize the bound over the function so that's
something that maybe we would like to do cause in the end we want a function that generalizes
well so we might say well okay you might say
okay you've convinced me that I shouldn't be minimizing just a training error
so I gave you an example where we used the class of all possible functions
the training is basically meaningless the test error can be arbitrarily different eventhough the training
errors are the same so maybe you convinced the training error is not the whole story
but you might say well in that case let's just minimize this right inside
of course we would like to do something like that we cannot do it directly because
okay this is a property of the function here but this over here is
not a property of the function it's a property of the function class that we are
choosing from so it doesn't matter what is the solution that you came up with
at the end but it matters
what set of solutions you were chosing it from so if you give someone a training set
some machinery guy he comes back and says hey I have a solution for you
then you cannot assess whether this is a good solution or not you should you
should just asking well which solutions did you choose from and if he said I choose from our
a huge class of solutions then can say well that's probably rubbish what you're telling me If he
so that is
i will tell
i will be your lecture this term
make sure you have and out and make sure you read it
it tells you everything you want to know about the course
this course
is about waves and vibrations
but also solutions
periodic not so periodic events
when you look around in the world
you see them everywhere
one thing
your heartbeat
that's the periodic oscillation
least i hope that for most of you
this periodic
some kind of aperiodic
the blinking of your eyes
the daily routines and you have it's
taking a shower
two classes
and occasionally doing some work all those are
periodic actions
when you drink
i think some orange juice
the notices i try to
move the liquid down into my stomach
that's not a steady stream
but it's a periodic motion
look at my throat
in fact
even if i don't want to swallow the lake
but simply have the ball was liquid and i turn it over
that we all know that the water doesn't come out like a steady stream
but it goes clock clock clock clock
that's some kind of the periodic motion
i have you
the toy which i used to entertain my dinner guests particularly
physicists is interesting
the liquid and the idea is to get the liquid there
and then the problem is how can you do to them the fastest possible way
well if you turn it over you see that phenomenon that i just mentioned
which is that
well it's not a steady stream it's almost pathetic
the way that runs from one side to the
i will take minutes
before is there
but it can be done in seventeen seconds
during the five minute intermission that we have
you may give it a try
and i hope you won't break it
and see whether any of you can think of the way
you can transfer liquid
in seventeen seconds
you have breakfast in the morning
and you can surely
put your breakfast plate on the table
what do you
some kind of the periodic motion
and two things can happen to displayed
it can move as in only i called is as muesli because i'm straumur
but it can also well
in fact something can wobble without moving at
that something can
move as smoothly without warning
in this case does both
and the a example of that
is what's called
the is this
which is
a metal disk
you'll see it shortly there
and these metal disc
we're going to wobble in this in a way that i will place
and then we'll follow its motion
as in new zealand
and the wobbling frequency
what is interesting as you will see
that the as new so motion which has a certain period
that period gets longer in time
but the wall motion
the frequency goes up
so i started here
and then i'll show it to you
in a way that is more
you can follow that
it's an amazing toy
to work out to physics
very very difficult
i was told that professor wilczek at MIT once gave a one-hour lecture
exclusively on the explanation
of these orders this
try to see the
as useful motion it will become clear as it slows down further
you may be able to use the wall motion i will hold my microphone close
here it is
very high frequency already that you hear it
quite amazing isn't it when you look at this
while building
frequency increased quite rapidly
recall the as you so motion slows down
how the frequency of
the wobble goes up
that an outcome of
very difficult
piece of physics right there
if you take a tennis ball
this is the super bowl
and you want it
the school student involvement thank you
then you also get some kind of the periodic motion whereby by
again the frequency increases just like
in the case of the order this guy the
breakfast plate
zero z
right but if you sort of right i said that's the thing that makes the
distribution normalize
and so if you had a discrete set of variables would be some if you
had continuous ones it would be an integral
it's just a constant that you get by summing or integrating over all configurations this
product of all the terms on your critiques
so it seems kind of boring but
in any learning problem that thing will be something like the log the likelihood of
your data
take the logo it would be the log likelihood so things like maximum likelihood or
expectation maximisation all of these things care very much the only efficient if you are
able to compute this quantity quickly
so it looks kind of innocuous but it's actually very important
right if we think about the complexity even in the discrete case you can see
it's exponential
right because
even if you just have to states a binary variables every node you have to
the information
so that thing if you think about naive is very hard
we're going to see is that if you are clever about it if you exploit
the graph structure when you've trees then you can do this exactly
you can do it by essentially
it's essentially form of dynamic programming it's known as the max product and the sum
product algorithm that's that's what we'll see
when you have cycles it's actually quite hard to many complexity theoretic results in the
literature that tell you that
it's very unlikely that people are going to be able to compute these sums in
general exactly for general problems
OK so the other problem that you might be interested in is also a summation
or integration problem let me just go back to the examples that we had
right so when we talking about speech recognition or we talking about predicting typewriter sequences
on your on your laptop or your ipad what you'd like to do is you
may be observed all the keystrokes up to some time t and you'd like to
predict the next time t plus one
that's what you'd like to do is marginalize efficiently like to summer integrate over all
these variables to try and predict what the marginal distribution is at that node
it's again a kind of summation problem into summation and integration problems
what's another problem that we might want to solve in this case
how many people know about sequence alignment problems in
computational biology
OK so what kind of problem i want to solve in that area
you could do that
but maybe let's let's be more concrete you might like to do the sequence alignment
problem you might like to search officially overall alignments and match alignments you might like
to find the alignment that maximizes the probability of being matched under some probability model
right so problems like sequence alignment many of them you can formulate them as
you're essentially building a graphical model
over sequences
and you're penalizing certain transitions are seen some transitions are more likely than others
and what you'd like to do it's kind of like a batch computation it's not
an online computation you'd like to search
over all sequences over the entire length of the sequence you'd like to search all
sequences and maximize
i find this sequence that has the highest probability of much of
matching the observed data
right so that's
like this problem i defined its instead of the summation that's a this problem down
in this problem we want to sum over all the variables in this problem we
want to maximize over the the variables
so there's sort of two different types of problems those that involve summations and those
that involve maximizations
and it sort of depends on your application sometimes you might want to compute the
likelihood of data
or you might want to compute marginal distribution to make predictions in other times you
might want to search the whole space to find the best alignment or for computer
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
OK let's get started
settle down a couple of announcements to make
and it's with great sadness that we announce there will be no lecture on Monday
no 5
with all the kleenex consumed the Kimberly-Clark went up 2 points on the New York
Stock Exchange religious freedom interview the timing of of where we are in the lectures
versus the whole of homework and there's no opportunity to interact with the recitation instructors
on Monday we're doing just this 1 time when the slide that the weekly quiz
over the Thursday that gives her time for people to contact their recitation structure and
what's going on with the lessons about I'd perhaps some of you haven't figured out
that the lecture has started and I still here talking and I invite people to
leave if they insist on
we up
so last day we talked about secondary bonding and we looked at the various forms
of secondary bonding here's the cartoons dipole-dipole interactions dipole induced dipole and solutions a little
bit of a divergent induced dipole induced dipole which was the London dispersion forces our
vendor evolves bonds and also hydrogen bonds and all of these helped us answer the
question what's the state of aggregation reason why ROC of aggregation is that this is
solid state chemistry we wanna when something is a solid so this helps us get
to that conclusion and then we came to the point where realize that three-quarters the
periodic table wasn't covered by the either are ionic bonding covalent bonding or
vendor balls bonding is primary form a bonding so we had to come up with
something else something else was metallic bonding we saw appalled through of early attempt in
1900 to model metals as a gas of free electrons moving about course where the
iron core in fact is a mix of the nucleus plus all the inner shell
and recognize that didn't take us very far so we wanted to continue the discussion
today we're going to look at this and the next installment which took place both
30 years later as part of the quantum revolution and is really to benchmarks here
the first one is
Felix Bloch Felix Bloch and display modern 1928
this was his PhD thesis
this is his PhD thesis we for his PhD thesis which was done under the
supervision of heisenberg that Leipzig took on an interesting problem so far using quantum theory
applied to gasses right
the lighter gasses bought talked talked about atomic hydrogen atomic hydrogen
you know the complexities of condensed matter
blocks PhD thesis on quantum theory of solid
let's take quantum theory applied to solids not bad for an open and quantum theory
of solids with his PhD at year's what he did you can follow the derivations
but it's quite simple firstly recognizes the atoms in a metal are arranged in a
periodic position there's an array not just thrown together in some jumbled so Adams Adams
and solid are on sat in regular
patterns rule learning next week arranged in such solids were the atoms were found in
regular patterns are called crystals crystals so he took that as 1 the benchmark the
2nd thing he says that the Member through says that the valence electrons free to
move around this is what if if these valence electrons were free to move around
what would they be subjected to they would be subjected to a potential this is
how we derive the energy levels and even a single hydrogen atom that the positive
charge the court that the negative charge electrodes and gonna electron and sees the net
positive charge of the atomic for but it's sees an array
this season
periodic variation potential so that's the 2nd thing he says
the periodic periodic potential periodic potential impacts on the valence electrons
and then invokes wave mechanics involves wave mechanics remember Schrodinger's equation was only enunciated a
couple years earlier 1926
is a PhD student years about the Schrodinger equation as applied to engage Adams and
he's applying it to
condensed matter
solves the Schrödinger equation with these constraints but and what is again get he gets
a set of solutions he gets a family of solutions but the family of solutions
and these give rise to a set of
wavelength of the electron that could move quickly through the crystal they could propagate in
other words by invoking the wave like properties of the electron he can rationalize how
these valence electrons can move through barriers that classical physics would impose
and so pretty soon of false electronic conductivity electronic conductivity so this is pretty good
for a further opening
volley and therefore PhD and he eventually to constant faculty positions and then in the
1930's when the nazis came to power block as did many of the scientists from
europe left and came to the United States and settled at Stanford and eventually he
won a Nobel Prize but not for this work this this was OK we got
Nobel Prize in 1952 for work started in 1945 and had to do with the
magnetic moments in the nucleus
so you have more than 1 good idea so that's the 1st thing we need
to think about how I in the band theory the 2nd was pair gentleman walter
height Walter height and in the same manner from last lecture Fritz London this was
before he came up with the dispersion idea the dispersion bonding was 1930 but he
and height were decided to go in 1927 desserts and spend a year post talking
with training will did they know the trading your had negotiated a position of Berlin
and names on they know new no soon arrived then the shredding left but anyways
that's what brought them to right and they decided let's take this idea of linear
combination of atomic orbitals and instead asking LinkedIn questions like is lithium 2 stable is
so this is advantageous for property standpoint but
it's very disadvantageous from the standpoint of
recycling how could one possibly recycled this material
let's compare
these two
let's compare the case of
so polyethylene consists of
many chains and they will
into penetrates and entangled
what are the bonds between these chains
the bonds between these chains are
van der waals
this is the van der waals
these are van der waals bonds and we know that animals bonds are operative at
low temperatures but not operative high temperatures so if we take polyethylene and heated
these bonds where we can and this will turn liquid
and we can be reprocess this
so by
going to high temperature
you can reprocess
because we're only breaking these
weak van der waals bonds now if we take this crosslinked
polly i supreme
crosslink collie i supreme
show it in this manner
how are we going to reprocess this if we if we begin to heat this
we're going to have to go to an extremely high temperature because we have to
break covalent bonds
well if we go to a temperature high enough to break these bonds
we got a temperature high enough to break the backbone we go to thermal destruction
of the entire material
so such materials cannot be reprocessed by heating so these are called thermo set
for most set
for most of
thermal said are very difficult to process
difficult to
you i say well you don't have to just do it by by thermally reprocessing
why don't you use some kind of chemistry
going there with chemistry that will attack these bonds these are strong covalent bonds what
kind of
solving solvent is going to be strong enough to kill a snip those bonds is
going to be very aggressive solvent and
one of the health effects of the use of that's all you want about the
company and the use of that and find out later that you've got class-action lawsuits
using such chemicals so this is the issue when you drive down the highway
and you see these mounds these mountains of spent automobile tires how to recycle
this is the issue
whereas over here you've made this up and you can redo it so such materials
are called thermal plastic
thermal plastic
they can be reprocessed or rendering plastic by
the temperature rise so they're environmentally much much easier to process
a few more things here with the polyethylene
this shows what i was doing on the
on the projector
the document camera rather this is the partially crystallized polyethylene and this is what it
looks like in the zones you don't have
all of the
change lining up but if you look at the atoms on and you will see
there's this c two h four units in the c two h four units are
lined up
and sure enough what is the basis unit here
it looks author on the as you would expect the molecule that has the aspect
ratio of two to one you expect is going to come out in one of
the brevity lattices that also has
some and i start to be associated with it
and here's an x-ray diffraction data
this is the
fraction of a fully crystalline polymers of we took a short length
and called it very slowly or took it out of the solvent we would end
up with something that's totally crystallin we see
we have a discrete peaks
here is the same material amorphous and this fits all the painful to look at
this because it's reminiscent of a question on the recent test this is what the
this is what the data shows
so by looking at this
mixed spectrum you can get a measure of the extent of crystallisation by looking at
the relative intensity of the peaks versus this broad single peak which is associated with
the first nearest neighbours
because an ethylene we know the carbon has hydrogens nearest neighbors
and so on
so this works just as well as the the free volume as a measure of
the degree of
so we see this
the last thing i want to touch upon is the polymer synthesis just to put
that into
setting i've already shown you addition polymerization
in addition polymerization
in addition polymerization involves the use of
radical or
time searching around the neighborhoods or outline
the motorbike which solves the segmentation cont problem completely for the the learner makes life
easier or if we know what describes motorbikes well we came and put them
the location of the most important features so how much are you willing to say
to the algorithm
it also depends how flexible
your model is how you know what is the the cost of human labor and
so on
of course there is the issue of batch one versus incremental learning it's all good
we have all the data available but in many cases like surveillance and so on
that we don't have that luxury or when we simply have too many images we
want to have efficient way of learning including the incremental methods we also have been
in training images in from a statistical point of view we have issues of over
fitting be very careful of that because what you see and the learning is the
noise of the training rather than the general nature of the object category and then
of course negative example is not a trivial issue at all what is the negative
of a motor bike so
and last we have the issue of prior prior will talk more about it but
it's a very interesting it's a very interesting concept in terms of
knowledge and learning
so k recognition
is were
no you have learned model you design the model now that the anomaly image comes
you're looking for the object and so in recognition there their speed is the main
issue because if you want to put this into robots are real
world systems you don't want to the
the machinery to be
to be cranking for ten hours in in order to recognise one thing so
do you want to search all over the space
for that object or do you want to have more efficient search over scale location
to find objects so these are issues one should keep in mind OK so
so i've spent my first half of the lectures setting up all the other the
problems and give you a taste of of what object recognition is is involved in
fact if you go home with this idea of
these three major
questions in object recognition and categorisation representation learning and testing be very happy so from
now on we're gonna go into specially toulmin generative models that have been used in
in the domain of
visual recognition
so the first one i term that i termed it as bag of words models
most of the early bag of words models are related to texture and
here are just some references for you so what does
that's of words model meaning or in a very very intuitive way what we're doing
is we take objects and we represent it in some kind of collection
the building blocks
of these objects so i specifically ask when will these building blocks to emphasise the
fact that most of the bag of words models do not have coherent geometric information
why do we even think was is possible to describe objects we actually got inspiration
from the text document community where if i show you document like this kind of
a lot to read but if i tell you there are some words like sensory
brain visual cortex and so on despite knowing these keywords are building blocks you get
a feeling of which class of document it comes from must be some kind of
scientific document about probably the visual system
the same thing goes for a second document where i tell you it includes things
like import-export trading you know it's probably some kind of business analysis or business news
so that means building blocks even without
the coherant geometric or in this case ordering information syntactic information gives you a lot
of meaning
two hundred documents and we believe the same is so for visual visual objects so
here the basic representation would be you take objects different classes of objects you somehow
find a dictionary of
these building blocks you represent each class of these objects by this dictionary so
i'm gonna go through a more detailed algorithm for for a couple of case studies
of different models from this bag of words object categories so we'll start with some
kind of learning with different classes of objects
and now we want to do
this is where the representation goes remember our our three issues so we will show
you how we represent images as bag of words and i will look at learning
really what the model is and how we learn that that and we want to
give taken although image and represented in the same way as all the training images
and make a decision based on the classifiers we have learned so that the overall
and will look at the representation issues first so there are three steps in representation
how do we get these building blocks how do we express them
i in
that's quite a according the same question
and so it
that itself to use in mixed method techniques
most compatible
most aligned
is when you
both questions both the quality separate them out
both open ended and non directional
that that's really
combination the works really well
so you might have a descriptive research design
and almost any of the qualitative research designs combined together
so example here would be
what's implications of the global recession
on the ability of countries and states
to address global warming
so in that situation there you've got the all the all the facing in the
open so whatever quantity that you cannot be more and quality there will be more
open ended and you put together you get an open-ended situation OK
what design could be collective case study
and that
subsumes mix of design is another thing you can do
and that's called a better design
and in tuchikoi because
fact a
and it all
we identified its ties to me because you can have
so the first one first type
you have set foot quantitative and qualitative questions
and typically you might
the question might be about how you integrate it
for example the quantitative results in quantifiers there might be a question of interest
second you might have a hybrid question
but what you said earlier
which might lead to a breakdown in the quantitative and qualitative questions
we do with this give example of the second question two extended interpretations much defaming
found at the two thousand four u s presidential election
OK how companies can be framed to better engage college students
so that might be a question that fits into the second time
the question is evolving different phases of the study
so as you do the study they just ignore the questions involved
so the so called to touch going and teddlie
they raise questions about whether only quite a quantification should be written
or whether you should have a single mixed methods question that you saw earlier
or single mix question transcends the quality and quantity some questions
so they have a few recommendations first
mixed methods studies need atleast one explicit formulated mixed methods question objective about the nature
and that question
quite a tighter questions that led to the specific needs
in answer to questions
OK second
so to benefit from these ones
a large and makes specific question
and it gives you the possibility of softball questions
the natural form of the question might be quite different in been sequential
so that's kind of this the quick tour through research questions
six is often design
and this is quite complex if you want to have a design that you know
you are able to
to make sense of
so we often have some force that typology so we say that a random sample
in its qualitative
none sampling in qualitative
but that's not strictly true
they're tighter generalizations external statistical
intelligence statistical
a if you have hours to external
that's when you go from the sample to the population so people say about generalizing
that's the big what they mean you go for from the sample to the population
another type that we don't often talk about this much
his intelligence is categorisation so you have a mate may be doing qualitative study
and you have
a sample
you have what's called key informants
and from there you go from the key informants
to the population
then you have
and it's good jazz asian
and that's where is very common in qualitative
well you see how it fits
so when you say and the themes where
you making in some kind of liquid risation k
OK so case stands you might be the case study
you go one by one
in the case
two major innovations case-by-case
the naturalistic state
points out
it's where you the reader
makes generalizations once you read the article from the findings to those of phi beta
site so we we've identified
so when you have a mixed methods study
you essentially have
at least two phases have a quantitative phase
and the qualitative phase
those faces i have some combination of random sampling could be
random on random
and the most common the most common type you have combinations
is that type four which were both in non random
because researchers have found that
in the qualitative what about ninety five percent studies
the social with sizes
use non random sampling and five ten years opposite that's the goal
most quantitative research about majorisation
and you look almost every information technique has that an assumption
it's typically hard to do
the political world is probably probably have more instances that because you're dealing with
a lot i you may may involve polling
we able to do that but in many other fields is very difficult to defend
true sense
at where is the sense of communication and interaction start in terms of not only
according to to the social emotional side and then you could robot potentially bridges with
people to help stop its own
cognitive development that was really the inspiration
because is still an idea that was driving lot of the work and social robots
or developmental approach something to show you a video of this robot in action with
the person
can work
OK and with this work list for this
and then show you
we're going to get there
believe that
OK thank you for
very much
he all along
so long some
kind of
one one
i don't want to
one two
so which is particularly good video i think
but what you want to see if this was really kind of our first attempt
at this and so
one of the things that we learn about this was that it was really
provocative and raises questions in terms of
you know what kind of creature we so to speak that we are so willing
and able to almost effortless effortlessly going to this kind of
very interpersonal interaction with something that obviously
just to machine i mean pulling sort of social cues like i think i of
but it is not trying to hide the fact that this machine
so i decided that's what kind of machine we need to build to really be
able to participate in an engaging sort of interactions with humans and of course the
scientific question what could be learned
about ourselves to the positive actually trying to create these sorts machines and of course
the final thrust would be
given abilities in machine learning disabilities what kinds of new applications like that enable
to help improve quality of life for people all over the world so this is
the question that motivates my work in the personal robotics
to go back to the project
so i think one of the things that's very intriguing about robotics is when you
think about humans
we're starting to appreciate in science that we are really you know our behavior it's
very complex is first gets at the intersection multiple facets or which are shown here
which i think also share strong energy provided to the fact that we used to
think that emotion cognition with very distinctive was cool rationality and there was hot motion
but now we're finding that actually motion honest deeply intertwined then that can be intelligent
certain motion systems are functioning properly we should think of as being the might be
distinct from the body
but now to development and so forth the finding the course manager told that we
have is very intimately connected to the embodiment that we have and of course were
profound social species so i think one thing that's exciting about robotics is as the
technology perhaps better than any other technology today
and really engage us and all of these different facets all these differences and i
think that really opened up new
opportunities in your questions to explore
the big i think better for change with a kind of paradigm change that a
lot of social robotics which are pushing that is in the past really robots more
so toward tool that we can use to do things for us that we can
do task far from us
and of course new sort of work is posing this question
what if robots can be partners who can do things with collaborators as and i
this is the opening of all these questions in terms of how do you need
human human bodies robot bodies and robert mines
so that the fundamental question what i want to touch impact that with you the
rest of this talk
so morning my my subordinating bodies we know that from psychology
we know from things such as the room by the back
four people were project mental states to understand and explain this behavior even though it's
clearly not
having either any sort and features and it turns out that even for humans is
is very low level features that when they move in a proper way this is
the famous that i have a little showing that even just moving shapes on the
screen they move an appropriate way that suggests chasing and fleeing
people don't describe the shapes in terms of physics in terms of spatial relations they
describe happening streams in terms of emotions and mental states
there's something about the way that our brains are wired with things moving behave in
certain ways
we use the only different way to think about them using terms this theorem under
the mental capacity to understand things in terms of the underlying mental states and of
course robotics is that you don't have to have an exact humanoid form in order
to do this is a very intriguing designs
so i want to show you video that maybe many of you have seen this
in two thousand four
when apple computers
i was trying to introduce new idea
so we are able to engage many kinds of morphology in this way of interacting
so one question that we had recently with what we actually built
a robot computer what if instead of having sort of animation and what we actually
built an everyday artifacts and infuse robotic
qualities to it so this is called broker and rocco has a number of degrees
of freedom
and you can imagine putting cameras and sensors and can areas behaviours here postures and
so forth so why is the interesting and this is the collaboration with the cartoon
the computer immediately to mary pressures
why is this interesting
we were inspired one of the questions that are going to computer was inspired by
a study done in nineteen eighty four by
john risk and
which is really exploring in humans again this interface between emotion
an embodiment and
and the role of the body
and it's very intriguing study where he took set of human subjects and he had
to do with that trace fossils so identified
o point here
so this is an interesting puzzle task were
is working
it also
so have the option to feel quite quite a number of times so basically what
he did is under the biometrics experiment invented the people in these two conditions into
another room and had to actually sit in the past year so this in very
might be analogous to being proud
successful and the idea perhaps it's too
as if they fail and how the whole that three minutes
and then brought them back and do more distressing for all of the unsolvable
what he found was that OK
what he found was in the case where people are body posture and mood congruence
people had more persistence on the task even in the case where the institute
so we called this that stoop to conquer
so this is an intriguing is intuitive right is coded but
again is deeply intertwined systems of course it's intriguing to think about what the robot
can robots interface with us in our bodies and our emotions and conditions in which
that can help us perform better
one question would be can you actually replicating this to conquer fact
as the problem
so but this picture was that a little bit vague
it was vague because
depending so you can you can put the ball in very different places so you
can put the ball the of this robot or agent
at the other place that there is a physical interaction with the environment like you
have a robot and it has person and we assign acting on the environment and
the environment is is putting energy into the sensors of the robot you can put
the body that
but on the other hand if you don't want to do this the physical interactions
but you may only are interested in this business of the brain pong
then probably you want to get some deeper
and this is what we are going to do so this is the viewpoint that
we're going to take you don't want to care about the physical processes
they say that after
this interaction happens is the environment
that need some
mechanism that that transforms advertising into cities of bits or whatever
so i just wanted to care about the software not the brain pod
this figure shows that shows how this is happening so there are these acts sensations
coming in
and the actual agent that we do care about is somebody inside and many things
can happen just this in the boundary of the robot you know the physical boundary
of the robot
so we
do not necessarily care is the the pure sensor readings right so we don't want
to care about the what voltages or whatever
so that would be some nice and clever
mechanism that do some field carrying the rejection of noise or whatever
but what's important for us is that after this is done
we can really just care about the brain of the robot
so in particular
it it it is good to keep in mind that you could have sensations coming
from axon and other than the internet part of the robot put it to stay
what do i mean by that so if you have here
if you have a body
then maybe you have
times are something like that if you're a box
and arms could have various chance and then you can measure the angles of the
chance of the angular velocity of the challenge those would be internal sensations and
and those sensations i really part of a of the sensations
in particular
there is one more thing that will hopefully become more clear
so we have we see here an arrow that states state
so particle of what happens is that there should be a mechanism the robot that
does some processing that constructs so something that's called the states it was the state
so the state should be something like citation statistics for the future
and this will be your main assumption that that in this series of talks
that that is some mechanism that's able to construct the state if
we see the consequences if there is no such mechanism
or how you can approximate such a mechanism but but this will be are working
how do this
and then
you know this spring practices sizeable the actions
but actions could be high level actions they do not necessarily have to be real
actions like turning the wheel by is
just one degree or something like that
so anyway so we're are going to have sector is some details
by proposing mathematical model
so this is a generic mathematica model
so you have planned control the
the state of the plant is developing according to this is activation so this is
a very generic information so
it has no structural whatsoever i'm just saying that the next state is dependent on
the previous state and the current actions and there is some noise injected into the
system so this state i was in in a noisy
and then
what the robot can also have this is not actually the state but just something
what is about
and you find
thank you
are not
we have help
from i think
right here is
they area
we must
in the
i mean it
so he
we want to
o o
so when
your you're notion how
close you are to the best error rate
the best
is larger than new
will be able to get an exponential convergence
and then
that someone
you know just how close you are to the best boxes
is smaller than
the convergence is is no longer
it should be a new there
then get convergence is no longer
exponential it's going to be as if we're in supervised learning land
this is going to be new squared here
so we all get a little bit of benefit from doing active learning
some sort of constant factor improvement
the number of labelled samples that are required
so these two are obviously straightforward to show you a little bit how having these
proofs work because it's it's informative
OK so does seem to think about is sort of the noiseless case
one year when you're running through
this to think about the noiseless case for thresholds when year
first thinking about the fear
so in the noiseless case thresholds
the area is a function of the threshold parameter is going to be
it's kind of like like this
some sort of
absolute value
and then
the claim is that
if you have
a small no
that doesn't really all to this picture very much it's going to increase the to
buy new and then these lines here can generally shift but i don't know
or maybe a bit less
so this this picture is going to look very similar when you have a small
middle married
so what that means is that
is it a constant fraction
the classifier to to area point you've i tried to this is about point two
five here
in a constant fraction about half of them
have an area greater than point two five
OK so
what that means is that if we have
about blog whatever delta samples to
the we label just at random
we're going to be able to get upper bounds and lower bounds
which are
type two within maybe one eight
it's still in the general case
the same logic applies except now the number of labelled samples requires is maybe a
little bit larger
it is the this this data collection company
this disagreement coefficient
OK so now
since i have the fractions
and have fraction of classifiers
air which is very the point two five
any bounded tied to within
o point one two five
you can be you can guarantee
at the minimum of around
it will
will be
o point one two five less
and the
the least half the cost of the hypotheses have
have narrative
the lower bound of twenty five or more
so you can eliminate
have a disagreement region
that's the that's the fundamental logic which is going on
and then you need if you do about this but you know how to do
OK so
so now
that that's the case when you get exponential improvement in very happy we still sort
of like to understand what happens when
when you have a substantial
no married
we get
the basic recursion process is going to
keep as it were keeping we cursing
the size of the region is something like lightning
and that's just using the prefix there
and now it's going to happen
it is we have this termination condition which is done
is less than epsilon
this is
this is one part of done is disagree with reason to be like news so
we have this new multiplayer here
so what happened is we recursively times and now the noise rises to height restriction
so now we have two
compute upper and lower bounds
and then we we get a little the boost from this new because new value
is is less than or equal to one
so if we want
this quantity to be less than that someone
we just need to get the bounds
we we need this to the men minus
the upper bound must lower bound
to be
spent two epsilon over new since new is less than one
it means that we need your samples to get tight enough found
and then and then done will be
about that song
so that's why
you get this kind of behaviour that
and then i guess
that people look at one two three or four abstract but not really more than
like his whole often the click
one link
and you can see that even more skewed for the
in this case almost three times as many people
click on
the result ranked number one
then on the result rank number two
so writing is very important in the sense that people click on the top ranked
and you can actually for people
here we have a result for regular search rankings for the first result is relevant
and the second is not relevant and that case it's not surprising that most people
take on the first result but then if you
search around the two
so now the first one is not one of them but
the second the second is the relevant one people still think on the first one
even though it is not relevant
so you can see there
some people automatically go the first one because they
i have developed some
trust in the search engines and the search engines will actually present most relevant
the result first
so in summary important frank
viewing abstracts uses a lot more likely to read the abstracts of the top ranked
then the extract of the lower ranked pages
taking the distribution is even more skewed for clicking
there's a very strong bias to become the top ranked page
even if the top ranked page is not relevant thirty percent of users will click
so getting the ranking is very important in getting the top ranked page right is
most important and so that's that's supposed to serve as motivation for
four why ranking information retrieval is an important problem
OK so that was the only way model the index processing boolean queries why do
we need ranked retrieval
and maybe can ask all i put some resources on
our books side information the article
so you've have for this that to you find this stuff useful information resources
shakespeare search engine that school in
and then russell's home page where you can look up the original slides that of
the of the user study the national
maybe i can ask the question
many of you i think uses maxent so i assume you spotlight and i'm not
sure that on on on this is this a similar search system is spotlighted billions
of system
no why not
right so it's important to distinguish between
a pupil in system where
things are where everything is presented that's the that satisfies the william period but then
some of things coastal
i mean have
some of the order of is imposed on this set were not so spotlight
imposes an ordering like you suggested that
i think it's actually the most recent opening
or a combination of the most recent opening up the number of openings
and in many other search engines use use use time for example if you search
for citations often you get the most recent citations on the line for example the
most recent citations first but they are million engines in the sense that
a document that does not contain all the keywords is not included in the results
and google also was initially a search engine like that
it was william in the sense that only documents that contain all the search terms
were included in the
results but then not was supposed to
any questions about this
o point or anything else in this
part of the lecture
OK and that's continue with the vector space model
OK a quick review of tf idf weighting
then the vector space model which represents theories and documents and i dimensional space
and then pivot normalisation that's an alternative to cosine normalisation that removes a bias inherent
in standard length normalisation
the reason for this is that again it's very nice methodological point
your system is not what you wanted to do how can you analyse it and
how can you prove that this is a nice example of
so we start with this line
these are the terms
all words by the way of using trying work interchangeably years
and these documents
and now moving from by
term incidence matrix
two a column matrix where each document is represented as a vector of counts so
now i want to use the card information the fact that sometimes occur several times
in the document because that is important information for ranking
we use the term frequency for that and that is defined as
the number of times that you because that is the term frequency tf td
we want to rank documents according to query document matching scores
and use the city as a component in these matching scores
but how
we could use water frequency simply the can't but that's not what we want because
the document ten occurrences of the term is more relevant than a document with one
occurrence speed
could surmise
but not type ten times more
relevance does not increase proportionally with term frequency
so we're trying to find some criteria for ranking but we don't want to do
it proportionally because
we need to have some of
we need to be very careful about how we include this information directly
so instead of raw frequency going to use long sequences
suppose there the the function minimizing
the objective is separable
so it's it's the sum of functions of blocks of the original vector right so
it separates out like this this could be all the way down to the components
but this could be vectors as well so it
this is separable
well in that case the lagrangian is separable
and because you're adding now find function but all i find functions are separable then
the component so
this is separable and what that says is that this minimisation
over the lagrangian over x actually splits and can be done in parallel because
it's it's because humanizing something that is of some
of functions of independent variables
so you just do it in parallel
that leads to
dual decomposition and that looks like this and again i know that many people know
this so but this is just sort of give you historical background and review so
with our this each of these things
minimizes the lagrangian give you a price vector each minimizes their the lagrangian terms separately
you collect the contribution to the equality constraints and you evaluate the residual of zero
you quit
otherwise you update the price vector and you can see that what this requires is
something like
the gathering the scattered
right so you have to gather
these components to evaluate the residual
and you scatter the price effect
right so that but now you have died doing distributed optimisation
all right
next topic is that's maybe from around nineteen sixty something like the next method of
and what method of multipliers well sort its method that's meant to robustify dual asset
right so
to actually make it so that it would work on things like linear programming and
stuff like that which this
absolutely will not and the idea here
goes back at least the sixties but in fact it can be can be argued
to go earlier to operator splitting methods but that case
it is to the normal this is this is here the usual lagrangian terms and
you can think of this is sort of like pure free market term this is
going to violate the constraints but you pay for it these prices
well you pay for it or you're subsidized for depends on which end of that
year on
and then you have another term which is always nonnegative quadratic penalty
right and this this this one is
that's always
sort of cost is never subsidy right so this is this is simply cost for
not for the market not clearing for example in economics right so it's an augmented
lagrangian and the method of multipliers
it looks like this
you minimize the augmented lagrangian
and then
you do i dual update and it's exactly the same
it's identical to
do less and except for one thing the
the the gain
in the gradient update has a very specific choices to play this role it's the
it's the parameters here
right and the reason for that and it's easy to
i understand that
the original problem i mean when it differentiable
the original problem the optimality conditions are primal
what about feasibility so you have to x equals b and then you have to
have dual feasibility which is that the gradient policy transpose why stars zero
and if xk plus one minimizes this thing where you work out the guns and
differentiable case but it's the same and non differentiable case you work out what
what it means to minimize that will it just means that the gradient of the
augmented lagrangian is zero when you work out what that is and you recognise
this term here and you realize
if i were to if this were to be y plus one then it says
the following it says that at the end of method of multipliers each step
dual feasibility always
right so so in fact what it says is that with that choice of
with that choice of update
dual update you could dual feasibility sort of that happens for free then what you're
what it means is
as the algorithm progresses which are hoping is that the is that the residuals the
primal residuals will go to zero
OK so that's the that's the idea
now that's good news and bad news
so the good news is that
adding the quadratic augmenting term on i should add you know you can add
other types of augmenting terms that's become very popular in the last couple of years
we bregman divergences are things like that always keep i'll stick with quadratic because it's
simple and if you understand that you can surely understand what happens if you had
like in entropy or something like that there are some OK
the good news is adding that
adding that regularisation makes this goal makes
dual as and go from a very fragile algorithm
that's the kind of the coaxed to work and in most cases you would think
that doesn't work at all to something
OK so in this case we said the costa going to catch point one millisecond
with point one seconds
costa going to the desk is ten million seconds
and now what we're left is to figure out what the probability of this
if you think about
a system for a little bit you might say well OK so what's the what's
the system look like what's the probability that the idea get that they we're actually
going to get hit this
and if you have with applications are doing is simply generating random
requests for random pages which might be one model the application behaves there doesn't seem
like the cat is going to buy is very much right because the cat is
going to be a small fraction of the total size of the disk it might
be in RAM so we might have a hundred megabytes we might ten jacobi to
right so
that means there's a factor one hundred difference between these two things of the discrete
page requests random probability that something is going to be in the captions can be
very low it's going to be only say one percent
but it turns out that almost all applications have an interesting property which is commonly
referred to as
locality of reference
what this means is that if you look at which pages a program is likely
to access over time be these pages of data or parts of a program typically
programs page has been accessed recently is very likely to be accessed again so simple
example might be that if you look at the files that are being used in
a computer system usually there's a small set of files the users working with any
given point in time running certain programs editing certain documents and there's a huge array
of other programs and files and documents there on the system that you are accessing
so and when those files are doing this active files are being accessed is much
there's a much higher probability of getting a hit of looking at those active files
there is going to any one of the other files so even when the difference
between these things is a factor of one hundred in the case of the web
maybe be very likely that we would have no ninety percent maybe of the pages
that have been accessed
are already in the cache stake
so in that case sorry this probability should be point nine ninety percent
OK so i suppose that the probability of
excuse me this should be this is the probability of hitting ninety percent probability of
missus then ten percent
OK so the if you if you think if you look at the now with
this sort of formula evaluates to receive point one plus
ten times point one so it's one point one million seconds
on average assuming that we get ninety percent hit rate cash
so if you if you know come come back to this diagram that means that
we can the throughput of this boxes
you know is one over
one point one member because throughput is just one over latency when we have just
sort of this one module which means that are now we can process something like
this this is something like
say this should be
one of related is that this is in millisecond so this point one one
the number of seconds this is point zero zero one one right so one of
our point zero zero one one is
about nine hundred cases we can get about nine hundred requests per second which can
process instead of just one hundred
this is approximately equal
OK so what we did manage to do is to increase the throughput of the
stage by about a factor of nine
i mean you can see that sort of all three of these stages are close
to about one thousand across the second increase the performance of the system pretty dramatically
by introducing cash
and you have to remember that this cat is only going to be a sort
of it's only going to be a good idea
when we're sure that we have this locality of reference property so if the web
server is
going to a random page then we're not going to be if the web server
sort of disaster for random page and every request the cache is not going to
be a good choice but most of the time web servers at this locality property
so the last little detail that we need to talk about when we talk about
is simply
the is the
sort of question about how we do
how we deal with page eviction so in this diagram here
when we call added to the cache
if the cache is already full of results we have to pick something to replace
so we need what's called a page removal or page
replacement property policies
you guys presumably have seen different page remove or plays replacement properties and six double
four before
i'll just talk about two very quickly
fifo policy and l are you policy
so if i o means is first in first out so it says the the
that the thing to throw out is the first thing that we loaded into the
OK so y access
a set of pages
no one is supposed to have a three element cache accesses pages one two three
two one four
what i'm going to do is low this with what i mean
you can access these three pages this is going to be paid one will be
the first one in my cache so when i try and load page four
i'm going to give it h one
i think that's what's going to happen in five five system because one was the
first one is loaded
but the least recently used approach says is instead of evicting the first thing that
was putting the cash we want to evict the last thing that was read
from the cache
so in this case if i do one two three two one and then again
for the last thing it was red with three and that's what i want from
so if you think about the intuition behind these two policies
and you said you realize that this fifo approach has a problem which is that
it's sort of contrary to this of the notion of locality of reference right because
it says it doesn't capture anything about health sort of frequently data i data is
accessed or when it was last accessed it simply
you just throw something in vitro something that has the it grows the sort of
everybody knows g packet type of fourier analysis on images
it assumes a fixed to the topology so we really can't use it in three
but given the widespread importance of three d there's really and the fact that three
d images
and three d objects are very large
you want some sort of compression methods
there's a lot of interest in this in the computer graphics community
so what i'm going to show you is one of the solutions that was open
computer graphics and then when compared with another approach
that i've been working on
so let's first familiarize themselves with what we mean by three objects so it really
object essentially is specified by
jamie two components
so you have an object here is a pretty small objects
you can model is a graph and this is the adjacency matrix of the graph
the topology of the object
and it's geometry by its geometry means
you can think of the XYZ coordinates functions and the graphs essentially implanting here each
of these coordinate functions on the graph
so the problem of three compression is essentially to find
a new set of coordinate representations
that you can use to projective geometry on the take up far less space than
the usual representation
now there are two approaches to solve this problem
one approach is to essentially ignore topology and just focus on geometry
so you can just take the score functions and then use your favourite compression method
but there's been growing movement in computer graphics to see whether you can actually do
something with topology and derive adaptive compression methods that bill that are specific to each
so as you go to large objects you can notice the size of the particular
on growing and so
even this is not a particularly large objects so you know this is this is
a very challenging problem because you objects in millions
of vertices and so you want to fast compression methods
so the method i want to start talking about first is one that was introduced
by khanin gottesman from israel nine siggraph two thousand
the idea is very simple
you take the topology of the object it's a graph
you generate the eigen vectors of the graph plots in
and then you project the coordinate functions on
the first few i vectors of the graph class and this is essentially
fourier analysis
extended to graphs so
let's first review this method and then let's see what the limitations of this method
are before introducing a different method
so we've seen that the graph the class c and has been used in many
contexts in machine learning actually was for studying on the mid-seventies by fiddler was a
czech mathematician to be used for spectral clustering lots of work and semi supervised learning
in this conference
and someone that you may not be familiar with we've been exploring the use of
the class c for approximating functions called value functions in markov decision process
so is about the class and let's think of about differential representation of according to
functions rather represent each function exactly what we're going to do is going to look
at the difference between the value of the function at some coordinator at some vertex
x minus the average of the values that you would get by taking the neighbors
and computing sort of the the the average to the extent the degree of vertex
so you can represent this effect in matrix form using this and this is one
of the class in school the discrete blocks in
there's a strong connection between the discrete laplacian and random walks
so if i take any
a weighted graph
undirected graph and random walk is just
the probability of visiting any neighbour
with probability proportional to one by degree of the vertex
the two kinds of plants intimately familiar with other combinatorial applies in those mentioned in
the first talk
and the normalized laplacian and you can easily show the normalized policy n
has its spectral structure very closely related to the random walk matrix and that's a
fairly easy identity show
this is classical fourier analysis on graphs
and let's see how it works on this problem before we look at what limitations
it has
so first let's look like in plus in on three d objects here some lori
connectors on the skull had
here's the higher order i lectures the two things are not one is generally the
supported by conductors the whole object so these basis functions are global demand not local
this is actually going to be a problem
and second you see the higher order argument is generally start eliminating high frequency regions
and so as you look at the argument personal or high order
you will see that they essentially have more variation and
they get less small
so the process is very simple you take a target function
you projected on the first few i vectors of the class and if you do
in linear least squares fitting non-linear least squares you can select the documents are order
and this is standard fourier
this discourse projection so here's an example of the pig and his original reconstruction of
the hundred basis functions
and his with a hundred basis functions
there's been a lot of follow-on work about with this approach in computer graphics where
people have to apply this to do things like spectral watermarking and various other things
there some variants of this approach that i will talk about so what are the
limitations of this approach
the limitations of this approach primarily have to do with the limitations of fourier analysis
one of the problems with doing i can vector approximations of these core functions is
that when you have functions that have very varying degree of smoothness it's very hard
to get them right so here you have the horns of the cow
which are very sharp
and you also have very smooth regions and you're trying to get large
i can vectors to correspond to approximate these sort of a shop regions while retaining
fidelity in the very small regions
especially for long
they will have very small number of users point or the point of view would
be useless and
remember that point separated b so it will be extraction
what you want this naive implementation is feasible to put into
random access memory and to use
so what we can do
we can
you can compress
we can compress the this is
the simplest approach what we can do
you can say OK
most of the work especially the end
they have the same
we have already
when we have only one point to the next right
again remove find special additional type of node history
and if you looking for kat the same example
in this area we have terminal also meaning that this is what
but if you looking for constantly
really it from this arabian coming to
this training and although there is no any other branches everything but a up
this approach
we have the same the same complexity we need to check exactly the same number
of characters
while size of memory
reduces dramatically and this talk it's important we now
can feet everything into
into our random access memory
also have
dry structures they
i have a lot of what the advantages because you can read them again incinerate
alphabetically sorted
but all of them the only one so
the biggest disadvantage is that
a lot of allocation of memories so there are some
additional memory but it's actually an avoidable should are doing if you are going to
do research in the dictionary
basically we always have some
not uniform but memory access but it's again in many senses and would you will
always have some
not a local memory access pattern in dictionary
OK so another approach what we can do
we can use that is completely another approach
in all previous slides we did some checking with some results we went to
to the right to the left
but what we can do can we can completely avoid
they can
take this work at
then calculate the hash function that has all
all of this war
and great some small numbers of small index
let's see this has a hash function that exist in the world simply too
some together owing according to all
characters of this work
it's not important but because it it doesn't
and around the place on the order of of characters in the world so you
can use something more complex but if you are you
if you use
somewhere in a prose you can do you can do it
and then
simply jump to
every element
this indicates that you got from this from this calculation
so sociology very fast only calculating fishpond
in so far
it's extremely fast too because simply doing this calculation and go to this element in
the input data
actually have
have to
the problem with this
so we need to select good point because
if you have and like it it's possible that huge number of towards getting the
same partition disarray
and it's not cool
you to call to avoid this but it's unavoidable because we're trying to
lose information using a lot of the compression
this is the first problem the second problem
in the two problems are connected to the size of the story
many scripting languages are using fashion default implementation of
map of structures that maps key to win
and name some of them is problem quite
why they're doing this extremely exactly because it fast
and in all scripting languages you're doing a lot of research and so so that
if you're
programmer only programmers here
if you are a programmer and you want to implement information retrieval system using
i there's always using something like this adding for
or if you using
get the same the same situation
the problem is what all doing if they have a college
if suddenly optics
for example dogs
comes with booklet full function and we see that in the same
cell of the array in the same element
we already have
don't care
so what are going to do
well it's pretty simple thing
in this case is simply
incremental size of this series twice
and reallocate elements new position
it's OK for scripting language
but if you are implemented by playing out a search engine
very soon when in this in this
you see that not only is system became extremely slow
not only
you're all tiny bit application that is very interesting but automation system is going down
because the size of the array
became so so huge
but it doesn't fit into memory in the process trying to
so this problem doing a lot
is that a lot of walking
removing weight from memory to the skin trying to relocate
and i have a lot of people who all around into this problem the programming
problem the try to
decision tree well that's the kind of thing is right
here we're trying to do is say OK what's the analogue for
for clustering and analog here is the property if the relation between the target and
the similarity function or science what relations give us enough information then we can hope
to cluster well and by what kind of
so i'm not coming the properties we haven't necessarily you know
the only ones one continues but so we're trying to figure out
what this theory looks like you know what kind of properties are sufficient for clustering
what properties are not and right now we've been looking at history property where you
can search the street conditions for your goals to produce tree you can look at
other kind of goals
you can relate the two implicit assumptions made by approximation algorithms percent objectives like k
median k means so if you're using an algorithm with approximation of one of these
implicitly you're hoping any approximate solution to this objective must actually be close to the
target function is that's the reason trying to optimize the objective
and if you make it explicit if you say look i'm just scanner
i'm using this argument because i'm hoping that any approximate solution of the objective function
is close to the target
and that you can prove that implies your data
most data points have to actually be strictly more similar to points of their labelled
another label the most have to have that condition can kinda connect these two the
simplest things you're something which is
this is just and so in this part we looking at what properties similarity function
are sufficient to be useful for clustering
reviewing the unlabelled data multiclass learning problem
the an interesting theory we had to relax we mean by useful useful means you're
producing just the right answer you really need strong conditions particularly organ a little slack
you say look it can produce the tree like the user figure out how specifically
meant to be then you can start saying all these conditions are sufficient
it this a kind of PAC model for clustering
these live interesting directions to explore here something we've just been looking at relatively recently
and i just want to mention some
nine research question
for instance very natural a very powerful class clustering algorithms are local spectral methods that
use i conductors and we haven't been able to come up with really natural properties
you know you say look if you're someone has this property then that spectral algorithm
will be well you can of course to find the property b
the property of the algorithm does
so you can say
i algorithm and the problem on the algorithm work to find them
a simple theorem is that has the property out
we are going natural properties something to look at the natural thing if you satisfy
that motivates the structure so we don't really know
this large surface could we don't really have very efficient algorithm especially when the topic
be nice to be able to do that
also this notion of usefulness so one thing i think it's quite interesting is
you could relax the notion of the tree
saints that's enough to produce small
directed acyclic graphs
for example if you go to our website for
the company like
the cell stuff like
that's buyer whatever company so
electronic that have little navigation bar where you can you navigate through the through the
items they sell
so have to be like a tree and so you can look at camera or
TV's are
refrigerators are selling but you can also search by price you can go there two
a hundred dollars a hundred and fifty whatever and and then you can you can
get to the cameras between one hundred two fifty either by cameras first immensely my
price price first then by can so the kind of organizing this stuff in that
structure and with and so it's a little bit you know way to think of
what's really happening is that having a single clustering you have a bunch of users
and each user has a cluster they're interested in like i might be interested in
cameras between two hundred fifty dollars
what i want is that the natural clusters are somehow living in the structure so
you be interesting to try to develop
the theory that
or other kinds of feedback so
the kind of feedback we're talking about now is the user really feedback to the
can then decide how far they want to click that it's a certain kind of
here's deciding how specifically meant to be you can imagine other kinds of feedback control
and so that's this is just
going back to the first part of some
the references related
all right so
so if we can just have questions or
but the things that
right so if you also had some knowledge about what the person one is like
there are really only interested in cluster bigger than a certain
five you can throw out
the parts the tree
so we were
the kind of property looking at were only making the assumption that for instance
everybody in the same cluster is
you know
the axes more similar to everybody else the same cluster anybody else we didn't assume
anything about how big question maybe x its own cluster by
given only the information we really want to produce poultry we make of no assumption
about what user one certainly if you had some other
no information about what the user wants like they said
furthermore every cluster size
a certain amount and you could print out things i think that's interesting question you
know whether this other
prior or other kinds of information they tell you look i got the similarity function
i think it's good and furthermore my clusters are big furthermore something else something else
you'd like to be able to use all the information
so right now we basically only using the similarity function one could imagine
you know
trying to
together kind information to count two
more so
on the other side from which starts with the
what is
so just
is not
all songs which is essentially the same function the
seems to the
this is just
OK so so so so
which was some of the sources seem to be saying is
long beach
similar work was just to start with one to one
on the relation of
a major
i think of
i mean are
well known
on the nineteenth
because of web two point o
a lot of online communities
pop up
so on the relevant to topic is social networks
we briefly discuss these two things so you have the big picture about the environment
where the block sphere
it's OK
the wheel
the blogsphere so by looking at this this is also from the
well wikipedia and what do you think you can be used to that very different
this is like web versus web two point o when we had where we don't
have web one point o and then we have web two point o but nowadays
probably you've heard about web three point o o four point o x point that
it's really not as significant as this
but we just talk about alec away at one point two one can you tell
the difference
what is the key difference here
the key difference here is
we have a lot of consumers here
but over there we had a lot of
these producers
they also very willing
to share
the contents the predicts
that's the difference because of that difference so you see lal of
this social media
application pop up
so characteristics of web two point o
we have like a rich
internet applications user generated the contents
o you probably have this sorry i should
say this earlier
we have a copy of that
but i think
we summit notes we
i changed alot OK so
this is bad news and the good news both right so we change the lot
for better
for better for worse or better
and this character now we come back to talk about to this characteristics the web
two point of o rich internet applications lot of applications new applications user-generated content
using rich contents
i will
later i will show you some examples
and the user developed the widgets
then collaborative environment
participatory web and the citizen
journalism have we heard about the solution to the rest of you have heard about
these things reason a lot less
eleven richest power of the long tail
i was the user generated data that's really
where the power is OK this is
web two point o is more
paradigm shift then that technology shift
of course it stimulated by the
improvements right innovation
now these are some examples
these are some examples web two point of service
blogs blog posts wordpress
and wiki keep
we give us city
social networking sites how many of you have account to facebook myspace
all of you
ronnie to you have one
so which one could or facebook
facebook so you usually we have all sorts some accounts their social networking sites
and digital media sharing websites youtube flickr
social tagging
these are all social media
because of this of participatory for users voluntarily
two not of things amazingly many OK
you were not imagine
in the early days
and in other cities of the other things so many many applications
the top twenty most visited websites
hopefully you recognise some of them
but it's not the given by us by alex
and forty percent of the top twenty websites are
web two point o sec what does that mean that means that allows these sites
allow people to participate to contribute OK
this is the one
then we have
and more and more people flock to the web
using various applications i showed the social for some social purposes
i don't know for me i have like
however a teenager can
i have three kids but the genetic changes that
he prefers
to talk to his friends
three internet
he does not want to invite them to hold OK it's very probably you have
the same experience
so that that's the trend
that's the tremendous
people they still socialize
but they socialize in a different way
when i was young i was running out out of the street and played with