that you would actually
try and to minimize this
so this only we'll start making scenes
as soon as we replace
this one up upon which actually takes into account
this is the
really really
wonderful trick
well structured estimation
so if you have a problem of that time
you've got some loss delta upon
one for instance
subject to well where the spies given as the argmin some problems
then i can find convex upper bound on this
simply through the barracks i excised great recording
in this case it was written out
one minus fighters per se
so this is
this is something that is the optimal solution
i promise
well any other ones
plus delta of apart from and one for all platforms
this looks like a bit at talk
but it's actually fairly straightforward principle now
how can we show that this is an upper bound on this expression here
well there is
well just plug-and-play chronicles by
that's since four pi
this is the argmin
apply transpose c
this term here
it's going to be great frequency of right
so the
and here we already have delta find one
now i have size great something
the term that i actually want to bound so therefore clearly the upper bound holds
so it's really easy to show
sometimes people rescale the margin here
and that actually tends to work much better if you can afford it
the trouble is here we cannot really afford several were to rescale
so this thing actually plays the role of the margin and it explain a little
bit ly
so this is the discrepancy between the correct score
well for any other permutation
but if this quantity here
is positive it means i'm in trouble
was if this quantity is positive then y prime
it will be
a bit to minimize of fighters per se
then the one is the identity permutation
now what i'm actually doing it
i'm going to add to this
the loss
many basically how much it costs me
by using pi prime
instead of the ones
well match
so what this does is it
good large margins
permutations pi prime
which would correspond to really disastrous match
so that's the multiclass large margin principle
i guess most of you when you drive a car
actually by the
the large margin principle
so for instance if you drive along the highway and it's really really smooth on
the side well maybe you're a little bit less careful and may be stray bits
assigned right at least i sometimes do that families
on the other hand if i drive mountainous road
and there is a
big gap on the side
and there is a huge danger that might just fall off i will try my
darndest actually stay away from that
so i will try to keep is larger margin is possible between this gap
which would be disastrous
and where am
and this is really just doing the same thing in equations here
anyway this is the key slide
of the entire presentation
in terms of the optimisation problem
don't worry
there's lots of pictures here
will get through in time so if you do that we can write about our
optimisation problems so remember before that here we have those losses are for matching well
some graphs in may be suboptimal way
here we just have replaced by this upper bound
it's clear to see that this is a common convex then it's linear constraint imply
and exciting
because i mean this is really just by trying to expose one
and so i get this constraint here
it's not for a convex optimization problem
and the other thing that's happened is
i've really made the scale of the seas match
so this is basically what fixes
the reason why have used the north of the square is regularizer
so now if i scale c to be very small all sorts of the bad
large margin solutions are going to take over so this prevents me from having just
a scale that goes to zero
and so i will actually have an effective regularizer
now we've got a convex problem great
but we pay for it very dealing with the exponential number of constraints
so we need to find the most violated constraint efficiently
but fortunately that again is solved by linear sound
so if you look at this line here and yes what's the point
which maximizes the right inside well that's just a linear sound from this is linear
and what do they do is
you just find the rest permutation
and then
at this to a subset of constraints to minimize for those constraints defined and express
constraints keep an interesting
now what's really happening here
so this is
the expectation is with respect to the stochastic component of a statistical models
and again for those of you familiar with second year undergraduate statistics will know the
covariance can be written as the expectation of the outer product of a random variable
or random vector minus the outer product of the mean
random vector
so we want to get an expression
for these terms here
no the maximum likelihood estimator
this is one of the reasons why maximum likelihood and unlikelihood present principle is
a very general principle and
it's one of which you will use and
we more or less all the time
if you want to
but the forward backward recursions of the hidden markov model fall from
maximizing the likelihood of your sequence given the markov property of the hidden markov properties
of the model so the likelihood principle is is one which is very general and
for good reason
it provides an unbiased estimator
what does that mean that means that if you have enough observations
and your model happens to be
true in the sense that it accurately
process by which the data set has been produced
then the parameters of that model
the estimates of the parameters of that model
if you use maximum likelihood will be unbiased other words you will tend towards the
true parameter values in the asymptotic limit
so it's comforting to know that this estimator will be unbiased so in other words
the expectation
estimated w heart
well actually the w where w and the two model parameters
the convention itself the expectation of w heart is equal to w
if you can convince yourself again grabbed me in the lecture india
there's a philosophical question here of course
george box
chemist and statistician is
quoted as saying all models are wrong
but some are useful
so far models are wrong
right and all models that you use and my and machine learning will typically be
all in the sense that they do not
accurately reflect
the process by which the data was was observed
and then doesn't make any sense
to have an unbiased estimator
real in the next lecture when i want to the bayesian methodology then this whole
question will arise yet again
and we'll see that in actual fact
it's quite a sensible question to ask but for the time being
let's take comfort in the fact that
if our model does indeed reflect the truth
an unbiased estimator is a good to half
OK so already and we have this part of the expression here
so this is just going to be w w transpose w two
model parameters so it just requires this matrix of
second order
for w
so how do we get
we know that w hat is this
this thing here
so let's just take the
o to product of these two things
OK so this is
BBC linear algebra so we just have this this here
now remember these here
these axes are given there's no stochastic
under this model element e of human stochastic component that we have the other target
so when we take the expectation with respect to w heart w heart transport was
because this whole thing is is is basically linear
the expectation operator
is going to operate on
he transpose
again i'm going to run through this quite quickly so that i don't hold you
back from your coffee but
for those of you who
i don't quite follow this can up in the laboratory or don't the corresponding lecture
notes which when the into the system
and a lot more detail
but in any case we need to get an expression for the expectation of t
he transports
our model a statistical model is basically t plus the deterministic component and then the
noise component so again we take the outer product and apply the expectation operator
so when we expand this
we see that we have no remember this w is the true model parameter so
this is deterministic so there will be no expectation
the expectation operator will operate on s
this is a stochastic elements on noise are enough
again this is deterministic and then we have the outer product of our entertainment
so the expectation
will just operate on e and e transpose
now what is the expectation of epsilon
and the expectation of the transpose
i sigma square
so this block so this just becomes an identity
scale by sigma square this is just the deterministic component so we have this good
now we can close this
and two e w hard w had transpose
and we end up with
if you want to go through it it's fairly trivial but
so we have this part of the true parameter values and then this
oddly familiar looking matrix here
and if we plug everything together
then the overall covariance
so we have our
corresponding to the expectation of the product of the
maximum likelihood estimator
we have this component here which councils
and we find that the covariance matrix
associated with the maximum likelihood estimator
is equal to this thing here
now remember
well people who does this come from
you should remember
this is actually the second derivatives of the likelihood with respect to the
the model parameters
the covariance
that you can relate this to consistency
it's got it slows down a bit today
to do that
which is about two pages
to build a very simple so i'm not going to do right now because i
want to get going on this topic
and so i will give you that if tomorrow i'll just put it in the
and then you have to pick up
but what the next step what we're in our exposition is to say is this
thing called cut conserve conservation or conservation result
which yields trying to achieve but it turns out
but that attempt to try and achieve that is the same as trying to show
that certain formal systems are consistent
i consistent mean that
you know we want to prove
but the former and negation
we want to prove some bad things like zero equals one
because we already have presumably if it's good enough for mathematics
we already have
zero on a long proven theory
so i think you just proved this thing we now theorem here is inconsistent things
like that
so we're talking about the consistency of the theory
i guess
that's the for next topic
well this is where negative results again kick kicking
it turns out just going to jump over the slide in the next because they
start to say i really apologize this
that i start to give you a brief outline of proof idea
and then i don't know how to brain seizures something and i didn't put it
which was sold by because just simple like you be nice to have slides
so t tomorrow morning
but what i will say is that in effect
of some
the system propose formalisation mathematics that is consistent
would be sufficient for
this conservation ideas all the data
but the hunters on to see if we could prove one of these formal systems
among other things that's what
falls out of all this work is that we can't do that
can't find
proof of the sort of looking for
well established some the ideal theory
some ideal theory is itself consistent
we believe it's consistent
we can act on that basis but we don't know is inconsistent certainly not
so we can find formal proof that it is not able to
that's the support of all these there is
so here's the particular theorem which will be working towards
and so the crime that they live in their villages try and sort of
i just read out once and then
then we'll continue from there to try and show you the steps that would lead
up to this thing
i think in the last and jeffrey
this is theorem four chapter fifteen OK so we're not just going to get like
that that's fine
the key idea we model so right now
the key idea
is the girl coco go this time
also quite young
and working in this area called program found away
to encode
in two
arithmetic itself
yes i realize that you could
set up key
the maps and things like that between the symbols of the formulas
and indeed the derivations the strings the whole form being put together this cube map
all at over two
statements in arithmetic
so these theories depend on you for proof depending on using arithmetic to code the
met metatheria formal theory
and then when you do that it turns out that there are
some problems
if is sufficiently strong which we want to be one of l'express mathematics so his
one state fear
suppose t the theory
formal theory containing arithmetic
then there's the sentence far
which encoding
asserts its own un provability
so this sentence somehow says
but it's not
there's an kind of the derivation of this of this form so far so good
they can be sentences which
i don't have
during the trouble because they're not they're kind
but it has these for the properties
if t is consistent
t will then t one have five
five theorem
and another property called omega consistency usually from
well now
this is just what we establish in here
assuming it is consistent
one be the case that this five thing
is in is in our theory of arithmetic
but intuitively
the sentence phi stu is true
it is unprovable
and it's it's that's what intention of the coating
is that says that central
so here's the formula which intuitively is true it's the truth arithmetic
it's got this property the property that is there
right now i
OK that assuming that the theory is consistent one the two
we're stuck
we exhibited we calculate we can find a way of showing that
t essentially files to capture all of mathematics
and this is consistent
let's it's inconsistent sorry
t is incomplete
on this assumption
there's a fairly can be working away towards thinking about how you how you get
to that structure how the coding works
we talk about mapping
or even having a reasonable idea of calculating
o or cow having calculate built inside formal theories
i got a little
discussion point here
again the on that moment
given time and we try and
i will try and get back to that one
are just tell the idea will do that for six
so here's my question
we assume got some theory
formalise arithmetic
it would be reasonable to assume
the antecedent of the roman one
if t is consistent then we want the other things
the idea is that
you place
that's that's the greek letters on the gas and that's a stronger form of consistent
i let that one go and it's this
so because consistency
it was this idea we didn't have something in negation
now i know i'm ready for the
so what's here
which are two
so called the little plastic equation
now with now so this this is like the key key
we're going to a lot of solutions but can we solve it with the delta
and i can i solved qxx is be our two-dimensional delta function
u y y equals
a delta function at zero zero
later i would like to solve it with the delta function
at some other point
x not why not
know so this is a point source
so what i wanted
i solving physically with this with this case
it's like fluid is
a going away
and it's
there is applied
at the the origin feeding fluid and you see what the picture would be like
as a source of point source at the origin
or at some other point
and it's
it's providing fluid which is traveling away no other sources
everywhere else the delta function is zero but at one point
we have a true point source
so this is the kind of problem you would solve an essay analyzing boston harbour
it's got its certain sources and what's what travels around and and then i would
also if if
just to say what i want to give him i would also like to solve
the problem with with source on the boundary
and the boundary values instead of the right hand side is all come to the
OK let me tackle this guy
well you can imagine what we need is
like a good guess
here's a good guess i think
i'm going to get a pair again
so i'm think of my function
given a the real part of the EU and then all well so what
actually you can predict here
what will be my
my geometry picture if i have
you can guess what what's what's the flow going to do
it shows up at this
centre and
it's got no other reason
choose any particular direction so we're willing to do
don't allow radio
so the goal
radio streamlined streamlines will be radio
these will be the lines as
and if this and then i want curves are perpendicular to those rays out from
the origin
circles around the origin so those will be
those would be the
potential equipotential u we'll hands OK let's see if we can make that happen
you equal cost obvious circle
and a single constantly already
OK well here's the hair function look at the logarithm
of c
that's interesting function
the figure out what it is
OK so
so we use
experts i y
or are either i theta
sorry i think better right because the logarithm of a sum is who knows
but the log of product is
can be because the product is the logarithm of this term
one of the other term was the log of the other terms
what's the logarithm of the the i say that
it's just so i say the right size
so what we
what we got here now we take the real part is
like technique you take the real part is this is are you
and take the imaginary part in this is RS
it was really easy
and to the UMTS and others that match
so so far i just
i suggested this function
but now notice how it doesn't match the picture
because the lines as stable constant are legal constant those arrays
and the lines
of our equal councillor circles
fogaras six
there are is
searching for twelve fourteen i go up to the top
and i love
does it
twelve fourteen doesn't overlap here
i looked at eighteen and it's it's greater so i go left
and then look here
does it overlaps
so then what happens
i looked at the left
says i go right
look here
then i go and i look the left it says no go right
i go here which is now
and now it's now
i returned no
and does twelve fourteen
overlap anything in the sense
so therefore it always works
so when the correctness in a minute
let's just do our analysis first
so we don't have to
do it because
the crevices is gonna
it's going to be a little bit tricky
OK so the time
it is or log again
because all i'm doing
is going down the tree
so i only takes time proportional to the height of the tree
OK so that's pretty easy
if i need to list all overlaps
was on list of all the overlaps how quickly can i do that
can somebody suggest how i could use this as a subroutine
to list all overlaps
suppose k overlaps
intervals that overlap my query level and i want to find every single one of
how fast can i do that
how do i do
the draw for the phi searches second time i might get the same value
go do what
yeah we find it we
o over site find the next one do it or none none left
now if i don't want
if i don't want my love
you know i have modified the data structure in sort of all that can
OK cost me OK log n third k overlaps
OK that's actually called an output sensitive algorithm because the
running time of it depends upon how much it outputs
OK so this is output
OK so you just
complete the best today for this problem by way of listing all
is for k plus log in with a different data structure
OK and actually that was open for a while
there's an open problem
why is this album always work
the key
issue the correctness is
i'm only i'm picking one way to go left to right
as great as long as it's in that subtree
how do i know that when i pick i decided when to go left that
might not be in the right subtree and i went the wrong way
OK if i went right that i accidently left one out on the left side
were always going just one direction
and that sort of the cleverness of the
they have the code
the theorem is let's let
l b
the set of intervals i prime
in the left
of the node acts
the set of i i primes
in the right of x
and now the two two-part summer show
the search
goes right
the set high prime
in l
such that i prime overlaps
is the empty set
that's the first thing so that it goes right
and there's nothing in the left subtree
it overlaps
always whenever the code goes right
no problem
OK because there was nothing on the left subtree to be found
everybody understand that
OK with that says
to prove this but i will make people understand say because the second one is
can be harder to understand
make sure you understand this one first any questions about this
if the search goes left
so i prime in l such that i prime
and this one
and this is the component in the y direction at decouples and that can go
so slowly that it can even have a group velocity of zero
when i show you
i can change the size of the gap
what that means in terms of this line
is the following i can lower my frequency
so my frequency will be somewhere here
it is ten to the ten
ten gigahertz
it's all about three centimeters sort of moment that h
becomes less than one point five centimetres that is no longer a way for the
y component to go through
what i'm doing
is to keep this point constant but this line
i am moving slowly up
because when i make a smaller it is this point is omega psi goes up
and so i make OC omega psi go up until it
it's my
figures like that again and then
right so here in our
in our thinking here we lowered over a guy
and i showed you what happens now to do the experiment i lower
and i moved this lineup
delighted that point
OK so i think we're ready for that now
you will be able to hear it i would like someone to witness it could
you come in with it
i wanted to see that the separation between the gap is now two centimetres
the standard on the side here not being you
so looking for the name
chris and the wonderful
my name is well
so this is at two centimetres you see that
this is the transmitter it
is polarized like this
here is the receiver which receives the polarized radiation like this
we modulated with five hundred and fifty years so you can hear it
we cannot here
and to the ten that's not the way
the nature of the science
nor can i a
this is five hundred fifty
the gap is two centimetres
i'm going to make it gets more with my hands
you watch it when
gets a one and a half centimetres
all of this
this appears
that is the consequence of the fact that this point it's you know
this is one and a half centimetres apart
i can rotate this ninety degrees
and rotate this ninety degrees so that now we have
in vector in this direction
there are no longer any restrictions
and the radiation goes because now
i have this red stuff
now i can make it gets smaller
and what do you think when i make gets smaller and smaller and smaller
very slowly will you nothing because if the gap has no cross-section opening anymore no
radiation can go through
don't expect miracles
if i now make get smaller and smaller and smaller nature has no problem sending
radiation through
nature is that the cross sectional opening
and is of course you make is opening never never never the less and less
and less radiation will go so i will now make it
gets smaller
she is my eyewitness put on top
now about one and a half centimetres
make it smaller about one centimeter to go well i want to i seventy seven
about three millimeters
obviously we slowly those
so you see thank you very much for assisting me
my pleasure actually
and so you see how bizarre it is that that behaviour
it is so
fundamentally different
for these two
and then the idea of the decoupling
that if you have a few
also late
in a direction that has x and y components that the radiation decouples
i think this is a nice moment denies natural moment to have our break
and i was just wondering why the attendance was so high that
then i was reminded of the fact that it's tuesday
so i'm very flattered that you all came
and we will hand them out
and then we will not start yet until the whistle
i will raise all the blackboard so you can see everything
kostunica you help us out
you also help
you also have to make sure that everyone
has one
i'm going to change
the situation very dramatically
i'm going to give you a closed box
as a conductor
our coordinate system is the same
x y si
and i simply
i call this
eight i call this b
and i call this see that is the length
and that's the coordinate system
and now
comes the question
nine out of electromagnetic radiation in this box
what is going to happen
there is no way that it can get in or out
it's in there
so clearly
are now
get the situation
that you have a cavity which very discreet residences
the decision boundary looks in the input space will change so if you use
a Gaussian kernel and you make it more and more nonlinear then this decision boundary will
also become more and more nonlinear and I can show you  a video of
this I hope so right so here's the Gaussian kernel very broad Gaussian kernel at the beginning
almost linear and turning up a non-linearity and grid computing the solution over and over
again and you can see  it becomes more and more nonlinear you know it's almost it's always
a hyperplane in the in the reproducing  kernel Hilbert space so at some point I stop this so
there's another just a few more examples of such nonlinear
surfaces that correspond to hyperplanes in repetition kernel Hilbert space this was from some
work that we did in computer graphics some time ago where we constructed methods to
represent three D objects as as essentially as hyperplanes in reproducing kernel Hilbert spaces and these systems
are then trained on surface points so you can download such models in the web
in the form of a surface points and you have millions of surface points for
such objects and then get decision boundaries like this and you can also use it
for for objects like that and then think of algorithms to between
objects so all these things are essentially hyperplanes in the reproducing Hilbert space so you can represent
complicated things this way and on the next slide I'll show you another example of a nice decision
boundary which some people think it's linear or which becomes linear if you embed it in the right
space so okay so we will go back to this one later okay so let's
go back to his kernel means so the kernel means algorithm was initially intended just as
a  tutorial logarithm in the first chapter of our book which you  see back there and
only later did we notice that is actually interesting in its own right
and the interesting thing is so as before I told you well we'll just check whether
the test point is closer to here or to here and I think also told you we
will get a decision boundary which is a hyperplane whose normal vector is this vector W
connecting the class means know what I've swept under the rug is what happens
if the two class means are identical seems like we're in trouble because the normal
vector would be zero it doesn't define a hyperplane so at that point I
thought maybe that's not interesting but actually it's quite interesting to think about when does
it become zero this vector so let's look at this in more detail maybe not in
maybe maybe we'll spend  ten to fifteen minutes on this because it leads to some interesting
statistical methods but so so briefly let's get a sorry let's get
an idea for when this happens so when is the mean of the positive class
in the feature space identical to the mean of the negative class now of course
if our feature space  is trivial so if we suppose we start with
vector real data and we don't map anywhere we directly work in our input space then this just
means that we have two data sets that have the same mean when also the
same first moment statistically speaking now what happens if we use a polynomial kernel for a
polynomial kernel it turns out you would remember probably I told you yesterday this kernel
implicitly computer mapping into the space spent by all products up to order D so it
turns out if you take two data sets map them into the feature space using this
kernel and if you find that in that feature space these two data sets have
the same means if you translate it back into what it means in the input space this actually
means that all empirical moments of the data sets are up to all the D coincide so that
means for instance for order two  that not just two the data sets have the same
average but they also have the same covariance structure or the same variance and co-variance and
if you look as as you increase this order more and more of the higher order  moments
of these two distributions  empirical distributions  will be identical so and it turns
out if you become sort of more more nonlinear in a certain sensitive if you have a
kernel which is strictly positive definite such as a gaussian kernel it turns out that
actually comparing the means in the feature space is the same as comparing the
full structure of the data sets so that if the two means in the
in the feature space are the same then actually the two data sets have to be the
same point by point so so roughly speaking this mean remembers each point that contributed to
it which is kind of surprising so of course think about it it's a high-dimensional
space so the median high-dimensional space in this sense contains more information than directly taking the
mean in the input space so let's maybe you find it surprising so let me try
to convince you of this last statement because the proof is very short so the
claim is that if the kernel is strictly positive definite if we take two data
sets one of them are called X one through X M one Y one through Y N map
them into that space compute the means in that space so this is the mean
of the positive data sets I'll use mu it's a shorthand for this mean mapping
this is the mean of the negative data set my claim is that if these two
means are the same then all the points X and Y the two sets of points must
be identical and let's prove slightly more general statement statements the following we
have two sets of points we assume that each points each set consists of
points that are Ys Ys distinct otherwise we get some nontrivial
ambiguities and some trivial ambiguities so X is a set of distinct points Y is
set of distinct points we're not saying anything about how X and Y are related and
it turns out  if we if for some coefficient vectors that are nonzero
if we have a zero we just throw it out we don't have to talk about
that so if for some nonzero coefficient vectors we find a kernel expansion in X which equals
a kernel expansion in the Ys then the set F X set X must
be equal to the set Y so in particular if these over M actually
this is just the mean and likewise here so two means are the same the sets are to be same
so let's see I haven't looked at this proof in a while hope I still understand it so so
without loss of so we we're going to prove by contradiction we have to prove
that two  sets are the same so let's assume that one of the sets contains an element
OK now let's do one it's a little more interesting what is sufficient statistic for
density estimation
which i mean variance or
the median and the mean squared
and actually when you look at the point where the gaussians you can see e
that's the
the likelihood function is linear
in a vector
which includes the mean and the mean square so they let me go back
the more general
case of sufficient statistics here
and trying
so have a sufficient statistic vector
the function of the data set
which delivers to you use something that you can use for maximum likelihood estimation and
the way you can think of is that the
log the likelihood of the data set under your model is a linear function of
the sufficient statistic factor
so let's try to write that down for the gas
and see how
this goes
so you can see in case
if you had let's just do the scalar case
you to get points in the log likelihood
the probability of the whole data set x
given some
i think that the likelihood function
i would say
and that's just
my one times the sum of all the data points here
the my
this is
analysis to expand this
so that gives you access to query
ninety two
this is
after square and now i'm going to just rewrite this as
the british
so x squared far
and because i wanted to be the original multiply by and here
and this is going to be free
so the average
and this is going to be
new square
this is actually the likelihood function
and you can see that the likelihood the entire likelihood of the data set just
depends on this vector here which i can write like this
where are
x bar one
that's the sufficient statistic vector and the
it's the likelihood is a linear function of this
which is just one
minus two new
in the one turn
but what we
the sufficient statistic is a vector which summarizes your data in a way that's all
you need to do you know to do maximum likelihood estimation
and this picture which is now
o are here is supposed to indicate if you want to take a bayesian approach
and think of the
parameters as random variables the sufficient statistic was separated from the around the US
and that's
o point i think our is going to develop more next week
things that this is
you can is not the case for any model
it's for any model that has sufficient statistics and the definition of sufficient statistics is
a linear function
all exponential family models have sufficient statistics and the average natural parameters and roughly speaking
only to start here only exponential family models have sufficient statistics
that's not quite true
can someone think of a simple example of model that is in the exponential family
has sufficient statistics
assuming that you know if you something
that's right
the uniform distribution
the uniform distribution is not really an exponential family and he
we really want to that
but it has easy sufficient statistics if i tell you this quantity x measuring it
uniformly distributed and i two hundred measurements x having written on a piece of paper
by an expert jury piece of paper what you need to know
about that set of numbers to give me the maximum likelihood uniform distribution
or let's write the minimum and the maximum so vector of sufficient statistics vector
it just tells you what you need to know
roughly speaking this is true but not
that is the
implicit implications here yes
that's exponential families a good thing to pursue because learning just involves collecting these factors
have sufficient statistics
and of course if you can do the exponential families some extended space then you
can you can have a nonparametric way life which fortunate
having just discussed maximum likelihood estimation for sort of ordinary distributions now let's talk about
maximum likelihood learning in these graphical models so there you have a graphical model like
this and i give you some observations remember the assumption is that everything is subject
to x one x two x three x four you have a big data table
which is formed by and and you want do maximum likelihood estimation in this small
and the back
of directed a sickly graphical models when all the nodes are observed
this particular symmetry is not present that is where you just have glide reflections
and translations and
she was fascinated by that symmetry within one month of going on with this
picture page
and drawing them up in trying to understand them he had made this
test elation
so this is his re redoing of polymers
picture that i showed you a moment ago
he said
within one month of going over
these pictures by the way you didn't say in this paper how to do it
it was just one page of pictures
but it might as well have been the rosetta stone for him
made this
the solution of lizards
we have to send symmetry you can see where four legs come together in this
world around here have been unable to pull that off
before he read
and so these pictures
and here is his very first french
what scares me
i guess i don't have that he made the point of that and in that
depicts at the centre of the print those losers he by the way so that
predict pull you
with a thank you letter
i mean you can think of writing a paper on some obscure journals
and thirteen years later you get a thank you letter for a paper
from an artist
with a credit saying here's what i made because of your paper
receive that thank you letter and the print some from asher
here's another one that should did that matters
these particular
motifs we have the bat and bird and butterfly and b
these have reflection symmetry
and if you look at the article text elation you can see very clearly that
those lines of reflection symmetry for each of the motifs there's also a line of
reflection symmetry
for the whole
test solution
here's another example
this is of dragonflies
on the right
tagging flies and dragonflies
this beautiful duality again doing ground nodes each dragonfly
has reflection symmetry
and the
the lines of reflection symmetry for the print fairly jump out at you are exactly
the same
treated motifs with reflection symmetry
in a funny way
he treated as an exception
if the motif have reflection symmetry it was very stiff
and he wanted swelling and flying and swimming motifs
and so
whenever he had a motif that have reflection symmetry he put a little story can
see here because it's off the screen will start at the bottom of his picture
and set up at least since symmetric and in every case we're on his symmetric
motif was arranged so that the line of symmetry of the motif was in fact
in line of symmetry of the whole plant
but there is one exception
and that
that's this one
at the bottom
asher says apparently symmetric motifs and it's true isn't quite symmetric if you
strong line right down the middle
this bird
the left wing is just a little bit wider than the right wing it's not
quite perfect mirror symmetry but it's darn close
and looking at this plant program but was very
interested to see can i make that so that i can make a perfect
action sequences executed in the initial state
the a
after the
technology all access will be girls
any questions about that
now i'm going to proceed with
sort of practical approach to landing
displayed based on solving the satisfiability problem will the less true logic
the idea here
is that
so we have
problem instance
like this here
this from the looks something else
then we have
planning are he
and the producer proposed formula
that is satisfiable
is plan
of link e
so this whole sequence of actions
the actions
that takes us from the initial state
one of the goals
this turned out to be when this was invented fifteen years ago
what is more selling planning problems
two reasons so
people have been considering
planning rules so there's no parameter p
then you have a couple of environment on the planet
you very strong constraints put those plans like
this allows the use of
if you methods as implemented in the current best SAT solvers
actually find the so when
the this for plan and you
even land upon but that's also what close to the actual planning
you can even things that must hold you in the plan execution by
the vessels like unit resolution rule and this list in indicates what black
how this thing works will be explained in the next slide
so the
the basic idea is to
propositional formula
that expresses what that action actually does
the idea is that we have a formula
sorry for variable for every state variable
for every state variable
value in the current state and then we have
propose to formalise
for every state variable value in the sectors
so that's why
if i was the variables a b c and so on
the median
two sets of frozen variables first that tells us what are the values of the
same person current state
and the prime the variance of these frozen variables tells us what are the values
of state variables in sixties
here is the
i think it's the same what world actually considered earlier
the precondition has all the
current state so this is simply the precondition prose form of had
in the
the point of action is shorter
and the effects
i have to be true
the successor states
so here we have
in britain the ball
every aspect of their actions
with the prime there
well say that in the second stage
this act must be
these things many people would normalising OK that's enough
you have to say that the people as the called and it must be true
the success but this is not enough because
we only have those first lines there
then we still allow
anything happens to all the remaining state schools and that's not what this actually about
because this action
formula here all souls has to say that you need
state variable
that is not affected by this action
has to retain its values
and this is what is what has been expressed by these equalities so for every
that area is not affected by the
has the same value in the current state and
state of
well from the third line on would be a b
more complicated
could be made complicated
he had a conditional effects because in some cases the variable changes its value and
some other it's not so
the the
formal definition of it will be slightly above in the simple case
no the effects on conditions
then it looks like this
general description of
the axis of
we have to consider every possible state variables
and all the possible effects that could have taken that so nothing happens
state variables me through the steps made false
the state variable is conditionally made through
the state variables conditional it falls
and the state variable is made up
true or false conditionally but was one of
case this difference
well i describe what happens that they were actually so
nothing happened is that there will be a vehicle is a is equivalent great prime
i'm going to fix all simple simply the
correspondingly there are
b prime there to signify it's the successor states
this one is of
making a true conditionally
each rule
if and only if
was through already
or the conditional the conditional is true in the cars
since same thing for the
conditional i think when
it could be false
it will be true if and only if
it was two already
and we have found the mean that i attacked by dynamics
and also many
you can see that is
so that
i direct link be
the our what got
OK so i think of
probability distribution
it means
some mission
but in some cases we are taking about not
taking just
that the point keep
so already
why and how can we talk about making
one tenth and so on
and we director
introduce divergence
maybe a bit too far
OK so
and i
good for
we have a convex functions
and for convex function of course if have a brain and
so the brain and i about
he's the one who expressed
so i mean
and now
what in the space of four b
maybe four
we know the cause of
nineteen the
if the diver
proposed by enriching
and the
come from the hunting convex function
and to bring on
and we know
he died young was also a member of f divergence and of course they come
the only unique died
put the ball square
we do to extend
i linked
saying that she is not the case
but our that
so what it if diver
so this is for the case and if it diverges
defined by this equation it
is convex set
that's fine
we modify
by using something the day about
twenty five
if i or but according to media
three major input p two
combination of the two that i not
thank you
surely we can define the divergence
how to find if i don't
if i'm line the
then in the next day that property here
on the about
convex function if we use these functions and we have the
i do we can diverse in this position he what the
it can be beaten
this one
and is this one
great brown and the field
probably this is a
i some p and the summit and q is equal
so just
but for media
we should have
no it's actually
the british public
OK i about the variance
and i
it is invariant
i mean
i mean this discrete his what the that OK
the probability that you to make
the city two
i just
eight clustering
well we have cost greedy
and i just
each group
probability of p and q e proportion
we cannot in general be
so let's type
we cannot distinguish panicking because it wasn't
in the case the court in court
you can see e
if guy but he
one that had
also they are
the image
among diagram
does not useful
OK to greenland here
and in the case of bregman divergence we're taking gradient
we have to go and
and that can be defined in this way
i mean i'm sure you're right
now we write in this
and i was right
right all the strong force with the cause there
at first looks very non unnatural
but the fact is that
what we
do when we do these
is we she right from the bottom and top
we look at what we want and then we construct
the proof from that
we do the math
that's why he writes that we can get this from
three readers getting
i understand that but this is sort of in the proof this
but what we have
we get that from that
let's call letters
we can have versions putting zero on the right hand of the structure
two which is all the right pushing right part one often use those directly
anything here so i i didn't write them down but
the is that we get this thing we can put it in where we needed
say the things the theorem which is what we need
extremely you all
the rules these left push and pop rules
some of the stress the trolls normal
looking ones
some of the
if you want to logic
the thing
you know you
the stricter qualification and how all men can take the direct actions were directed at
think it
thirty years of
the these things are going i mean a lot to these names they have to
combinatory logic which i don't think one lecture on right now
are just
well used as names
because people are injured by their names
by those letters it's just easier
tivities something we
premises is something you probably
just would not something in some for all logical systems and we can see
in this lecture we talk about about
well we talk about lambda calculus briefly
associativity really make sense
in that context
persian associativity it which is you at some different results
and this is a strong commutativity
john's wort system a lot of system calls are handled consistent called
and c for strong commutativity
at hand
these as well
now that might be more we're going to talk about some commuting
i mean to take a
well hated by australian are relevant logicians
and it's something that stands in the way
this decidability proofs and a lot of other things on the next lecture
it's been blamed for
it's called currys paradox
OK and
last from all talk was k
what do these things
faced me in the equation and I had to have something to replace them with
now using this already in calculus of this this distinction of that might have been
a year and a half ago but just let me remind you of typically in
calculus for example when you want to do this kind of integral what's a x
times the square root of one minus X squared DX
the substitution you would use for that is you
equals one minus X squared
right and then you calculate and then you observe that this next EX more like
snakes of DU apart from a constant factor so this would be an example of
direct substitution
you put it in and convert the integral into an integral and you what would
be an example of inverse substitution will I take away the x
and ask you instead to do this integral
and you know that the right thing to do is not to start with you
but to start with the exon right x equals sign cosine you
so this is the direct substitution in that integral but this integral calls for an
inverse substitution in order to be able to do it and notice that will practically
the same but of course as you know from your experience not
the very different
so I'm going to watch for that distinction as I do all these examples the
first one I want to do is an example of a direct substitution
In fact
but but but but but but but but but but
so applies to an equation of the form Y prime equals
to turn kinds of terms on the right hand side a of x some what
was used P of X
you X times Y
Q of X times any power whatsoever of walleye will notice for example if anymore
what kind of equation with this the wider the end would be what
and this would be a linear equation which you know itself and so on
equals 0 we already know how to do so let's assume that is not 0
so there were new territory
well what if any are equal to 1 you can separate variables so that 2
is not exciting but nonetheless it will be included what I'm going to say now
if that is 2 or 3 were men could be one half so any anything
even 0 is alright is just silly at any number
could be negative n equals minus flight that would be fine also
all this kind of equation to get its name is called Bernoulli's equation
after named after which Bernoulli I have not the faintest idea they were fighting 3
or 4 of them and they fought with each other but they're smart
the key trick you like
to solving any Bernoulli equation 11 called 1 of thing collect the most important is
what's missing
it must not have a pure exterminated if I in and that goes for constant
term needed in other words it must look exactly like this
everything multiplied by Y were power 2 terms so for example if I add 1
to this
the equation becomes not doable
it's very easy to contaminated into an equation that unsolvable it's gonna look just like
now you got 1 on your homework so you got several Pol Pot 1 part
to have really equations on themselves you know this this is practical but in some
sense when we got the idea is to divide by dividing by a wide end
ignore all formulas that you're given just remember that when you see something that looks
like this
or something that you can turn it into something that looks like this divide through
by 1 and power no matter what energy alright so why prime over why the
end is equal to
the effects times
1 over 1 to the n minus 1 right
what you have access
and from these examples you know you didn't have this concept before but now you
have that we can check this by
testing your generalisation performance in machine learning the lingo you would say here's the training
set i give you three examples and now the rest of this is the test
it's kind of transduction problem if you know that the term so let's go through
some test examples
yes yes in two for now
a little more uncertainty there which is fine
but you know
we're bayesian our model predicts that just fine as you'll see
OK so that's the idea that somehow
you've got this right i mean i guess you we don't know what the ground
truth is but trust me your right
right so this is one kind of problem that we study but common misunderstanding this
sort of problem all over the place i mean just in perception we perceive the
three d world from a two d image that has a certain kind of we
on the data
a lot of the interest in our group and cognitive science more generally is in
large scale systems of knowledge what are sometimes called intuitive theories but some machine learning
is usually focused on learning a little bit of knowledge like learning a single concept
or single function but our knowledge of the world
you can think of it as having many of these bits but they are integrated
into some larger system it's larger than the more than the sum of the sum
of the parts so we have intuitive theories of physics or intuitive theories of psychology
that underlie our common sense in the world right here i am standing up here
my ability to not fall off the stage my ability to to make sure my
laptop doesn't fall and suffer catastrophic failure hitting the ground all these things is guided
by an implicit intuitive theory of of how physical
objects in dynamics and you can see evidence that even very young children like infants
who can even speak or walk have these kinds of intuitive theories about how objects
work or an intuitive psychology we if you've heard of theory of mind that's the
kind of intuitive psychology where we see people
acting in the world even just moving around and when you see somebody moving you
don't just see them as object in motion but you see them as an entity
governed by these
very interesting latent variables mental states like beliefs and desires you see somebody had at
that if somebody wanted is got up in the middle of this lecture and ran
out the door i wouldn't be wouldn't just BMT my motion area processing that would
be thinking what's wrong with that forget something about what i say that intuitive psychology
we interpret and and and make predictions about other people's behavior by inferring these latent
variables and time permitting at at the end of
the next lecture on all talk about how we can take ideas from probabilistic inference
in machine learning all the way up to those kinds of systems of knowledge
so our our goal is to try to reverse engineer these
these pieces of cognition and how they get there however learning works and then also
to try to build more human like machine learning algorithms and i'll go back and
forth between those two problems this isn't just to say that you know any ideal
computational model we come up with necessarily describes how the how the mind works but
i think it's pretty clear that human learning is is the gold standard machine learning
should be
aspiring to to match these for these kinds of problems
now this
these problems are not actually original two psychologists or machine learning people but they have
a history in the western philosophical tradition under the name of the problem of induction
so as long as people at least in the western tradition have been thinking about
thinking they've been thinking about these problems and talking about play-doh aristotle
the whole modern european philosophical tradition and as long as people have been thinking about
how you generalize beyond the data that's given they have the same kind of answer
just basically they're just different variants on it if you're making leaps to go beyond
a small number of data points which are going to be on the data that's
in there this country be some other bits that make up the gap some other
kind of knowledge is usually something more abstract that you can bring to bear on
this particular situation and in bayesian full call these priors
people in
in general machine learning to people talk about inductive bias
the people
to to and which is the best people
no 1 was available to take advantage of the weather on Saturday now
it was good weather on Saturday in theory and the we have and number 2
uh 1 7 and everybody is downloaded the notes for today right or who is
not downloaded the notes for today's class OK so 0
supposed to download the notes of
don't have extra copies
but maybe you can look on with someone sitting nearby
but when it comes to certain things will be doing that
and anybody have an equal in some particular matters
yes I want and right OK so
was still in group as the TA and he should be here momentarily what he
gives he's running from class across campus so there's 1 other person who situation I
think is like yours
oversee so who here cannot make either office hours or recitation
OK the 0 3 people OK so what I'm going to ask you to do
is to meet with me Andrew F. 2 class today and come up with the
time knows he symmetry wants to do what we talked about as a possible solution
is just stay to schedule another
office hours segment on friday OK and he will discuss various options with you but
it would but if this if we do this through e-mail will get resolved by
August so 0
you should 3 we should stay after class and talk it over with Andrew who
should be here
should be here in theory that OK the rest of the world
but I wouldn't say that but in your case it will be so that the
words that that that that the bottom line is there's no recitation time that everybody
can make that is not horribly inconvenient if we had recitation friday 7 AM everybody
can make it and there and no 1 wants that so but of his that
I don't actually know historically how much recitation has proven useful to people so but
my sense is you could probably compass the same thing in office and that's the
idea that the officers probably good substitute for 1 or maybe even better so OK
and and then you have homework due today so just make sure you drop it
off when you walk out of the classroom you don't need to
you need to turn it into right now and also today you probably wondering why
I'm wired for uh and being filmed this is part of MIT is a listeriosis
OpenCourseWare projects so how many of you not familiar with Open Courseware so you you
don't know what it is where you where you at MIT all on their own
OK so Bristol you could lose your registration status just for not knowing what open
to the course
Open Courseware is MIT is big thing where instead of trying to make money by
selling distance editor whatever at MIT has decided that
perfect verb and I hope to get like over 90 % faculty participation eventually just
1 on faculty just posters materials in a well-designed way
with official institutes support so that anybody in the world and see what's going on
in the course
answers said that is not say you get an MIT education but you can see
what we do so
people consider material here and then they're they're gonna be I think there could be
filming 3 lectures here just to illustrate the how professor reacts to brilliant students so
In with that in
with that in mind let's start today's lecture so Mr.
In OK so
thank you so this homework assignment should be due next Tuesday this class I you
disappointed is not going to meet next Tuesday because in my next Tuesday and Monday
class the right that's the way it so it works to parity in the schedule
between Monday Wednesday classes Tuesday Thursday classes so we need this Tuesday and Thursday and
we don't meet again until next Thursday so next summer we do instead of next
tuesday next Thursday the 19th OK and what I want you to do is exercises
3 7 from the handout on Newton's method and exercises 1 to 14 17 18
it is expensive ok and it is some of them doesn't in the sense
that you can point and say you know this is my function
k nine have a whole space of possible functions and you can draw
from that space at the same time can easily quantify
how uncertain you are and the other interesting thing about this
picture is that if we see where the uncertainty is high that indicates
perhaps where we should collect more data
ok now that's not setting that's often talked about in sort
of standard supervised learning it's sort of active learning setting
where if we know where uncertainty is
we can actually make a question and ask okay we want an example in
this area what's the label of that example
and that can drive the learning there's a very interesting sort of
research question of how to do that well on fish
this is just a picture of continuing this sort of drawing points
and you can see that as you drawn more and more points
you still have multiple hypotheses in the sort of a patient
view because you have a distribution over hypotheses but
they all sort of clustered together in order to fit the data
in the limit as you have an infinite amount of data the optimization
becomes the same as maximum likelihood
but when you have a small amount of data the prior has say
ok and so the the hypothesis that you get are driven by both the
prior and the data
ok so so base in the bayes in these kind of interesting because
it tells us about what are our assumptions that gives us the uncertainty
estimates it can guide active learning
it is tricky ok in the sense that if you for example overwhelm
your prior with data quickly that prob prior doesn't really help
you it's also tricky because it is
sort of expensive to work with this sort of sample hypotheses
but but it can be actually quite interesting are there any questions
or comments about the ok ok ok
so now the last thing i want to to to mention to you
is logistic regression y well because it's sort of the equivalent
of linear regression for classification problems and goes
going to tell you all about how to do this a lot better
but this is kind of usual statistical view of things
so here we have a hypothesis ok and the hypothesis is a logistic
function this linear combination of the inputs so that
is the input w to suppose x is a linear combination
and then we do this and you get this sort of shape
ok the function that those and the like this you'll see
lot more about this later is also called sigmoid neuron in the
neural net literature
so why is this close to linear ok we're going to interpret the output
of this hypothesis as the probability of the class label being
one given the input ok and so if that's our interpretation and
if we look at the log-odds ratio of the probability of the two
classes binary classification case y equal to one and like for
to zero you get the weights times the inputs
ok so that's linear ok and that's the sense which we have things
that learning and
the interesting thing is that if we find the best weights here
ok the best weights are going to maximize the conditional likelihood
of the outputs given the inputs ok so that's kind of nice
it's again a maximum likelihood criterion and it's sort of us sort
of standard discriminative setting
ok so now what are we going to optimize well we can optimize
the cross-entropy ok so how do we think about the cross-entropy
we have some distribution i have observed outputs in the data
and then we have some distribution as generated by the
output of our hypothesis ok we're going to measure how far off
one is from the other ok so the log-likelihood of the hypothesis
of course you
and each vertex for each vertex
in two
with the weight
one of the least weight edge
do a vertex
so here's the code
to restore out
with q
being all vertices
you start out with
with a being if you will the empty set
and what going do is the least weight edge therefore four
for everything in
in the priority queue
it's is basically going to be
because none of them have any
it is the least weight edge
to the empty set is going to be empty
i'm going to start out with one guy
o colin as
which was set to zero
for some arbitrary
as in fig
and the main part of the algorithm
kicks in
that certain initialisation
and when when we do the analysis someone write some stuff on the left-hand side
of the board so if you're taking notes you may want to also leave little
bit is based on the left-hand side you notes
so while
is not empty
we get the smallest element
and then we some stuff
and the only thing i should mention here is OK i'm just going on here
and then we run on the
on example
OK so what we do is we
take out the smallest element out of the queue at each step
and then for everything in the adjacency list of everything for which i have an
going to
from b to
to you
we take a look
and if
the is still in
in our set
the minus a so things we've taken out are going to be part of it
OK every time we take something out this continue that we construct
four at every step we want to find what's the cheapest edge connecting that a
and everything else we basically are going to take
whatever that cheapest thing is
OK that you and now bring that into a find the next cheapest one
and we just keep repeating that process
OK well will do it on the example
the what we do is every time we bring it and
i keep track of what was the
vertex responsible
for bringing me and and what i claim is that at the end
if i look at
the set of these pairs that i've
made here the
and higher v
four is the minimum spanning tree
let's just do this
what that we're all set so let's get rid of
let's get rid of these guys here because we're we compute the
from scratch
OK so you may want
copy new things over in here
we cut the graph over again your text was is going to do it but
it turned out this is exactly the board
gary society OK just
well OK
so we we start out make everything the infinity
OK so that's where my keep the
the key value
and then what i'm going to do
he is fine one vertex error call him as that
i mean this vertex here call that as so basically and now make him be
now what i do is i execute extract men
so basically what i do is alter shape him like this
he has now
the join set a
so a is going to be
this is going to be a
and this
elements of the mindset
so then what we do is we take a look
at r
we extract him
and then for each
imagine the adjacency list OK so that for each vertex in distance so this that
these guys here
we're going to look to see if it still in q that is in b
minor say
and if so
we're going to do
and the and its
t value is less than what the value is the edge there when replaced by
the edge value
so in this case we replace this by seven
we replace this by fifteen
replace this phi ten
because we we're interested in is what is the cheapest
now notice that everything in
the minus a
that's what's in the priority queue everything in there
OK now has its
it's cheapest way of connecting it
to the things that i've already removed the things that are in a
so now i just
OK when i actually do that update
there's actually something implicit going on in the priority queue
and that is that i have to do a decrease KEY
there's an implicit
decrease of the key
so increased he is trying to operation lowers the value
the key in the priority queue
so that's implicitly going on when i look at what data structure many used to
implement their priority queue
OK so common data structures for implementing priority queue are
he i mean he
OK so i have to make sure that i'm actually
doing this operation i can't just change it not affect my he so there's no
implicit operation going on
OK now i repeat
i find the cheapest
o thing all and i also have to set now
the pointer
from each of these guys back to
you so here this guy
so a pointer going this way
this guy sets the pointer going this way
in this guy point going this way that's my pi
i think it's going to keep track of who
cost me too
you know
to set my value to what it is
so now we go in and we find the cheapest thing again
and we're going to do it faster
because the fast our OK so now we're going to go
in reinforcement learning is called outcome devaluation
so here what happens is you train
the press ever
in order to get food
and then after the rats trained
change the value of the food
separately in a separate scenario not in the same box where the rats used depressing
for food but like in the home case for instance
letting the rats eat the food and then injecting it with lithium chloride which makes
rats feel really really sick to their stomach
makes them not want to eat that food anymore it's like food poisoning happens to
us to is called conditioned taste aversion you go to rest it's something you really
bad stomach ache you don't ever want to go to that restaurant again are certainly
not order that food so that's what happens to the rats here they don't want
to eat the food anymore you give them the food and they like they walk
that has the feel like throwing things at it
or another way to do this is to just make the round stated
on even for one another food just making really really say to give him as
much food as he wants so that now
the racial food in the experiment has a much lower value
in both cases
now the question is will the rack continue pressing for the food
and that's compared to iraq the didn't have this
the valuations of a normal rat that was trained on this and then just tested
so we know that
this track will continue pressing
questions will these continue pressing at the same rate and the reason we're doing this
in in comparison situation is specifically because this test is usually done with no rewards
so we don't want to see new learning
want to see whether the rat put together its knowledge of contingency is what does
this leverpressing give me and its knowledge of what is the worth of this cheese
with the reward function in the transition function
are these going to be put together without new learning about the food
and the result is
the results are
it depends
if you train the rat only moderately so train the rat for four days to
start with him in four sections each of them half an hour and then do
the devaluation and then do the test you see
that rats press much less for the devalued reward for reward that was not devalued
but if you train the more in the initial training of talking about
in this stage
the training for fifteen days they're not for four days
they don't stop pressing
even when the reward is devalued
press the same
this in this experiment they used to time t
not chloride and there are different experiments a whole host of experiments shown this this
you know i know i think this is holland's results in not killcross so this
with lithium chloride
with the poisoning
so it seems like animals will sometimes work for food they don't want and the
reason i'm saying they don't want it
even in this case
is that we can look at their magazine behavior which is how many times they
go to the food magazine to actually eat the food and we see that in
both cases even after extensive training they go to the magazine last for the food
is developed the watson developing this looks like it's not significant but it's within subject
design is significantly different these two
in both cases
they don't go to get the food but in one case they continue pressing
to earn the food
i saw question from side
and this is associated this kind of behavior after extensive training with what we know
about our daily life which is in our daily life action some has become automatically
call the habitual after the extensively trained if we repeat them again and again and
again we drive home to the same place every day
then even when we move house
we continue driving by mistake to the old place
although we know in our cognition and everything that we don't live there anymore it's
not that we don't know the reward is not there anymore we just failed to
put two to two and two together and not drive to the old place
so this is been turned
the same in rats habitual behavior where they continue pressing goal directed behavior when they
stop pressing whether directed tool goal they kind of
put together in their mind
made and stated
right i understand
know this is a good question so theoretically with the devaluation really if as effective
after extensive training as it was after moderate training and they take that so
sometimes here it's enough to do well poisoning and here you have to do three
poisoning three poisonings on three different days but they poison them until the point where
they give the food and they just don't want to eat it
and that's when they go to detect they put them back in the box is
the labyrinth and test that so that's controlled for the the good question
OK so we started in some cases
in some cases animals are habitual in other cases
in other cases animals are
goal directed
so people really really interested in this is starting to look at
what areas of the brain
lead to these kinds of behaviors in this kind of learning and what they saw
and also you only two results
it's just to
now in cumbria with all kinds of areas of the brain that mean nothing at
this point
is that there are some areas of the brain specifically the dorsolateral striatum
in this experiment these overtrained rats so if you don't lesion their brain what they
going to do is going to continue responding in this in the devalued cases much
as they responded in the
non devalued case
but if you lesion if you cut
the dorsolateral striatum out of the brain and then do all the training and everything
and then suddenly
their goal directed so they press less for devalued option than for the value adoption
even after thirty days of training or as long as you want to train the
never become habitual
so the idea was that the dorsolateral striatum is the seat of habits
if you don't have the dorsolateral striatum in your brain you can learn happens
and this is also true if you don't in the dorsolateral straightaway you just depleting
dopamine from you kill all the neurons that
project to a
yes and no OK
with the tools we have an and the knowledge that we haven't been there before
absolutely yes
I don't be negative but you don't have the cooperative spirit going on
the chanting and don't know why
the young engineers are sharper
and no 1 was injured but don't know a whole lot more
and irony
but you don't get along well
you know this is not only do you don't want to get out of here
that would overhaul and that's this observation made it might might be that you know
might not always used to restricted and the goes up freehand management to not just
the working
the 2nd thing is
they asked become and consult with them and they lost technical capability didn't using the
engineers much after a certain time on the shuttle and then after the last accident
to the bring engineers and
I i've never looked at that and you know I'm I'm on the payroll but
also the capability was was was
greatly lacking and so we developed some ways to bring up to speed in about
a year and a half profound which which happens
observations about way out please all yoga class sometimes have I told management to syntactic
there's a meeting and you tell somebody will be there at the time you be
there at that time
if tell somebody you Michael deliverable at that time and you make a deliverable that
can be a man and a woman of the word
and I have found that like and don't know that think screw have too much
that we set a multitude of did too because the 1st to secondary class there
was I think can only in the sent back when Letterman the class the other
but but but learn or whatever you get along with folksy that you bodies they'll
be there for a lifetime and you going have some grief and they give some
headaches and you give you some with your thinking
work words that none of you had a great achievements that sometimes but that's major
the hidden costs
about doing that because the user of the history the
so that we can think of the of how the rest of and some test
for hundreds of hours that was the total number of hours for all those tests
not per hour lecture together was minded artist 1 of the major question to see
if the reduced number 1 . and 3 areas that we're working on right now
that uh 1 reason is to bring the engineers to technical speed where they can
stand up and be counted in you can estimate technical question that give you technical
actions and this is my analysis and this is how I got back to do
that we recommended back to Johnson spacecraft centers that do you better get you engineers
be went on interest you get get to know how to make the calculations to
run these programs you gotta be able to do all that you integration contractors they
need to have that capability and they've done on OK and they're really came up
to speed and the Mr. that also increases CFD capabilities and I'm very envious of
what you can do with the however
it hasn't decrease the amount of runs at the requesting it's increasing demand runs at
their request because they do this little bitty analysis and use the cable tray going
down there and the suggested go Sonic under the cable well I don't know was
it went on to say that we will use the data point here and a
data point here and actually if these shows can cosine candidate all we need to
test estimate that's there and so ate could better don't think it will act like
the the covariate did you wanna make sure and 1 day it the 1 day
and I think yes that's going to happen but right now and there's still a
lot of questions even in the city years man and on the right and on
the right hand and they always been accused of thinking what the right answer is
if you give it to you and that's that's really not true a number that
was for a number of years but there that CFD is so great and the
use overflow by the way is 1 of primary the contract and and as
the question
you have a question like that this is not an easy thing to that maybe
that talk about showing talk about the Apollo from Mr. before Apollo we went to
the point at which the with a single string avionics systems we when I have
you what computer
on the command service module we had the 1 service propulsion system to get you
out of 1 orbit to agenda and I think today
it will be very difficult to
I do that I think you're probably going to have to
have multiple stroke multiple strings you have about escape system and all of the escape
system something in that context may be more difficult to think that tools you have
today will make it easier but I do think what we know today is just
like the best set on the understanding a little bit about the management board it's
gonna be having some respects my comment is that next time we go to find
out how hard it really was
because I don't think it's going to be hard to do this that's not personal
feeling that the people agree with 1 of the toughest decisions we ever made the
space program that's never talked about it but this is what we decided to
public was probably
the most fantastic mentioned that we ever came up with that was the 1st time
we left the influence of gravity
we went into orbit around we get out of land on the moon but we
did everything we had to do for the 1st time I think that was probably
the boldest decisions of the that mass and the government men and again I look
back amateur how we will make that decision protested cost 1 man led the attack
was george lowe whose deputy was to measure the Apollo program just space so that
we can get the administrator and they became friends have oppressive of of principal techniques
that was really fantastic project
one should dismiss
my second example
of getting personal is what's called the four one nine scans in advance
fy scan which you've all received email saying you know i've got ten million dollars
in the bank account in wherever they need to transfer
and if you get sucked into that you pay an advance fee to enable the
transfer and you never see it again of course
and you might think who on earth would fall for that nobody in this room
clearly but people still do
the figures here
the blue ones
to the left of the two thousand six the red ones
to the right of the two thousand five because this is a hundred million US
in the united states
the next highest is the UK and goes down
so people do still fall for this
one of the reasons they fall for well with see later on it can be
more complicated more subtle
than it looks
i've been talking about how large these things are in terms of money
let's put some other kinds of numbers on the
my group deals with the data involving millions or billions of banking transactions that's what
really what we're interested in
some of the biggest UK banks
carry out billions of
credit card transactions a year
but one terror just one terrorism case can against one or two stops suspects can
involve analyzing that sort of amount of data
six thousand got but eight thousand CD's two hundred phones and so on
a lot of police resources going into is the source of making up these numbers
now that might get down to
in particular area that myself my group mainly working
the first part of the group mainly working
the banking fraud
banking fraud got many aspects
here are some i referred to identity theft money laundering is is something i
you can say a little bit about i carried out big money laundering project
anti-money laundering project with one of the
big investment banks in the city of london
i've never seen i've never seen
so many zeros after pound sign
it is quite awe-inspiring
with their it's all part of the
it was transferring money between different accounts and some of those accounts for different countries
of course
so germany transfers the sum of money to the united states
it will be
an important and particularly tough aspects of banking fraud is employed for all staff fraud
in particular sleepers who are inserted into the bank and sit there working in perfectly
perfectly legitimate ways
but can become process i came across an example of this not long ago
i should say by the stuff guess fraud in banking is
perpetrated by organised crime syndicates it's generally not individuals that occasionally get in the u
UK recently there was the secretary who stole
four million pounds i think from her
employers who ran a hedge fund something like that he didn't notice it gone
obviously was a hedge fund
but normally fraud in banking is perpetrated by organised crime syndicates and i came across
an example
in which
one of the syndicate to targeted very bright
student computer science mathematics whatever some
early on in his career
identified he was particularly clever and that he was impoverished didn't have much money was
finding it hard to make ends meet
so they gave him a handsome bursary and awards scholarships
and they also
equipped him with a very nice flat in whatever city he was studying
and they did this throughout his three years keeping in basically in lots of money
they the condition being that he would go and work for them or whoever they
nominated when he graduated so he graduated with an absolutely excellent degree
and he got a job in a bank had put him in the bank
and he works in this bank for a number of years being successfully was a
working very bright lad
and he worked his way up and then one day he was very successful one
he was put in charge of all the incoming checks and transfers coming into the
nobody else was there because they trust limiting working for a number of years
to the end of the day he disappeared and all the money had been paid
into another camp gone
completely elsewhere
tens of millions of pounds
the cost what happened after this is also interesting
the police managed to track this he disappeared the police managed to track him down
but remember this sort of crimes perpetrated by organised crime syndicates
try to ring the people who have been providing who provided him with a scholarship
and support over all these years and put him in his job and of course
there was nobody there they just vanished he was left face music by himself
sometimes these people think in really long term
sort of ways
OK so my main focus is in
the retail consumer banking sector that involves things like personal banking credit cards mortgages car
and so on
the reason i am particularly interested in this area is because it's natural area for
statistician you know the numbers are large
the numbers with pound signs in front of large it's natural area statisticians
so we do a lot of work in in the banking area in general not
just for
let's look at
plastic card
fraud data
give you more ideas sort of problems we're going to encounter i'm going to
i've listed them here
but i'm going to look at some of them in detail in the following slides
first as i say there are many transactions often billions this means any other algorithms
must be efficient
let me remind you that
in data mining there are two kinds of data mining one is building a global
principle in many cases you can use the sample of data to do that class
segmentation or aggression whatever you don't necessarily have to use all billion cases
but if your aim is anomaly detection fraud detection or something like that
well you do have to look at each case
you can't just take a sample of ten thousand after the billion
you probably missed the fraught if you do that
so this means means at algorithms coefficients
you will find that there are mixed variable types
generally knocks text or image in this area
but there are categorical and continuous whatever variables
i've already referred to the large number of variables and i'll show you an example
some of the variables are incomprehensible
and many are irrelevant so they might for example be a numerical code showing the
type of sale credit card terminal which is being used which typically will be important
is possible it is typically one the
and we want know
people we working with the banks were no
what those codes mean
there are of course
dramatically different misclassification cost misclassifying a fraud as legitimate failing to detect one is much
more serious than the other way around
there are many ways of committing fraud give examples
the class sizes are unbalanced the normal sort of figure border magnitude ball-park figure four