for today
is that the expected high
a randomly built
binary search tree
it is indeed or n log n so log n
so too
four log
this is what we this is what we'd like to know
because that tells it tells us if we just build
a binary search tree randomly then we can search and on log n time
for sorting
it's not
as big a deal
just care about the expected running time of of creating the thing
here now we know that we can once we prove this theorem we know that
we can search quickly
in expectation
which in fact most of the time
so the rest of today's lecture will be proving this theorem it's quite tricky
you might imagine another big probability analysis along the lines of quicksort and
and everything
so i'm going to start with an outline of proof
so any questions about the here should be pretty clear what we want
this is even weirder than most of the analyses we've seen
it's going to use
was exponentiating random variable
and to do that we need
called jensen's inequality
we prove that tool
usually we don't hurt
probability tools but this one we're approach
it's not too hard
well some
basic analysis
so the theorem are the lemma says
that if we have what's called a convex function and you shall know what that
means but the financing
eighty four gun
have a convex function f we have a random variable x you take f of
the expectation that most the expectation of f
of the random variable
think about it enough to draw convex functions that is fairly intuitive
that will prove it
what that allows us to do
is instead of
the random variable that tells us
the height
the tree
x and call
the random variables are the
the heights
of the st
randomly constructed st
on n nodes
well instead of analyzing
this desired
random variable x and so should have been complex
we're going to analyse
we can analyse any convex function
of XML
and we're going to analyse
so i'm going to define y and to be two
so the power xn
the big question here is why bother doing this the answer is because it works
and it wouldn't work we analyse xn
will see some intuition about later on but it's not very intuitive
this is just a
bizarre analysis where you need the extra tricks
so what we're going down the expectation of y and and from that using jensen's
we're going to get a bound on the expectation of xn pretty tight bound actually
because if we can bound
we can bound the exponent up to constant factors exponentiation up to constant factors
we can bound xn
even better because it takes you take logs to get access
so leaving figure out what the cost and this
so what will prove
this is the
part of the proof
the expected value of y and his or her and q
here we won't really know what the consonants
don't need two
and then
but these pieces together so let's that
what we really care about
is the expectation of xn
was the height of the tree what we find out about it is
this fact
so we some some horizontal space here
we get the expectation of two accent
that's the expectation
why and
so we learned about order and humans
and jensen's inequality tells us if we take this function
to the x
we plug in here
then on the left-hand side
we get to to the next
so we get to the xn
is that most
you have to the accent
so that's where we use jensen's inequality because what we care about is you xn
so now we have about say well to to that you've xn is at most
and here
so if we take the log of both sides we get you have XML
the log events you
already in this funny way log water and you which will actually tell us the
constant this is three log n
was order one
we will prove that the expected height of a randomly constructed binary search tree on
n nodes
is roughly three log n
at most
i'll say more about that later
so you've now seen
the end of the proof
the foreshadowing and now this is the top down approach to you sort of see
what the steps are now we just have to do the steps
k step one
take a bit of work but it's easy
because it
very basic stuff step two
and some come and go and you get this like heavy-tailed distribution with the spike at twenty
and again if you ask how long people talk most are very short and again
it's it's surprisingly straight power law where most most of the conversations are shorter but some are
longer and I think this is like two days or something and then I cut if off
let's skip this one let's skip this one  so this may be also interesting
what I'm showing here is this is age versus age and the colour is
the number of conversations right so in absolute measures if you go and pick
a point right this is  symmetric but still this would mean that there are the most conversations between people
of ages I don't know fifteen to twenty or something right and you can see
these sort of correlation with the age that people tend to talk with the people of the same age
or similar age so now we can ask so here we have the number of conversations
now we can do the same and ask
what's the total what's the conversation duration and you can see for example that these
old people
talk the longest then then here again younger people talk talk also quite long
but in this active part of population right this is a deep so we'll be here these are the
people who have to work right they are like twenty five to fourty right and you
can see something similar again in number of messages per conversation right again this active part
of population has very short conversations while this older  people seems to have a lot
of time and also young people seems to have some time  but sorry
so we should be over here here down
that's you okay maybe but then let me show
the next one so now you can ask how many messages per unit time now you can saw
your your your parents are typing very slowly or something right because these guys the young guys
are like typing really fast right they exchange a lot and then the rest does very
poorly so this is one then  you can like take the countries
I think the session that's a good question and I was talking to people
and they couldn't really tell me but I think that session closes when the last person leaves
so when the last message is exchanged so if you have your I don't know window open with the
same person for some for a long time I think they have some time
out and they would sort of close the session I think that's how they have it implemented but
I don't know the exact answer sorry so this is now where you say who
talks so you group all the users from a particular country and you ask who talks to whom
and just the width is like the log number of conversations and what you can
see here is basically right everyone talks to United States and there then you
have these clusters by language right so you have like China Hong Kong Thailand Spanish-speaking
countries Belgium and France Portugese-speaking countries Turkey and Germany makes
a lot of sense Canada and United Kingdom also and so on so this
is the number and this is the conversation duration so here it's funny because all these
like arab states they seem to talk amongst themselves very long and then you have
like  Azerbaijan and russia I don't really have interpretation for these these guys
like to talk to each other here but it's funny so this part is funny sure
have like France and Saudi Arabia France and Cameroon right but still like so okay
here is some these another view on the data and what you can also do
is just so wherever you see a log in of a person you can go and get their location and plot
plot it as a dot right so now here the red would mean a lot of
logins and green blue means very few logins and you can see for example right
this to be Japan this is South Korea here there should be North Korea but it's
empty this is like Australia right you can see like the the here is the Africa
right East Coast West Coast europe and so on so so this is
one so so this is europe now again you can see nicely so for example this to
be the Alps where there's nothing right like the western europe UK
Finland  up here Denmark and so on so this is now superimposed on
the map of the world I don't know if  if if it's you can see it well
but all these blue circles that I added these are the locations where there's one
more than one million logins from the people and you can see that
all these major cities appear on the map right like the largest European ones and
so on so this is per capita right so this
is so so you can see like now you can see that like
Midwest has a lot per capita right in in the previous graph it didn't exist right or here it's it's
you may be have this kind of structure so
you do penalize
small differences small contrast because they
may correspond to noise
big differences are taken to correspond to
actually falling one of the other so then you get kind of what's the process
we we'd like to be able to deal with that kind of pairwise energy function
but you can't do it with this construction
in fact you know this is not
quite as general as we
could have on this
graph because actually i could start introducing
eight years ago diagonally between
turns you get a bit more general generality out that so if you come to
us as a paper where he analyses
prior that kind where you have these columns of nodes and just as many edges
as you like
nodes in the two columns and he asked the question what is the most general
g function you could possibly get that way
taking on board this restriction that you want the
he for neighbouring
the pixels to be a function of the difference between the labels on the neighbouring
pixels to you accept that restriction it turns out that this is different from difference
function has to be convex you implemented anything you like but it's got to be
convex so that's the one cover this case
so you know this is any construction
it has the great
benefit like the binary construction
the optimal you get out of this really is the global optimum
and that's guarantee you know methods that do that you can follow between we should
be grateful that we get
as same has convexity constraint which is OK sort of classical problems in know like
almost like the slide yesterday was going through you know being the filtering traditional reconstruction
and that's done with complex
priors but if if you want to beyond on convex it's what do
so here's another idea which is very widely used
people who do graph cut and this is called for expansion
back to the same problem again
but now the idea is
to do
repeated binary optimisation
and so what you do at each
binary step
each step deals with a particular value alpha in the range of x in other
words one of your available labels so in each step of this organization we elect
label alpha the alphas
the different levels are all going to be visited in some order such that every
every label is visited in particular cycle
at that at particular step of the cycle
what we do is considered changing all of the existing labels at all the pixels
to alpha
so the only choice you five you leave the label as it is we change
it to this new label value alpha and so that defines a binary problem over
binary variables that called them y k
so if y k is zero
we get the old value of xk and y k is one we get out
of the only that the only allowed knew that so now i could minimize respect
to y
and i have myself binary
via binary labels graph cut problem
and so i can do that contact
no worries
just use graph cut from the before the break
no one
will very worried
should i be worried
there is something you should be worrying about you can tell my telephone there's something
for that
we can use binary graph solve
we can use truckers' binary problems provided what
provided the problem is
i think we can say
well so yes positive or in the canonical form with regular
so we really ought to check the regularity of we really check the regularity of
this problem i mean you know anything doesn't look right you have a slight intuition
about this
not saying you should
any idea
i don't know what it looks like it's the first time that i we get
we're going to check regularity and see what implications the regularity has if anything for
the class of g functions that can be dealt with
what i've done here is constructed
i mean i'm going to
the new notation here g super y for the pairwise potential in the new binary
problem because i now have
g to mean the pairwise potential for the multi
for the integer value problem that you why is now the pairwise potential for the
binary value problem so what we should have is that this binary problem
the pairwise potentials satisfies the regularity condition that is that the off diagonal elements
the sum exceeds the sum of the
diagonal elements
this is what we should be
so now what i've done is i've actually filled in
what the
all of the
this two by two table it in terms of the original GP
so the g cost the pairwise costs we incur believing things alone
that's the zero zero in the binary problem
that means leave things alone but excels
and that's just the original cost of x and x
but if i look at zero
if i take
why primed equals one
in the new problem
what that means is i replaced excel
the prime to excel
replaces it labelled by out now
the pairwise cost dying there in the original problem is now
and so on to the other pixels i believe that this table
and now i write down the
regularity condition just summing up the off diagonal elements comparing with the diagonal elements we
get this
now you know this is all
satisfied by any metric
because for metric
g about for the first of all the genes of positive psychology of alpha alpha
is zero
so i'm left with is
here x and ex-prime has got to be less than you have XML property of
an ex-prime which is just the triangle inequality
so the triangle inequality and
the identity
condition here for metrics
i'm home and dry
it turns out this is definitely satisfied by
any metric that's good because that includes
this guy and parts
and the truncated quadratic replacing with the quadratic which is also useful for the whole
of the functions there which are which are in place that's very useful
what a good idea
question was could i love the black
the answer is yes
actually there is another
there's another
variation on alpha expansion but i think in the it's of time i'm going to
skip it but it's alpha beta swap it's called you it's a little bit more
laborious a bit more work with less restrictions all you need then on g is
that be a semi metric to a metric but without the triangle inequality
so the the question is
does the flow get complex the mall as you have in the graph
bayesian paradigm if you like
this is just an indication
you should never just take numbers at face value without thinking about implications of certain
in particular in this case the implications of uniform sampling and using
functions based on frequency
alongside carry on but only if it all
OK then yes now take more than ten
so we well spend all our what i'm going to do all speed through some
without taking enough time for you to be able to understand them
well i sorry i probably just so there's some people who
that's familiar the sum of all it straight away
but all spaces and slides and i'll get them
because it's nearly more interesting in looking at life
so when i was just looking ahead to how quickly
may use those models i've shown you
in more
complex cases in this actually goes to question asked earlier
but what if the discontinuity in that function
what if the models a more complex formal basis functions from all data whatever
can we exploit this technique effectively
more complex models where the answer is yes of course
and so complicated you want to be
with the approximation techniques that you have to use
but one area where
bayesian inference can work very well
is in a large linear models so we gain an advantage in computation
having models linear in the way
and since the support vector machine came along
a lot of interest
in models that have lots and lots of basis functions or inputs or whatever
but these are included in the model linearly
we can sort of use frame shed so far
we can apply it models with lots of basis functions
which gives potentially very complex models we can do some interesting useful things
this is something i call the sparse bayesian learning framework which
the relevance vector machine is just one
i mean just skim through
something so
if you're familiar with the idea of sparse models this sort of idea
and if you've got lots of weight
well stating regularisation making them all small
i want to be nice if instead you just set low to zero and then
used the few went
there's plenty of good reasons for doing that
you might actually be interested in what the weights are some clinical applications that's the
there are also other
reasons for wanting sparse models
one is they ran a lot faster
take this memory
models require hundreds of weights or thousands of weights
to be stored basis functions to be calculated waiting
so when i was at microsoft
in those dark dark days
i works on handwriting recognition on wikipedia is there in tablet PC
so i must say is probably only the north point one percent of the system
contain anything can be considered to be my intellectual and there is a little bit
and there's also the game for the xbox called forza motorsport
which had some albums running in it
we designed at microsoft research in cambridge
they included some bayesian inference going on content exactly what it was
but it was that class
no one but the game because it
but it was fun to account for while
so i'm just going to go south get this really quickly
sparse bayesian approach
exactly the same i showed you earlier in terms of the likelihood function
that's exactly show you again seem like
the difference here is that we have a slight change in the priors
so the single hyperparam we now have one hundred from to her weight
charles get out of these slides online i don't if plan to put the whole
winter school slides online put slides online at my
website very very near future
so skimming of
skin process slide
we can't this approximate inference step again
and we have the exact same problem we contact calculate the joint posterior
nine out of potentially thousands about this as well we've just got one thirty thousand
one for each weight
so we do the same thing as before
this decomposition
again we want to maximize the type two maximum likelihood and we maximize
this posterior hyper parameter posterior
but this time ago potentially thousands had to
so we can calculate the weight posterior again
and that simply has the same form as before instead of hyperparameters alpha i have
a diagonal matrix with all its hyperparameters
o thing to note here
if any of those hyperparam susceptibility that sets that individual weight to zero
that can gives some mechanism
before pruning out deleting individual way before when we had one alpha which said that
infinity the whole thing went to zero now use
in practical terms
so you want to infinity just theorize that one way
i give this kind of mechanism
getting rid
so the question is how is that mechanism going to work
that indeed is not going to happen on alpha is going to go to infinity
we do exactly the same as before
catholic that marginal likelihood function
and we simply maximise this
we respect out
alpha this time is a collection of maybe thousands of
so what we can't do is
july grand for with the minimum
is that was quite totally feasible experiment
so we're going to have to do this time
it's look at maximizing this using a sort of hell climbing technique for nonlinear optimization
we can plug into conjugate gradients we can to any number of things but if
you're optimisation expert
you can think of many things today
but actually this function has some nice properties
mean we can actually come up with
efficient and
not to be easy to describe optimisation
if we look at the marginal likelihood is only two cases depends
how the other high ground set
we look at just one hyperparameter
the the two cases good case and about k
then there's more
the tax laws
in europe
another not
the idea
i love
don't do you
or on
a core
i know
yes yes yes
he said
as you can
well that
well i
five years on
who are all you do
the a
one of the two
i want to tell me
he then
next to know
this well
not as you know the year of
right right
o crashed for me
there is
the model
as long
what you
this is
at the moment
it is always
an upper bound
the marginal polytope here may be really expensive to compute exactly
so that the space of all the marginals
but what i might be able to do is i might be able to outer
bound that
so in a way what's happening is
if this is my complicated marginal polytope
the convex set but it might be really complicates
well putting up a box like so around it
it is going to give me an upper bound
on g of data if i replace m by n prime
likewise if i have my entropy
and that upper bounded by some other function here
but it's also going to give me an upper bound
so what this means is combining an outer bound on the polytope
an upper bound on the entropy
might be able to reduce my optimisation problem two one that's tractable
and even though this has been an upper bound on my logposterior by minimize that
at least i won't be optimizing something that's completely off the mark
so this is what we get is the optimisation problem
and then
well sort of
basically that's just what i explained in the previous slide if you use semidefinite constraints
for the covariance matrix if you just say well my marginal polytope surely has to
have such a form that get a proper covariance matrix
then i to kill two birds with one stone first of all i a covariance
matrix which will allow me to give an upper bound on the entropy
secondly it also
i mean the constraints in some way
my marginal polytope
and then i get to semidefinite programming problems now most of you know that those
problems can be are all pain and we hoped that it will be possible to
scale this up to anywhere
near realistic problem size
at the present that's not the case and
while this gives you very nice theoretical insights stay clear of this method
and the OK basically
i think what i want to say about graphical models and connections in this case
i've got time for some question
the new
junction tree
well if it's one i one know
how do you use
while the right question
this is something i deliberately tried to avoid any how
so this is something where you
need to use domain knowledge of the problem is defined as all
so reason for this
what you might want to
well think
and the bush
the president bush
so obviously you assume that they were
he played features
and like one
here for the best players
but the place at all
but in addition to that
what you might also notice that well since
this very seriously time
well you will have an issue with
you think that the centre will probably all be
the or not with
i'm happy
to share this next session
my name is
and it's going to be very interesting session right after lunch and in particular with
the interesting invited talk
given by
you can find this very impressive biography material and about
reception that just
one is the one or two words he graduated from MIT media lab in two
thousand two
he's now with columbia university
he received an NSF career award and most importantly he has just written a very
interesting book
which you can use this one is website by machine learning
and so he started it will be machine learning applied to multi modal interfaces
so with that and
thanks very severe still on your time and effort this morning so
i'll try to maintain a steady
his but actually also released because a lot of ideas here are not for wikipedia
and i think it's great to have a community of people are ambitious things more
but with the very last is that we're working on which is uncharted territory for
us which is looking at surgical drills surgical procedures with microscopic robots
five and the second but really are
continue area here were
we don't know anything about the signal properties noise dynamics and things like that very
complicated robot cost model
o dollars and so on but it's actually becoming an industry standard so
and we're looking forward to sharing data and share some of the court
the main approach is going to be dynamic bayesian networks
approach which is popular in the machine learning community
of cookery talking about
what motivated us to go to the ends and
you want to multimodal animal person perspective
and i want review about the underlying machine which is really just bayesian networks and
the standard algorithms behind how they can be used by variations of the classical
is in networks which are things like hidden markov models models in common use and
i would expect things like the expectation maximisation algorithm
and that unlike his mission to new
graphs that are more relevant to our particular multimodal market
and now show shows examples just scattered examples of different policies in these networks the
first one hit in our model
we'll talk about learning and doing maximum likelihood and high training and then use it
to learn
interactive gestures
another example is input output more model also fit the framework and they can be
used to do on visual interaction learning
and we're platforms
and then we'll move to
what kind of the current state of the art
the graphical models community and that's intractable dynamic bayes nets and our talks coming up
on variational estimation structure the field so on what we talk about generalizing generalizing the
learning algorithm
first of to handle
graphs are really intractable with distribution log on as we we try to do exact
inference and then will show a particular model which appeared you're
in UAI two thousand four which is this dynamical systems to which is the tree
on top of many different dynamical systems so that can connecting many common filters in
nature and in the tree structure will look at that for multi person visual interaction
football by tracking football players american football so there's a there's a handful of players
being trapped in the field i will talk about how we we're trying to apply
to surgical drills and then getting other people involved in ongoing directions and how there
are some similarities between this type of data
and the data that you're would
OK so i just put the money
what i want to go beyond the simplest dynamical system
and those dynamical systems
are in the markov walls and columns filters and actually is graph the exact same
the structure of the fuzzy common has a continuous they
the model one hundred has discrete
but this is really meant to model one single processing time one single dynamic process
with the same kind of markov assumption but it turns out to be somewhat remarkable
modalities markov processes and that's
true for combining
multiple videos model what also heterogeneous
without his audio and video particles are sometimes different timescales audio video and haptics different
scales of time also for aptitude scales also from noise characteristics of calcium noise
types processes are
the number of common filters are there are more multinomial distributions there's also to
unusual noise probably so we can just them all together into one
monolithic model
and the actual sums of money rescinded as well for tracking
even a single person and not only in each has different dynamics you can move
more quickly and you can move your upper arms also to person and
dynamics also have different speed dynamics and you could also imagine the only weakly coupled
so people don't
walking in lockstep and walking and he together still some unsynchronized someone stops the other
person will stop well
the personal
continuing talking about conversation so there's weak coupling the what happened is that the different
coupling we don't want to put everything on one dataset so given to time series
so maybe this one person walking here's another person walking or tracking down
we don't want to put this on one more time recognise this as
you don't want to be seen people walking together because this person might
change the face of the wall saying this person might be walking
let's stop and catch that doesn't mean they're not working together but if you put
them one time series you can only do one kind of dynamic time warping within
my walls and they really aligned perfectly these templates of what we don't recognise the
really is
the same gesture the same behavior so i'm going to be looking in different ways
to zipper multiple interacting processes with different graphical models and different bayesian networks
so let's do a quick review for many votes this might be
not really on Byars's credit Commons content but were just a nondescript come loses license
the basic make it anywhere in the world what we're doing is aggregating and that's
the service of an intermediary is that today and that's the real technology but not
send Roddy is differences which like a search you know aggravator on their kind of
aggravated to make neighbor every kind and this distribution over the world and so the
real value here is it Antennariidae established a new space for tax and and 4
other categorization schemes for Boggs and they also they also produced a real-time but search
engine so that that give it a value so that people didn't happen I go
to Yahoo brands of blogs or whatever an ought to have their blog somewhere on
the work with that's the kind of thing that I can think will happen but
there really isn't any and will see what happens in terms of the Web infrastructure
but the whole but that cost dynamics of hosting with the exception video there's no
cost anymore video that's all that's the big problem IN but you know these there's
gonna be a good host anything anywhere my choice is a writer would be which
can lead to I want to be like I want to know I'm not a
photographer I wanna photographs on the Massengill site not real job but they didn't invite
me National Geographic so I get into real child not now I you know that's
the that's the sort of thing flicker as it has also micro economy of communities
like that reputation communities and I it's really that's really what these things or for
fight that I respect your point about that kind timing excellent about religion somewhat small
commonly Christian comedies John you must be wary of the giddy geographic but appeared database
of places such abuses that you could use mom and she the question you see
the semantic Web technology he said he wished he would've useful which ones would you
views of how would succeed give money but I wish they would exist but I
could use some somehow whistling there were about for instance that at the look Getty
again animal by remember why is it that way work but is geographically Geo quarters
and the global and that's what the properties but I wanted the semantic Web technology
is not like you know Al or something and pull up and Poland's what kind
of a website is more what the ecosystem that and if it semantic Web but
it's a acid develops it will create more pieces of infrastructure Princess you know right
off the shelf I get to have a Google Maps said the news to a
bronzes as well but I think the last thing on the shop like India's flicker
photos half of that in all these like big databases right right there and infrastructure
is like falling off a lot of course we're gonna use that's the semantic Web
technology is in like that like a big buying into a whole world or something
from the point of view of state bond for office buildings in sleeping bags it
doesn't it's not like off-the-shelf and that's what I wish it would be like things
that turn giant kinds are back question about this this you said you knew basically
agreed of structure data on which to than overlaid and unstructured data but disagreed I
suppose would be the viewpoint would differ so you these greedy domain-specific said so for
example for geographical data mean there differences between people so it is 1 part of
China is not a part of that depends we ask so is that something he
you should take into account is something you should ignore and take a majority viewpoint
and so easy domain-specific me for traveling maybe just geographical database would look different too
and for political organization has a real good actually but in my take is that
there's plenty of there's plenty in different geographic databases for different purposes said I mean
there's a and the put that they they've all politically but also just some sometimes
they had the construction of some really good you like to reporters others on I
wish they would have to be a single 1 at the World ontology in web
servers for this would not have wanted to say enough Mr. capability request I need
governing space for destinations here's the ideas is based on working right now this user
just tighten this weird were in Chinese I don't understand is this a place in
the year as there's an archaeologist cool what's the Geo Court it's great was the
country's what's that's felt like OK romance that were pretty much easier beneath picture there
is that there's no the the coffers as the come will travel but for intellectual
everything sitting there i can now do bayesian inference
in fact the posterior given data of all that
all right so how do you do that well there are couple ways you'll see
several in this talk the simplest way is to use the gibbs sampler
so how do get sampling here
we begin after in data points you take one data point i pull it out
and look how to sign a given every other datapoints right that the earlier
well this is very easy by exchangeability this is the key issue
you could always take a given data point first moved into the list potential as
data points
now that the in the list all the other clusters of already come in and
sat down
and would as it were to have this customers sit down
what the chinese restaurant rules it sits at a table or number people ready take
that's part of the likelihood term
and then the prior and then we have the likelihood which is that i to
depending on what parameters are for the table would data point i am how close
i am those parameters
so it's really simple that decipher data a utility inside out which stable i said
that's where the gibbs sampler does in european do that for data points anything
after makes the proposition on the number of occupied tables
and the parameter vector is it the stable
here's an example we did this for the next day later this is an abstract
from oral NIPS conference
and our clusters here forty had a one hundred dimensional multinomial distributions and so we
ran this
parameter free
OK there is no free parameters are plugged in and out came some clusterings
i don't i will show you some clusters later but the important point here is
the number of the posterior mode with twenty six clusters
that's the most probable number of clusters in the data from this point point this
algorithm so we're looking now from from the data just some of the clusters of
this is
reasonable topics
OK let me give you more interesting example
a biological example
it's really ready made for the dirichlet process
or the chinese restaurant process
so haplotypes are
sequence markers on a single chromosome
OK so let's consider in a certain region of the genome m binary markers
markers so you have an area c in some places for a year to year
maturity or whatever
two possibilities and every
one of m places in some on some chromosome
so there must there are therefore two the impossible
haplotype pipeline patterns of
binary markers in this region of the haplotype is pattern of binary markers on one
but if i were to as a everybody in this room i not find two
the tmcm is you know fifty three hundred fifty happen i would find even maybe
well i would be very interesting but
there are hundreds in an old barn or or
doesn't it all upon so there are very many fewer viewers than you'd expect to
be some commentary
it's very interesting know what happened to talk
it's in the the the hard part of the problem is that when you actually
as a
you have to remember there are two chromosomes
and the pairs and you lose the order in which
markers on which chromosome
as you have to reconstitute back
it's called the phasing problem here is that the underlying biological through one chromosome i
have walker a
the CIA other chromosome i have little will be in the big c
when i actually get the data out of the biological as they have lost ordering
i get i just know there's a capital a little a cover of i don't
know which both with the there are all possible combinations of these what could underlie
by that one person state i couldn't deal public and do it but i have
a whole bunch of people it's now clustering problem and i can actually figure out
what the underlying haplotype
this is the clustering problem to the genetic write down the probability of a so-called
phenotype which is the the phenotype if unordered set of markers
probably the type which is the sum
over all pairs of haplotypes were making human i one chromosome from the father one
chromosome from other and i do that with probability p of h one
have from other divisions to have
father on the product lines i meant something called hardy weinberg equilibrium
that's not really important for us
and then given those haplotypes
what the problem that i see that the time is the problem here is just
the probability of the order
loss and recovery
from those haplotype is fact that you are one zero
and i sum over all possible choices of apple pie
but genetics here i see that the probability of my data is the mixture model
in this information was kind of a trivial one zero
probability here
and these are well known probabilities from the archival population
so it's really important about the problem is all this stuff here this capital what
is the size of the bag of haplotypes with the pool
how many applications are there
we can infer that you know everything about this problem
why plays a big role is that it is the first in some derivative expansion
some long wavelength expansion this is the first you can write down or higher order
terms will involve
caravaggio's extrinsic or intrinsic are higher derivatives therefore when you think about the problem of
a long distance scales this is the first thing that comes in
it is furthermore the only actions that we know how to quantized exactly this is
of course also four
now this is the actual now when you think about
these relativistic strings first of all the one thing that should be made clear is
that these are quite different from violin strings you know we are of course all
used the strings in everyday life classical strings like violin strings the strings have some
unusual properties here is one way to
i understand them
one can remember use arbitrary ways to parametrize
the project of this thing so let's use the simplest one it's called static parametrisation
what according to power is real time
x zero and the coordinates sigma along this training is basically a coordinate that measures
the distance between the two fixing surface string of the violin you the violin string
you fix it into points
along the direction x one c
and let's use the coordinates sigma there now you can easily expand about this comparable
to action and you can recognise here something more familiar to you see this is
an actual to think about the energy if you prefer the hamming tony and you
just flip a sign of
so sure how to
now i have done something
click back
they came
i would like to it from here
sure maybe i'm just not use this gadget so a so change the sign of
the minus one half and then you have an energy now you see this energy
has three it has a constant term first of all what this has to be
i understood as a mass so this thing has a mass which is mentioned times
length show for a relativistic string must ensure if thing had no expanded what had
the second term is simply kinetic energy right it's the transverse oscillation energy which carries
some kinetic energy and the third term is the gradient show you see this is
the usual
the expression for waves propagating in two dimensions but they propagate at the speed of
light novel things are of course not sure that's where the were the relativistic comes
in waves propagate at the speed of light and the mass density is the same
thing as mentioned if this thing is not stretched it has enormous there's no such
thing as a string to rest here because if it's simply a you know let's
go from that once it shrinks to a point and there's nothing left
now by contrast the violin string has a mass density which is typically much bigger
than extension
and it therefore supports both transverse and longitudinal waves
raveling supplements
speeds it has substructure in other words and it can also stay paul if you
remove the fixings you know it may not be as offensive but it will still
be there before have of course some energy dense
when you try to quantify the strains it is actually much more useful to use
a very different parameterisation which is not these static parameterisation that they show it to
but which is called
the conformal parametrisation
here is how this is defined actually conformal coordinates
one wants to the tangent vector to the surface
remember the trajectory of this thing to be everywhere orthogonal and of equal length
the length can vary from place to place but they have to be orthogonal and
of equal length in other words you are trying to basically by the the surface
with small squares
that's the conformal parametrisation now just to a to understand a bit more
if you think about the parametrisation of the search for us by latitude and longitude
this is not
it is an orthogonal parameterisation latitude longitude are orthogonal at every point however whereas one
degree longitude is about a hundred kilometres one degree in i am in latitude and
one degree longitude is
the same hundred ten kilometres from the equator but it is zero for some of
the polish on the ball
you move around a millimetre you know you're basically going around a three hundred sixty
degrees of course that's
thank you
right so this is not a good example of conformal parametrisation here a however it
is an orthogonal one and you know you can now imagine i want try to
grow parameterizations which are conformal of the sphere where you everywhere have small squares
now why is this nice well you see if you think about this induced metric
that i talked about before it takes this form
if d x is orthogonal to the sigma x the that the off diagonal terms
of the matrix zero that's the orthogonality
and if the two legs are equal up to sign actually then this whole thing
becomes simply some fact or it's called the conformal factor and they usually euclidean or
hear lawrence symmetric one zero zero minus one
therefore when you we take the square root of the determinant of these you see
that the action becomes quadratic equations of motion become linear and you can just sort
of the system
so it's very convenient choice and something that we cannot do for the membrane for
higher dimensional objects that's part of the technicalities on y but there is a more
fundamental reason of why string theory has played a more dominant role than other extended
objects in physics
now in this conformal coordinates if you write down the equations
for this training
they become just free massless wave equations in two dimensions show every recorded that satisfies
this free
a massless wave equation
and in two dimensions this equation has a very simple solution
so far
we have only discussed
in this course electricity
come down
but this course
it's about electricity
want to talk about magnetism
in the fifth century BC
the greeks already knew
there are some rocks that track bits of irony
they are very plentiful in the district of magnesium
so that's when a magnet
and magnetism comes from
the rocks contain iron oxides
which we will call
eleven hundred eighty
the chinese used these needles of magnetite
to make compasses
and in the thirteenth century
it was discovered
that magnetite have two places
of maximum attraction which we call poles
so if you take one piece of magnetite
it always has two poles
let's call one call a
being in a repel each other
bnb repel each other
with a and and b
attract each other
there's a huge difference
between electricity
and magnetism
was electricity also have two polarities
but you are free to choose a plus or minus o
was magnetism you don't have that source
the poles always come in pairs
isolated magnetic poles do not exist as a physicist what's a magnetic monopole
do not exist as far as we know
if anyone finds a magnetic monopole
i don't think that people are not looking
that would certainly be worth a nobel prize in principle
there could exist but as far as we know
they don't exist it never been seen
electric monopoles do exist if you have a plus charts
that some
electric multiple
never mind this charge electric charge
that is an electric monopole if you have a plus and minus of equal strength
that is an electric dipole
whenever you have magnets
you always
the magnetic dipole there's no such thing
as a magnetic monopole
in the sixteenth century
gilbert discovered that the earth is really a giant magnet
and he experimented
was compasses
and he was effectively the first person to map out
the electromagnetic field of the earth
and if you take one of those magnetized needles
and the needle
is pointing
in this direction
which is the direction
of northern canada
then by convention we call this side of the new class
not was north
and we call this side of the new
since a repels a
and the rebels b
with a and b tracks each other
in north carolina that
is the magnetic south pole you're not the magnetic north pole
that said you can of course
so this is the way that we find the directions north and south
of these magnetite
a crucial discovery was made eighteen nineteen
by the danish physicist hirsch that
he discovered
the magnetic needle
he was born a current in the wire
this link
with electricity
this is arguably perhaps the the most important
experiment ever
first that
that the current in the wire
produces a magnetic fields
and that the magnetic needle
moves in response to the magnetic field which is produced by
the wire
and this magnificent discovery caused an explosion
of activity in the nineteenth century notably by
and here by
and by henry
and it culminated into the brilliant work
of the scottish theoreticians
maxwell composed universal
field theory
which connects electricity was magnetism
is at the heart
of this course
maxwell's equations you'll see them all for your all four
by the end of this
if i have a current
a wire
let's say the wire is perpendicular to the blackboards
and the current
into the blackboards
i put across in there
if the current comes out of the blackboard
i put it up there
and historical reason for that
always talked about vectors in eighteen one and of course if you've never seen a
and i'm going to show you a vector this is a vector
and this
is when it comes to you
that's why you see the dot
and this is when it goes away from you
that's where you crossed
so these current
in the experiment again the subject played went like this only god
all the time
when did we start
one one OK
that's about those two and a half hours to two hours
so these are two stimuli and screen
and the stimuli could be included either you know like the location was randomized controlled
trial there are two types of trials either the trials with this like snowflake and
then we are looking things
trials with these two we're looking things
these are actually randomized for different subjects there were different pair different fractals
the deal was on trials where they saw these
they stand a chance to get a reward juice reward
if they chose one stimulus they would get the reward sixty percent probability another stimulus
or thirty percent probability they don't know this in advance and to learn this by
trial and error
the other type of trials
they would also get something with sixty percent probability thirty percent probability that this wasn't
used this was considered a neutral reward this is actually artificial saliva
they didn't know that cause that starts being neutral people's faces but actually when you
just get it in your mouth it just feels like
nothing kind of like your own space
and they had to play this game
randomly interleaving these kinds of trials
what they saw before you get to the two conditions what they saw that in
this case subject started preferring this stimulus in this case they were in different because
they don't really care about the reward so firstly we can see that the subjects
learned the contingencies
you know they had
in this experiment in one block
everything was as i described right now so
this is called instrumental block were subject actions could affect
their rewards
just as i said and they had another block
that was the problem lovin block we're actually they didn't get to choose
they would see to stimuli then the computer would make
a square around one of them so that's the computer made the choice and they
just had to indicate
what the computer chose left right that was to equate the motor action the computer
actually chosen based on their previous choices it was yoked to their own previous choices
but they don't know that doesn't matter
so they could they they had to choose what the computer chose and they got
the rewards with the same probabilities
according to the stimuli that the computer to the stimulus to the computer chosen
i take on question for you
is to think about why the experiment was designed this way and
i think of prediction errors they were trying to generate as many prediction errors possible
the reason that all these experiments use probabilistic rewards to get prediction errors at the
time of reward the reward count of can ever be completely
predicted and the reason to use of is the reason that they use two different
trial types so that the stimuli can be predicted either so there's the prediction error
at the time the stimulus
it out
the results show
but the results showed was that
if you take a prediction error signal as so you take a model you fit
to the behaviour you generate the prediction errors that you think should happen at different
times convolved with this he went have response function exactly what i showed you before
and now i look for areas in the brain
that correlate with this prediction error
what they saw was that there were two areas in the straight
as you now expect from an actor critic mechanism there's
the area the ventral straight up
each one of these plots shows correlation
it shows the areas that were correlated the ventral striatum was correlated with prediction errors
both in the fallopian tasks of both when they did when they choices
well the choices were not around when they could only predict what was going to
happen but the computer made the choices and in instrumental task where they made their
own choices and this is in this is showing the conjunction of both
both tasks
and the dorsal striatum in the
ventral is is isn't
o ventral dorsal or they come from animal
from the animal anatomy is of interest to the
belly indoor as to the back so think of you know and also there has
that somewhere to the top is dorsal more to the bottom spectral so as the
ventral striatum and appears the dorsal well higher
here is the dorsal striatum
and the dorsal striatum only correlated with prediction errors and instrumental task and not in
the fallopian tasks so the idea was
in problem behavior when you only need predictions you need the critic
but not the actor
and the instrumental task you need both created and actors both of them
correlated with prediction errors
and you might ask yourself why are we seeing prediction errors in the straight and
that's the way you minimize this energy function
and there is the
perhaps the cost
like that then
although the
connected to the top one which assumes no non-zero we'll get
value zero
and all the ones the bottom will give anyone so i assigned zero or one
each pixel in the image represent
what so segmentation
this is
well i'll be talking about several classes later on i'll be talking about many classes
later on
in the
the most simple case it's two classes in fact that's that's a very useful case
art studio things like that you need many classes
so basically you have your source you one using zero and know
and you
and express the energy
it turns out
in terms of
and expression
with the a a one a two are random variables associated with the two nodes
are there either zero or one
and you can express energy as nick as
so the polynomial
in these terms
and there a way of taking each of those things
two a one
it turns out to be equal to
h from the source to a one with the label to one
five a one by which means a one by means
if a one one a one hour zero one zero one by one feels so
that means
a and its there
and this is well then you have
terms like
which is the right form a one a two by
that gives you
and h to do all those for all of these
in the expression
the rest
and yet
what is sometimes called t eighty eight which joins the sort of thing the energies
which pairwise terms
right then
find cost cuts
of that
that's the way
minimize the fact that are function
the minimum cost
corresponds to the minimum
of the energy function
i said
this can be done by maximum flow we try to push
along edges from the source
nonzero so inference there lots of ways get one going from sorcerer two to five
we can push
for a long time
an extract
the floor which was to become zero
the five become three and then we go into finding other ones
so for instance here
we had
how each those factor of minus four
this gives you
the equivalent energy function
i'll go through one more thing and then i'll start getting down to a little bit
the mathematics behind this
so this becomes more clear precisely how you
one of the things
people thought about
and this seems like grounds ICCV from sponsors conferences here in ICCV is basically
the top about conferences
the idea is
suppose we have to solve similar problems many times so for instance if you go
to i mean i talk about in those images but if i want to segment
people or things from videos
then separate video
things being separated by one thirty second not much has changed so you probably solving
are very similar
graph cut problem to the one
he sold
one thirty the second ago
can you not
recycle of the computation to a lot more simply
the answer is yes questions
like this problem we can solve it gets solution and a similar problem pb can
solve and get a solution
you read a a lot of the same work so
maybe these things are similar to some problems a b and b is similar so
that just the difference between these
try and solve
just in the sense for the difference
let they get the solution is it's quicker
so for instance as an example which really has nothing to do with graph cuts
just illustrate three
you want to evaluate that
that function when you look at them
the very different they very similar to each other the bottom line
two times of one plus five so want to compute the top one doesn't make
sense to go through the whole computation tree the bottom line when all you need
to do
is just
at the population
mop up to get five residents that's just the idea
now how does this apply here
the idea is to come up with the dynamic solution two
st mincut problem was the graph cut
that may be into time instances very similar
so for instance a segmentation of videos
the idea is
good afternoon my name is ross girshick and i will be presenting not fast object
detection this is joint work with my advisor of thousands while at the university of
chicago and david mcallister TTI chicago
we present a method for building fast cascade detectors from state of the art deformable
part models and by doing this were able to speed up detection times by more
than an order of magnitude and we demonstrate this with state-of-the-art models from the UC
TTI object detection system which has been a a consistent top performer in the detection
task of the pascal VOC challenge
so here are some examples of the speedups are able to get by moving to
cascade based architecture so for many object classes were able to perform detections must in
one second per image we see some representative speedups ranging between say that seven times
the twenty four times over the baseline algorithm and we get an average of about
fourteen and a half times overall twenty classes and pascal two thousand seven at the
two nodes i like to make about these figures one is that this is the
single threaded implementations with the multi threaded implementations should be possible to perform detections at
several frames per second
in the other is that this is a very conservative cascade thresholds chosen in order
to get the full range of recall so they were able to report average precision
numbers that are competitive with essentially the same as the baseline so this is the
cascade operating in slow motion and they don't show how
we can trade off recall in order to get faster detection times
so we focus mostly on the case of star models because they lead to very
simple algorithms and yet there still able to perform reasonably well in difficult real world
so this review time model it's pretty simple form of pictorial structures model
is defined in terms of a set of parts each part has a function which
tells you how well it matches to particular location in an image
one of these parts is distinguished as the root in that case it's this triangular
nose in the centre of the remaining parts which are the eyes and the mouth
are encouraged at some position relative to the root but they are allowed to move
from the anchor point but it costs something which is modeled by deformation penalty function
given one of these models and the test image were interested in doing detection which
basically amounts to finding good configurations such as this configuration of the model in front
resignation in space
so we can formalise this a bit more by defining what we mean by the
score of an object hypothesis
so an object hypothesis is defined by
choosing a location omega for the root part
then we have to choose the displacement delta i for each other non root parts
in this delta i displacement is measured relative to an anchor position AI which is
a function of the real location
given this hypothesis
we can define the score
by computing the parts score for the route
and then summing over the remaining on root parts
in which we take into account the score number parts at their displaced locations relative
to their anchor points
but then we have to subtract away the displacement cost removing those parts
so we can then extend the score
the hypothesis to a single score for relocation of the object and we do this
by maximising over part displacements so intuitively you can think of this function score omega
as computing the maximum score over any possible hypothesis of this object which places the
report part location omega
now realizing the equation this is done by replacing the terms in the sum but
this function score i which is given the anchor position of the i th part
and then on the right hand side here for maximizing over the space of displacements
of this part and intuitively we're looking for the optimal trade-off between how well the
part matches data wise and the trade-off between how much penalty suffer from moving apart
relative to tinker point
now with all that in place we can finally detection simply by thresholding score function
the last
is it like you
drawn from the distribution is large
i would like to thank link so OK so he keeps on going
but laws for
and this can also be implemented in form of graphical model is essentially the same
no sample
from from the she what we would do is they were assembled from the and
it was quite a bit lot of the u
the stick breaking procedure then we could just use
and in any case that they will indicate which is the sixth was chosen and
then he would send them accordingly
parameter from the basis
and this gives you a slightly modified version or
so we have these spices are added from the stick breaking distribution
this debate process data indicate that they will indicating which probably shows that choose and
the parameters themselves drawn from the base distribution so it gives you
right away and explanation of this
auxiliary variable over here
so this is these other ways where you generate
realizations of of of the of the test generated by g
and the interesting application again this is the noisy case that you can observe the
factors which make from some models you're always observed that the parameters themselves we have
to add another
they and the hierarchy for the measurement of
so the
o pai gives you the
an infinite number of amplitudes so this is not very practical reason for this is
really infinite dimensional thing but if you would allow yourself to two infinite dimensionality and
this is the way you could generate samples from from that then you the first
to stick breaking
sampling to produce infinite number of times and then they
given the prior probability for the indicator variables and based on the state of the
indicator variables with
chris samba the corresponding
thirteen not fish
but OK later on this will be made practical by choosing the finite approximation
you cannot sometimes infinite i cannot even represent but if you decide to make it
to terminate you can contemporary these
so the interesting case the most interesting case is application is again that we observe
some some data which are not just because it if it does correspond to parameters
in the model essentially so we assume some process here of generating observations given that
so it might be that is
probability of x i j given x given that i this could be a density
like and we see this could be if somebody calls him density and then that's
with the parameters and nicholson are you can also think of
for conditional model so if you want to predict preferences for example you might have
some input to your model and want to predict what the user
if the user would like this product or not
so that's the reason later on the them the models which are used in applications
and the fact that the parameters in these models
and this is the situation discussed yesterday usually and has a hierarchical bayesian approach and
sometimes is also called the bayes nonparametric hierarchical modeling
are previously was sometimes called mixture usually processes of seriously process makes it much more
accurate there's not really a mixture of dirichlet process mixture of these pieces
so what we did here the other thing which changed is that we added the
data over here
this was model before and now we
assume that we can observe
this is directly but only from data
and we minimize that over y
now i claim
that is equal to minus
x i x j
if i take the suspicion minimize y
well find this was just get an idea that
supposing that
x i
because xj
because xk
equals one
hasvalue minus one
strong my
it's the slide
i think this minus one here
minus one
if x cycles exchange was this careful one
this has minus one
what is this
if i each of these is now zero
so inside the brackets minus one
and i minimize that by putting why one get minus one
why was the you like this one them so that equal
if they're all
but if they're not
one of those is zero
on the right hand side is zero
and clearly
i can put y zero here and get
so this is the case
this minimum so the idea is
you can just verify that
the idea is i introduced this new variable y
and instead of minimizing just the exact minimizer about the x and y as well
and then
i don't worry about that but
the minimum of the function is the same as the minimum of the function
so i replied could that one in my graph instead
to look at this you find this is
excited by y
as xj by y
xk but why
minus y
so the miners why i could
i put a plus
are minus one
now i have an expression that minimizes over y has exactly the same value
as this
by my
by my usual thing
i have
x y
and zero
then one
what it
one of these edges represent
that's why
excited by
xj by
why xk by
so this graph
when minimized over y has the same values which is equal to this
it's like taking second place these cube terms
my little by adding an extra note
introduces extra edges into the red
in this manner i can minimize
straints similarly
q because it's exactly the same
however many of these take
i take a bunch of them
many variables like
introduced one extra variable
joint not like this
then i can
include that has term the cost function
similarly if i had excited by exchange by
xk by acidic side chains that the exact same thing with this
so that's the observation that allows you to include is cubic in fact any terms
now in the case any cubic term can be written like this it's obvious cases
they can't all be written
the the terms you can put them on the homogeneous form
so this is not a unique way of doing it
so look at
and how you can use this
general idea
if you look at the pairwise energy functions seven unitary new pairwise terms markov random
and then you can
so things like
like this
he returns pairwise terms
get afficionados minimisation but
this is restricted expressive power limit what you can do
with this so what about using higher order cliques
you've cost functions
like this
now we're not claiming do any of the cost function but some useful ones
you can
previous work showed this may be useful thing to do
example from the field
this image
eight thousand six if you look carefully doesn't
if you look carefully at this for the noisy
the texture on the ground plane particularly
is the higher order mrfs
not very clear probably from where you can see the
lose the texture
in the middle
we retain the more noise texture because the texture and
learn to play secure
hierarchically functions so you get better results previous
previous work
but OK maybe this is computationally
vector w connecting the class means is the normal
OK so that would be one way to do it and if we write it
down like this
we have to cheque whether this dot product is this angle is small after the
ninety degrees and take this we just have to to look at the dot product
because you remember the product is
the cosine of the angle
so we just have to check whether this dot product is positive or negative
so we write down all these things
OK so if we substitute all of this we have all these quantities up here
and we have plus minus which we know how to this thing we know how
to compute x minus c and we just substitute everything
we get this quantity here
this is all the products
which is the cosine of the angle so we have the it
the arithmetic sign
this is positive or negative and now we use the fact that
the dot product between
can be computed maybe i'm a bit further in this direction can be computed by
is a similarity function because we said before we are assuming all similarity function has
representation as the product in this space
so now we substitute the similarity function
and here and here
thank you have plus b we're not going to worry about this this is a
that you
that just contains all the quantities that don't depend on the test point x so
we consider this constant
so anyway so this is our classification function and let's think about it and look
at it from minute why does this function to do it just takes a test
point x
it computes
the similarity between x and all positive points of this is that some of the
positive points
six the average such similarity
it does the same for all negative points again average and here we have some
constant and this can actually be also interpreted in statistical terms if you want a
density estimation which is called the parzen windows method to the past the window method
given some
the kernel function
which is
similarity function like this with special properties with the property that it is a nonnegative
and it integrates to one so i think of it as a normalised gaussian
so given such a density functional window functions
we place one such function on each training point x i
and then this thing would be a parzen windows estimates of the density that has
generated the positive class
likewise this would be a parzen windows estimate of the density that has generated the
negative class and roughly speaking the classifier which is
well it's
more likely that the point comes from the negative of the positive class
but but in this case we arrived at this from a purely
geometric point of view
we will use this during the point of view all the time
so since we are
running a little bit later normally
i take a break this point and people
there are themselves how out to derive this thing but i recommend that if you
haven't seen this kind of classifier for
i try to do it tonight don't the in the break into it in a
slightly different way because there are different ways of doing it as i mentioned before
i mean we now than using this angle between this vector on this but you
might as well
just as well
directly compute the distance between this point and this point
and the distance between these points
sorry between this point and this point and i just checked which of the two
distance distances so you just write down the one distance
subtract the other distance and then check whether what you get is positive and negative
it turns out if you if you do that
if you get it right you should exactly arrive at the same same decision function
so that's a little exercise to try at some point
i could actually
try to give you a little bit more of this
by the way i should have mentioned this morning when i mentioned the sponsors of
this meeting i should have mentioned also the model works because it turned out they
sponsored practical sessions by giving us that licenses for free spirit
they not work
let's take a look
OK so
that we start to have some parameter here
just i think only the top one is active so i'm using the cosine similarity
function talk about that more later but i think of it as a doesn't actually
it's housing and
here this is the width of the standard deviation so i have no idea why
in the
i have two sets of points
and i train this
classifier it turns out if the width of this is very wide and effectively working
directly in the input space so i in this space that you see in this
two-dimensional space in this case you see the decision boundary is pretty much straight line
and the decision boundary just sort of if you think of the two class means
is the smallest of one of the vector connecting the two class means
and if i make the problem in order to get more complicated
and then this is the classifier not might start
it problems that make it more difficult
so now this is the problem that cannot be solved with a straight line anymore
and you can see indeed
this decision function that i've shown you before
these plates are
extraordinarily large
and so if i have to draw on the field lines
in a situation like this
the field lines
it would be
like so in the upper plate is positive
in the field in here
it would be the same everywhere
the outside zero and outside zero here
clearly this cannot be true
if you get into
this area here where you only the end of these plates
that is not possible
why not well you can use your symmetry arguments of gauss law is not going
to help you
if you get anywhere near this area and it is very difficult to calculate the
electric field configuration
when you are near the edges which we call the
french fields
next well of course
was a clever man
and he knew how to do that
today we can also do that very easily
with computers
but i'll show you from maxwell's
original publications
that in a situation like that
he was already perfectly capable
of calculating these electric field lines
you have these two
plates which one is blessed which one nine it doesn't matter he doesn't whatever is
in there
and what you see is an extremely strong field inside the two plates
remember that the density
of field lines tells you something about the strength
very strong fields but when you get near the edge
the future is not really zero
field strengths drops very rapidly because look the density is very low
but it is not zero
and the electric field is non-zero and is zero there
in our assumption in our
simplification we have however
so that the play so large
that we don't have to worry about any and effects
and in that case
the electric field
is only exist and in between the plates
but not
anywhere else
and i want to
demonstrate to you some of the things that
we've learned today
and the first thing that i want to demonstrate is
that the electric field
a large plane
in more or less constant
it doesn't matter how far away you are
the way i'm going to do that is of course i don't have an infinite
large plate the plane that you're going to see only a few square metres in
and so is only something like one by one metre
then it would only be true
that the electric field is very close to constant if i stay very close to
that plane the moment that i go out as far as the media of course
it's no longer true
so it's very qualitative what i'm going to to show
but you're going to see very shortly they're very large plane
going to get it in a few minutes
let's assume that we look at that plane and so on
so he was playing
look at it from and so on will be put here
will block view that's why we don't have it up now
and what i will do now is connected with the vendor graph which is behind
the weight of human it's an class will pay attention to me enough to you
is the graph we're going to attach it to defend the graph
and then
we use this interesting fishing rod
which is small
mylar balloon which we will charge with the same charges the then graph
the same charges the plate
and we will hold that in front of the
and then
of course there will be
for us
so here is my
glass rolled
this is the vertical
and because they will be
a repelling force on this
airfield belong
there will be
and angle
the electric force on it because the
to have the same charge
and this is the angle theta
but i will show you
projected on the wall
and when i move this
away from this plane
you will see that the angles they become smaller yes of course because look how
small that plane is
no matter what i do if i go from twenty to forty centimeters you can
really say that the plane is infinitely large compared to forty cents but you see
that the angle of data will change very slowly
and then
we will remove that playing
and then we will do exactly the same experiment but we'll use only defend graph
which produces now an electric field
the electric field now
falls off as one of our square
it's not constant as a function of distance but it falls off as one of
our square and this is a hollow sphere
so you can think of it as all the charts right at the centre
as we demonstrate
on the blackboard still here
you know you get that amazing results
so now
if i place this
fishing rod
well known
near the
then the graph
you will see that this angle theta
drop very fast when i start moving my hand away
extraordinarily fast if i double the distance to the center
the force on that little object will become four times smaller inverse
are square
so let's first though the
and then we'll try to do the
the single
then the graph
and will try to optimize
the light conditions we have
projection here
the carbon arc
which will
hopefully produce
light in that direction
if the carbon arc works
a block of i've got to thank you
so it is carbon arc
it's coming on
and you'll see there
details be clouding our way is a very powerful technique for solving larger problems in
that context we're looking at some of the classic data structures like stacked skews this
maps and sets as part of domain for that
we do have to use the c plus plus programming language but this is not
a c possible score so to be clear about what you're getting what you wanted
that we use here is the vehicle we c plus plus years the vehicle we
happen to think there are good reasons to actually you exposed to both languages all
talk about that little bit more later but in particular proposes an enormous language has
a lot of language features as well as very large standard library and our goal
is not at all to turn you into like this industrial strife knows every detail
about a quarter cincinnati post there's another class one of the three d that it
doesn't have to do that that's what you're looking for i suggest you take a
look at that but what we're about supporting advanced programming techniques taking those those foundations
and building on them to be able to solve problems we have an easy possible
you will learn some simple but i always considered a side effect of what we're
doing so just
the clear on that
so just a little note on placement if you're kind of in between and not
really sure
these are very very rough guidelines but they give you some idea of which group
sort of gravitate toward where right if you're new to programming we're not confident that
your background maybe it was kind of a long time ago it was self-taught maybe
it was of course that you felt was was not as good as it could
have been or you didn't do as well and it you know what six a
is a great place to start writing actually is by all kinds of extremely popular
courses therefore right and services a wide
a group of people with a little bit of background or some some no background
all very well getting to speed if you do have something like a sulphurous course
experience so you did well i want to six a or to some of course
or perhaps even self-taught way through all of those materials right if you're ready to
move on one a six b so an AP course in high school the curriculum
is a pretty good match for that
one sixty years so you're in great place if you have this here and a
little bit more going for years you have one extra time the corner you want
to sit in the company of only the uber geek so you can check out
one six x which is a there to be covered the same kind of topical
ground but it's a different level of intensity comes across a couple of the assignments
cover some material that we will get a chance to cover and just pushing the
envelope a little bit there if you actually had experience coupled the first two courses
so you've done all the things that we're talking about here and being you feel
comfortable with that it might be the right place three was one of seven which
is the
third course in our sequence then just skipping over one of six courses in in
entirely that's somewhat rare so if you're thinking about that encourage you to talk to
be a little bit to
make sure that you will be missing out on something important in doing so but
certainly there are students who have
for example the p a
APC a b curriculum is pretty comparable to this course here and so depending on
how high quality the course you had was it might very well be that one
of them is right in some situations where the course was maybe a little bit
lacking many simple ways that we can help just reinforce the things you learn and
just kind of build the stronger foundation to move forward from the conjunction and so
the question about placement
general sense about
that sort of thing
talking too fast
in like that you can see from whatever you want
i so
what philosophy
i think you know there's this statement about what was officially are but i also
think that there was a very long tradition at stanford that they come back from
actually student motivation which is the thing i was here is an underground actually in
the eighties when the one successful just getting off the ground and in the the
times definitely undergraduate computer science department and the kind of believe that the in the
kind of nice period for computer science was well that should get math degree and
only then would you be mature enough to learn about computers somehow
that was you know you're ready as freshman and there was just a groundswell of
different enjoyed you know we want access to programming we want that kind of made
it happen and so part of one of the really careful thought about what they
want sixs would be at stanford and what we want them to be in a
kind of philosophical sense and one is that we want all students of all majors
and backgrounds we don't have version one o six that's for the majors year potential
leaders version of the non nominator version for
eternal freeze when get here we think we we can bring it all together and
design of course that actually addresses kind of this wide disparate group but still serves
that well probably because you know you're CS major you i'm going to turn you
into one that's my plan
that's never right not having to make that choice major and tell into the junior
is is the gift right to lie to explore and to feel unencumbered by having
made that decision when you applied and i think it's important to kind of respect
that given that never forget about trying to make sure courses finally you one way
or the other before you've figured out so you are all welcome here we try
to make it accessible to everyone had we have plans that i think help to
make that work right
we do try to provide a solid practical foundation programming that given our placement at
stanford in the middle silicon valley there's a strong inference important for us to try
to produce students who actually kind of from the get-go are learning things are actually
quite useful outside the classroom rather than can teach you have a very academic and
very interesting and mathematical language like scheme but that is very rarely used outside of
the classroom trying to teach you on the tools and languages and techniques that are
actually in active practice so we're using java plus plus two of the most prevalent
languages out the industry and we do a lot of learning by doing right we
assign challenging full-fledged program for the you work on a new building so it is
not designed to be academic exercises that really are building skills that that have applicability
come here and
outside of the class
we have a big emphasis on truth and beauty that this is one area in
which some of the seventy two courses that we seem to come in with have
a little bit more trouble with this is tackling this part of it which is
that there watching a program to work
many of them are not pretty
and so forth right so
so i think you know these are technologies that really
i have a big impact on society as a whole
and i think that's also part of what makes it very exciting to work on
these problems
so in terms of you know the four former definition of what information retrieval is
i don't want to really bore you too much of that but you know marauding
includes for instance say information retrieval deals with adequately identifying information content of documentary data
so this was still very much
focusing on
text documents
and a more recent different take on what information retrieval has been over for IR
deals with uncertainty and vagueness in information systems so that is more focusing on what's
really different information retrieval as opposed to
database systems
right in database systems we also query and we get answers from our data and
the idea here that you know we have uncertainty
that is the representation that we have available does not
reflect what the semantics what the meaning of the data is so there is a
and we also have a certain vagueness as
as far as the information need for instance of users concerned
OK so that we don't know exactly
you know by the query by what we observe it might be very hard to
figure out what users actually looking for
and of course you know there are many facets of what i are is today
is not just query based search it also encompasses things like categorizing annotating documents organizing
information repositories assessing things like the quality of the information sources understanding users multimedia and
so on and so forth
to conclude this first introductory part where i think that machine learning comes into the
picture here is on two sites so on one side
we are given
what i just you know i would like to call it just bits and bytes
right we just giving large volumes of data may be text data it's a my
or some type of multimedia data and be interested in finding some interpretation of the
data and extract finding hidden regularities let's say structure that underlies the data so this
is what i call interpretation here and that's mainly what we would call unsupervised learning
and data mining right
this is this part over here where we actually want to discover regularities the other
aspect deals with the question of generalisation because
in such a context we often have data that's annotated let's say by human experts
but these human expert might not be able to annotate all the data that available
but maybe only a portion of the data so we would like to generalize you
know from given examples to make our method scalable to much larger volumes of data
so and we might to dealing with issues of classification recognition and so on and
so forth
so these are the two
aspects where i think machine learning methods can really be
useful this kind so
so the rest of my lectures i was basically structured like this so the
the first part we'll mainly deal with unsupervised learning methods in information retrieval and the
second there will be a second part dealing with supervised learning methods
and i have an optional part dealing with with multimedia text and images we see
you know how we how we how we kind of proceed but i will have
time to do that not so that the first lecture today