on the right to have a good convergence properties we see that actually deals with
some things that this idea something from this weighted empirical measure is what makes particle
filters because that later
so to summarize the basic particle filtering
so as to approximate the collection of posterior distribution p of x one and given
y one you posted as follows
first time instance use all capital in particles according to the wire
then you weights those particles according to their likelihood with time warner
so that gives you an approximation of the stars which time one
because you want to obtain weighted sum up all you want some pool weighted evenly
to have the same weight
your so capital and times for you but the approximation of the
of the
so the solution to obtain new approximation which is
not purely measure
the following time index
following time index when you outside minus one you have capital particles approximate distributed according
to the distribution of time minus one use onboard extend each parse according to the
why the markov process you wait everybody to take into account basically the new acceleration
that does come about time that you do this particle approximation
of the target distribution from which are so-called capital in time to obtain new
approximation will become approximation was distribution so this is the bootstrap filter this is essentially
the key
garrison which was proposed in nineteen ninety three by golden silver missed
that's very simple sample resample
so what we obtain
so at each time and you obtain a
monte carlo approximation of the cell distribution
of ireland italy
actually can you also obtain at each time
you obtain an approximation of the marginal likelihood of interest on this is appeal byproduct
of the uris you get it all
this is the free lunch basically esteem gets you nothing
this is not a reason which is very easy to implement on show the computational
linear in the number of particles
the memory requirement in its most basic version
increases linearly with time because you need to store basically
the component x one selects on this capital and version of
if you are interested in approximating
not the joint distribution of x one xn given the observation that you're only interested
in computing the marginal distribution of the last component x and in y one and
then in this case the memory requirements do not increase with time index of for
all the talking application this is the subject you're interested so very simple algorithms
it's easy to analyse as well on foremost application actually more memory requirements also do
not increase over time so that's basically particle filters
only it seemed that essentially by using this
sampling or something mechanism we shape what we wanted to do that is we've come
multicellular mechanism to approximate those this sequence of it i'm unsure distribution
now i'm going to show you what i like to emphasise is that actually
we sort of part of the problem but we have haven't stumbled the pollen action
so let's have a look at what we call it to illustrate what coli what
happens basically when you're using particle filters
so the
i'm going to consider a a very simple example suggest look
basically to
the but some of the of the pictures
assume you are basically the particle physics
so what going to sample capital and particles according basically to the prior
on the most of the corresponds to the location of the particle x wanted i
so you've got capital out of
what you're doing is that those particles
we waited basically according to the like u-g-l-y y one given x one i think
they are related
the ones who got weighted approximate you waited empirical measure of your so called capital
in times from this weighted empirical measures
so articles are going to die
also article organ multiple of point OK
but that
is that time two
obviously you lost some confidence you
basically corresponding to the particle which have died at time one on some article about
multiple offspring
he basically each class correspond to what they could in the past space approximating the
joint distribution p of x one x two given y one y two
you reweights each of these parts according to the likelihood that time of the observation
to y two
you can sample on this weighted empirical measures some particles are going die some got
all going to springs
and you could possibly sway you move for a long
this is for example in this case the simple case the approximation you get
the posterior distribution
just the the distribution of the twenty fourth continent during the celebration of the twenty
the lognormal
and called at the cut point
and they say we have and one in ten thousand
chance of a false positive
you see ninety nine point nine nine
one minus
the is
that the data that they had for normals
hundred forty cases
none of which was bigger than the cut point because they had cut the tail of the distribution
so here's what they did in fact
they cut off the tail
and then said
it has a small tail
the sciences business
it is just one example
it pointed all i should i critical issue here
this was the penultimate version
that the eleventh hour
got spooked by the possibility
that was real actually
that water would sue them
for publishing this article
and so right at the eleventh hour
they trigger lack thereof of
one of the things i talk about in these
articles the prosecutor's fallacy
it is he hears what they do
they concluded
that if u have
he very small chance that something
that you must be
with probability one minus that's
so there are mixing up you know the inverting the conditional
and i explained that this you have to use bayes rule
to do then
if you want a really more about the prosecutors for fallacy
i google market can and the prosecutor's fallacy
will take you to
the new york times article
but by buchanan about
a woman named anna
the burke
from the netherlands who had the misfortune
being in
the operating room when lotsof patients died
she was tried
on the basis of
the rarity
i love
the confluence of all those things
and a very small probability that this was gonna happen and therefore she was guilty of
when i wrote this article
i cited
you can
andy editors and i wanna take out of
i so why
this is an elegant paper
he said that's the problem
he writes better than you do
if you wanna see something another elegant presentation google peter donnelly in ten conference and
he'll tell you about a similar case
um sally clark
in new came there was convicted
love killing two of her kids
who died in witnesses
sudden infant death syndrome and you can that called her death
and this doesn't happen
very often
and they calculated probability one in seventy
some million
that happens and therefore she's guilty
now my duty here's and this is where we don't even know there was a crime just like with
on a deeper
anyway dolly doesn't terrific job explaining this
should telling you how
eh pediatrician
we can
dim the lights on the blackboard again
and i will look at the slide
right so
if the tip is very far from the surface we give it kind of a
whitish color and as
closer and closer
the surface
we give it a darker and darker orangey color
and finally when it so far down here you actually
in content tunneling to the plan give it blue-collar
so that's how you get this image
the basis of this technique
so now you also notice that the seal molecules have a
peculiar arrangement
this is
not to do too
the most awkward
language intelligent design
this is due to a very
patient experimental i e graduate student
was that twenty four hours
putting the CEO molecules into this particular position
so how do you do that
he did it in the following way
the first
so if you see all molecules and put them anywhere on the surface to expose
the surface to some
and then he managed the surface to figure out where they were
and so if the seal molecules
or my balls at the bottom of the sea of molecules
in my foot here is the time to write just missed the surface right figure
out what they were doing your work
so that he's can move
c molecules
so it brings the ten
you know close to
one of the molecules
and then if you
but a voltage pulse and piezoelectric and actually shark that
well you can sure that that you get the feel molecule and it goes flying
that's nice but now we're going to go
well in order to find out how to do the whole sort of thing and
i find it somewhere all the way over here right now i really want over
the operation
and i well
twenty four hours later you get this little man
and i know it was twenty four hours later
all right so i
gonna be a while before this kind of nanotechnology assembling molecule by molecule
b for the system to be critical put a public ewels where you want them
all right
but some
even though
kind of visual observation of the atoms and molecules
it really wasn't possible
a hundred years ago
the evidence that i alluded to were quickly went through earlier
it was really quite compelling for the existence of a atom
and the
observation of the we
that was the most basic constituents of matter the elementary particles
you couldn't hear anything smaller than an atom
in fact at the end of the last century
it was generally believed
at the theoretical structure
of the universe was complete
nature was understood
there were no more
discoveries to be made and after all
there were by this time
in the late eighteen hundreds of a lot of the well tony mechanics had already
been known for two hundred fifty years mechanics that
guides the motion of all bodies around the human astronomical
thermodynamics was completely developed
the taxable mechanics was developed statistical mechanics which relate
the microscopic description of the behaviour of matter
to the macroscopic description
of the behaviour of matter
and also
there were these
i think six parents young presnell and her
seem to put to rest
the question of whether or not white was the particle or wave
all those experiments seem to be absolutely conclusive
light was a way
those experiments demonstrated maxwell's equations maxwell's equations used by
optics and electromagnetism
so i
you know by this time
there were was
all of these accomplishments idea was the
everything was done
the idea
was that the war the remains
was largely to investigate the next small point
everything else was done
however at the same time
by the
late eighteen hundreds
there began to be two sets of observations two tracks of observation
if you look closely
i began to illustrate that
things more
why so clear
maybe things were quite as well understood
what are those observations
well one of those observations is the discovery that we're going to start looking at
the atom is not
the most basic constituent
that you can take an animal park
into an electron
in the nucleus at least an electron and the nucleus
that's one track
the other track is
of prize as well for the most method with the most potential even if it
doesn't actually win at this stage of the competition
there's a number of simplifications in this challenge and and you might be able to
imagine a number of things which make it more realistic and maybe this is the
way of making sure the challenge rewards methods potential is that women future challenges which
make it harder which will reward those methods which are really got the long vision
here so the number of things we obviously we wouldn't know that because precisely we'd
measuring from stars galaxies may be more realistic and kernel may be more realistic in
many of many objects in each image maybe overlapping objects noise may be correlated between
a number of things satellite tracks cosmic rays think some of your thought about this
in a different astronomical context all
so practicalities
in the next two weeks we will present our description of this challenge
and that really summarizes in more detail what i've said in this talk
and with
now at the moment starting to produce the simulations with the research assistant that's fine
about ask out really really helpful and we're going to work on these simulations ourselves
make sure that it's not we're not waste your time with any bugs or any
we don't make it would make sure it's not too easy
and so we we all the time results online and we propose to run the
challenge for about six months starting in the middle of this year
after the end of the challenge we
make you the true inputs public and you're welcome to do what you like with
them and then write papers now all then all was this many you can great
so there's no kind of data rights issue here
i want to skip to asking you some questions in a minute so there's about
a hundred million galaxy images
just to summarise one galaxy per image all you have to do with dean is
deep involvement average here
and we're looking for an accuracy on this typical value point oh three and actually
about one percent
so they that to be able to do the future measurements that we we got
planned and the other that is the one equation you need to know
and you're very welcome to you we'd like we'd like your feedback during the challenge
and we'd like that to be a available to everybody so on this discussion forum
we have in cosmology and we've created a new section called the coffee we've created
a new section he scroll down you'll find section called great oh eight
which you can post your questions two
and it's also a nice section called understanding cosmology where you can send any basic
questions that you have on cosmology too you if you want and they can do
it anonymously which i find quite useful how OK
so i'd like to ask you some questions now so i'd like to see a
show of hands to get an idea of where we are this challenge so do
you think there's there's too much astronomy to learn to participate in this challenge
so hands up if you think yes
hands up if you think now
OK great well we certainly believe that's the case so this could looks promising OK
and this timeline we've got maybe starting in about five months' time and the challenge
running six months is this this timeline too short
so these things talk time is too short
and who thinks it's it's fine
and who thinks it's too long
we did debate making a one-year competition we thought that would be off-putting so OK
great so my final final question really and some responding really to what michelle said
of my KVL KCL method
i need to write down all my element relationships so before i do that that
we go ahead and label all the pages and currents that are unknowns in the
the the label
what it is and currents associated with source
as you
notice i continue to follow this convention
where whenever i label voltages and currents for an element
i will show the current going into the positive terminal of the of the element
after element very low voltage
so so you have been not nine
let me let me pause for five seconds and show you a point of confusion
that happens sometimes
often don't confuse between
what is called the elements of the variable associated with the element was is the
element values OK notice that capital be not is the voltage that this what source
while this
name here
you not is simply a variable that is used to label the voltage across the
so so only i can labels
he won the world department store
and i one the current flowing through the resistor
so this method of labeling
where i
follow the convention
the current flows into the positive terminal is called the associated variables discipline
now to argue the what discipline in situations where you have the choice
OK of an idea of
well possible choices you pick one as a convention OK so here
the convention we use associated variables discipline and then use that method to consistently labelled
the unknown voltages and currents in our circuits
OK so let me continue the labeling
i four
i three
we three here and
the two
and i two
v five
and i five i think that's it
so go ahead and labelled all my unknowns
these are the voltages and currents are the voltages and currents associated with each of
the elements
and my goal is to is to solve for these
in terms of
in terms of our solution here
let's follow the method outlined for you
so the first step
i'm simply going to go ahead and write down all the elements b i
relationships OK so the first step
i'm going to write down onto the relationships
so what
can someone allowed for me
the relationship for people that source
OK good
so we be zero is the capital of you know that is that
the very moving on is simply equal to the voltage
similarly i can like the others
v one is either one or one
we need to do is i two r two and so on
OK and have one two three four five six elements so i will get
six such equations
step two
i'm going go ahead and write KCL
kcl for the nodes in my in my system
and so that we start with node a
so four a i get
let me take this all the current swing out of the node
so i get
i not flowing out
i one
flowing out
plus i for flying and we must sum to zero
OK for
then i can go ahead and do the other nodes let's say for example i
do know be
four node b
i have
i two going out
that's positive
i three
and i i one is coming in so i give my i want equals zero
OK so i have
one two three
four nodes
OK so i i would get four equations
OK it turns out that the fourth equation
is not independent you can derive it from the others so i can be independent
equations of this
i can then write KVL
and for KVL i just go around my lips here
and that we go through the
this first loop here
in this manner
OK and so the trick that i use
just to be incredibly careful when you go through this into the neuron minus and
plus is correct
because otherwise you can get
come up with an
uncertainty which is this is sometimes called an error in the measurement really so
and the way you find the answer is
that you have to read
used to practice here
you get the largest value possibly could never get a larger value
you'll find that you get two point zero zero six
i would say
the answer is then
there is a reason
this is the dimension number
because it's
length divided by length
the time t one
divided by
would be the square root of one divided by
that is the
mention that this is an argument that we have there
and we find if we take the square root of the number
o five one point four one four
was minus o point
o thing
so here
is a firm prediction
this is a prediction
we're going to make
we're going to
measure thirty one
and they're going to be a number
and then we're going to measure q two
not going to be you know
i have done this experiment ten times
and the numbers always reproduced within about one millisecond
so i could just adopt an uncertainty one millisecond i want to be a little
bit on the safe side occasionally deflected by two seconds
let's be conservative
and that's assuming
i can measure
an accuracy
of about
two minutes
that's really state
we can measure these times
and then
we can take the ratio
and then we can see
at the time it takes for small
the height
very high
i will make it a little
one of the what we would like to all
all right
we have set up here
we first do the experiments with the
three years
see this year
and the time
the moment i pull the strings
contact with local start
the moment hits four
otherwise at all
OK but i'm really
everything that
it lies the i
seven hundred eighty one
so this number
it down because you need for your second sign
seven hundred eighty one millisecond was uncertainty of many
ready for the second one
OK nothing wrong
in ready
zero right
thank you
one zero
five hundred and and fifty one
nervous because i
i hope that
is it works
so i take my
and i'm not going to
the ratio
you can find by adding the two years
and the CDC study bacteria in nineteen seventy eight looked at the incidence of measles
in both states that enforce the laws versus those that did not
and as you can see
you had a ten fold difference in the incidence of measles so in fact mandates
were effective
achieving high levels of immunization
ending outbreaks of measles
well we have had a growth in the number of kids parents choosing to exempt
their children from
and there are
important risks that those kids are exposed to
exemptors are much more likely to get measles
and there are more likely to get whooping cough
perhaps even more important
vaccinated no vaccine is percent effective some people who get the vaccine or not but
they assume that they are
and there are also individuals in the community who can be in
because of medical conditions
among the vaccine for years
about one percent
vaccinated children actually acquired
they're measles cases in an outbreak
from an example to
so exemptors are in fact spreaders
who in parallel health of others in the community
now let's look at where we are nationally
there are three kinds of exemptions
this state immunization was
medical exemptions
religious exemptions
so called philosophical or personal choice exemptions
and the green states here
i have
philosophical personal choice
or if you want to be british or australian conscientious objectors
and keep in mind where those states are also show you the next slide
which is the
rate of immunisation exemptions
across the country and just go back
you can see that it's most of the highest rates of exemptions are in the
in the areas of the country there are
philosophical exemptions allowed
and washington state as you may notice my state leads the nation
perhaps why have been focusing on this issue for
this is a map of washington state
that shows the counties
and the colors of red here
designated counties that have greater than five percent of kids
and then to spend one extra second year y
i think the five percent number
if you have a school
in which
ninety five percent of the kids are immunized against measles
and five percent are not
and measles gets into that school schools
it will do all it can do which is typical of susceptible
five percent is a high enough rate and susceptibility to sustain measles outbreak in a
closed environment like schools
so here's where we were in nineteen
ninety nine
and the doctor by the way is greater than ten percent exemptions
and here is where we are today
now if you ask me what are the reasons for exemptions
the short answer is i don't know
our belief
based on some interviews and experience the belief of
people who work in public health in my community is that the reasons vary in
different parts of our state in parts of our state these are people who have
major concerns about vaccine safety
i have an alternative lifestyle in other areas of the state is individuals who have
a civil libertarian view
and object to the state requires irrespective of the medical issues involved
so let's look what's happened to the US and this is measles cases from last
the first thing you should notice by this slide is cross hatching
and all of the cross patch areas are immunized so the vast majority of the
measles cases are heard in people who were unimmunized
and next focus on the colours
the orange half
are individuals were unimmunized by choice
they opted out
so half the measles cases essentially of last year
or duty individuals who had opted out
much more concerning is this slide in this slide is a little complicated so i'm
going to go through it somewhat slowly the red line shows you
the total number of imported measles cases each year
the blue
bars are imported cases
the yellow bars are cases that occur within the country as a result of importations
so look at the two thousand eight bar and what you see
it is
that measles spread
two of far greater extent in two thousand eight
of course we have
the first
then we can
but it be
he was
well the
well i mean
just me
you know
cdc four
the problem
we he
it was
so what
from you
all o
what what
there are right this is what you want
so the
i'll summarize
like what we want
you might like a
well let's you have to do
it was
but more
the other role some finite number
where the integral is infinite
it's never undefined
it's always defined
i think that's need
a few people don't think it's needed
too bad
now i guess i guess what i was first starting this i don't think was
maybe either because it was too complicated
so you have an excuse
if you think about it for a while and you understand that and you don't
think it's the
then i think you have a real problem
so now
i did this
getting too many slides here
here we go
here's something new
by the looks no
let's look at the function now
just defined on the interval zero to one
suppose that h two a is equal to one for each rational number
and it's zero for each irrational number
OK in other words this is the function which
which looks absolutely wild
just goes up to here
and this one
or zero
and this one of these at this dense set of points
which we've already said doesn't amount to anything
and it's zero everywhere else
now you put that into the ring line integral
and the minor road goes crazy
because no matter how small i make this interval
there are an infinite number of
rational numbers in that interval
and therefore the reminded broken never even get started
for the love began to grow
on the other hand look at what happens now we have a bunch of points
which are sitting in one
we have a bunch of points which are sitting at zero the only thing we
have to do is evaluate the measure
of the set of points which are up in some tiny intervals
i've been here
what's this measure
the set of tees corresponding to the rational numbers
we already said that was zero
now that's why the big integration works
any countable set
and in fact any these uncountable sets of measure zero
get lost in here
because you're combining them all together and you say
they don't contribute to the integral at all
that's why the big integration is so simple
you can forget about all that stuff
when we look the last time
that the fourier series
four a
four square wave
and remember we found that
everything behave very nicely
except where the square wave had this continuity
the fourier series converges to the mid point
and that was kind of awkward
the midpoints where the function is discontinuous
don't amount to anything
because in that case there just too often there are only two points
measure zero just what is the what
you all felt intuitively when you saw that example that those points were not important
he felt that this was mathematical carpet
well the bank felt was mathematical carpenter
but he went one step further and he said here's the way of getting rid
is independent of z
given y
what do i mean by that i mean the following the for the family of
distributions whose joint distribution factorizes according to the graph is it the case that every
such distribution must satisfy the property
that's what i mean
so if you think about it this way
imagine i had distribution in which all the variables are independent i just constructed distribution
by taking the
defining marginal distributions for every variable and the joint is the product of the marginal
so by construction all the variables are independent every conditional independence property you can think
of necessarily holds for the distribution of everything just independent everything else
i can describe such a distribution by this graph it would be consistent with this
graph because this graph which specifies certain conditional independence properties and it would certainly be
true my particular distribution
what is not
what is not the case this
what is the case for this particular test is that every possible distribution described by
that graph that satisfy the property
i could have the conditional independence property which holds by virtue of the particular numerical
values are chosen for my distribution but i might describe this this joint distribution due
to the graph which has lots of links and so all its conditional independence properties
are not fully visible to you
it makes sense
put another way
i fully connected graph describes any distribution
but but equally vacuous
and that's an important point to come back and discuss
a very easy way to see what i mean by that in minute to return
to that
o one
yes especially if it's a fully connected graph
its undirected then is only one clique which is the set of all nodes are
just says define any function over the variables you like so long as it is
nonnegative normalized to one is completely general distribution
so is it the case that any distribution which factorizes according to this graph satisfies
the conditional independence property and yes it is and the test is very simple and
a graphical test we simply test whether the conditioning variables associated here
the variables of interest x and z in this case and they do what i
mean by that is every path
from any node in the set z to any node in the set x
any path is blocked every path is blocked by one of the observed noticeable think
about imagine trying to get from x to z
well you can't do it because every node is observed to think observed nodes blocking
and i think you can see
hopefully you can see why this is
the joint distribution of all everything
the product of cliques a function of the variables in that claim
two nodes which
which don't have a direct connection between them so let's take this note here in
this note here there no direct path between them so they can't belong to the
same clique
so in terms of the variables x and z
to be very complicated involving followed factors and all these factors which involve variables in
a lot of these and other factors which involve variables in z
and the lots of other factors
but x
this note here and this note here can't both appear in the same factor
and therefore
when we condition on y
this must be this must take the form
some function of x times some another function of z
time some other stuff but so far as x and z are concerned
and so what i normalize it
i have the property that p of x
and said given y
this p of x given y
he is a given
which is why conditional independence property
so in other words
the graph specifies factorizations
we can use the graph to test for conditional independence properties in the case of
the undirected graph the test is very simple we test the graph separation so way
to think of that
is to think of looking for every path from every node in one set to
every node in another set and asking whether that path is blocked by an observed
is blocked for every path that conditional independence property must hold if there exists
even one part which is unblocked
that conditional independence property doesn't necessarily hold
it might hold for the particular numerical values that you have your joint distribution but
it doesn't necessarily holds for every member of the family of distributions described by the
so just to say that again in
and in the course of the the same idea but from a different way
we can think of the graph is the fields
so here's a graph
a directed graph and how some of the variables are observed in this case
and imagine
we consider
so x here is the set of all variables described by the graph
imagine we consider every possible distribution every possible joint distribution over those variables
and we ask
it does not can that joint distribution be written
as a product of factors consistent with this particular graph
if it can be passed passes through the filter if it can't get blocked
so in general we have on the right-hand side of the filter is the smallest
set of distributions on the left-hand side
we can do the same thing again we can take the set of all distributions
very distribution we can say
does satisfy the conditional independence properties specified by this graph
so is this
independent of this given those two
which graphs says must be the case
if the joint distribution satisfies all the conditional independence properties required by the graph and
its line through one to the other side
and if not it isn't so that these two families the theorem to prove theorems
but if you want i recommend lawrence's book for elegant proofs then the theorem is
that given the definitions i've given you factorisation conditional independence for undirected graph those two
families of the same
there's this little technicality about if the distribution is strictly zero somewhere in this little
subtlety is not quite true
total discounted that special case
so the
the joint distribution distribution here which factorizes into product of marginals will go through every
and the weight of such a payload of our telescope was about a thousand kilograms
these balloons would go up two hundred forty thousand feet
and they were used there about five hundred feet across also use
pictures of them very shortly
it was a risky business in that
no guarantee of success
you want to be known
if they were so much the better
if they didn't work tough luck
there was just no way
that you could recover the money they were very thin balloons made
of polyethylene
and the thickness of the body was better than cigarettes
so you can imagine how easy it is to damage them
and if you don't damage them during the launch
it's easy to damage them on the way up
due to the jet stream
and the
very cold layers of air
that you have trouble pos
so i would like to
so you know some slides
and then we will get back to
talking a little bit more about
x-ray astronomy
all right
so let's see what we have first
you see here of my undergraduate students
at the time they were undergraduates student now they are both phd's
some of you may think that science doesn't have much romance but
there's a lot of merit
and they have kids
this is bad only
still very important in working with me on it
and this is jim
they're working on the electronic which is enormously
tedious task
the wiring of the
you see the plant in texas where these balloons were built
these were extremely long holes as you can imagine
and here the
the goal of the balloon which i like
pieces that you see in the tangerine on the surface of the tangerine they were
sealed together with its
and only women were allowed to do this work
because it was well known that men are too impatient and make many more mistakes
so only women were allowed there was nothing to do with discrimination but simply because
women were better doing this work
here balloon comes out of the box is a picture i took in texas
where we launched balloons from
nicely covered with this being sheet
and we have this
huge cloth on the on the grass
because the balloon is so thin that if you would put it on the grass
it would
to demonstrate way i told the skin is about
know then
cigarette papers carefully taken out
we inspected closely
and in this case there was some concern
that might be holding in the balloon
in fact it wasn't leased the hole in the thing covered
and so we carefully inspected whether the whole
propagated deeper and i wasn't too worried because this was not my balloon
it's always said you can see some of your colleagues
having a balloon that
doesn't get up
and i'm taking you to
the desert town in australia
central australia alice springs
i've learned many balloons from alice springs
now you get a pretty good idea of what the launch is going to be
like here is the launch track
the telescope is on the launch track
all of this is anti balloon
and here's is what we call the roll or
holds the balloon down and only this part of the world is going to be
inflated his the track
the UID inflation two
so which reinflate
it takes place almost always early morning
near sunset in the evening because that's when the wind is very calm and we
need very calm conditions
it is this part of the balloon is going to be inflated
and so it is going to be a huge force
the buoyant force i hope you'll remember q made law
of several thousands of kilograms force up and so this vehicle here
weighs about four five tons to hold it down
and when we launched the balloon we actually released his arm we flip these are
so you will see that
how to bloom
will make it on the way up
so this is alice springs australia again
sun is rising and we started inflation CUDA inflation tubes
and report the helium in the balloon it's this is
very critical phase of the launch
because if there is a little bit of side wind
and the blue touches the ground
and it's all over it just
it's damaged
you bought you don't even continue
this is a little later when they we call this the bubble
this is
the role are here and this is all these anti balloon new direction
and this part is only some eighty feet high so
you see these cause that i told you about earlier
this is all these tedious work that is done by these women who sealed these
course together
they all come together near apex
the big one
all right now you see the situation from the launch struck site
for this
reflection here is thirty seven degrees
it's a little bit different for rapid former very close to thirty seven
if you calculate multi angle uris
in the case
that we see the rainbow
you will find that i six degrees i mentioned earlier
and are is roughly forty degrees that means you're only three degrees away from the proof strength
and that means that the light that comes in he that is unpolarized that enters
the range still unpolarized when it comes back at this point it's almost a hundred
per cent polarized by electric vector is oscillating perpendicular to the blackboard so standing like
this it's polarized like this
but of course since we're dealing with an arc
i think the whole thing is actual symmetric remembered at
it's all right you like so
and it's all right here like so
and it's polarized helix
and the reason is
that's the balancing the reflection in the back
it's very very close
to the brewster angle
i like to
walk on the beach
and plum island is one of my favourite beaches
and i have
is occasions
look at the waves coming in water splashing up
this beautiful water drop
and then she whispered you see a rainbow in this war
the sun is there
the location of plum island
looking always in east and then you watch again for another wave to come in
wave comes in water splashes up first
rainbow and it's gone and so i was there
three years ago with my friend bill produced
also physicist
and i thought without insulting below one point out to him that
if you look at the right moment that the right direction you see
and so
back and the way in which
what is biceps rainbow i said they look it
look so that
this is nothing
and no one comes up she's beautiful rainbow gone
we'll see nothing
but only irritated with bill because it looks all
class some people just don't wanna see things right the middle of
and one
i look real
and i notice he was wearing sunglasses
and the sunglasses that you buy in the store
this is the direction of polarization of polarized sunglasses
and so
poor bill was killing
the light that came back
you're probably looking at this part of the rainbow
and his sunglasses
polarized light in this election so you wouldn't see
thirty billion ever not wear sunglasses he says location is that take them all
put them off and he said
i see the rainbow
that's the proof that the rainbow polarized
so now i want to
something that you may think is a rainbow
but it
and since i don't want to mislead u which students for that matter
i want you to appreciate what you're going to see
going to think you see a rainbow
but it's almost a rainbow but not quite
i've one drop of water
units this
in the glass
and that's my one drop water
and i'm going to shine an enormously bright dream of life right at
that's going to be very unpleasant through
but looking straight into the sun
don't worry
but there's something about
now you won't see you won't see some
so what comes back
from that one range of if i look at the long range
this cone of light will come back
in my direction
so there will be
a read outside of the cone
gradually turning to blue
inside white white light
this white light
and i'm going to project on screen
and that's what i'm going to show you
so it's not the rainbow but it has everything in it
that explains the
and that's the red light the polarized
because the red line is the result of a balancing of inside the water
at very close to the everything
now you may think that's why handed out to polarizes
wrong physics again
because once the light bounces off the screen
no longer polarized is only polarized but i am i'm in a privileged position for me is polarized
what i can do and will do
i will hold polarimeter
in the being so that you will see that i can actually
show the direction of polarization
so we first have to lower the screen
and then you eyes have to adjust to the doctors
don't put your hopes to high you're not going to see
will include white collars
i have only one one draw have headmaster with me
one one
so would you hold to
that's why i said to adjust the doctors suppose
so relaxed
try to enjoy it
take thirty second's for your eyes together little used to be
darkness and then
you will see the intersection of the screen
cone of light
is produced by
one wonderful
there you have it
and i'm going to look for my
polarizing okay
so let's agree
what you see unmistakable
you'll see first that around outside in the blue mountains
and you see white like here
you understand where that comes from
that's again reflected light in the back of the raindrop but all the colors are
superimposed on each other and you stupid waste very little white lie they don't know
cross was why rules
because the of
to me
mine tuning than half
i x zoom
the a simple case that the
the vector only exist in the x direction
so it has a certain amplitude i call it is zero x
and i make it traveling wave of course cosine omega t
minus case
so EY
and easy
only a factor in the
x direction
the complicated three-dimensional wave equation
collapses now
the one dimensional wave equation
of the nine terms that you have here
only one term survives
and that is d two e EX squared
that then becomes
zero times actually non-zero
and when you take the square the two it is clear the only one to
because there is no you why there is no easy
and so this now becomes
the two
the square so this is now
wave equation i started
now remember that the curl of e
his minor the stability
so the kernel of e
in this case
you can check that because you know what the kernel is
here's the
the kernel of the e
there's only one trim that survives
right down here the curl of e
the only one term that survived and then is dx c
in the y direction
and that now must be equal
two minus
so that is max well
although this and later i will raise it sort it you can see it is
important that you can see it's above my head
so my question now is what is being
so this is a traveling wave
in the same direction
we've has any vector only in the x direction
as of now
and i want to know what is the associated we feel
for one thing you can already see that to be field is going to be
in the y direction
if we take the
so this is the next
and we take the derivative
again see get minus k
you get easier access
and then the cosine becomes minus sign so this becomes a plus
times the sign
omega t minus casey
and that now
equals minus
so are almost there all we have to do now is doing integration in time
so we bring the DTO does it's important that we get the the y direction
that is very important
very important
that's why
very important that's going to be the direction of the field
don't forget that y
so now you're going to be true here
you do it integration in time
so now you get to be filled
that is going to be associated with that traveling wave
electric field
so if you do it the goal the omega pops out below here
so sorry get k
the zero axis
divided by omega
the sign becomes minus the cosine but i also have a minus sign is so
those two minus signs council
so i get the cosine
of omega t
minus casey
but only got divided by casey
that is the speed
of light
so i can also write is now
we write it down we in the y direction
indicate that it is in the y direction
he zero x divided by c because only god divided by casey
times the cosine
omega t
just to remind you use you why again
but of course the already indicates that
so now you've found
the b field
that is associated
with this he feels
i used to say and i said earlier one is the other one can not
without the other
so if we compare the two now you see two you see several things
which holds in general
that is you see that the the magnitude of the if you do the math
of the b field
the magnitude of the b field you can call these zero why
seat times lower
then the magnitude of if you
cdc here
notice also that
the field
and the be field in phase with each other
you have your cosine omega t minus casey
you have the same here
there is no phase difference between them
that means if one reaches a maximum the outer reaches a maximum and if one
is zero the other is zero
because they oscillate
with that frequency omega
notice also that b
is perpendicular to e
because he's in the next election and is in the y direction
notice also that
each one of them is perpendicular to the direction of propagation
is perpendicular to the direction
and b is perpendicular
two to see direct
all this follows
from maxwell's equations
now i would like to make
of what
this electromagnetic wave looks like
and i will make an attempt to make you see it's not so easy
but i make an attempt
so here
is the
x direction
and here is the y direction
and this b
the same direction
i pick
a particular moment in time
so that just picks at
put them on the continent
on top of that
these are typically graphical display that's it doesn't need to graphic and text sometimes flash
media but it's really just graphical act and the showing
increase the band evanescence the
and since that i just want to reach as many users as possible
want that to use is typically CPM cost per impression
that's not really thinking that users will click on the
they just want users to see the accent and the rest
that is displayed
different from that is
context matters
there is some content on some but it for instance in this case
this is the photography
a forum for photographers first and on the side we show at which is in
so for instance
this is one the
olympus digital cameras so it is relevant to the content of the page
so here
what i want is that the user should be attracted to me
and attracted enough to actually click on it
like a lightning rod
so in this case
that works problem is slightly more complicated instead of just pushing out the
you want which are actually very relevant to the one
that the user is ninety two actually like can be attracted to click on so
so typically these extra as short
and also on the page will be use it is actually interested in
however the problems here that
we use independence very
so you can do it photographer's forum
does that mean that you are interested in buying digital cameras
is it just because you
you just browsing the forum and you want to read some stuff and if you're
just not interested in buying
if you're not going to show by
and that is not really gaining anything but surely is
and again thickening of what is it called matching acts is called is a very
hard problem
because what is really the content for instance for food what is the content of
the form
because there are many different topics to be discussed by many different users and so
so the twenty fourth that
that the page which they want match that
this but it is very long it's very noisy as many different we don't know
exactly what the user is looking for
together these two the onto your user intent on the very long and noisy queries
mean that he creates a fairly low some said
and so
typically one CBC
there will be only when they click on not just when you should be
i think this is the
is that
familiar setting of sponsored search and this is probably the biggest
the most common setting in
thank you so because this is a lot of money for many different
so here
they use to search for it
so that's and it's iniquity
you want show sponsored search that we generally with this user query
so the nice thing here is
you don't need to be axed at the end of the
according to the page because you know exactly what the user is interested in
you know what the user said
i'm interested in buying digital cameras something you just one of the big apps that
match is given way
so the good thing is that the user declares
his intention for instance the user says that
is the key word in my search when their immediately north
this user is very interesting
product but adaptation become which are about
this particular product and there is a high chance the user would be interested that
again since
the query is very short typically what he works
it's much easier to pick good at is quite good
and matching the school
and so
typically the click rates are much higher in sponsored search than in one match
and the revenue model again it's typically cost per click
so that has to be you if
if you want good enough access users having to click and yet there has been
some recent move towards
when two of the CPA model
you want to use this to create and then by or something but it can
this still the CPC's more
questions about this for example
so those are two important properties it's maximisation the pointwise supremum
then another
a natural question is
suppose i have a composition of two functions h and g
are some special properties on that allow you to conclude that the composition of h
in g is convex if you know
properties of agent she separately
and there are several tombs like this for example if g is convex
and h is convex nondecreasing then f is convex
or a g is concave and it is convex and non increasing
for example the exponential g is convex if g is compact
because in this case it's the second property g if g is convex
then well an exponential
actually first property exponentially is convex and increasing so x but you
one of the ricci will be convex if g is concave and always positive
because then
you this theorem second one
h is just one over x o positivex
and this sort of technicality here if you
is a increasing or nondecreasing
then you have to look at each over its entire domain
and the assumption is that if x is outside the domain you find the infinity
for example if you have a h is excreted
but it's only defined for positive x
that's not an increasing
because it's only defined for positive x
then negative x your assumption is that the present political negative effect
and if you look at the at the end of the week
it's of increase
and if you didn't
if you forget about this sometimes you get wrong results for this composition
and we can do the same for effective composition the only difference is a to
the function of the vector
so each of the component is replaced by non linear function g k
and then you have actually many more
possible to these are but two examples g
it's each component GI's effect and it is convex
and nondecreasing in each article meaning everything all other arguments and only three things
in each arguement
this is called
for example the sum of the logarithms of GI effects is concave if g is
concave and positive policy on this
and then there's also because log some of x the financial GI effects is convex
if g is convex
because we've seen that the log of the sum of x x is convex
i was one of the examples earlier
it's also increasing
in each variable
please your argument x and exponentially
convex function g i think it's because of its position
another property is something that looks very much like this maximisation property but now it's
applied minimisation
so again we take a function f of two variables u of x y
and this property it tells us that the certain conditions b
the minimum of over
the second component is
if you if you minimize over y
x then the resulting function fx is convex the other property that we had before
was the supreme court
f of x y
and maximize over y
i go the convex function of x
here the the condition was that if had to be convex in x for fixed
and then there is no
restriction on how it depends on my why doesn't have to be a continuous variable
could be an integer
i think
and there is no restriction on this set
the only condition was had be convex in x x y
so here something similar but we it's you need some conditions on y
the first of all we need the function f to be jointly convex in x
just explore exploit jointly convex in x y
and then this set see that the minimisation over has to be convex
that's true then the result of this minimisation is a convex function
available to minimize y
and you are the result of the function of x
and if it's convex joined in x and y then conflict
so an example would be suppose i have a convex set s
and compute i define a function f of x as the business of the point
x to the set s
before if x is in s and this is the
if x is outside its this here
o point
so the nearest point means you minimize the norm
and this is true in any norm
just use for genetic NOR
to minimize the difference between x and y
overall points y and is that the distance x to the
well this is the function convex function of x y and the context right
and then we minimize over a convex
o vectors y
therefore this minimisation is convex function of x
and the the last one is similar to this linear fractional property that we saw
four sets
so it's not the construction of a convex function gives you another new convex function
suppose f is convex
and then i replace to introduce new variable t
can very easy in addition to the
currently like
so there is the argument of x over the
and i multiply functionality
and i do this for positive values of p and
this me new function of x and the theta
OK so the same bound the number of
when we speak
not so this is not only wrong but it's also negative quantity and the drop
it because i'm not about
not it
w zero zero from zero that that the
OK so now this game is also a bound on the number of mistakes
we're mistake
it is
all the update in which my in laws
it was my matching with making up whenever the lot is bigger than the zero
but sometimes my
nineteen left so be that my matching is negative
and and
because of this
but this is not about the number of states
the terms about bounds the number and they don't say anything that in the perceptron
but they get relationship that you can describe in
not that i cannot say anything about converges to the solution here
i should be question
so is asking whether
you say that that is not just the strict inequality
could i don't know whether it so the question is whether this bound can be
expected achieve
if the
the question
so whether this is there are situations in which
this can be achieved
i don't know
in terms of discrete orthogonal i know and i will tell you of value about
it later
that in the case of mistakes
it is true
OK so mistakes i can that situations in which the perceptron convergence theorem is by
so i believe that
i don't know about this one
and i hope that this is an idea but i together with of perception is
not that there was little before is that we are not getting it converges to
the solution
because we were making up their whenever our model is
bigger than smaller than one
and we have a fine
upper bound on the cumulative in
that we
we don't know how much we can lower bound the progress that we we make
make it
could make it happen because this guy
i just find it funny because the rhyme
so what i make up that whenever making up the space only when we know
that these guys because they want
so we can say something
because there's nothing but unfortunately we don't get the game
converges the SVM solution
so there are variants of perceptron that the approximate bitter close solution
one of them is out now
the green by club didn't feel that as several other
might probably the closest to the original percent
so you can you can use iterative update the perceptron like well approximated from the
this is not what one of them
no this is not state is that this the real off
so we know that
we that we can about the number of up
we can bound the because any and every up can control the
caused by it too long to be close to zero
in proc
we can only
one particular giving the of
all you the states sorry for you
of course
thank you said before you can about the number of mistakes
so the number of your everything making up
you might have been mistaken depending on whether you're in the last is bigger than
one or smaller than one
six is this
and in any case the squared hinge loss is an upper bound on the
on the non of them if they show you know that whenever you make a
mistake it involves a great deal of its upper bound
and when you don't make a mistake it is a positive or zero
so it is true it is also an upper bound on the
but is the same as perceptron in terms of number of states is that anything
more than
now what about the nonseparable streams here
again there is there are a couple of ways of showing this i want to
show you
how to deal with non separable streams by using a reduction
which i think is is the cool trick
and you know computer scientist love reduction error
so i hope you like
in other areas of
of of logic based knowledge representation
especially for software engineering where this is very useful mechanism as well to capture modularity
so so this is the bad news but the good news is that we can
approximate coverage without losing this guarantee
and what we will see in a little bit is the syntactic approximation of semantic
approximation of
the real coverage
better to sort of conservative extensions are
they the property of this is that it's very fast it is syntactically don't need
to reason or to computer module
the other good news is that we can still guarantee module so so so so
we do not give up on this coverage property
we might get slightly too big modules
but so far
the modules we got were
nobody complained about versus how it contains thirty four axioms and i think it should
only contain thirty two axes
so we have compared it with other mechanisms it has to be told that there
have been
modularisation approaches around where
you don't get this coverage
guarantee but which computes still larger model so we're looking into this and i don't
think we're quite hopeful that this is a very useful way of computing this module
and you will see it
them in action in the second
a last point i want to mention safety
coverage and safety are sort of dual to each other and i won't go into
any further detail about safety but it's another thing that you should keep in mind
all that i want you to take home from here that this is an important
thing when you design ontologies in a modular way
this assuming that you want to reuse module from another ontology because you don't know
this this topic of the topic that this module covers very well you're not an
expert then you want to preserve it while through the important
so you don't want to change the meaning of the importance of the important terms
through the impart action
now all being o
encapsulation doesn't come with all doesn't have any any notion of this encapsulation and it
could well be that before
before the import arthritis was not a genetic disorder and then new imported and suddenly
arthritis happens to be a genetic disorder
we don't want this if we are not really experts in this area
this is a very important topic in the modular you usage of ontologies
it is also closely related to what we have seen before to this conservative extensions
it's on an ongoing subject in research and development and i just ask you to
just stay tuned because i'm very
hopefully optimistic that's the part of this safe reuse will be soon provided as well
it's on its way
and now i hand over
message here
which will
provide you with a system that
if you want to this
so you think you can have your
we're going to do now we show you
the tools are being developed as plugins for four and this is the point where
you might want to follow along
i know on laptops
if you
if you download approach foreign extracted set file you get some directory structure looks like
this if you just start show for
using either command all the
batch files from windows
some significant changes to the solution
it's better
so what i want you to following along someone going to show you is first
i want you to open the
univ bench ontology
we chose which you could have downloaded from the website
so low conductance ology first
and so this is pretty four
being developed at the university of manchester
designed and developed at university of manchester and what you see is an overview of
the ontology
so this is just the ontology that you've seen for the tutorial this morning
fairly familiar with it
and as holly pointed out this ontology doesn't contain any information about computer science start
so lectures in a CIO
computer science students in which computer science courses they take
and what we would like to do
is extract module from the computer science ontology so if you just think back to
the methodology
what we do first is we load the ontology that we want to take commercial
from when you the complete ontology so i'll open problem one
we open the ontology
in the same window suppressed yes when you get that dialogue
and selects
computer science ontology
so that that's loaded the name of the ontology shown on the top here
and now what we'll do is extract module if i'm going too fast for people
who are following along to stick your hand up and i slow down slightly
and so
we have to do this we use was heard
we can get to this from the refactoring manually
which is extracts move axioms
so here we have always said
and there's only one option on the moment and some other options for doing some
of the syntactic extractions of ontologies
in fact seems an ontology but for the purpose of the tutorial have added the
mean we just want to use this one extract method which uses the methodology that
all these already outlined
so the press continued
and then we select the ontology that we want to move or copy axioms from
in this case this computer science ontology
and then i press continue again
and now we're presented with the pain where we can select the terms from the
ontology we from which we want to take the module
so in this case we want to expand the tree if you do
command click or a old like i think on windows XP whole tree in one
go we want to take turns from this computer science ontology and we want to
use them
in our university ontology
so to do this we just select items from the tree in the usual way
and what i'm going to do
it selects faculty
and all of the classes below faculty
one of the ideas
and this is the idea of constructing this artificial sequences if we have this graphical
model which is basically connected what we do
and each of these
i can think of these black connections is this
joint probability says
constraints that one does not to be like this this yellow pixels should have
neighbours should be olympics
what algorithm does then is
you only take a spanning tree
of the nodes
and this is one very application of our algorithm is much more general than this
but this is the sort of ideas
adding constraints success you relax the problem to make the problem is
so you might
take it to a place solar out in
and it's easy to sample a spanning tree we can draw an exact some
using again the forward backward algorithm before back applies to three not just the chains
you have
you draw samples from that and then
at the next time step this is the new distribution and what you do is
you move those samples
by adding this constraint
so the idea is to distribute the samples
and then you add constraints one at the time and you kind of hurt the
samples to this area of very low probability we want to be
if you have shown the sample something and it's very
again discussed in high dimensions with this very small space where all the samples should
go too
then you heard them with by adding this constraint
it's not different than what is done to solve satisfiability
problems you know systems and a i where people have these like walksat algorithms for
that constraints one at time
it's kind of summer so
the sample sort of my great
the same is true when you have a model with the static parameter
in europe serving adding observations and this is what japan did
because adding an observation
is adding constraint on what the model is
every time you add an observation saying i also want to model to be like
too much to be able to explain this observation
so it's adding constraints
so this is pretty much online learning
now skip the mathematical details
it's also used for experimental design
for the computation of expected utility
remember that i mentioned so far have been talking only about bayesian inference but
i mentioned in the beginning we also care about of finding out the best action
for something
here the beautiful idea of peter miller
his idea was
suppose we want to compute the utility of an action
and we have a model how states
x is given actions
and we have utilities crashed the stage just like that example we that
yes there was a small stable of reward and so on
what he does
is he
increases effect is terms
and multiplies the term by itself again
OK just like that here
and then you marginalize
over x
so you again have a growing state space we start with one term then you
have two then you have three
you growing distaste pages like i was going to graph
and the effect of this is if you do this
what you're doing is you're kneeling in the use
the utility function is getting more and more and more peak
and it's getting paid at the action that the best action so as to sample
the axis you're finding the best action
it's very beautiful if you've ever tried to do is very very hard is one
of the hardest problems out there and when you and then you can do again
like a particle filter and these are the weights
you interpret the utilities as probabilities normalize them and you can do these sequences
and that allows you to solve the problem of experimental design
which is
which observations together in order to maximize my knowledge about them on safer planet
on incomes
there some sort of meteorite coming around here
and i want to figure out where to point my instruments
and this experiment will cost me
a hundred thousand dollars
how can i best
get the most information out of the trajectory of this object
with as few resources as possible so which experiment to carry out or if i'm
doing clinical trials
how can
when is the best for me to to look at this patient
in order to have the best understanding of how cancer develops
because you don't want to have the patient come into your office every day access
to expensive
and sort of here is an example where
you have
very even in this very
simple case only heart
we have something like a sine wave
what you're trying to do is you trying to learn
the parameters a the frequency interface
based on taking x observations of the sine wave
so this is not permitted process so this is a bunch of sine wave
and if you've taken two points already this point and this point
which every time you get data your class
just like in accounting process
and now you want to know what do i think the next observation
in order to learn the frequency
and so on of this
i think
and the NELF after fifty steps in red is the new utility
this is using
in this case because there one in which we can do numerical
three michigan in numerical computation quadrature
through the annealing to tell you exactly what to take the next point to take
the next observation
that's also in machine learning this sort of
there's something from the very similar collective learning for active learning to but simpler
which is giving that i have a finite set of objects which one should i
thank you very much
morning everybody
i really appreciate you coming to the
yesterday lavish dinners
make it one
let's start with a couple of slides
why this and what the motivations were so
i'm going to to talk about three four
what the machine learning task
one of them is classification binary classification so from labeled training positive and negative you're
trying to learn how to use them all
i can see
this is a very long time
there a slightly different is the red task and in my case and i'm talking
about right which means the training data is ranked it's
and it is still possible to next so
prince they can be movies you like you don't like trying to come up with
the model that was the move is in order
preceding the name
that is the probability estimation when you
you want to come model
the posterior probability of the positive class given the description of an example
questions that
i'm not pretending to want
morning star and i think some of the most of questions just
to get your mind going about in which you have
one question could be is there a natural hierarchy among these tasks
and if you think about it and maybe one possible answer could be is to
be the hierarchy is role
on the top so
because the probability estimation of interacting just using the probability is directly descended directly that
and if you think that would be
forgiven these
i mean because that's what i think but i don't want to give you may
be a hint that the difference is that the one
is the middle
question you ask is
given most machine learning models you can somehow used to do each of these tasks
and i'll show you a decision trees to do
the tracking probability estimates
but when you try to
is it simply a matter of adjusting the loss function of futuristic in order to
try to use
right before it is how to work with svms or do we really need to
figure out
robert that
there is increasing evidence in the literature to be very nice to rochdale yesterday
that small
to be classified as a whole practice
and so to achieve
hi area under curve i will explain what
is if you have seen before
and there is a similar quite
intriguing analysis that
if so we all know that adaboost
rank boosting
best case is that the two rank four
ranking but it turns out that even the original adaboost under certain circumstances produces
that produces the same ranker
as rank although not necessarily
with the same speed so these are the most intriguing questions the final question
i want to throw has to do do with probability estimation
there is evidence that some of which is good by rail the test
well some of them
the distortion again
the question is
can we understand more
what can we learn from this
finally this is my final motivational slide this is also the case
range is going to be this morning
here is a couple of very simple example simplest example i can then go
to illustrate some of these points so
the first example is intended to show
that's good probability estimation is not necessarily aligned with rank
if you
look here is
we go with probability one for the positive class probability zero
and suppose that we have for example they all probability roughly point five but they
are right
a point five two
o point five one point four nine or something like that and so we're not
making any remaining as
well i think there is defined as opposed the next so that problem
we already have
however the
o point five
if you say yes to measure the quality of probability estimates the mean squared when
one of them is one
each of these has square point twenty five to the mean squared error is five
now this second that example we know this because they if you want to in
neither not because it gets zero
the last point five still in
each roughly twenty five
two point five four two and a half
the probability and
we didn't know that you we assume that we knew it but in fact we
don't know it so we want to estimate
and here this is the estimation of
being at time t in state i at time t minus one in the j
and we need to estimate these two things separately
and to do that we need another variable that
there is also handy
which is
if you remember we used this as far viable which was used to compute the
likelihood of a sequence given the HMM three computed basically the likelihood of the of
the sequence from the start up to time t and big in in state i
at time t
we are going to compute the rest and now we are going to call that
which is
the probability to to with the rest of the sequence
starting from time t plus one
and being wife being at time t
so it's very interesting to see the relation between alpha and beta because i thought
computers the likelihood of the past and because the likelihood of the future you're going
to see that the joint each other very
in a very useful either
to compute are expected value
so again
this term will become very useful later and
furthermore there is variation which i'm not going to go through but you can convince
yourself that it does work
and this derivation is very useful because it transform this term which
appears very difficult
in two small terms that contains again transition
the same beta for future so now you to have a recurrence
to compute beta
but the recurrence doesn't go into the past but into the future but it doesn't
matter you can compute it in a very efficient way in in the same way
that you were able to compute the phi you can compute the beta
and in fact it costs the same
to compute the beta band the on far
in the end
the cost to compute all the beta for all the state and all the this
the this
and time is going to be of the of the number of transitions
and the number of time steps
now why did we compute
it's been anyway
well in fact this is because we want to do this e step and e
step is to compute the idea make so there are two things to compute basically
you want to estimate this term the pretty of being in time
he in state i given the data
and again
how will not show the derivation but what is very interesting
you can see that
this decomposes into are as far as i know beta
and that's all
so we have an efficient way to compute and five
we have an efficient way to compute beta
and computing the
jointly using them jointly you can compute the the expectation there so now we have
an efficient way to compute the e step of our HMM that is one part
of it but the second part
which is
computing the expectation over
nuclear transition
used you you can still work out the questions the derivation is given here and
it's it's it's useful to look at them but they will not now be derived
in front of you but you should be able to do it yourself in the
end you can again is to make that with terms like bit
as far as transitions and emissions of things that you have already in your hand
so if you compute phi beta and you already have the mission and transitions with
that you can compute the expected value of emissions and the expected value of transitions
for all possible transitions and emission and this is
you're e step so
you have an efficient way to compute is it inviable
the same way you can compute the
posterior on initial state again it's going to depend on i find bigger
so very handy
and now
so you have done e step and in the end we have two steps first
estimated inviolable and the second is if you have this estimate
how can you maximize the value of parameters in such a way that that you
maximize the likelihood and what we have seen is that in order to do that
we only need to maximize this auxiliary
functions so
what we're going to do is to compute the derivative of the
function with respect to other parameters of the model
and we're going to said that to zero so we know that we are not
and we also know that if we maximize its auxiliary function we also maximize the
this can be shown
as i said for the german so basically
i'm just going to work out the questions but i'm not going to do it
now in front of you but if you it's quite simple to take the whole
thing and derived this equation with respect to the various parameters that you haven't said
to zero
have the derivations in on my website if you're interested
and in the end has for the gene and you obtain new values
based on all the values of the transitions and the posterior that you estimated during
and same thing participation in fact if you're in general that people use for emissions
are things like gaussian mixture model so we know how to compute the you forgot
initial model so in fact there is a way to efficiently combine the DM of
HMM billion of g and
basically it's going to use the same equations that we have seen for GMM
and they're all going to be weighted by the posterior probability of being in a
given state at a given time and they the same equation so we have the
step equations for HMM as well now that gives us only one iteration through time
after training at greater but we if we iterate this e and e m we
maximize the likelihood of the training data
this is training
so we have solved
the second problem of the nature the first one was how to compute the like