go over that again
we have here
but it's a and b
what it comes down from above
i want to run through
one of their runs out
and we collect is one of rob's hearing but could be
and this one is collected in buckets is also conductor
the brain can be
it's connected to see that's crucial
and the paint can be is connected with the
and here
there are two balls
which i can bring
close together i run water
and after a while i see is part
i can even see is sparked when the distance is something like six millimetres we
be about potential difference of about twenty
how does it work
water has a ph of seven
that means one in ten two to seven molecule
it's ionized
i have always minus
eight was
those are going to be the current carriers
ions are doing the work you are doing the job
let's make an enlargement here of ten a
and can they let us assume that purely by chance
it has a little bit of
the positive charge on it could be negative just with positive for
here cases where you will see
just by chance like you have a little bit of net charge and not completely
so this can has a little bit of positive x-factor structure
now here's the drop
from the spout
what's going to happen
through induction polarisation
you get a little bit of extra excess negative charge here a little bit of
access positive there
because the positive repel each other and the negative being attracted
so it explores goes a little bit up and the always minus comes a little
bit down
but now to drop breaks
and he goes to draw
so it's a little bit negative
so now a little bit of negative drop
come down
so this becomes negative
but this is connected with me
toby becomes negative
what do you think is going to happen i was the drops that fall through
they are going to become positive
because if b is negative
then of course this will be reversed the bottom will be positive the torque will
be negative
so those drops now to the going to fall through
i'm going to be positive
closely becomes positive
but c is connected with a
so a becomes more positive
and so a can do even better job now
on these
one of the polarizing even more
so you get a runaway process
and the whole system feeds on itself
the potential difference here
become so high
thank you exceed three million volt meter
and then you get a breakdown
and you see is part
you can think of a continuous stream of water
as a stream of individual dropped
so it also works
if you just have a regular stream of water going down
who is doing the work here
someone has to do the work
you have a battery
the battery is being charged
and then it is discharged
so this part was going to work
any idea
if you thought about that
very good
granted that is doing the work
we can see that very easily
the current
that is flowing and the electric field
how is the current flowing
if the negative charge is going down
we all agree that the current is going up
if positive charges going down
we agreed that the current is going down
this side of the out
will be slightly positive this is slightly negative
because the age plus
more abundant here than there
so we're going to get the current through the water
this direction
x and y
of the loss between the predicted
g of x and the true
and the cumulative error would be
as i said before the summer
of the errors made at each prediction so at each data point you make a
prediction and you compute the
in the online setting at least you would allow
g to change
as time goes so as you get more instances would allow you to change so
it should be more GI
written here
OK know the notation i will use g n as to denote my the function
returned by my my algorithm
so the the small and will will mean that's my GENI depends on the data
on this on the training set of data of size n
OK and you can given the loss
defining this or this way you can define the optimal
or the function
at the the optimal loss
by just are
if you
river rewrite using this notation
the quantities before
so in the case of model identification so
what is in blue is what i consider and these as also possibilities which i
don't consider
if you do motherly identification you comparing
gn with stories from star here
and you have some kind of this tends to be between those two functions and
you try to minimize it
here we do not risk minimisation so we try to minimize the loss
sorry trilogy here
OK so and
so you should mean over g
of the loss k
then you have
what they call the average case approach where
what you try to minimize it
the sum over
a certain set of possible distributions are possible generation mechanisms
of the difference between the loss of terrorism and the loss of the best one
the minimax approach
you take the maximum over this restricted set of probability distributions and the regret approach
you take the maximum over all possible distributions but you compare
you're lost with the loss of functions in the reference class
capital g
that makes sense for
OK so this is a small technical point but it's quite important so when you
consider such a quantity and you try to prove lower bounds but something that you
may encounter sometimes
what you do is you construct as i said before bad
distributions are given another reason you construct the distribution that will make this algorithm make
as many mistakes as possible
you can construct this p in in a way that depends
on the sample size or not
so even if you do it in a way that depend on the sample size
you what is called the week
lower bound
where if if the but he does not depend on the sample size you get
the stronger bond this it's more interesting because
the problem is fixed so p fixed but what is not fixed is the sample
size you can get more instances of a given problem in what you're interested in
is whether when the problem is fixed and you get more instances whether you will
eventually be able to get to low value for this quantity or not
so we strongly robots are more interesting
i want to finish
by giving you
a few statements of kind of negative results in that setting so once you have
set of these all these notation you can show several things
what are the which are called the no free lunch theorems a simple one is
so this is kind of the area reach after a certain number of epochs for
for a number of votes for is the size of the learning right and this
is the predicted value for money right exactly
is the minimum that means that it predicts the optimality right
these ideas as as you want
it works for four
members things also
i think i'm going to stop him at the time and perhaps some question thank
you for your attention
i think this
there was
OK so also across networks have their own set of problems that actually chose to
quite extensively so we have the initial banjo had some papers that showed that if
you want those because something really useful
one is going to be so intrinsically hard
so that's sort of put a really big damper on on people work on on
our current that some people claim to have algorithms that work pretty well but it's
not clear
so the so there was something is they work well i mean i'm not an
those techniques necessary applied
i think it's
in addition
used to specify
OK so guess that know
the remarkable is sort of orthogonal to choosing the right step size
we like to do is basically allows you to if you have to consider that
oliver broccoli does any preconditions the space so is gonna essentially had the effect of
artificially increasing the
running rating dimensions whether the loss has low low curvature and to decrease its interactions
with the has high curvature to like preconditioning then you still have to choose the
constant there was also the
the step size k which is kind of a global constant global multiplayer for all
of those all of those dates and for that you can use the technique that
we all mentioned or this technique of
stochastic estimation of it because out the
i don't use that very often because heuristics the heuristic way so simple and it
works well enough that is really not worth it
well it depends what you're interested in so
so if you're interested in
you know some of the industry applications data mining you know probabilistic regression is going
to do a good job for use of syllogistic logic action
but if we interested in is building intelligent machines
then please is to regression find something else but so that's where you really have
to think about more more sophisticated models
like city planning writes say a unsupervised learning for canopy training data that where there
was a whole you know so like special session on this so you may have
now i have attended
that's kind of
the best hope we have at the moment said this is pretty much the only
one to
he was
right so you
so thing to explain again way
with that was kind of the argument i i tried to make which is that
you know this could be a lot of it with a large that this would
be a lot more dimensions that are
or more directions that are
the considered solutions
and in the limit is
is that images were the first layer for example the two layer neural net is
very very large so large that all the way already there so no need to
run them at all the big the problem becomes effectively combats
not technically convex but certainly convex
so that's going to discuss the argument that there is this image this analogy make
if you think about a nearly square because we're trying to is easy something in
trying to find the best you square solution to two regression problem for example if
you have fewer samples new dimensions is very simple to solve
if you have more more samples and dimension is very simple to solve right at
the time when you have exactly the number of samples is dimensions then the has
extremely ill conditioned right at that point
it's actually a condition number is infinity
the you know is algorithms converge it's really bad when when the system is just
the right size it's really that it's much better this way over private which we
in which case you need to regularize
or if its way onto parameterized which case it's going to self realized
so what is the start is that you make a system where the goal is
to be new regularizer help
OK and people neural nets didn't didn't used to do this because
we already washed by the fact that these decisions were telling us you know you
shouldn't have parameters and you have to examples
it's just not true
you want a lot of parameters in training samples and industry arise
here one later
nine years and they are an example
so because of this experiment to make right turns so to say that actually happened
tried but could be written about five minutes but no i mean something is not
right for example is with gaussian that if you if you make them bigger secrets
maps for example to very large numbers
two situation for example you have ten times more parameters in the model and you
have training samples
they actually work better
you your training
optimism what you get
if you think wins is reasonably effective for
o is free
i think
maybe we should start with three lives
which is to think about what i like
but that's the reason it's OK
OK so
so the question was you know if
if there's a reasonably good methods for knowledge free supervised learning and then we should
try to push the
towards to supervise running
and we could we would be able to solve more complex problems so first of
i i don't believe there is any knowledge three supervised learning methods that just doesn't
exist is it's not knowledge free and it's not unbiased so that certain
yeah it looks like this general purpose the same where we like to think that
our brains general purpose but it's not true at all it's very very very specialized
and so there are certain types of functions so with the gas and for kernel
for example
efficiently implement certain types of functions
i would be would be horribly inefficient for all kinds of functions is likely to
be inefficient for many many more functions than it will be efficient you know that
the number of functions to be efficient for
so every model is restricted in fact there is no free lunch
there that show that you know if you have a generic learning model is really
general actually done anything because you know there's is no it's going to previously mentioned
about so so every model specific and the fact that we think it's generally sit
in vision
this is not
so there
like it's random
fictitious knowledge
so it should be here can be fitted better or equally in this case
all data can be fit perfectly so he called the whole
the size of
of sample space
the rank is large again OK now
take inappropriate
assume the data
like parabola
and you ask regret quadratic fit
quite adequately norms are quite rigid class i mean it's not very flexible can only
quadratic data
and you data are quadratic so did quite well
that means not too many other d prime
can be fitted as well
so the rank will be small
and the natural thing to do is now you select the model complexity that has
many mineral offering
so counting
all the because data seems like the daunting task but for linear basis function regression
you have a closed form solution which just involves the computation of the determinant
you can i mean what first accounting it gets to measure i mean you look
for the volume of the volume in sweden which is just reduced to determine you
can compute it efficiently
the maximum
like the palace maximum likelihood like i big and MDL
log only depends on the regression
when is for k nearest neighbour we only have the function f had we don't
start with the underlying class optimise so you start
with a hat
it also works for k nearest neighbour
it depends on your loss function takes the loss function to counter and the
does it
sort of
on the right
it works without a stochastic noise model
mean bayesian rationally just across the more
noise model
and here
you just need the regression function
so the polynomial or the k nearest neighbour regression
the most important thing is you can directly apply to nonparametric regression like
that cannot
so that was the
brief introduction to model selection so remember two ways empirical model selection which is more
faithful to cross validation
a theoretical model selection which is often associated with the big time
next is how we have take real problems
the real world is called the place data is complex all these simplistic methods
i'm not really useful
there are various ways of going to
complex domains one is one powerful and
systematic one is probabilistic graphical models bayesian networks
undirected bayesian networks
three models
other nonparametric
if you have density estimation problems
you can use approximate inference variational methods
sampling methods very important
and at the end i will talk about how to combine different models
quite different
o point is posting
OK graphical models
yes there ought to be a whole lecture
by to be area about graphical models can be brief year
have a feature vector x one x two x three two x seven
so it's a classification problem
spam not spam
and you want to infer the probability that the email is spam so what you
have is
now let's let's the density estimation problem
OK so you want to infer
so you have your
you have fewer
i mean you could regard seven class level if you want to
but it doesn't really matter so
you have a feature vector x one x seven here
a lot of data and you want to infer the probability distribution from which samples
the next one two
if you look at that as assume you features are binary
i mean the most simple case there are binary
then you have to go to the
the other thing is example two to the seventh
this how the twenty eight possible inputs
i mean these probabilities in the interval zero one
but assume that just be
number zero and one
there are one
then you would have to go to the power of hundred twenty eight
possible functions
so there already a huge space
roughly you could say
to reliably for this function if you take the whole cluster space you need the
sample size of two
on the twenty eighth which you
never have
because it's close to the size of the universe already
so what you need
again and again you need either a restricted model class war
some other selection criteria
and one nice way
i respect your space is
to consider graphical models of bayes networks so
you have some understanding or not you can learn that
how these very are related to each other for instance they are
i know that
there is you no just directly influenced like from
the number in laughlin porn for instance
but the indirect words you know which
contribute to the probability of of these words and so on and you could have
some specific models or
and that
consort with them
implies console you have some medical model
which you can write down here is a graphical models one
which effectively
you might do related theory
and and up with the bound which is so far
the true performance you're likely to see
that is not very useful to tell the practitioner well i'm not going to do
worse than the universe exploding and it's not very useful thing so
that has for a long time been the problem of statistical learning theory but in
certain settings they do have nontrivial bounds that are useful
and i think it's becoming more exciting area
there's also another philosophical
can which
can be referred to as the bayesian view of some people would just say that
it's probabilistic modeling view and a lot more my work has been in this area
you should
probably downweight anything i say about this error up weight anything that sort of statistical
learning theory
the bayesian says what steps back and says
what we really doing is is inference if
if we are trying to use data from the world to set a bunch of
numbers in a computer program a computer program is because we don't know what the
number should be
what we're trying to do
work out what those numbers should be
but we did have some idea beforehand
what the weight vector should be this whole idea of regularisation which turns out to
be important says
i have some prior beliefs about what a good system would look like
and then given those probabilities about what a good system should look like getting data
and that data is the future
and under certain assumptions assumptions if you're doing something of that flavour taking prior beliefs
observing data and coming up with this terrible
there is only one way to do which is to use bayesian statistics
i emphasise under certain assumptions
those assumptions arguably don't always hold in machine learning setting there are cases where i
think the basic idea is certainly a very useful one thing
i'm going to give you
very quickly
overview of
roughly what the bayesian view on machine learning is
given the heat of the day and that we haven't had the introductory mass
lecture yet
i don't expect everybody to follow this but i would like to ask questions if
you don't
and if you can't follow everything i'm saying
then the graphical model selection will probably reveal a lot of this material so hopefully
you'll just get some flavour so that when you see this again it will make
more sense the second time
we have a model of this form where we have a weight vector which is
the length of
this matrix have a weight vector that this long we have one weight for every
we have some prior beliefs about what that weight vector might be like
it's probably not too big we might think so
that's exactly the view fertilization so
in the bayesian view we do everything with probability distribution so instead of just saying
i'd like to penalize large values what i do is i put down what's called
the prior probability distribution
here w that just says
what my beliefs about what might be so if i only had one way
i could use something like a guassian distribution
centered around there that says very high probability that the value is somewhere near zero
and very small probability that we have some large value sort of
more than three say
and for a vector we can just use some multi very guessing distribution
i guess in prior over everywhere
what bayesian story that does is
OK you specify your prior now you're allowed to look at the dataset so the
dataset it's made exactly the vector y and i just calling that the and all
of his life
so now we can say well
distribution over what the weight i like now
given that we've seen the data
and that is given by bayes rule
it's proportional to
our prior beliefs about what the weights were before we saw the data
multiplied by
how probable the data that we've seen are given that particular setting of the weight
so for any given weight we can score how could that weighted by combining and
how well it matches the data
then it might be that one particular way tapestry distribution
is tighter because we know more and it might be centered around the different places
so rather than coming up with one particular white
we can say how plausible we think a whole bunch of settings of the weights
that might seem like it with thing to do
it might not depends on sort of what your background as well
he told tell you anything about statistics first
so what do we actually do to do with this
in the story i told you the first time and we had a single weight
vector that we'd fitted and then to make predictions it was obvious what today we
just plugged in the one weight vector that we knew and we applied to our
person we got some sort of answer
now we're going to have to deal with the fact that we've got this distribution
we don't know what the weight vector is so it doesn't seem to make sense
to say one value it could be any of these values and we don't know
so what we do is
we minimize our expected loss
and the expectation is under the distribution represents our uncertainty
so we're going to make some predictions calling why that's sort of estimate of what
output it is
that's the minimum value under an expectation so some of the probability distribution of an
of loss
if we can to pick a particular why
then if the true value y started will suffer this loss
but we of course we don't know what the true value is
so what we need to do is average over
each of the
possible true values weighted by how probable we think they are given the data set
so we're going to have to make future predictions text are
we don't know why stop but we can say what we think i distribution over
it is given the data set and the average over that
something to avoid confusion if you're reading up on this stuff
is this something called the bayes classifier
which has absolutely nothing to do with bayesian inference is kind of confusing thing the
besides one retreating here this is this is prototype example
let's specialize in this
that's another is the LP duality theorem you can restrict yourself
to be
and it should
we can restrict more
two where we have two matroid polytope
now remember for matroid polytope vertices
are zero and i
the vertices are the zero one vectors of the independent sets in the matrix
in other words the polymatroid is simply the whole
so one vectors of the independent sets
now that pollinator intersection theorem says that
where the polymer
hope to two matroids
the vertices of the intersection
are precisely the vectors that are the vertices of
of both of
no no vertices at all are
they they they the vectors of the sets that are independent both
mean right
and furthermore you had TTI and this
now the interesting point here
it doesn't work for three matrix
you take the third matroid trade intersect
you get garbage
and now let's apply this to the
optimum branchings whereas the out branches of first going to specialize more
in your wrote book
and you may making right book this is the only major intersection theorem that they're
going to get to you
because they don't know about linear pro they get their stone non-linear programming unfortunately
now i don't know how it is now that there was a time when even
computer scientist in a linear programming
a typical master and still doesn't know linear programming because
linear programming is
so to relegated by pure mathematicians two
you know the dirty
stuff that practical people like you do right
they don't realize that they're totally impractical people like me that love interest to a
linear programming also so
this is the the book set that the
math department use
is only that there is
where everything's been specialized
cardinality is
but we've seen that is simply a special case
the polytope
intersection there
now here's our first example applications
a branching rooted at the node we've already described that
what of branching is
well let's describe branching in another way
it's the spanning tree
the spanning trees of a graph for the basis of a matroid aren't they
the access to that are from our supergraph of the independent sets of a matroid
the basis of that to the spanning trees of
so in one of two i was so we're going to restrict ourselves to the
basis that is not simply
change one of the inequalities to integration
so the basis of one of the major the spanning trees of this
directed graph
can you guess what the
other major it is
the other major in a subset of edges is independent
it it's is for each node different from the road there is exactly one entry
a subset of edges is independent and the second matrix for every node differ from
the exactly one edge that's that enters
is that good definition of branching
a spanning tree such that every no different from the root has exactly one it
these are two metro and so
finding an optimal rembrandt is finally
OP is optimizing over those two metropolitan right
that's all there is to it
i actually direct in this case the direct algorithm is
it is especially elegant
so i briefly actually here you don't have to you don't have to know about
trade you don't even have to know about linear program in order to
this it's more complicated than the number of algorithms for finding an optimal spanning tree
but not much more
you choose the best actually should no different from road
and when a directed cycle is created by this
chooses choose the best edge to for each node different choose the best edge directed
well you live liable to create a cycle directed cycles in doing so
when that happens you shrink the directed cycle track away was going
it continues to treat this sort of like and i choose the best edge directed
toward that
you might create another direct disciple shrink it away
eventually this is going to stop where you have a brain change
in all in the back of course you have to say what that means
eventually you're going to get a branching in this graph of all these pseudo knowledge
there you start phase one
now you simply expand the pseudo nodes
in the cycles in the reverse order they choose from the
you fill them in from motorcycles
it's a time expander cycle you there is a unique way
you get a branching
and that set of edges expand another attack back up to seven that year at
the moment that's out what could be more beautiful
but that is this is an application that the way that was discovered was is
an application
of matroid intersection
here's another quickly here's another
application matrix infection important matroid sums
we've got a family of matroids
and so by
and there's a specified rank functions are
now we say
a subset of the elements
is independent
remember that
some elements is independent if its cardinality
for every so
one such a
such as independent if for every subset s j
this inequality holds
well OK so that's an independence assumptions
but in fact
and if you want to do really accurate just two more steps as you go
first sort of sensible
a sensible thing to
what we're doing then when we learn deep belief net
we have this model was according to this model
we learn these weights
using our approximation
having learned those waves
we then freeze them here
we take the
aggregated posterior distribution get then we try to model that
which involves learning these weights
but with all the weights tied together so we really need is infinite
and we keep doing that until you bought
it's very hard to know how many leisure you should use zoom will tell you
that you should use too many less according to his
because he was only using rather small net
because he was doing is
my belief is that
actually things very robust
and you got me something for evolution to do
and what evolution is going to do is decide roughly how many lesser-known units
now there's one little snack to this whole argument
which is that
when these weights with the same as these weights
this stuff up here constructed prior distribution that this exactly complimentary to like it so
i can do exact inference
by taking this binary vector most find by these weights and putting the second
once start changing these weights
if they use the transpose these weights which are different it won't be doing exact
so i'm going to lose because i'm not doing inference right
however when i change these weights
i'll be getting a better model of the aggregated posterior is
so i'm going to win because i get a better model of the aggregated posterior
and the question is
how does what i lose by doing inference from compared with what i win by
getting better model
and the answer is you win more than you lose
when you right and the national bank
so when i change these weights
i get a better
variational bound
and even though my inferences and right anymore it's still pretty good
it started off being perfect
the change was this not quite perfect but it's still the case of these almost
it's about
that's what typically happens
that's all proved in this paper which is the basically from the stuff
i want to quickly
so much more going to do
so this is not remarkable change in equilibrium has worry which is one so get
big you don't get very far from the data
and there might be
huge low-energy regions never visit
and of course those will mean that the probability of things you do this is
actually very low in the models distribution because the models putting all its weight on
these the things that you never see
because you never see the
you don't realise that you think you've got a good model but you haven't
it's amazing that given that could have it doesn't really screw you
in general it doesn't describe anything not just fine with this sort of one step
but there's nothing you can do which is what mark radford neal did to begin
which is to say
instead of
running my by starting at the data each time
why don't i do the following
i'm going to have a number of markov chains
and these markov chains i don't we initialize the the data
this is received it of
we just keep running these markov chains
and as a change the weights
so change the ways the markov chain rings
so each time and update the weights i run each of these markov chains a
little bit
now if the markov chain was already close to equilibrium
and i didn't change the weights much
will stay close to
so as long as i change the way slowly enough all these markov chains are
running will be close to the close to equilibrium
so they'll do just fine for estimating this sort of the i according to the
model this
when the models the group
so these persistent chains for estimating that
and then first meeting the i share with the data i just take the data
i data in units and just look at the correlation
so it's not easy thing to do
that was the original idea bots machine so you would you be away you look
at things in yesterday's correlations and then you go to sleep and you'd imagine things
by running is marketing for a long time you to measure the correlations
and then you take the difference those two statistics and that's a lot
it's actually the idea was used
as you're asleep you
measure these models statistics and then the next day
you change your weight in proportion to the difference between this decision measure when your
weight the models decision is when you're asleep
so that that's how you actually work
according to that theory which may not be right
we can try and i
implement that learning algorithm
and it turns out it works very well
and it works very well not at all for the reason that you might think
so one thing to think about this chain is doing something very similar to the
because you start off with very small weights was easy to reach equilibrium and human
the weights get bigger
so if you look at this chain it looks very like a simulated annealing chain
where the temperature is getting long
and in fact if you are persistent chain for a long time during the conduct
close to equilibrium
then if you started with the final weights and ran for the entire length of
time you learned for
to try and get to equilibrium
because it was doing this sort of thinking start small weights and gradually declines
but it turns out you can learn much faster than that and also will predict
and in fact you only need about a hundred of these facts actually was just
one of these chains which is very surprising
and that's the reason why the learning works much better than you'd expect
i'm not going
so what's happening when you do learning is
you're changing the weights by
you raise them by the statistics you measured
with the data
and you love them according to the correlations you measured in these
markov chains that you running to estimate what the model believes
what that means is
if you think of these markov chains like fantasy particles moving around energy surface
whatever fancy particle is
the learning will say raise the energy there
and that makes the fantasy particles go somewhere else
so you can get trapped in local optima
OK if you get always the same you might have some deep local optima the
particle might just sort of thing here
trying to jump out but is very high in the various states
but if your learning
using this particle for learning
it is stuck in the middle
i mean it was going to keep going up until it falls out the
so the a funny interaction between the learning algorithm
and these markov chains
the has the effect of making the markov chains mix extremely fast
only the gradient 0
but the Hessian
is not to be the figure of the inverse of the Hessian is not too
this some positive numbers so that the norm of the Hessian matrix is not too
big know what I mean by the norm of the Hessian matrix
and that I'm going to need to put somewhere
and then put the norm over here so the norm of a matrix what's called
the operator norm of a matrix
it is
the maximum norm and max subject to a norm x less than or equal to
which assesses OK how big
when I think of them as a linear operator
and I hit any x with enormous circa 1 with how big could because
came out that coincides with the definitions
yes no less singular 1 equal 1 doesn't really matter
I'm so this says
so right and this is the norm
on linear operators
on matrices
so it may not you look a little confused not OK right so this is
a norm and is the norm of the inverse of the Hessian is not too
bad that's the 1st condition the 2nd edition says
there exists a beta unit is the neighborhood so that long as axis
the distance from x to the optimum is at most data this condition holds what
is this kind of a condition called
and if you know the name yes it's called a Lipschitz so a Lipschitz condition
when we say something is Lipschitz it means that
we can bound relative change
so what this says that the Hessian is Ralph is Lipschitz
and effect as well I used a capital l here
for lipshitz
OK so this is this is looking from sufficiently close to x star
the difference in the Hessians
is bounded by some absolute constant times the distance
for X is from dot
you have a question OK
OK so that's that these by the way ladies gentlemen this is all technical jock
in away so that at a certain level of becomes valuable to study the interplay
here but right now because because because I didn't give a loose interpretation of this
and it's going to be very loops
OK for so this is the 1st Edition says the inverse of my question is
not too big which means my Hessian is I can bounded away from being singular
you can think of it that way
OK and this
in a neighborhood around for a point sufficiently close
my point where the gradient is 0
my Hessian is lipshitz
and then the 3rd condition says is my current point is really close to x
star in the following since its distance from x star in effect strictly less than
some gamma
which is going to be the minimum of data and 2 h over 3
why the 2 and why the 3
OK because the arithmetic will work out nicely
OK so this is the knowledge cash
this is my Hessian is well behaved
in the neighborhood of x star
if I start sufficiently close to x star
and of my Hessian in fact now is well behaved in a neighborhood but I
can but added that it's it's nonsingular
and then I get quadratic convergence
I'm gonna prove this later in the lecture
but I just want people to digest it for a little bit and want people
to see
thank you
a little bit about it so we can let me do a simple example
the people see what's going on here
my 1st example is going to be a one-dimensional example and then you available to
see exactly what's happening
it's a form of one-dimensional example I'm going to choose the function and I'm up
to you your name will show that's action which should so suppose for example I
have a one-dimensional function f of x peers 7 X minus log of X
what's the great people state of greedy will talk about 1st derivative so what's the
1st derivative
the 7 minus 1 over X and what's the 2nd derivatives
1 over X squared tank
and now your name is like rags OK rods OK
rods say what's the Newton was the Newton direction going to be at x
minus the amount of data to will away
it has 1 over square squares you move from 1 over X squared inverse which
is just XQuery right the fact that would be the Newton direction and that says
the next iteration of xn is going to be x minus
and you work this out
have appropriate adjustments OK so
X minus I got it right yes I got
the reaction you're looking at
how much you form in a certain amount of time
so here
it might be what the data would look like as time goes on you see
an increase in then it starts to level off
you can consider the average rate
which would be defined as some changing concentration over particular change in time
you could express that as the change are delta
of the concentration of an old over the change in time delta time
and you could pick some places and calculate an average rate
so you could draw lines over two different concentrations at two different times and calculate
what the rate is in that interval
so we can do that the average rate two different concentrations at those two different
different times
changing concentration over change in time
and that gives you a value
but this
this average rate than depends
on time interval chosen so
it's going to be a different rate here then it might have been down here
up here so
that tells you may be something but it doesn't necessarily tell you all the things
that are going on because it just depends on a particular area
so instead of considering average rate you can start talking about instantaneous rate the rate
at a particular time
and so that's the instantaneous rate
and so you really wanting to know what is the the rate they have a
hundred and fifty second at that particular moment in time what was the rate
so here it is talking about the limit
as that change in time approaches zero
and that can also be expressed in terms of d concentration of an o t
so the change in concentration of NO
with time at a particular particular moment
so as
that change in time
approaches zero
the rate becomes the same as the slope of the line tangent to that particular
point in time at time t the one you're interested in
so it's a find the instantaneous rate at one hundred and fifty
a second series
so we can do that
the rate at that particular time
so we're going to draw a line tangent to the curve
and figure out the slope of that line
so we can do that find the slope
get some different points
and look at the instantaneous rate
so we can calculate the slope of that line
and come up with a rate so
in this case seven point seven times ten to the minus five and this is
in molar per second
which is the common u
unit four great
OK so it tells us about a particular instantaneous rate at one at one given
and an important thing to consider is an initial rate so that's the instantaneous rate
at time equals zero so the initial
initial rate of the reaction
so that's a little bit about measuring rates and we'll talk more about plotting data
when you're trying to get out rate constants and other other factors
so rate expressions
so we can express the rate of the reaction when we're measuring
a reaction you can often pick to measure the increase in the amount of products
being formed
you can also consider the decrease in the amount of reactants so you can measure
rate either way looking for disappearance or looking for appearance and often decisions about how
you're going to measure the rate depends on how easy it is to measure changes
something so there's usually practical considerations that go on here
so then the rate can be expressed in terms of the disappearance
of one of the reactance here and o two so
the rate is going to depend on how fast that disappearing
the disappearance of the second reactant over here
and the appearance
then one of the product
the other product
and this of course is only true
if we assume there's is no intermediates
because sometimes the rate at which
reactor will disappear
will not be the same as the rate at which it will appear because it's
what the steps involved in between the this comes back to mechanism which we're going
to talk about in the next week
so but this is what's known as the great expressions
so let's look at an example
so here interaction
two h i guess going to h two gas because i two gas
so the right
could be considered in terms of the disappearance of the reactant
and here we see that for every two
h either disappears that's decompose we have one
h two and one
i two
so for going to set up or rate expression
we're going to have to multiply this term by half
if it's going to be equal to the rate at which
h two appears or the rate at which
i two appears so the stoichiometry here matters so if you just looked at the
rate of disappearance of HIV
you it wouldn't be equal to help assets for me because two are going away
for every one of each of these that is formed
so then in general
you would write the expression this way
so minus
minus one over a where a is the stoichiometry
reacting in a
d eighty t
find one over b
dp dt
plus one over c
d dt
plus one over t
that's hard to say
right so those are rate expressions
now we come to rate law
so great
is the relationship between race and concentrations
there's going to be related by
a proportionality constant called little pay rate constant
so big k was why
equilibrium constant and now we have little k which is the the rate constant lies
going to tell you how the rate depends on the things in the reactions will
be rate constants and there's going to be concentration terms
and it has to be experimentally determined what that rate law is
you have to pay for it by accepting to be less accurate
lots of things to make more mistakes or having more training examples
this image products and understanding hospital situation people could be very first
but there is the monkeys opening or in practice is that
when you have explanations when
there is already discussion about explainable on systems where you say well beaten on network
is not explainable because you cannot understand what all rules the following
and something like the decision tree
it's nice explanation
but you also know that when you take a decision tree with simple explanations not
as well
that's up to the fact that structure
this is an example of this idea
but if you want an explanation
you have to pay for it by accepting a lower accuracy
that's not very satisfactory form in the
practical proposals the
and that in his view this is what we can the map
so well
to change it you have to work quite hard
and so it's not possible to change by taking another viewpoint of the problem
but it's not going to be as simple that
is that the question
no blood was very optimistic because we can still act win situation that we don't
that we know less nothing more likely to share
i understand what you said and this is why the that science is going to
change dramatically
if there is an opportunity for acting well without full understanding
it's unthinkable
people will not take advantage of people over the next centuries
but that we also means accepting
a modification in the way we understand science and modification in the way we need
an explanation
my expensive when they have to with very precise i find it and unreadable
just very painful to read so i think she less impact
but i
that's optimistic way because OK we want to buy explanation letters by more examples but
the pessimistic way
these are the examples we get that fixed the limited
and if we have an opportunity to act but
on the basis of these examples only
o dollars
will take the opportunity to win win
even though they don't understand
i'd say not many in this form of the final
they are now
i guess people have something to work on it
but the i mean
i'm not aware of political was all that
with some marginal from by
that the third way
the so the way that can be done in this article
the second battalion the first the what the most striking element i know about
is to show that whatever
guarantees is given for the task is
made using
mathematical tools derive from the second
so you prove the second and then you make approximation to prove the first
that led
as i think that the second actually more essential
the second is purely combinatorial the first one has been made
work in infinity the
in continuous space by using tweaks and losing some constant factor of the way
so in the third part
is discussing some
cases of non inference things we can consider doing
and in this part
there are two
quite interesting propositions that
i'm going to describe
the first thing is that
large margins are basically wrong
we have of course when you do not imagine in the feature space
what the large margin means completely depending on how you define the space
and how do you find the space is completely arbitrary
this is related to the parameterisation problem in bayesian theory like
if you take a business that sort of like common but this is how i
understand it
if you take a base in the port
you have to arbitrate parameterisation
one is the parametrisation of the input is how do you present your pocket
suppose you want to recognise handwritten digits
well you take the square root of pixels to prison by zero and one with
completely arbitrary
we know for a fact that i doesn't work that way and the digits were
designed to be easy way by
so you could think of for presenting digits biases the most rock or by a
circular are of pixels or something else
and of course when you're describe the function
that that operate on the basis the way
you said that the space where you tries you put them
is extremely important
the second parametrisation issues
is the parameter space of the functions how you parametrized functions
and in the bayesian theory this is very important because this is how to define
the prior of the priorities defined on the parameterisation of the functions
and if you look in the bayesian
you realize that there is a lot of thinking about this parametrisation of the function
so there is that physics u
i recognise this is about a factor
and then use your
the probability of the state is exponentially
proportional to the energy
that what is the connection between
such density
in space
and they can that reasoning and values
that are computed from the matrix and
and one thing that interested me was going to use this for
analysis of of
dynamical systems
to do this we need some mathematical analysis
here's the first observation for celebrations that the matrix m
of which are computing the
you can vectors
is a joint semantic one
and we all know that symmetric scissors
are always the analyzable and they have
a set of
there you can vectors are
they all follow model
orthogonal and they form the basis
of of are and
therefore the same holds for the next markov matrix that we've just constructed
moreover if you took ceylon
large enough all points are connected you can move from each point to each other
and therefore
the first thing about this matrix is one with multiplicity one
and it has
in addition a sequence of n minus one
a nonincreasing and values on the j
and as i said both the writing vectors on the left eigenvectors they for basis
of our own
first writing conductor
the steady state distribution of the random walk
because of the way i constructed it within epsilon large enough
regardless of where you start from
if you
long enough
the probability of staying of reaching y
is exactly this
first a conductor
berlin normalise it
i have one or was one
what i want to do
is to measure how two points are close
and as i've said before in original space
that is a difficult task can no in the original space in high dimensional space
i can know if two points are close
only very closely they're far apart i don't know how close they are
one way to measure closeness
is with respect to this random walk
so specifically
for any two points x not the next one
i can measure their closeness at some time t
by starting at x not in looking at the probability distribution at some later time
t so if this is actually not that's going to be some kind of about
here x not
making the same
o thing for x one
starting next one random walk
what is the
well because this was after time t
and see how these two were
are close to each other
that is a matter of
the dynamical proximity between two points with respect to this
random walk
and you can always so this is an l two norm but you can always
have a weighted l two norm
it turns out that if you take this weighted l two norm
where you
divide by people believe that this is the solution
norm has an intimate connection to the
you can vectors and again functions
as we have computed
and this is
spelled out in the following spectral theorem that the distance
the construction because the fourier transform is an isometry
minimizing zero to the energy in the time domain and the four domain is the
so what the minimum energy reconstruction does it sets to zeros the data that have
not seen
and so we construct messy
trigonometric polynomial
that has the frequency that i've seen and none of the other frequencies
and of course this message trigonometric polynomial which is here
look nothing like this
that has all frequencies
right now
well you cannot see this but
so this was my beautiful friend
and the phantom is not stars in the pixel domain but it's great explorers
so what you would do is you would minimize l one norm of what sparse
and what's passes the gradient so you minimize l one norm of the weight
that's because the total variation norm
and what if you do something else the filtered backprojection that people do in the
field to get this but if you minimize the total variation norm you have perfect
recovery and why because the gradient is extremely sparse
so one will get uses sparse solution
OK and that's another
time i got in trouble with reserve his university of wisconsin actually because i've is
i this radiologists and the data
about phantoms undersampled according to his polar geometry as in action you before
and i would return the results and the results they were always exact holds the
centre of this guy gave me
and at some point he said well manually completely fudging
in sciences in
what is the phone number of dean and so on and so forth
but then i gave them the code
people could see that it's actually
OK so of course all these experiments called for an explanation and explanation you've seen
this variation is is result which said that
for example thinking time and frequency is it's a theorem that is the number of
measurements essentially bigger than this one again then the recovery is complete exact
all right so this i don't really need to talk about because
well i've given you so much history in the first lecture about the use of
the one norm in geophysics and the early results in the mathematical signal processing community
which i will highlight a different set of results of the fact that we can
reconstruct sparse objects some undersampled frequency data has been known in the theory of computer
science at about the same time and there are some nice results by hand gilbert
and colleagues showings is how can this this can be done with completely different algorithms
even though the emphasis in this work is not at all on reconstruction from many
many sample data rather it's on speeding up things like fifty
so it's much more
it's not inspired by data analysis it inspired by
numerical linear algebra
OK so now compressed sensing what is it
OK alright so compressed sensing is trying to kind of resolve one of these
enormous down that we live with which is that
we live in a world that is a bit strange where we spend a lot
of time and effort and money acquiring data
when we know ahead of time that most of what we acquire we will end
up throwing it away
and a good example of this is my digital camera
my digital camera has lots of sensors
and so when i go in the backyard and i take a picture and i
don't from precedent
the rule five is about fifty megabytes and that's what i see
and then around japan two thousand
and it will compress down this picture two
a hundred hundredfold and so i would get a GP five of about one hundred
and fifty kilo right
so roughly speaking i through a ninety nine percent of the one i look at
the difference between these two pictures there's not much
and so
the the kind of the paradigm we live in is very strange which we we
spend a lot of time designing sensors and growing data
and the first thing we do have to require data is to throw most of
and so the question that we like to as it seems enormously wasteful
and i hope it's not stable for society it seems enormously wasteful another question that
you need to ask is is it possible to acquire the part that you will
not throw away
because really the kind of the
the way the world goes at the moment is we have very expensive sensors take
a lot of higher resolution data
but because we cannot is transmitter stores its data we need to compress it
so we compress them
so that we can transmit them store them
and we send them to receiver whose then compresses but in this compression stage
well essentially discard ninety nine percent of what we have measured of course
to be able to get this kind of pictures i need to be able to
look at the entire dataset to know what is it that i need to away
for example i need to compute its coefficient in the wavelet domain names and throw
away the little ones the big ones
all right so
will see that there is a way of doing this of arbitrary rethinking this picture
in in in a different way
and that is there that actually almost all
suggestions for
with these models
we discussed
one idea is to use the expansion is a
and somehow
music as an expression of the
around the world
this been explored
it's probably not so much
approximation to resolve his life
not as good
variational bound on the
much like
that i don't like it like this the
that and higher
and this is i about this
what defined
that dog get
the approximation
is actually turn things that
you can around the world
that's right
optimize processes
process and
one of the this is
to the front
and observations then the posterior is
as in right
to be a lot of work
so one can think of
the reduced form tried to
it's called to take action
which is why
and i realized that
i discovered that
all right
so now
much like
has a like the
in fact
well justified
it's hard
i want to find the
this is what must
you need to know
is that right use the
that means that every
that's not
my house
OK so what i want to
something of a
all size
i don't want to make sure is the site potentials
i going to have
now since we have been
and i
not so you know
it's also known
the approximation
the distribution over targets
the class label
probability that one by one
which is
by something
this is also to have
functional shape
but this is still somehow
because this one
so over
four different values of y
this thing you can do
we don't necessarily which is on the one that the sum of the two thousand
one is
not one
the main idea is that we
from i times
i normalized
such a long way to go into it is maybe see
target is so vision targets the prior
the likelihood that you cannot be computed but you know to
define it has
constructs can produce simulations from this likelihood
the trick is to
related to this very
the essential
properties that if you select from the prior
so the prime then you studio
from this model
and you wait until easy
is equal to one
the observed data
the time you get out of this movement
produces a a prime that is exactly
from the posterior distribution
is it true
just look at the distribution of
upcoming sit on it is that
prior times to accept the bridge to accept is for why
even today are so it's accept reject one one
it was
in nineteen
in nineteen eighty four by
then and also in nineteen eighty four
peter diggle
morning a conceptual way then
for the then in a practical way
but as the augmentation of what is the posterior distribution devices solution uses a prior
has a prediction for population
and in some cases weights
to the data that must mimic the traditional and so that's our spirits quite interesting because it gives
a fairly
intuitive approach to bayesian statistics but of course in practice it was only two nineteen ninety seven
that it became a practical tool
now is it practical well as i write it is not practical because wedding forces equal why
means at this is an even that must occur
at the human scale
you cannot wait
billions of years for is equal to one and therefore
you be see
is drifting away from this exact condition is the posture
but lowing form some tolerance around
so there
so we don't accept
only one is equal to other ones is closing after one
namely one distance between why and psi ops distance is less than a certain epsilon
and epsilon is tolerance
that you're ready to tolerate
and actually in practice
this is better and that you're forced to tolerate if you want to solve the problem
before you retire
now of course this produces an approximation
and this approximation
means actually estimating from the true pushchairs but from the convolution
this poster by
this tolerance
thank you
and that's that's the price you have to pay
more should pay four
selling approximately the problem
because the algorithm just you can write it in in a few lines you see from the data
as you from the fairy story used absolute
conditional on this value of the parameter and you wait until
xeon and why
closing of now there is another degree of approximation that is found in in most
cases namely that you cannot wait
four the whole data to be close to the whole to nail
and so forth
this proximity
to occur
in the reduced space
through the use of
statistics that are called summary statistics
which doesn't mean anything because they are statistics that is transforming the data
the body that are usually not sufficient so they are throwing away some part of
the information contained in the data but paradoxically they will explain minutes
this is unnecessary to do anything useful
really commonly used machine learning so it's it's used to the point where people often
won't mention that that's what this scoring on
i don't believe it's always the right thing for applications i gave an example of
reading text that is not true that you're going to necessarily just care about
whether you got the right answer on the check and you're going to also wanted
more complicated system that spits out don't know and that should be part of the
loss function how bad it is i don't know that's impossible to the k
something else you might do is achieve some sort of tolerance so i'm predicting the
strength of the concrete and i predict that it will have a tensile strength of
five and some units now
then they go away and build that concrete and i actually only had
tensile strength of four point five
are they allowed to see me
well presumably we had some sort of contract where i said
i'm going to predict the tensile strength and i think that i'm going to get
it correct within the bounds so one sort of loss might be and my within
the tolerance it i agree to
in which case that's OK otherwise are going to experience some loss
you have to be a bit careful with that sort of loss function say
i heard this story about consulting for
chemical plant
the law said that there was a strict limit on the amount of pollutants they
catch up into the river
the loss is
it's fine with legal as long as you
stay with this level of pollutants
otherwise it's illegal and that's bad we will or biting companies that's infinitely bad so
we going infinite loss so that never happened
and that's a terrible loss function to use because then what a computer system will
is it will
desperately trying stay legal and keep all the pollutants within the tolerance that
real systems are noisy
bad things happen maybe at some point you're going to exceed the legal threshold in
which case you experience infinite loss and after that it doesn't matter what you do
seem as well just dump all pollutants that you can into the river because it's
easier and so you need to sort of thing very carefully when you're constructing these
things and think realistically about about applications
having said all of that people don't necessarily do
the loss functions you'll see in papers are often much more
concerned with of a different symbol of a convex things that will make the code
easier to write the theory easier to do this algorithms easier to analyse say a
choosing loss functions is a compromise and
something that you will have to think about and return later to issue practical issues
to do with loss functions they you can sit down and come up with the
loss function and then it turns out to be not very good
and i'll give you examples of that later
in fact right now so
here it is
the regression problem we saw before
and here it is
another point on training set
so this is a very common situation you get outliers in data so someone's entering
these numbers in the table orange lemon orange lemon and then they were ham-fisted and
they put in one instead of minus one
or it just turns out that one of the items are free what happens to
be deformed and it's weird
and you don't want your whole learning system to be dominated by what turned out
to be a mistake what turned out to be something that was just a freak
so here we pull down the whole regression surface because of this one point
and maybe that's an unreasonable thing to do
so a least squares is often said to be not very robust to outliers and
what some people do with trying to identify these outliers and toss them out and
then we do the fit may be what you want to do is something other
than least squares
something that says
you know i i still want to sort of not ignore this happened but
i went to dominate everything i do
because of the
here's another example we saw before so a
this is the classification problem
the purple line is the result of fitting this data set by least squares
the weight vector associated with the purple line
and we predicting the response for given publication so we're computing the value which is
that which is w transpose x this thing is called the activation
if you want to do with and what we're trying to do is fit that
two are observed data which turns out to be plus one to minus one because
the classification problem
so now
as we move away from the plane at the plane that there
so it will get bigger it will be
one then it will be bigger than one so
a long way away from the plane we're going to get very large values and
the reason this curve is skewed because if it within the sensible place like the
green light all of these points would be very far away from
and then maybe very mismatched from the value of one we trying to get so
when the reason that using this quest classification turned out to be a bad idea
is these point look like outline
two this model
what we can do is look at the different loss functions that we could use
the classification instead of
instead of the square
here i've got said this this activation which is sort of a measure of how
far away from this decision plan and my find a very long way away
from it in one direction i get a very large positive values and that indicates
positive class
very negative values indicate very clearly on the other side so
system is going to very confident say things are in the negative class if that
is very negative
so here's an example of the loss function
if the true label is one
the black line shows the zero one loss
we have lots one
if z is negative because for all negative values we going to predict minus one
and the true label with one as soon as we get a positive value the
black curve
because they're so for any positive value
the losses there
the zero one loss is maybe a sensible thing to fit classification
that's what the sensible decision boundary could be derived from
the squared error is the screen which says
if you're
really really far from the decision boundary on the correct side of the decision boundary
then for some reason i'm going to experience loss because of that
which is a bit of a funny thing to do
it makes sense if we are fitting classification problem for the thing that we're minimising
to be monotonic function of this activation if we claiming that very positive value should
indicate positive labels them as we move really really far out and we strongly saying
that the true label is positive then we should definitely has are lost
so the other two curves
blue curve on the red curves show monotonic functions that we could use instead
the only thing is called the hinge loss and is used in something called support
and then we look at the situation at the end
during the second second
it is clear
and this is a straight line
that the velocity remains constant
and it remains minus six meters per second
that's exactly what it was at this point at the end
you can see it go six meters
plus three two minus three
in one second
so the velocity
his minus six
meters per second
the acceleration is therefore zero
you see that acceleration changes abruptly from minus six meters per second squared
two zero so
i can tell you what it is exactly at this moment in time
that's the situation during
second what is the situation at the end
of the second section
sect couldn't
at the end i know that x equals minus three
what is the velocity
i don't know
because it changes abruptly from minus six two zero so i don't know exactly what
is at that point it's
non physical things
very abrupt change
that's also very tricky things
because if the velocity
his minus sixty on this side of the two seconds
and he becomes zero
and if that happens it in a split second there must be a huge acceleration
just at that point which is non physical
so i would also put a question mark
at the a i don't know what it is
so they go to the thirty second
this part
let's first look
during the third
the object isn't going anywhere just sitting there
x remains minus three
the velocity
is zero
and is zero we can agree on that
what is the situation at the end
of the thirty seconds that means people three
well i know is that x minus three
that's non-negotiable
what the velocities
i don't know
because it's changing abruptly
one zero
a positive value sort of ill-defined
and the same is true for the acceleration of sudden change in velocity
that means there must be a huge acceleration
i no
ill defined
because this curve
is of course not very physical
let's now look
the last seconds four seconds
chris during
it's going from ninety three to play six in a straight line sort of velocity
is constant
is the velocity is constant there you can immediately conclude that is zero there is
no acceleration
and it goes ninety meters in a time span of one second
but it's now
plus nine meters per second
the object first
i went from
positive values of x
two zero into negative values for x doing all the time
the velocity was
sign convention and now
the velocity
it goes back to six
the velocity becomes plus nine
a second
what is the story at the end of the four seconds
well i can say is that actually because plastics
i don't know much more
i don't know what the velocities
neither do i know what the acceleration is the plot stops there any
now i would
i think that it is reasonable to ask the following question
what is the average velocity for instance between time zero and time for
average velocity
we define average velocity
as the position
at time
four seconds minus the position at time zero
divided by four
that is i definition
zero it is about six
at for applies six
so the upstairs is zero
the familiar with the bias variance dilemma in statistics its version of the same problem
cognitive scientist sometimes talk about constraints can you have learn has some hypothesis space and
there are some constraints that that tell you you
all logically possible hypotheses about what the word could mean maybe some
some are more
right than others
so we know that in some sense the former the answer but the questions that
we we want our are go beyond just saying abstract knowledge we want to know
how does some kind of prior knowledge abstract knowledge guide learning and inference from sparse
data what form does it take across different domains and tasks and how might that
technology itself be acquired particularly in machine learning
there's that you know there's there's an aesthetic value and some of the practical value
in wanting to have to wiring is little by hand as possible
now it's an open question how much of the brain is kind of wired by
hand maybe the invisible hand evolution but
it's it's quite likely that some significant parts of cognition are wired into supported by
things that are wired and so we don't necessarily want to say everything is learned
a lot of the deepest questions in the field these questions of nature versus nurture
empiricism versus nativism are debates about what's wired and what isn't and having computational tools
that can tell us how the most fundamental aspects knowledge might in principle be acquired
will give us useful ways to understand in reality whether and where
these these aspects of knowledge are in fact learned from data
and the kind of thing will talk about here in these two lectures are
using some ideas again you know most of these are somewhat familiar in machine learning
and i think you've seen oops i think you've seen versions of of some of
these already here
but i'm going to show you how to apply them to these kinds of problems
motivated by human learning and maybe mix them up in some interesting ways that are
not standard machine learning but i think we'll give us the potential for more interesting
human like machine learning approaches so roughly these ideas that will be talking about the
technical ideas i've organised in answer to these questions but really they all go together
interesting ways not just for convenience so the basic form
of understanding how abstract knowledge guide learning from sparse data will be formalising from a
bayesian point of view sort of more generally probabilistic inference point of view and and
thinking very strong in in terms of generative models so your your prior knowledge is
not just a bunch of numbers but it takes so takes the form of a
almost like a causal description of what's out there in the world that generates the
data that you're seeing
the the the kind of generative models will talk about some of them are going
to be the sort of things are familiar with
if for machine learning and most of what do today are going to stick to
that so you know things like representations like that multi dimensional vector spaces are graphical
models but to capture these more
cognitive parts of cognition higher-level intuitive theories regarding any more structured kinds of representations of
things like grammars logic schemas even even programs so we're going to be writing down
probabilities over logic or or or programs where those things will describe much more
powerfully structured generative models and from from again from a sort of historical point of
view these these more structured representations are often not certainly not associated with machine learning
or even the whole
a statistical approach to a i but more the kind of classical good old-fashioned AI
in the early days of AI where everything was about symbols in logic and all
that and what many people have come to realize is that if you like there
are these there's two classic areas of artificial intelligence and they had caught have corresponding
areas in cognitive science the symbolic
error and the statistical error and people have come to realize that those aren't don't
have to be defined as
competing conflicting worldviews but actually a lot of the the the interesting meat is to
be found in coming up with ways to combine those ideas and to be able
to do probabilistic inference over structured representations
and in even very sophisticated kinds of symbolic objects like computer programs
so there is for example and its last year some of us and bunch of
others organised a workshop on probabilistic programming which means many different things but it's it's
giving tools to try to do this sort of thing and it's it's it's increasingly
very active area of research on both human and machine sites
and then as far as trying to understand how these these this EM technology might
be acquired well if you like we're asking what the priors come from and within
bayesian statistics in certain very simple forms bayesian statisticians have long had an answer to
that they called hierarchical models hierarchical bayes and over the last few years in part
through the work of people like you y and zoubin and others and a lot
of people here organising this summer school these ideas have have come into machine learning
and in very powerful ways and i think you've already seen some of them but
you know the the cut the kind science version of hierarchical bayes what is sometimes
called learning to learn where you take the priors that the guide learning themselves are
the objects of learning so we'll see some of those ideas and will also be
a little bit of nonparametric bayes which i think you i was just to tell
you about this this is very important because
if you think about it
human learning where learning over entire lifetime and again you not just learning a little
bit of knowledge here the problems which motivate the nonparametric approach are
central here right you can just say that a model of some fixed finite complexity
and you know what that is in advance but you're going to have to have
ways to allow the effective complexity of the model to grow over whole lifetime trading
off the in occam's razor it's always it you know the the complexity and fit
just the sorts of things that are are very elegantly approach to nonparametric perspective
so we'll see
some of these five years over today in the next
OK so so we finished the introduction there will be kind of three ten kind
case study areas for probably
the next
twenty minutes or so i'll talk about
cognition as probabilistic inference this is just laying the groundwork basically showing how the basic
idea of bayesian inference and some very very simple kinds of generative models really really
simple you might even think trivial almost textbook statistics
a lot
and then you the
three of them on the top of it
you always
that is
i always
you want
why do we
well one
you really are
so i or
where i
by the time
i would like to
i t
i will be one
of the
dictionary that has to be stable
so these are the classical release about quality
if you change is going to have to change this is not too difficult to
the more difficult elements that you have to get
if that you have to be able to recover
the appropriate that's the appropriate features
for that you have to make sure that an element g
combination of elements of down
correlate in some sense that there is a dictionary
she's in love
then the dictionary which is not like
that you think that this be a kind of be different from individual elements of
that may not reach
so what are the kind of necessary conditions you have to make that work
you need to survive the condition if you kill five people with you there is
no way you'll be able to recover
you the here that these weights for shouldn't look alike too much
the way the lead and if they slightly translated with that they are basically the
same they look too much like you won't be able to distinguish
the set should not be too large because the set is too large
this you will never
so these are the basic conditions in order to be able to do that can
OK let's let's now go to the problem of video so in that case you
have an operator which subsamples the data
and the first idea that comes to mind is for example to do linear interpolation
and that's what you get when you go from here to here which is to
be explained interpolation
what immediately realizes that you could do better and why can you do resolution
because you have some kind of prior information about the fact that there are some
geometric regularities
for example the directions
well you should interpolate on
uniform neighbourhood you should interpolate to exploit this regularly along this direction
now the problem is that you don't know these directions so
you have to find
so that's the basic intuition behind that
if you look at this basic intuition in the fourier domain that's what you
on the left you have the original signal centre
so the fourier transform one line long
this is something you have your phone
population basically makes the projection over space which is the fixed base of low frequency
and what direction on interpolation will do is to that the space of frequency of
which are project you do that and boom you recover of course a much more
precise interpolation
the idea that we're going to do is the following
for this kind of problem
dictionary techniques
two they work or they don't work that's the question OK if you want to
try dictionary you may be used for example with
well let's said reasonable they provide sparse representation now the problems of with that is
that they have a very large or fine scale
you want to recover the fine scale
that may be
in other words you're going to be which is zero so the weight coefficients fine
scale idea
that's why a lot of work was done in the early two thousands to try
to build a different dictionary richard dictionary with geometrical structures
curvelet bandlets x like many trials have been done these are examples of bandlet so
how do you constructive and by linear combination of wavelengths to build a gated structures
so that these structures will take advantage of geometric regularity and will not die
issues of samples and that's how
we decided was that kind of tool to build
the company
so basically huge dictionary that
you have a theory which states it provides you a great sparsity presentation of any
piecewise regular cartoon image
if you go to venture capitalist and you can get money out of that because
luckily they've never done process for
and then you have to try to do it doesn't
doesn't work what does it mean doesn't it works very nicely on five six ten
images but when you need to have video that going to show four hours to
people who are in front of the screen to look whether
it's good or not it doesn't work
it doesn't work because in fact it doesn't provide sufficiently sparse representation
so that you will not be able to
to solve your inverse problems in a stable way
what do people do in practice
they is something but simple they tried to freely
try to grab all these
the degree of freedom which are these elements from the dictionary they basically have one
degree of freedom which is the direction of interpolation and we so this is equivalent
to projection in this space
so the idea is to say well
what can you do
if you have to solve this problem instead of having a dictionary
waveform with many many of these
let's structure the problem and just have a dictionary of vector space
so i'm going to work with the dictionary of vector space
and the only condition so this is the work which is
question you
his thesis an
the basic idea is you're going to build new vector space so that you're operator
the restriction of your operator to the image of these spaces is invertible
you want this in practice
and as you do the same thing that was the dictionary tried to decompose a
sparse representation
as a linear combination of elements in your vector space
but it's much easier vector space of
doing a combination of two vector spaces are very similar
you look at the data
and of course there is
combination of image of your elements of vector space by the operation to you
so you have fast this transform dictionary of vector space
so basically it's the same idea
you can out of that version
and what does it mean to hurt you belong to the vector space e to
the u
so by the inverse what is is bounded inverse doing
this is the direction of interpolation basically what i'm just saying
i found locally what's the appropriate direction i'm going to invert
the set something we a directional into polish
the reason why this is much more stable again is that
you have much fewer vector space and the number of elements
OK now how do construct vector
one way to do it which is simple is to begin from something that
reasonably sparse in this case where something here to work with vector space which are
built with blocks
of wavelet coefficients OK so i'm going to build here block b of wavelet coefficients
and within the space of log p of wavelet coefficients i recombine them to potentially
be correlated coefficient make it better than approximation
we use a new orthogonal basis
PCA basis which typically could be looks like it is it but the main point
is example
that last space which are basically
constructed by lots of ways this
we potentially in combination with these wavelengths two
as i said we correlates the crayfish
how many PCA coefficients are going to take going to adjust it so that my
operator you is invertible over myspace
is about using the
which was
o point in order to optimise your hyperparameters
i think this is a really important thing before i don't think even for human
vision or for computer vision will be able to do it with these friends energy
functions were to figure out how to make use of these hundreds of thousands of
numbers that we get any given visual input i just want to mention that the
c ninety nine percent of the work recently has been
in the training test paradigm
actually interacts with his thesis which was supervised by geoff hinton actually did empirical basis
for low level vision many years ago
and this
it's now become much more popular topic but i think it's time to revisit this
idea was new techniques many of which have been developed developed again here in hopes
for nonparametric inference i think we can go back and he was much more complicated
products energy functions using this framework
OK so in conclusion i convinced that despite the mind
the vision and humans is actually consistent with highly sophisticated energy minimisation
problems we can go to optimise the energy
despite the NP hardness
and you can get functions despite an exponential number of constraints but despite this progress
we have a lot of work to do to match the remarkable performance of low
vision in humans thank you very much
such services see that military regime by the computer vision or biological vision
one thing that strikes me is the computational neuroscientist is claiming that the human
vision is fantastic and it all these problems that text console with computer vision
and to me it seems that
so just naively that
human knowledge might not solve these these problems for two reasons why
we can do in fact just as we heard yesterday the continent track more than
four objects at the same time as moving so
really i don't think we're solving these problems really at the pixel level at which
this computer algorithms are trying to do so
o if i tend to think carefully about the image i might be able to
do pixel by pixel but usually i don't care about it i just go with
the with just eleven and second
if so i don't think it's the last major part that is solving it using
fantastic kind of visual models of what let's look like well what people look like
and all that
two to solve it just
just the way you use your model to so we don't have horses building all
other classes of objects and all the money is coming from highland division rather than
motion so i'm wondering whether you think these ideas might actually help to improve your
computer vision algorithms that have two points there
the second point i think it's about definition so i would define an algorithm that
description at the pixel level
the resolution as low level vision problem so it doesn't matter if you use knowledge
it's orthogonal to the issue of whether use knowledge not so
as far as i'm concerned you can think of of recognition field to optical flow
not only that's that's fine with me you can do without any that's that's very
question we do this we ask people to leave the pixel
in this experiment was talking about with the city charter capable of doing it in
the end that is you are capable of the velocity field can i ask you
to this pixel of correctly and you can say yes or no for every pixel
so it's true that may be that requires positive feedback loops but in the end
you have your visual system is capable of giving us these pixel accurate pixies at
what's right about that solving the global optimization problem since maybe a discussion about
in proceed simultaneously is an interesting one but
people come about three or four
simultaneously has about yesterday thanks
also question OK
thanks for you get
i was wondering whether you think that activision
good jump in in support the search for the energy function
should then we think he and seymour density of
how we should move in order to better perceive
and what is the right function
USS solution should look at the history