the nice structure and then if you went to the third dimension you would see
the structure in the wrong then you don't quite see in this two dimensions
the fact that these um
angle around is different here
as i say go for large neighborhoods because these graphs are disconnected and that's meant
that this is what pushed back the green are relying on the red
although you can see some nice structure and that's section there
that you don't see in
peace yet but this is meant we had together these large neighborhoods to ensure these portions the manifold connected
i mean i can be a problem obviously with these neighborhood graphs
gene expression again i don't really see anything much and at one
i'm really close the scottish now
and i sound like our secretaries in sheffield apparently as well
so again you see
some separation but this is weird because sarah
one appears to students in the speech group has something moved into
the man
so i'm not quite sure the embedding very good
in fact i'm kind of skeptical about whether
the question i can that's is a good thing to do
in many cases i tell you what i think it's good is if you've got
enormous amounts of data because the igon value problem you do is a sparse igon
value problem computationally that's very quick solve
but it's very few data points often gives really bad embeddings and that's because it's
not putting any effort into thinking about what these adjacency weight should be and i'll
come back to that later when i tried unify
the perspective
it's fast because it doesn't do anything
and that's not a bad thing
if you think about
page rank
it's basically laplacian i can maps
google algorithm so you can do this on web scale data
then adjacency just the linkage between um
different web pages
very very similar so you can do this on an almost data and if you
go for almost data it turns out it doesn't matter that you don't parameterized
the uh
graph very much but if on the data sets are used here
me particularly this one where there's only a few data very high-dimensional but few data
it's not doing a great job so i would tend to think of using the
question might maximum going very very large data um because certainly but that you can't
do isomap
which i think is a really good uh
basic thing to so if you see the results the mean has some really nice
results and things like that value dataset and uses the semi supervised learning so we
can if only really work in domains that i haven't shown here
locally linear embeddings
you know i i really hate this not locally linear embeddings are like that but
what i hate about spectral methods is what i'm doing now and i'm gonna try
and correct the mean it
it's what i do is i stand up when i say
i has not a way of doing dimensionality reduction
imagine everything's living and the diffusion equation or everything's locally linear all this and this
is there and you can modern think about makes sense
if you try and teach that's
to undergraduates which i think must be the final aim any the research doing being
able to incorporate incorporated into an undergraduate course you have to do
three lectures on each methods in order for them to understand what's going on there
it's completely different motivations and you get a flavor
well this is i'm going through because now
this is a new way to do dimensionality reduction which says let's approximate and nonlinear
manifold by small linear patches and it's a really nice idea
assume distance between data points is small relative to the curvature so if you look
in your neighborhood that we've been talking about before and assume that is linear in
the neighborhood the curvature is moving quickly
then you find a set of linear regression weights for this locally linear patch and that's this equation here
you try and reconstruct a point from its neighbors
by this weighted
weighting of its neighbours so you've got a point why i and you try and
reconstruct its value by weighting neighbours about point with a quadratic error function
object if it is
invariant to rotation and rescaling view data but is not invariant to translation so there's
something we're gonna much do to the subjective
i end
sam roweis and lawrence saul proposes an motivated well if you want to if we modify with translation
so adding mutual hawai i's so this is minus why jason a minus mu there
we add any object if we get this form and not changes the value of
the objective so in order to fix the if you constrain the sum to one
the sum of the weights to one
that's a minus mu and not councils without new yeah so that's an important thing
is not just regression this would just be regression
in the data space rather than in the feature points space and minimize the subjective
but this is regression with can extract constraint that the sum of w must be
equal to one
you see these constraints popping up everywhere right the classy and transpose one
so that's gonna be meaningful data it's got another
but you can see here in this in the way we the subjective here
now the idea is to then
these w's
breach data point breeze neighborhood and then you look across all the neighborhoods
and you start with a new dataset will cortex and you force acts to be a low dimensional dataset
and he was actually low dimensional data you some across all the neighbours you get
this which is the same objective function that is really expressed in a different way
regression from
now is just very very simple mathematical inequality which i call the basic inequality which
reads as follows and then we try to read off from the basic inequality what
can see
the basic inequality here is kind of prediction error exp hat minus expletives zero how
well can i predict the true underlying regression surface
you scale it is one hour and that's not important so you take euclidean norm
then there is actually an additional term is less or equal than something
i will discuss this here below
and here comes this other terminal at that time the l one norm of the
true underlying parameter
OK this is kind of really the spirit of the whole as the game you
say OK if my truth is sparse if they the zero is sparse
then it should work and what means inspires sparse
actually reduced the last typically means sparse respectively l one or because this is the
normal to the regularisation
OK so what you have in mind is actually
they zero one norm is not that large spas
so this term is kind of small
because you believe
that year truce sparse if it's not sparse hopelessly lost you can not do statistical
inference in a non sparse problem
OK so the basic inequality is really trivial i just want to give you
an idea how trivial it is so first of all you just write down the
different using the definition of the last so you know
it minimizes discrete aeropostale one or so whatever the data happens always smaller or equal
to use any other value fate now the other value of pages spectral one debate
OK and then i just this term
this is made up y x beta zero plus eight phelan you pick it apart
you rewrite this term you have here prediction error in comes the ceylon
and then comes this additional crossair to through very easy to do
and then on the right hand side we write if there exists long just you
squared two norm and then you plug it in
this can solve
and you end up with this basic inequality very simple just uses the definition of
the class
if you want to do some theory about linear models and i mean all other
models generalized linear models additive models multitask models it's always the same game going on
so we need to say something about this to this crossed
and the other one just sparsity will do it for us
so this is the main thing
let's just do it in the linear model
here is a very simple but actually quite sharp inequality so here is my
cross terms and this is trivial but this is just a
triangle inequality so you can bounded
you just take that part and you always wanted to do something with the l
one norm because last is a one
guided methodology
so here you have the one norm this will be hopefully small if it had
to do a good job and then you have to use other to two times
the max
over these variables which come from its transpose sticks
it's very easy to write down
OK now comes the trick
and i mean all irritations at least what i see do this trick
he say
let's take the probabilistic part decided separate the probabilistic part the right stuff
from the more analytical part which i will discuss
so what you do is you say OK
here this guy let's just look on this set
of events that
kind of maximum here is small
let's look at the set
two times the max here of this is literally for in a lambda zero and
lambda is sometimes called the noise level of the problems
OK this is the probabilistic part of the problem then you know this article is
lambda zero
so ontologies is really two why not going into the details
and then you can come up with this on this table
which will have high probability travel just argue you have this inequality here so you
have your prediction error scale even something more than here's something and again if they
to parts with respect to the one norm
it is a small number
so in a way this is just
the train arrived just take it apart and now i need to say something about
what is the probability forty six
and this is really how current theories going
so i need to say something how should we choose to land here
if you look for land the beginning to land zero so i need to say
something about how we choose to learn the zero
and i want to say something about the probability forty six times
OK to
heuristics is choose lambda as small as possible right and you make this error term
as small as possible but there is a trade here lambda shouldn't be too small
if i take a very small don't have to build large into lambda zero effect
pick lambda zero
now four of how they look like
so what
about the same
so that they have a problem with the help of one of k
and the parameters here
has to be posted but didn't need not sum to one this is how people
when the output of one
the dirichlet
distribution with all
with the parameters of one
simply if you a
uniform distribution over the probability simplex
so this is in the case
when he goes tree
and you've probably is fact each vertex corresponds to one
and if i
each and
each point within the triangle corresponds to
it's a pi factor and this i that they would have
value which is a lot
o or one
so it is the one who is three i think that would mean that i
want is pretty big
but i when i feel pretty small
when the parameters of the tree they
all of the one
that we can all get a little bump in the center
and the like
so these are the very david cameron who
this is the duration of the parameter five
you can see that the but
more concentrated around
around the the
the size of the parameter corresponds to how concentrated its
it's the the distribution
when you have a problem
and this is why i i who
the bomb help shift around this simplex
and if the permit is less than one
so that
instead of
now concentrating around a little boy
all the math counts rates
and the cluster around the but this is
so that's what the distribution of the black
so this
interesting properties of dirichlet distributions which is useful
in terms of
i dirichlet process
the first one that's what i call an agglomerative
property of dirichlet distributions
let's say that i want your i e
is drawn from one iteration with the help of one of our key
and you pick
one and i two and add them together
this factor
which belongs to the k minus one dimensional probability simplex
the thing
is it is also a dirichlet distribution
but with the parameters
out of one of the added together
and generally if we have
i want to i j if you think the partition of
the should
is partition of one k
then we start
for each but that it l
i one
the sum all the entries of high i within that subset
this thing belong to that
j dimensional probability simplex
and this thing
we also dirichlet distributed with the corresponding parameters some together
it is an important property of
patricia distributions which would be using them
so the contents of the agglomerative property is one
is that semantic property so
in the case of the agglomerative property you pick who components of our
of all back up high and we add them together in the case of the
estimated with within one component of the vector and we into
and the way we split
is as follows so
again we assume that i want to i is usually distributed with the parameter
independently the
how long how cool from a dirichlet
from a two dimensional grid
with parameters given by
two tablespoons
his hundred and eighty
i needed to know more
for this
and so i had to do my own homework on it
the least you see here
what this character can do for you
so you hundred eighty calories two people's tablespoons of put tablespoons very low fat
and the rest may interest you
before you use it
i had no c one
which i calculated and measured it
in fact
what kind of demonstration i will be doing today you can
the right but it's very strongly temperature dependent
could be different yesterday from today
i measured c two two reasonable accuracy
notice that the density
of the
in terms of kilograms per cubic metre is very close to see two i mentioned
very close not exactly but very close
the steel ball bearings have a density of about seventy eight hundred
cubic meter and i'm going to drop in that carries zero
four ball bearings
and they have diameters of an a challenge
o five thirty seconds three sixteen
a quarter of an inch
and what i calculated
it was the
terminal velocity as a function of radius
all these ball bearings
all of this is on the web
so what you see here it is a logarithmic plot this is the log scale
and this is a log scale you see this being
and he was you the is in meters of the ball bearings
and this
is my solution to equation number one
when i substitute various values of in there i get the terminal
speed like this
and this is the critical
speed which is as one of our relationship
if you look at these black dots here
then the terminal speed is ten times larger year
then the critical speed
and so i noticed that when you are at speeds above that
the during
exclusively in domain two
and your terminal
speed is proportional to the square root of the radius of the ball bearings
black dot is a factor of ten below the critical speed
so you see when you at low speeds when you work here
you see that you fall into exclusively in two main one
and you see that the terminal speed is proportional to our square this slope here
plus two
this diagram in this slope here
this plus one half
are ball bearings all year
and so we are exclusively operating in regime one with viscous terms
now you could say well what is the meaning of this critical
speedy here if they never reach that speed any out
this critical speed for small ball bearings would be some hundred meters per second that's
about two hundred miles per hour
there's nothing wrong with injecting
a ball-bearing with four hundred miles per hour into
this era in which case
if you inject it with four hundred miles per hour you will be above the
speed and so
for a short while
what emotion b
controlled by
the pressure term but of course when gravity takes over
you ultimately end up
in regione
but that's the meaning of the critical velocity if you could give the ball bearings
such a high speed
the two terms i
equal that's all it means
very well now we are going to
look at the the various
ball bearings various sizes
i'll show you how we do the experiment you will shortly see
a on the screen there
seven marks
which are one centimeter apart
there in the liquid one two three four five six seven
here is the liquid
and the ball bearings drop from above
when it reaches this line i will start my time
and when it crosses one two three four when it crosses this line
i will stop my time
each mark is about one centimeter apart
so this
is a journey of about four centimeters
and we'll measure the time it takes to go from here
here and the terminal
is given
clearly regime once you see the terminal velocity
not at the time that it will take
is of course this this and let me call it
ball bearings travel
divided by t
terminal velocity
and that is proportional to jue in which she was
by one of our scripts
now i will give you the
not the radio but i'll give you the diameters of these ball bearings that's the
they come
so we're going to get a list here
of the diameters
of the barbarians and the amateurs is in inches
i smallest one has diameter of and a two minutes
that i have
o five thirty seconds
i have three six things
all the things come inches that's one of those things
and i have one quarter inch diameter
if i plot here plot if i give you here the diameter in terms of
one thirty seconds of an end
and this is for
five six
and eight
if the time that it takes is proportional to one of our school and it
will also be proportional to one over the square score that's the same
what i'm going to plot
is not
one of the squares but to get some nice numbers
i'm going to plot for you
hundreds of these grids
well by d is then in these units one thirty second of an inch
and that gives me some nice numbers then i get to six point two five
i get the four point
zero zero you can see a hundred divided by twenty five
is exactly four
i get two point
seven eight here and my last number is one point five six
and now i'm going to time
and my timing uncertainty
it is of course dictated by my reaction time
that should be at least o point one second
however you will see when i reach the quarter inch
ball bearings that goes so fast that my ever could well be tens of the
second goes in the flesh
i would allow you to tens of the second
and here i really don't know maybe one one-tenth so maybe two-tenths of a second
gives you a big negative term low energy that's good is happy network
so happy networks are ones where
the binary is an on the positive weights between
one nice property of this is if you differentiate this energy with the rest of
the negative and she would like to wait you just get this product of states
so the jury is very easy to manipulate the energies
by changing the weights
those are the derivatives
and that
and we want to do is
change the way to change the energies to change the probabilities so that the log
probability of the data is high
so for joint configurations
the visible hidden that
the probability of the joint configurations for e minus the energy if
you run the net in the right way
so if you take one of these nets
and i just go backwards and forwards
updating all these units in parallel and updating all these units in parallel
using the the majestic to pick binary states
then if i don't have this week what's called equilibrium distribution or stationary distribution and
in that stationary distribution
it will be sampling
during vectors in proportion to e to the minus energy
so learned you ones will be some a lot
so the probability of
during that will be e to the minus its energy
normalized by
the same quantity over all all possible pairs of the visible and hidden that
and if you want the probability visible that
just marginalize out age some lateral h
get that
so rose to learning we just need to
take logs and take derivatives and now we can just all the weights to change
and is the appropriate way
and when you do that
you very simple learning rule
so what's nice about both machines
this stuff was only discovered a few years later by people doing maxent
run this markov chain where you start with some data
you activate the hidden units use
reactivated the pixels from the hidden units and you go
exports until you reach equilibria
you could take a long time
and you're getting fantasies from the model that is the kind of thing the model
believes being generated and this completely forgotten where it started
that's the definition of
and when you show your data
you measure the correlation between
the binary states
six thousand buyers states feature detectors visible units and units
that zero here means when you showing your data times zero in this markov chain
and the angle brackets just physics for the expected value of
i don't like using because i can't even manage
you do this measure the same statistic
when the model is sampled from the things he believes in
and hey presto the learning algorithm is
if you want to maximize the log probabilities well that
measure the statistical the visible that the prime here
and these angle brackets are kind of average over the noise in these guys
and the same statistical on the models of the program
that is
the derivative of the log prob
so we got a very simple and will
and its local it only depends on
the behaviour of the two units of the way connects
which is quite surprising because the derivatives here
depends only on the weights in the network
but its dependence on all the other weights in the network shows up this difference
of correlations so the process of settling to equilibrium
it's kind of propagating information around the net
in order to produce these statistics and those statistics are telling you
the telling this weight w i j
everything you need to know about all the other weights
so is in backpropagation explicitly by the chain rule going backwards
this just runs this
also gibbs sampling and that somehow gets the information to statistics
this rule we figured out the general case in the
early eighties
and then i thought this kind of that was very interesting because it's only got
one hidden layer with no connections between them
this just the sort of boring special case
many years later i maybe got million times as fast
so the way making a million times faster service
instead of running along change in equilibrium
one hundred steps
you just go on and off again
that is not actually quite the right algorithm but it works quite nicely
there's a post writing maybe today
tony conditions under which it doesn't work there's all sorts of conditions you make this
graph but what
when i say
so you got you come down you go up against the new measure the difference
in these statistics
and sort of what you're seeing is what the statistics are with data
and you seem sort of the direction in which is heading is it goes towards
equilibrium and how this this beginning to change the model gets to have a say
about what should be going on
and that difference is enough to allow you to do learning
so and we'll see later a much better justification for using this
because you more insight into it
and this is very justified when the weights are quite small
but we can substitute the learning allows infinity here
for this little c to go up down
so now that goes a million times faster reasoning is a million times as fast
is because it's a hundred times less computation
and it took me seventeen years to think of it
and in the seventeen years computers got ten thousand times faster
it was very important to take a long time to think of it
so i'm going show you a little example
where you take some little hundred digits
you have only fifty feature detector neurons
you start off with all random weights
right click the detectors you reconstruct the pixels activity sectors again
and you can think of it is
with the data there
every time a is active common with slightly
when you've got reconstructions
every time a pair of the feature vector pixel active you going decrement weights slightly
one way of thinking of it is
i think it gives some insight into what the algorithm that two
the reconstructions
will typically be things that the network is how here where is the reality
the show some reality it represents the reality
then you ask you to reconstruct the reality
and the reconstructed with the sort of surprising corners not off the reconstruct something smoother
more regularly
it's something that prefers to believe
on the training of community consists saying this
take the stuff you'd like to believe
i don't believe it
take the stuff is actually there and you believe it
george bush used to run the other algorithms
what i'm showing you here is the weights the little network like this learns we
show lots of images to use
and so each of these big squares is the a feature vector
and the show you the strengths of the two hundred fifty six connections to the
they are discarded transcription
and this
RNA messenger RNA they can be translated to proteins so when i put an arrow
from the june one to produce one i'm just saying that one gene produces one
and you will see that it's not the direct harold you must first produce
messenger RNA and then this is our messenger RNA is introduced into a pretty
and the genes can
for several point eight
once you have these
protein these proteins can
in fact do many
it can be fine sense here
i'm not designed
specific what they called design
which is going to catalyze
some bioc biochemical reaction
with w one
and with the body that that's transforming into metabolite to
i would like to
by this chemical reactions but also pretty
o point but things can be
can interact with another protein physical interaction and and from the and also called a
complex complex put
and contains our so
very active in a different kind of
activities in the sense
but here
we have we have only
as interactions between molecule between proteins
and was the w h
so what's interesting here
in fact when the seller has to respond to some input signal
for instance the scene and maintenance in which says
i put quotes here which saved now
make differenciation
so so as to respond and as two
how to control in the way that it responds and noise is controlled
is implemented by a network
in fact the network at the level of
gene regulatory network
so genes in fact interact and make possible the production of pertains
but there some proteins interact physically
and this
matrix is called
protein protein interaction network
and of course the
seven hours of live in you
live in being is is alive and their metabolism and they are biochemical reactions this
level which is sensitive
metabolic network
so in fact we have another network which is called signalling
the best way of signaling networks
it's usually the network which involves for instance hormones and different kind of
internet formations that are going to
two BBC news
two proteins
in general all eventually two
thirty two
two genes
but here i'm just going to talk about
gene regulatory networks
protein protein interaction network and we want to go into detail for metabolic networks but
it's also very very important in bioinformatics in fact you should know how to engineer
the metabolism
of the bacteria for instance you can use if you want to to to
to process since your garbage is all you can really engineers some bacteria of all
the small micro organisms to do something for you
so it's really important
to be
two no one twenty to understand to manage with all these three levels
from another point of view
if you know how
the same react
so this is one way to continue when you're in QA and with this automaton
is deterministic
it that it's not a singleton animals set
and yet it has the notion of
nondeterministic nondeterminism so
gonna play with different ones
but we are interested in
given one computer to declare this computation is successful
i would say that this computation is successful
it took several successful it's branch of this country
i'm gonna give you what authority
property the tree automata because it's the tree automata
this is done the definition of what is x what is a successful run
and you put all
i mean
two two
two your quite successful will have different kinds of treatments will have
the moment that whatever and it's always a matter of
looking for
so parity
so i come back
the issue
that's the way you branch a new form a tree like can very e
something which
kind of
as the number two in the states
OK so state
finance state finance set
that's the way i will leave when they find so this is given OK specifi
definition of around
on the
on the example just the formal definition here it doesn't matter
this is what you
about three which causes which is called one zero
i have a in the input
and i have QA
that was my formula
so what i choose
in my in my previous here
i look at it
in my input rate
was the way and this is a
in my examples
in the set
number ten our example had only once one l
because it was deterministic but in general you may have different
so i to pick up and
down in computation
that some
o my lord
and what should be the this
is around if it's away
with states
one of the problems for binary tree
so that
the labeling is locally called ondition relation tells
around finite automata is the sequence
each position
from one state to the next one of functional relation that is given for to
this is exactly justify that is the computation
you have to put some label the full state here
OK alright
what i'd like to do i got a lot of questions afterwards yesterday about continuous
space models of i just that was
i'm done with the thing now moving on to different topics in different topic is
is well it turns out computation kind of matters which may be is not so
you could say the planning is just the convex so what we can do at
this point we can learn very sophisticated models of potentially very very big world
environment but we can't act in necessarily must we can do the planning you could
say plan is just a computational problem is not learning problem but
we can now learn much larger environments then we can plan
that's not good so something we'd have to do something or these models that we
spend so much time learning are useless we can plan
so let me tell you about a trick that p a couple people have used
i've never seen described quite this way before but i think it's a useful way
to look at so yesterday i told you about three classes of reinforcement learning algorithm
policy search value function based
learning and model based learning so what's happening in this case is here we we
search for policy directly
by interacting with the environment here we interact with the environment and learn value function
and the policy is generated from that computationally here we interact with the environment to
learn the transitions and rewards and computationally create value function and the policy from that
OK so that sort of seems to cover everything
but here's the thing to notice
once we have learned transition and reward function o in this computation here's is what's
taking too long so what can we do to make this computation cheaper
well one thing to notice is that this transition in the and the reward function
here constitute like a little many environment like a little copy of the world inside
the agents had
and so what can you do when you've got a world that you can interact
with you can do
reinforcement learning
so here's an approach an odd approach or possibly out approach but it turns out
to be
extremely insightful policy search inside model based methods so
this out of boxes when interact with the world to learn the model
transition model and reward function
then inside the agent's head it's going to interact with its model to learn the
policy so it's doing policy search reinforcement learning all in
mental space
OK to come up with a policy which they can can then run in the
real world
why is agood well some of these policies search methods are actually pretty efficient
computationally even if they're not great in terms of the data we can get all
the data we want now just by querying this model it's this their first day
and night so
so there's one thought and the related that we can go up another level and
OK well we can
user experience to learn transition and reward functions and then
pretending that world is the real world learning value function from and use that i
function generative model
these ideas are actually surprisingly helpful because all the crazy approximations that people have come
up with for doing value function
reinforcement learning and doing policy search we can use them in the context of the
model based methods
all these things are trying to sell the bellman equation but but
this one the what i meant by this picture is just literally trying to solve
the bellman equation strictly computationally but one way of approximating that is by throwing reinforcement
learning tools at just in simulation so it is trying to silence trying to solve
the model these all these guys are trying to solve the model but the particular
techniques that are being used in these boxes are themselves describable as reinforcement learning methods
which just not learning from real data the learning from the model
well there are many
policy search will in this in this box here yes so it's basically you propose
a policy in your head then you run it in your head and if it's
good then you run in the real world if it's not then you change in
your head and then rewrite it in your head to see if you can improve
it so you can do various kinds of hill climbing gradient ascent or other clever
techniques to come up with ways of improving this policy relative to the model
right and then what you have that what you think it's good enough for the
for the model then you release it into the real world
so no additional
real world experience was needed for the tuning of that policy so here's what i
would say is one of the most successful examples of this particular approach which is
autonomous helicopter flight where the outer approaches this model based reinforcement learning in particular
in get all in their two thousand three work i think they've done a lot
of other things with the same idea
the first parameter the model space are trying to control helicopter that's going around three
and they have they know alot about helicopters they just don't know everything all the
detailed numbers but they know that this rotor effects
will call it thrust OK so they have a lot of information about how the
state variable should affect other state variables
they basically had like almost like a DBN like they always have a
and influence diagram but they can exit the different variables to each other but they
don't have all the numbers killed and so they created this
parameterized model and then use experience in the real world to set the parameters
OK so the learning of the model basically fills in the details creating a complete
simulation models
the end up their particular work eighteen actually use
because they didn't have the policy at the head of person fly the helicopter but
not in a way that it was being copied just in a way that would
take it through the state space of it so so that there was enough data
to tune
the model so that it would accurately reflect how the helicopter really works
the resulting model very high dimensional space and action space so to solve it instead
of trying to solve it analytically or with
that can come out from another vocabulary that can come of mexican wherever you want
and then you can say OK for all the cities i want to use these
external URI
and i want to link that to that one in that case the RDF export
everything in the wiki
will be able to say OK
sun is the city
this vocabulary for example
so can reduce external your eyes with in the wiki
you very limited in what you can create basically you can only create hierarchies of
properties and hierarchies of categories it's basically
so nothing more of the ontology and that
o great OK
the wiki already has number of data is available inside
the missing numbers already for populations for example it also has other your eyes go
for annotations
just as an RDF which means that we don't have semantic impact on the OWL
and which may be useful for example to add some metadata about the concept
but annotations are rarely used the semantic media because because most users just don't have
the need for
it is for well for dates for example a see my birthday is on february
twenty seven nineteen seventy eight it has its using a lot of cleverness in the
background to try to get the data out of it it has the back
because it's based on the mice equal data implementation you can't have stated goal before
nineteen ten or something like that so which
it has to be repaired at some point we have actually
because got the patch
for this problem from the most funny of source actually take
there was a community that created the wiki for
creation of some
i don't know if you know what creationism is the belief that god created the
world five-and-a-half thousand years ago
and before that there was nothing and all the things like dinosaurs or
geological features that we think about than that basically about box in science
because you know the world is only five thousand years ago but big and they
had the wiki
three percent in knowledge about creationism and ID and they noticed about the need to
go further back in time to nineteen ten
not too much further back but still so they created the patch for their own
to allow dates back up to five and a half thousand years ago
and then we have to think can make few years more to it so that
they actually created the patch for the whole sixty four
basically forever back in time
and we're still working on implementing the system but it's just nice to see that
sometimes those kind of come in
email is one data type to be used enumeration so you can say that a
property may use should only the following two or three or four values or whatever
just like in our enumeration
the geographic coordinates
lots of questions on numbers we already have pages and other pages and we can
basically identities
strange just
some characters temperature
this implemented because the translation from says to farenheit is not no inflation
text which is a long string for you have
so this is that we don't have extra features for
length order dimension like weights and so on this because this is implemented in the
datatype you can actually tell
it has to be this often number you and it has a unit
and then you can also define within the wiki
that different units can be converted into each other for certain conversion factor
we have the temperature data type extra implemented because it's not what you can do
fahrenheit with kelvin celsius but for most of the other units out there you can
actually just useful in order to become conversion and therefore you can define whatever
unit conversions you like in your wiki
also any new
datatypes is pretty easy if you can you if you are willing to programmed in
so all these other conversions or the conversions two you just on weak interface don't
have to be a problem for that if you want to add further datatypes you
have to be a programmer and that the mean ph
is at different levels that we encounter she m
one of the nice things the whole conversion factors was that there are quite a
number of spend now that are
dedicated to
fantasy worlds of science fiction worlds but they have partially their own
measurement systems so they're not using inches and all meters or whatever but they've invented
the complete measurement system and they can basically had
those conversions to the system and have the biggest building intelligent with it and
even translated two meters and what kind of stuff
in right
exactly in semantic media wiki we made the this
decision and this restriction
that the subject has always to be the page
so you cannot talk about anything else
and it was on page but about was on
that has several reasons
minus one minus one plus one plus one for instance
so do plus one here is
his three we can shatter set of size three we consider any set of size
i can't get all
two to four sixteen
another way of looking at that and here are written in the right way with
with the additional offset parameter theta
is we can directly look at
how many points we can shatter by
by this class of linear threshold functions and you know i want to step through
the proof but it's easy to see that you can show
you can show the points if and only if these vectors of x one minus
one extreme response on this means the concatenation of the vector x one with that
the last component is minus one these that these n vectors are linearly independent
right if they are linearly independent then we can not just get the science right
we can actually get these values to anything we what rogers by inverting this
this matrix if
you know we can certainly shatter set that is linearly independent and you can show
that if there
but if if we can shatter set in asserting independent
but of course that means we can find a sequence of m equal to
the dimension plus one that are linearly independent
and we can now and we can find separate any bigger
so so
n can be any bigger than d plus one
two allows to shut and we can find a basis of that dimension
of this form
right is the direct proof that we can shatter set of
size t plus one but the VC dimension is equal to t plus one in
this case
OK so here is the
so we've seen that if
if m is smaller than the VC dimension
by by definition the growth function is to the end
so it's exponential in m when m
bigger than the VC dimension we get a polynomial rate of growth
of the growth function and this is called cells lemon
OK so
or sometimes called the south sherlock
so here's the VC dimension is not given d
the growth function and
is no more than the sum of them choose
and two xi
so somewhere in two zero up to m tuesday
let me
it's a little bit about why
why this is true
right so i guess in the in the
the original proof that we saw in using this sort of the result we're working
backwards the growth function looks like this you know we have inequality here
the linear threshold functions and you know as a result we know how big n
has to be before we drop below to the end that tells the VC dimension
sounds lemma tells us that in general we can go the other way around that
that when we know the VC dimension is less than some quantity that tells us
that the
the growth function grows no more than
in m with exponent
the VC dimension
OK so why is it true there
yeah i know of
i guess
a quite distinct groups of of cells level i want to show you the the
so this is the shifting the shifting proof
all right at the table your memory i showed you an example of this this
table for the case of a
linear threshold functions on the real line
right this is a table of values of the functions take on a particular sequence
x one through x m
right this is the restrictions of functions so that sequence down here we have distinct
functions each row corresponds to a function from class but gives the distinct signs sequence
right at the next one is minus one if it x twos plus one and
so on
OK so here in this example
there are
just five
distinct rows to the table so the cardinality of the set of restrictions is is
five we counting rows in the table
OK and the idea of the
of cells liver all we're doing is saying if the VC dimension is no more
than d
the number of the rows the number of rows in the table
can't be too large
OK so we're working to see that the number of rows is not too big
and the idea is to change this table into a form that that doesn't increase
the VC dimension
but it's easy to count the rose
right doesn't doesn't increase in summation doesn't change the number rose but it's easy to
counter the rows have been that within the transformed table
OK and the transformation is as follows so
we work column by column
for each column
right we change every plus one minus
if that leaves the row that isn't already in the table so we shifting down
from plus one to minus one everywhere that we can that the doesn't eliminate arrived
from the table doesn't leave us with the right it's already in the table
so for instance if we if we start with the first column take this plus
we can shifted down to minus because we'd be left with minus minus minus plus
plus and we don't have anything like that
we don't have any any rather like that in the table this one is closest
but it's ends
OK then we can take this one and then shifted down to minus plus plus
minus plus because there's nothing
like that in the
in the table
right if this had been a plus then we could and should that one down
because we would be left with the road was identical
so let's just do that shifting down column by column ensuring always that we only
when they when they left with the distinct row in the table
right so here's the transformed table in that case so you know we saw we
started first column we can shift everything down when we get the second column we're
left with the first let's think about that when we get the second column well
if we have to leave this is a plus
right why is that well in the first column we should do that minor so
we had minus minus minus plus plus and we get to the second column we
can change that to minus minus minus plus plus because there's already
row in the table k
so we end up with a table it looks like this
all right so
what can we say about this table
well one observation is that if we ever see
a bunch of classes in road
what do we know
but if i see two classes like this
i know that somewhere else in the table i can change one of those classes
two months and i have to have the road
or i can change this plus two months and i have to have the right
right i can change both of them to minus
you have to have the right
OK so everything so we have this closed below property rights that if we if
we were to shift anything down from here
OK we would get a row that's already in the table
so i didn't mention you know your way through all the columns and you keep
on going until you end up with this table you know with the fixed point
of this transformation OK no no no
no more shifting can be done
and this is the the table you end up with after after that full process
so close that it may mean that you need to work through the columns more
than more than once
OK so
closer to be equivalent using an equivalence
now this atom has to be a predicate
and the arguments of that predicate should be the variables and the constants that appear
in the formula
because i want to add them to have one grounding for each one of the
and the way to get this make sure that have the same arguments on both
other than that the conversion is still the same
now we get to the weighted model counting procedure
what changes here two things the first thing is that we're going to have a
new argument there were passing down the recursive calls to weighted model counting and this
argument is the set of substitution constraints
again this is just as in first-order theorem proving right is either substitutions i had
the constra i have this as a as i do unifications
i have the substitutions that made this unifications go through
and made the
resolutions possible they accumulate as i progressed the inference the same thing is going to
happen here
i'm going to accumulate substitution constraints
a substitution constraints applied to acquire just means that i'm only going to consider the
groundings of that clause there are consistent with the substitution
so if i have something like friends x y
and i've replaced x y and now i'm only interested in france and the y
OK this is what it does
and as i mentioned before we need to consider
and substitutions so we're going to have four types sufficient constraints variables equal to constant
variable not equal to a constant
very equal to variable variable not equal to variable because all these cases need to
be handled differently
and in fact i have a much richer and more compact languages substitution constraints this
is just the minimum language that allows us to do everything that we do in
resolution theorem proving and probabilistic inference
and and then the final and most important changes that now we need to go
to war WMC with them and lift each of the steps
so let's see how we do that
however the base case
the base is joyfully simple to lift
because remember all that we have in the base case was the product of this
over all the atoms
notice that now this is only over all the things that are allowed by the
substitution that i'm carrying around right
i'm carrying a substitutionary
so now i have all the things that are consistent with the substitution and all
i have to do
is instead of being being multiplication
for each at
i just raised this to the number of rounds of the
allowed by the constitution
notice that this this very simple and very innocent but it's a fabulous gain in
because the number of runs of the method can easily be in the millions or
and if we weren't doing lifted inference so basically have to do a million or
billion multiplications
and now instead of being able multiplications i just risen to power
so we want to do this if we can
again if the CNF is unsatisfiable then returned zero obviously that part didn't change the
next part is the decomposition step
now i need to look for u lifted decomposition
what is it to decomposition
it's a decomposition of the set of clauses into remedies are first order clauses now
and the condition now is that it
the two the let's say that the composer CNF into two sub seeing as it
has to be the case that no grounding of one atom in here appears in
right if this to CNS she even one chronicle one at another independent like can
but we can check the condition and if that condition applies again i can just
decompose this into the products
of the individual a class counts and again i can take each one of those
in just raise it to its number of rounds again i'm getting another exponential reduction
in one here but if i have many many many different copies of the same
class i don't need to keep multiplying it just need to compute the value once
and raised to the corresponding
finally of course in the worst case i have to split
and this is actually the most complicated step
what does it mean to split on the first order at
i suppose that i split on the atom friends and x
what this means is that i'm actually splitting on all elements of the
and going on friends and and and friends and above bob and friends and the
so naively splitting on the first part of the atom actually creates an exponential number
of branch
and that's bad news we don't want to do that if we can avoid it
it turns out that usually we can avoid it for the following reasons
is that it doesn't actually matter which particular people and is friends with
what actually matters is how many she's friends with and how many she's not
so what i want to do is i want to count those cases in fact
they may not even all
depending on what my current knowledge bases so now what i have is the sum
of true groundings of the late so i just i took an exponential number of
splits and it became a linear number of splits
and then what i do before i send this overall
like this
and for each of those what why have i have a recursive call to tell
i with the CNF
simplified by setting this set into the corresponding value
and with the with the additional substitutions that i used to unify the set with
the CNN whatever those might be
so this is the recursive call
notice that the most enlightened part however occurs every year
this is the recursive call so i think that the one i'm going to get
is a bunch of these sums right with some of the products from their own
i notice what's happening here right
what i have here
at the end of the day
it's just the polynomial
in the weights of the formulas
that's that's all it is it's appalling
and so this is the minimum you buy and as i do this right so
this is the number of true groundings is the number of false surroundings as i
do this for more and more atoms right i'm just going to get a monomial
with more and more of them at the end of the day the weight of
the monomials
it is just the number of worlds in which that combination of members of true
and false of the formulas
even though this is complicated at some level it's very to intuitive
probabilistic inference is computing the multilinear function
lifted inference computing the polynomial
of arbitrary degree in fact it was could be very high
if you think about it you know doing ground inference is a lot like doing
while not being allowed to use powers
imagining outerwear feedbacks to the ten you have to multiplied by itself n times
well if you have access to the million you have to multiply exploits of a
million times
that's what differences with lifted inference we just you know raise it you know to
whatever it is and keep going
so this is how we have this is the basic schema for how we do
model counting and therefore probabilistic theorem proving suffice it to say that you know this
game as i just showed here you know isn't that efficient there's there's a bunch
i mean this is already a lot more efficient than the in-ground difference but it
can be made a lot more efficient using several things
many of them are just standard things that we can inherit from either improving or
different samples of random information that was supposedly your random number generator basically
that are
on each trial
and then this they did that within the things a story and they have to
do it as little delay and so on and so ten fifteen seconds later they
have to make the next decision
although you may but the the the subject here don't do that
i'll talk about that in more detail in the next study because the next it's
even more crucial
and in the in the next study we had left and right button responses and
you can basically look at
certain parameters of stochasticity of sequential sequential dependence you can for example look at autocorrelation
you can look at the distribution of phase durations is another one you can look
at and it's we chose subjects to be
as close to random number generator as possible so they came in first
we didn't tell them they have to be random we didn't tell them that they
had to produce a random sequence we didn't tell them that they had to match
we told them simply that they could randomly choose the point that they are in
the next experiment what what they freely choose which button which button to press
and we chose all subjects are roughly spontaneously that if you think every person has
narrator which of those of
i don't show any sequential dependence so we we pre selected subjects for this this
you know you got the support that point so looked into this she's and supplement
of this paper we look into this and you can't seventy percent from history
you can do just about fifty percent from the history this would look at first
order correlation for example you can show you can train a classifier on sequences of
its own so many previous trials and things like that and you can buy classifiers
will show you in the next talk of in the next section of talk show
you how this
developed in time and you can also see how it increases with the distance from
the previous trial and this increase with the distance from the previous trials suggest is
not some overlap of information from the previous trial that you're picking up this room
is a very important point where we took particular care to look into this point
in the paper
by doing so
it a
you mean if you take the whole brain as as high as input
he says that's not what we're doing here
i've shown you a single study here where we're taking this will take in the
region of interest in the visual system what we do there is we choose voxels
based on two criteria
a that they're in a particular brain area for example b one b two b
and b are activated by the stimulus
independent independent of
no independent of
independent of the question whether it prefers once the most of the others to despite
look where other voxel stimulus response
without introducing any specific information that would allow you to discriminate
of course you don't have any leakage or pre selection that kind of allows you
to tripoli around this and if you run it on noise stimuli you see that
the the disk the accuracies are chance level and you get a distribution around now
or chance you get the distribution around chance level but we don't use regions of
interest here
this is based on a on the searchlight approach to map the information across the
whole range and then you do a correction for the fact that you're correcting cross
large number of you doing this across large number of brain areas
this is the output we what you get is the output of this is a
tells you
based on specific statistical criterion where there is information
above chance and you get home and it's like you can i mean this is
this is not a three d rendered man but it could show three d man
rendered map we can see exactly parts of the brain but called the information it
is not biased in any way by regions of interest
and that would not be valid and the reason it wouldn't be valid is that
the region of interest would have to come from something specific from some specific reasoning
and the reasoning would be it has shown overall activity for example and that's not
that easy because the overall activity does not necessarily going hand-in-hand with the decodable information
so they can be independent from each other
then you know the difference between function f in RKHS the FOV of its brain
is probably smaller than the number of times the distance between the senate prime but
the distance induced by the kernel
so let's assume that we focus on the notion of small norman
can we say small number of this thing is small then you see that one
of the consequences that at least one of its prime
can be very large as soon as it is close to prime
in terms of the metric induced by the count
so this is something we call smooth smoothness in the sense that
we're not very too much between similar points and here the similarity measure the in
terms of
can i used
so this means in particular that you you might want to to remember
these simple people
having a small on the dark ages
implies sort function with a small number of features
in it is a function that cannot be too much between points and that's when
you can tell whether it is the geometric finer points so it can be very
to merge with respect to to the geometry defined by the kind on the point
but if you example of that
well so let's start with the simplest can only not victoria's
remember that when you you shall space
these are are and is based on torus the simplest and what the known for
can we describe the RKHS and an ontology
and after that the answer is yes
so it is very important because go back to the definition bit of the RKHS
the typical function k chase
like the of the phi kappa psi ix
so if you have a fairly simply side that effects
you that when you some of phi exciting piece
it's intuitive definition of ix OK so called the new the some of the size
at the annual of these would be something like that
so far the RKHS of the linear kernel
is the set of null functions
so you can summarize by saying that an explosion RKHS as the value that is
and furthermore one month of competition can easily show that in fact one of these
is written as the body is
what is the norm in a RKHS of these functions so the solution now is
seen as one point of the RKHS
well known distortion in fact is exactly equal to the euclidean norm of w
the body was seen as a victory so show that you can just go back
to the previous definition of the norm and your directly
so let's see let's look at this picture for instance suppose that piece is just
the real line so you are you making the enoch nl
on the real numbers
what are the functions in the RKHS i said these are the not functions so
we have three not functions
so the horizontal axis is case
OK and the vertical axis is evolving
april three that this question to the functions f of the
two weeks in red for the people you know and visible
these are two and green
these are three examples of functions in the RKHS of these individual on the RKHS
and what the known this function what the numbers to the number of the of
the use of this is exactly the slope here
so the red one is normal to the blue one of one and the green
minimum of twenty five and what the smoothness assumption
well remember that this was the first to do that when the number small the
the those very too much with respect to the metric induced by the kernel so
here the kind of it doesn't do any change in the space is the metric
of the canons just instances and this thing is that if the numbers small
then the function as a small so
OK that's the direct intervention of the archbishop
now you can when the can not another thing is sometimes a bit more tricky
here we just summarize non result i not provide because it's a bit technical but
orthonormal columns that in this case here this factorisation that we're looking for in this
PLSA approach is not really one way let's say the columns here are orthonormal
or are the rose here but rather
we have you know very different types of constraints namely that all the entries are
nonnegative in all these numbers that show up in these matrices are probabilities so they
better be
nonnegative otherwise you know it it's doesn't it doesn't correspond to the semantics of the
probabilistic model and also we have certain normalisation constraints but the normalisation constraint are not
such that the two norm is one but rather that the one norm of let's
say these
here are these here sorry no in that formulation is actually the one norm of
the columns here and the rose here that has to sum to one
right and it again because of the normalisation that's induced by the fact that we
are talking about probabilities here
OK so this has also been investigated under the name nonnegative matrix factorizations by leniency
and others and actually
this gives us a model in this nonnegative matrix factorisation under certain
conditions are actually equivalent to one another
OK so
so now how do we actually learn such a model how do we fit the
the model based on data
we can in the simplest case just to look like lihood estimation OK so we
have all parameters theta and pi and we're given that say just the count the
count matrix n
i mean if we write and what the log likelihood is actually the sum over
all document word pairs
and then we have the number of times that of course of course is that
the euro then
you know effectively that determine the sum does not show up so
you know there's some although it looks really big because it goes over all pairs
only goes over the past that actually have non-zero occurrence frequency
and then here and now we have the log probability
o five
that word given the document as predicted by our model and this is exactly this
mixture formed right so the log of the probability says the sum of his e
and then
here w is e times gives you given d
OK so that's what we try to maximize with respect to the parameters
pi and theta
of course you know this is a
you know this is a non convex problem is had to be expected if we
deal with with mixture problems here
and what we can do the following kind of standard procedure
in dealing with latent variable models is performed in expectation maximisation
or use the expectation maximisation algorithm to perform maximum likelihood estimation and
and if we do that and i actually give the derivation of this algorithm later
but let me show you what is argued amounts to it's also very intuitive what
we get
in the EMI with them we alternate between e step and m step and in
the e step what we do is we compute the posterior probability of this concept
variable given a particular occurrence of a particular word in a specific document OK so
for every word that occurs
we would compute that probability is the probability that word occurrence is related to a
particular concepts and how is that
you know what is that the posterior probability were just by bayes rule we can
write it as p of the given d
OK so basically dropping the w and then p of w given
comedy actually but but because of the independence assumptions made in this model
we can drop the users just p of w given c and then it has
to be normalized
appropriately so that it sums to one if we sum over all possible disease
so we can think of that as the probability that a particular occurrence is explained
why this concept c and you can see that of course if the document is
more likely to be related to the concept the probability will be higher as is
if the word we're talking about here actually has a high probability to express this
particular concept right so that it's is also very intuitive and then in the m
you know so we in the e step we compute the this these red guys
here based on the blue
dynamics which in coming from physics this is a very powerful i
really powerful idea
because i was used to make the ball move basically
in the the disorder in the
on the generalisation been oppose basically per cent in the literature
in particular basically there're some paper by mark girolami on user click food they apologized
we mystical riemannian manifold ncnc
we're essentially what you're let me has done
it bad he's been please propose an extension
of these techniques where on all
the velocity instead of being distributed according to the normal distribution of corvallis independent of
x it's using the geometry of the target distribution pi x you're interested in so
as to essentially make this thing dependent on x on exploit all come up we
basically i reason which actually exploit are much better at exploring the uh
target distribution so there's a lot of the charge in subject
four so there we sense
of the surface story of stone by the mediterranean multiculturism our for yourself to sell
the paper recently developed by so this is not the kind of song about
techniques in multicolored
the last
techniques discuss
he's something you less sophisticated that sort of slice sampling
well i mean to an MCMC things
which basically you can understand even after having been introduced to MCMC only non often
it's called palestine period
OK so proud on
he's basically
what you cannot do
is that once more on the on the notion of basically using aleksei volleyball on
the CI target distribution that was introduced by jerome thompson in the nineties on this
has become extremely popular in physics
let's start with an example so
basically you interest in the prior distribution pi x
OK on this distribution might be
to be high dimensional on my during modelled on is very difficult to come up
with good MCMC algorithm to sample from OK
so what you're going to do you going to do something which is a bit
which is the cornerstone of the calloway
say well OK
it might be very difficult to sample from the original target distribution pi x OK
he might be it it's always much easier
to some poor from the temperature version of of
by of x that is
basically sample from the distribution
i think that has been raised to an exponent which is below one OK on
renormalized OK so why is it the case was simply
so i've got a really warfare
so assume basically
you have a bimodal target distribution that correspond to pi that's OK
so that corresponds to five four one
he's basically you look
at the same target distribution pi x rays to pull if i already normalised
as essentially phi goes to zero is going to flatten
completely the initial target distribution
then essentially
so the distance between the two initial node here is going to come to vanish
as you make the gamma defy the exponent five goes to zero and then you
have solution is much easier to sample four actually
OK so that's still not idea
prior to this idea the something you or you differently here you from is the
real side of instead of comparing that is the raising the target distributions to be
to between zero and one what you can do instead is closely you can raise
it so poor that is
superior to one and you know that as you expand and phi k goes to
then this resulting distribution is gonna concentrate itself on the set of global maximum of
of of by this is simulated annealing OK so whereas and healing what you do
is your the initial target distribution to exponent which are large because it means that
you concentrate the target distribution are on the set of global maximum OK
during the review process nor is it basically sorry you're raise it to exponent which
are belong to flatten it as much as possible because sampling from such a flat
distribution is much much easier
OK so that's the idea of going to use it quite quite a lot of
time later
particle methods that is used quite a lot as well so now what to do
OK so that's not neither side but all use this idea so as to build
efficient markov chain monte carlo
well what you can do is not going to say
is trying to sample only formed by x
which correspond to you in my case two
five p capital p we have introduced this kind of p minus one artificial distribution
you know you're going to be the market share extended space
well known you external the markov chain what does it targets
basically the following in violent solution which is basically the point out of the temperature
target from k one to p
so that's basically the idea is to build a markov chain is going to be
the nc shane so as to sample from this going on to do this kind
of things
hello hello
you can tell everybody hear me with my
so our first like to thank the organisers were giving me the opportunity to tell
you about the area that working on my name is the white a mother gatsby
unit this itself in london and be telling you about an introduction to bayesian nonparametric
i think so
the next week peter orbanz will also tell you about some foundational
stuff on bayesian nonparametrics as well so this lecture will become more introductory stereo giving
you a bit of an idea of how of what bayesian nonparametric models
and then after peter orbanz lectures out a bit more
more advanced models
on thursday
so here is the outline for today's talk first tell you about
some examples of parametric models that you
you put have probably seen final some in earlier parts of the
this summer school
and and then
you feel a bit of introduction of his nonparametrics and as an example outcome go
true in a bit more detail
particle model called infinite mixture model
OK and then will introduce them in
part of this talk which is the dirichlet process
so some examples of parametric models
so i think you guys have seen this carl rasmussen's
talk right so i suppose they want to do supervised learning and we have to
learn a function from some input space x
to an output space y so for example the function might look like this
and we are given a bunch of training data so
x one is here and by one is the high point for example in the
next two and y two and so on and then we fit a function which
goes true
this set of life
so the typical parametric way of doing things will be
let's start with a set of basis functions right so this is a set of
functions which can which describes the basic shapes from which we can be of functions
so then we say that we parameterized function f
of x uses the parameters w some linear combination of the basis functions and here
and of course the parents w and
if just doing something very simple we might say well defined as a set of
such that our
training output y i is as close as possible to the function evaluated at the
training input
x i
and of course we use the squared norm because it's the simplest one and want
to minimize
this quantity over the training set
so this very simple but will be bayesian in this lecture so
this is following calls footsteps so instead i will rephrase this using a probabilistic model
in particular what would say is that our output y i given our input x
y and the parameters w
will be simply
was it will have the mean given by the function evaluated at x i
plus some
absolutely i which is drawn from some girls in distribution
and then i will also place the prior on properties so wk will be some
not some constant will because in distributed with zero mean and some
the variance tempo square
and what we want to do is compute the posterior as if in conflict you
OK so let's look at the form of the function that
the thing is a linear combination of
basis functions
so firstly
what basis functions should we use right so there's this kind of a number of
questions that we can ask ourselves whether this is a good model firstly what basis
functions to use you know you could be using the same gaussian shaped
basis functions that and that basically gives us the assumption that
all functions as small we can use things like that are kind triangular shaped and
then that might give us piecewise linear sort of functions for example
the second question is how many basis functions to reduce so
the it in the sense this number of basis functions kate house is the complexity
class of our
so far
class of functions that we approximating the true function with
do we actually have the belief that
the true function f star
can be expressed
a linear combination of basis functions
for some
a set of parameters w
so this is typically unlikely because
as we know from carl's lecture the typical the true function is typically can very
complicated and very hard to approximate anyway so this is very unlikely that we can
come up with a finite set of basis functions that can approximate out to function
without knowing it
without knowing the true function to begin with
and finally do we even believe that the nice processes goes what
what if we don't actually believe that the nice process goes what can we do
about it
so there no questions about so
we can starting out with this parametric family of functions and these are questions about
whether we want to go beyond this particular parametric family
and of course
because in process is a way of going beyond a parametric family to a non
parametric family
no promontory family of functions
so here's another example
so you want to do that the estimation
so this is an unsupervised learning task now and we are
yes we suppose that some true underlying density f star
this this and this and from which we do have obtained i i d samples
from so this this forms of training set x i so the bots here comes
the i i d samples from after
and what we want to do is to somehow recover the underlying density here after
OK from the training set
again the simplest thing we might want to do is to assume some sort of
exponential family distribution system for example something like cows so this is the because in
parameterized by its mean and its covariance
he has a normalisation term here and then
here is the
everybody knows this thing anyway so
so what's the problem with the girls firstly is union model right
for something like this way multimodal you would you would definitely not be able to
fit the data so you just give it a single bump into still trip
secondly the shape is quite restrictive right so in high dimensions we know that
the shiva because basically looks like
like pancake of bubble bobble simply
are about the people
and of course it was it has things like like pretty elect tales basically as
x goes to infinity then the problem the probability of x goes down really quickly
instead what we might want to do is to use a mixture model right so
we will promote
the density f of x
using a mixture of k different colours in for example
this lecture is going to be a little bit different from the first one what
i wanted this lecture
its cover several topics
which a fairly elementary level in the sense for the important building blocks for some
of the other things that you learn about in this summer school so
while of in themselves they have somewhat limited applicability there are
very important foundational ideas for things like graphical models approximate inference techniques and so on
before i start electrodes with dimension one thing very briefly yesterday i talked about my
sort of personal vision of the third generation of
machine learning based on graphical models and approximate inference techniques and one of the examples
i used was a medical example looking for gene environment fractions in in childhood asthma
this actually is an area in the area of
by medicine healthcare
it is one which i think is is one of the prime target areas this
third generation machine intelligence and it's one that i think we very exciting over the
next ten years and this is one of the reasons why so it's widely agreed
that we're at the beginning of the personal healthcare revolution people differ as to what
form that will take but what are the ingredients is the advent of electronic health
in the UK because of its national health service is actually relatively to other countries
quite far advanced least in in in primary health care
you know your GP or first line position
we already have access to data set about ten million people have been collected over
the last twelve years that's pretty big data set really with the UK's and i
think most countries is fully integrated electronic health records so from cradle to grave or
your personal information is is available to not only two two physicians to experts and
people who travel abroad and so on and together that represents represents a big opportunity
obviously for data mining and in particular for personalized healthcare so one ingredient
and the UK spending about fourteen
a billion pounds of taxpayers' money has made some progress towards this
it's called connecting for health in the UK and most most countries have similar programs
the interesting thing is personal genomic so today you can go to companies such as
the ones listed here and then the drop of blood some saliva on measure about
a few hundred thousand single nucleotide polymorphisms are genetic variations and i'll come back and
i'll tell you that you've got such and such percentage increase probability of getting cancer
or you're much less likely to have a heart attack on the average and so
on all all very primitive i think it's fair to say this stage for a
glimpse of what might be to come and the glimpse really i think is this
that the the cost
the human genome is is plummeting is on an exponential curve but we be the
halving time is not of eighteen months like most laws more like six months
and so while the first the human genome project cost several billion dollars was a
planet wide collaboration there is now the next prize for technology in which the recurring
costs will be just ten thousand dollars to sequence the entire human genome most people
expect that price became very soon the national institute of health in the US senate
target of twenty fourteen four one thousand dollar the human genome so sometimes the next
few years for the less the price of laptop you have your entire genome sequenced
and the question is so what
OK in that
we've got this long history of season and is what does it mean question that's
really that's really the question so by looking at
the phenotype physiological environmental data from health records combining it with the
the what's said to be an explosion in genomic data there's an opportunity to
to realize this personal healthcare revolution to tailor drugs to individuals and in all sorts
of things with huge benefits financial benefits and benefits in terms of the quality of
healthcare people receive but the heart of it of course in statistics we're not going
to build first principle simulations of the human body that would be the ultimate way
of doing this that's not gonna happen probably for many centuries in the mean time
we can look at statistics of large data sets so this is actually quite a
big this the reason i'm mentioning all of this is because this is one of
the big growth areas for the lab here in cambridge we're offering scholarships internships people
partly through the phd for three months and postdoctoral fellowships if anybody's interested in that
instead of sharing that vision and working with us on that please come and find
me at some point during the summer school
all right so on with the tutorial so i said i was going to cover
a bunch of the basic but very important topics to do with with bayesian inference
and i thought i'd start with a little bit of the discussion about why
why bother with all these probabilities at all in the first place
let's consider
an example is hypothetical example puts the numbers in the these numbers are just pulled
out of thin air but so so just take them as initiative not not representative
of the real world
let's imagine we want to build a medical screening system to undertake people emotionally healthy
we want to screen for for some kind of cancer say let's say it image
and one of these images in fact depicts a pre-cancerous condition and the others is
normal in this case it's quite easy to tell apart in other cases it's quite
so what we have is an image
vector x that we collect
from from from the population in general and we want to classify these as either
cancer or precancerous
or normal so that's the goal to classification problem
and so effectively that that's the decision we need to
take an image as input and the end of the day we need to make
a decision either to sell that person that's fine come back in three years for
your next screening or to say something not quite right here would like to do
some more tests
OK this the two sort of possible outcomes
so you could just build some sort of machine which sucks in images the inputs
and spits out cancer normal the output of this sort of decision engine we certainly
do that could be very useful
we could in two steps we could go via probabilities we can compute
the posterior probability
that's a vector x belongs to the council the normal class and subsequent subsequently we
could use the probabilities in the decision steps to make that decision
and seems appealing because the probability is of course tell us whether we very confident
or other machine is very confident that this person is normal or whether i think
something about this course this is a course for non-scientists that portion of the the
enrollment policies is not a suggestion i really don't want science majors in this class
if you are a science major i'm going to notice because that's one of the
things that appears on the class list which are major is so don't don't take
the course of you're science major let me point out that are the freshman don't
have a major so it doesn't matter if you intend to be a science major
if you're if you're freshman if you are science major i recommend astro to ten
which is being given this term i have a little hand out all the different
introductory astronomy courses at the front of the room if you're interested
let's say
it is also true
that this course is kind intended for non-science majors who have a certain basic high
school level
comfort with sort of tenth grade science and math if you're extremely phobic about these
kinds of things i would say
astronomy one twenty while has a similar level of math has a so much shallower
learning curve and is somewhat deeper safety net so if you're the kind of person
who breaks into a sweat when somebody writes down an equal sign check out one
let's see
but that's not the biggest difference between this class and one twenty i think the
biggest difference is what the classes trying to do
astronomy one twenty and also one ten and another courses in our department and elsewhere
in the university are basically survey courses most introductory science courses are survey courses that
cover a fairly wide subject matter this isn't that what this course is supposed to
do is we're going to talk about three particular topics in a very considerable detail
enough detail so that by the end of our discussion you'll understand what's going on
in current research in this topic and by current i don't need this decade i
mean this week astronomy is currently in this stage of very rapid advancement and one
of the things that happened every time i've taught this course in the past is
that at some point during the semester someone will publish some piece of research which
changes some aspect of the curriculum coming waving some paper and everything will be changed
and i can guarantee that of course because i can't predict the future but it
happened every time in the past so we're really are trying to get you all
the way out to the frontiers of the subject
i think this is actually a better approach for non-science majors because after all we
live in the internet age if you want to find out a bunch of facts
about some scientific topic you can go online to go to wikipedia or wherever look
these facts up that's not a big problem the problem comes when there are two
sets of facts which directly contradict each other this happens quite frequently in
in scientific topics these days particularly those with a kind of political or moral overtones
and you get you get facts that directly contradict each other what you're supposed to
do about that
what i'm hoping is that by talking about situations in which the fact at the
moment really are known yet you can develop some skills in interpreting these kind of
contradictory facts for yourself
if you don't do that then the only alternative is to listen to the experts
argue with each other and vote for whoever argues the loudest or looks the best
when they're doing it or has a degree from harvard or whatever it is and
you guys can do better than that and so the hope is that by
practising this kind of scale of evaluating science when the answer is not fully understood
that you can develop skills that will stand you in good stead when you run
into scientific controversies in a political context or legal context or just as ordinary citizens
in the course of your lives
it also happens that the three particular topics i think of some some real interest
and importance in themselves and i'll get to the three topics again in just a
moment here but let me point out that this kind of approach has the downside
to it and this has been pointed out repeatedly on course evaluations because we're dealing
with stuff which ultimately the answers are not yet understood there's no textbooks
there can be a textbook we have figured out what to put in the textbooks
you and the problem for with that is that that makes the lecture is very
important because that's the only information you're going to get there's a whole bunch of
on line readings and stuff but they tend to have a point of view
and so it's really the lectures that are the basis of course
the problem with that is that i've chosen to give this course at the ungodly
early hour of nine thirty in the morning and you guys are going to have
to show up and so here's the deal maker deal with you
your job is to get to class by nine thirty in the morning my job
is to keep you awake once here
OK so if we both succeed in cooperating in this and will probably will probably
be OK but but seriously if you're if you're anticipating regular difficulties in getting to
class this is not actually a great class to take because there's no backup in
the form of the textbook
alright the particular topics that are under discussion i listed them here in green
the first of them are extrasolar planets by which i mean planets around stars other
than the sun it's well known that there are many many of these planets all
you have to do is watch star trek or something like that and you you'll
find many many examples and this has been a staple of science fiction for quite
a long time
oddly enough until ten years ago there was absolutely no evidence for this we assumed
that because the stars the normal starring there many other stars of the sun is
the normal starring there are many other stars like the sun that there must be
many planets of the same kind as the planet and also the solar system circling
around all these other stars but until nineteen ninety five there was not one bit
of evidence to support that idea
since nineteen ninety five this has become a huge growth industry and research we now
know of hundreds literally hundreds of planet all of them discovered in the last ten
years and so this is the situation in which what ten years ago was science
no no we have to what what we what we tried was like maybe taking
different amounts of time
trying to see
how hard that changes and that that didn't change much but we didn't specifically look
at how it evolves over time
so i don't have an answer for that so the only the only thing is
that we find that for for many times
especially like for example for being in the exponent is not
uniform over all the degree of danger so for example in
link in your you get this like sort of three three three
types of behaviour if you have a small degree no you are very sticky
then you and i mean the range you sort of
average to continue for a high degree node again you are suppressed
so we found is that for example especially thinking that sort of three ranges of
the same while in the rest of the networks it seems you speaking at the
same rate regardless of what you
we're dealing with one
he was
so so we were talking to them actually turns out there are people who put
email addresses in the profile and these are people who just want to have as
most things as possible and i think one thing that the person has forty plus
thousand things
that the conjecture is that these people are these people sort of the people that
are very sticky at the people who just getting things and doing nothing else and
they actually put an email that you can even wider
and then the low degree not guys again sticky and talking to them was because
they trying to send the more more reminders about what is going on around the
network to create more edges
so this is sort of two reasons why they are there are more stick it
on a very limited range
here are
o for which
you believe that
well we
that could be the exponential basically explanation could i think that's a good point actually
i think that what is what is
going going to sort of some kind of random surfer type model where like maker
hopping decided could not and continue
and just because high degree nodes have sort of more that's fascinating to them
that that could that that that sort of the mechanism for reference that could be
the mechanism for preferential attachment
but you are more likely to keep on the other hand what is also could
be a problem in our data right is the
the the natural way to close this is by trying to see all these of
your friends created this new french and then you go through them and we can
see that it is exactly creating triangles
so that's
maybe another
another reason why i they is not too realistic
very well
you could actually
they a three
the a
but was
they offer
well there
they were they actually
i think this is an excellent point the reason so to be able to i
think to be able to verify we would have to go
beyond two hops
we could go beyond two hubs because the number of possible that's increases so much
that you can't compute any more
so that's the reason why sort of one of the reasons why we are so
focused on trying to see just because we were able to compute the likely
but i think that's that's a great point and actually we should be
so that is that if you just look at i know the number how does
the k core structure so course so basically you like feeling of the network by
removing clothing he also wrote the removal of the degree one nodes of degree two
thousand see hundred workforce
and i
if we don't release if the community says small then we should see sort
one component and then as as we keep deleting things at some point in time
see a lot of them and then we would be just left one by one
the question is how these pieces are attached to write and i don't know if
it is some kind of threshold or something
because it it's not clear you know is it like to high degree nodes
having this in the lead like
two low degree nodes having these being bridges between the two communities right
four four
four the
she the OK that's a great that's a great point because what we want science
subject right what he wanted to do was this and this is likely remove the
risk strategies which is like the moved see the components are connected by a single
so this is why when you people perform this simple substitution of the two for
the one norm
we're going to have some of the weights which i exactly zero and this
scheme performs of feature selection in that
since has been
very popular recently people just
just use that because some
now i mean
people like
but to decision problems that are well
now let's go back to the zero norm problem
minimizing the one is kind of surrogates to problem we we see that because of
his diamond
the shape
objective we're going to have some ways are going to be equal to zero
but all real objective was to actually minimize the number of nonzero weights
and that's what's called the the zero and zero is nothing but the
number of nonzero weights
as we said before it's and st objective to optimize
so we can replace it by some
more well-behaved functions
and wasn't collaborators have devised a scheme to minimize the objective
and they show that actually boils down to very simple algorithm
you start with some sigma
that all scaling factors
and they all equal to one
then compute the solution of your SVM
on some datasets
and then what you're going to do is going to define scaling factors that are
actually values of your
of w star
and you re-evaluate your scaling factor at each step
by multiplying them by the w star
in absolute values and very easy what you do is that you're going to risk
your input at each iteration
but how important they are
to the predictor
using the absolute value of the weights
and you have some kind of an exponential decay
of those least important features
still linear SVM but it can be generalized to the nonlinear is here
the in a similar way what you do for
recursive feature elimination
in that case you don't choose the absolute value of the w
but you scaling factors that correspond to
the derivative of
you're cost functions
with respect
two the variables
and this can be
efficiently optimize efficiently approximated if you assume that the support vectors don't change
two consecutive steps that is when you remove the future that you're interested in if
you assume that this for the global change you can easily estimate that
but actually
find the original papers the authors only dealt with
the linear SVM
and this is you know
completely straightforward to implement and and a very efficient method
so in summary for embedded methods
and then this is a good inspiration to design new feature selection algorithms for you
know you're all algorithms so for example if you have like you know how to
do it in some question how can we do feature selection for nonstationary process so
how can we do feature selection for this so that other algorithms what the answer
would be that know tried
try methods of scaling factors applied to massive scanning factors in the process of of
this is this is one simple way of doing things
but this is not too far from wrapper techniques and can be extended to multiclass
into regression but they have the advantage that they faster
then the proper techniques you don't have to do with what as many trainings of
of classifiers or predictors
so in other words we're talking about algorithms and
technical things we're going to go into more philosophical things going to talk about the
problem of causality
so far
just said that you know feature selection
deals with removing features to improve or least degrade prediction of y
regardless of how
these are pictures all wired to the target
and i've given you these two examples as the justification why one should use multivariate
feature selection not just univariate feature selection
number to tell you that everything i told you so far was long
and actually is very dangerous to do multivariate feature selection
this is an example from real life data
in which we have discovered when features
and that was very
so discriminant by itself
and then the second feature
that helped
the first feature but by itself was not this at all
this example is an example of mass spectrometry
in which all the points in the spectrum were used as control
the opportunity here is the value of the teacher
so for example at this position here
we have overlaid on the spectrum of one class which are the rights that trying
to speak of the other class the green spectrum so you can see the examples
of the red class are well separated from the examples of the great class using
this particular feature x one
this would be that feature in the scatterplot
there was another hx two
they had been extracted by or feature selection algorithm