interaction is either present in the tree or not you pick some subset of those
pairwise interactions and you get tree and by the way the chain of course is
just a special kind of tree right
so you should think tree is something where you can grab the campaign whole tree
and then a change is just something where hundreds of years i grabbed this tree
no by definition does not allow more than one hundred
because i think i say except us
which which has no
but you could imagine a model in which you have more than one reason that
would be called the force
the also
perfectly valid
OK so i just want to make a point here which is kind of interesting
in the case of trees
undirected graphical models and directed graphical models are exactly equivalent
if i have an undirected graphical model which has a tree structure graph directed graphical
model which has a tree structure will make exactly the same conditional independence assumptions about
the distribution and they parameterise exactly the same family of distributions over the joint so
there was really no difference between directed undirected models and the reason for that is
that in
in undirected
trees the cliques
are all the pairs of connected nodes but you can always make the partition function
one by choosing the clique potentials to just be the probability of each node given
a single parent
there's no explaining away as i said in trees and so on
they directed undirected models are exactly equivalent in the choice of the route is arbitrary
when when the trees are fully
so another characterisation trees is that there is exactly one path between any pair of
nodes with without retracing her steps
that's an equivalent characterization
the tree grass tree structure
so that tells you how to characterize
so i am going to
just skip over
some of the mathematical
slide here
and then tell you the result of learning in in trees which is sort of
two part story has a happy ending but the the
the story starts with the likelihood function
and what you notice that if i told you the structure of the tree
maximum likelihood estimation would be easy but you already knew that because you the maximum
likelihood estimation in any directed acyclic graphical model if everything was observed is easy you
just take each node and all of its parents make the graphical model you do
maximum likelihood learning each of those many graph models here it's really easy each node
and all the parents just each node in one other wikipedia has only one parent
so you have about graphical models who nodes and you just maximum likelihood learning in
each of them
now the trees on the one example
we can go beyond the maximum likelihood learning and we can use structure learning in
trees as well
and and so i'm going to just trying to to give you a flavor of
of that about so this is just the maximum likelihood estimation given the structure of
the tree is easy actually a special case of the result that
we solve
and now i want to tell you about this amazing results of challenge you
in nineteen seventy four
which showed how you could do optimal structure learning in tree structured models so
we shall and we do they said well
let's assume that you have a set of random variables and you want to model
the joint distribution
and you want to model for the joint distribution to be a tree structured graphical
so there will be some groups which
as it turned out
arbitrary but just for now imagine that you have some room and each node has
exactly one parent and given its parent has the conditional distribution of over time
and they said
how can we
learn not only the maximum likelihood parameter is given us
a particular tree structure but also the best possible tree structures
for that reason remember so i give you some observations and you want to learn
both the optimal tree structure and once you have that's really the optimal point
so it's like
are we going to do what you have to decide what we have to decide
which nodes are parents of which other
that's the basic decision you make
and in full
you could search all possible combinatorial structures
you could consider every tree for each tree it's easy to find the maximum likelihood
parameters evaluate the maximum likelihood parameters by the likelihood of the data to try and
extreme heat the true because like
how many trees are there on n variables
OK lots of pretty good answer to the question about slightly more precisely
in fact or
you have to make it
essentially a permutation of each of these which apparently comes before you
it was
is there a better way
then searching all possible trees because clearly searching all possible trees is intractable and it
turns that that the answer is yes
learning the structure in tree models can be converted into good old computer science problem
which is called maximum weight spanning tree
so this is a very nice example of the fact of the sort intersection of
graph algorithms and probability and statistics that particular constraints statistical model
for the distribution of a large number of variables
and we're going to find the optimal model
by solving what appeared to just be an arbitrary right
i'll tell you kind of what the answer is
and then all try and develop
just very briefly
the it's
the following
the answer is no
you rewrite the likelihood function
so that
he has
the former
l healthy the
some of it has you can imagine into calling for a sum over all pairs
of nodes i and j
time so
function w x i x j
which you can compute just
and are you
whatever it is given a ranking of all the objects
right this is highest this one is first recorded this discarded and this one is
lost the card is discarded
OK when you get to know what it's always put in the beginning and then
one of them is the last is discarded and the this
we had a mass algorithms to combine the weights of the experts now what we
do is we combine
two ways
the rank we combine the rankings we do weighted combination of the rankings we do
it in the following way
so this is the map this is the
the priority producer
from the weights and ranks by the master policy we compute
a weighted combination of the ranks
all objects in the virtual in the virtual caches
some over the weights and that's the combined waiting and then we sort according to
and and that's the rank
the master rank
so ideally what we want is to get the master rank
we want to take our cash to be just the beginning of that this is
a capsized and this is sort of our ideal cache
so it's the highest ranked objects comport
according to the combined rankings
nine the expert on and up one ranking so in it's kind of it
you know
the real thing
ten one
so the policy is the following week he
our real cash
he would do
the target cash the cache and then that means of course we have to refresh
constantly all the objects that are in the semantic difference this causes too much reverting
they too much
you imagine or
the lowest rank are objects are discarded
and need to make rule
because you need to make a rule
you whenever you
get somebody new
just to throw out
the lowest ranked objects were ranked now is the combined rank
now we have no revenge
that of course means that
the real cache is going
right behind the ideal cache
this is the ideal cache is based according to the combined rank the real cash
because i don't do all the time
he is very lazy leveraging
based on demand
the two catches i never a fancy way to do it would be
in practice what happens
you the system is either a lot
you want to use the ideal time to sort of
do some brief
so how do refer objects
you read
you read should i checked
that is in the semantic difference
when the system is i am now how much idle time well simulated that pass
on process
we model illness
this way
and we prefetch most people the objects in the symmetric difference
so in these large
we present a lot when is small detached revenge very little
one more trick we needed
what new if this is
there's a bunch of datasets huge datasets we have been benchmark datasets for this kind
of thing
caching studied law
what happens is if you look
of the master and see which objects
we're here
one in the top hit the most
most hits in the real cache have high are ranked so
we only
reef and we read french but only
top forty to sixty percent of the are ranked objects we don't aim for the
ideal cache
we don't aim for the ideal cache we only aimed that we have the top
so that's an additional trick we need
and then we
and we can start here a bunch of datasets huge datasets
they from some kind of simulators
the CMU
if this would be the
in the network and how they communicate which people we should vaccinate so that the
the network would get completely resistant toward certain disease
and so
so this is
by prof analysis type of feature which we would like to know about certain network
and what we know about the real world networks of the social network service silent
two but a random attack so that's a random attack could be
so i was checking this this ice-t closed collaboration effort so
the question was the following karl
the average that's between
other institutions in europe will change if you remove fraunhofer doesn't change much
obviously this would be a big loss for europe and so on but actually research
would still continue
i wouldn't of
but let's say it's interesting
if you have that's a society are system social network if we remove just the
top notes
this and so a certain amount of top node then the the network the dissolves
so we know this let's say that from the wars usually if somebody well in
the past effects the country and then remove the top of the society than the
rest of the society kind of
fell apart from this sort of the same with be we that let's see if
he would remove all the web pages we do degree more than five
then this would be enough to disconnect the web
and this is a very small percentage of web pages with a degree
more than five
so even if you would have let's say a random network on the social network
with this week's and so on random networks so much much better results with this
targeted attacks
people will be
randomly interconnected then
basically you cannot really grab the networking in such a way that you would destroy
this would be extremely useful they are useful
i don't know the communication people
you know
as long as the
a lot redundancy you can say that the redundancies c store in in in in
this additional additional links can do
the question then a common problem
OK let's keep this motif so basically what motives would be just templates which you
can spot in certain networks and based on certain templates
of various shapes then you can you can infer certain properties of certain communication so
that even with study email graphs then probably some bitterness with what appear in the
shrinking diameter so this is something which which is also not so intuitive but interesting
so inclusion intuitively we would say that if the graph grows so the network that
princess will grow and
the the diameter of the network would also grow and so the question is let's
in FP five with at other so many new projects in new institutions whether
diameter with shrink or it would grow so intuitively i would say probably growth but
usually is that because
we have this social phenomenon
so that people get interlinked and actually the diameter decreases so that we can spot
now after so this was part of this analysis which i was doing for european
commission so
f before at six and FP seven so has much smaller diameter so let's from
four is much closer to anybody has now been inactive five days because we all
know about this cliques in stable stable partner linkages let's see in european projects and
so this is kind of effect which we can spot also another networks not just
in project collaboration also in other social network
this would be
through that's only thing that this would be through citations and so these are actually
experiments which confirmed from this we
i would say that the
the human population growth
you can always form
you can always former network or local law growth which which with respect this
for sure but on average so that there was a couple of types of networks
which collects we're testing so including internet and scientific citations which are quite
well i mean i would say representative networks so that in these networks of
the diameter was actually shrinking
OK now i think the last topic of this features before this application so what
so before i forget
i mentioned this at the end of the
no i mentioned the discussion section i guess two
two days ago
but so many of you may want you to see that but this is the
this is the web page
on which i collected together a number of things including the
files for the lectures that i'm giving but in particular i wanted to point to
these homework problems here so these are the problems are are taken from the university
of london course that this is all somehow coming from
in particular
for this problem she numbers seven and eight
if you if you look into these sub directories here what you find is some
and if you if you look at these programs and look at the nodes in
the problem sheets themselves it will tell you how to
right little c plus plus programs that use classes from the room library that will
allow you to do a number of the things that we're discussing in these lectures
so it will allow you for example to come to generate random numbers using the
monte carlo method it will allow you to
training use various multivariate classification methods which is something i'm going to talk about now
just in in the hour that follows
and it will allow you also to do simple fitting exercises using this program called
mean we many of you have probably run into mean we in one form or
another so i just wanted to point you to these
software tools
because i realized when giving these lectures i'll talk about this is that statistical method
and mister that's all very nice but it's a bit abstract how to actually go
use that but if you go looking at these programs and play around with and
then you can find it you can actually make use of these methods in
in a real practice
OK so let's go on now out
the lectures and two days ago i we had talked about the monte carlo method
but there was just a few small comments that i had not
but i didn't have time to make
so we had talked about for example the transformation method and the acceptance rejection method
which allows you to create this sequence of random values that follow some distribution
so that was the final i think that was the last slide i showed that
two days ago that showed this example of the acceptance rejection method
but now
i wanted to then say a few words about how
the monte carlo method is is typically used in particle physics and they really so
hard to main areas where monte carlo is used mainly what are called event generators
and the detector simulation
so let me say just something about event generators what that means is that you
you select physical process that you would like to simulate so a simple one would
be the plus minus goes to mu plus new minus and figure out what are
the kinematic variables that would characterize the final state of that process well this is
hardly a two body final state so it's very easy because by the time you
throw in the energy and momentum conservation the entire final state is characterized by two
some sort of scattering angle and some sort of azimuthal angle the angle about the
the collision axis
so then you say are you go to your your friendly
theorist and you say
what is such and such a theory predicts for distribution of those variables that characterize
the final state and there will be some probability density function some joint probability density
that characterize say
the cosine of the scattering angle or the the azimuthal angle
and in this case if you have an unpolarized diplomacy minus being is particularly simple
the the
the azimuthal angle phi
it's simply uniformly distributed between zero and two pi
and if i take as my random variable the cosine of the scattering angle then
it follows the PDF kind of like that it's got one plus some coefficient times
cosine data plus cosine squared OK so so you go from your theorist two
writing down the probability density for the variables that characterize the final state
and then you simply use the monte carlo method to generate events that is to
say to generate values cosine theta and phi and then you can regard those somehow
simulated events
that's a very simple example and there are obviously
far more complicated examples for example proton proton goes to hadrons instead of just having
to simulate two particles in the final state maybe you have you have hundreds
and even in plus minus custom you possibly minus by the time you throw in
all of the radiative corrections and so forth it can also be very complicated beast
and so this has become a big industry among phenomenal just to write these
event generators that can simulate these these events so you i'm sure you're familiar with
programs like here and here we go in there are many others as well
the idea is that these are monte carlo programs whose output are are events their
stimuli for each event you get a list of generated particles and their momentum vectors
and and it said you know what type of particle is generated
so there's
accuracy with high probability
not surprisingly if we want to have some kind of down the overall failure probability
the whole learning algorithm is low
it's going to have to estimate the probability of failure any the component is going
to have to be much lower than that because all the component all the things
it has to estimate have to be correct for the overall reaction to work so
the papers to talk about this stuff goes through the derivations and say exactly how
those quantities relate to each other
that's a lot of uses of the union bound for example so if you want
to you if you want to the
the group to succeed then you have to make sure that
well you do you do that make sure that each component succeeds in you estimate
probability the failures being the son
which is a little over conservative but
it gets polynomial bounds
the bounds tend to be really i mean like you can see with one minus
gamma to eight and things like that the bounds tend to be really
not useful
in the sense that the number of you literally look at the numbers they give
out it's like oh yes yes you have been all you have to do is
learn for seven
seventy two trillion trials and you'll have an accurate estimate but that so in practice
we don't actually run that ended it seems like it this it seems like it
tends to work fine with
much smaller numbers but the analysis does seem to lead us towards
the useful algorithms so
even if the numbers on exactly right the overall framework seem to be right
yes some so we're not
we're getting away from that here because now the bound if you actually look at
the general quick based learning algorithm it ends up being a polynomial in the number
of i don't knows that the quick algorithm makes
as opposed to the number of states in the world
so that's a big advantage that there's something you can learn faster than
separately estimated quantity for each state then the learning actually ends up happening faster
but we're not quite there yet so here's an example of using
max and robotic example where we discretize everything so it looks continuous but we're not
treating it continuous this is a sony aibo wearing a fetching rasberry beret
and green fanny pack so they can be tracked from above so the state information
is the position orientation coming from an overhead camera and is trying to escape from
the box
its actions are
forward backward turn left turn right kind of sidle left inside all right
and it takes a while for to learn about all
four thousand states in the world
but it eventually learns enough that they can get itself out of the box so
we compare this we can compare this to q learning because that would have been
o would put the robot risk it takes a very long time for children to
learn the robot but we did something similar which is we learn model but we
explored by taking random actions occasionally which often how q learning is implemented and it
just it is a lot slower would taking random actions in the beginning is really
bad because it doesn't know anything yet and should be taking
it should be trying everything
sorry taking random actions biased towards what you think is the best is a bad
idea because in the beginning it should be biased and in the end it should
be very heavily biased towards towards the
for the actions are actually correct and armax more less does that automatically because it
it's making decisions based on how many times it right actions in each of the
states of those things that hasn't tried yet it actually walk all the way across
the world to try
right it's not waiting for some random sequence of events to happen to get into
this new situation much more direct
what is the
don't pay attention to the
actually don't worry i don't remember this these are these are unpublished results so we
never really quite clean it up but it's supposed to be
trials otherwise is three thousand i think it's steps like actual robot
the average number of steps
to get to the goal
per trial
all right but this is not generalizing transitions and also list let's start talking about
what does it mean to start getting away from detailed information about each separate state
to start generalizing across states
OK so
the there's lots of ways we can do this on the talk about several of
them the very first on the talk about is a simple kind of merging of
this kind of this robot example with simple
graphical model representation so here the basic idea is similar similar to show you some
of the robot has to the previous one where there's a will there's a sony
aibo it's got its position x y and its orientation data but there also in
the world of ball all the just kind of wobbles around ignoring the the robot
but it gets in the way and we have a penalty if the robot comes
in contact with the ball
it doesn't literally heard it
because that would be that would be wrong to look at the great guess but
but we do give it a minus one which is really just as bad and
what it's trying to predict from this is the change in the ball's position
the robots position and the robot orientation and what we do is advance in this
case we have the grandson who built this created a little independence model that says
OK the ball's position
that seems wrong
so they get the estimated model and then i broke it
which the i think this editor
is what we want to fix
the part of
the bottom opening and then just go away let's talk about that so so
the ball is the ball really is just independent just moves around so the ball
position should only depend on the ball position this is this is how the variable
changes as a function of what it is now
that that seems right
the robots x and y
do should depend on its orientation
i guess it depends on what action we're doing turning versus going straight
but i'm going to say maybe this and should be reversed
right so the robots orientation impacts its change in position and orientation
but the robots position only affects its exposition so this is for something like that
like turner straight
art anywhere
the point is that we don't have to estimate the full cross product of influences
between all the variables and how they're going to change in the next time step
we can factor the mountain this way and then each of these pieces so where
the parameters here so we need to estimate how the ball changes
as a function of where it was
in fact i think we ignore that we just say
the change in the ball's position is independent of its current position
right it's new position depends on the opposition but change is independent the robot x
and y coordinates the tree the change in the x y y or don't
have any of that are not affected by where it is
because there's no obstacles or anything in this world than the ball
and that only has an impact on the reward anyway so
so this picture i think you should just ignore that picture entirely
it is used to bear no relation but
because something like this
so what i find beta j so i have two linear combinations of kernel functions
two different linear combinations i'm going to assume that all the coefficients are non-zero otherwise
exploring many of the seventies zero we just throw it out
and i will also assume that the players output
the points are pairwise distinct
OK so we don't have reputations of points in all set
so let's see let's see where this takes us to begin to prove that if
the kernel is strictly positive definite then this equation implies that all points identical
so the first thing is will subtract the right hand side from the whole equations
then we get
we get this thing here
and actually that's
we actually do are going to be going to do a proof by contradiction
it so i assume
that there exists one point in the city x
so there's one expansion point on this site
that doesn't occur on the other side
for simplicity let's say is the first point
so the first point is not in set y
so obviously it doesn't matter whether it's the first point to any other point i
can reorder the some OK and also i could do the same thing the other
way around i could assume that the set disappointing the set why that doesn't occur
in the set x the whole proof is symmetric i would get the same kind
of contradiction
so if i can get a contradiction from this assuming the case strictly positive if
and then i know
these things
have to be
so i'm going to just rewrite this quantity here
by i mean there might be cases where points y and points x identical of
assume that within the next step wind pairwise distinct within the said why they pairwise
distinct but there might be a point in the same way that able to points
in the set x and vice versa so let's just get rid of this so
let's rewrite this as
this kind of some
we have introduced a new
coefficients lambda points that i saw in the simplest case these divisions love that would
just be on five for the first points admit minus but i j for the
rest of the points but in some points might be identical and then i might
combine some of them can you new acquisitions lambda
and also these edits in the simple case the first that's all equal to the
axis and the rest is equal to the but some of them might be identical
in general they could be anything the only thing i know this is zero
what do i know about the ties
well some of them might be combinations of ten thousand better so there might only
become zero even if i have solved with non-zero values however what i do know
is that the first one is nonzero
i don't know this i know it because i was assuming that the first point
doesn't occur in the second set and also i know the first point only occurs
once in the first set
these coefficients the first love one is actually equal to have one
OK number want people to have one thousand one by assumption
o is non-zero
OK so i know this thing is nonzero
if the two means identical
so next what i'm going to do is of
take so these are
specific function in my repeated this specific function ri reproducing kernel hilbert spaces zero function
exists it's expressed in this way you know i'll take the dot product
with another function and actually i choose the function
to be this way exactly the same function in this case
i'll take the dot product between this and this and this vector is zero then
the product is zero because the product i barley now
so then what i get
if lambda i lambda j
OK of
i j
is zero
now let's look at this closely for a minute so
by construction
now i compute the i can values of the graph laplacian and what they get
to like it four times
more zero
and then i get again but actually if you look at the scale i mean
zero point zero tools so it's
really a huge gap and can only
imagine that might also go wrong but essentially the ideal case we have to get
here and then you have
near the
the story goes you should choose k four
if we now look get a slightly more noisy data
it's already becomes obvious that it's not so clear so here we have
probably if you look at it you would still say we have four clusters
but if you look at the angle values
OK here's maybe get
but maybe not so this is really and if you look at this here
i mean you can see any capital all just goes up
so some of the idea of this approach is that there are some bones which
this is the ratio cut normalized cut in terms of i but
i actually don't believe that so
that's not i mean if it's so obvious that we don't need to have and
i can get to to find out what the number of clusters is if it's
not obvious
usually does not work that at least my interpretation
so we talk about other methods to
two is number of clusters in tomorrow so if they're completely different methods which are
not particularly i mean this is just designed for spectral clustering of course you can
do that for into
so we will see other methods later
OK now the question is so so far i've presented everything in pretty symmetric way
so you can either do normalized unnormalized spectral clustering
and both of them sort of make sense
now the question is of course with twenty two
and now there this is point strong opinions
my strong opinion that you should always always always use normalized spectral clustering
and there are essentially two reasons for that
there are many reasons but i have only two one slide so
the first documented
well i intuitively
the cut objective function only looks at the
similarity between clusters and says we want the points which are in different clusters of
low similarity
but that's often also should to the other side it's a point in the same
cluster should have high similarity
now one can see that right so if
if one writes what there was in the similarity of a cluster is
this is just the sum of i and j in the same cluster as i
and essentially you can write this as the volume of a minus the cost of
i don't want to go into that's just two lines
but what is clear and then the point is normalized spectral clustering it says we
minimize the cut
minimize those terms
which means we maximize implicitly maximize both of those terms
so implicitly we we maximize
maximize the denominator which is one a so we try to maximize their with similarity
so the normalized cut function you have both objectives first directly minimizes the similarity between
clusters but implicitly also maximizes similarity within clusters
and and this doesn't happen for a shortcut because the problem is that this term
in the denominator
is not related to the within cluster similarity because you could i mean just count
how many data points are all but it doesn't say anything about the connections between
those data points
somehow this aspect isn't taking into account for a shortcut but is with the normalized
so that's the first arguement
there's a second arguement which is essentially my see
which is about consistency so one can prove and i don't go into any details
but if you
so statistically consistency is the question you
OK we we assume we are given we draw data points from some distribution now
we get more and more data points and the question is what happens so assume
that the cells in data points but tomorrow someone gets another thousand another thousand
after five weeks to use some of converge with your customers either doesn't jump from
day to day depending on the number of data points you have currently get completely
different results
the surprising fact that actually clustering is very nice in this respect so it always
converges it always converges also to something which is meaningful
so it behaves in a very nice way
unnormalized spectral clustering can go completely wrong somehow so one can prove that there are
cases where
pretty obvious case something like which i had on the previous slide just four goals
in clusters
it converges to something trivial or it doesn't converted all very
things happen
but so i don't want to go into detail but it's also an argument which
tend use normalized spectral clustering
we will talk about that
the answer is no not
maybe not really
OK so now
the first record
so that was more or less what i wanted to tell you about spectral clustering
but there's another
pretty new approach which does something very similar
which i find also very elegant and i want to present this on a few
slides only
the thing that's just
the way i formulated clustering is we said OK we have those two groups and
the one that
o point between labels for very low similarity
now the question is if you have something like this a social network whatever so
a really large graph
that's why you
but i don't
i'd like to like
and and i'd like to
i think it's
there are far more girls
it was done
and i can
so that
i am
today the
so that
and then also
four five
how will it ever do
and my
thank you
by five
she would
is i
this is
one of
and i will talk about
the future live
x two
one of
so the more common
which actually is not
three rules
and also to about
and if you look just at the five thousand eight and things between five and
small mumford fourteen high dimensional space
now this manifold is important
because it
defines in the high dimensional space the high dimensional space what direction locally important
so if you make a high separation margin but the margins across the money for
interestingly is not the same thing is the margins along the manifold because in terms
number of points that can be mapped from the input space is going to be
completely different
so by making digits that in between five and eight
by randomisation or by averaging
you create new points that are this manifold
and by using this points in the
by basically treating the latent increase retail using these points
you have to take into account the topology of the
money out information from the input space
the high dimensional space
define what the large margin means
does it make a mess of the question
it's possible
prefer queries that lie
between the
so they did not
that is the opposite case
one of the squares but the squares the example of the classes
they're not five and it the something else
you dream
the thing that important the distribution deal was going into hiding in high dimensional space
their condition by the number of transform you go to map the low dimensional
during that in the low dimensional space
the new map data in the high dimensional space in the same way you marked
the real one
so locally in the high dimensional space
this is very important
they're going to tell you
how things we
they cannot be labeled
not exactly because this all the time particularly should be
in the part the corner there should be in between
you can see this is the background class
this class of all the things
that follow the sentence on russian descent kind of
the live in the same space
one represented the high dimensional space
leave with example that interesting
so the distribution and i dimensional space
it represents
the manifold or the
the domain in which you we'll examples i like
and so by doing that
you basically are able
we define large margin with the mausoleum
that's the closest picture i can do in two dimensions taken during one million dimensions
but we can try and three by using the hands
suppose you have something in two dimensions you have examples in two dimensions
and you might them into three
there we go on a long some manifold
just because the transformation of the two-dimensional space into the three dimensions
if it's continues is going to be used
give you a two dimensional manifold
in the on this two-dimensional manifold only
actually examples
and they're not going to be everywhere on the manifold
now you're going to make a large margin separation
in the high dimensional space the three-dimensional space
so if you find the last margin separation that's oriented
across the manifold
you cannot mean the same thing that is is oriented along the manifold
so maybe you should try some drawing experiments talk
this is
not exactly true
because if you're not a low dimensional space into high dimensional space and green things
in the low dimensional space
then this thing you dream that we still live on the manifold
of the high dimensional space is defined by the conformation
is the intervening in low dimensional manifolds
when you mark a low dimensional space into high dimensional space
you cannot mappings anywhere
and so i notified him out them in a place that's
not anywhere
and that's that is the description of the transformation in making
at the beginning of trying to be inspired to see that this is the worst
thing to try and do
i think sometimes
well frequently
you know the learning theory lags way behind the practice and this is sort of
always sort of
difficulty because
it's much harder often to get a good analysis of an algorithm
so for instance support vector machines came out and working well before they were actually
and often you know this sort of
the intuition behind what's going on which people used to design an algorithm and then
you know learning theories struggle on and try and figure out well you know what's
going on why is it working wise boosting doing what's going on
but having said that i think that there is
you know added value by doing that analysis because it does highlight one of the
features that make the thing work
how can they be further exploited or you know refined improved and so i think
there is no sort of something being brought to to the table
of understanding
and in the sense you know its places what we're doing on a slightly more
for scientific footing
so what i discovered was the central result i call it statistical learning theory which
is the pattern
and it has a very nice sort planes
structure to it
characterizes learning and so on
but despite that
as i argued with the case to support vector machines or indeed with boosting it
actually fails to capture what we really are experiencing in the real world and so
in the sense failed theory
but then i showed how learning theories and that the time had come to analyse
the new algorithms for this margin based analysis
and usually using covering numbers
so i gave you quite a lot of
detail of and
you obviously you know burn the candle at midnight try and solve those problems
and then today and moved into the more modern sort of approach is based on
concentration inequalities
and maybe you
aiming to do rademacher complexity which i hope i've convinced you is is very clean
and useful tool
and i've shown you
how we can use rademacher complexity for
classification and SVM
little overview of how it can be applied in kernel PCA have given hopefully
and after the flavour
of what's going on
and you know
obviously the main
achievement i hope is that you can now
you know talk learning theory
speak when you at
two people at the
cocktail party
so that point i think i'll close and just ask questions
and comments that you want to make
thank you
so i
the idea is this works well for me
it's a little bit strange because
he is the number of
i mean the letters we use
don't could it seems that
the larger the this smaller
the problem
the rest
because we use more projections
no because the large we get k this wall of this gets
the second term the second term gets larger is
so we get worse remember this is the
residual is about what we use
so we
use but because the level of the k
the smaller the region is the residual well
not in the new data
the problem of OK i see what you're saying sorry yes there is
a version of about what this captures
OK i understand what you're saying
OK so
as i have given you the version that
perhaps captures what you're saying there is a version that says the minimum
i bigger than or equal to k
with an idea so
what i'm saying is you can
once you've got a capturing of the space
obviously by adding more dimensions going capture more
that's true
but what this is saying is that
if you're in high dimensional spaces and this doesn't fall
quickly enough
before this gets larger than
even by adding extra dimensions you not gonna there's gonna be a significant chance that
your data is not in those dimensions
what we're trying to do is estimated you know even if you go
for more and more dimensions
you are going to be able to capture the new data unless
this falls fast enough
before this gets a
i understand what
this a slight
we had to
so given a real data
which is
i have
ninety of
what you do in life your conclusions
what would you do differently see compared to what is being done
two years ago where people typically will
all these papers that i have to do this in the experiment the values of
and gamma kernels
need to cross validation
and this sort the trial and error
kind of have to move
OK so how would how would the bounds health and with
so you think you media with support vector machines i guess in the first instance
so here's a support vector machine band and the question
is the band couldn't
to allow us to choose c
essentially i mean one
so when we are choosing let's say we want to try different values seen on
support vector machines
we can try different values of c and
the normal way too
estimate which is the best choice is to cross validation
so cross validation is quite expensive because you have to compute the support vector machine
say to fold to do it
ten different training sets and then estimate only the that said
using them equal to about thirty
end during
so next
they predicted
so the construction that was not originally
what was i didn't know was the idea
that such a device
useful very practical purposes
could be used in
given semantically so it
and here is
particular mission which was used for predicted
and here's a counterweight just blocks
the the future
eight of water in the ocean
so it was a very
find mechanics
it is surprising that the person wanted to
make it all made their own hands
just all over them
and the book started
and number fields produced
but it was
there you are
nineteen seventy city
and that is once you don't have switch to
much more important
fuck for
making the
other missions
so to say much info removed that the function
has never been constructed
in this in much of
so the city
approach the same problem
from other direction
he submitted the paper
methods for calculation of the function
but you can see the classical
mathematical methods for calculating the function
what was known before during
there was
classical political information
there was human so-called three months ago formula
following the basic in unpublished manuscripts of three month
and then
these ideas
this idea is wrong later superseded
in particular
the station target
found organism which was
fast and typically many the
function at the same time
and do what they wrote about students message
although one of them is that the size of the
and to the good ones
seem to have been proposed
for computing that office
commodity curious
at large states
name on during
it was designed to produce high accuracy
then we get into by the truth about
on the remainder term in the semantic formula
that able to available at the time
at the same time be more efficient
then there was
very good estimate for the remainder terms
and that in that formula are now available
which seem to make students methods and this and this is
but here
by different methods
the mean merciful calculated that the function
what i meant by the student must is something different metaphore proven that
zeros lie on the critical line
and this message was introduced in another paper
after the war
the paper is organised as a report
about particular inclination
was performed here in manchester
in june nineteen fifty
the manchester university markmonitor the computer
was used to do
some conclusions
concerned with the distribution of the rules of the game under the function
it was intended
in fact to determine
but there are any zeros
not on the critical line and sort particular intervals
it's interesting to note
that the calculations for down and up to me
that is zero would be found on the critical line
and the calculations with the directed more towards finding zero
as proving the nonexistence
it's interesting to
two and q about computer
the computer will probably have his own ideas
that's how
so steps would be done
sort sensor may be omitted without serious loss of accuracy
believe that also
but think still here by the computer
he mean
human being
and then
he wanted to speak about the machine
he used
at the moment the computer
during growth
there is no reason in principle
but computation
should be carried through
visiting the
that useful semantical analysis
the procedure was such
that if it had been acutely fall
and to the motion made no errors in the period
then one could be sure
that no zeros over the critical line
as interval in creation
one with it on the computer
the city it can be rather tiresome to achieve
but in connection with such a subject analytical theory of numbers
but it is in this sense
it seems us
so the question is
how is it possible
that after a finite population
video numbers approximated is
limited accuracy
we can be sure
the zeros lie exactly on the line one half
and such technique was long before during
and i explain briefly this technique and then
explain what
it was new
was what new was introduced by q and k
and the fact that somebody wonderful things
they allow many
interesting things
and for example
you can see that
i don't
and if you want to know how many zeros
lie inside area
we can calculate it
by calculators such a contour integral
what is important
this is an integer
so we need not calculate exactly the integral
it would be sufficient calculated the communities they
and is possible error
one so
then it would just
around is related to the nearest integer
we have the identity of those two spines those two elementary trees
have been chosen
and we the position of
this the junction operation happen so we know the examples and is moving this pp
right here
so the feature vectors could potentially attract any subset of the information shown here on
the slide
in practice we look at features like the following two words
involved in this junction operations
maybe information about the surrounding roads
maybe information about the parts of speech to the to the world's for the noun
in this case
and in particular subsets of the junction operations are these three terminals
actually very useful in describing the grammatical relations in this case of object relations in
this particular
junction operation
so the feature vectors again we can leverage the flexibility
these definitions
including quite features which look at all kinds of surface features of the string
as in legacy of
combined with these junctional operations
so that's more or less it for the whole
so just to survive this up
the goal
system as an input sentence x to a parse tree y
the nineteen forty looks rather similar to see graphs
so they have to parse tree for input
there's not going to parse tree
which maximizes the gain summer schools
but and now rather than associating schools with state transitions associated schools with these junctional
we have some of these things which are said to people
specifying one of these the junction operations this being used to build the tree
so true evaluated by the plausibility of score
of the different junction operations which form a tree
and you can compare this model from here as you can see it's very similar
OK so how does this work
let me talk about some experiments
inference parameter estimation of things that come to next
the training the model we use the averaged perceptron algorithm for the inference we use
passive dynamic programming which i'll talk about
in terms of data out to results on the
and we'll street journal treebank is pretty standard evaluation
method metric
and terms of the evaluation metric is being used we can look at precision and
in terms of recovering fragments of these histories
in particular recovering constituents within these parse trees and rules within these trees
so it's a good precision recall and f one score in recovering these these structures
the main comparisons are made out to
pcfg based models of smoking about these and then we talk about
methods which are based on PCFG is just briefly so we can do the comparisons
so like i said pcfgs associated probabilities with symmetry
and they have this problem in that in this kind of another pcfgs with a
very small number of non terminals
they failed to capture the context dependencies you see in language
so this is the this is a big problem
the main method to do this
has been to expand the set of the terminals in the grammar
in this different ways
so here's one world which is perhaps the simplest which is to add an annotation
to each nonterminal
keep track of its parent at nonterminal
so clearly parent annotations
so for example
here we now have a tag which keeps track of the fact that NP has
an s right above it
and so my we keep track of the factors and p has VP
right above it
so essentially and one
context the training
and we now have these
expand nonterminals and we just estimate regular PCFG using this method
so this is perhaps the simplest method
well we do this
another option which is very well now it seems what are called lexicalized pcfgs
and in some sense these are somewhat similar to the tree adjoining grammars i assure
so in this case
we had information to nonterminals again by propagating worlds up through the streets
OK so for example
we propagate the channel saw mary in various different ways
now have additional information on these nonterminals specifying these headwords
the regular PCFG again
and of course we need quite a bit of care in estimating these rules production
probabilities very large number of non terminals a number of large numbers of possible rules
so i estimating these parameters
take some care but it can be done
the standard method compared to
which is very very interesting recent work
is due to petrov and klein last year
so here the idea is to gain a lot of non terminals in the grammar
to split in some sense it's pure find but to learn those spirits automatically using
so now imagine i take each nonterminal CNS nonterminal
and i said i can split this into one hundred twenty eight different possibilities some
number possibilities
now these spirits are latent
they observed in the training data and so it was essentially to recover these latent
and to really make this work think this is the major inside petrov and klein
bottles of allowing different nonterminals to split to different degrees unique some kind of model
and this is quite quite effective
so let me do some results in some areas
messages of these results
parent annotation methods
so it works PCFG but still has about twenty percent
in terms of recovering these constituents
so that's evidence that you know
the simple well even this method for refining nonterminals doesn't work too well
computer lexicalized pcfgs
we can see is about twenty five percent reduction in error
if we look at the map also attacked a small this down here
and this is probably primarily due to the features which we can include in this
model which are quite difficult to include lexicalized pcfgs
so we've reached this idea so cial style features to include surface features and include
various overlapping features which are very difficult to get into pcfgs
finally if we compare petrov and klein
mister see some improvements over the course of the results are closer
first of all the
way nonlinear autonomous system looks you've got some practice with it
why now
so this is not linear
so all these the right hand side no longer simple combinations kx
plus b y
nonlinear an autonomous there's no
these are functions are just that's why there's no t on the right-hand side
i remember the way to get geometric most of today will be geometric
the way to get a geometric picture that is first by constructing the velocity field
of those components are the functions f and g
so the velocity field
the velocity field which gives a picture of the system
in house solutions
the solutions to the system from the point of view of functions they would look
like pairs of functions x t y t
but from the point of view geometry
they are
when you plot them as parametric equations they are called trajectories
the field
which simply means that they are occurs everywhere having the right velocity so
a typical car would look like
there's a trajectory
and we know its trajectory because each point the vector on it has
of course the right direction the tangent direction but more than that it has the
right velocity so
here for example the point is traveling more slowly
here it's traveling more rapidly because the velocity vectors is bigger longer
so it reject this is the picture of the typical trajectory
the only other thing that i should mention it on the critical points
if you work the problems for this week
the first couple of problems you already seen the significance of the critical points of
well from monday's lecture you know they
from the point of view of solutions they are constant solutions
from the point of view the field they are where
the field is zero
there's no velocity vector in other words what is vector is zero and therefore the
point being there is no reason to go anywhere else
spelling it out it's where we
partial derivatives that where the values of the functions on the right-hand side which give
the two components the i j component of the field where they are zero
OK that's all the by way of
recall today i guess
the topic for the day
it is not the kind of behaviour that you have not yet observed
the computer screen unless you work ahead
and that is
their trajectories
so you don't go along to infinity or
and at the critical point the critical points with just sit there all the time
but this third type of behavior
a trajectory can have where neither sits for all time
goes well for all time
instead it repeats itself
so i think is called closed trajectory
what does it look like well
if the closed curve in the plane
which at every point
it's trajectory i e the
the arrows at each point let's let's say it's traced
in the clockwise direction just
and i make the errors of the arrows will go
the errors of the field will go like this
here is going slowly here is very slow
here example speed again
so one
for such a trajectory what's happening well
it's going
he goes around in finite time with then
repeats itself
it just goes round and round forever
if you go if you land on that trajectory so
it represents
a system
which returns to its original state periodically
it represents
of the system
now we've seen in the one example of that we see an example of
a simple example where
this simple system
it's widely using things like vision and spatial statistics but for some things it does
not work very well
so the likelihood when you have long chains of inference is quite likely to mess
because of the likelihood is only optimizing the connections between neighbors because my anything about
so you know if you want to say well done during the shape if it
doesn't work well the question is what can you do
well another thing that you can do is discriminative learning
so people often use discriminative learning just because it's more accurate i typically get more
accurate results of this from active learning but another advantage of discriminative learning is that
this term
now becomes easy to compute
because what makes institutions hard as we all know is that they have many very
tall and isolated peaks
but as i condition on more and more evidence more and more this speaks disappear
or become smaller in the limit i have only one p
so now this computation is a lot easier
and in fact i can even approximate it
by the counts in the MDP state
if the peak
at the end of the state is large enough that it dominates the others then
the concept that peak are actually very good approximation of the constant you get by
summing of the exponential number of states
so we can do this
as long as you know in advance which variables are going to be query and
retrieval are going to be
in particular very simple but yet very effective algorithm for discriminative learning in the islands
it's based on the voted perceptron algorithm that mike collins originally developed for training hidden
markov models discriminatively
voted perceptron itself is an extension of another good old perception of
and here's how it works
so it assumes that the network is linear chain here are the observations here are
the hidden states
we start out with all the weights being zero
and then i repeat the following some number of times
i can for each x
i compute the most likely why
using the viterbi algorithm right polynomial because this is the change
i do the counts in that state
subtract them from the counts in the data and that's my learning signal
so i multiply by learning rate and that my words
and at the end i returned the average of the weights of early iterations
this is better than returning just the final weights because empirically it gives better results
more resistant to overfitting and also allows for certain theoretical guarantees that otherwise wouldn't
now our goal
is to generalize this algorithm to apply to arbitrary markov logic networks
and in fact think that that's very easy because you just need to change one
thing in it
and that is
you replace viterbi by PPP
with PTPE canada my my MEP inference on any more that i want and then
as still have the counts in the the
johnson solution and the whole island as before
now this relatively learning is slower than the likelihood it's also from that often requires
no more tuning of parameters because there's looting was going on
but if you're willing to go through that work in many cases it gives much
better results
so that's what learning
let's think about structure learning
we would like to discover
mln formulas from data
how can we do that
well the first thing to notice is that this is a generalisation of the problem
of feature induction in markov networks
this is just the more general form of features the you know the first of
the features and they're not just conjunctive but at some level you could imagine taking
the techniques for example indelibly appeared at all and you know generalizing to first order
in fact that's one of the things that we've done
another thing to notice is that this is really a kind of inductive logic programming
and that was problem is if feel that has existed for thirty years and you
know there's a lot of very mature stuff there
the problem in that larger problem is learning a logic programme from relational database
and here what we're doing is very similar except for two key things one is
that typically in ILP we just learn horn clauses right the prolog program is the
set of one was but he will arbitrary clauses not just horn
and the other big difference is that in NLP typically we're just trying to optimize
the accuracy of the rules are the accuracy and coverage or something like that and
that doesn't work proceed because now we're trying to build the probabilistic models
so not evaluation function should be likelihood posterior probability or something like that
but we can make is to changes right we can we can modify all helps
you know in ILP system to learn the hard to learn any clauses not just
and we can use like because evolution function and not potentially we have a programme
that learns millions from from the
the problem however is that the program is going to be exceedingly slow
there's going to be exceedingly slow is that as i generate candidate clauses
i have to compute the new likelihoods
to compute the new likelihoods i need to compute the modified weights
notice that every time i i change across potentially all the weights change
so i have to read the the word optimization
remember that the optimisation itself cause inference as a subroutine or in a best guess
puts this is just the like i i'm doing potentially millions of weight optimizations this
is going to be slow
so what can we do
actually surprisingly there's a a couple of very simple things that we can do that
makes something else become the bottleneck
and that's that's basically to notice
right that's
when i change of clause
chances are most weights won't change much
so i want to start my new optimisation from the previous optimum not from scratch
number one number two
at this point i'm just trying to select the best because i'm actually trying to
find the optimal weight it so i can use convergence threshold
now if you start
with with points that are close to the ones that you want then you have
this conversion threshold and use a quasi newton optimise it usually conversion you know a
couple of iterations
so it will be very fast
and so what turns out to be the bottom like is something else
it's counting clause groundings
remember the sufficient statistics for learning in MLN
thank you sign in my curable disease work
yes say something
those in the back want to come down a little bit some of the slides
a little bit smaller
i first i'd like to thank you very much
the organisers and also
response to the financial sponsors for this building
without we wouldn't be here today and with great hopes that this building will spark
new ideas and new collaborations this first deal with unsolved problems that will solve problems
that can describe
it is work many people before they even begin
i would like to set the stage
this talk
but is given a little practice for instance here because
this after this conference attached to school
for starting very fortunate because in the last century there were mainly dealing with all
the systems
and such as solid state physics and these were uncovered four hundred systems
and that's exactly to major advances in society for example the transistor laser it's hard
to imagine a society with
with without both of these important inventions
no one can predict the future but many people do believe that the future will
be uncovering
governor of systems but disordered systems such as the question
challenge was to know what matters because disordered systems are some sort of so complex
is indeed different and this so different that it's not even clear what matters in
this talk will seek to build a paradigm was developed in the last century of
what matters
a critical point and me
a critical point is not the temperature process or the pressure process but rather a
combination of both that witnessed in the concept called the correlation length
so it is in this century we will uncover some unifying principles that can be
some sort of a conceptual framework that these phenomena that previously thought to be unlinked
an example that was also developed at the end of the last century to its
developers in this audience kirkpatrick and stuff is the phenomenon of percolation which was first
proposed as a mathematical model with potential application to gas masks and then in the
hands of these two men and many others
scientists has been found to apply to a wide range of systems that no one
ever expected would apply to such as the generation
OK so the title of the book which is in your is the application of
statistical physics to understand complex systems i've described the work of many many many collaborators
ten of whom are actually on the programme of this meeting by coincidence i had
nothing to do with this
finding this meeting so i
feeling very good at the kind of my collaborators are independent invited to this meeting
and i might point out that all of them could probably give talk better than
i in fact i was tempted to form some of the yesterday to see if
they would like to give the starting
i i hesitated
do that
the key question will ask is indeed this question that was developed in critical point
phenomenon namely what matters
and we focus on a few specific examples first what matters for
complex fluids these for one specific complex that would
secondly what matters economic fluctuations the question is very important particularly today
when most people think that today would be the worst case the most volatile financial
entire decade if not the century according to greenspan yesterday
of the tenth century and really what determines the switching of complex system because after
all in natural systems switches and yet systems behave as if they suddenly switch for
example the economy relatively suddenly switches from the healthy
economy to completely disastrous one for such as lehman brothers canada lose ninety six percent
of its value in a very short
with disastrous consequences at least four
the wife of my son who works for
i try to to do this
but details in and out of his website and so forth and so on
and last but not least before i start i'd like to dedicate this
very special woman my mother who today becomes eighty eight years old
so let's start with some probability
problem problem that is
let's get lost it for everything that's going to come
next and that's the problem of physics and the simple question it is what's the
diameter of the problem
if we know it's there
in the most obvious way to any physicist
and in fact the motives use and is even that for all dimensions down the
four dimensions as symbol well
for example
a two v
so this path
so far a e f b this graph
at school so that they can produce
that that will be blocked
by definition
either of these two conditions
you do that has
and the observer head to head
or had tails
or it has a tail to tail node which is not observed not any of
this and
there's about you
not necessarily
a path is just the sequence of edge
it doesn't need to follow the direction of the edges
i just have a little but here
which is
which is of course
to have
look at
this should be
tails tails and this should be heads
so please correct
these that you or any but just giving an example of a particular
this fact will be called block and
if this whole things
tail to tail or a head here in old which is of
that's the first condition
we immediately see
that is conditions here
one of these conditions has to hold for the past to be blocked either these
or is
for these particular pattern here we already see immediately that the first condition already holds
here we have an observer
and this is the tail to tail
these the tail to tail
so yes
so basically this work is that it is this passes walk
so now let's see this back here
let's see whether this that he blocked
the path from a to c
so we didn't even bother about
asking the question about the second condition here for this case because we already identified
that was already blocked so let's investigate this particular case
so that you will be blocked if it contains an observer
had tail or had tail well
it does not apply
because there alternative
tail to tail node world
there's not a head-to-head all there's no head to head node here
not so
so basically in all of these conditions
apply for this benefit so this that is
not all
so now let's study is graphs
we know
and know is not absolutely labelled according to
given that its label
a model of a with respect to the so basically
these no here
is head to tail nodes
for this
it happens also to be head tail for this pattern but its head to head
node for these
because remember define that here we are concerned with blocking that
see sparse
by definition we don't care about the direction of the edges
it doesn't matter
so i had tail tail
so let's look at these graphs here and let's consider the same well as another
factor is the same graph
let's just i'm just conditioning on different
conditioning on the is no instead of conditioning on that
let's study the same graph
the same thing
that's the thing but
let's ask whether the sparse here he's blocked people's not looked into the ground
let's see what it's like
if i conditional on these particular five
so first let's see whether it contains a tail to to tail or head tail
which is observed
these that he has no servant
i have no
observations i only have one observation here
i don't have any observations here
the first time to have observe the semantic rest mean doesn't
the first condition does not hold
because i an observable to belong to the past
let's see the second commission
the second condition is for you can use to
is to have a head to head node
which is not observed
nor any of its descendants use of
well it does have a head to head node
which is not observed
but one of its descendants is observed i haven't formally define what is and is
although this later but you can immediately figure out what that means right
from the semantics of the business
so basically
it's lots of fun
because yes
we have a head to head node
yes they had little is not so much
but some of its descendants is observed
these here
does not satisfy the first condition
and does not satisfy the second condition is
so this here
is not all
so that's extremely important because
you may think that because you haven't seen any observation this this person what
i'm sorry
i mean
you know
in this particular case
it's the other way around
and that brings us
so basically the following
you have documents and you want to assign the categories
each document can belong to more than one category
so you have the document about mike tyson having tax problems
that might belong to the sports category and the business category and the politics category
if ten is political aspect to his tax problems so the multilabel supervised learning problem
is learning to assign
x is to
zero labels
and so
if you have
ten classes
there are ten classes then how many possible combinations of labels
two the ten
so too to the ten combinations
which is about
love tenderness tender the six
the ten to three
one thousand twenty four
and if you are twenty classes there would be about a million
so if you twenty classes and you and each document was allowed to belong to
one or more classes
then there will be some combinations of classes the chances are you've never seen in
your training data
but you'd still like to be able to predict that combination for a test documents
my and
you so one one way to attack this problem would be to build ten separate
binary classifiers
and then to just you classifies talk sports and non-sports business on arts business
and then two much
allow the document to belong to all the labels of the classifiers that said it
belonged to that corresponding class
but of course
can you
can you see
a type of information
so supposing you had ten class built ten separate classifiers
there's the source of information that in the training data they are not going to
have to capture using those ten classifiers
what information is not going to be able to capture directly
the correlation between the classes
and so
if you use a i'm log linear model approach
then you can have the feature functions
the feature function
after nineteen
x and y
might be
belongs to y
and the business belongs to y
so you know this is the feature function depends on wind doesn't depend on x
at all
you can still learn a weight far from your training data
and if you learn positive weight for this feature function
it's going to be saying that everything else being equal
sports and business go together
and if you look the negative weight for it is going to say everything else
being equal
if it's a sports document then is not also business document and vice versa
but if you are using a log linear model with feature function the key thing
is if you are using feature functions to attack this multilabel problem
then you can
directly learn correlations
the different parts of your class
and that's why
we use the word structured input structured output so i'm here
so we have a thousand twenty four labels
but those thousand twenty four labels have internal structure because their subsets
and then we can use feature functions to represent that internal and then we can
learn whether that we we can learn which
structure cases of favorable which structure cases unfavourable
well that's
i think that's going to depend mainly on your training set size
so if you
think of
so if we have ten classes
then i guess that ten choose to
forty five possible pairs
and must say i could have forty five feature functions like this
if i have a lot of training data i probably have enough examples of each
two of them to learn a reliable preference for against that there
but if i have a file if i consider triples like sports and business and
well there i ten choose three of those which
would be forty five times eight
you know in the three hundreds
that there are a lot more triples
i'm going to have
less reliable evidence from the training data
about each of the triples
and so it's going to be a judgement call
how many feature functions i want to put in my model
so what i could certainly do is i could
i could create one feature function we strip of pairs
and then i could see for each of those triples how many times it occurred
in the training data and it only occurs zero wants the training data in my
not so much
creator feature function for it because
the model
because the parameter i would learned the that feature function probably be unreliable
t one
c infinity in time
equal to t one or e
plus he invented
compare with the process
it says that i can achieve t one over people as t infinity
so what does that say
we take a look and compare this with our lower bounds
on runtime
how efficient is this
how does this compare with the optimal execution
yes two competitive
within a factor of two of optimal
because this is the lower bound
and this is the lower bound
so if i take twice the max
of these two
twice the maximum of these two
that's going to be
bigger than the sum
some within a factor of two
whichever is stronger lower bound for any situation so this says you get within factor
the efficiency and schedule in terms of runtime process
OK everybody that
so let's proved this theorem it's very it's quite elegant theorem
it's not hard theorem one of the nice things by the way about
this week is that nothing is very hard
it just requires you to think differently
OK so the proof
it has to do with counting up how many
complete steps we have and how many incomplete steps we have
so we'll start with the number of complete steps
can somebody tell me
how was the largest number of complete steps i could possibly have
i heard somebody on what
t one over p
why is that
yes so
the number of complete steps is at most t one over p because one
and once you had this many then t one works
everest complete step from getting
he worked at
so if i did more than t one over p
steps i would
have there been no more work to be done
number complete steps cannot be bigger than t one of p
that's this piece
now we can the
incomplete steps and shows founded by t infinity
so let's consider incomplete step
let's see what happens
let's let
the prime
the subgraphs
should be
so we draw pictures here
imagine we have withdrawn towards
you have a graph
the graph g
you actually people's careers are example here so
imagine that this is the graph g
showing the procedures here
because actually
is there works for any DAG
and the
procedure outlines are not necessarily care about is the threads
so imagine that my my dad g
imagine that i have
executed up to this point
which ones i executed
the execution these guys
so the things ranging primer just the thing that have yet to be executed
these guys are the ones that already exist
and imagine
that all of them are unit time threads without loss of generality this theorem would
go through even if
each of these had a particular goal
time associated with it
the same schedule you have work just fine
so how can i characterize the threads that are ready to be executed
which are the threads that are ready to be executed here let's just say
i mean
that one
no that's not ready to be executed y
because it's got a processor here
this guy
OK so this guy is ready to be executed
and these guys were executed
there's too
treasury how can i characterizes what's their property which graph theoretic property in
she prime
it tells me whether or not something is ready to be executed
has no predecessor but was was another way of saying that in
got no predecessor in g prime was doesn't mean for node not have processor in
a graph
in degree is
right same thing
the threads
with in degree
zero in prime
the ones that are ready to be executed
and if it's incomplete step
what do i do
and the next step would be chosen as are if we are interested in functions
that map to realign to the real i want to draw functions that maps a
are two to the real line then we would choose are two here
and are
then in that case we can actually choose
as the projection operator we can actually choose the euclidean projector
if it exists parallel projection
exactly coincides with this
and the family of marginals would be the
the the finite dimensional would be a set of finite dimensional gaussians on the space
but of course we can't use just any gaussians but we have set the power
to set the parameters of the gaussians in exactly this this way that we get
the projective so that their marginals of each other
in order to
ensure that the margins are projective
we have to start with what we can do is we can start with
it was i mean function so we we pretend we already know augusta process defines
mean function and we define the covariance function
and and then we produce or marginal parameters by discretizing
we start with one mean function one covariance functions and then we choose for for
marginal on on
and points
and locations of the real line
we choose
the function values corresponding to these points of the mean function and we substitute these
into the into the covariance function and the covariance matrix of this this is like
the kernel matrix
one of kernel
remember that he is our set
is is is the domain of the function that we chose at random
the index that is the domain of all random function
and if we if we choose finite subset i corresponding to one of these subspaces
then the elements of this of this subset i are points correspond to points on
the real line
and these are exactly the point that we get observations and so we get an
observation of finite number of points to which you want to play goes process these
points correspond
two finite subset of the simplex to a finite number of dimensions degrees of freedom
this is
so this is this is
i'm just using some function here that that satisfies the properties of the main functions
that's just some function properly continuous functions and i'm using a positive definite function but
i'm not i'm not yet assuming that these are actually
in any way related to an existing gaussianprocess it's just the way to a convenient
way to make sure that the
the marginals that and producing that they are actually
that they actually protective
since we have to produce an infinite number of marginals we can't write them all
so you always need some kind of functional like this
to determine your parameters
and then check that this gives you a set of marginals that are actually
prove that this gives you a set of models that are consistent
and that is what is also what what you why was i was telling you
in his first lecture
ratio that
and that the director distribution is kind set
so you called consistent i project
this is a
OK i want to end up with this we apply this this extension theorem tells
us we have gaussian process measure that exists and is unique
OK and it actually then turns out you can then check that this skulls process
actually has this mean function in this covariance function but that is something you have
proof separately is not something that the extension tells the extra work required to
that's a very good question
that's exactly that's exactly what the problems are
so this is this is something that that looks like a perfect construction of girls
and actually it it was also used in the the same serum is used in
the original paper on the dirichlet process
but the problem is both constructions in way are actually wrong
if you look back at the
at the theorem here
so he just ask what is the sigma algebra
one which this measure is defined the serum doesn't tell you
are these the way it stated here doesn't tell you and this is the way
the prioris for Abybythis strange thingracing exponential of the trace of this matrix so
this is a essentially a sum of products matrix calculated from the coordinatescorrectly for
the translation summingonly overmatchedpairsthat thingswon't apply by A and scaled andthat
forms the expanded well I didn't know very much about random rotations when I started
doing this so I didn'tdidn't quite know what I should put in
for Pof Acause I want to have something tractable here that I can now use
in my samplingof Asoone theof having aco-worker who works in
differentexperiences so I noticed this thatif if P of A had the same form of
thisand it was the Pof A was the exponentialthe traceof something times Aokay
then thesomethings wouldhead up you'd have you'd have conjugacyinfactconditional conjugacy so
that seemedto be a good ideaokay that seemeda quitea
nice idea that we would have this would beconjugate transformation so I wrote
to and saidhave you ever seen a distribution like thisis
this thing something you know aboutthey said ah yes this is wellknown it'ssomething called
the matrix Fisher distribution andit ca becharacterized in various ways it happens to be
let's have a little little quizhow many what's thedimension of variation in a in three-dimensional
three-dimensional rotation matrixhow many degrees offreedomthree six anymore noone thinks nine
because it's rotation match it there must beconstraintsthree six you're right it's three
if youpilote a plane oraustere ship you talk aboutpitch yaw and roll
so thisin a three-dimensional case this is actuallythe a three degrees of freedom
the densityand threedimensionsyou would've expectsome strange measurebut is quitea well-knownthing
it it could be constructed as something likethe aGaussian distribution conditioned on
a spherical shell and then slicedin anappropriate wayit's quite a nice objectso that'sthat's something we
can sample fromwe can do the the posterior samplingif we might assume that particular priorstructure on that
oh this think I didn't mention sorry isif if you takeF zero to
bezerothen this just a uniform distributionone souniform
random rotation of the matrixand youdon't you justdon't care so that'squite a common choice
asfor thematching matrixthis isthe the simplest idea we simply add and subtract matches
at random we try andadd backdelete them or switch themand that
anything aboutthat is because of the need form of the joint distribution you can
see allit happens whenwe change M is the terms comein and out ofto this
soyou think about metropolishastings type sampling is very easy to computethe update
ratio so this this is a very verycheap update it is lot of these very quickly
wecan do theposterior samplingforall the unknown simultaneously and you know youit works
works pretty well on these this sort of relatively small scale
and then we come to the issue what do we report well I stressed in the first lecture that you
don'tyou know you have to think about what you report as an estimate and even
in a quite a simple caseso for continuous variables the posterior expectation is often
a choice you takethen the expectation the posterior distribution has a natural easily understood
thing in common choice and it corresponds to quadratic losswhat about me the matching
matrixif you want a point estimate at a matchingmatrixthis is our bestestimate of the
how they match but you can't take you can't take a posterior expectation of the
binary matrixwell of course you canbut the entries of the averageare not
allzero oh oneprobablynon of them is zero oh oneokay so that seems quite unsatisfactory and
youcould of coursethreshold that to get a matching but it raises all sorts of issues
and it doesn't of course guarantee that each point is only matchto one thing
well depending on the level oftruncation soit ismuch more satisfactory to think about a
suitable loss function for the matching matrixokay and to get the optimalbayesian and
estimate for that sowe're we're in this area of trying to use decision theory
based optimal bayesian estimation of a matching majof a quantitythat's only calculatedwithin
the posteriorsample
but as I said this morning sometimes ifyou depending on thechoice of
loss function sometimesyou can do that computationally that is you can optimize
essentially onoptimizebased on the result of theM C M Crun withoutinteracting
over that run so you got some flexibility and this is a particular choice but
it's quite a naturalonewe simplygonna penalize false positives and false
negatives okay so thatwe we weconjecturesthere's twonumbersboth positive numbers
L zero one and L one zero so if you declareXJ and YKto
beamatch and not really a matchyou pay aprice andsame way the other way around
it could be different prices and if you getit rightthen you don't pay anything at all and it turns
out that that's has thatstructure I described is separable and so you can you can
implementoptimumbayesian estimation using this loss functionbased on summary statistics
of theM C M C run it had a very natural summary statisticscause it turns out
the optimal matching isthe is that which maximizes this quantity and this is very
easily interpreted soP J Kis a temporary notation meaning the posterior probability theJ and Kare matched
given the dataokay sothat's somethingthat's easily estimated from theM CM Crunyou know in