you can pay if you want to up to a couple of thousand from a
total of this stuff and the cheapest you'll get out of it in the duty-free
is one hundred forty euros for this ridiculous little
top it and my wife tells me it's absolutely wonderful i made a stupid mistake
when i was traveling three weeks in a row one occasion of going insane i'm
really going to get something nice and this nice lady in the duty-free told library
and swears that the most fantastic thing ever and you're trapped after that because there's
no going back but here's the point
you go into the department store and you got these tiny little tops maybe about
that size
and it's cost one hundred forty years they'll give you a sample
which is about and they are tens of what's inside the tub
it's fantastic if you've got ten those in fact if you go on ebay you
can buy the samples they couldn't give a damn it costs them money
because of the norm of reciprocity they know that when they give you a gift
they can more easily get you went and by the way this month
if you buy that we have an extra small gift with three sample sizes this
nice pouch and so on and so forth and they know they will close sixty
seventy percent more you want to the supermarket somebody is giving out samples of chocolate
cake you don't want chocolate cake you don't like chocolate well maybe you like it
if you don't want to you definitely don't need it
you try to avoid eye contact you take a little piece and you know you're
not going to buy it even though you have sampled the and actually putting trial
you're wondering why am i doing this and you think i'll take it off and
put on the shelf around the corner but you don't you buy it that sonoma
reciprocity when you catch somebody doing something right when you give them recognition one squirt
dopamine they feel better
they want to do it again secondly they want to pay you back
you become more charismatic more appealing some the more engaged they want to give you
what you want you just want them to engage in a little bit more to
work with the work when you've made it clear what you want
and then you provide them with this then you get that reciprocal action
this is really really interesting area let me let me give you a little bit
of greek mythology education
really really fast and some of you may have heard of this particular myth of
pygmalion and galatea the psychologist talk about the pygmalion complex of the pygmalion effect i
should say
and it's it describes
the fact it describes an effect that has been established over forty fifty years of
research that the single
the most important factor in raising the performance of an individual is the expectation
that that person's leader has of the pygmalion effect just like pygmalion
imagining the perfect woman and carving the absolute perfect figure of a woman that you
can imagine in his mind and it came to life
like the sculptor pygmalion leader having high expectations of the people they work for
has the biggest of all of the impacts has the the
the most significant impact on raising persontoperformance now nineteen thirty two
a guy called dale carnegie wrote a book that you've probably heard of called how
to win friends and influence people
and and some people say i think they say it sold more copies in the
twentieth century the the bible and things like that but is the key one of
his principles and there was very simple
he said if you want to get the best of people
give them a high reputation
to live up to
set the bar high
when i first joined this company
i was originally running the irish and and united kingdom organisations and i so our
organisation is based on an agency or distributorship agreement and i i was an independent
businessperson running the irish and UK operations
and they adopted me and to what my colleagues called the dark side to to
work with the corporate team and it's about school when he the founders of the
i brought me out to dinner fill me full cocktails before we negotiate the money
by the way of course they didn't get rich by being stupid and at the
end of the the dinner
so as when we finish the whole thing came up and he shook my hand
like that he said derek you one of the most talented individuals that i've had
the pleasure to work with and one of the things that i like about working
with two is
the quality of what to produce
i think we've ever worked on one
you always greatly exceeded expectations and everything seems to come in on time
and he went on and i walked out there feeling kind of that my head
was full of dopamine i mean i was swelling was coming out my ears
i was feeling great back home to my wife honey i didn't get much money
but you should hear what he said about me
it was great now
clever man whether he knew what he was doing or not he said an expectation
here he gave me what currently called the high reputation to live up to so
the first time he said to me i needed to work on such such what
did i do
exactly the same as i would have done except i worked on it longer
harder and even though we set up a little bit higher than i thought it
was capable of attending push for he knew me well enough to know what i
was capable of what strengths i had what areas i need to develop and then
he said hey i needed to do this he just said here's where i thought
i could achieve here's what he thought i could achieve
and because he gave me the reputation stretch
pygmalion his car having the perfect person the perfect performance and what happens when i
i pulled myself up there's a well
i could do well
i'd better than i thought
two things happened one is
well he knows this stuff he knows me better than i know myself there's charisma
when i'm around him
i do better that's charisma that's engagement leaders expectation your expectations of people that you
work for you are tremendously important but you have to know them
at the level that we spoke about their earlier on the second thing that happens
when you
when that somebody achieves at that level is they suddenly become galaxy here
they say
o g i know i could do that and the second most
important factor in driving a person's performance and productivity and achievement is their expectations of
a good leader
knows people well enough
to set the bar there
when they pull themselves there they raise their expectations themselves what do you do that
you know well enough just to raise a little bit more and you get this
in fact
go wrong
saying that
that is they can get model
so wrong
one of these
we had a
you can be in
turn it should be
you that's
it is
come on
they do not
they later
you know
good well
o of
of a
this 1 here is what hydrogen women had electrons that's isoelectronic with helium
this thing here this is just a naked proton so it doesn't it doesn't work
it doesn't work
so we need to find another schemes and that solution was provided for us by
GM lewis GM lewis and he asks the question what is
if we share
electrons and by no means the valence electrons and what if we could share what
if we could share electrons well let's look at it and see what happens well
we know that hydrogen is 1
so we take another hydrogen stick over here 1 as we know we have electron
here and let's say
the x denotes the other the electron from this hydrogen and now we form
a bond but we have well this is isoelectronic with helium and so is the
isoelectronic with helium
and so we think we can and we have a lot of both each hydrogen
has access to each electron
and now we have a satisfied systems that we can do the same thing with
what we're going to have to do with nitrogen atoms but this is the case
where we have would have to work to have sharing electrons and
in general we have sharing of 2
sharing to achieve electrons octet stability let's take a look at let's look at nitrogen
to see if it goes to succeeded that applies that applies here as well as
well we know nitrogen has what nitrogen is of 1 s 2 2 s 2
to the 3
we've got 5 electrons here and there in the valence shell it we take nitrogen
and let's just go 1 2 3 1 4 5
1 2 3 4 5 . 2 3 4 5 6 7 and 8 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 8
we got to cases where each 1 of those things now
this isoelectric within the neon
and we have achieved octet stability I
in the in the same way right so Lewis called this
because called collaborative
for example used
of valence
the lecture right so you take the call here
and we take the valence here and that comes called valence
right covalent right and let's be a little
need of little terminology here in this region in here contains the bonding domains right
and than non bonding electrons are not
nonbinding domains and this structure that's that I depicted using the axes the knows what
is called the Lewis structure
that is called it's called Lewis structure and that's
this is actually from Lewis's notes now remember
but this is 1902 so that was a whole lot going on there was a
lot of physics going on but we don't know a whole lot about atomic structure
back in those days but you can see this is right out of his
right out of his notebook and you can see arranged the adams by road and
he's trying to figure out the lithium has 1
beryllium magnesium have to boron aluminum have 3 and he's trying to figure out how
to arrange these things this is right out of his relatives noble and look up
at the top
got a bit of a mistake the trying helium octet stable he tried but the
electrons around helium in working but look down here
you electric field may be
that's assuming the down direction smaller smaller here
smaller smaller even than zero zero zero here and here the electric field be like
and that whole pattern then
standing wave
so this is down this is up and also it's like that this is always
he's always nodal lines
imagine now
that is and is open
so i just removed the short circuit
and i leave it open
i hope you remember
the experiments we did with strings
this is really the equivalent of this training is attached
so you get to know there
reflectivity is minus one mountain comes back as very
this no
when the entries of
so there nothing at the end completely nothing
that is the situation that it is right now by the way this is completely
open is why here
this is why are not connected
so in this is open
you expect the reflectivity
of plus one
just like with the story that the mountains comes back as amount
and if that's the case
then you get the maximum
of the if you get an and sign up here right here in the middle
you get you know to lines and right here in the middle you get you
know old ones
so we get this shift of one-quarter wavelength
from where you only have notable
lines you get now and high nodes and where you had earlier and i note
you know get nodes
so this is open
these i don't know to lines
so those the locations
across the y here
where there is no potential difference at all moments in time
so this is what we will refer to as close
i want to draw the parallel with are streams and
i even think that in
my problem sets that i give you a chance to
work a little bit on this
remember was streams we can fix the length of the string in such a way
that we get resonance
we can write string at one end
moving to senior in little bit
and the end is fixed
and we can set the system in resonance
the wavelength that we don't get level of
and being an integer
so n equals one
three et cetera the wavelength is into l divided by n
you can also regulate here
and leave this and open
we even discussed that you've demonstrated that
in which case
you get resonance
for lambda and
because for l divided by
two n minus one
and of course the frequency at which you reach that resonance
omega of and
it's always k of and
times the speed of propagation which in this case is the speed of light
OK of and is two pi divided by
the wavelength
so the way i'm going to do this demonstration for you
we have chosen the length of these wires
such that the system is resonance when it is open
so we have length
which is four point
two five metres
the wavelength
three point four years
so the lengths
is one and one-quarter wavelength
and so when it is opened
richard is here
and this
is one quarter wavelength
is one
half wavelength and so on
if i leave these open and that's what i'm going to do
and i have you lights
it is connected
between these two is that i can slide along so i have the light your
light source
this is very specialised sources
as an enormously high all week resistance
so that when i put it here that i'm not disturbing
the potential difference between the wires are not changing the boundary conditions really
because it is enormously high ohmic resistance
and the light bulb
lights up even with a minutely small current
so the first thing
that i'm going to show you is that
if i turn on the
transmitter which i will use the same one that i have here make sure don't
get electrocuted no
so we're going to take this off
and may help actually if we give you
will have lots of
exercises lots of chances you will have an assignment to
the play was is a little bit now comes my method number two
message number two
is again as we had with the dot product
is a
geometrical methods
let me try to
work on this board between
if you know vector a
and you know vector b
and you know to the angle a
then the cross product c
because crosby
is the magnitude of a
times the magnitude of b
times the sign of data
the cosine of data as we had before was the dot product is the sign
of data
you can already immediately see that
this will be zero if there is either zero degrees one hundred eighty degrees
the dot product was zero
when the angle between them was ninety degrees
this number can be larger than zero sign theta is larger than zero can also
be smaller than zero
now we only have the magnitude
of the vector and now comes the hardest part one is the direction of the
and that is something
that you have to engrave your minds and not forget
the direction is found as follows
take a
because he first mentioned
you rotate a over the shortest possible angle to be
if you had in your hand corkscrew and i show that in a minute
then you turn the court through is seen from uses clockwise
and the corkscrew would go into the black hole
and if the corkscrew goes into the blackboard
you will see the tail of the vector and you will see across
little plus sign and therefore
we put that
like so
product is always perpendicular
both a and b
but at least it was two choices it can you come out the blackboard or
it can go in the
and i just told you
rich convention use
and i want to show that to you
in a way that
appeal to more
this is what i have
used before
television help sex sessions i've given MIDI monopoly monopolies made not to be or to
i have indicated here and here is a corkscrew
there's a corkscrew
i'm going to do the corkscrew as seen from your side clockwise
and you'll see
that's the
corkscrew goes in into to the ball take
and that's the direction that of the vector
if we had to be crossed a
then you take being your hands you're or they would over the short is angle
to eight now you have to rotate counterclockwise
and when you rotate counterclockwise
the corkscrew comes to you there you go
and so the vector is now pointing in this direction
and if the vector is pointing
so it's you
then we would indicate that missus circle
and the adult
in other words for this factor
the cross and a
we have exactly the same magnitude
no difference
it would be
coming out of the blackboard and that words
eight crosby
equals minus
the cross and
as a
doctor b is the same as b built
we will encounter cross product when we deal with talks
and when we deal with
angular momentum which is not the easiest part of it one
let's take an extremely
example again
i don't mean to
and so you with such a simple example but you will get chances more advanced
chances on the assignment
i gave the vector a
x rule for the unit vector
in x direction that means a of x is one
and a y zero and nailsea easier zero
and suppose b
it is why rules
that means b of y is one
b of a is
and you see
at the phase transformation from isotropic to nematic drastic change in length here by a
factor of two
and actually exist some systems in which show and
spontaneous information by a factor of three to four
if we measure the order parameter again
this typical order from the temperature curve which can be correlated
and from this weekend
a determine the coupling coefficient
but looking at these mentioned polymath
and this might be interesting for some people who already know this liquid crystalline elastomers
one very interesting aspect
when we start with the non orders
elastomer mentioned last month as mentioned in the beginning of such an elastomer then of
course we have an all order parameter of zero because it's polycrystalline material
and then we apply mechanical stress
make microscopic orientation
and actually end up with a uniformly ordered system
the nematic order parameter might be extrapolated to the elongation of zero
the most interesting aspect is that this uniform orientation of the systems already
can be observed it and elongation of
c thirty percent then we get a microscopically ordered sample
however if you look
at best
train curve of the system
then we see
and that the orientation process
or this behavior which has been named soft elasticity by mark warner
this process
and it according to the mechanical measurements about fifty percent
but we see that we already observed in one of the main thirty percent
that's an interesting behavior which is a little bit puzzling
in our explanation is if we look
these types of liquid crystal made pollen then of course these problems can form so-called
and when we apply mechanical stress we have to remove these happens
and when we remove these happens this
that's not change essentially change the conformation of the polymer backbone and consequently does not
so a change in the
entropy elasticity
another interesting
very new results
which exceeds the properties known
for these so-called such elastomers which has been obtained by my phd students human calls
this year
we again look at the length of the sample as function of the as function
of temperature and the order parameter could as function of temperature
and from this experiment you already can identify that's not behaviour
which can be directly correlated
and the correlation of lang's work because the order parameter can no longer be described
with the linear behavior as in the frame of the land decision theory in other
for these main chain systems for this liquid crystal and main chain systems there's another
and if you
estimation in calculation of this we see that the length changes with the order parameter
with the power of four
with an exponent of four
very strong nonlinear behavior
microscopic dimension and state of all
up to now there no explanation for this type of behavior
i think this might be a typical example for a system where entropy elasticity changes
into and p lest he due to the chemical constitution of on networks these are
some of these new
network we already this morning source sort some of this curve you see a strong
load on elastomer
the change of temperature and the spontaneous
the question is of course when we want to apply the system for example as
artificial muscles it would be straightforward to look for
another external he's not another stimulus not temperature
and another possibility to
change the dimension of the network
it is by applying light and with life changing the state of order the state
of all the comforts to the microscopic dimension when on very old
for example if you such as molecule which is around like molecule if you make
for example cis trans isomerase station of such a molecule then you get end up
with a bent molecule spend molecule locally
reduces the state of order of the
medically all molecules and this reduction in the state of order should be directly indicated
in the change of the length of the sentence
and the very simple explanation of
the these molecules act as so you fallen nematic phase
and with the in with a simple linear relationship between concentration at phase transformation temperature
we should expect the behavior that for example if you have the town's molecule if
you increase the concentration of this
since molecule of the spend molecule you should decrease
the first transformation temperature and accordingly at the given temperature should reduce the state of
this has been investigated in UK
during the last years doing with our with our european project
i will give you just one ca one example that is really perfectly works
here we have taken such robert
at constant length
shine light
at a constant length on the sample and measure the retracted force
as a function of of
and you see you get a very fast response slower response the stationary state and
it's smooth simple
that is wrong
but that in the case of course we've got enough data
if we had a hundred
data points
are there
one hundred data points out there will be no further ahead
simply having lots of samples doesn't help either
unless they are well spread out
the the
the main over x
no noise anyway here
it's not relevant noise just makes it a little bit more difficult but not very
much more difficult
if you've got loads of data that is well spread out those two hundred points
on that one then you need to model
the data and the model of the same thing so no problem there is that
if you've got some noise on that you could still eyeball it
and get a very good
OK so
the questions are
we got enough data
we can see what we've been looking at
it's the one dimensional problem that is is there is one dimension to x
as the dimensionality of x goes up then
the possibility of seeing what f of x looks like
very very rapidly
OK in two dimensions
it's quite difficult
on the screen to see what the two dimensional function looks like if you just
got a few points dotted around on it
OK is quite good in one dimension with that sine wave
it becomes much more difficult in three dimensions and higher
then without the assistance of
LSD or something else
we have no chance whatsoever
my there may be
there are several points that can see these things in their heads or whatever i
don't know but i can't
and i doubt that many if you can because you have been in the papers
one thing i would have heard of
so we lose the ability to see some car really get any good information about
what sort of shape are expected
OK so high dimensionality
we got enough data well the number of samples we're going to require turns out
to be exponential in d the dimension
of x
OK so without going into any technicalities if you've if n samples is enough
in one dimension so
four our sinewave wave six samples turned out to be enough
OK then in n dimensions
sorry day dimensions we can only enter the power d
so in two dimensions you need thirty six samples to get the same density of
four hours
sine wave original time-life problem and in
ten dimensions
then you're going to have
six the pattem ten which is quite large number
OK so
there's a problem
OK that the amount of data we need goes up
in order to say that we well sampled goes up quite rapidly with their dimensionality
so the question is how do we know if the data well spaced so only
mention this OK
putting them on us on a fixed grid like like i did for that sign
is one
possibility if we're in a happy situation of being able to do experiments
OK so
somebody over here mentioned doing multiple experiments
a single conditions
that is something to be aspired to sort of problem we'd love to be able
to do
many many experiments at every single value of x and to choose our values of
x carefully and then we have a superb information
typically in data modelling problems particularly engineering once we don't have the luxury of doing
experiments at all
what we do is
get samples from
something we're measuring anyway
OK i did some work some years ago for what was then british steel and
they measured
i mean it
about a hundred and sixty pressures and a hundred and sixty temperatures on a blast
hopelessly muddled
one label it
you need to be sure that you get minds and classes
so for the careful KVL
i would like to do is let's started c
let's say i started c
and from c and we got a
in would be
from the american back c
that's hard reversed my little
the trick will follow
it is as i
as my finger walks through
and labeled which was the first sign that i see for that
OK so i'm going start from c
and i go up
i start by pointing into
the elements the water sought elements and pointing towards the minus sign for the beano
is understood right down the minus
then i go through
they come up to a input on b
it points to the plus sign up to the one
so that's a plus b one
and then punch into the plus sign of the week
so i guess plus two and that is zero
so that that matters which have not as well so this is sort of the
first equation
similarly i can go through my other loops and write down the equations for
and the convention that i like to follow is go to the loop
i i don't
as the sign for the page
the first find the encounter for that
you can do the exact opposite if you want to be different but you know
one of the longest a consistent it would be OK
all right so in the same manner here
there are four that i can afford equation again one of them turns out to
dependent on the others so end up getting
three independent equations so i get
a total of twelve equations
the equations
six elements
OK what and five resistors
there are six unknown voltages and six unknown currents
two sets of equations and growth
twelve unknowns can take all the equations
put them through
a big crank
and so that and grind
and if i was really crowell give give this is a homework problem
and have grinding grain grain grinding you get your six voltages and six current
OK it works
OK you get from the equation
and this method
just works
notice that
this is quite a wider grubby methods wide-ranging
i get equations and
it's what i've been doing for simple circuit like this
suffice it to say that this fundamental methods
is just one step away from maxwell's equations simply works
so what we do is that in the rest of this lecture
i'll introduce you to a couple methods one is an intuitive method
and another one called the node method is limited formal but uses is much more
i guess much more errors
and the KVL KCL method
method two
so the relevant section to read in the course notes is
section two point four
one of the things that would be stressing this semester is intuition
OK what you find
what you'll find that has become much easier as majors and so on and go
or if you talk to your desire professors and so on you will find that
very rarely they actually go ahead and apply the former methods of analysis
OK by and large
engineers would look at the circuit and simply by observation i don't
and usually in the past what it's like to do is
ignored that process
and foreign students that look the former methods and you will know develop their own
intuition and be able to do it
what way trying do this term is distressed the intuitive methods
anthony show you how into the process goes so you can very quickly solve many
of the circuit simply by by inspection
OK so this method and show you here
is one such intuitive method
and i call it the element
combination rules
OK for many simple circuits can you can solve them very quickly by applying this
components of this method are these
i learned about how to compose a bunch of elements so let's say for example
i have a sort of resistors
one through the end
in cities
you can use KVL
and KCL
are to show
is equivalent to
a single resistor whose value is given by
the sum of the resistances
OK so you have a resistance in series then effectively it's the same as if
there was a single resistor values the sum of all the resistances
you can look at the course notes for a proof of
for the formation of this fact
similarly if i have
it the sensors and power
so we call them conductances
conductance is
the reciprocal of a resistance
if the distance is measured in ohms
conductance is measured in mos image
so so that's the conductance g one g two
and g three
they're effectively
and these are the different voxels here these are the different samples of brain activity
and you can divide your data into training and test data the problem is the
this question you could very easily addressed in with information theory
mutual information for example the problem is that the dimensionality is far too high
for you to be able to estimate this i mean you don't have very many
so i mean how to deal with this this is something that yakov is currently
looking into
one way we're doing this is to use in canonical correlation analysis
canonical correlation analysis is a way what you do is you basically have two
multivariate variables you try and find projection of each of these variables
that maximizes correlation between these two
and then we do this for training data set and test data so you can
see that here we do this this is the first canonical variates
here as quest as a function of the
it's kind of like autocorrelation function some of the multivariate autocorrelation function
so basically what actually cross correlation function is shifting the activity in both great areas
with respect to each other and you can see as you might expect to get
to peak around zero time lag but if you then go to the test you
can see that you get sometimes you get these kind of skewed distributions and part
of this is explained by the autocorrelation of a my signal
one thing you can do you can you can try and analysed systematically analyse the
this cross correlation function here this multivariate cross correlation function here
and then try and c
get the a hint that
information blowing from one brain area to another area
and so to measure the asymmetry basically measure the correlation
with the like one too positive like minus one minus two and you compute the
distribution of these image values and this is what you can see here on the
bottom left
is it the colour coding tells you the direction of symmetry
basically information seemingly flow from the brain area from brain area a to b
or from b to
and that's on the right here
is a man
that tells you that is is very hard to to the coherency analysis that you
can do with it e energy is or is very hard to visualize them but
you can see here that there are a number of arras tell you information flow
from one brain area to another brain area or you could say
one brain area having predictive information about the buildup of the pattern in the second
brain areas it to point in time and what you can see here is that
this effect seems to hold these two regions frontal polar cortex because this have
predictive information of the build up of information occurs later in the supplementary motor area
and but according to you have to be careful with this because of course there's
is a hidden variable in this hidden variable is
the predictive information i've already shown you previously
so in this this already says you're going to expect this
the degree but i think the key point is this something that is extremely fascinating
is the question of trying to find multivariate multivariate conductivity measures
so try to understand not
the consequent activity measure is just some simple correlation that most people use never mind
what this is about is trying to tell you how to build up of information
one brain area is related to the information of the brain area
and just just to mention that we did more of these studies so this is
study where you can see determinants of high level decision means where people again have
to make the adding or subtracting tasks so you can see very similar pattern again
frontal polar cortex impecunious
and another interesting point is that the buildup of this information
the question how this is related to other slow process in the brain
so there is no other slow process in the brain but really talks about and
that's the default network
mister before network is medial prefrontal cortex and petunias these activity in these two brain
there's always goes up when people are in the scanner on the avatar
so say your scanner and you have to do ten is the calculation of the
them and then this
default network goes up
activity in the simple network is called full network
what i show you is that is
the area is very similar to the areas that contain information about people about people's
prospective memory
between the different species in the system
so you have the whole park which has resulted in these two
see that
i'd like to do talking lot about feedback loops
because these are the things that made in the dynamics and the quality qualitative dynamics
you will also see that i chosen image to give you feedback loops into this
no there
the point being to actually create when we're actually looking at our research programs
remember to actually
look at all the kinds of feedback loops that we will be there
in your self organizing
this is
it's not always easy to capture ghosts this because
nonlinear one of the of the service
there is also interesting for to me and i don't quite understand how it works
possibly by people study groups in study organisations in a study collective
have the water back on local orderings
and this is also very interested in self organizing system this is what happens here
to merge the essentials influences the time local interactions with tried and this is how
to see what's going on in small interactions and how
eustace is being maintained by the way how is a single point
it's multiple points
and how self-regulation is actually
happening now what this is function
all the dendrites
and to by a chapter at university
and created decorative structures from the parameters so that means that the global granulation of
the glory i back into injuries mathematical models modelling tool and is able to generate
the local structure and of the structure
it doesn't make any sense and i'm making this you human know
i don't try to the mathematical model what's in your kind of structure in the
brain to that
the ensembles and self organizing systems will continue some ways we call it inuit
organisation and this generates new functions and new structure get function
the function possibilities
four different kinds of fish monastery
but not necessarily more just
and with different information processing capabilities and that's the
what kinds of information processing capabilities what structure to get you
and so on
that's a conceptual break philosophical right
with anybody like clarification about too general
two months specific
was used
and so my data
the engineering works the moment and staying constant building block
and so decided to apply to pretty because that's a separate from set was understand
it was the basis for these these and then when we get to the idea
to just a few examples of what did was connections model and that bring
in sense down to context
so we could just try and terminates on ideas to
use which is that the most important for me
so hopefully that
but the school i want to
it does
yes it does but now how big is the memory of how much more is
needed this the most beautiful beautiful research
right i and back to model it was surely the
children and i'd like to look at the time and memory that you need in
order to get to the next one organisation in fact from the fact that you
do in memory
so you can get memory
cases have a real-time right here situated in active
behaviour with absolutely no need for any information about what's the before which is what
you find virtual organizations
outside of structure
there's nothing that gives you any ideas that strategy
new structure that you
because when connected to the
well inactive
you start the dynamic process gets created three
the interaction of behaviour of the system
so it constantly interacting constantly processing information generating patterns organising certain
well connected increased
you get the transition into a new form of more stable necessary morgan that's not
necessarily better able to come process information
this is just
well OK so that would be a change OK
that we should i don't know
you know i don't
one of the disease
well i think that's called meta cognition
there's nothing
so what you
two technological one
i one instruments one extension
year what seems to be similar behaviour
they never married that
and then goes to another way
and fact the
large-scale behaviour over time
and it's back again and again if anybody can explain this better than that
know there are ways of bounding this generalization and probably the tightest is the PAC
Bayes bound so I'll just show you that and that will be the motivation if you
like for the particular optimization if you're interested in this more detail of this I'll
be talking about this afternoon so the way you you measure margin is simply
by taking the the label multiplying it by the actual underlying linear function value
so remember in order to get the classification we're just gonna take the sign
of this function you know if it's bigger than zero positive if it's less than zero
negative but obviously we're interested in how much bigger than zero and how much
less than zero so before we take the sign we just multiply it by the label so
this will now be positive if it's correctly classified so it's a positive example plus
one and this is positive then it's correctly classified as negative example and this is negative
if it's correctly classified and if it's wrongly classified it's gonna be negative so the margin is
positive if it is correctly classified and we're interested in in fining hyperplanes that sort
of keep that margin as large as possible
so the margin of a linear function is just the minimum over the training data
of this of this margin in fact we typically maximize this but allow some margin
errors so some of the points may fail to meet that that minimum margin so here's
a sort of classic picture I'm sure you've all seen you know the hyperplane
the positive data the negative data and there's a clear separation and the points that
are at the distance here are distance gamma or the you know the margin from
the hyperplane so the bound that I'm gonna sort of suggest motivates this is this
PAC bayes bound which basically says that the probability of missclassification of a
test point can be bounded by this quantity here now K L inverse is just a
way of sort of inverting this equation here which says that the difference between Q and P
is bounded in some way by A so A being small makes P and Q
close so if I specify Q and A I know that P can't be too big
and basically P's the thing I'm interested in and Q is my empirical error and
A is my measure of complexity and so this is what I actually am bounding
here so this is sort of our bound on P the true error I have to
put a factor of 2 in don't worry about that but this is my
proxy for the empirical error but it's a margin based measure and this is my
proxy for the for the sort of complexity term and basically what the empirical error
measures is the average of this margin multiplied by mu so mu is a factor I can
optimize it's a trade-off between increasing margins here but paying a penalty here by the
complexity it's basically the norm of the weight vector that I'm I'm varying here
and so this quantity F tilde is just the earth function inverted so
it's sort of the bigger the margin the smaller penalty I pay going to
zero as as if this goes to infinity as this goes the margin goes to
zero you pay zero point five and as you get more and more misclassified
you pay up to one here and so this is sort of an empirical average
of the margin and and then this is your you which you can boost by
varying mu and this is the penalty you pay for varying mu so now if you
think about optimizing this you want to optimize this quantity while controlling this quantity and
the slack variable now you can't see this cause there's another line here but the this
is the slack variable optimize thing that you optimize and the support vector machine superimposed
on this is a line that corresponds to the this quantity here this this sort of
inverse of the cumulative normal distribution and so what I'm saying is if we sort
of take as a proxy for this this line and so opstim optimize the
average rather than of this F tilde of this quantity here and for the
other quantity here we just have the norm squared then you end up with this
optimization so you minimize the norm squared of the weight vector plus the sum of these
xis which are the measuring how far you up that slope which is basically the amount
like this was first marketed that actually this function will be trivial to do
was only able do then is you would sit
CIJ is still to be i the j
prior to actually one minus that so that's the type of such that
it's zero only if
vertex i
of the graph first graph and vertex j after six graph after same
and then you optimize away
that's not the interesting case we interested in finding more general scientist
is the hungarian marriage
so let's say here's some hungarian man yes some hungarian women
so i'm not very good at drawing and they all need to get married to
each other
and so they all have a preference
for each other so for instance hungarian men five like maybe hungarian woman six
more than he likes number two number three with a
so they have some pairwise happiness
and you know that at the end of the day and they all must get
so what you do is
you've been trying to find the permutation
which maps
while the hungarian manner
to all the hungarian women
in such a way that the overall happiness is
the unhappiness is not minimize so the CIJ from before are basically unhappiness course
so it's say for instance hungarian man number three hates number five
c i j
c three five will be very large
people have studied this problem for a long time
this for instance the on munkres algorithm
which sources
so just writing out the optimisation problem again
so we minimize piping permutation matrix
five IJCAI j
under the constraints applied j
has interested in one
and the matrix is doubly stochastic
you can actually go and show
but you can relax this optimisation problem here
which is an integer problem
to one that's a linear programme
so what's different
for all i have done is i've just replaced this
integral constraint here
one interval constraint
we can clearly see that this is a linear objective function point
you can see that all the constraints are linear
so i've got a linear objective function linear constraint i can clearly just go and
so solely by using a linear programming solver
you would probably actually do something slightly smarter than that
and use
for instance something like quick match or some other algorithms which
well space you specific properties of this optimisation problem but
in theory you can do it
now y
would actually solve this problem if i want to solve that one
well the nice thing about this problem is that
if you look at the polytope
which contains all of feasible solutions FI
so basically
all those doubly stochastic matrices
we know that for linear programming
the optimality is achieved at one of the vertices
anyone would
let's say
that's the polytope that contains all the points
and if no
all those coordinates here are integers
we know that since
and optimality
five star is going to sit at one of those vertices if they all have
only into integral trees
then i know that the solution of this problem is equivalent to that
that the phi j's will only be are series one
the reason why this works is because the concert this constraint matrix
it is so called totally unimodular
and it actually a fairly large class of discrete optimization process chapters nice property
the reason why mentioning it is because quite often you might actually not find itself
related to the truth value of what you put in here
because this thing
it doesn't have as much interesting logic perhaps it
some of the other
but with connected k we can build up
sentences of arbitrary
for the purposes of classical
we concentrate on just a few of these
these two
we like
we also like all
either or
we like
or if
a binary connectives put it you put into
the negation not
it's not true that
is connective
just for notational convenience we give ourselves some notation for writing these things
and we usually right
like this
binary operation you also see
the ampersand or adopt or
other notations or even just simply juxtaposition
for the conjunction for for and
four disjunction
we're on the same thing upside down and that seems to be
common symbol for that you also see vertical stroke or other things but
this today
notations that i use
four negation
denying things
i shall right
this corner
you also sees in the literature and places it till the
or a minus
of other things sometimes you then see letters for these
OK a
but we can use this column
and it's
for the conditional
implications material implications
people used to say
i shall use arrow
single arrow
so those will be
basic connectives
in the literature you'll also see double arrow quite commonly or hawk
or other things
i guess all the letters c
but will use these and with these we can build up
of any complexity
right the other thing we need to be able to do with this languages generalise
so we don't just want to be able to say
canberra is bigger than captains flat
we want to say that
there is some city is bigger than cats
such that you see
it's never negative so that's the way to the first one and
i want to do do mornings and also
we tend to give human is to try to solve the
so maybe
maybe i'll give you the ones who have so the first one OK
so if you plug in the definition of the kernel into this
formula here
you know this
you know what you have to use the
product is actually a linear
so what does this mean means you can
these provisions inside
you can also some insight
so what you do is you have to move
the AI can efficiency
in this part of the dot product
you have to move
a j
so this the product
likewise you move the sum over time
here in the hall j here
if you do that then you probably see how it works
don't be shy because of security and i'm not going to work can admitted
OK so maybe i'll give you the solution of the first one now
and then maybe i'll give you a few hints about the other one
OK so
so as i mentioned before
the dot product is not so you can move coefficients in some sense i i'm
actually going to move
everything related to i to this part of the dot product everything related to data
this part
so then i get this
what i a i
five x i
and here the sum over j
now if you look at this for a second you can see
this is actually the same as this just
i mean a name for the for the summation index but it doesn't matter
this is the same vector this one so this may be of the form
times vector
since we assume that is the dot product
the dot product of a vector with itself is actually always nonnegative
o assumptions
this dot product
it can be negative
in any questions about this part
so it
you know what i'm what i'm using here
is the fact that k corresponds to the can be written
the product the product in space right i'm not assuming that k is positive i
just assume k can be reached
like this
these angular brackets denote the products
and then i'm using the facts
and plug it in the definition
of positive definite term to verify
what actually is nonnegative
and then i know it's positive definite at this point here under substituting it i
don't know whether it is positive or negative and i go through use the fact
that this is the sort of product i know that in the end i see
that is negative
because and also some hints for the other problems
so in the second problem
the hindus you should consider a set of points
so nobody in the definition of positive definite kernels
you have
since the end points and coefficients corresponding to them
just to prove the second property
you should only consider one point
and what efficient
so i think about
liquid again doesn't not some kind of backwards when you think that you start with
gas atoms far apart then you move closer you get liquid atoms and you press
the liquid out to get solid
but water special
water special because the bonding in the solid is more open than bonding in the
liquid and i can look at this and say because when i press
from solid to liquid
this tells me that the density of the solid is lower than the density liquid
i look at that i say
i scube slow
i students flow and there are other there are other
systems for which the same happens i hear silicon
look it's silicon
here's the phase diagram for silicon pressure versus temperature you see
down here it's FCC the diamond cubic structure
and if we go there's the melting point of silicon we go to the liquid
it's got more nearest neighbour how many nearest neighbours there's the solid had its sp
three hybrids has four nearest neighbours most liquids have about six nearest neighbours
so when you have these open structures like silicon germanium the silicate glasses and i
you actually go to a more condensed system when you first liquefied and this is
how you skate by the way
you know you down here one atmosphere but minus five degrees c and you put
your weight on the blades so that's the mass which then becomes the force on
a small area which becomes the pressure and then that allows you
the cross this line so you go i don't thin film of water
and if the temperature gets really cold
it's down here around minus twenty and i've had the pleasure skating one it's minus
my mass
converted to of appropriate pressure on the blades is not high enough to cross this
and skating experience is very different because now it's just it's just steel blades on
and it's you don't get traction
to put it simply you fall
OK you all not good not good OK so let's let's look at a few
others if we contrast here this is the limit simple fcc metals and what we
see with aluminum in this case it's normal liquid has about six to eight nearest
neighbors and the solid has twelve nearest neighbours so
the solid is denser than the liquid you see that the phase diagram
here's nitrogen nitrogen is are let's see what we have it's at one atmosphere pressure
melting point is sixty three kelvin its boiling point seventy seven kelvin you remember that
because MIT is seventy seven mass
so nitrogen boils at seventy seven kelvin
and the triple point is down here it's it's about one hundred of the degree
and it turns out it's about an eighth of an atmosphere pressure this is the
triple point of nitrogen ice in boiling liquid nitrogen but this has a positive slope
so this means that the solid nitrogen ice sinks to the bottom of the liquid
nitrogen i thought since it's friday maybe we could have just a little bit of
fun here with liquid nitrogen so i'm going to get dressed first have to practice
a science i have to send an example for you see i this year one
of my staff patrick trapezoid what to wear lab coats i said OK
i tried it
try to do this problem
this is work which which designed did you go to the
valentino over such
what going because nitrogen
it's gets some nitrogen
have some fun and so we're going to be working at seventy seven kelvin
and for those of you on the back to put this up on
monitors no food in the laboratory put that over there
four this
OK so
so the first thing we do is let's let's look at glass transition temperatures so
i have some rubber gloves or have to face crazy over this way
OK creating to do with this so here's some rubber gloves and so you know
you can hear that there
are acting lassiter above thirty g so this is just covalent bonds
what i wanna do
as a former member nitrogen here
and know if you noticed but these gloves are chiral
just justification or
i chose chiral gloves
OK so now
so they
so the below the glass transition temperature on sorry crazy
get to
so how did one more time
got a glass transition temperature also if you wanted to drill the
if you want to draw the rubber stopper of course now you can hear the
key to the site so you can hear that
it's robbery drop in their little mind its own business also-ran rap it's also got
glass transition temperature
so we can show that
going into liquid nitrogen
OK so
here are flexible now
OK now you can hear how it changes
i should have been wearing gloves and all that
OK how about protein or you know the other thing we can do thing we
can do is i wanna make some liquid oxygen so i don't know can we
just cut to the to the computer slide for second one show people what we're
going to do here
this next one
so what do is to put a graduated cylinder inside filled this with liquid nitrogen
and these are the boiling points of oxygen argon and nitrogen and nitrogen is at
seventy seven so this is all seventy seven kelvin but oxygen condenses ninety so we're
gonna make liquid oxygen with a little bit of argon ice
the truth
all talking a minute
it says that
this pattern has
support of this in a slight they don't call probability because it's not a
you know it's only from this particular data set
therefore they use support so
in some sense if we feel a bit losing in our terminology you can say
probability of x
that belongs to the
class i
probability of that pattern belongs to class j
these probabilities are highly different
then we are interested in this
so if the same pattern as in probability
both classes
then this pattern doesn't tell us very much to
so that's basically the idea here
as long as the
the support is very large
then we are interested in this part
or you could use some kind of javascript tests saying that you to make the
so you can control that how big these patterns can be
and then just that what he is he actually used them
basically decision trees
to build these these patterns
so these rules
you know as i said earlier can be generated from decision trees so for example
i hope you know what decision trees right
so so if you know the decision trees all you have to do is you
start from the root
and go to the leaves
i say
you know you know by definition
the lead should be highly
dominated by one particular class
which means that expression
going along the branch is basically defined congress
leaf nodes should give you some description of
how get out there and that description is a contest
but unfortunately you know these are greedy methods and generally decision trees tend to one
so they don't capture the whole
the distribution of these patterns
so therefore you will miss many many useful patterns
so one of the ways you can remedy this is you know if you're not
really interested in all the patterns you can actually feel use random forest and collect
these problems and and of course when you do that and forest sometimes you discover
the same pattern
so what you have to do is make sure you know if you find the
same thing
but random forests pretty pretty fast algorithms and you can tell i really interesting patterns
so different contrast set mining algorithms that you know once you have decided you can
see economics going into building
you know variations of this definition variations of several of these algorithms
so for example you might have you might have a very good contrast pattern seems
the probability ratios or support ratio could be extremely large
the individual probabilities are extremely minor
you know for example
it's a very strange and never appeared in
in one case
but appeared only once which is just the noise
then you say well
you know it has contrast ratio infinity because in one case support is zero
the other cases you know
one and then but still the ratio is infinity so therefore you think it's very
hard but could be brought practical purposes
just the noise
so therefore
people try to put that all these patterns that you're interested
they should have a minimum support
in the dominant class then over dominant classes
and and sometimes we also have this notion that
they could be
i know there could be some kind of noise
so some patterns are allowed to have some minimality
you know the maximum probability of support it could have been other countries could be
so the latter the the support ratio
we believe that this is a more interesting
o or the difference could be latch
so there's a particular group of patterns that i was telling you which is called
jumping emerging patterns
these are
quite powerful in the sense that
you know this pattern x never appears
in the in the dataset one
but it appears in dataset two which means
it has basically infinite
growth in the sense
you know more from zero to
so these patterns are are quite
quite quite dominant quite powerful and maybe
they will tell us something really interesting in order to
the typically languages use these get to language that means
you're looking a conjunction of patterns
that means feature one taking this value
seven taking this value and features
you know
eleven taking this value this the kind of expression language we try to to use
if you try to use anything more computational complexities
horrible i mean even in this case it's horrible
but is or even worse
so this a particular dataset you know in the machine learning people use this come
from UCI
university of california irvine
so they have a group of of data data sets but is there some are
inconsistent some are synthetic some
actually collected
this particular one was called mushroom that is basically the two groups
the things that you can make the things if you if you die
the edible and
all poisonous
so in this case
they collected certain features
i think if i remember correctly it has about twenty three
different features
like one of the feature is this mountain in order
it has gone you know
and then stalk surface you know the stop
with a small tour of when these kinds of things
and and also it has the
the color
and it has a number of rings for example how many
rings it has
and so forth so for example
if you see a pattern like this you know you're somebody brings so much to
and you say oh it doesn't have any
that smell
and then you see that the start surface below the ring is small
you know it's it's reasonably small
and he has only one ring of these these rings that has
so now we have some knowledge that says that
the the support
is point two percent in the poisonous case
to see this kind of an observation
whereas in the labelled case we see
nearly fifty seven point six per cent of them had this but features
so we know that the ratio of this particular
these two hundred eighty eight so that means the are
are much more towards an ability rather than
o point
and of course on this just one if eat there's a good chance
that we must do that
because it is still present this so what you have to do is to collect
many many such patterns and the combination of them
is the one that gives you
much much higher confidence
so here is a nice example
and i'll give you the actual data later
so so let's assume we have two tissues one is normal tissue and the other
one is
cancer tissue
let's assume that we have somehow selected for groups of
each rule tells you
one particular tissues so here we have
eight issues four of them normal
and four of them
well do that thing with the starting again
so now we're going to look at problems with the same
you know this
this formula for the energy looks the same
but now we're going to allow x
to have
multi multivalued labels that we will have to be
and so this is clearly what we want it to go back to stereo and
the the full
stereo problem with all those different levels of disparity so xk is in that context
i will have
disparity values
and we need to be able to solve
real integer optimisation problem in that case
so what we do this
well here's one construction which is
a different graph construction that there
related to the last one but that is generalized to allow the multiple levels that
were previously
we had a single
row of nodes corresponding excels and the source and the sink
rose of nodes
each column corresponds to a pixel
and each row corresponds to
an integer values such as the disparity value
so now the convention is
if the cut in this graph
comes here
connecting leaving
the node four
excel with value one connected to the source but no others the source then we
interpret that as meaning that it one has value
big one here has value one a pixel to here has value two and so
on because of three here
as value to because
that is the
the first one that still can be connected to the source
and now we have to lay out cos along the edges of this graph in
such a way
as to represent
the real valued costs
that you see up here
the first thing is that
edges here get into the costs associated with them because it's not allowed
all the
curve here to cut through these because we have no meaningful interpretation of that
there are going to have to take a special form
such that the air for particular into into value is going to be
so the so
this page here is simply f one for this big cutting through this
incurs cost
corresponding to the the the
the the label on that day the weight on the stage and that that corresponds
to for the particular
the level of disparity at pixel k
horizontal edges
a little bit more complicated because although i haven't illustrated on this diagram we could
have just not just one level
but two levels supposing i jumped up to here
so the separating cross this and you also this week
then proceeded to the right we would have jump two levels once and so then
the cost incurred would have to be
he applied to one and three
so what that means is that this function g gets made up
as of some
of the costs on horizontal
links in this diagram
g one three is constrained to be the sum of g one two
he two three
there's definitely a constraint being applied here too
the nature of this
pairwise cost function
so supposing the
but see posing the horizontal
links here all constant cost on the
what gene function with that implements
but i think that was just a unit cost of all of these horizontal links
he function with the implementing
it would be
i guess
the function of the
one and here
the shock
it's just going to be the absolute differences so it's going to implement
x and x prime is going to have before
he to allow
x minus ex-prime minister prime
it will also
x is just going to be
the modulus x because what the gene function is doing in that case is simply
counting the number of horizontal links
the dog crossed by
by the separating by the cut
as it as it leaps of this diagram
so define the next level of the next node
so that you know that doesn't sound
a very versatile that's useful function actually
we'd like
what is much more useful though
it's something which is a mixture of that
the potts prior to the potts prior
is the icing prior for
labels so
potts prior something
is function g tilde like that one
which charges nothing
but when the when the difference between prime this is nothing but some fixed value
it's that function just like the i think belong on multiple a multiple label values
so this is a useful function because it's
it doesn't continue to penalize differences when they get
like for example in the image reconstruction that's very good because what happens is that
when two pixels are different you know the cost very different you don't have to
be more cost
you know it's like saying well
the discontinuity that we follow the edge of one object onto another object and having
decided that the cost to be paid for having edged that at the end of
the matter having more contrast across the doesn't change
so actually useful
it is something in between those
there's too where
the universal schedule which has been carefully worked out to maximize the benefit both for
the individual child
and for the community and to minimize the side effects
alternate schedules give credence to erroneous beliefs
and the and so
unfounded fears
i think they misinform by failing to distinguish between good and bad science
it leaves in infants vulnerable by
withholding vaccines for the period of
when they are most vulnerable to the adverse effects of disease and encourages basically free
riding or relying on immunization immunizing other people
in order to protect your child
finally by spacing out the schedule you're absolutely increasing the cost of immunizing community
have under-invested in vaccine safety science
questions have arisen and will continue to arise
resources to answer rapidly
that are not in
the budgets for vaccine safety
we need to study the factors associated with adverse reactions including the genetic potential genetic
we need to look at the efficacy and safety of vaccines in special populations what
i mean by special populations
individuals will who
who have for example congenital heart disease
individuals with
family histories of certain kinds of disorders
we need to increase the capacity to do large epidemiologic studies
i have shown and why they need to be large we need to explore greater
time window
after immunization we we look
first effects
this is
just a quick snapshot of how big a study has to be
to look at
an adverse reaction
so if you're looking at something that occurs about one hundred thousand times
you need about three hundred thousand people a year study
so the last rotavirus vaccine was licensed
was tested in seventy thousand children prior to license because we were looking for an
adverse event
with prior vaccine
occurred about one in ten
now on to the issue of risk communication
risk communication is complex
and i'm just touching here
we have a number of in britain biases two of them
just the way we are wired intellectually the omission bias bias is that it's safer
to do nothing
and to do something
and i come back to the withdrawal of rotavirus vaccine
we accept that more deaths
rather than
be responsible for aid
compression we overestimate rare risks and we underestimate common is
many of us suspect will never go out of golf course with an umbrella thunderstorms
but you might very well
drive to the shopping centre without putting to sea
that's it
good example of irrational behavior
the risks are far greater than the way the shopping center
and then there's this issue is the credibility of your information so source
and there's a belief in the future just remember statement the beginning
and if you read it well enough to exercise right
your immune system will be strong and you get sick
or you can protect your child somehow
from contagion
but what you feel or how much their size
talking to this audience it's
particularly important to emphasise that while good science is essential but it is not sufficient
it's complex junk science out there safety concerns are presented as plausible
and people's concerns are by and large often fear-based
and science along
is not sufficient
to overcome their fears
and just large enough
with scientific information
they have black
often lack trust in the integrity
of the expert spokesperson
and they have faith in told alternative billy
when you deal with issues that are of low concern
expertise is what people look to
they believe you if you are an expert but if you do deal with issues
of high concern
what they care about is your compassion not expertise
and i love this quote i just found it was from will rogers
very fairly
state-of-the-art segmentations of pretty complicated rich data from bayesian nonparametric models
there's some work on
the word segmentation again using bayesian nonparametric models
you know the the line involved in these papers is the bayesian nonparametric models compared
to competitors
so that gives you some comfort
there's still work in language modeling with
hierarchical pitman yor language model
which can give excellent results compared to
other competing methods
related work in compression
with the sequence memoizer
that is
beating state-of-the-art
compression algorithms
so there are success stories
i guess i'm just not involved in any of the work that's OK
so here's another one
from nacional man and holden
which compares support vector machines with the sparse former gassing process classifiers
and the interesting thing here is that on a whole bunch of different kind of
standard-issue CIS datasets
you get error rates for the SVM
and the gas in process and then sparse version of the guassian process which is
actually an approximation to the full gaussianprocess by the way
but it's a lot faster and it's a hell lot sparser OK so if you
look if you compare these columns here
if you look at the number of support vectors which is support vector machines are
supposed to be sparse
here's the number of support vectors for these different problems here is a sort of
roughly comparable quantity which is the number
basis points from sportscaster process
you know sometimes you get
very comparable performance
rather than
you know two rather than a hundred and twenty two
or something like that
and in this one does actually better than the SVM in this using exactly the
same kernel by the way
we could probably better if you
a lot of the kernel learning in guassian process which is certainly very very well
so you want to hear me ran more of the axioms
yes processes
i'm actually gonna speak more about that in the preference learning workshop
make some more enemies
and in fact i think this is policy but we're we're actually pursuing and much
systematic large-scale comparison
because people are so damn interested in classification
so with alex things first replying kind of
really flesh out this comparison little more
OK so
i want to talk briefly about covariance matrices modelling covariance which is different kind of
structure that we can model here i think we do have
actually this is what maybe there's the trend there's been recent works
where i think we have
competitive results with
are methods
so why why would be interested in modeling covariance matrices
well the problem of the covariance matrices as a
change as a function of time or during
is actually interesting to a lot of people and they tend to be people in
the common
we're looking at the relationship between a bunch of different variables
the change over time
and the models are commonly used in things like multivariate garch
multivariate stochastic volatility models
x this article sigma inverse right so but we at sparsifying regularizer on x which
is our estimate sigma inverse right now we turn the crank on lambda to trade
sparsity of the inverse versus
versus fit here OK
and i mean this is something that's been so i mean just some of the
things people have looked at it actually others have two including people here it's just
talking to someone before
OK so
what do you do again it's only you just do the x equals the thing
about it will see some splittings that don't involve this embarrassing
splitting here
and you get something that looks like this here's your this thing
we know how to minimize that we have to call quadratically augmented
this we have to deal with because that's going to be a soft threshold right
so on the x step you minimize this thing
and otherwise you do is far side sorry a soft thresholding you do this then
update and so you look at this for a while and you can solve this
you know lbfgs or something like that you look at it long enough and it
should start dawning on u u we can solve that
semi analytic actually analytic right certainly can solve that analytical analytically right and the key
would be to say look without loss of generality we can do this for x
for this unilaterally invariant so you can assume that x is a is diagonal then
splits and it turns out this is unilateral invariant to frobenius norm squared so you
can solve this analytically
it's just this you compute and i can decomposition
and then you solve quadratic involving the eigen values and then reassembled OK so it
says that the cost is an idea composition so again you know you're right a
blind script and you know it's not i totally and optimize
and then optimize you get something that's you know within a factor of ten or
something like that of the state of the art
type think for something like this right which again for maximum coding time i mean
like i five minutes or something like that maybe forty five minutes of pencil and
paper to do that they worked out what the update is this is not that
what we now it was that that definitions up that that section and the point
there's just by assembling these bits and pieces
you can actually do stuff with this i mean quite
quite quickly you can get something up and running
OK now look at
distributed optimisation and to do that we're just going to look at
two canonical problems one month in much more detail than the other which is consensus
and so it's sort of like the canonical
like it's the first it's the whole world of
distributed optimisation and it's got a beautiful interpretation it's the it's very simple
but i'd honestly want to understand this
you understand all you understand other distributed optimisation problem so OK
or at least this is a stepping stone to it you we want to minimize
a sum
of functions of the variables and these functions because if you want to think of
the something i think of that phi is the loss function for the i th
block of training data
so that that's what it is right it's some something like that
and so you can make some big deal and you could say oh this is
like collaborative filtering because you see i have all these different data sources and they're
going to combine and minimize the total loss and come up with an axe that's
better than any of them by themselves might have come up with something make big
story about so that's that's the problem OK
so we simply write this way again it's quite stupid what you do is you
allow each one has its own private opinion
so instead of a global variable x they all have their own local opinion XII
and you have a constraint that says you can have your own good local opinion
but but it has to be in concert they'll have to be agree with this
global variables e again it doesn't these things look so obvious and silly that it
doesn't look like anything good is going to come from this right OK
that's the idea
just turn the crank u four men augmented lagrangian
you minimize it turns out this first one obviously splits entirely so the only thing
you have to do is approx
is approx operator on each phi
then you do all how do you how do you minimize the stadium over e
well that's
trivial this is totally irrelevant a bunch of linear functions that's a bunch of quadratic
technologies quadratic functions is the norm squared i'm ERD minimize that like an average i
mean it's for it's political justice thing
this can even be simplified more because it turns out
the sum of the dual variables is zero
and so it turns out you end up with a very very simple algorithm it's
just beautiful and it looks like this
it's this it says each what each it's it each
work whatever subunit or agent separately minimize their function plus the linear terms that's irrelevant
of course is just first statics right was the linear terms
plus this quadratic and the quadratic penalizes you from moving from the last
average and i mean if you send a message to this thing and say OK
time's up please give me what tell me what x is you an average all
of the opinion local opinions and that would be many the winds averaging work well
because everything is convex and so jensen's inequality says you average and things get better
OK so that's what
that's the idea so you get this beautiful quadratic penalty
for everything and you can sort of understand all the bits and pieces of this
right so in fact this would be a dual decomposition
right there
this with the penalty
and then this as you have the quadratic regularisation you me towards the mean and
makes the algorithm go from quite
are non robust fragile to utterly and completely robust and you can see it's like
a scatter gather to think that you know what it's not even its not together
even that is is not correct and that the wrong way of course the average
million vectors of size millions the exactly wrong method would be
to gather them all in one place and average them so but i you know
what i mean by this so
the statistical interpretation is absolutely beautiful it says this
if you want to basically what this is let's do distributed maximum likelihood street maximum
likelihood says i have a bunch of data blocks each each one never have those
are encased that i have i and the only thing i have to do is
only one method i have to implement for each box each box of data the
and the only thing you have to do is approx operators right you have to
be able to minimize i have to be able to pass in this thing in
this thing or for that matter i combine these into one thing i pass in
one thing
and then i had i say minimize your loss function plus the quadratic
but minimizing loss function plus the quadratic has very simple interpretation is just MAP estimate
x maximum a posterior probability estimation with the gas in prior to the only thing
that you have to implement on each of these data boxes or anything like that
is a is a map methods so that's it
it doesn't matter what the measurements are how many there are utterly irrelevant the only
reason that method you send to the box a prior with the gaussians