a positive integer
so far those clusters then
this thing is
is finite so we have
alfalfa k so k is very large integers so this public is going to be
a very small number no plus a positive integer so this time is not going
to be zero and that which is not going to be zero so this things
perfectly well defined
so what about forty and the clusters and also for the clusters for which there
is actually no data associated with
those clusters this and here was going to be zero
right and of course we're going to be in trouble because we're going to have
a problem
alfalfa ketumile here
this can be really small so the probability that
it item being assigned to that particular class there will be arbitrarily small scale becomes
very very large
so what happens then
well we can really do anything about what we can do is to say that
if we lump all of this difference
and the classes together
right so this
a lot of them
and hopefully it'll council of this small probability alpha divided by k
and it does happen so what's the you can work out the probability that they
tied i being assigned to an empty cluster
is going to be proportional to alpha alpha k
multiplied by the number of clusters in a mixture model
and case by is the number of occupied clusters
and k minus case studies more-or-less k
because k is much larger than that
so this term here is going to be OK and that was going to be
OK as well is this simply going to be the marginal probability of the data
x y where we integrate out the parameters for the cluster
as k goes to infinity and also
let's see what happens so
as big k goes to infinity this term is going to go to zero
this term here
it is going to go to one
OK stylized funded by and
and came in this case that over k is going to be more less one
for large k
this thing
it doesn't account cannot be his
they're all simply the marginal probability of the data
no other data points
now we
we don't OK
OK so
we do that
so that goes to zero this goes to one
so now
the probability of the data item i to cluster k
you simply cannot be proportional to
the cut
the current number of data items there assigned to cluster k
multiplied by the likelihood and divided by some of the normalisation constant
and the probability of
this data item be assigned to a an empty cluster
so you can think of this as i guess i should call these components rather
than clusters so the probability that
the that if i is going to be assigned to
and the component is going to be proportional to alpha
times the probability of x i
the marginal probability of x i will be have integrate out the parameters of the
components and we have and minus one plus alpha ten
now here this constant into not
so we can think of this as introducing new components to explain the data
and this
basically reusing components to explain this particular data point
of course they put the maximum number of components that this model uses and most
so now we can
go back to ODP them all
do the same is exactly the same
samples from the prior
you can see that it is also has bumps of structures looks quite similar to
define an action model
at the two data points here we're going to have to have a lot more
mass you know
but of course we always have mass
going also to
so that that's
try to create as many clusters as we can
i'm not sure this will see
so so it
we need more data points because there's currently very few data points here so it
becomes has decided that it doesn't really really need that many clusters to explain
explain to you add more and more
data points here hopefully
creating cluster here
OK and among these two clusters again it's
saying that there's not enough data points here so i'm not going to use two
clusters to explain you just use one of the cluster
so this
but two points here
hopefully it will also create false cluster
so you see that you know it's
this editor useful clusters
more point in the
and hopefully will start to split this cluster into two
seems to be working on so it was decided that the five classes you can
as well as many classes as you want and you just keep on using more
and more clusters as was
so that's infinite mixture model
well it's doing gibbs sampling the question is
how do you control the trade went to introduce new clusters went to not introduce
i see no reason shaking hands well it's close
it's pretty close
probably yes
yes in that's what we call studios generalizations
which is you get the response to
civil war
but suppose
the edge of their abilities
there is much higher
or or much slower
in that case we might get a reaction from the dog to dog is discriminate
between the stimuli
we call that stimulus discrimination so it's it's recognising that
die or human being
i will respond to
similar one
but that but that generalization will only go so far
and then the organism will discriminate
and will not respond to the stimulus
is to do
by by now you probably have seen that
classical conditioning
does not explained very complex
it's rather so we can say the last conditioning
explains only simple behaviors such as
drawings such as primitive emotional reactions which is here or excitement
we think of classical conditioning you should think about
should be
relatively simple here
and yet as i said cluster is important because it tells us that neutral stimulus
can evoke the same criminal behavior such as here has been natural systems
organisms can make substitutions
from the initial stimulus
for this
primitive response yes
that stimulus substitution
does occur
so let's go going to the slide
i don't know how long did his work in russia
these concepts over two
in the early part of the twentieth century
a he
very important in the history of psychology
was john b
what's what's it was a
a faculty member at johns hopkins university
that time
johns hopkins either recently was the first
united states
offer doctorate
we're really was a
researchers are free to choose and john watson was active
in the early days of psychology in america
pushing a certain
version psychology which is psychology as a scientific
in our brain and
you can imagine there you know other versions of psychology in europe for example
they were less designed by right
well what's and wanted a particular
this version of psychology that focuses on observable behavior so he pushed the years to
as the only legitimate
or psychology
his most famous experiments
in involved
a baby boy who has come to be known to us as
little here is heard of little house
that the nearest seen pictures of this video because allow
very interesting stuff and watson is in those c
in conditioning will
well if you
many of the story here
our little however was not afraid of rats
he would see a white rat and
i want to touch you was shown evidence that here at all
what's in a range of experiments in which
when the white rabbit here
and the first one i wanted to show you about
there is an argument for
you see
just this one
when can also show you this is this is also kind of this is a
you get a few very
if it works
in this case
OK i hope my computer hasn't lost more videos so here we have an interesting
application of support vector regression possible to a program called implicit surface approximation
so what's implicit surface approximation
so the problem is you
you've got some
some data
sampled from the object
assume x is some three-dimensional object you have a set of surface points which you
might have acquired for instance using laser scan of the object
and you are trying to estimate a function with the property that it's zero on
the surface of the object non-zero elsewhere
so you have you want to function which is
the above zero
on this set and if you want on the on the component is non-zero and
most specifically this one particular such a function which is particularly nice for football
processing and this function is called the signed distance function
so let's look at the two-dimensional surface of an object
so the signed distance function has the property that at any given point in space
its value modulus
absolute value will be equal to the distance of that point from the surface of
the object
and the sign of the function will be positive outside the object negative inside the
OK so this function is negative in here positive party out here and it crosses
you're exactly on the surface of the object
signed distance function
and you can estimate the scientists function from the time in different ways and you
can get representations like this you can represent such objects as the zero sets of
support support the expansions the training algorithm is a modified form of support vector regression
maybe i don't have to go into details on that you get such solutions and
then one of the nice things is you can try to do
so maybe i'll show you to your own this lines you can try to do
things like more between objects
take something
might have it
and with the help of better version of it
so what's the problem of morphing suppose we have a for two different heads of
a man and woman
and you would like to compute the head which is somewhere in between so i'm
assuming has given us three d objects
and i would like to compute a three d object which is somewhere in between
if i just take the linear combination of these two heads i won't get very
good results because these objects are not in correspondence because i don't know where are
the eyes well the noses and so on
so what you would like to do is you would like to compute its solution
which does something like this
and i'll tell you how to do this hard to compute this kind of solution
from signed distance function estimated from using support vector machines
so the way it works is
so if you have two different objects
so it's a have one person which looks like this
another person which
he has like this
you would like to estimate what people call wall field so that the mapping which
given a point in this
on this object will
i tell you
what's the corresponding point on this object so it's a mapping in this case from
two r two
of course this is if you
just write like this you don't see it how you can solve this problem but
the way we work is that
first of all you would like this mapping to have the property of course that
each surface point here will be mapped to a certain point over here really a
little constraint but it turns out this is not enough it but if you enforce
that warping not only maps surface points to service points but it actually keeps the
value of the scientists function invariant
then you're in business it turns out so what does that mean so you have
assigned distance function for this subject you have one for this objective function which is
negative and a positive out here simple there's been asking the signed distance function should
be invariant means in particular
points where the function is zero should be point not point about this function is
zero points which are
one centimeter outside of this object to be mapped to point out one centimeter outside
of this subject and so on and if additionally you use just stand up support
vector machine regularizer it turns out that this is something like it in the last
of vector regression problems
which we can solve and solving it we can get this fairly nice morphs between
these objects
let's see what i can show in terms of results i think i had a
pretty nice one and here
so here we've got them off computed between human and monkey
and the state transition so pair of tags which are adjacent in the sentence
now typically these feature vector representations will look at all kinds of features of the
input sentence conjoined with these two tags so might for example be sensitive to the
fact that cake
it's being assigned the tag now
or maybe the technologies here we have some surrounding context in the string and so
on and so on
and one of the nice things about crfs is the freedom with which you can
define these feature vectors
so the i
for cns looks like the family so the optimal
state sequence y staff particular input x
is the right maximizes the sum of two terms
so here i have some of the and positions in the sentence on something of
position by position
and in this position essentially state transition because so pair of labels just i showed
and in the state transitions gets a score
this an into the inner products between the vector w and the feature vector
so you can think of these inner products as being a measure of the plausibility
probability of this particular state transition this particular
position in the sentence
we can find the highest scoring state sequence using the viterbi algorithm
because the
the last decomposes in this way we can use dynamic programming to search through the
space of possible structures efficiently
because that's zero
the big question is how do we know
generalize the same style models to parsing
so a couple of options one which has been explored
it is to think about context free grammars
the representations the context free grammars induce and how this can be leveraged within CRF
the alternative which to talk about next
is based on alternative tree adjoining grammars
this work by arab and jewish in many of his colleagues
OK so tags or the tree adjoining grammars
so this was originally chinese these grammars like i can do anything close to justice
for instead of going to describe a fairly simple tag like formalism that we've applied
recently into this particular problem
OK so in context free grammars
the basic elements in the grammar set of these rewrite rules
in tree adjoining grammars
the grammar is essentially defined by a set of what are called elementary trees
so these look like tree fragments
and in this particular case the using elementary trees in the simple spine like structures
so the structures and grammar look like lexical items
which is often called the anchor of the tree
some small
substructure but some small fragmentary above it
so for example may has a couple of levels going up to an MP
it has a few more levels
and so on so these are the basic units
in tree adjoining grammars
so the question is how we got larger pieces of syntactic structure
and so in general they are
basic operations which can be used to combine these military fragments into larger pieces of
and the operation the news today is something called sister junction
so sister junction basically takes
two these spines that just showing
and joins them together combines them to form a larger piece of the syntactic structures
in particular and this disjunction operation takes one spine modifier
which is the main spine here
and the spine which is called the head that's the inspiron here
in addition it takes the position at which the modifier spine
attaches underneath that's fine
so underneath this as position
OK so this is a primitive upcoming operation that combines these two trains and essentially
forms the rule goes to NP VP at this point in the tree
so we can keep going
and actually you can imagine a full parse tree for the sentence
essentially being formed
by a series of these kind of junction operations
so let see the
constraints on these production operations are the costs so regular grammars you might have some
constraints on how these things can combine exactly with different elementary trees can join
in that case we simply use costs essentially we should abandon CF style model
so intuitively we can think about it for tree here we're not decomposing this into
a set of the junction operations
so parsing into tag intuitively looks like a bottom-up process when first for each word
in the input to choose one of these elementary trees so you choose to the
predicted structure and secondly you choose how these different pieces structure fit together to form
a full parse tree
so i might be what might be interested in these kind of grammars as an
alternative site to see if cheese
so i made a couple of advantages
the first is the following
if you think about the lexical entries in the grammar
these quite naturally
captures constraints
associated with lexical items
so basically constraint that this one source of
we see this piece of tree fragment above it
so this is quite natural way to capture the influence of individual words on the
highest structure in the tree
perhaps more properly
we can start to associate probabilities all costs with this combination operations i just spoke
so for example one operation might be to combine
these fragments are associated with repeats and k
to form the structure
with the sister junction operations i additional
and this can have probability of cost
now essentially what we're doing here the form the structures with choosing the cake is
the direct object of eats
and by the parameters which can have access to this information
actually this this kind of parameters have been shown time and time again to be
very useful in disambiguating different structures of choosing between different parts
in contrast to pcfgs like i said in tags we associate costs probabilities with these
a junction operations
this contrasts in cfgs we associate probabilities cost rules something quite different
when parameterizing of thinking about the problem in these two cases
the next trick is going to be too
generalize ideas about feature vectors in conditional random fields
two these junction operations
so the models we have been using essentially
matt these junction operations to feature vectors
so now we have the feature vector mapping which looks as far as we have
an input x which is the string
and we have information which basically specifies everything i've shown you end up here
so we have the indices of head word in the world
participating in this relationship
so three and five in this case
the fifth
one going however we consider case that this falling unit is receiving top down information
intuitively if this top of
top down information to know that he if is large that means that the probability
of wiping activity is high
so using the energy function we can also write down the conditional
the probability that x saving one and it turns out that it can be simply
written as softmax function
similar way x off but
we just at the top down and bottom up information together inside the exponential function
and we can sample from this conditional distributions by simply using a multinomial distribution
so i described above convolutional deep belief network and i'm going to disk
so experimental results
we evaluated our model two hundred ten digit data
we trained a two layer convolutional deep belief network on unlabeled and the training data
and it turns out that the first layer learns strokes and the second layer learned
some groupings of the strokes
and be computed the test error
with different number of labelled examples
in summary our
performance very competitively compared to other state of the art models
in the next experiment we trained to layer convolutional deep belief network representation from a
set of natural images
and the resulting
representation is that in the first layer
it learns localized oriented edges
and in the second layer
it combines the first layer resentation into a richer set of features
for example contours onerous and parts surface boundaries
and we evaluate our representation two
caltech one of the classification task
we can see that
our first layer representation gives a fairly good results but after combining the first and
second the representation
the accuracy improves significantly
and our final result is sixty five percent accuracy for thirty training images per class
and this is very competitive results using other state-of-the-art features such as SIFT
and considering that our presentation was trained from natural image which is completely unrelated to
the caltech one on images
this shows that our convolutional DBN representation learned
fairly generic informative representation for images
in the next experiment we
trained in three layer convolutional deep belief network for multiple to cover images
for example if the train from
all images of faces in the second layer representation tend to learn all took part
representation such as our eyes or nose
and the third representation
it combines the part based on their representation in into
the concept of full of
and our model can too
we can discover similar object part an object
our representation
for many other classes such as cars elephants chairs
in our quantitative evaluation
we measure how informative each feature representation in the second or third layer is
so going back to the
previous slide
we have trained forty of features in the second layer and twenty four features and
the third layer
we pick just one second layer feature
and then compute the activation for the non
activation for the
cars based
non face images
and we can compute the
precision recall curves and compute the area
so called the average precision
so we have
forty thousand average precision values for the second there twenty four hours precision values for
the third layer
this is the distribution of average precision values
you can see that the first layer bases overall has a fairly small are averaged
precision values however as the layer goes up the second there has significantly higher average
precision and third layer of features even at even higher average precision
so this suggests that the higher the feature
the lines are more informative for object class
we also tested if our present patient can learn from some external objects so we
train from images of faces cars and more like an airplane
as a result our
the second feature
learn some mixture of object specific parts of shared parts
and in the third layer by combining these
the second feature representation
it discovers more and more objects that's bigger presentation
as of quantitative evaluation may be measured conditional entropy so
conditional entropy
keep of class labels given that features are active
as in the previous six experiment we have forty
conditional entropy values for the second there and twenty four conditional entropy values for the
the third layer
and here are the distribution of country conditional entropy values
overall we see that the first layer
features are have very high conditional entropy which means that even though they active it's
not very specific to optical however
that's the layer goes up the
distribution for the conditional entropy values become more closer to one
meaning that when you know that the first
when you know that the third level features are active and it's very specific to
to class
so finally experiment we tested hierarchical probabilistic inference
this experiment is inspired by
the mumford paper
as a motivating example we can consider OK situation where we observed images of faces
the team for several one you've really got to meet my good colleague of mine
my name is eric lander and
but i will faculty here in the biology department in fact were both members over
at the whitehead institute for biomedical research and we just for whole weekend together into
tree and so above and i've been doing this course together for a number of
years and very much love i and i taken a brief moment in introduce myself
since time and they have to do so yes i am by training
well actually
i'm really a geneticist by training and actually pure mathematicians that was actually my undergraduate
degree was in my phd was but then wandered into biology and for the last
almost twenty years i have been doing genetics in some form or another style of
genetics and look forward to talk a lot about genetics and it's really lovely with
my first lecture today is actually going to be our first introduction to genetics i
am i
just for other background
i direct this new brood institute that is
here it's actually a joint institute between MIT and harvard and you will know it
now is a hole in the ground next to legal sea seafood if you see
a bunch of cranes and things opposite the biology building and absolute legal seafood next
whitehead that the broad institute we have ambitions someday to be more than the hole
in the ground but actually rise above the ground and the broder's about genomic medicine
and using genomes and things like that and the broad institute includes
this centre MIT
that was one of the leading participants in the human genome project so that a
lot of what i do with my day job in addition to teaching is work
on things like the human genome project and now we actually have sequence the human
genome figure out what the the world at all means and i hope i get
a chance to tell you during the course of this this class about the human
genome and about what's in it and things like that and is one of the
exact tremendously love about teaching biology as opposed i can get in trouble to any
of the other required introductory courses is that are curriculum changes every year because the
field is moving so rapidly i look back at what we talk ten years ago
in this course because of the teaching that long and all sorts of open questions
now we know the answers to are part of the curriculum some of the things
we thought we knew what we now know are false and we know new things
and every year we get introduced new stuff and
i know i mean with all due respect to calculus it's just not the case
for calculus that that there's anything really new to introduce most of its order settle
down about about three or four centuries ago and
you know that's not the case with what we do anyway that's why
so bob has been talking to
biochemistry large
i'm not sure to genetics but
i want you to understand that there is an overarching framework that explains how all
the materials you're going to see released in the first half or more of this
course fit together and eventually but i mention it again
i will use this following diagram
it's kind of our roadmap for subway map of
we're we're going in this course
what we really want to do is understand biological function
most how is it that an organism is able to
breathing air and distributed to its cells how is it an organism is able to
move its muscles how is it that organism is able to fight off in the
invaders through its body microbes things like that how is it that an embryo develops
into a full adult zillions of questions asked by biological function
two complementary approaches to studying biological function over the course of the past
century or so in biology have been the following
there have been the biochemistry
six to break down the organism into individual components and study them on their own
and the test
they will take an organism to a biochemist wishing to study the beauty of a
butterfly flapping in the wind and understanding of the mechanics of of of how it
could possibly flat those wings at all he was here she would start by taking
the butterfly putting in blunder pressing pur
and making an extract and try to purify individual components that would that would explain
muscles moving back and forth and all that
this is of course the geneticist point of view but it's all right you have
to have bob whose whole represent biochemistry just fine and then what they want to
purify at individual components
individual components
away from the audience
and the most important individual type of components of a study of proteins
because the resilience of proteins and they do all sorts of things in the body
and so you could say in some sense that this whole theme of biochemistry which
that started at the turn of the twentieth century really just just a few years
before the turn of the twentieth century of writing up an organism studying its components
in being able to find for example to understand how i can digest lunch
well how you can digest the sugars trying to use fraction eight find some protein
that's able to digest the sugar all by itself without the rest of the organism
an enzyme to do that that's the logic of biochemistry
genetics is the complementary point of view
genetics is the study of organisms
minus one component
of course
what i mean by that i mutants
the geneticists who wants to understand the butterflies and how the butterfly can can can
will isolate butterfly strains that have lost the ability to fly
and ideally one is extremely close to related to the normal butterfly and but but
for some reason ideally due to the mutation of a single component and alan able
to fly and the geneticists within say a high that component must matter awful lot
for the ability to fly because the butterfly lacks that components can fly
it's totally complementary point of view and the objects the geneticists study in order to
do that our genes
now what is of course
hard for you guys to understand but will form of structure for some of the
lectures i'm going to give over the continuous part of course is that through most
of the twentieth century
the folks to study biochemistry try to understand proteins folks wants to study genetics and
try to understand mutants
i had nothing to say to each other
they didn't speak the same language they had nothing to relate to each other by
because there was no idea of how those genes stock
which started as a totally abstract business could possibly related protein stuff
which started as you know very practical and the best thing and they went for
a very long time as if they were to ships sailing in the dark and
where each other and i exaggerate but it's more true than not
the great intellectual
was the unification of these two points of view
through the discipline of molecular biology
molecular biology was the discipline that realize oh my goodness institute from queens of the
stone inside the same like that in fact genes encode proteins proteins are encoded by
genes hard
and now they should this actually we want to deal with large amounts of data
and want to deal with it using relational databases and one key should that that
we don't want to move data around you don't want to take the data from
the database and loaded for example in our reasoning main memory because it might not
be possible we cannot go several gigabytes of data and deal with it in main
memory so one key point here is to keep the data in the sources and
not move it around
and that's why we need to devise a suitable mechanisms and technology such that the
ontology can map to the data the data is kept in the data sources and
this is very much related to notions in data integration and is that they will
go quite in detail about this part
so the question is that we
i want to do that we ask ourselves into which we try to provide an
answer to tour the following
first of all which is the right query language using in such a context to
to address operations
the second question is which is the right ontology language is a language that allows
us to deal with data efficiently while still keeping to counter semantics and doing reasoning
then how can we bridge the semantic mismatch that we have between
the ontology where we have observed object and the data sources where we have values
and so in in a relational database strings numbers we don't have objects so there
is a mismatch which we need to bridge
and all of these for all of these want support from two
and so on
the question then across this reaches is how can ontology based
deal with accessing large amounts of data and integrating large amounts of data while taking
into account here
and we will try to provide some answers and some solutions to these questions in
this tutorial
let's let's start with the first question namely the query language
so can include data through ontologies now if you look at which clear language use
we can consider to extreme cases one case is the one that is deeply considered
in knowledge representation so to use essentially classes and properties of the ontology
two also to query so we ask for the instances of a class
and this is what is called instance checking in description logics ontology languages
the other extreme is to go towards full SQL
OK what is used in databases which
by the way amounts to using first order logic is a query language
for those of you unfamiliar this SQL corvettes SQL is equivalent to first-order logic
that's it
because very briefly these two extremes now
using just classes and properties is in general not really what we are that why
because while ontology language i really tailored that good at capturing intensional knowledge not that's
clearly the the because they are not able to
essentially it
so ontology language they don't use explicit verbose and that can be used in in
first order logic to create joins
to create a market connections from one object to other objects an ontology languages don't
have this ability so
they allow only for very restricted forms of joint essentially chaining individual that's what they
can express but is in general sufficiently want to create data
so ontology languages are not good query languages
on the other hand going towards full SQL is problematic why
because here in the context not you not answering queries on the database in the
context of incomplete information we want to reason about data and using SQL of first
order logic in while doing reasoning i mean we have to face the problem that
this is essentially undecidable so we cannot use first-order logic why fully take into account
the semantics having inference procedures that i have written to sound and complete with respect
to the semantic problem is undecidable
the solution is to look for something in between
one good candidate as a query language are conjunctive queries and units of conjunctive queries
why because this if disagree languages have already been considered in the context of incomplete
information mainly in in information integration they are quite expressive they capture most of the
features that users post
and they correspond to a fragment of SQL relational algebra that this has been well
studied and for which also database engine optimized
so let me to select project join fragments
also just as a market will just be discussed briefly conjunctive queries can also be
written as sparql queries and using his part syntax so for those of you unfamiliar
with sparql know already conjunctive queries effect show two late using will use precise spot
the syntax conjunctive query
now that conjunctive queries
the conjunctive query can be written as a first order query so first or expression
that just uses some operator first order logic namely just conjunction and the existential quantification
so it's essentially conjunction of forms
with variables that are either the one thing which really interested in all existentially quantified
and they can also be constant various terms
and now when we create an ontology design items
can be the
concepts and
of the classes and properties of the ontology when we create databases are be just
the database relations
just validation purpose will also use the simpler notation where we drop this extension that
because all that was that don't appear in what is called the head of the
query i implicitly existentially quantified so it's not actually necessary to write explicitly these existential
quantifier simplicity and we can recognise it in this expression
and this is by the way what is called a datalog notation for which i
think is very also use a common set of conjunction
now let's look at an example
if you simple example of an ontology
which is our
university domain so the running example we have used throughout the whole tutorial
and it is actually design inclusion assertions between concepts disjointness assertions and they involve also
properties now
in some of the examples that i will use it will not use this notation
use just graphically graphical notation which is equivalent to this one because i believe it
easier to understand what we are talking about
if we see a diagram like this instead of
seeing a set of inclusion assertions like this notice that these that express exactly the
it's a constraint on our domain as the set of inclusion assertions so get that
it it for it to convey the the same information
you know the main we have faculty member professors are a subclass of faculty so
associate professors also faculty members we have associate professor and dean
what professors by the way know as professor can be eighteen so these two classes
are disjoint we also colleges
a faculty member
work for colleges deans and heads of colleges and by the way each college has
exactly one unit each gene has exactly one college and each faculty members to work
for one college and the college must have at least one
a faculty member so this is essentially what is expressed in the set of inclusion
use graphical notation and now
starts on the second we have some laughs i see people at the pleasure for
me to welcome olivier bousquet he is french so and he studied at all these
big called sin
paris in two thousand two he got his phd from the call polytechnic on concentration
inequalities and empirical process theory for machine learning
his thesis was awarded the best pieces of the quality
quite political technique and he also won the best paper award at the conference on
learning theory during his phd time
after his phd he moved shortly the US and then came to the MPI here
where he worked for three years of senior post doc
and that was before he turned to the dark side then went industry back to
france in paris he worked at NASA says the
research manager and recently moved to call the insurrection
in his research career he was mostly interested in learning theory but he also contributed
to more applied things so i heard you are
co-author on semi supervised learning paper of any so he also knows what theory is
good for
before i give the word two
well if you just let me mention that he was also the organizer of the
last machine learning summer school into being and so i guess
the nice for him to speaker again i
morning morning everyone thank you very much for this introduction and i wish to thank
the organisers for fighting first and also parents
it's kind of a
an important moment for me because four years ago i was in this room and
i was introducing the speakers
and i know it's a lot of work in
i mean it
very difficult to organize such an event and to make it accessible and this one
seems very successful so far
so i won't be here at the end but i hope you will all
give them a lot of applause at the end to congratulate the organiser for these
OK so he was a bit i mean it was very nice dinner yesterday and
a lot of drinks
probably you were you would not be continuing what direction durational this talk so i
will try to give you a very slow start this morning
and hasbro and say that i have turned to the dark side
which means that
i started thinking about you know what is this all for the series the how
does it help in practice and does it really make a difference in the real
world when you're
you know in the company and someone asked to design learning algorithms
does it really helps to prevent hearing before
so what we
try to attempt in this lecture
it is to show you that you know
all the details mathematical details you can figure them out when you look at the
papers you want you know enough of you know what the definition that you can
more this figure out that details understand
the proofs of the papers
what is harder though is to understand the meaning behind the school or really
you can infer from this series and what what you can do in practice and
how does it help you
or guide you towards building the right and so this really be really the goal
of these pictures
there was three parts of
with a
we will look into
so what are what and why
which is you know what is learning theory and why i was studying it
what are the foundations and will in the second part of this picture with this
person would not renounce theorem which is
i think an important piece of it
and tomorrow we go into the bounds
and show i i will show you how to put some bounds on how to
they around with the different techniques that exists
they have to tomorrow
i will discuss it with the implication and the consequences how to interpret these these
so again
the goal of this course is not really
it's not really true
you know give you a lot of the results a lot of but more you
look the nation's keep things simple and really
give insight that but i'm trying to do do most of the day i mean
most of the picture
and we of course cover
i think that the story of the domain general results and advanced topics
so let's start
so before
telling you what is learning here you have to tell you what is this here
and what is the goal of
you know
finding serial
this is
i mean definition of what is the series
and i have a slightly important words here
important is that we are looking at the phenomenon and we try to explain this
and we want to explain it in a repeatable way
and also
this explanation should help us to make predictions about this phenomenon that's the important point
so in a way you can think of history as model
something that kind of represents
or describe
some phenomena
that's model helps us understand the
you know the various
things that happen when you want to experiment in this case it would be the
phenomenon of running of course
and of course predict what's going to happen later
two more definitions that would be useful
this lecture
deduction and induction these are often opposed and actually they are of course if you
look at the
the deduction is really
you go from there
general axioms the general rules and to try to derive consequences
so you go from the general to specific and specific is saying here so you
go from the action and to right
european approval
this is really
what mathematics is is all about
induction is more what physics is all about which is
you look at a specific examples you make observations about the nature and then you
try to infer the the general principle that the actions of nature
this is how you create is usually from observing nature
there's also something in between the ages of action
which should probably have heard of
which is going from specific to specific without even mentioning model
but these are
two important things
from general to specific of specific genome
so what is a good theory series one that is
you know intuitively makes sense for and which is simple and concise so you have
a lot of observation and you can
look outside of sort of a lot of natural phenomena and if you can explain
pixels where white is positive and black is negative
so you can see this guy here
he has learned little feature like this he likes to be so destroyed and he
really is this you don't have anything
so if you turn this guy on the train generation image looks like that
and if you turn on some subset
about twenty of these guys
it turns out if you turn on the sensible subset attractive generate images just like
it two
here's an example
after learning i show it some more tombs
but is never seen before
and i ask you to reconstruct
does a pretty good job reconstructing
the reconstructions have been more regular in the real data
but he we construct very well for a whole variety of tissues
that's with only fifty feature vectors so you can think of is activated subset of
them and then basically added together the weights that subset
put on function and change the image
and it does jolly good job reconstructing tissues
it's not quite perfect when you get a very unusual feature like vertical tail
very few twos have it makes it sort of messes up with it
but it does quite a good job within fifty feature vectors now what we're going
to do
it is we going to take this model was trained on two is the police
the whole world consists of two years and insurance threes
it's a bit like showing george bush real data
now it has opinions about what the world should be like
this is what he sees be
think about the difference in two thousand three is the difference is that you know
threes don't join up there
and they don't have the tail
but we can fix that we just drop out of the input over here
and hey presto we didn't change much in institute
so it's easy to know if we turn on the learning it will very quickly
learn to do that and we learn to deal with twos and threes
OK so that's a little example of this algorithm runs to show it works
this is sort of a bit of an aside but
i want to distinguish a whole bunch of ways of combining probabilistic models
so one thing we are all very familiar with is if you have
kind of probabilistic model as a gaussians
you can have a bunch of those
on average the distributions together take some weighted average of those distributions that some action
the problem with the mixture is
the combined distribution can never be sharper than the sharpest of the individual distributions
so i'm never gonna get very sharp
representations of things that way
an alternative is to take part in the distributions we normalize
so i could take a whole bunch of guys into multiply them together
if i takes a
OK seeing here guessing here and i multiply them together
what i get is
something attainable goes in the middle
that'll have
half the variance of the gaussians and here
and there's almost no probability mass there but when we normalise it turns into gas
the middle
one is the more multiply together the shopper things get
so by having very vague individual models multiplying together get very short
i can't do that with a mixture
but i have this normalization to make slow difficult
and you can think of restricted boltzmann machines as being a product model
in fact is the product of mixtures
so each of the hidden units is saying i mixture model
if i
then i believe in a uniform distribution
if i'm all
i believe in
factorial distribution across visible units where the probability beta visible unit is
the sigmoid of the weight of my connection
so put weight on the connections are majestic that's the probability of each of the
units for the independent
and then when you turn on a bunch of these guys
you get the products of all these distributions
that's what you do when you add up all these
restricted boltzmann machine is the product model
each hidden unit is one little probabilistic model there be multiplied together
and what we can do now is we can take this product models
and we're going to compose
that's another way to combine models where we take the hidden units one model
we make the data for the next model
so that the
input to the next restricted boltzmann machine is the
in units of the previous one
so sort stuck in
so you can think of one theme of this tutorial is these guys were better
than those guys
and in particular if you take these guys and you compose and together you get
something really nice
so the main reason is restricted boltzmann machines are interesting
it's because you can compose that you construct come up
and we're going to learn in the following way
which i would justify minute
we cannot regular features and just where i just showed you
then when you take the activations of those features when the model being driven by
and we could take the binding activations we could actually is real that use the
theory is much cleaner if you say take binary activations he works but in practice
if you take real values but all stick with the theory
you take up
you take data
activate your feature vectors
you take the binary states the feature vectors
and then the data for training the next restricted boltzmann machines to the next level
so it's kind of a simple as it could be
the actual algorithm
and what you can show is that we would like to show is that it
takes some data
they build a restricted boltzmann she model this data
so far
generate from my model generate stuff a bit like the data
if i know i don't know the hidden load
sufficient size
and had in the right way
i'd like to be able to guarantee
in this sort of expected sense that i get a better model of the data
about another layer can always improve the model
this model really perfect
and you can almost guarantee that
we can't quite guarantee that the first time you do you can guarantee that you
get a better model but in general as you add more layers what you can
guarantee is that
the more complicated models get with more
it will be of
i will have a better bound on the log probability of the data
so you have a model the some variational bound this says the problems they must
be at least as much
when i add a new life
and take the band for this deep model
it's a better bound low probability will bigger
necessarily model
if you knew way
so that's good enough you definitely sort of improving the travellers
so let's suppose we do this
three less
so because i you take some data
you learn a restricted boltzmann machine here so you learn these weights
and they're kind of the same weights in both directions
then you take the states of the hidden units
that you've got by
taking the data multiplying by these weights putting it through the majestic and sampling
you say about the relative distances
between this points
they are also unique to
what is means the falling if you have a set of points in the plane
and you already know
the distances that correspond to the edges of the graph
then all the other distances
are uniquely determined you can compute demonstration but you don't need to compute them to
know that they are uniquely determined
why this is important this is important for two reasons
what's the maximal clique of a graph
if you think the maximal clique of these graphs
these on the picture
the maximal clique of these graphs is four
this is an example of a maximal clique
in other words
there are no five or more nodes in this graph that are only
the maximum number of
of nodes that are all neighbors
between themselves is four
for the maximal clique size of these graphs these peaks
it doesn't depend on the number of points
i can be as many as i want here
and the maximal clique is fixed
the first thing
the second thing
which is important about this graph
using graph
the and later or not
i think well
you'll find that the graph is already
because every cycle in the graph
as a course
if you think about this cycle here
has the score in a cycle of course when i see any cycle is any
cycle greater than three because the cycle of size three
by definition has no core
so the interesting thing about these graph is that it has very two properties that
are sufficient
to use the junction tree of
it is the three and later graph
that allows you to use the junction tree of
the size of the maximal clique
this fix it is independent of the number of moles independent on the problem in
the size of the
that makes the junction tree algorithm
so one thing allows you to use the junction tree algorithm
the other thing
it tells you that if you use the junction tree
you two have
only polynomial
complexity on the sizes
the graph
you can actually show
that these means basically
well you can generalize these results to any dimension actually
but let me just come back
a little bit
and show that
these graphs column globally rigid because there
the length of the edge is uniquely determined the lengths of the absence of edges
if you wish
is are globally rigid graph
we call this graph three three
this is the technical name
to call this graph
the generalisation of the three basically is the graph that you obtained by adding new
connected to
three previous
nodes which are
which is fully connected to each form strictly
and size of
clique sizes four
so originally
so in general you can prove that
k tree graph in other words
that one is true tree graph
so it has three reference note if you wish and the top
in general if you have a k tree graph so we came reference points in
the talk
you can solve the problem in i to came in well
so if you are in the plane
OK cayman on course to so k equals three so you need to keep the
tree three graph
if you are in this space three-dimensional space you need for reference point by the
that's exactly how GPS works
they're using this result
how do you know your position if you had distances
from yourself four satellite
you can determine
in the maximal clique size is fixed cables
so that's the case
i was talking before
that's the case
and basically the junction tree algorithm
if minimizing these things
OK tree graphical models
where these things is basically a sum over there
two the nuclear already here is the
i mean square ready depending on the neutron number four different
i said to be generic tree
gold platinum iridium so
you see you have these learned that you have some
so to structure here
just to mention that this experiment very precise experiment has been performed have been far
from here it's stand
using the eyes the practice of very precise measurement are proof from here from
ready masses etcetera
you see there are ways of this is the first experimental proof
of the lack of
accuracy of liquid drop
so the proof is they'll nuclei
so halo nuclei have been discovered and predicted by ten percent
and you see that this is for any equal eight isaac told you see the
different experimental results from root mean square
and you see that for each element new have very huge
so this is presented here where you have
you eleven which is very huge
using you have all their so far very light systems you don't follow
at all these these a one
law which is only an average
the second problem concerned the nuclear masses
so what is plotted here is the difference between experimental and theoretical masses calculated with
the liquid drop
in any v depending on the neutron number
and you see that you have an average very good
results are zero but you have some discrepancies here
some things
that can be applied to a few enemy
and it speaks appears for magic numbers eight twenty twenty eight fifty eighty two one
twenty six
it's always the same
whatever the isotopic see eye to set up to consider
so these numbers you can see that when you look at the
two neutron separation energy so two neutron separation energy the energy that you have to
put into the system to remove two neutrons
so you calculate that the difference between the binding energy of the nucleus you are
minus is the daughter nuclides
so if you look that as a function of the new numbers
so you see that you have a small c increase
and then ship
you have drops very sudden drops
so it means that
to remove so this proper sorry for magic nuclei
so it's it's show that this magic nuclei have very high
are very stable they have an increased particle stability
so if you want to extract particle from them you really have to
to put a lot of energy that cannot be reproduced by this liquid drop approach
third example of something which is not so good with this liquid drop is that
if you take a liquid then you want to have fish and you will only
symmetric fission that means fragment with the same mass in information improprieties
so but it's not the case experimentally
so these are very famous results of energy is saying germany
from this group so you have the fragment mass distribution for different fissioning system uranium
thorium opinion
you see them as distribution so what
if you have only one peak it means that the fragments
most probable fragments are identical so you have same fragments
but you see that it's not the case for all these nuclei
can here
two pick it means one small fragment one big
and most of these
i mean i said do have such
another important point here
that you are dealing with these then was one hundred thirty eight and eighty
proton and neutron so around two hundred forty nucleons
and you see that you change only one
and you completely changed features
that experimentally observed
so it means that
it's very difficult to treat something
as the war you really have to
to look carefully at the behavior of each
so because of that
it seems that
you can describe the system like these but you really have
to consider the nucleons and the interaction between them
so what i have shown before is that they are
cumulant generating function that's what we're computing there
you can in fact write it as some from x equals zero to one
of x times the probability of experts and expectation
and so it says this quantity here this is really just the probability that the
coin comes up heads that's the probability that x is equal to one
so that's a very special case of the mean parameter
and all i'm saying here is that this is true more generally that it doesn't
matter here the function i had was just x feedbacks is equal to x
but i could have any function in the same relation hold
so the the mean parameters are basically moments there's sort of moments of these profiles
actions that we started with the sufficient statistics
OK so what he here now is we we sort of seeing the
critical equation is whether or not we can choose status so the expectation of the
sufficient statistic is equal to the mu
new here just the fixed number that you're choosing
and we need to try and solve this equation we need to understand when that
equation has a solution
now what i'm doing here is is again just a more general version of what
i did before
so i didn't go into the details but it's not too hard to do
if you remember in the bernoulli case
when we assume that there was a solution to this equation
so that sort of the nice case when mu was in zero one
then you can go through a bit of algebra
and what we found is the dual function had the simple form
we found it was able to me a lot of music
i didn't go through his elder brother i encourage you to do it so it's
not hard
this is what we found is that
it has a nice form
when he was in
the zero one intro
and so for those of you who were familiar with entropy
you would have recognised this but for everyone else this turns out to be the
you can compute this with a little calculation this is the entropy of the distribution
it looks like this is actually the minus entropy the exact
so i'm doing here is is just more formally saying
o if i do have a solution i can go through some calculations and i'll
see that the dual function is minus entropy when you have a solution
so that that's not really anything new
and what this brings is really to the key thing this is something that i
hinted at before
and it's this question here
we really have to worry now about for which duties that equation has a solution
in this case we already worried about it and we sort of looked both analytically
and i geometrically and we solve this equation has solution when mu in zero one
but no solution otherwise
and so
otherwise was not zero one we saw before that we got plus infinity
right so this is the case when there was
no solution to the no stationary point
right so we need to sort of understand this question more generally
this example was very easy because
mu we've worked out is just the probability that the coin is one
so it makes perfect sense that you should be between zero and one if you
flip a coin the probability has been zero and one
when working with more complicated exponential families is not always easy and we'll see this
is actually very hard sometimes
so any questions so far
just to recap before i got question so we saw this example with
the bernouilli
we sort of what we can do this more generally and that's really just taking
the intuition we had from the special case and the same we can do it
in any exponential family
and we've argued so far that if this if we do have a stationary point
that in fact we get the dual function is negative entropy just like we had
over here
but now what we're worried about this is when we don't necessarily have a stationary
point what happens then we need to figure out what that means
they questions about that
so this is the word of encouragement we're almost there
implementation it's fast execution the fact the FFT the fast fourier transform
and if time permits i make some comments on the discrete cosine transform and
it's it also can be implemented by
the FFT
so it's equally fast
so actually this is pretty much to find whether were at the transition now short
so let's previous lecture was about
fourier transforms this one focuses on the discrete case and it's still in the applied
book section five is the fifteenth
and chapter four
as the material on fourier transforms in general
and of course you know that i'm going to give up matrix in its expression
to all to the main ideas
the main idea is being transformed
it's fast execution is
and the convolution
the central ideas of of the subject and familiar to many of you
you probably could get the a formula right more often than i
and in the second lecture today
will really to move into the way book
discussing filtering
actually in the same lecture i'm going to have filters in the time domain and
frequency domain in
the domain
the the
health care the basic tool of signal processing
OK so
here's a basic tool and i've written up
so we have to decide how many samples we have
capital and
and sometimes will run from zero to n minus one typically
and indices will go from zero to minus one so we have and samples
and we want to find and fourier coefficients
the discrete fourier coefficients that
so of so that the number
this complex number into the two pi over n
comes into the
everywhere here so let's be sure we've got that number pin down work in the
complex plane
and the drama
a circle of radius one the unit circle
so course this is the real axis
this is the imaginary axis so that that number right there would be i
and now wears the number w
is it on the circle
everything of modulus one absolute magnitude one is on the circle this is an e
the i
so say that the angle is two pi over n so where does it go
o one and
i mean the whole animal use two pi
and we will say the two pi and so we go
we take n to be eight
so that would be
either too high
i over eight
so let's w
maybe i should really call it w and
to indicate that it's
determined by the number and OK and now you're going to see powers of w
so let's just be sure we've got those down
why are we w squared for example
you notice i don't write the
rectangular the real and imaginary parts could
cosine and sine of two pi
when you multiply numbers
the this form is the polar form is much much better
and when those numbers are on the unit circle
so the polar are is one
then there's absolutely no question superior
this so our is one we just adding angles when we multiply so if i
swear that one what number again
i get i doubles the angle angle was two pi rate forty five degrees gobbles
two i
so that the cube that would be here and another
i take the cube by multiply by another
in two by over a dyad angle once more here's the fourth power
so this is w eight and
there's w eight square which is the same as w four and that's a big
deal actually the fact that w eights were does this same as w four and
in this example i
so i eventually if in the fast fourier transform i'm going to be interested in
the in the in in
and the half size transform
so this is anticipating what's coming that
here's an equal eight years
i am equal four and the point is the w and swearing is wm
and that's
trivial but
a row vector multiplying three by three matrix
what's the output
what's the product row
and OK it's a right
all right
sorry i matrix times column is the columns of matrix
times column
the column
and we know what column in it
over here i'm doing a road times the matrix and what and what is the
what the answer it's one of the first row
so it's one times one times rho one
two times wrote to
plus seven times wrote three
when as we do matrix multiplication
keep your eye on
what it's doing with all that
and what it's doing what what it's doing in this case is
it's combining the roles
we have a combination of a linear combination of the roles OK i want to
use that
so my question is what's the matrix that does this first
that takes
subtract three of equation one
from equation two
that's what i want to do
so this is going to be a matrix that going to subtract
time for a couple times wrote one
and leave the other rows the same just i mean the answer is going to
be there
so whatever matrix this is
and you're going to like tell me what matrix will do it it's the matrix
leave the first row and change
the the last row and train
but takes three of these away from this output zero there two there and minus
what matrix will do
it should be a pretty simple matrix
because we're doing a very simple steps
we're just doing this that that changes wrote two so actually rule one is not
changing so
do tell me how the matrix should begin
so the first row of the matrix
will be one
zero zero
because that's just the right thing that takes one of that and none of the
other rows and that's what we want what's the last row of the matrix
zero zero line
that takes
one of the third row and none of the other rows that's great OK
now suppose i didn't want to do anything at all
both my role well i guess maybe i had a case here when i already
had a zero
and i didn't have to do anything what matrix does nothing
i guess leaves
you were you were
if i put in
if i put and zero one zero that would be
that would be
that's the major what's the name of the matrix
the identity matrix right
so it does absolutely nothing it just multiplies everything and leaves and where it is
is like one like the number one
for matrices
but that's not what we want because we want to change this
rho two
what's the correct
what should i put it here now
to come out to do to do it right
i want to get what we want what i'm after trying to subtract might want
three all one to gets subtracted off
so what that role what's the right matrix the finished matrix for me
the negative three goes here
and what goes here that one
and what goes here the zero
that's the good night
that's the matrix that take
minus three of rho one was the road to
and gives the new road to should we just like sheikh
particular entry
how do i check a particular entry of the matrix
in matrix multiplication
like suppose i wanted to check
the entry here
that's the and
column three
so where does the entry in row two column three come from
i would look at road to of this guy
and column
three of this one
to get that number number comes from the second row
can be defined for
should be mindful
topological spaces very often represents
the top space
so what you see is an abstract this is what what this competition
one called the discrete representation spaces like this that's
points which is the primary means by this
so that's something sensational
which is a bit of neuron
the result using your
is to get better
the only thing to do
this disaster one
here's an example because not
you try to use
the example
so what is
it is
it was
be one
one is one
and what you find is seen
it is
because the vector space
so this easier
is the vector space one generation one b
but this
c one
is the vector space here is one
these features
and then use the users just want to
this is a
so and so that is this one this is the stationary bike so that in
this space
i think of it as just a collection of
so you
is that that
it is
we want to
so the first one
it's hard to do this and
five one
that is not going to be read as
seventy five
you will find
this is not the right
the red
just like
two seasons
his problems
now this is not just a relation is
very simple systems
so not just
what we are interested
this is something like this
this is used
the truth is that every vertex
incidence relations the system
this just too
is that exists
is on the verge
there is no
that's on who's written
so that was
the design
the difference between these
CR number two
because the force
and the position vector
make an angle of hundred eighty degrees with each other when the object is here
or here or here it makes no difference
and so to talk
relative to
is zero so i also know that the angular momentum is not changing a relative
to point c
but only relative to point c because any other point that you've chosen here here
or here
there would be no pork
and the annual omentum would be changing so something very special about this point c
angular momentum is only conserved in this case
o point c
now i take another example
by angular momentum is only conserved
relative to one point but not to any other point
i take
a ruler or rods
and the role have mass and
and length l
and c is the centre of mass of the world
but i force it to spin about point b
and this distance is d
think of this as a horizontal
and i'm rotating it
there's an angular velocity
let's say we rotated in this direction
four about that point he would have been in their perpendicular to the blackboard and
i rotated
i'd like to know
what the
magnitude is of the angular momentum
relative to point b in for that
i go immediately to equation five
but it tells me that it is the moment of inertia
about that axis will point p
times omega
i remember the parallel axis theorem
i know that the moment of inertia for rotation about the centre of mass
food is axis perpendicular to the blackboard
i know that one
he was one twelve
l square but i just looked it up in the table because i don't remember
so that would be the moment of inertia about this axis and then the parallel
axis theorem tells me i have to add
plus and the square
times omega
i'm not interested in the direction of l because it's immediately obvious if it's rotating
then the direction of the angular momentum will be perpendicular to the blackboard
and into the backward
i claim
but at this point p
there must be a force acting on this ruler
and the forces in this direction
and i can make you see that
the best way
my first
showing you
the case of a
mass was wrong
with two equal masses at both ends
i rotate about its axis
perpendicular to the blackboard
there is going to be a centripetal force and the centripetal force here
and the two equal they cancel each other out so there will be no force
on that page the point about which the to rotate
i had
the situation
such that this is my masters rolled
and you have added two equal masses
but now i rotate about this point
this centripetal
the forces larger than this one
so now i have a symmetry
so now there will be
the force on this been
the rule will push on the pin and actually my reaction to pin will push
the ruler and is because of the same asymmetry that you have here that there
will be a force from the beam on point p
however i don't care about that force because i'm going to take the talk relative
to point b
and when i think it or relative to point b any forceful through point p
has no effect because the position vector is zero
but i want you to appreciate that there is a force
so if i take that to work
relative to point b
i do
not worry about this
well the talk relative to that point p
is zero and so it's clear
that angular momentum relative to point p
must be conserved
angular momentum relative to point b is conserved
take any of the point
it doesn't matter which one you take this point q
take this point here take this point here and you momentum is not conserved
immediately see that if i take this point q here
that this
is the
position vector
and you see that are cross f is nonzero this talk relative to point q
you know momentum is not conserved only this point that point
it's very
i now take the same ruler
but i'm going to
make it rotate about the centre of mass
here is now the same
now i'm going to rotate
about the centre of mass
same direction
the stationary axes twenty six one hundred and is rotating about their
centre of mass is my centre of mass
now there is no force
on this page because of the symmetry which i just explained sort of pain is
not pushing on the
rather either
so there no force at all
if this is a frictionless
if there is no force at all
then the talk
relative to any point must be zero not only relative to this point but also
relative to this point and relative to this point because if the force is zero
then any cross product of rnf is zero
so now you see the special case that i alluded to
in equation number six
now you have the case
that the angular momentum
of this rotating object is the same
no matter which
o point you choose recall that the spin
angular momentum it is an intrinsic property
of a spinning object
and it is the same relative to any point that you choose
and if you want to know
larger this
be able to tell you about this is the simplest case and perhaps the most
fundamental case
and so most method estimate actually real from a real valued function are around two
and threshold
and and that's what produces the classification
so you really do classification to it so i will actually cool concentrate on getting
this real valued functions and the
in classification so he here some pictures
what you want to do is something like this
so let me show you this
OK so this is your data
so this x y use
and this so why one right so data point is an x y pair this
is x this is why
and given so what your goal given a new data point you might want to
predict y one
well as you can see the data is a little noisy it's kind of a
little all over the place but there is some pattern the pattern is something like
so noise is sort of a very persistent feature of the data i think it's
important to understand the noise is everywhere in the one thing you can say well
i can always tell an image of seven from an image of not first is
not eventually you can
there are some examples they especially like well some of them either to the another
but for nine can be extremely similar for example and sometimes you just don't know
they were trying to write than suppose how do you actually know what the labour
i made some guy inherited down and tries to label other things but this guy
will just make will make a mistake once in a while no matter what
and so no matter what you have here date is always nice almost
so you'll have to deal with the issue of notes and in some sense it's
a fundamental issue
so what do what you want to have
something like this
so this in some sense is the a function which fits this data very nice
and so given the new point eight just read the value of the function and
that's my project
in fact i can tell you
the secret but that's actually data was generated from this distribution
it's not
so this is in some sense the best to come
OK so
what about this
so this is a very nice
well behaved function but it doesn't seem to fit the data very well
this actually fitting something
well for this
it is something which underfits you're not fitting well enough it's some nice
pleasant function to delist it's almost like a straight line but unfortunately it doesn't work
very well
and now this
is also not nice function perhaps it fits the data perfectly however as you can
notice this is some polynomial of high degree which if it exactly to the data
so it fits the data perfectly however
if i have a data points you do i really think it's going to be
out there
well you may be not so this is in a an example of overfitting your
feet the data that you have perfectly but on the new points
you probably do very bad
you will
here you build the
basically as badly on the new point as you do on points here so it's
pretty badly here
but on the new point it will probably not do much more
so this is an underfit it
it works consistently but badly
this works very well on the data but we work about learning
this is perfect so i don't know what what what is perfect it's hard to
tell you why
i mean in this case this is actually the fourth
you would know that this is exactly the true
OK so
i hope this is so
one point to be made from all pictures is you never should try to fit
the data exact if it exactly fit all the noise which is in the day
that you will always have
and in some sense that you have to be careful as part of the thing
you have to be careful with
about other methods for blind source separation
so we began with the problem of blind source separation and then we'll talk i
see as the kind of the the method for
for solving the rights separation problem
and it is true that
most work on blind source separation well
the the the large majority of the work online separation is using ICA to do
that but there are also the source of the class of other kinds of methods
for blind source separation that are completely different completely but rather different from ICA
well so the basic point is that we have this
the same kind of of basic of linear mixture models
it's just that now we write the time index t here for all the option
by optical signals and the sourcing
because the point is that these signals in real time signals they are not we
don't just have a sample of a random vector but we really have time sequence
and timing that me
so this as we saw before this that we can estimate this kind of model
in general we can not estimate the the sourcing in general that basically if we
take a if we assume that the is i
gaussian random variables so when i say random variables i mean that they have no
time structure
so different time points they are just independent i mean a single
the signal will be such that the values in two different time points to subsequent
time points are independent from each other then
then we can there's nothing we can do
so what
there are two ways actually to get to get to be able to do something
that first
first is the method of ICA
which is why we assume that these into these components the the social signals on
nongaussian and then we can use these ideas of higher order statistics that is in
to basically not different measures of nongaussianity to give the information that we the extreme
information that we need
but the other way
is to assume that these is i are time dependent signals
that is they have some kind of meaningful bond structures like you know maybe something
like this kind of sinusoidal functions for example
and then we can use these correlations over time
to get more information
so something more and more information than is contained in the covariance matrix
well the simplest thing
two rule probabilities that well what could look at this is this kind of the
lagged covariance matrix so power here
is a small time lag maybe that could be equal to one
which means that we are here computing the covariances
we have computing covariances of
x y
at timepoint t
and then of another signal x j
at timepoint t minus
one of the simplest case
so we get some more statistics and some more information and perhaps we can then
use that to estimate
estimate the
the model
and it turns out that this is really this is exactly what you can do
in the early nineties at the same time as people were working in this in
this area on the theory of ICA this proposed that we could do that if
we could use this i this method to separate sources
to the way of looking at this principle is that we could say that we
find that the correlating matrix w
that not only the whites are
are uncorrelated with the with
each other
in the ordinary sense
but also they are uncorrelated with black divisions so we have the covariances
why i t
and why i t minus one is zero
but then also
the same thing will be true if we take
lag series services j
j known as the image so not only these components these components are
uncorrelated when you look at them look at the same time point but also they
will be uncorrelated
when you
look at that and get them at slightly different time points
for example and with the lack of one
and so this will actually this will under certain assumptions solve this problem that we
don't have
enough information in the covariance matrix
OK well i had actually it here
so all of these pieces practices something actually extremely simple
so first we whiten the data we use any whitening matrix
z just like in in ICA the two of us
and now
well we find orthogonal transformation since we know that all widening transformations can be represented
by an orthogonal transformation of industrial
whitening transformation
and we find this orthogonal transformation not not not to maximize nongaussianity just ICA
but so
that's the lagged covariance
matrix of this thing equals idea
now it happens that this is actually computationally very easy thing to do
because if you look at this
if you look at the core of these lagged covariance matrix
then by definition where of when x equals a times is
choice he makes x is going to take a maximum 2 2
lawyers in the
calculations this is the calculation that are has to make this is the calculation of
the estimate so let's do it
dual so we could just think about ah so ah as think OK I'm going
to take the best text
but it has to be best against the worst
this is the
today the words from this point of view that's right the worst from his ways
OK now if I was strong enough we can work this out
we don't know what the
so that you can we can we try to see if we can do it
this is this is the payoff written out in full
so what basically what is x have to do it he has to presented y
with the with the what's the presented wi with with with 2 columns where
white otherwise no reason to go 1 way or the other
I think in this case
so what will why usually get when it went when why think about this way
suppose chooses column 1
what can we expect payoff to the
on on the average after zillions of play
for x 1 + 1 x 2 and
is that right
wise positions
we we've why the payoff y in choosing from 1 would be for 1 +
1 x 2
that's the payoff from column 1
the payoff from column until
2 X 1 and 7
and I think X wants to adjust those those of the same I think
that seems right to me
is provided this gives
non-native non negative axis so what does that tell us that tells us that 2
x 1
it's 6 x 2
is that what we get out of this this leads to
subtracting the 2 X 1 that gives us 2 X 1 in 6 excuse
and wants to me like this sort of B
some of the bigger ones 3 quarters and this should only be 1 quarter
I think that's the conclusion
do you like know other there's no reason for why the change because if
if we then do it that way why Welch
then the average payoff when X 1 is a physical is 3 quarters
and X 2 is 1 quarter is three-quarters 1 I get them for the for
those Member of just
1 quarter and that's makes ones
note 3
three-quarters terms there's really I think we get 3 in the quarter and I believe
that's the value of the game
you can say wait a minute I haven't figured out
strategy and and that's true
policy so let's figure out why strategy in the same reasoning
OK so why strategy will be
if you are an effective row 1 is chosen as the average payoff is more
y 1 plus 2
whereas in the 2nd row is chosen the average payoff will be wide 1 .
7 . 2
and if he makes those equal
there are will have no reason to choose 1 row or another so what would
that give us that'll was really that leads to
3 Y 1 is 5 white so there in the ratio of 5 to 3
so maybe
3 8 sense of 5 and 3 8 5 8 1 3 8
because then 3 times 5 does give 5 times 3
right now I think we've got
so there is a particular game that's solved
a particularly game itself so that we have and the so that the 1st and
most important point is this is the point we saw earlier that in in this
game and make strategies that that's a randomized make strategy if there is any patterns
the opponent will take advantage
here there's no patterns except the only pattern is this is for the time and
this is one-fourth of the time and then of et and as you plug those
numbers into the payoff you would get
3 quarter sure
we could agree yes
this is the best point with widest 1 chain yes
you I guess there is somehow yeah this is that's probably an and so this
is a remark it what the end result is
is the fact that
the best
X the best X X can be
is to guarantee himself this amount
and the best way I can do is to guarantee not pay more than that
is making a small they can against anything
and the beauty is this minimax theorem
that this minimax equals the maximum that that's that's is duality of course of the
2 players are somehow it locked in this
dual picture and
which what wanted
i just think about what you do if you're doing likelihood based inference here you
go away and calculate this distribution
so the data
and the stuff about the point history of very highly cover correlated in this calculation
be non-trivial
to be a certain amount of work presumably to calculate nothing if you could
so with the ABC approach you just change the metric
and you get different
and i said what's wrong with it could going to
thinking about it
OK so just to give you the punchline from the science story
the reason these problems interesting is big controversy surrounding this a paleontologist all certain that
primates diverged after the demise of the dinosaurs sixty five million years ago gave us
a certain that a large proportion of the system and what the geneticists using DNA
from other primates a fairly sure that the divergence times back here somewhere
so what our work is done as i looked at a reasonable model of evolution
from the paleontology literature
and actually
the inference of what we expect the average time to be given the data we
have available can although we can't say for sure is in the cretaceous
the primary dinosaurs alongside
it seems we call without even reason uncertainties by about here
so we put most on that over here
the prior distribution but it's actually fairly robust this prior
so using the fossil evidence alone you can't constrain
the primary difference time to the cretaceous
the back to the monte carlo the ABC there's a couple of extensions that may
or may not be possible
the first one has been suggested is that we can use the albums to do
model selection
so in theory the acceptance rate from these algorithms
approximates the
the normalizing constant
from you all
so no matter constant partition function evidence whatever you call it can
so this is the probability of the data given the model
so we can approximate that with acceptance rate from ABC
in practice i think we shown
it's fairly hopeless
so more both the choice of exile rho and so on
there's a few other methods something
this is fairly up to date but i know this is difficult to calculate because
i think it's also
course of these ABC albums only and any good if you can your simulators cheap
if it take you ten seconds to simulate a sample output from your model probably
no good never mind if you have to take two weeks like people can so
one option might be to emulate the stochastic models so we know something about emulating
deterministic models
and believe down the couple of other people the stuff on emulating stochastic models but
still work to be done there is
a paper by richard boys and darren wilkinson submission where they
approximated the output by some parametric family and later date parameter values guassian process to
the emulated math model for the stochastic simulator
it just to summarise again
no longer bound to do this they allowed to do inference in models for which
we would not otherwise be able to can we can
we can let the centre given whatever money they want and long as we can
see observations from a reasonably cheaply we can do some sort of inference for them
very easy to code relating to give it to take into account any problem can
i failure to adapt if you change your model anyway if you change your priors
if you want to add more data
the inference which is the same
with the MCMC if you change your model you often find you need to go
through the whole process of the tuning everything finding new proposal distributions setting mixing convergence
and so on the face simple as that