cruel repulsive hideous creatures
horrible monsters
then he saw one of them creeping towards him
he aimed his weapon
and opened fire on it
the enemy gave that strange horrible cry that all of them used
to utter
then a deathly silence
it was dead
the cry and the sight of the dead body made him shudder
in the course of time many of them had become accustomed
took no notice of that but not he they were horrible disgusting
creatures with only two legs
two arms
two eyes that sickening white skin and without scales
so while reading we are thinking of something like that and on the contrary
to a something
like that
Karl Rosenkranz in his aesthetics of ugliness draws an analogy between ugliness and moral
just as evil in seeing are the opposite of good
whose hell they represent so his ugliness the hell of beauty
I want only to show you many experiments made by an unknown American artists
that artist that I found in internet suggesting what they say
call uglifications
ugly is not only the opposite of beauty because if we examine this synonyms of
ugly we find repellent horrible horrendous disgusting disagreeable grotesque abominable repulsive oduse
indecent fool dirty obscene repugnant frightening object monstrous
horrid horrifying unpleasant terrible terrifying frightful nightmarish revolting sickening fetid
fearsome ingnoble ungainly displeasing tiresome offensive deformed
disfigured and so on so there is a variety a very rich phenomenology
in general it seems that the experience of beauty arouses what can't defined as
disinterested pleasure
whereas we would like to have all that seems agreeable to us and to take
part in all that seems good the judgment of taste the site of a
flower procuse a pleasure that excludes any desire for possession or consumption we don't you
don't want to eat the the flower you want to
he has certain philosophers have a wonder whether it is possible to make an aesthetic
judgment of ugliness
given that ugliness arouses emotional reactions such as disgust and repulsion
as a matter of fact we owe to distinguish between manifestation of ugliness in itself
like the ugliness of an extrement decomposing carry on someone covered with sause who gives
us nauseating stench or this animal which
last year won the contest for the ugliest dog in the world
and we have to distinguish it these sort of natural
total ugliness from formal ugliness
understood as a lack of equilibrium in the organic relationship between the parts of the
hole besides these beautiful paintings by Ghirlandaio suggest has the tender attitude
of the grandchild that shows that a person an animal or else can be ugly
and at the same time
and lovable
as it happens to us with many
actors they are ugly but we like them
however these portrait what is also an example of beautiful artistic representation of
which is another kind
of concept because there is also the artistic ugliness let's see in the contrary
these example of ugly artistic representation
a real example of teach incidentally the author was Adolf Hitler and the
fact that he decided later to shift to politics has been certainly a disaster
for the history of the world but a happy event for the history of
art the the Greek identify the beautiful with good
kalos kai agathos and by consequent ugly with evil
see for instance the description of Thersites in
Thersites was the ugliest man that stood before Ilium bandy legs and lame in
one foot he had round shoulders hunched over his chest
he had a pointed head and sparse thin hair
Achilles and Ulysses hated him the most for he often insulted them
but at the same the Greek know that Socrates
was as ugly as Silenus
but he had a great soul
and Aesop
who according to the legend was repugnant to the sight disgusting fat belly bulching head
pug nose gibbous he was swarthy and short with flat feet short arms bendy legs thick lips
stammered and was quite unable to express himself
what's defined as a
benefactor of humanity
we idealize the Greek culture and mainly focused around beauty and harmony
we idealize the Greek culture as a culture mainly focused about around beauty and harmony but
we frequently forget that the Greek world was also populated by terrifying creatures hybrids
that violated the lows of natural forms like the harpies or the sirens were not
right the correct probability distribution
and now we have in
and edge here
then again rain sprinkler become dependent
marginally which is also incorrect this is nothing i can do to represent
the simple sets of
dependencies that arise very naturally from causal relationships can cause variables and variables
now there's another interesting aspect of
graphs like this
these particular structures exhibit something called explaining away
which is
imagine that we observe that the ground was wet
now there are two possible explanations under this model
either if all these arranged either range
or the sprinklers on
or with some very small probability both
both rate and this was
so we have to think of all the possible explanations for the ground being where
if we
look at
the weather report and we find that in fact it did rain
knowing this variable
explains away the observation that the ground was wet
and therefore we don't need to infer that the sprinkler was on
these two variables by having a common child
become dependent on each other in this particular way once we observed that
sure way of saying that is that observing the the sprinkler is on would explain
away the observation of the ground was wet making it less probable that it rained
let's move on to directed graphical models are directed basically graphs these are sometimes called
bayesian networks but i also think this is a great name for them in particular
have a footnote here
which says
bayesian networks can and often are learned using non bayesian in other words frequentist method
bayesian networks there's nothing about these networks the required parameters structure learning using bayesian methods
and if you look in the prose book
but it doesn't actually use this method
for the most part for learning bayesian so let's call them more descriptively we can
just call them directed
graphical models are directed acyclic graphs
and directed acyclic graph
corresponds to a factorisation of the joint probability distribution in the following way
we say
that is we have this graph that means that the join probability of the
variables factors into the probability distribution over a
that is the probability distribution over b
the probability distribution over the given a and b
he would be in the
given c and d
in in general we have is that the joint distribution factors into the product
the probability of each other variables
given its parents in the graph
the parents of via just the parents of node i that obviously the nodes that
at the tail end of the arrows that point to that
that's directed graphical models
and like undirected graph and
and factor graphs
we can read off the conditional independence relationships between the variables from the directed graph
now in undirected graphs and factor graphs is really easy we just want to have
and we can tell whether things are conditionally independent or not
now we have a slightly more complicated criterion which takes
you know
in our so to get you we don't have an hour the so
if you live in your example work afterwards you want
x is conditionally independent from y given the that variables v
if v
dependency separate that these separate x from y
so think of
dependency flowing through the graph and we're trying to see whether the set of variables
separate x from y
so that x and y become independent when we observed variables be
and here is the definition
the separation
the set b
the separate x from y
if every undirected path that mean path when we actually
i can go
along the
arrows and backwards through the
if every undirected path between x and b x and y
that that we can it we can boost the performance from
the of pretty much when we reach the limit but we can do individual
so i talk a little bit about the timeline and
the tree methods date back
twenty three years or so twenty four years two cards being able to actually go
way beyond that because they've been invented multiple fields but probably the most influential
and in many ways the best outline was
but by
the o'brien j freeman
ocean stone and it's a commercial product now which is good one
but there are trees in both pretty much every sweet
by leo o'brien was
i recently submitted
two the statistics journal
and was rejected
and they got into the machine learning journal november nineteen six where he became a
citation classic within a year two
and made him a hero and that fields
the statistics field of which i'm very fundament ingenuity by our engineers but still suspicions
were just one of these statisticians but it has a habit sometimes leading its owner
are not recognizing generating a lot of fields that become successful elsewhere but the idea
was to
two bootstrap aggregates of different models
and this
so somewhat both out of the blue
adaboost came out in ninety seven was very strange and heuristic procedure
the the
started to do very well people excited
and then it sort of cleanup and input into statistical framework for a few years
importance sampling
is much more recent starting to make things clear
divided you want to cover some of the
details here you want to get to one
this year so so john when he hits a little more this
parallel to the simple fact that they tried
one one
i formal station
so are they saying
a from this problem we have turned their home
they were
how rules
so we're right
so what
they are
so so
my friend
and then the more simply my polish
the called decision that that's all
two of i neural
so what these were
i said oh by the
price caused by a fuzzy rules
four we
we've shown
they are also going to say a few things that you can tell us
so these are different
how we call this rule is
so we see some of the features of trees and why they is not all
five stations they're all
what is this song for this is a list of all of
and when you assemble as you have say
is the problem
but we don't have what i look at one hundred three and so on to
go away
so what is that
also we talk about that
and you know this is an i i
these were
forty five years of finer
because the
i the
no indication that we are all
but five years later i think
i think this see more
thank you
all right so we do a little bit of overview predictive learning and decision trees
predictive learning just together are addition right we have to
independent the labels are inputs t p in this example in response to the good
or bad
good is blue band screen
you might
i don't know how comes out of the scaling your nodes sorry about that we
can think ahead completely
so in the one of mark while looking at the green you know there's there's
definitely of boundary then there's the one there in the middle there is the question
mark what's what's that should only be labeled
depending on what estimation technique you have a different label for that or you may
even have and and certainly value for year determination
we can be descriptive trying to summarize the data
in some way to understand what actionable or predicting which is more likely what we
focus on
what is the response to the class of new point middle
so ordinary linear regression will fit data
both the interior points and on the boundary points
the two creations are called the MIB creations
and the you might be flow
can lead to the solution to this might creations
as in newport in fact
yemeni flow
it's essentially has the same computational power as the ricci flow for surfaces however this
will sectors they hold for manifold
as we have seen we have some results from the smoke setting but you are
to apply this to the engineer feels we need to discard as everything
now comes the discrete as asian
in engineering fields
surfaces are represented as piece that's linear
triangular meshes
and so it's kind of discrete models can be easily acquired using the scanners in
real time these days
on such kind of peace last linear constructions we can define the notion of metrics
curvature is an exceptional
the discrete metric is defined as the function over edges
say just says the l one l two announce three in the first figure
the function should satisfy in the triangle inequality
the discrete curvature another hand
it is also a function but is defined on the viruses
and the worries
footage each were is the curvature is defined as the
difference between two pi
and it's running angles for the interior minister and sort the boundary waters
the curvature defined as pi minus the surrounding angles
also we will we will like to know that the total curvature should satisfy the
discrete gas with that theory
the discrete metrics
can determine the discrete curvature by using the cosine law
here i show the cosine law in the euclidean case we also have the similar
laws for hyperbolic and spherical cases
as we have seen the ricci flow
well the discrete curvature flows deform the metric can family
and in the discrete setting we have two approaches to the discrete rising this process
the first one is analogy call one
this is by discrete you might be flow
it uses the typical discrete notions of metric and the vertex and the come from
factors a second one is john magic approach which is the discrete ricci flow
this way use the so-called circle packing metric
OK let's look at the discrete you might be flow first
for the you have to be flow
we can define the can formal factor well actually it's a lot of that come
from the factor which is you
on the various is directly
and we use the
excellent as the discrete metric
in this way we can deform by multiplying with
eight e to the u i and times e to the u j
and the discrete you might be flow in this case can be defined using the
following differential equation which is defined in terms of the your URI and k i
on the other hand discrete ricci flow
defines in another way
it uses the so-called circle packing metric
basically for everyone x on the surface
we can associated with a circle of radius
and for each edge
the two circles can intersect at the end goal of
i j
and the edge length could be given using the cosine law
again here i only you show the euclidean case you have similar results for hyperbolic
and spherical one
for the
this could ricci flow
we can define it in terms of the vertex really i
that my and the vertex curvature k i
as i have said discrete ricci flow can be defined for euclidean hyperbolic or spherical
cases for example for euclidean cases
we can define an edgy cut the entropy energy
then is actually an integration
the surfaces
using this energy
during them all these are not allowed to to show that
the euclidean ricci energy is well defined and in this context that means there exists
a unique global minimum
and the discrete euclidean ricci flow converges to that global minimum
guaranteed by that syria we can find some numerical methods so the discrete ricci flow
the first method is a gradient descent method
since ricci flow is just the gradient flow to minimise the ricci energy
we can use the gradient descent method directly or in another way
we can use the newton's method here we need to compute the hessian matrix of
the ricci energy in the following way
this figure shows the results of the discrete euclidean ricci flow
the figure on the left is the original surface and the figure in the middle
is the
canonical metric
wisconsin college actually hear the country's zero
and the figure on the right is a universal covering space
now into surface
we can apply the discrete ricci flow for hyperbolic cases and here is the result
from the hyperbolic discrete ricci flow the surface on the left can be double covered
for the hygienist closed surface and then we can flatten the surface into the hyperbolic
OK after discrete house everything
we are allowed to apply the discrete curvature flows
two sold some practical problems in engineering fields
and actually many such kind of problems can be formulated as finding a special metric
with certain curvature concerts
service privatisation
it is actually to find a flat metric
it's about the general setting of the
a structured learning problem and he
because i asked him so he made a distinction between the gentleman at the end
of this commitment to the he told us the advantage of discriminative method
is the ability to t incorporates
more information into the model such as sequences looking into the previous or next observations
in order to predict the label and he talked about the dynamic programming for sequences
two he said that every decoding is good for
computing the most likely
label assignment for sequences and forward backward algorithm is good for
computing the expectations and we saw MEMM serious and perceptrons as
as the discriminative methods now we're going to see if the ends in detail so
all one thing he didn't explicitly mention is the perceptron we can think of the
perceptron as as a as a classification method where we're trying to find find a
hyperplane that separates the data
and of a given that one obvious thing to do is to find a hyperplane
that separates the data with a maximum margin as opposed to just finding a separation
hyperplane and as we can do in st anne's and we're going to talk about
it spans two instructional domain more in detail
well because that is something that i have proposed with my advisor in a graduate
and also
there is there there was a follow-up paper by ben taskar and colleagues in and
turns it seems to be the most cited paper in this field really structured learning
field so i think that this is some crucial
literature so for svms where we will first defines a margin and then look into
the primal and dual of optimisation problems will see an algorithm and then david we'll
talk about generalisation bounds
so in the general setting binary classification problem what does this mean and do we
have a binary class
classification we have a lose lose squares
and that does and we want to set fire to find a hyperplane and what
is he says is to find a hyperplane
that separates the data with maximum margin the hyperplane w that separates the data with
maximum margin where the marginal
gamma is defined to be the distance
from each class
that are closest to the separation hyperplane
so given this hyperplane
each state
when we take the inner product
in look its and we can assign label rate if it's less than the one
that it is
if it's sorry if this is this is the type of its name negative we
assign it to the negative class and close to be assigned to the positive class
and this optimisation problem can be as we have seen many times in this summer
school can be stated in terms of in l two norm we try to minimize
the l two norm of the separating hyperplane with respect to some constraints and the
constraints tell us that for each
data points
the label we assign
to that data point which is the sign of this
in our product so much to the correct label
and not only that the real value coming from the inner product gives us confidence
score and we want to be
larger than one we want that multiplied with the correct label to be larger than
OK we need is already well and then in the real world problems in in
in general it's not possible it is not possible to
as for being a separation hyperplane so we're going to have some nice we we
we say that not all the constraints will be key can be
we can cannot
we can achieve all the constraints so we're going to allow someone relations in those
so there will be some data points like this which may not which may be
classified incorrectly or they will be some data points like this which may not achieve
some marginal so for those we're going to introduce some slack variable size
so that we we achieve the margin constraints but we're gonna get penalised in our
objective function for this innovation
for the slack variables
and the constraints that hold with equality we're going to call them active constraints
and the data points that correspond to those constraints we're going to call them support
and again we have seen this many times
that in fact are separating hyperplane can be represented in terms of our support vectors
so when we are given a new data point x
the way we classify as we take the inner product with into one
of this new data
with the support vectors and combine them linearly with some
alpha parameters
so this was the standard binary class support vector
machine setting
and how
can we generalize this to structured problems
well first we need to define the margin what is the marginal
i should have said in the previous slide that the margin
is actually this value
the real value the the compatibility score of
i'm sorry to the
the confidence of our assignment
ten data point times it's correct labels
and in this case
what we say
what they it from your hands
previous work which he also presented here we say we define the separation had the
separation margin as follows for each data point i will look at the value which
i'm sure everyone here is familiar with the recommendation problem where
we have some set of users and some set of items
the goal is to predict which items are given user will like
now we've got several sort of data
which can help solve this problem so most importantly we've got ratings data
which is some indication of how much user will let users like other items
we might also have information which is specific about the items so variations and these
might have cast lists or johnr information or use or items are actually going to
the technical specifications for example
we might also have information about a user so we could have demographic information it's
very easy to where they live or information from social network data
so there are two main approaches to recommendation problem in collaborative filtering and content based
so collaborative filtering
the idea is to use the information about which
i sense
like four to make predictions what i can say like future
this method in general works really really well
those who follow the netflix prize it doesn't work quite million dollars well yet but
really close
how to coaching
generally works very well
because it captures in general both the
features of nice and so whether maybe
it will recommend horror movies like armor these
also differentiate between good horror movie about her
however this has problems the main problems of what we do we got fourteen movie
which we haven't which alternated for
what we do need to come the meeting you get what you recommend in that
in one sense is edge problems but quite important problems because
if your business is recommending movies you really want to recommend new to people
and if you got to website recommends things to people who want to make sure
that new people
stable system rather than the realise of the ratings of the recommendations of rubbish only
want someone else's recommender system
so this is quite a problem with current methods
on the other hand we have content based methods
and content based filtering we look at what items users like to recommend items that
are similar to the ones that uses light and some
measure of similarity based on the content of the items
this has the advantage that center new items very easily doesn't matter enunciated by got
that's what active in it all
what genre it is o
reviews on IMDB or whatever
and in general content based filtering
really good at capturing
jonathan type information
but there less good
that with less good at identifying quality of an itemset telling thing that could hardly
be invited her
so it seems these two approaches have complementary
advantages and problem
so we were looking for a
that combine these two
approaches to recommendation
matrix factorisation is quite commonly used approach in
recommender systems are taken captive filtering
and the basic idea here is we you are
ratings data as a incomplete matrix containing the
ratings given by the users to the end with movies
which i that rises matrix product too low rank matrices here a and b
where a is you by k
b is k by and
we some
social fourteen
right the ratings from this
to make
so we extend we can extend this idea to factor most places at the same
so here i've demonstrated how we can
factorize a partially observed
we been things matrix are
and the fully observed content matrix s
and here
are is addressed a b s is called the bayes factor is going to be
in c
and the latent matrix b is constrained to be common to both makes these
now here shown to just two matches but if we had
in addition to have contemplated as we also had
demographic information because i not the matrix to the left of the diagram constraint that
going backwards to me would easy by a matrix where is common between the
make the user matrix and the ratings matrix are
we can take this model and
users are for for the matrix factorisation we can use a new calcium cases the
approach can take with this model
where we have the ratings matrix are the entries this or gas industries is given
by the product of the
the matrix and some variants the sweat
and similarly the matrix given by justice peter means times b
in order to perform bayesian inference in this we put priors on the
this makes is a b and c which is this prior to be zero mean
we can use
variational bayes to perform inference in this model
this works out very nicely simply means
we introduce a variational distribution to have a b and c
we use jensen's inequality to learn about the log likelihood on the marginal likelihood
we then it is our
one of the approximation which is we assume that our variational distribution can be factorized
into the product of the
individual distributions on a b and c
if we do this we see that the variational distributions are also gaussians
we can derive the updates to the means and variances these variational distributions on a
b and c
we hold
two constant and updates a b and c in turn until convergence
this is exactly what we did on the movie lens dataset
so here are the movies dataset is the data set
around thousand users and around thousand half movies
we've got a a hundred thousand ratings in total and that's what we sell participate
paychecks obviously
the constant data included with the movie lens dataset
there is a
binary shorts genre information where each movie is associated with zero or more
a set of genres
in orbit
o is the half
that makes it always
so is the a half year this is also
one half
and remember
the potential energy
equals minus
and so
and earth
divided by our
so here you see plus half
you see minus one
this is indeed minus
after potential energy
what is the total energy
of the earth
around the sun that means the sum
of potential energy
genetic and
the kinetic energy is minus one
and the potential energy is you
so this is
is it plus one half you
that means it's negative
because you itself is negative
it is also
equal to minus k
i just calculated for fun
how large that number is it's the negative number large that is
and it turns out to be approximately minus
o point seven
i'm stand two to thirty
we do this
if we get bored and we want to
leave the solar system
then we can ask yourself the question if we model rocket to the earth and
we fired rockets
how much speed should we give it
to get away from the sun once and for all and never come back
well we would have to do is make the total energy of the or zero
so it can cruise all the way to infinity
and have zero speed when it gets there
how can i make this zero
well i have two heads
the kinetic energy exactly k
because my netscape was k is zero
if i have to
the kinetic energy k
then the new kinetic energy
after the rocket burn
could be exactly two k potential energy is not changing
because you fired a rocket when you there
and so you the same position after rocket fire and so you potential energy hasn't
but you can edit energy must have doubled it hasn't doubled this doesn't become zero
but if the kinetic energy has doubled
then the speed must have gone up
by the square root of two because kinetic energy is proportional to the square
so to escape velocity
must be the square root of two
i'm for the velocity
and that would be forty earth the square root of two
i'm thirty which is about forty two kilometres
per second
by looking at the energy considerations
you can
connection between
total energy
escape velocity
make the whole picture internally
we talked for one whole lecture
about resistive forces
i still remember the number of that lecture number twelve
because it's the one lecture i work
on it more than any other
with the help
my graduate students they fully with it
these wonderful
calculations numerical solution
and so
let's talk a little bit about
they resist the forces
if an object moves through the air or liquid
there's a resistive force
which all these opposes the velocity
it has two terms
k one times the this is the speed is always positive
was a two
and this is the unit vector
of the velocity always opposing develop
so this is
is the magnitude of the resistive force
we dealt exclusively with fears remember
and we get some
would experiment with spheres k one
equal c one times are
and k two
times are square
and we did some experiments with corn cereal
and this was
the search for which see one
was approximately one hundred sixty
and c two
it's about one point two
ten to thirty kilograms per cubic metres
o memory units of this
because that's always density
in fact it's always a little smaller than the actual density of the
the equator of the sphere itself this is more complicated
unit but you can figure that one out for yourself and so we had ball
bearings one-eighth of an inch diameter two quarter of an inch
and we dropped in
carol here
if we take the one for now
which is a quarter of an inch diameter
and the mass of the water
it's about o point one grams
we know density
of steel and so you can figure out the mass just take my word for
and so the question now is
if this
well there starts to fall what is this speed that it will
chief well
in the beginning
there is
only MG
on that ball
and the teeny-weeny little resistive force
as the speed built up
the resisting force will grow
and there comes a time
that it's equal
two mg
then object will not be accelerated anymore
and it will have what we call the for terminal velocity
so what are the conditions for terminal velocity
this term equals MC
in other words that
c one
he two
this graph becomes equal
two mg
and that's the case
then we have reached the terminal
this is a
quadratic equation in
view of t
you know c one
you know c to you know to radius of the ball bearings in order massive
ball-bearing so we can solve for the terminal
velocity you get two solutions it is
quadratic equation one it will be non-physical you will see so you keep the one
that is physical but if you did that
that would be
the city thing to do
and the reason why that would be silly is
but i claim that this term
which by the way we call the pressure terms
this term
can be completely ignored
the most beautiful
we put it in the with we put it in there
label set
we will come up with the most support the process
this is this is what we're trying to do also worked perfectly direction
but we're trying to work applied in the framework of the los angeles
so why you will be able to say and reason
so all of
don't have we represent our data to explain why we should be able to say
the most difficult
representation with a our documents which the work to create a table
one have the documents so the terms
and we have the characters of its terminates document
so what we are endorsing the call caller utterances of the documents and the war
the problem we have its war because what i've synonyms many water polysems
and this can create a disconnection between the topics of the documents and words what
i mean and example
if we take the world if a document has to walk able inside
we don't know if you do the topic its fruits or it's a computers max
so here's where second
and a he
also try to give something behind there was something about the
topics of the day
of the document
and how he does that
he does that by introducing london viable which is the components
actually the topic
and with an organ model one model our our algorithm using the equation there were
actually the
we have the profile of the component of the final of the topic that ended
the war
from what's gone there consisted the topic
and the topics
with sorry in a document from the wood from
four which set up its the document
but just beginning we're just semisupervised
say so one two
top place in semi supervised learning
we will use the framework organisms revise framework introduced by e
the and a good last year two thousand five
so let's see
normally can
can be used as we can extend the same this over my this was revised
more easily
but there's a problem that the curious it that the ratio of labeled unlabeled data
is really low
then many components with no knowledge data appears
and that's great the problem of
and that's the problem because then arbitrary probabilities will be assigned to the to these
and this will also influence or
because the components on the labeled data then even a real answer to probability
we learn
we'll assign the particular labelled the components and then we can alternative if said in
so the idea is to introduce another viable with a fake label
let's say zero lazio zero then
the labelled data we keep their labor really and they labelled data we all get
the labels so
he was in the binary case
for example
the labelled examples keep their own labels and all the labels gets into
into the new labels
i'm using
this matrix
we can say we can train our model of course after the training
we have
somehow to assign these probabilities
which are obtained for the fake label in the truly because this is what we
are interesting in
so using this equation what we're doing is downweighting the unlabelled example which is actually
and to a
but of course the influence but there there are not enforced and the label example
which are the motion to set
so using this
this new viable
our model
it becomes
it's like this
and in order to train on more than we use a in my life has
all have london bibles
the log likelihood of all of our model is actually the sum of the documents
is the sum of the degree of fulfilment so full words
o thing concurrency of occurrences of the word in a document
times the probability that john on the local food and probability of document the water
and the label of this work including the fake
here's the EM with my one day
get the data we are now
i'm not going a using
using their
the cloister naive brindley before
we obtain their
the probability so far of the classification probabilities
so here is where active learning appeared
want to apply stacked learning on the top of the same supervised learning
now all labelled data have probability
of being in a in class
so which is the most ambiguous example
where we use
which is the most
in this method with it
the example which is which has the highest entropy
in the multiclass case in the binary this can be supplied simplified there
document was the probability closest to p o five
with which is so this document will label will put it in a set of
labelled examples and we train our models
so this is a the simple as that
so we experiment with it in order to
to test our method and it's an ongoing work so we haven't done months we
use three binary problems of the twenty news groups
we try to find three examples
the one more difficult than the other so the first one is visible this wiki
see versus martin rees in the southeast
so the first is quite easy to moderate with moderate and the other hard in
the brain is is the number of examples of the set
one of its category
we used a eighty percent of the training set us there
eighty percent of the day this training set
from wheat that we use to labelled examples as a initial sec one of class
and all the others
and ten percent just to test the accuracy of our system
the comparison who have done is say our method with uses supervised learning reversibility plus
active learning
and we tested with a semisupervised principle is random query
where the idea is perform the same supervised PLSA
and then instead of being active learning with just amount of a document from the
labelled set
and we live in it
and as a as a baseline we to the SVM blast active learning which is
the example closest to the margin
but what we mostly interesting in the comparison of the two first because it's the
active learning part
i want to see if it helps or not
so this year something some results from the first experiment from the first set there
the black line the first in the top it's our algorithm which is the same
as revised the prospect of learning
and then
it is several file but
this quantity here
is one minus
that quantity
get that
so ever classifiers are perfect
this summer
that's so probability plus one
and this is the issue of maybe they're imperfect right
but are that's it's pretty easy to analyse
OK so
you can take the probably analysis in contrast originates
o thing but the bushes to the expectation because of to inequality
and you get this statement says the distance between
your prediction in
any the actual
spent about
you are binary regret spirited
this is essentially worthless currency come from
so these problems
right so that we have this this
which is defining
how we predict
what's news for an adversary
again we're going to have an adversarial analysis
we're saying
suppose an adversary has some but it's too
because when and
that should probably be that
as the most efficient way
for him to shift the sum
the distance to dig and sift the sum is to control the multiclass ar
so the most efficient way to disturb the sum
it's actually
at the same disturbance for every element of the cell
and that's because of this current
in order to get a big disturbance you have to pay
you have to pay the square
of the regret
so i
that's correct
this says that
the size of the disturbance
so it's thousand disturbances like the square root
so the amount that you pay
so far you go out
the size the disturbances how far you go
so this into the diminishing returns the further you go out
the less disturbance you actually get
he says that going disturb something that each element of the sum
the same amount if you're never adversary
OK so the most efficient way
disturbs the sum
by epsilon times the number
binary classifiers
is to disturb each individual elements that
yes i was this problem but how you define convex to concave
and so this is
it's kind of this context but it can be concave in other contexts
i guess i think of convex
you can say things that
all lines go through the region that
yet there may be a parody issue
is so the appropriate thing that's the graph
the graph is clear
OK so
what this says is that
if we change the l one sometimes by beta and so on
we know choosing classes is no more than
four epsilon
worse than the minimum as far as the area
how do we see that all case remember this
beta and that's the one
and then let's go back a page
as i did this
so if we had
we have the upside on here
then this factor of two means that we can
overestimate probability
two times as long
so a b or two
this is a plus b or b ten ships on which is close to tend
to to be that's over two
i think of it is
in reality is a hard problem but this one looks relatively easy to ask for
the past so that you can you can debate about that
the this one looks is just because we've been trained on this kind of data for a long long time
during our life
this kind of thing chunks
different looks looks hard frost were not used this data
and which maybe makes it more interesting already makes it apparent that it's a hard
problem and of course a lot of the problems that we are
dealing with differences in bioinformatics
is this type of that
we have seen that kind of data flow
so this is the brain has learned to solve problems
we can see that this policy to us
and this a famous neuroscientist horace barlow
once said that brings nothing but statistical decision organ
we have different organs in our body
so the pump blood
so them clean the blood and this one
it's build four statistical decisions that's the brain so if you're we're studying empirical inference and learning since we also
doing theoretical brain research
not at the level of looking at neurons but at the level of tasks that the brain cells
so now it is shown you to inference problems one look easy
two dimensional problem where should directly see what's going on where we probably see in
which case we can generalize which is we can't
you want to task
in the
let's look at another hard inference problem or if you look at some
if what are general properties of hard inference problem
so this is a problem from bioinformatics
the classifier that this is just a component of a larger system to find genes
and this is the classifier that classifies d-day sequence locations i forgot to ask the
other computational biologists in the audience also
okay so
i miss
eight significant group before it my question
classifying human any human being sequence locations
in two three
classes and it doesn't matter if you don't know about these topics
it's just a three-class classification problem which is highly
so the class that have the same size
in the input data x these pieces of these sequence of a certain things
window around the
place that you want to classify
this is a hundred forty one
we have fifteen million training points
and type of
machine learning methods
this is a certain
type performance criteria because the precision recall curve
it doesn't matter
so what the details of the point that i want to make your own is
but here to increase the number of training examples gets better so initially four small
training sets you are more there's a chance level
so the data set looks random to
but as we increase the number of training points quite a bit
here we are ten million
we can do a very good job
it's solving this classification problem
maybe this looks like a trivial point but i think it's important to
keep this in mind
so when we think about machine learning
and if we were human looking at this data set we would always be the regime somewhere
down here we would look a small datasets
we would maybe think that this is
completely random there's no structure
but if we have advanced machine learning methods that can handle large datasets and find their relationships
we can be over here
and we can certainly see a lot of structure
so all the stuff that maybe that might appear human random to us humans
it may not be so random and we might be able to find structure in machine learning
and i think that's only gradually
being acknowledged
this can be a real paradigm shift in how we interpret data in the world
nothing machine learning is going to play an important role in the cell
study the right topic
so what's there
characteristics such problems
and typically out
so you have to look at many simultaneously
they are
complex in various ways
we have
little prior knowledge
by which i mean the difference we don't have a full mechanistic model politicized we had that
what scientists had that and probably they wouldn't
but with the asking us for help they wouldn't bother with applying machine learning
and the
because as a consequence of these points
typically we need large datasets
and this kind of course only be processed if we have
computers which
was because an enabling technology for machine learning
the increase in computing power over the last decades
and if we have advanced inference methods
and yes i really made this point
the first one we can solve problems that humans can solve
and the
even though this is probably just because the datasets are even if it's just a data set size dimensionality
it's a major step
okay so i mean what is the main issue in machine learning
maybe main issues generalization
and in the end just to give you an idea what generalization about is about was problem
the suppose we see this number sequence
one two four seven
ask question what's the next number in the sequence
any guesses
many others
twelve okay
so alone is this
the first
good solution
it's the simple sequence
it's called the lazy caterer's sequence because it's the
maximum number of pieces into which you can cut a piece of cake with end caps
you just have to make sure that every
additional cut intersects all previous cuts in that case being cut gives you an additional pieces
and the same size but there are pieces
and so this is a simple sequence
twelve was also good
is this one
thirteen is the so-called triple matches sequence each numbers the some of the previous three
sixteen we're going to ask me in front explanation later on
said sixteen injured
and the well this one is nice one
this is a sequence that ends twenty eight
this is the set of divisors twenty eight
this is the
when the whisky came up with this that there is no expressions of pi and e interleaved
which is a
also a nice sequence a mathematician
so if you if you look at that and try to to perform the
it's this implementation we
cost you complexity of explosion exponentially in the length of the
of the sequence
it's too much
let's not is that the only factor in the joint distribution
the joint distribution of of the sequence that is really them depending on the
on the last
the last state to the last element in sequence
is the estimates in the sequence
not anyone this one doesn't depend
on qn
in fact as as as a show before in in the little example
and i can be factorized
all the rest of
of the sequence
all the other probabilities
remember that
joint probability is this product
so i take on the last element
and factorize all the rest
because it's not going to be some of our over two in
i'm simply applying
the stability of multiplication over addition
OK so
i'm just doing
let's proceed with this marginalization
if a sum over
sure enough since i have here
q n minus one
this will be a function of
of the
state in the sequence the human is one element in the sequence
if a sum over two minus one
again so first
this again can factorize
as they did previously
using the
the sequence until minus one and then the property of minus one so again
i can factorize
out of the sum
if a sum over
over that it will be a function of n minus two
if some over the
and minus one element in in the sequence
and so on
it's a c
t plus one
so i have now
the probability of my sequence from the first element to the
take two
t plus one element
but i have collected a better function which depend
ieong show
t plus one
if a sum over t plus one
we have
so here
this decomposes into
the sequence until t
and the probability of seeing given
of t plus one given t so if a sum over t plus one
and we have
the function of
OK so now i have to stop because the
because i can and some of it
i can begin from the other side of the of the sequence
i can do the same thing because i can factorize this time for from the
other side take one one in the join in the product of the joint distribution
take the first term instead of taking the last one
this again broke into
i can break into the sediments in the cell the prior probability times the probability
she and
now after two given to us
and this
if a sum
first of all could one it will be a functionof of q two and then
doing that repeatedly
we have
in the end
OK so the
almost the last step is the ice over two t plus one
and i have to have fit finish taking nine or the products mainly during probity
and i only have this last
have collected a function f phi of minus one
if a sum over t minus one
i have
this alpha qt
in the end i
the in the beginning i had this big
some asian problem
and then they just have these two products
we use it of course that i find beta that are computed recursively
and the complexity this time is the
it's a square of of of the links of my
my sequence
square of number of states which is much smaller than the
the naive approach
so having that
we can compute a lot of things
this too so if
it's easy to compute them once
and stop them
then did the
no you two to compute a lot of things in this in this graphical model
for example we see that we can compute the temperature of two consecutive state of
two consecutive sorry elements in a sequence
so you would be
as i was going through the chain and stopping
at the first amendment
something for the first moment from the other side stopping the second element
but that's that's an idea to two
so it's the easter fairly simple simple example
but it so those of you who know all
he then that given markov mothers you know that there is forward backward
i was algorithm who works like that just makes more difficult because the qtrs observed
so you have there are latent variables
so you will not do
directed inference like that you will have to find info about words using their expectation
where are you
you have this latent you estimate them then you used them to maxima lies and
in something like that in fact in the chain
hmm are
our journey generalisation of that
in fact what we need here is to be
in independent
conditionally independent have group of separated
separated the
the correct
three y one
i would have a high discriminant value then every incorrect three one
all right
i have a set of constraints like that for every training
and then i regularized and again all
if that problem has a solution
then i know i have
the weight vector that gives me zero training
probably not
possible in practice so we have to introduce a loss function
for example if i can
this one i can actually get
then i would want to pay a penalty
a large proportion of
and that's all
how bad this
new prediction
and there are multiple ways of you can see how we can achieve that in
the linear model
one called slack rescaling one margin scaling margin rescaling simply
he'll the distance that you want to have in the
correct one and each incorrect one
the love you have incorrect one over ten
we have a slack variable that takes the value that's that followed by the
so in terms of an optimisation problem which is likely to replace the mach one
with the loss function just trying to value
and then the slack variables here
into the objective again just like in regular SVM
and again it's easy to see
some of the slack variables gives you an upper bound on the training
just like for regular SVM is one
so by solving this optimisation problem
optimized train
so let's try that
actually for natural language parsing
what i've done here it is
they can depend treebank
that's the standard
use only short sentences to be more efficient one
efficiency is are actually
so i'm using mark johnson part
and a trained
probabilistic context free grammars in the generative and i just think about
in the same grammar
using the SVM approach
when using this f one for the loss that the typical kind of war that
people use to evaluate
quality of parts
and again just like four
text classification
we are actually doing exactly the same model
it is the
that's exactly the same parameters but once trained in action
kind of the naive bayes equivalent of grammar
and once the train is indiscriminate fashion
and what you see is both that the error rate the the number of correct
the accuracy of the network
he goes
and you want to work well
not as much as the text classification but is using
ask and others have
done therefore much more complicated creatures and i think
using essentially the same approach
what they were managed to get essentially a state of the art
let me wrap up with this general framework
i wanted to apply
this method to this general to two in the problem after all
yes if i think to specify loss function
so how bad is it to predict a particular label
number one is correct
i have to come up with the representation
and i can often build on generative models conditional random field
then to do prediction i solve this discriminant value discriminant problem over
this linear model
and for training i have to solve this product
and what have also in the rest of the talk is actually
quite a lot of structure prediction problems fit into this
so one thing that you may wonder was glossed over
small details right
actually solve the problem
if you look at the
so if the convex quadratic programs
it's a bit
what kind of
in the the notation here is
that i have a lot of constraints
in particular
in this for annotation here is
the constraint that
the correct course three has to have
high value any incorrect parts
the constraint for every
incorrect car possible
that's an exponential number of constraints
i wanted to find that
it's you
so typing this into map that is not possible even for small toy problems
so how do actually solve these programs is that actually tractable
so that
brings up the question of how well actually training was not just the formulation of
the problem but the training
so let's think about this
so here's the optimisation problem again
and despite the fact that i have a lot of constraints here
if you think about it
then the solution that i'm looking for
just lies in the corner
this is depiction where the shading is the objective value
and the lines of constraints
really solution
probably going to be only a few constraints that actually act
these other great of constraints here
well there in the problem but they don't actually i can just leave
and what they were able to show
initially was the fact you can
you only are interested in solution
correct up to some epsilon which
the arbitrary
then the number of constraints that you have to consider that after the solution is
polynomially bounded
in that
but despite the fact that you have an exponential number of constraints the number actually
need is small
white's polynomial
polynomial but it
i like to think that the k i squared distribution is a gamma because that's
where i don't have to remember lots of get different distributions but it's a gamma
distribution and the way i parameterize gamma which is this form here is this density
that's the normalizer the
many important part of actually i minus one e to the minus be x
that's the form of the distribution and x
in this form the mean of this distribution is over be sometimes people said it
so that the bees underneath x and the main is eight times be but this
is the way i like to do it
writing in the case where it is shown that it scale by sigma squared
yeah so this is actually a scale parameter
armies sigma squared appears underneath it yeah so you've got a gamma distribution
the square this value here is distributed as a gamma with any parameter the shape parameters at a half
and so what i think it was the rate parameter
sector one over two sigma squared
so the nice thing about this is what you're interested in is the distance from the actual origin all the
a sample
you increase the dimensions yeah
and what it turns out is the gamma rather nicely if we want to gamma
variables hear and ask what's inside the square root hair
that's also gamma distributed
as long as the scales these two gammas the same
which they are resuming the same variance is gamma distributed with shape parameter
which is the sum of the shape parameters these guys so in this case is one
and the scale rate parameter which is the same as before
that's it these guys are independent which i'm assuming they are so it that's important
we're assuming with sampling each about features about data in this calcium egg is being
independently sampled from gauss in distribution which is spherical
so we can compute this cumulative density function and indeed we can do it
on peak
dimensional data
so people dimensional data the sum over these why i squared
these like why i squared so this is the i th data points in each
dimension and it is distributed as a gamma with shape parameter p e over to
now that means that the expected value
on the this distribution is pete times sigma squared
so what we typically do is will ask about one over pete times expected value
so that we keep the expected value of the squared distances and peter mentions now
from the origin
to be sigma squared so that means that in the case that the standard normal
it's gonna be one yeah so we'll be working with standard normals
so the scaling and that's scales the rate parameter on
ants we've got now
i density formula that says what will that distance the squared distance how is the
squared distance from the mean distributed now that's nice because in our galaxy egg model
we can now ask the question how
that's square distance from the mean vary with the number of dimensions you see this density is a function p
the mean distance from the
so the mean distance from the origin
which is the mean in this case
that's the entire volume of the egg and you start out with a yoke which
is sixty five percent of the egg
hands a white which was i think twenty eight percent not initially the volume of the white portion goes up
but then actually it starts to drop down
i mean you see the yolk drops down as well until when you get two thousand dimensions
with what defined to be the aluminium
you basically have only
see points which are back distance from the mean all your data sets
and at shell design makes sense
so that's very counterintuitive but is what you think if you look at the calcium
because you can see the calcium the data is close to the mean right
you know the galaxy and the data is close to the mean
it's very obvious right
now there's a fun factor every model we assume is a calcium
so this is a two-dimensional joint calcium with variance one
but actually no it's not a three-dimensional graphs and i'm just showing you the marginal two points to the to
two variables in our gauss you
so a three-dimensional grousing about means that when you look in these two dimensions with
projecting the third dimension down on the first to
so the amount of data that appears close to the mean hit but really in
the third dimension it's sitting away from the mean because it's a three-dimensional graphs
we are not a one-dimensional calcium
so that dimensions
right being projected onto the so that they use it and it really
two other dimensions where the data is away from the mean and it's being projected down to the mean
no it was a five dimensional gaussier
okay i can go online for a while and we are to a thousand dimensions
that say with a thousand dimensions this is a marginal distribution from a thousand dimensional
nine hundred ninety i dimensions are not visualizing just seeing projected down to me
so that means that there is no data the me
if you go to here we can even accounting processes an infinite dimensional gaussians so
you can even talk about infinite dimensional gaussians and look at these two parts survey
yet so there is definitely no data because we've improved the
projected infinite density
dimensions down to the mean
when you look at a guassian well you could guassian is on the restating its
mean whatever people say about what's happening in high dimensional spaces i can see myself
that the state and the mean but remember you're looking at
potentially projection a very very high-dimensional calcium down to those two dimensions which means
the all this data in the high dimensional gaussians must be nowhere near the mean yeah
so in fact this approximation is so good that in many areas they will use a gas in distribution
taking it a highdimensions approximations for sphere
so in very high dimensions if you want to have a uniform data distributed over sphere
you can approximate with a calcium
and that's the sort of known physics trick
what very well
i dimensions going the thousands
so galcians are
bad distributions
half so
the other thing that happens
is interpoint distances so in one slide this is the shiny show that the same
thing happens with the distance between data points if the sample from this calcium density
for very similar reasons it comes out very quickly if you think about it so
if you've got to data points both samples from the same guassian
and then subtracting one of the other leads to another calcium density
and squaring it then again listed this gamma density
that's the only new step subtracting one from another and sigma squared comes to sigma
squared everything else stays the same and you can see
that these data points a gamma distributed
the interpoint distances gamma distributed
with the properties of the gamma being pe over to
appeared before sigma squared rather than to sigma squared as we saw before
immediately right down the corresponding fourier transforms on the homage homogeneous space so in the
case of the sphere
what you get
and that therefore it transform of
this function on the sphere
and the representation rho
was going to be
the integral
again representation matrices call
so the surface integral over the rotation group SO internal rotations of the representation matrices
multiplied by the function but it wasn't controversial you the function of rotation of function
is not on rotations of the sphere to function
function evaluated
o point which you get by rotating your starting element by r
homogeneous spaces are kind of natural construction
and once you know the theory of harmonic analysis on groups you automatically have a
theory of
i harmonic analysis in to mogeneous space is just by this formula
and translations on
on the homogeneous space corresponding natural way to translations of the original group
everything that i said before including the by spectrum and capture this result does carry
OK so we can construct rotation invariance on the sphere we have a function on
the sphere we've form in the fourier transform given by that
from that from the by spectrum and we get at a bunch of numbers
which are going to be
invariant rotating the sphere this is something that's potentially really useful in all sorts of
applications involving rotational invariance
there's is the catch and the catch is that in this sort of context when
you have homogeneous spaces the
singularity condition might be violated
so it seems at first sight the seems
not this business of matrices not being singular and the fourier transform it turns out
that when you do this sort of integral so when you can afford
more that by something and work on homogeneous spaces as opposed to groups
originally typically what happens is at least some of the companies to become singular
so things
become more complicated because
the real power of
the by spectrum
you have to do a bit more work to get
so these are the suggested graphical representation for the
rotations acting on the sphere
thank you
this is all nice and
let's get back to the problem of constructing rotation and translation invariant
how do we link up
what we have
you know about
invariance with respect to the action of combat groups and say something like the sphere
two original problem of invariance with respect to translation and rotation
in the plane
the reason we can't
directly apply
the by spectrum and characterize results two
to this case is that
the group of rigid body motions is not compact
that means that both the overall representation theory
becomes unpleasantly complicated
and also this completeness result
it's something that we can't prove
the idea
and that became up with about a year ago is to establish an isomorphism between
these two types of problems at least local isomorphism
to establish a connection between what we want which is translation and rotation invariance on
the plane
and what we have which is rotation invariance
on the two and on the sphere in
part three
connection is really not that complicated so if you think about what happens when you
project your image onto the sphere
and the anyway but made the most simple way that you can think of just
projecting vertically down by the z axis
and then you think about
what happens to this projected image when you subject the original image to transformations so
things like translation this way
and translation that way
and rotations
then you discover that
effectively what's going to be happening in the sphere is just three-dimensional rotations
in our three
so this is like modelling
noncompact problems locally
by compact problem in one high what in one dimension i
thank you
this is all that it takes to reduce
the original non-combat problem of rotations and translations
into the
classical problem of
symmetry on the sphere
we can push through the all the by spectral
fifty project
we have we can start with the initial image say h
we have project down the sphere
and this is the kind of simple minded way
or or
so this is just the
particular way in which we choose to present the simplest ways to express it in
polar coordinates
so we have to parameterize the sphere somehow in thesis with weight apprentices in terms
of spherical
many wanted project the
the easiest way to set up the correspondences if we start out with those in
the first place
so we start out with
image in order to permit rise concordance with projected onto the sphere and then we
take the
fourier transforms
if you think about
clearly if you look into a little bit in figure out what fourier transformation on
the sphere actually means it turns out that it all boils down to if taking
the spherical harmonic expansion
so these things these matrices coming out there
going to be put together from the ordinary
spherical harmonic coefficients of projected image
so there is this you know
picture of so that
the manifold
and some people agree with this people x from say that's kind of wrong picture to
think about
i think i agree with him but it's but still useful
what we like to do is you know turn ideally what an ideal feature extractor to
do is
a bunch of
samples data points
and tell you
if there is a manifold data tell you where your manifold
with a number of components and have a separate set of components that tell you
distance manifold in all the other dimensions in the space
ok so what you really want you want to kind of
two sets of of variables y is where you want manifold on the other one is
where you are away from the manifold
ok so if you have for example the set of manifold for possible faces all human faces
it's high-dimensional manifold
for a particular person is bounded by the number of muscles in your face and the
number of you know degrees of freedom you can move around six
that if you include everybody then there is some sort of you know number dimensions
basically bounded by the genome of you know how many different cases you can have
what do
and so
you know if we had this manifold then if if we had this kind of a
set features separation
you could use
the first part to tell
who you're looking at what expression making
and you can use the second half
the part tells you you know how far away you are from the manifold to
tell you
if it's a face on not
or something else
so you know disentangling the explanatory factors of variation is really what unsupervised learning should be that
there is a general idea which sort emerging a little bit there is no kind
of concrete our theoretical justification for business what people are doing in the end
which is that feature extractor should really be composed of to steps
a non-linear step basically embeds
the input
into a very high dimensional space on high dimensional space ok this is similar to the
kind of kernel kind of thing right to and things to high-dimensional space so that things are more easily separable that
same stuff
except you know not based on the kernel trick based on other things
f has to be non-linear because it's linear doesn't do anything useful for you
ok so and then your input into a high-dimensional space in some sort of non-linear way
but what to do here is that the breaking this space the the space part of
the things that are semantically similar or even identical will end up in different bins
this representation to be very far apart
so the second step which is sort of generalized pooling similar to the pooling doing commercial nets
is to regroup
the things here are supposed to be similar
ok so whatever
you get vectors here represent two faces and happen to be very different
you somehow encode then such a way that here and have been
yeah it may or may be linear or and sorry that encour you're
probably up or
what people in fact this is something like
i l
so score some squares some components
subset of components
yeah ok yeah yeah right ok so here's an example for very concrete example for the
those of mainstream approach to computer vision and to accomplish on its right so
as a nick are very much for the for example
so formidable features which do here is k-means so you can you take
a seat vector
your need through k-means algorithm k-means is going to
give you a binary vector with all zeros but
and one one at the location of the
prototype this close to the input ok
so just when i take cold kind of encoding if you want
word right visual word
the pulley here takes all those feature vectors for the entire image just represent
or you know combines and some
so knowledge it is a histogram of words and you can see that you have a classifier
and the the the goal of this is to basically give you shifted guyon so
once you do this segregation the position of feature doesn't matter anymore just the presence of that matters
ok to regroup things that were you know
now it turns out when you do something that sparse coding here works much better if you do k-means
sparse coding
preserves a bit of
of ce ity between things right
which k-means just completely
ok so we have this manifold picture a bunch of data points
and what we like is
to can learn function that gives us the dependency between x one x to here in this case
we're going to do is we're going to that this general framework i think that
is most appropriate for this
is sort energy-based framework which consisted
it's actually learning an energy function or think of it as a contrast function that tells you
i give you point of the contrast wanting to scalar that tells you whether you are
on the manifold not on the manifold
if function is
is able to do this internally has to be able to to kind of
do this disentangling features right has to be able to
tell which direction manifold is you know what's the closest point manifold and you know where i doing
manifold things on this right
that's all we can do we're going to train system
to produce a single scalar the scalar to sort of contrast function that tells you
how far we are fundamental data
so let's say we take samples coming from the spiral here
around p c k you can see with only one dimension so it's to
between put problem to a problem
and you can see why
principal component
piece here will find
this may axis here the point cloud
and the the reconstruction error would be zero for anything that's on the principal axis and
with quadratically as we move away from it
i if you sparse coding
you know it will sort of the latter that
i don't give you a tree
and we know that the elimination algorithm could work
but i want to sort of think about doing elimination cleverly i wanna do elimination
in parallel by message passing like i did before
a natural idea the probably many of you would have would be well i can
just sort of start clumping the nodes together i don't have to treat this would
be a simple example i have just a single cycle here
and i could sort of start clumping the notes together and then i could make
a tree on those clumps or clusters of nodes
so for instance one way to do the to put all nodes that are in
the same creature one and three are in the same clique put them in what
you might call supernodes
so this is a new node and it's got a copy of x one and
x three it's sort of new random
and then i could put another supernote here for one and two and another supernova
two and four and another one for three and four
right so i sort of taking my model and i've reduced it to a tree
and then you might think OK well done i can this is the tree and
i can run a message passing algorithm on this this graph
it is that quite skipping because some connection
is there any predictability to
i think my mike is going to
it's not like you
sir batteries
the battery is dead
OK so i
OK so tree here
that's annoying
so you might think that you're off to the races that you can just run
your message passing on the street but the problem here
so what's the problem here
is anyone sort of understand this that
this is useful to think about because this the starts to illustrate what it means
to be local
message passing algorithms are local
they do dumb things that nodes and they as sings along edges they don't know
what's going on globally in the grass they don't care
that's part of the beauty it's beautiful because it makes them fast and efficient and
but it actually causes problems here
so what have intuition for the problem is
so there's and you want to give you think of yourself as the local algorithm
think i'm sitting here and i'm sort of doing stuff with
x three and x four here and standing along this edge
but someone else's my friend is sitting here with x one x three as well
and sending stuff along this edge
we're not actually talking directly ever
any communication we have is getting relayed around i never speaking directly to my friend
in this graph
so any intuition
what would happen if i ran the sum product algorithm on this graph what answer
would give me
why why
one of the
o because i michael sort of you trying to make a tree
true i could
but there's a kind of symmetry here it actually wouldn't matter which edge i forgot
right it's there's the rotational symmetry but that's true
so you could certainly run the sum product algorithm on this graph there's nothing to
stop you from doing it but what you want to understand is that it would
compute something
it would be correct
but it would be correct for the wrong model it wouldn't compute the right thing
for this graph which is what you're interested in
so the reason is because you again have to think about low
locality there's there's really one copy of x three sitting here
and there's another copy of x three sitting here
but in this model there is no way that those two copies know that they
just to give you an an idea that is an application of what i've just
presented so first of all we talk about ontology and metadata ontology refers to the
schema level and metadata refers to the instance level so metadata to ontology is which
would be the instances so let's take that simple ontology have academic staff the disquiet
cooperating with each other so one academic staff can operate with another academic staff and
you know that phd students and assistant professors are academic staff
so now we have two homepages from two of my colleagues on the one hand
you have six the time that and she different stop and if you look now
this would be what your browser shows you this would be the web page you
have you know you will be uniquely identify the websites on the one hand and
on the other hand
and if you look now two the first quote this so-called metadata within the military
attacks html a technically spoken so can include additional information in the hands of those
html documents and she could for example add that secret hundred extra a phd student
which cooperates with assistant professor steffen stop
so he wouldn't stand exactly the schema that just provided
and what differs from html here if you know the so-called age and have which
left text in html then you also have links between pages but you don't have
actually meaning but if you if you were the link between the two persons that
cooperate with each other then you have a well-defined meaning of what these links actually
good for
when we actually use that but there exists the so-called interactive community portal which is
a perfect the thematic network web and if you are interested in topics and themes
around ontology and semantic web and this is a very good starting point because it
notes because it lists the important person that currently in the arena the european research
so this is a nice way of starting your to to find nice documents and
and how does it work technically so that you know that's not true
maintain the paper about ourselves because we had the burden of producing the paper but
we don't want to maintain the content for the next so the idea is that
each partner provides annotation within its own homepages and then we collect the metadata
from the participating partners and integrate it into our portal so that they do first
because they annotate web approach similar to what i've shown before and there exists also
tools that support this man this annotation tasks you typically have a manual annotation but
we don't know have also semi-automatic annotations but we will a bit more about that
in the second part of this tutorial then you integrate different sources different the sources
from different partners but you could also imagine that you have databases we have telephone
lists which you could also integrate then the common language the just that has been
living ontology so for example the common
commercial solution would be to map some databases into an ontology so could map different
data sources into one ontology and then query simply the ontology the thing the entropy
and for intelligence services so this is just an easy example for that and do
and what we do in the papers the first to generate the pattern of the
pre defined ontology so we provide the navigational structures so if you look now for
example at the top level navigational structures this is actually
you derived out of the ontology
we provided permanent search engine so you could ask you those against the ontology and
that as answers the combined results from the participating partners and last but not least
you can produce pre-defined forms to your data manually into the petals so this would
be quite common scenario for example for which is currently up and running
or are all the rage that
there are some things that
this is the test that that is an ongoing effort so currently if you look
you will mostly find the metadata from of course the institute and some partners so
so far we actually provided the basic infrastructure in the next step would be the
partners provide their metadata and the next step would be to make it more melodramatic
because nobody really wants to annotate all homepages automatically and this is one the topics
around that interact better for example we have also the semantic web to make paper
which we know which relies on
so the technology these papers can exchange content for example so you can add the
news events in one part and then it is interchanged with the other portal and
OK well good morning and a very warm welcome to cambridge from this surface typically
sunny day and you know it from in here
OK and over here i guess
so because this is the first talk of the summer school i thought is something
slightly different instead of
trying to teach a lot of technical detail which i think you get from a
lot of the later talks
i thought i'd give you sort of personal perspective on where i think we are
in the field of machine learning and in particular have come to believe that the
next ten years also going to be the most exciting in the entire history of
the field of machine learning because we have some very exciting new techniques which allow
us to address the whole
class of new kinds of applications such really what i want to talk about
in this first talk and it's very much a personal perspective of course of lectures
may have other views on this is well
let me begin with perhaps the most important slide that you'll see which is this
which is to encourage you to ask questions and to make the summer school interactive
now i'm going to stand here two lots of
ninety minutes that you're going to be sat there for twenty lots of ninety minutes
or something it's a it's a long two weeks and
you will get a lot more out of it if we if we make it
interactive so please just interrupt and ask questions as we go through
almost as important as the slide which is just to mention that
o p
taking material taken second talk from from this textbook and a copy here if it
if you like to take a look
i'm going to characterize what i think is happening in the field of machine learning
as a sort of third generation of machine learning and so better explain my terminology
by telling you what i mean by
the first and second generations
was really the first and second generations of machine intelligence i guess
what i call the first generation is is good old-fashioned AI artificial intelligence
and the nice cohen from minsk from nineteen sixty seven within a generation the problem
of creating artificial intelligence will largely be solved
and two years later
anybody recognise this is what this is
how great this is from the film two thousand one so this was i think
released in nineteen sixty eight or they are about the same era and depicted the
by the year two thousand would have the intelligent putative conversation about philosophy with all
sorts of things
and the sort of canonical
first generation technique was the expert system
based on knowledge extracted from humans
i had a number of successes and indeed even today there are some problems with
if you want to solve those problems an expert system is going to be the
best way to go
but in most applications the
technical expert system suffers from this combinatorial explosion of lots of rules there are exceptions
to the rules exceptions to exceptions and so on and so by and large expert
systems failed to deliver on the on the vision
so can first generation as handcrafted rules everything is built out of rules extracted from
human maybe probabilistic rules but the all hand crafted
so so-called second generation is characterized by things like neural networks support vector machines he
proved to be much more successful in terms of applications so his example handwriting recognition
and there are thousands of other applications now all of these techniques
and again even today they remain extremely valuable from a practical perspective
one of the difficulties though is that incorporating article complex domain knowledge is going give
you examples of this
as we go through
OK have tried second generation as black box statistical models the emphasis is very much
is on learning from data any prior knowledge is built in is is a rather
general nature like continuity or maybe some translation invariance or something it's hard to build
this is rich domain knowledge
so i think i'm very excited about what i'm going to call third-generation machine intelligence
that characterized by
deep integration of rich domain knowledge combined with statistical learning
that's really the sort of theme of this this first talk
so there are three
ingredients to this framework first is that it's based on a bayesian approach the second
is that it makes use of probabilistic graphical models in order to describe the the
the the approach to the problem the modelling of the problem and it makes use
of fast inference techniques which are based on passing local messages around these graphs in
order to find tractable solutions and in a way which which is very efficient and
scale to very large datasets
although called generation these ideas have their origins going back a very long way in
all sorts of fields like to school
physics and electrical engineering signal processing and so on so these sort of generations of
it in a sense up in parallel with this i think is for me one
of the sort of it's very exciting frontiers of machine learning right now
OK let's just begin then with talking a little bit about those three things in
turn i'm just going to skim lightly over these topics and you'll be familiar with
some of them perhaps others less so
but later talks will drill down into more detail i want to give you a
flavour for these different topics and hopefully sort of motivate you to to be excited
about them into
sorry about this
the material is that
it has to do with the web page analysis text categorisation position filtering and structuring
of factual information and all this connects also with the stronger for natural language processing
which is a separate area of
information processing and this is a prerequisite for successful text and web mining
visualization we've seen see some ways of visualizing the data as well as visualizing the
discovered knowledge
and of course machine learning that's where our research
is mainly in
and this as i explained before is an expression coming from artificial intelligence and we
are also very interested here in the relation of machine learning with statistics
if time allows i would have some slides on that relation later on
there is obviously a very strong connection between machine learning data mining and statistics so
all you have to do with inductive techniques for data analysis so you have data
start from the data and then you induce knowledge out of the data
so in this is induction
goes from
reasoning from proper properties of data or individuals to properties which hold on the population
of individuals so some people could say well
why do we need data mining and knowledge discovery in databases isn't this just statistics
and some good marketing around it we would say well it has much has been
done in machine learning separately from statistics you can see the representation formalisms for tuesday
data is
a much different also sometimes the emphasis is different
and if we were the very roughly some up
we went
possibly say that statistics is particularly appropriate for hypothesis testing and data analysis with certain
theoretical expectations about data distribution independent random sampling and so on are satisfied so there
is a strong machinery and artillery about what data should be like that we can
then use reasonable statistical
these rules which hold on for a population obviously you should start with this
for sufficiently large
data sample if the sample is not large enough statisticians will not touch the data
at all and i would say we can't do anything which has strong reasons of
well machine learning people are much more
occasionally we start with very few data and we dare to say something what is
hidden in the data now this is particularly interesting with microarray data analysis analysis in
bioinformatics were getting the samples is extremely expensive and there's a laborious process
before another sample is obtained and it turns out that actually he even with not
that many data available you can
induce some interesting piece of knowledge which can be of use for scientific purposes so
with machine learning we
there occasionally to induce some knowledge of the less data
our main aim is to
induce knowledge in the form which is understandable to humans and that's one of the
strong points of machine learning and data mining
what is the relation between the expressions data mining and knowledge discovery in databases
data mining
similar is machine learning is aimed at finding patterns revealing hidden regularities and relationships in
the data whereas knowledge discovery in databases is viewed as the process
which includes also
data cleaning selecting the
the data for the the and it includes the entire process of data analysis including
the statisticians sort of hypothesis selection and we view data mining is one of the
key elements in this process
if we
illustrate this process
graph most this is from third-party libraries
i do some when programming values for the winter two API which the graphics stuff
others across from ones like open GL you can do x system i think magazine
called carbon
i might be wrong about that
OK carbon
there's a lot to ensure you won't have trouble finding it just you want have
and whatever that does it for you shop around this and take a look
the ones we give you a pretty nice i'd like to tell you how they
work cetera i actually don't know because it's really really really hard so go take
a look around and you find the ones that are quite nice
now have to this point are simple things like how to read input how to
convert a string things that you know what the nice weather important not going to
make a break your program
the thing is really going to make a difference
is a
the vector the set the map this tactic you those are important
if you don't have map the number of things you can do in the program
kind of just drop exponentially it's really impressive how much you need data structures
the good news is that c plus plus not only has very good support for
these data structures that has probably the best library in any standard programming language that
does these things for you
it's something called the standard template library which is the here
now for every single container class you have seen in this class of eighty two
you will find many STL the name might be a little different syntax is that
we are but conceptually it's the same thing vector the vector no matter what language
write map is a map stack is still alive though he was still five etcetera
the on top of that gives you these things called algorithms i'll show all how
talk about this and all that
basically the best thing since sliced bread
i'm not kidding it's really wonderful is really amazing and talk about that a little
but the scale is one of the major features of the c plus plus library
it's brilliantly designed it's very meaning it's not so the most intuitive thing once you
get a handle on it's very powerful
but we can kind of visualizing this looks like it's kind of like this
somewhat human this structure
at the very bottom of the container
the data structures is your vector maps your set
iterators on top of that now you've all seen iterators in this class you've seen
map iterators fifteen set iterators
yes you know is basically all the iterators every single content class has interesting iterate
over vector generator mapping iterate over sets
and those working to build this thing called algorithms which are going to talk to
you later where the functions that operate on ranges of data
and it's really impressive what you can do with these things will show a little
bit of that later
and these contain classes of the good news is the names are pretty similar basically
take the one i six version make it case you've got your FTL so big
vector turns into little vector big into little map et cetera
the one exception is grid there is no grid class it's very easy to make
one i have to do is just take it back to induce the matter as
a two dimensional container in one dimensional one
the back that's how are great work so you have to go that one but
otherwise everything carefully and quite nice
again they have the same fundamental abstractions you know how to work with the fact
that you know how to use scale factor with the lectures syntax
the big thing i will say up front the emphasis in the STL is on
speed in fact they are designed to be really really fast and that means that
there are notion of safety are good one good one so what this means is
that you have to derive bounds checking
when iterating you have to make sure you don't want fit your container
and stuff like that
and one of the major reasons we didn't go over the st on the classes
that very it's just that which is if you're trying to figure out how to
work with vector it was really bad if you also have to worry about doing
found striking if you're working the map and you have to use the st map
you probably will never want to use another map for the rest of your life
it's pretty complicated
but the point is that this is what you'll see in a professional environment because
it's a very good library in very
i want to give you a quick example of what this might look like
so this is a program written using the CS one is expected to undergo changes
you have failed to show you it's the same thing with the will of the
difference in fact
the first thing to do is say well respected at age we gave you you
have to change that the standard vector
which is a vector in brackets
OK let's see number characters we changed over three characters
next thing the big vector becomes vector OK
four characters
the only really big differences this as a function of everyone to guess who is
in in my class
what you call the function to append something to the end of the vector
or take a guess
that would be nice it's actually called back
there is actually good reason for this means that all these different cannot have similar
function name
pushback and potato
OK anyway so that's probably about ten or eleven character changes
and to live over the thing is exactly what you've seen before
there is a side function there are bracketing go into a gun access things
the result is that you can see it's not that different
i mean there are couple subtleties that i didn't going to hear about how the
vector in the still behave differently from the vector you've seen but overall it is
the same content
the other one i want to call your attention to the film and so if
you work with the st all you need to know to containers and the rest
of all of you know that no map
you've got the whole thing down
yes your map is like our map itself instead of going string to some value
it's any key types you want to any value type one
so you can match strings to ends you can have in the strings you can
map stack of q of and two vector of double
i don't know why you would you had the ability to do so
the problem is that the interface on map was probably designed by someone who didn't
like people it's really hard to use on anyone who you will tell you that
what's the hang of it though it's pretty intuitive and the result is you have
a very fast container that rules can make it back any program you right it's
quite useful
so again i don't expect you to memorize every single bit of syntax here everything
i'm saying this has given back your mind is what you want to look into
the matters when you do need to know so could take a look at that
one pursue c plus plus
now iterators
so the interiors seen in this class are very nice very well behaved like warm
and fuzzy like oh you know has next
next hasnext next no no has and
i still generators are designed to look like pointers
now you might wonder why anyone voluntarily make something look like appointed the very good
reason what this means is that there are about is smart pointer which means they
know nothing
so if you want to iterate over range had have two different narrators states start
stop there people looking forward to you get
and admittedly
well it's more work but it's very useful because it means that if you want
to iterate over a twenty elements slice out of four hundred million on the container
you can do that try to another library if you have to go into all
the way to start
they keep iterating
the other thing you need to know about the iterators to the read right
so you can actually crawl over container and i think the values with the iterator
so you can do in our library
it's a bit more work the syntax basically looks like point reading and writing the
result is that there are much more powerful and a lot more flexible
so here's a quick example
i just wrote some code you user factor the thing take a look at this
right here
so basically there's a couple parts to point out i just want to show you
this you see this later on located get in everything
the first thing is that this big in function
we call into writer they call it began to get me started writer
we need to introduce fine range we keep going to look at the called and
which means stop
meera forward you know hasnext next nights with plus plus
and then to read from a narrator right to it it the reference