however here here's the problem
individuals do not consciously maximize anything
anybody who associates consciousness conscious behavior with brain behavior is making very dense state
consciousness is very small icebergs it
of the brain and behavior most decision making by humans is not very consciously to
me i can't
this may well unconscious
on maximizing is something done by council of maximise some
completely obvious i still hear sociologist saying that people don't maximum when you choose to
he maximize
what maximizing
you know to consciously to maximize
individual choices need not be welfare enhancing people often do things that hurt them
there's nothing that says trends preferences as to maximize your lifespan
lead to personal happiness or something like that it may or may not
also these are more technical point preferences are function of the current state
so if you look at the traditional rational actor model
it doesn't have the current state status quo
one thing continent to first get out taught us
you must but the current state of the organism
if you to explain behavior is behavior is always the differential movement from the present
to another state
i believe beliefs
economists beliefs as individual properties like preferences you know i like asparagus you know it
i believe in the big mind you believe the big problem
OK we don't care
however to do game theory
and to coordinate behavior in aligned group of agents
individual beliefs have to be coordinated
the content of different lines have to be similar
individual beliefs
are part of the net social network of interdependent beliefs one things human heart
humans have very
very weird if you study
you behaviour primates like tomasello paul van allen et al work with
learning in
chimpanzees baboons et cetera
they don't they don't have a theory of mind way we may different approach
the notion of symmetric reasoning if i'm thinking something
and i know that you thinking that same thing
i can infer what you believe from what i believe or from your actions
this is very important and it must be added certainly game theory and rational actor
model to get anything like
model of human behavior
well i've already talked about game theory
the game theory
from across evolutionary game theory and time for complex systems i mentioned
but i guess and because you have to quote
dead time this is great
social life comes from the double source the likeness of consciousness is
and the division of labor
the beauty of
that's more
is not
division of labour
cemented together
that's theory social workers and by the way i only been talking about social work
i'm not talking about social disorder that
the disequilibrium fly
you know the the next step
and he recognised the division of labour supported by the like this consciousness
economists have worked on the division of labor
don't mention the like this country
no theory of y two lines would have the same content
and then you get the great economics
statement there's no such thing as society here only in the there are individual men
and women
because she throws and their families
so i was i was just asked to do something that i was trying to
do anyway to put into context where we are and to motivate where we came
from and maybe to repeat little bit what we did at the end yesterday chose
to say
we should interrupted any time i'm not sure if it is the first time i
didn't happen but please
you do if you want to discuss anything please do
i got some of the questions
was a question
you can't hear me
the cat idaho michigan and
i don't know why it works for the other speakers and not for
most of my life
i put it up
she tried
why is that
very large
a belong
OK i'll try to speak a bit louder and that doesn't work then i'll hold
here so so you just give me signal don't worry i've i've always had this
problem in lot of my i remember when i was a student phd advisor threatened
that he would me micron like that for the group meetings
events OK
so i also got a couple of questions yesterday
that might be able to address during the talk today
and so
let's see somewhere where do we come from we started with well we started that
last part of the talk with the definition of a positive definite kernels and in
a way we could have started the whole
actually that we could have just dropped all this stuff about what we think a
similarity measure studied informally with the similarity measure we could just say OK this is
a similarity measure and that's what we consider similarity measures
a positive definite kernel function which means a function of two arguments which is symmetric
and which has this property that if we compute the gram matrix by substituting all
pairs of training examples in this ground matrix will be positive definite
which means that this equality holds true
so we could have something like that and then we show to certain properties for
these kinds of kernels and we showed how to construct the feature space and as
such nice i would like to do that because a lot of people work with
support vector machines and kernels take it for granted and i think it's something magic
this feature space and you need some complicated theorems in functional analysis but in fact
it's quite elementary we're done
all the steps basically together how to construct this feature space so
i think if only if if it's only four losing your respect and feeling more
comfortable with it then that's already
the purpose for doing this construction so so let's quickly think about this again so
are the idea was we take
so we want to map our input points which come from some set into a
function space so this is space of functions mapping that's it into real numbers so
we have we start with points let's say is o input space you points here
are functions on that space each point is mapped into a function
and the point will be mapped into the function that we get if we substitute
point into one of the arguments of the kernel function and we keep the other
argument so this is the a function of that first opened argument
so that's our representations and
note that actually in this case it could well be an infinite dimensional space function
spaces of infinite dimensional
is the space of all continuous functions on the interval is infinite dimensional so we
map of points into this very high dimensional space
with is nonlinear mapping
and now we have to construct a dot product in that space to construct the
product we first have to turn it into a vector space we do that in
the trivial way we just by claiming that linear combinations of such points are also
space so we just to the linear completion of the space within construct dot product
and we want the dot product to satisfy
when zero press has a given information on one of another defamation
and if we compare theory c
so this is experiments this is very
we see that the first here
these simulated to
this one
is well reproduced
and this one you see
we can say that it's quite axial vibration
so that's why it's very important to make progress posted description
of nuclear structure and making new experiments
when we consider that it's oblate and prolate it's move the weight function so these
are the weight function for the first time
so zero plus two plus four to six ago then here
so a
if you've got this is the probability of present so consider this line
we present pool at the slack overlay
so here is located
and here you have stayed overlay
that's one way to identify in their only top quality
in the media it's try access to pre-ex then is the degree of freedom
that allows us to go continuously from april eight two
so now i'm going to talk about a new structure
as we have in this exotic nuclei a lot of neutron excess
do we expect new things so
this is an example that presented last time concerning the term given by then you
the sand which have been discovered so
the radius of this guy is very huge and that's been interpreted as kind meetings
so how means you have the car here of the night
and you have two external neutron
it was very huge special extension
one spending with this is that it's like goldman system so means history but since
then you really need these three bodies with body forces
to have something but if you take away one of the elements so it's no
more about
for example you need to ten is not
so there are now local search
other so not only these light nuclei but also made as nuclear
or to look at the present time and for example
something also
any it's serious is these impact factors are more than calculations
so these are the results of calculations with these models so this has been done
in oxygen sixteen
to obtain m forty six
and you can see here
these are alpha particles
so i'm particles out they rearrange themselves to have these structure exact another structure so
these shapes are predicted
so i'm cluster is predicted by theory
so that means that
in some you know you shouldn't you don't have
proton neutron but you have some structure and for structure inside this
this is a very famous
it that picture from the contest and so you amassed member excitation energy
so first that are different configurations which are predicted
here magnesium flares and fun
oxygen first three and five
and here only outside
the same for magnesium they also can
so this has been predicted by different approaches
what about experiments so there some experiments are performed for example this is an experiment
beryllium ten
from that these people so these are
citation energy
and what you see here
that you have some state
which looked like a really really passionate about and so
this behavior spacing that
the spacing between the labels looks like fashion brands
and in fact if you compare this speculation is associated to the shape
where you have two fires and two neutrons something very well different
this is and the most famous examples in the old state with
in the past only was i think
that it should exist as you have stated that seventy and leaving you was looking
at the amount of carbon in the cosmos and he said because of
i capture had you get it should be you should have stayed here
gallant twenty so these that has been discovered rather good energy
and you can not reproduce the states if you consider usual shell model calculations with
three particle proton and neutron
the only way
you have to represent states to consider and outside clusters
so this date is considered as three and five cluster here
and even more of considered and was also the can even at the same states
so this is
the way we describe things
zero placed second of the states
people are
looking at these new structure and now they are not only looking at the scene
elements is the number
of nucleons proportional to alpha particles
but also the predicted that you can have different first and different neutron configurations
so that's why this
if you the minimax optimal universal code
so now i can find a fine MDL
at least
one version for model selection and that worked well we just have to model
and one and two
so think about this for example is the first order and second order markov model
for data
now according to this modern version of MDL if you want to select between those
two models for the same data
you should take
the model for which the associated optimal universal model so that's the normalized maximum likelihood
model assigns the largest probability to the data
or equivalently you pick the model which gives the smallest coupling to the data
if you use the minimax optimal universal code relative to the model
i only did this for models but
exactly the same thing can be done for infinite models in a moment we'll see
how and then it becomes actually practically useful
o thing to do
let's look at this
again so we have two models we select the one which minimizes
the code length according to these universal called
if we recall that this is the fraction
of the probability according to the maximum likelihood divided by the sum of over all
sequences of the probability according to the next like for that sequence
so the mines like fraction is equal to minus log of the numerator plus lack
of the denominator
so we select the model from which this summer smallest
and you can think of this as the trade which is familiar in other model
selection methods
like AIC and BIC trade-off between goodness of fit
and complexity
so if the best fitting distribution in your model fits the data better than this
will be larger so minus local this will be small
on the other hand if the complexity of your model
is larger complexity here means that can fit more patterns well
that's as we will see roughly corresponds to how many parameters to model has
and this term will get larger so this term the richard model is the more
data patterns that can fit in there for the more risk of overfitting
the largest this term will be
so hard large this term for finite models well
we've already seen if you ever find models and elements
this term must be bounded by the log of the number of elements because you've
already seen it can always called the data with the two part code
where the overhead for each
is log
right space simply encoding
the index
of the maximum likelihood distribution theta had
by a uniform called which takes look and bits
here we have the same overhead for every particular sequence because we know there's a
code of overhead mark this particular over it must be smaller than log on the
model how much smaller
so the question is of course doesn't make any sense nor is using the normalized
maximum likelihood distribution to compare models
and to try to convince you that it does
i'll give four interpretations of it
and actually the first interpretation i already gave
basically what you do is if you believe as an axiom the MDL idea that
it's good
to select the model which allows for the shortest
code length of the data
then i already have a i mean but then you have to believe that but
if you believe that there is a clear motivation already because what we do here
is exactly that select the model which allows to for the most compression of the
and to formalize the idea we associate each model set of distributions with the coat
and we do that in such a way that all distributions within the model are
treated on an equal footing
of course we can
associate a code to encode data for the model in an arbitrary way what we
did it in a way
the city overhead we have we have two whatever distribution in the model
is a good code for the data is as small as possible
and note and this makes it really different from any other approach to machine learning
and statistics that i know of
this done in worst-case setting not case over distributions that might generate data but worst
case over data
so it's really important to realize that i haven't talked for one
second about things which generate data i have taken no expectations they don't exist here
we use distributions only
encode data
and not something from which data might come here
and we then look at how good these distributions are in the worst case overall
data sequences so we make no assumptions about the data comes from at all
at least when defining our model later we were defining our methods
later we're going to prove that the method works well in some cases then will
make such assumptions but for now we have made those assumptions at all
we want to use codes which work well no matter what data we get
so now the the second interpretation
has something to do with this complexity term
and it turns out you can give that kind of counting geometric interpretation
it turns out you can think of this as something like total fit your model
assigns to the data
equivalent either lock not of the number of elements in your model
the model is finite it would be this before ready it's more equal than a
lot of the number of elements
but something like the effective number of distributions so what is that
if i look now there's a lot of this
complexity term but the term itself
i can rewrite it the sum in two separate terrorist can take the sum over
all theta as
in my model and the sum over all data from which that particular seat
fits the data best
the probability of the data according to see this and this is simply the same
so i partition the set of all sequences into those sequences which have the same
maximum likelihood estimator
so now i can rewrite this of course is the sum over all theta my
model of the probability
according to see to that i get a sequence for which
peter is actually the maximum likelihood estimator
and this is of course the sum of all theta of one minus the probability
that i get
a sequence for which he is not the maximum likelihood estimator
according to peter
so this is the probability according to see to the data look as if they
do not come from theta
i think of very simple model that's a bernoulli model with just four
elements the probability of one zero point twos are point fours or point six point
if the frequency of one is approximately zero point four
you look at the terminus some with zero point two this is the probability that
you get
some sequence for example with the frequency of zero point four or even larger such
that the theta had is not equal to zero point two
this you can pull this one out of the sum and if this is the
final this is simply the number of distributions and you get strictly negative terms
which you might call the amount of confusion in your model
so this is the probability
according to see to that the maximum likelihood estimator is not the time the probability
according to see that you get an atypical
sequence with that which doesn't look like sums over all theta
here here here here
we are really
we had our
observation of
now what
in this case
now the right now
in the
the you
and here
all right
it was longer
the rest of the
you are
it be
o nine
a lot of
is it
because they
you are
which is
it is not
and what happens to the well known shell structure
but we know very well in the stable nuclei what happens when we move away
from the stable nucleus
concerning the limit of existence you have here is an important member neutron number
what we are looking at for example you consider given
given the number of full-time fifteen for example and then you add neutral neutral neutral
neutral and then
you can no more and one neutron the system is no more about some of
these neutron is no more about
so it means that the limit of existence it that point
so when you have all these points for all the value and for all n
you can define this new mode of existence what a neutral what we call the
so this has been defined by with the different
what are the main features of these three lines are the fact that
this report only playing here is not so far from stability
so that's why we can reach now
so far
a small number of nuclei we can reach these three planes farm
for the in the proton rich side so that we can we can show the
these three plants is very far away
from the stability this neutron drip line
so that's why when we talk about exotic nuclei we talk about neutron rich nuclei
and neutron rich nuclei if really neutron rich you can
mimic what happens in the neutron stars so
that's why we are mostly interested in neutral matter
it's really a challenge to locate these drip lines from an experimental point of view
it's to challenge because the
counting rate and prediction is very low so it's very difficult concerning theory
what i want to show you that you need a very big accuracy
when you look at the by means you have to to consider infinity on this
bound of not so you have to calculate the what we call s and what
i presented yesterday
neutron separation energy this neutron separation energy the energy that you need to put into
the system
take away one nucleon so it's the difference between the mass
four so many energy of the system
minus the binding energy of the daughter system
so you need to know very precisely
the masses of the constituent so you need to have
the population valid for all the different isotopes and i suppose
and a few calculations have been performed to check the validity of the present approaches
concerning the mass predictions
so this is the well known d one s force that has been used since
the nineteen eighties and it has been fitted into that into only a few nuclei
that we're well known at that time these stable magic nuclei
but since then many many new nuclei have been discovered experimentally so that's why people
have tried to do OK what are the prediction problem as all these
for these four what is plotted here is the difference between theoretical and experimental
binding energy for the different nuclei depending on n so the number of neutrons
so you have having color different isotopes chance
and you see that you have average zero but you have some brief here today
so for example for these chain here
so this is an act and i you can have a to ten amy
maybe it's not so much if you consider the binding energy which is two thousand
two thousand amy
so it's o point five per cent
so it's not so bad but when you calculate the
it's and so the separation energy
you need to do be difference between this point and this point here
and this is to a
so that's it's really bad to calculate
the limit of existence of these nuclei
so that's why you can not know more
of calculation like that
so people have tried to react just
with these force here the one m
m four masses
in order to better reproduce the results
so first they have tried
to be better with these three so they have something flat here
so it's better now to get this in
progress has been made recently
in order to introduce more correlation and having something
almost flat here
the root mean square west three MTV for the initial for you when is sort
of three in a b and now it's less than eight hundred kv
so it's better
be careful for these nucleosome person for astrophysical calculations are really need very precise
values for the masses what they would like
it would be something with
and accuracy on the order of tens of kv
so we are off by one order of magnitude
so that's why in astrophysics
cold calculation they used evaluated data or database and experiment
but then we try to
to make progress in order to to to give them some
microscopic calculations that are needed for these processes
so i think that in a few years a lot of progress will be made
in that direction in order to really improve
the calculations and the first
but it's indirect so you
we prove the first but then you don't
feet the experimental data directly you do all your complicated calculation and then you have
an expectation value which is the mass
and then you feel that
so it's difficult to re-educate these parameters
and we try also to derive that first from first principles in order not to
have so many parameters
so what about new magic numbers in exotic nuclei
so i told you yesterday that there is something that we well know
are these magic numbers so these magic numbers that are due to che to gaps
in the single particle levels here
and we know that these nuclei are especially stable
but what about this magic nuclei
when you move away away from the stability when you're dealing with exotic nuclei and
this is really a current issue that is study here for example
as did in many other laboratories
this is the the region that is of interest nowadays and it was twenty eight
so this should be magic numbers and this is the magic number
very important so here's some just some examples from
perspective or relative estimation sizes so most of you will think the table longer than
this one
and the this monster is smaller than the than the one behind it whereas in
fact if you just rotate the image you see the effect types exactly the same
size and what's this exactly the same size so what's happening is you've seen your
eyes taking in the whole scene interpreting it and then giving us size judgement based
on that based on the links the table things like this all the
the size the place in in the corridor for monsters and that judgement is completely
but it's also very useful
because it tends to real seems to give you the right the right and the
right judgement even though visually in terms of the actual vision it's wrong
OK if you just a few final points on human object recognition so there's a
thing called pop out if you see a real object on basically that background if
you see
horizontal age
basically i feel the vertical niches things pop out immediately you don't need to do
any visual search they appear immediately you're i can count immediately to the right place
so you able to process that followed out very quickly and secondly you can recognise
objects well if you happen to have been trained a lot and that human faces
case in point humans are very good at setting human faces
we're actually getting quite good at it faces as well in terms of computer vision
and humans are also very good at recognizing family faces which were not quite so
good at yet
just this just because there's have a lot of experience with faces standing faces for
a very early age
for other kinds of objects which are not kind of expert objects which is not
about it seems that you have to do some kind of process analogous to aligning
the object was some kind of reference image sure templated you have
the that object class
and the alignment for example gets slower if you have to move the thing for
them and if you recognition gets slower
look all kinds of psychophysics experiments on these kinds of things so it seems that
humans do use representations which are probably mainly to d
mainly kind of template based for the object recognition
these very difficult experiments to do so nothing is certain but that seems to be
what the current experiments show
OK just a few things on the visual
one is asian individual
so i optical nerve goes back to the natural genetic nucleus which is a small
kind of switch box in the center of your brain and it gets mapped onto
the visual cortex v one region we start doing visual processing left and right halves
of the size of both eyes separated and move to the right and left half
the one and the stereo processing happens
in and the one region mainly
the LGN
what is actually a single blow but he returns to
does a lot of contrast normalisation and things like that as well kind of roots
things it helps contrast normalizes does all sorts of strange things but not
things that you count as being very high-level processing just kind of a regulator box
in the center
so i said
these two things then you go through what called the one simple cells which basically
linear filters
and through the one complex cells
which are kind of
there's the rectification states of this kind like an energy or half wave rectification going
followed by some kind of integration
responses over local region which is what the the one complex cells to each stage
of this process the strong game controllers natural division from nearby cells and other things
that are going on
the reason is already dance image enhancement is sorted out of course a lot of
for camera what will be attitude control control of the united states and things
audience signal routing some kind of contrast control and support cells are multiscale decomposition
complex cells disintegration of that
so let's just see some examples of this
so response and the origins a center surround the response
the center
some signal coming in in in
the signals around the suppressed things so that the matter
natural brain with that kind of response
a single cell and all
so you can see that these kinds responses simple cells
basically by filters or each filters various different types and complex cells integrate normalized responses
a number of different simple cells so they tend have rather lot like
regions with negative and positive
one thing the simple cells you can actually model and pretty well with what are
called global fields filters so will come back to that later but basically complex exponentials
of gaussians so nice to wave waves type things you can model the fitting nowhere
so we models of these things listed that level but it's not doesn't take is
very far
some statistics of tuning distributions may be is not important but basically this is a
o bandwidth so
of the cells the spread over angular special
the figures you typically have them with the one half octaves and angular bandwidth about
forty degrees and that means you can build a model these cells may be used
for vision later if you
a nice model makes use signal independent
you get numbers which are very much like human numbers
OK so it seems that there no the
the figures are coherent with nature in some sense
so i said that this energy model something important to know if you look into
for example neural types of treatments of vision simple cells get halfway rectified in then
integrated into a complex cell
walter lewin
in its own direction of increasing x
if i call this point
eight x equals zero
and i call this point b x equals x
and i can calculate the work that i have to do to bring it from
a to b
walter lewin has to do
bring it from a to b
if the integrals
in going from a to b
one of my force
the x to dot product
but since the angle between the two
zero degrees the cosine of the angle
is one so i can forget about the fact that is the dot product i
moved in this direction
so that becomes the integral in going from zero
two a position x
plus x
plus kx
the x and that is one half
x quick
and this is what we call the potential energy
this is potential and it means that we
x equals zero
we define potential energy to be zero you don't have to do that but it
would be ridiculous to do it any other way
so in the case that we have
the new or situation of gravity
we had a choice where we put our zero
potential energy
in case that we deal with very large distances
we do not have the choice anymore
we defined it in such a way
that the potential energy at infinity is zero
as a result of that
all the potential entities
and negative
and here was the spring
you don't have a choice either you choose
x equals zero
you choose potential energy to be zero
so if you know
make a plot
of the potential energy as a function of x
you get the parabola
and if you are here
if the object is here
and the force is always in the direction
opposing increasing
potential energy if you go this way potential energy increases
so it's clear
that the force
it's going to be
in this direction
if you're here
the force is always in the direction opposing increasing potential energy
increase in potential energy is in this direction
so the force is in this election see restoring force
always in the direction opposite to increasing
potential energy
if you release an object here at zero speed it will therefore go
so it's lower potential energy force
will drive it to lower potential energy
if we know the force
in this case the spring force
or in those cases the gravitational force we were able to calculate the potential energy
now the question is can we also go back
we knew the potential energy can we don't find
the force again and the answer is
yes we can
let's take the situation of the spring first
we have that the
potential energy u
of the spring
equals plus
one half k
x squared
and if i take the derivative
well that was x
then i get
plus kx
but the force
the spring force itself is minus kx
so this equals minus
the spring force
so we have that
was minus f and i put px there
because it's the one dimensional problem
it is only in the
the minus sign
he's telling you
that the force is always pointing
in the direction which is opposite
two increasing values of the potential energy
that is what the minus sign is that which darren you in the face what
i've been telling you for the past five minutes
we have a three-dimensional situation that we know the potential energy
as a function of x y and z
then we can
go back and find the forces as a function of x y and zee doesn't
matter where these are spring to what is gravity or but the electric forces or
nuclear forces
you then find
the UTX
it was miners
f of x
the UT y
because minus
and the UTC
people minus
after what does this mean
it means
that if you're in three-dimensional space
if you move only in the x direction you keep
y and z constant
example positive if it's positive example negative if it's a negative example and so then
you can as usual apply the the trick for evaluating a test point in which
you have some alpha rhi kappa X I X where the alpha rhies are these counts
now one nice property of this algorithm is we're starting to see sparsity because
one of the perceptron convergence algorithm bounds the number of updates in terms of the
margin in fact it's R squared over gamma squared where gamma is the margin of the of
the best classifier on the training data and so that means that if you
have a reasonable margin you won't have made very many updates and you'll have made significantly
fewer updates than there are training examples and if you haven't updated on a training
example than its alpha rhi is still zero because it's never got incremented beyond zero
so when you're evaluating you actually only need to actually evaluate the inner product so
those guys that you've actually updated on so in a way it's a little counterintuitive that your
classification depends on the tough examples and not on the easy examples you'd expect the
kind of easy examples to be nice sort of ones that show you the right way
but actually you're using the ones that cost you grief in the training phase as
to guide your classification of a test example but this is means that this is
actually a very efficient evaluation and as I said this was actually published in nineteen sixty four by
Aizerman et al in the USSR despite actually a bound that you can prove on
the performance of this thing which is very tight it does tend to overfit a bit
and they abandoned this method and didn't pursue it um but I would contend that if
you actually replace the update rule by this margin version which is a bit
more aggressive it updates more readily in other words the problem with this previous
thing is that when it finishes some of the training data could be only just
correctly classified you know they as soon as it gets this classification right it stops
no point in doing anymore it's sort of super lazy and that sort of leaves the
the decision boundary potentially quite close to training data and that can lead to some poor
performance but if you add in this parameter tau and which is set bigger
than zero then it's being a bit more aggressive and it's saying no I'm not happy
just to be correctly classified I wanna get a bit of a margin and for instance you
can just set tau equals one and you're guaranteed to get half of the optimal margin so
it's a very easy optimization to do and I would contend it's pretty competitive
with the support vector machine there's not much between this and sort vector machines so
sort of nice to think that you are one parameter away from a from a kernel classification
algorithm able to generalize in high-dimensions in nineteen sixty four but okay I'm using site historical fact
okay so let's move to support vector machines so what what are we trying
to do in support vector machines it's the usual thing we're really familiar now is just
a linear function in a kernel defined feature space
the only difference is that we're going to optimize relative to a slightly different performance
measure and the measure that we're gonna optimize is this idea of a
margin on the training data and the reason that that is chosen is there's a bound
that shows you that the margin translates into good performance on test data so
it's the same idea as the the ridge regression where we would keep in control of
the weight vector in some sense the margin keeps control of the complexity and in
a very explicit sense actually you can see it is reducing the norm of the weight vector so
it's a very explicit link there but I will just mention this is is you
identify super exponential faster exponential growth of prize which are characteristic of this positive feedback
the best textbook example that i always had to my students to explain this positive
feedback either behaviour of human population in the last two
thousand years
where the log of the population now one
billion seven billion people here of two hundred two thousand years
should be
exponential these matters was right
the constant
the rate of growth you should have constant slope here
what you see is this super exponential acceleration were constantly the rate of growth of
the population has increased and we understand why the carrying capacity of the earth has
increased by positive feedback of human populations
in captivity
expression of new niches
industrial revolution agricultural revolution and so forth pushing this in accidentally whether the positive feedback
in finance many
i don't have time to go through
the behaviour of very important imitation
it is a fundamental aspect i believe of markets it is actually not the stupid
that often using cartoons
it is about actually
being rational to imitate because we don't know everything and when is that if a
look in the
and i was not preparing you you would all major to look at the floor
it might be danger it is rational to imitate the thing we learn it is
put in the software artificially intelligent
there are even actually even journal of finance the show that
hedge funds mutual funds immediately show their are geographic and so on and so forth
so this gives rise when you take all this into account positive feedback by imitation
by many of the processes
in pp core level behaviour
and that's very important about doesn't come out of the blue comes when something rather
positive emerges out of the preceding phase which was small
it's a mistake to say so there is a good sign always start nuclear with
new outlook maybe some displacement of technology like the ITC bubble or like the real
estate bubble in eighteen forty in the in the UK
and then you have pretty creation before you can state and evolution
and when you collect data you see these really commonality when you collect these these
i would say a butterfly these bubbles
that led to the crash using this characteristic has resurgence of this super express tracks
which we can model
brother precisely just want to mention that we can also play with
george erasmus student here in the room with agent based model that takes into account
imitation learning process and you find a that is just wide new white noise news
can create crashes
here i want to advertise the presentation by
one of my students visiting chinese leader in
well on wednesdays going actually to explain much more the technicalities of the type of
techniques that we use to identify bubbles in particle of these very interesting innovations
which is the
first methodology that we have
found which may consist in the evolution of the price itself rather than return that's
open to the public questions how do is is to make the most prize which
is not stationary
the big problems in econometric estimation versus the return but that's
so what know which cover now having said that i'm using this technology
and i'm just showing my textbook example of a series of about of crashes the
of the price on carbon which is the free market
the full of time
you have an average exponential growth but the market is always
bubbling below port accelerating crashing accelerating pressure activating crushing accelerating in the super exponential with
the row growth rate of the price is growing itself as a function of time
and then it's not just neighbouring crashes and the systematic precocious of this event as
very clearly are very clear
with distorted we can go back to
the story and the show indeed the first evidence of about when for example the
intense stop with were multiplied by a factor
fourteen as opposed to the non intense stock just move be within the range of
ten percent
i mean that is the scarcity
so that automatically new at this super exponential acceleration and that the value huge capital
inflow in the US poor in actually to buy the internet technology has been documented
like emerging market
that is young nineteen ninety four nineteen ninety seven this is you as being actually
floated by cash to force the market
the response of the fed was these growth of the money minor money supply
very interestingly
city with the money money supply growth and decay of the
fed interest rate which begin became negative just in the aftermath of the crash of
these ideas about what you see in real meaning you adjust for inflation
if you think about it a real rate which is negative so you you just
want to spend that's what happened before
and this occurred at the time when the estimation productivity with the highest
and the economy there will be the you that this is a recipe for disaster
there's one productivity is accelerating this when you actually we should increase interest rate two
slow down with the engine that exactly the opposite what was done by my great
and what happened this is the data where you can actually see
contrary to the market we acting
the set policing
we show that the policy was actually lagging behind the
successive drafts of the market what was showing here is nasdaq index SP five hundred
index from the time in the aftermath of the
crash and then the subsequent two years of dismal performance of the market and direction
of the fed here
in the red showing how flagged by two months
two months trying to somehow stop these descent on the market very interesting now the
question is can we say that this paper titles so suggests that there was a
causal slaving of the fed to market this requires much more investigation
now this of course bush
real estate bubble tremendous height
and with this technology was just telling you we were able to actually published in
advance when you're in
in advance
that the peak of the UK bubble
all the US bubble
it would be respectively in mid two thousand four on the two thousand six in
the case of the US just to impress new
that this crisis of this stick this picks may not be so much
so much and predictable or as is often claimed that clear evidence of consistent regime
region so when the human is being asked what do they think is that the
threshold they just pick up right where they've been seeing the machine present samples so
there really humanism doing in this particular case maybe there would be a better way
to construct it in the yellow situations it's more interesting information out there but really
humans just reporting where has machine been looking at x
and it's not the person is doing very much
of anything in that case there's that it's your question
the in the
that's an interesting question so
and that gets to work so the question is
if a person were yoked with a learn a better way to solve this
the issue of where is the threshold maybe people
if you haven't done this before they just kind of do some random picking of
but once they see what the machine is doing i can do this by section
maybe people start to do bisection and i guess there have two
so that's a good point and that might be right we didn't evaluate whether they
learn how to learn better by being yoked to the machine and they perform better
in future cases that's interesting and i guess we can use for cooking use summarizer
are two kinds of flavours of strategies that people tended to follow in the active
mode so
one of the strategies people do
would be to do just by bisection and then they come an error in this
estimate the asked that same question again
and for low
uncertainty that i the procedure actually works relatively well
so that was one strategy
and the other was are more gradient type of approach where they
searches to sort start off at one point in kind of explore from there and
follow their knows something like that like then this idea just doing binary search and
repeating queries in this case asking for the same egg to hatch many times until
you sure whether you think it's more probably snicker or bird is one way of
making a noise tolerant
active learning algorithm you start off with our algorithm is designed to work well without
noise present and then you just follow the same algorithm but each time you take
a sample you repeatedly query that's one approach it turns out to be suboptimal
it in terms of sample complexity those procedures are repeated querying don't work as well
as something like the BBC method this probabilistic bisection that's so this question takes any
other questions and human active learning stuff
OK so let me just go quickly snatches century when fixing so one of the
reasons people don't do very well
in the very noisy setting
you might have to do with memory because
it requires you to remember what you've seen before you to do an informed decision
if there is not much uncertainty uncertainty
just remembering what happened the night last four five x suffices but with more uncertainty
want to go
so far away into the past so that might be one reason people are also
not very wrong answer
right just to follow up on that one thing we've sort of back to your
question is maybe what people would need in certain scenarios is helpful
way of summarizing past experience graphically or some other visual way that would help them
make more informed choices
as they are learning so there could be ways to help augment human memory limitations
that are suggested by this as well so there are a lot of different directions
it might be my goal with this question
what we know that the
they have a certain number of queries i'm not sure if he even knew the
number of queries specific for each subject task was after
after you're done just give us
give give our best bet that
they they probably would
that's what i like in the twenty questions and that's what
people do like kids like playing games like OK only have
there's only a few policies on the board
what should i do try to
i guess these are just give certainty there so the other person as well as
regression so on
but in this case the number of business
six and they didn't even knew it they had to report what was there as
what we have is that the covariance between t and t j could be some
x i and x j
it could be some function of x i and x j
usually what we have is that some function
where the covariance decreases
with distance between x i and x j
so nearby points in input space tend to have similar
target value output values and far points and have uncorrelated
output values
i wish i had to wait for the end of the war
here's a summary of what the gas process actually is
so guess in process places the prior directly on the space of functions
such that
any finite selection of points x one through x and
in this input space the corresponding function values he one thirty and have a multivariate
gaussians distribution
for example these are
four samples from guassian process
where does the input space and this is the output space
these are samples from the prior
if we observe some data would say we observe these three data points these to
be samples from the posterior distribution
of this casting process
you know the the functions go through the data i have higher probability
once we observed the data and the functions they don't go through the data
so the covariance between two function values ti and tj
under this prize given by the covariance function
some function of x i and x j
which typically decays monotonically with the distance between these two
and that encodes the fact that you believe the function to be sort of smooth
but you can put all sorts of information here you can build in periodic function
is you can have a rough functions if you want get functions with different length
scales you functions with jumps in the etcetera etcetera
and you do all that by controlling this covariance function
and the covariance function is exactly
why people sometimes call the kernel function
so the kernel
is essentially
it has to satisfy certain positive definiteness constraints and those of the same constraints that
the covariance function has to satisfy
and the kernel is also
often derived in terms of the dot product in some feature space and here exactly
i define this covariance function
in terms of the dot product in feature spaces dot products some over d
of these
elements in d could actually be infinite dimensional by one two
OK so this is finite
covariance you know this is the covariance function
the comes from a finite number of basis functions but many useful covariance functions correspond
to infinitely many basis functions just like many
the kernel corresponds to a mapping into two-dimensional
feature spaces
what we want to think of this
it is if we have a kernel or covariance function and then either we could
do something like
you know
support vector regression using the kernel or we can do something like calcium process regression
well we treat that kernel as a covariance function casting process and then we get
things like error bars on all predictions we can compute marginal likelihood so we can
compare between different kernels and do model selection
etcetera etcetera
that's the regression case and i can tell you about classification but let me take
some questions
speech recognition problem which
support vector machines basically
finding the mean of the gas in process
and if i the mean of gas process and as far as i understand it
so basically
you have
essentially you don't get the sparsity
right in the quadratic support vector machines support vector regression if you do support vector
now it
the quadratic term
and then you don't get the error bars either that you get in in this
procedure so you don't have uncertainty in the values of x you don't get the
model selection procedures and so on
yeah i
i'm not sure why we would want to use those
any other questions about this
what you see here is a covariance function
which says that the covariance between x i and x j
the cases e to the minus
the norm of excitement six
OK you know minus the norm squared
so the covariance function decays with distance between science today
go for it
four modules of graphical models
now it seems like you
i mean field another type of graphical models like vision
it's just not my field will see that there there will be no
are but just connect nodes
let's start
if you remember you saw
the networks
we basically
o thing in bayesian networks
by starting from
this object which is the probability
of the five
five will be
index smaller
o thing
so there is no right
we were working on these options essentially the assumption was that we were going to
a few edges
that connect
and then we obtain the conditional independence assumption
and this also that when we should use
conditional independence assumptions of the conditional independence assumption
p as well
there are certain types of conditional independence
statements that cannot
the set five exactly what you want to do
make it a little bit more precise
state is
very very
in other words there are certain classes
all interesting probability distribution
that vision is more
appropriate appropriate
model to represent
so if you like freedom also represent clusters of
it is
so there is another class of graphical model which you come here
it is widely used in many of the party
o thing about michael feels that they
look for the specification of a different class
of conditional independence day
when compared the
so in some sense microbial invasion
not exactly those of her relationship with
class of
condition and status for light field
can be
we find easily in terms of graph we know that we know all directed edges
with undirected
and those things that formal separation in the case of the americans in this case
will become much easier
because there will be no all directions in the
edges and things
is it understand what
in same cases we had
the concept of the separation
in vision that had the concept of
in the case of the
or just think
this is exactly this case for example
a set a is separated
from the set b by the set
in this case
we simply say that
this is true if
every path that goes from here to here
passes through
one element
there's basically no from a to b
that doesn't go through c
more technically if you have an undirected graph g being a b and c disjoint
subsets of nodes
if every path from a to b includes at least one of them c
then c is said to separate a from b
in december
this is the
this case definition very simple because it is about a bold action
this definition of graphs by
the definition
in the same way as we have a definition for these words
which was much more tricky
the feature from mark
it is
in the same way as patient networks work class or but distribution that could be
prior look forward to
the graph
in the microrna is set of probability distributions
that that that basically explores what is a best way to
estimate the slope of a power-law dis distribution and how to test for
various hypothesis in like because we can have a we can have a power-low
you can have a log normal and so on so there are many different kinds of
distributions that are all heavy tailed and then you'd like to distinguish between them and this is
the paper that deals with that so if you'd like more on that topic
check out this paper okay so I can change
so this is what I want to talk about next so now we saw how
how how the networks are what I want to talk now is how do
things propagate in the network right so this will be like part two then we'll do a
break and then I'll I'll show this because I think it's very interesting and
entertaining so this is this is the outline of what I'll talk in this part right so
I want first I want to go over some basic mathematical models of wireless propagation and then
diffusion and also see what kind of algorithmic consequences do these models
give us then I want to show some empirical studies of of diffusion on large on
on large networks namely the the viral marketing how people recommend products and the
how information propagates and then show some more things so I I showed this
slide slide already right I asked the question what do we know about the
networks and in the in the in the past so in the previous before
lunch what we saw was was about the structure so now we want to know
about processes and dynamics and what you should think off is again the same slide as I
had right for example this shows how the DVD recommendations propagate right this would be people
that made a that buy a DVD and then they make recommendations and you see nobody really
follows them maybe this person followed and then made some more recommendations and I think this
is this is the propagation graph of some of some disease how it started
and how it spread and just visually the graphs have this similar structure of having these
like clouds of points so what should you think of diffusion or what is diffusion
right it's like a behavior that cascades from node to node in an epidemic
fashion okay and there are numerous examples of these for example we can have
like news opinions rumors fads that propagate through the social network we can have this
word of mouth effects in like marketing like how new websites free web based services how
do we get to know out of them right usually some friend tells us and
we are happy and we go tell we go tell this on then a also very classical example are
viruses virus propagation you have to be in with someone so if I have flu I
have to be in contact with someone else so that they get the flu right so it also
propagates over over the network then similarly you could say for like smoking
recycling so this like changes in social priorities or behavior then same for like news coverage
how the particular topic diffuses through the network I'll talk this about this more towards the end
and so on sorry
okay so this is what I want and now I want to briefly review some
of the classical studies of diffusion and it all started here in nineteen forty-three where
Ryan and Gross were studying the the spread of new agricultural practices right so they
went to Iowa and they they talked for a few years with these
like two hundred sixty farmers and in that time so I think at the end of
nineteen twenties there was a new corn seed this seed if you planted
this new corn seed instead of traditional corn seed then you would harvest much more much
more corn but the problem with this new one is that every year you have
to buy it again right so you can't save some of the seed from the previous years and
plant that seed again and get more and more corn so every year you
have to buy this new corn so there is some trade off for the farmer so
they have to buy this seed every year which is a disadvantage for them but they
could harvest more and more corn so they were studying how how this
corn adoption spread between these armers and what they found was that these
interpersonal network played the crucial role in adoption of these new hybrid corn seed so
what they basically established is that diffusion is a social process right how new new
corn seed got adopted is a is a is a social process then so
this is the first study the second study that came a bit later
was the spread of a new medical practices so here these people from
Columbia University they went and they studied adoption of a new drug between the doctors
Illinois so they they went and they talked to the doctors at that time
there was some new new antibiotic that just came out and for doctors
they they see how the adoption of this new antibiotic that was very good spread
and again they saw for example that the clinical studies and like scientific evaluations
they did not play much role in doctors like convincing doctors
to use this antibiotic but what played the role was like social power of peers for
example the one of the most important features was that people who were at the
same hospital were more likely to adopt this new behavior and so on so again it's
the it's the social network the social network that leads to adoption and not necessarily some
kind of objective studies that this antibiotic really works okay so these so these are two
most well known ones for example people also tried to study another classical study would
be the adoption of the of the Dvorzak keyboard so the querty keyboard we are
are using today is like very slow for typing right so there is this new keyboard
layout that is much better so you could think that that could also
spread virally right if you use it you you are happy with it you tell it to your friends but that doesn't
spread nobody is using that keyboard so it seems I don't know the threshold to enter to to high or
there was another study where they went to Chile and they were they went
to some village some tribe and they were trying to promote that
theladies at home should cook the water before using it and again what they
found was that they did not influence the right people at start so that the whole village
would start pre-cooking the water before they are using it sort of prevent the diseases so
there are successful examples of I don't know diffusion and there are also many not successful
examples of diffusion the diffusion or cascades can can have a very very very
interesting flavors for example there was just a recent study where they were studied
they were studying how being overweight spreads virally right so for example they
found they in the paper they have this claim that if you have a overweight friend then
introduce a binary random variable say that marks the relevance of the document d
and we have a query q and what we'd like to know is whether given
a particular query document
d is relevant not and you know one way to look at this is simply
to apply this rule here
and so we will have to contributions here
the prior probability of relevance for document well that can is usually based on things
like popularity of the document or it's just a constant on the context
and then something written here which is
you know in in plain language you can understand or you could express is the
probability of generating a particular query q
to ask for relevant d so given that we assume that the document is relevant
what's the probability to ask
for the document with a particular query
and that's basically
OK so
the standard approach to that is
to basically treat the query terms as a sample
drawn from relevant documents basically
i mean their models of different complexity here but basically what we'd like to have
is a
a model for each document that tells us how probable so the words are and
then we just assume that queries the sample generated from these were
OK so this is
this is the language modeling paradigm again to make clear conceptually so the idea is
the user has some
document in mind that is kind of irrelevant relevant doc perhaps or
a relevant document
and from that
use it generates
a particular query
and then we'd like to reverse
so what is no need approach
for doing that where we just say well we just use you know the maximum
likelihood estimate here i mean we're calling it there is basically no we could just
use the
just the the
count statistics
right normalize and that's the probability to see word in the document so that just
it assigns relative frequencies words that actually occur but then of course we have this
that the terms did not occur gets zero probability and then you know a query
that contains the term that contained in the document will just get a score of
the real question here is in the estimation problem is how can we bring in
the other documents in the collection is a very practical point of view
the idea is not just to treat document in isolation but rather the whole collection
which is also encoded in this term document matrix that encodes the whole
the document collection
and how can we bring that into improved to come up with better estimates
all of these
document specific language model the probability of the word given doc
and so this
the approach that
we've been developing under the name probabilistic latent semantic analysis works like this OK we
have again document in terms
and we introduce an intermediate
layer like bottleneck layer of so called latent concepts
and what we
try to do now instead of you know learning directly
probabilities of terms and documents we learn the probability for each document two
if you like participate in particular con cept
and then the probability
for each concept that that concept is expressed as concept is expressed by a particular
term OK so the idea is we might have a document here
dealing with issues related to trade hopefully our models we feed our model talk about
the second
you will find a concept that might correspond to something like trade and that might
have very high probability to be expressed by terms like coming
in trade
notice that these a concept expression probabilities are estimated based on all documents that are
dealing with a concept
we use in the whole collection at that point try to
and what we're doing here anyway
is we'll see the next slide is basically a mixture model where we assume that
each document is composed of simple
a mixture of topics or concepts
and that's what we're trying to uncover
the nice thing about this is is completely unsupervised
just based on the co occurrences of words
OK and here's what i just described the picture
it is also very simple
as an algebraic expression
how this model looks like so
probability of word given document is a simple mixture here because these services are document
language model
we have these latent concept
and then
we have this concept expression probabilities and this document specific mixture
another way to look at this is to say that it's a convex combination of
these second expression for every document
and these add up to one negative
right forms a convex combination everything appeared w given c is a vector from the
convex combination of the
OK so we're trying to find kind of the basis or set of
vectors here
so that by
so the final decision will be on treaty restricted boltzmann machines using approximations like gradient
i teach monty them in
this thank you can you hear me
so i am
what is the same group rocks
and i'm going to talk about how to train these restricted boltzmann machines and related
we have seen
many most famous using contrastive divergence but the ways
so let's talk about about markov random fields mrfs also known as undirected graphical models
with without hidden unit
these these things in the popular through machines an example but also
from the physical ones
with connections between the visible units
this can be used for
from the training dataset that this
unsupervised learning nothing conditionally here
the problem which is the thing you might want to do with this is intractable
unless of course you specify very restrictive collectivity like true collectivity or collectivity
and you know you throw
the potential of these models
i fully connected
there are many things because
so some work and
and i mentioned
this various data collected
gradient approximators suggest contrastive divergence pseudo likelihood and so must be a fairly inaccurate
as the rest has shown you
using CV one contrastive divergence with one step pretty bad models
and the very popular ground is this one
just do something else using direct way
that's good news
there is is a solution that works a lot better all of these
well let's have a look at what exactly is the issue here is that the
markov random fields models
which means that the
they defined
for that you cannot immediately
see probability because it has to be divided by the sum of these normalized probabilities
and that is what makes so many things and is intractable
the training procedure for these models for these
levels consist of two parts
first we must increase the probability
of the training data
second last
reduce the probability
states of configurations that do not appear in the training data
so one of the best papers by christina now called this that the probability of
from some area
and that's what we have to do
yes and it may have
the large probability to training data but it sounds like
as probability elsewhere that's the model
so must to reduce amount probability elsewhere
using itself
it's not to difficult
the problem is to find the area
i would be if we could draw samples from but that's one of the things
that's intractable in these models
so has the difficulty
to get samples what want to get approximate samples what one usually does this sort
of the markov chain
with gibbs transition operators transition operators
initialize some state
for many updates and
after long time say
the statement about approximate sample he's going to do the
the other thing going to reduce the possibility
that's a lot of time if you want to do that
and when they said well takes infinite time that's not available
some things do this the approximately
there was
so samples
not really examples but the
blood samples that it's close to the training data so
contrastive divergence mentioned and pseudo likelihood of the best examples of these
in pseudolikelihood also explains
you take one you take the training data points and change one of the values
in that
and you decide that what you get that
use that sort example to do something that of course is very close to the
training data
so was contested edits especially contrastive divergence with one step which is the most popular
approach because it's the fastest
markov chain at some training data
but we should have a lot of questions like what is this denomination c
and more than what are these functions fj which are functions of x and y
and so maybe i'm so i'll give the quick answer to the question was the
nominator first
so this is sort of the to just the formal answer
e of x and w
is the sum
over all y prime
some of the j
fj j
why prime
here we have
the numerator which refers to x and y x and y come from here
and here we have a sum over all y prime
of the numerator
x and y prime so i plugged in why prime et cetera why can can
and i said the only thing that we need to assume
about the
this about the labels that y is that is finite and the reason why
the reason i need the labels so widely finite is you here i'm something of
everything in the label set so that only well-defined if i'm something of a finite
but can somebody explain
this has to be the formal definition of c
without this having really any particular intuitive meaning it still has mathematically has to be
this why
normalisation so can you explain a bit more
for any x
one otherwise is going to be the label
when i sum of all the wise
the sum of the probabilities has to be one
the so
and then i get the probabilities by having different numerator by some the numerator is
over all y
and then divide into the numerator denominator the result has to equal one
this is just you have the most basic principle of probabilities that
if you have a set of mutually exclusive events
then the sum of their
an exhaustive and the sum of the probabilities one so just from a formal point
of view the denominator has taken to some of the numerator
the nominator
he calls some of new readers
and that's the busy
i'll come back to this but on that
the first level explanation of why xe is the way it is
these are much
h j
of x and y
is called
a feature function
it plays the role of the feature in the just aggression i had wj times
here my my ex is not necessary vectors
so i can't i could multiply wj by xj xj may not even exist
but this function f plays the role of the features and functions i call the
feature function
it is
so function from tax crosswise
to the wheels
there's a arm
so notice so
f j if x and y
is greater than zero
and wj is greater than zero
p of y given x w
compared to
j of x and y
equals zero
the intuitive meaning of the feature function
if it has positive weight
is that
the bigger the value of the feature function
the more
this why
is compatible with this tax
of course
i think so
x y equals
of compatibility
between x and y
if you have
if for a particular accent particular why
the feature function is has a big
and they have a positive wj
then that y is going to have a high probability
OK if the feature
it is
negatively correlated
so if we had
if if if wj was positive
then f j had a negative value
then the bigger the negative value
insularity that
companies that
a second optically
optical behaviour
well the transparent to visible light again the high
covalent bonds transparent to visible light
and in the case of
amorphous amorphous there
amorphous are clear
and when we have the semi crystalline
semi crystal and set up
in regions of higher
adam density which translate into regions of higher refractive index
and since the refractive indices are not match between the amorphous and the
semi crystalline regime this acts effectively as an interface that can scatter light so the
semi crystal and although there is formally the transparent to visible light these in fact
proved to be opaque as you can see from the appearance of that node you
now question to ask is could you generate semi crystalline zones
that were
either index matched or
on the length scales shorter than that of visible light we saw that in the
inorganic case with the difference between higher serum glass envisions the only difference was that
the crystallites in visions
were much much smaller and as a result we were able to get the strengthening
effect without incurring a penalty of opacity
third one is chemically inert
colors are chemically inert
again the strong covalent bonds
octet stability same same reasons and this leads to very extensive used in packaging
packaging especially of food
and beverages and foods and beverages exploit this
this property
and lastly there is solid at room temperature
solid room temperature long molecules even though there are only weak van der waals bonds
operative between molecules remember the strong covalent bonds are within the molecule if you want
to ask the question is something solid liquid or gas you have to ask how
does one molecule bonded to another one of identical composition and for that we've got
not strong covalent bonds but we've got weak van der waals bonds
we then evolved bonds
but there operating over such large contact areas these molecules are very very long so
the long
molecule presents a high surface to volume ratio
very high
very high surface to volume ratio
and that leads to
strong bonding and ultimately it leads to
so we have entanglement we have a weak van der waals bonds over
high surface to volume ratio and that leads to
solidity at room temperature
and we recognise last day that absent crosslinking
absolutely crosslinking
can process these by
this gives us plastics can be reprocessed
and even in the case of hydrogen bonding although the nylons have to go to
slightly higher temperatures we are able to
reprocess the nylons in the case of crosslinking of course we have to go to
other measures because heating to very very high temperatures capable of breaking the cross links
will also breaks backbone so these things become not very easily recyclable
and in fact i've got here is that the recycle codes which you see on
products today
here's the
first one is the polyethylene terephthalate which we just saw the reaction for using these
plastics for many of the things such as in this case is dishwasher detergent the
two-litre soda bottles and so on are are the
the high density polyethylene
it's this one here
the next one v is the reaction i show to the beginning of the lecture
polyvinyl chloride fourth one is low density polyethylene which is the stretch and c and
so on and i want to note that all of these have names associated with
these are inventions all of these materials i'm showing you are inventions of the modern
they all came
as a result of
patenting et cetera so you see this one nineteen forty nineteen fifty one these are
very very recent materials
polypropylene nineteen fifty one polystyrene technically was and was isolated by a german apothecary in
eighteen thirty nine who didn't realize what he had had some material already got out
of this resonant was around nineteen twenty two when herman starting here
the reason that in fact this was the long chain of styrene and polystyrene he
wrote extensively on and eventually won the nobel prize for it but technically simon isolated
eighteen thirty nine and n seven is everything else so if you see seven at
the bottom it's
so that's the that's the change
look at
now the one love plus distribution so this may be something that
well you know quite is familiar with
so that one
for instance
is this quite a bit so like atomic decay
well the time with probability
theta dx atom will decay
and this in a certain time interval if it still exists so we can look
at the distribution of
the cave-ins
over time
and then if you consult your physics book
and you will see that
p of x
is given by theta times e to the c takes
is the positive orthant it actually turns out that it has to be in
so there should be a minus you otherwise it doesn't make so much sense
is after you want to decay
all the teams don't grow over time
so how do we
now get this back into an exponential families notation
well we just do a standard log exp trick
so this is it to the
this is the weight in the product is just the product between two numbers
namely a minus six
c is the miners again
and theta
the negative log of the
it's really simple sufficient statistic namely for fixes one six
and the normalisation is also quite simple
you can see that this function is clearly convex in theta
here's an example of one
OK everybody in an exponential decay before
but it's also exponential families distribution
engineer's favourite
normal distribution everybody some that before
and this is why would learn
if it's just the univariate one multivariate once local deformation but not so much
but that doesn't really look like an inner product between some for fixing something else
at all
well let's see how we can reshape this
o p of x
i can just write it out
so the first thing is i'm going to push this into the exponential
the second thing is going to expand
this query expression
so get one is one of the two sigma square enix square
plus mu over sigma square x
minus mu square to sigma squared minus one half block of two pi sigma square
it's good
you get some manufacturer from p x squared
i get some other linear factor from px
get some junk here
which ensures that everything integrates out to one
now let's write it in terms of well in approach between something in the axis
and the parameters theta
and then something else
so we get
it's easy to be
in approach between x and x squared on one hand and theta
which now captures those two parameters
now this integral doesn't always exist in particular doesn't exist
if this term is not negative
then the integral diverge
so we've seen interesting
phenomenon occurring that the domain of the status
need not be
all of far
can be a subset of far
in fact it's a convex subset of
why so because if got the convex function we want to ensure that this is
less equal than it it's like that it doesn't diverge
so basically
it's this is pretty
then that the brain will be a convex domain
now the last bit that you have to do is you have to rewrite this
in terms of theta one and theta two
quite tedious
but you can work it out
theta one of the mu sigma square
so welcome back everybody
what happens before was actually quite scary
somebody came up to me and said
alex i don't understand this graph while way i talked a lot of other people
they didn't understand is OK
this is scary for several reasons
OK first of all it means that really awful job explaining it effectively
and i was explaining that in the morning
by all means if something like this happens when you have to ask you and
asking enough
so it's your fault right
no but seriously to ask you something is not clear
don't be shy
i mean rather ask a stupid question
the point is if you ask a stupid question
you're not going embarrass yourself but what it will do is it will tell me
that i didn't explain things well
i mean
i don't expect you to ask terribly interesting questions was that at some point will
lead to new paper they so as in questions not to show off how right
you are
it's so that actually information is if something isn't clear please ask
i mean it seriously but also in the other lectures please do so
otherwise you will not learn this stuff
the lectures they know this stuff at least
usually we try to pretend that beta
you must ask otherwise
and just carry on now
back to these
so i do this this graph here had k and y there now
you probably remember from nando
that these are random variables right
so k actually would be
my covariance matrix
OK so this depends on my doctor so i have some x here
and this
determines k
as follows that k i j is simply k
of x y and xj
so is no statistical dependency between those two
it's a fully deterministic things
i could make this
stochastic by simply the also assuming that they have some parameter like signal which is
the kernel with which also can determine
they might just so happened that will have to my topic and then i draw
something when they get my covariance matrix
o thing this will not be deterministic dependency anymore but let's not make things messy
then there should be
so want my kernels
well i can say well i'm going to observe some teas
which are
jointly normal according to this mean you and this covariance matrix k well actually couldn't
actually include incorporate new directly but anyway
now unfortunately i'm not really observing those city's directly but i'm observing the wise which
are the tease was an additive noise
for instance the tease could be
well the voltages at the socket or sockets all throughout kerala
now what i'm observing otherwise which is what happens if i take my voltmeter plug
it in
it's going to be a bit unreliable
there might be some overall fluctuations of the voltage
throughout callow
simply because maybe the wiring isn't terribly good maybe at some places the ball is
heating up some water what even
so these variations will be equal will be can be dealt with by k
so for instance if i have some network right
some real wiring network so these are some parts here
so you've got to heart here
it's not visible
give the the argmax them
so let's say this is a wiring diagram of color
maybe the hot here
another one here
maybe he is a big one
so when i go
and i take my voltmeter and plug into the socket everywhere here
and then measure things
they would of course assume that those two voltages are quite similar
because they come up the same cable here
you could also think of that as internet throughput like it's really horrible up here
but maybe in the lecture theatre works and down there we are having tea is
not really working very well
this diagram can then be directly translated into this matrix k