sorry just over the three and have stopped short this what mean
three point seven five just
now i will cocktail you
two and four
cocktail two in four
this appointment standstill
this of course
going to be starting up this will start up because i give them both the
same amplitude i will not go to close to now
i'll make it was one of the ways to get
two large values and it becomes
a little bit unrealistic
what you see there so i'm going to give number two one
and two and then going to give number
five zero
number four also won
and already going to be to see that
the motion is going to see becomes already sort of
a little bit chaotic little
ready to position now
two normal modes
this one which i start off a one here
and this one which i started one here and it equal zero released both with
zero speed
one the
yes i do
this motion is already not so
it still
sort of
symmetric for all these reasons because this one
now what i want to do
started off line
now we're starting all five
this talk will be very asymmetric because look article number one
i set them all of positive positive positive positive positive positive
will start of very high
look at the number five the negative or positive negative positive
number five will start very low number one will stand very hard very
and then when it starts to oscillate
will take
more than
age of the universe to come back to that same shape but it extremely rare
you and i know one really really any more
what's going on
and it is even impossible to measure
that the motion is always very simple namely the superposition
very well behaving
normal mode solutions which is a linear superposition of very five very simple normal mode
but the net result is total
other scales
please that's the way
it is to us
but it can be
it can be dissected into five very simple
so these were
transverse motions
and the same idea holds for longer truly almost so you can have
five beats
six springs
and then
oscillation in this direction we call that longitudinal oscillation
in this case
this patient displacement is
perpendicular to the
also ladies we call that transfers but the other you can imagine
except that the displacement i then all the best direction for the longitudinal story
we will shortly and the domain of waves
to make you
see the idea to big difference the transverse waves and
longitudinal waves sound pressure waves
my direction to you
pressure wave is is doing this so areas is also lady in the same direction
that is that is one two know way
this is a nice moment
the brake wheel brake five minutes
and we'll start exactly five minutes from now
thank you very much for the performance
it was pre-arranged by the way
so we are now ready
make the step
two continuous medium whereby n goes to infinity well
you can argue that goes through many atoms
as we can
line almost very close to infinity
and it shouldn't come as a surprise of course
that now
you're going to get the entire string which is now continuous mass you no longer
have individual beats
that entire string
it's going to oscillate
sinusoidal was about
it is and one
that's going to oscillate
like this
and also
three hundred thirty three frames and it's like one hundred twenty of those in and
seventeen years
tracks in these are the tracks
which as shown by different colours
you are these new tracks one time
a different locations in the
so these are the competitors in the ground truth and what we have so there
is a finite sequence as shown in the beginning
the talk
these other ships in the size of ship is about forty minutes seventeen and we
had about four hundred fifty three friends and reflected about fifty of those to track
and these are the tracks of each of these but in a different location c
and as you can see the contracting for quite long time which is just good
these are the competitors in the country
the computer
these are all
all the tracks and probably this is the most beautiful slide i talk to lots
of lace colours
and south courses of the failures
the fact that many of the severe occlusions
and illumination changes
we have to some quantitative analysis and was selected about fifty
athletes from sequence one
twenty five seconds to fifteen to three and
this is the combination the the forty track
the ground truth and
the the
our method method shown in the black
and then the ground which shows the
brown as you can see that we can train very close
to the contrary
we have to compare if you want to use the traditional methods like mean shift
the government and so we have the area
for to track our method is shown in the green and the mean shift and
it is shown as you see mean shift get distracted and you get out of
some of these cases on the right side and
we have to look at the what is the role of each of the flow
field so if use only
steady flow field there is great and this is the green line which is the
dynamic field and the blue one is all fields combined as you see the average
error in tracking down to
when you have all combined blue one and gives you a pretty good results as
compared to each individual floor
then deeper what citizens of the area
so one thing we found out the extent of becoming less and then this motion
straight that's like that
motion and fluffy you know is commits more
and at least four take because the different from the local
washington of these people
so now let me talk about a couple of pieces which are the scale between
so i give to you know extreme one is the macroscopic to the microscopic level
mesoscopic and in this case
they're going to use the normal behaviour
of the crowd
and you can use the social force model
OK so the idea here is that the social force model to describe the dynamics
and the crowd behavior comes from the changes in the crowd
and the
another approach to generate force OK so so we started with video again into the
show and then compute this interaction force
then from their computers for flow and can be some features using the become
our approach and then basically that some kind of classifier
i don't know what
this is the kind of article is in the social force model this was by
so there are these people shown in the
then is called goal so there is an
which is shown in the channel and actually lasted just short of the green
and then there's the interaction forward from this is that the people which is shown
in the end so the basic model is that which follows the second neutral would
say is the forces equals mass multiplied by acceleration and the force two parts of
the force f pmf interaction
infinite action is the force the walls
in the history the people in FP
it's basically the difference between science philosophy
and the
actually velocity
so doing that you get this equation for the interaction force and that's what we
the ontology can be different levels of ontologies you've seen before of discussion about is
there one ontology can be different ontologies you can have some background knowledge that is
what your company already have has
like for example lists of dictionaries or whatever
and then you can add documents possibly you must normalized so that it doesn't matter
if you receive word final or PDF document used in three dimensions same way
and then you need medium to strong text images and data
and as output to provide annotations typically you will find RDF triples stored in a
triple store
we the uncertainty associated with see that in a minute
so there are many useful tools that are listed in the in the
lies just show you an example of a to the are really lots of that
this is actually media was developed in my lab
active media has the possibility to upload an OWL ontology and documents and what you
you can
very simply the annotation by dragging and dropping things by saying this
the wellcome foundation is whoever is visited
a specific company for example this was an application about visiting now the interesting thing
is that is that you can see it's not just that it's very easy to
annotate text in this way of the document by the ontology value drag and drop
you can create relations this is something you can download from the webpage one is
available but the
that's not all
but is also the annotation of images because there is an image there
one of the things that they store enables you to do is when you have
but text list you go to the image you select image and then say well
you see you draw score square around the post
and you say
this is the person who is visiting
and in this case so it is visited and in this case
using the context of the that's it and you know
is it mappings the bore or is it same buckinghamshire or is it actually peter
and so uses the context of the text will help you annotate the images and
then you can of course attached image recognition for example if you
and then you can also you also want to annotate across documents
this means that in this case it is a homepage bicycle potential very old one
and one from steffen staab you want to say that the person represented here is
actually the students of
someone else
he said full for example what
three are
other methods like this is an ontology called com that enables you to store
of multimedia documents so that just the data
the document said
you also say that every piece of information the in your ontology actually comes from
and this is something that the media does
manual annotation is quite daunting task
the basic point is that
you can try to do it
you know i love it but users are not very happy users typically don't want
to do it
because it takes a lot of time and every new documented they produce will have
to be annotated so you might want to annotate annotation the automated the process of
annotation and so on
this is because so the legacy data is generated huge
so what do you see want to use
something that is what you can see is basis of course this the main the
main thing in that case you just have to
and i think the schema and we are talking about here about about the annotation
of instances so you want to take text documents and images of whatever you have
to ask you and that like entity extraction where you just some names for example
but you can have relations as one
in texas so you can say this document this did this
you can have a table phase because he also lost some documents especially in companies
tend to be actually forms the tables sortable structure is an area
event structure means actually building everything we will see in a second but on data
has rolled eighty five fil vibration analysis will have lots of other tasks for images
lots of tasks so we are talking of quite daunting
as the set of pass if you just restricted information extraction from text
the task for entity extraction the structural relation extraction event structure start with the simplest
one named entity recognition is classification
and it is like japanese is first in this case and then there is a
complexity scales because up to event recognition where you're actually capture the whole event is
described in this case was that there was a company by hiring a person and
this person
lieutenant company this is very
classic example
now if you look at and named entity recognition
there are many ways of doing it the task is to recognise and classify the
name the named entities so you can say paul jacobs is person
i promise
this is going on on video i promise that we will fix up any type
before we release the
the slides
so use potentially complex structure and then
with row
processes of systematic way
increasing it from zero
and you can come up with
an optimal
not necessarily optimal in the mathematical sense but a good trade off between
accuracy on the training samples sum of squares
the smoothness of the function
in many ways that's what we do
in some cases
so what happens if the data will constrain the shape of the function wherever it
we've got the data a number of points
this this demand for smoothness will constrain the function from doing anything too silly
when it's when you're away from the data in the gaps between
so a whole variety of regularisation approaches again if we just simply take the kinds
of models tony looked at the classification
like logistic regression or something then we don't get these nice closed form solutions but
nonetheless we can still do the same things we can so constrained functional
so restricting flexibility is a typical
way of
dealing with this problem of what takes place
in between the date
OK and crop up in a number of ways during the week
so is my little
multi media animated the proud of this
powerpoint which drives him crazy
what we have here
it is
away now
of finding out what is happening in between the samples
OK because
it's all very well having a way of restricting the flexibility
but we need a basis on which to make that trade trade-off
and so we need to know what is happening in between
we don't have the true function
if we did we wouldn't be bothering with any this will pack up and go
what we do is some form of validation
what you what is illustrated here is the most basic form validation
which is called
usually the hold-out method
the hold-out method
there we go
hold out
green circles the flashing on and off they just indicating
the data that has been used for training
OK so
tony mentions splitting up your data into
a number of components here we've done
very basic thing we've got
one his ten data points
i've taken this
one two three four
five of them
and trained
a flexible structure
with those five the five are
but the the
the green flashing ellipses
we can see because we got very
flexible structure
we get very close to these data points
case we get a very small mean squared errors
in these
areas here
but i've got
another five samples which are held out
of my
the entire training set
OK so now
because my best to guess what the
true function is doing
in between my training samples
i can measure
the distance
my estimated function is the turquoise function here
and these held out data points
and get a measure of my performance
i can for instance
look at the mean squared error
some squared error or i can work out
some of them major performer
the sum of absolute errors something doesn't matter whatever i'm interested in
however it my performance indicator
so i measure my performance on these held out sample
and that tells me something about how well under
so in this particular case i one of the look is the
the root mean squared error
k across
cut and paste good cut paste
the way see i can express as the weight of the edge i removed
plus the way i t one
plus the weight of t two
so that's the total weight
so the answer is pretty simple suppose that there were some
t one prime was better
then t one
for g one
suppose some better way
forming a spanning tree
i would make up eighty prime
which was just consists ten the edges you
and in the end you v
she won prime
union t
so i take if i had a better
spanning tree
venturi of lower waves
for t one
i call that t one prime
i just substitute that
and make up a spanning tree that consisted of my original my edge u v
whatever worked well forty one prime
and worked whatever work property and that would be
that would be a spanning tree
and it would be better
then t itself was
for g
because the way these
it's just that the weight for this i now just get use the weight of
t one prime and that's less
and so therefore
the assumption that
that t was the minimum spanning tree would be violated if i could find better
one for the sub piece
so we have this nice
optimal substructure
OK i have some problems in that are
they can be there that exhibit optimally five and
globally optimal solution
the whole problem
within that i can find optimal solutions to subproblems
so now the question is
that's one hallmark that's one hallmark of dynamic programming what about overlapping subproblems i have
that property
five overlapping subproblems over here
this paper problems
a way of finding overlapping co occurring patterns of words but that's a good point
you're right i don't really answer the question topical i turn it into co occurring
and then i discuss how we're finding these spas overlapping co occurring sets of words
but it's
something worth more thing about it an excellent question and it's it's kind of a
it's an issue you build generative process and you imagine it working one way and
then it works another way that saying something you about to process or about the
intuitions that you're having about the data not being correct
it's good question
OK so this this this this makes sense so this is just an intuition that
that what LDA is doing is softening the strict definition of co occurrence in a
mixture model to allow for overlapping sets of co occurring words and using the dirichlet
prior as a way of enforcing that a document can be about all the topics
at once
OK and that's that's the punchline here
the other thing
well this model has no notion of hierarchy so right this is just the flat
set of distributions over words
and words that are more general so like in baseball there are words about baseball
in general and there words about specific team if i could name one player i
mention the example and the
like paper so
so in your right here in the based in the baseball topics since they all
co occur together we would find general words about baseball in the same topic as
words like the paper who specific to a team
although the words that are specific will necessarily have lower probability than the general words
i you know it's almost like this is finding one level if there is a
hierarchy and you don't
if if you feel like the hierarchy is an extremely important part of what you're
trying to get out of the corpus then you should put a hierarchical structure somehow
on these topics which is something you can do
OK then will the last common and then we'll move on
so the
the right answer that i have no idea
OK but that's a good point but i don't want to go back to the
site that somehow is you produce alpha you're putting more probability on on distributions that
have smaller entropy
and there's really good paper by
bill bialek and
some of some colleagues about the
o b i a l i k
about he's
a neuroscientist and is
does that and it's about the implicit assumptions about the entropy of a distribution that
putting in their sleep prior on something has
that would be what i would point you to learn more about that OK
OK so
that's what i was hoping to talk a little bit about the intuitions for why
this does anything and again you know thinking about the likelihood term is essential they're
not just thinking about the properties of the priors which are also very important you
can see they both had an important component in our our lose understanding what's going
OK so
LTA this simple topic model can be embedded in more complicated models embodying further intuitions
about structures of texts this is already alluded to with things like hierarchies and there
any proposal is
we used to find some sort of objective functions
and you have a main condition that things that
as i see it is this optimiza it splits urinating clusters and you want short
distances within each of
you cannot accept that the
clusters come up with that despotic kings
but then you went the secondary condition that maybe you don't want unfortunatelly that he
found clusters are
and this is very thickly forested is the two moons dataset or you have some
data that comes up in the clouds
but wait
but in another set of data comes up in a closed that way
and if you very they pass a very very close neighbors union all these
there are bus training
this enables all the way here but nothing in between get the distance between two
close points in different clusters is much closer than
some distance within the clusters
it should
the very well one the second benjamini maybe not just keep it in mind
many people from university of phoenix use it to say that the western church
having to rule on the case of pornography in the US
somehow was forced to decide whether something was or was not pornography
i have two in that it could not define pornography but definitely he could recognise
it when the history
and then if it stays
this is the clustering
you can define testimonial you can recognise that with clustering when you see it
and this is great if you're in a place into the
many three d
but how about seeing the clusters in
one thousand dimensional space
you see
that's what form of proportionalities many interesting
there are fewer so proposed the following three axioms
scale invariance
if your studies like this and you you need
the clustering is still the same
if you look at them differently this points here on this point here just because
the length of the unit
in the middle is
you done for me up really any potential to st
and consistent
if you have clustering
you want some point
in one
in such a way that the distances
the colleagues in the same cluster of
think one article and simultaneously all the distances to all the points you know the
cluster is the statewide or increase
and the clustering does not
he says he will axioms
and the great terror behind
there is no
clustering algorithm that can actually see proposition
so this is why for the case
researchers have been proposed by this of clustering of because no one of them will
ever get nasty properties that somehow wasn't not
may is preceded
but they were being looking after
and when you get one of their and sometimes you need be changed and
the scale invariance was away or
the solution is there is is no solution to the problem is over specified
now of course
when you see these
seventy one of the sea
properties becomes very subspecies
for some of users can invite me for some of his which are made of
business maybe some people with this belief consistency they're all sorts of unsourced police area
on all consistency is the stronger condition bring impose we should
but all of them came afterwards
the then what are the terms we don't know yet these people are working on
shaven headed in toronto is
has number of
contributions to history and i'm sorry i haven't followed up the rest
but something exciting is maybe going on here
in k means
throwing geometry
we throwing geometry means that we accept
that we're going to measure distances between of our situations and that no one is
going to give us the distance we have to to come up with one
and if it doesn't make sense for the data
the outcome will not make any sense
and you don't know how to mister whether during this time is the right one
a sense of scale
use a fully informative so it's news is totally independent from the previous ones
but the correct definition of fully informative news because it's piece of news is totally
compared with the that should be no correlation like now but the definition of randomness
is indeed and sometimes you have subsequent random use of the same sign
if the agents over learn about this
because we use bayesian learning
they may be tempted to actually overweight the social imitation factor
all the way back to the new and then her collectivity increases pressure
let's go on to the next stage would go fast on the real estate bubble
and mortgage and backed security above all to address the question of
the denture before going faster detection this world is water
global phenomena
you see the
returns the percentage over a four-year period in various countries
you see the US actually the phenomenon was even larger in some places absent in
some rare places cases
i want just to show you again that is a super exponential acceleration was present
for example in the UK
this is one of the example
roger we did identify the bubble
in advances actually a year before the we correctly predicted that they would be meet
two thousand four and this was published about a year and a half before the
another example for the US
we're here we identify this super exponential growth on the series of
showing here in color
the hot state where
really the price was skyrocketing in the super exponential growth with different colors showing that
w this region
not only was happening so the phenomenon was really as you all know
localized is called nationalist cause and on the
especially california nevada and so on
two years later you see here map where the darkest color show that they did
the measure of the delinquency rates
it shows a very strong correlation between
this analysis and
delinquency rates very interestingly the
of the federal reserve wrote academic paper of this time
we show that one of the
concept the c
motivation for these level
it was actually the
equity extraction
this is called right is the fact that
the on real estate was you know due to this refinancing so that homeowners were
extract value from the house actually to spend more by
BMW's anything like that again in an accelerated fashion this time scale
this is just to to show you that after this big now
we are in in know drop trophy so
why are they dangerous
well this is the captain way of the subsequent about associated with the the real
which shows the different schematic
blocks of
partners of interaction so we had to bore
getting along from the lander a mortgage broker
have this monthly payment that are given to the investment bank that actually
i had a a long contract but you have also the securitisation
mortgage-backed security character that obligations on that have been released solved over all over the
planet to hedge fund two severin freund and so on so that is the global
and this slide actually lists across different partners it's a game
the different problems
that needs a full investigation
this starting from
predatory lending these
very interesting
phenomenon there many studies have now shown that excess learning was
expanded the progress level
mortgage fraud quite significant
adverse selection
mould has many different levels
and the principal agent age in the agency problem but where we are rampant in
the development of the system subsequent to the secretion securitisation of credit risk
just to be very short
so there's a few are not family
corresponded to
four banks would loan to three back these loans from values
home owners
in two different tranches of the course
with rating
the triple eight me that's very low probability of default
homeowners which had a good well spaces
all the way down to basically extremely dangerous someone very poor or
basically the
holmes has been
and it
basically without any collateral
and very little margin and so by
recap packaging or this instrument into single financial things
this was
actually rated by the rating agencies as a
with the consequence that we have heard and we we know
with the cascade phenomenon i just want to say something about the cascade phenomena according
across these different elements
which can be by sculptor
a lot of that is shown
across different disciplines and i will show you two incarnation about one in earthquakes
and the other one in epileptic seizures to make big strides to
connecting the fields that one
you deal with the connected passed and you ask what kind of
avalanches what kind of events can occur
obviously the distribution of the sizes of the risk can
derived from the because going disconnect part is
controlled by the key by the largest component of the system that it could be
that makes can spread beyond the size of the stick disconnected but when they become
coupled is obvious that you have the possibility and that's what the model support of
james across elements and then you develop
two kinds to possible classes of distribution
either heavy tailed distributions are also called power law distributions
and they even more so that's already serious because you have the load non-zero probability
of having quite large events laughter is really revealed
but that somehow
is not so bad because
you can as good or
risk manager
identified its distribution and somehow
measure your residual risk exposure by extrapolating the distribution
much more research
the possibility actually to develop this kind of distribution where
this extreme kings outliers
which occur rarely
which ones as long as they don't occur you don't have any idea about the
OK so this works
but let's see a case where doesn't work and all i'm going to do is
to add one more unlabelled data points
to the data set
you see them
why are there
just like i
and well so at some point
you started propagated in the wrong fishing and then that guy will invade
this reaching and eventually get something else
all right
so just to keep this in mind semisupervised learning may not always work and that
this is a repeating theme in today's talk
so let's move on to
our first
actually second model mixture model you have already seen that that's the two cows examples
let's make it more formal
again here is an example but this time in two d
so let's say you have
some labelled data points and i actually tell you that each class is accounts distribution
if that's the case what you do right you're given this data point this training
data set then it's easy rate you would estimate the mean and covariance of your
account in distributions
so model is a mixture of gaussians which has the following parameters you have w
one w two those are the weights of the two gaussians three respectively they should
sum to one
and then you have to mean and the covariance covariance matrices
the first the full joint model so the joint model is like first you pick
which comes in you generate data points and then use that gaussians
to generate your point
OK so if you know the parameters of the system then the classification is done
by bayes rule o
that's what you get
and if you do it here
contours are the sample mean and sample covariance of your labelled data set
if you apply bayes rule you can plot the decision boundary in this case the
decision boundary is
the very hard to see
green line limit raise it for you it's kind of like this
that's all fine except that when you see
more unlabelled data points
OK so
the green dots are unlabelled data points from the same distribution
no you realize that the maximum likelihood estimate for the guys in distributions are not
so good
instead what you should should have use something like this
OK the two gaussian distributions have more
nicer covariance more diagno h
and the decision boundary
estimated from this data
it is the green line here almost vertical
and we want to capture this notion
so what's the difference here what the differences
how are you going to estimate the parameters of your accounts in mixture models
in particular
we will be doing maximum likelihood but in one case we will maximize the labelled
data likelihood but when you have
o labelled data what you should do is to maximize the
a different form of likelihood they're taking into consideration the unlabelled data
in this mixture model
we make the assumption that you actually know
the form of the model so that means you know it's a mixture of two
gaussians see
but then what you want to look at is this quantity
the probability of
both the labeled data and unlabeled data
now since we do not have
the labels on the unlabelled data you need to marginalize them out
OK so that means you need to sum over the labels on the unlabelled data
OK so this is a joint probability on the labelled data and marginal probability on
the unlabelled data
OK then
that's the quality you want to optimize
you can do maximum likelihood or you can do MAP estimate or you can be
whatever you like
but you want to optimize that quantity
there are many
so that's the to the talk what
i should say
this work was done to about fifteen years ago and autonomous driving has come along
way so many of you were for the doctor grand challenge where one of my
colleagues have action prove that the winning team the winning team to drive a car
across the desert by itself
the album was i think absolutely amazing work force time but you know states of
autonomous driving has also come a long way since then
the so
what you just saw
was an example on making supervised learning and in particular was example of what they
call the regression problem because the vehicle is trying to predict a continuous values variables
over continuous value steering directions we call these so called called the regression problem
what i want to do today is talk about to offer supervised learning algorithm and
it will also be to regression on
the running example then we use on
throughout today's lecture on she can return to the example trying to predict housing prices
it's actually a data set on
collected by RTA
dan ramage on housing prices in portland oregon
so here's a data set of the number of houses of of different sizes
and so on
here are their asking prices in thousands of
o point of thousands
and so on you can take this data and plotted square feet
and so you may get the data set like that the question is given a
data set like this given trait what call it training set like this how do
learn to predict the relationship between the size of house
and the price of the home
so initially come back and modify this talk will be more later on the introduced
some notation which be using actually throughout the rest of the squad
the first is notation is on going to let
the lower case alphabet n denote the number of training examples images number of roles
of the number of from examples holds and prices have been you know in in
this particular dataset we have
what actually happened forty seven training examples of what i wrote down five
throughout this quarter en route to use the output and
to denote the number of training examples
on i'm going to use the lowercase alphabet x
to denote the input variables which all which are often also called the features and
so in this case x with denote the size of the holes are looking at
on the twenty news y to denote holds
the area all which is sometimes also called the targets
target variable
and so
on one pair a comma why is what comprises one training example in other words
one row on the table i i i draw just now what people work on
one training example
and the i th training example
in other words the i th row in that table i'm going to write as
it's class
why i and so on
for the in this notation i'm going to use the superstring i is not exponentiation
so this is not x power i want to pass i in this notation of
this superstring i parentheses is just seven in that sense the i th row
well the training examples
in supervised learning this is how
so this is this is the
what we're going to do
training set
on and we're going to feed our training set comprising our EM training examples of
forty seven training example into learning
algorithm that has opened
a function that maps the by tradition for historical reasons on is usually denoted
lowercase alphabet h and is called the hypothesis
don't worry too much about whether the term hypothesis is the
more turn this use historical reasons
and the hypothesis is job is to so take as input
you know because the new host was first want estimate on what the hypothesis does
it takes as input on a new living area in square feet saying out
yes made the price of this whole
so the hypothesis h
that's from inputs x
outputs y
so in to design learning algorithms on the first we have to decide is how
we want to represent the hypothesis and just for the purposes of this lecture for
the purpose of first learning algorithm on going to use a linear representation for the
hypothesis so i'm going to represent the hypothesis as it affects people
it is zero
plus the the one x where
x here is is the input feature and so that's the
the size of the holes were considering
more generally
come back to this on
more generally for many
because many regression problems we have more than one input feature so for example
if all is just knowing the size of the holes is
we know also
yes some of them
so this
right now
and you get something
he said he
so the same
i know that
now what
so i think it would be the
and of course in the world
so go and
just to
it is not
so you know
the rest
so o
so i give
is equal
he goes way this
he did
the it will
ten is you
thank you
and know
you are
so there like
so he
yes right
so this the right
the right
using this is what do
you know
well maybe one to
so that
if you think it is
in the same
now this
and this is all huge
the graph g
all right
he was with
and this is
as you see i see is
they want believe what we know
o you can
what you just to the west
right so
you know what
it is
this is the same
you know you know
you know
you to
he says you want
what do you
to this
the rules
i mean these really
well that would be
if q one positive
and this might be
representation forty one
if q two were negative
this might be
representation forty two
pointing towards the negative charge
and if this one
were negative
i would have here
contributions three
and so on
and we use the superposition principle as we did last time was coulombs law
that the
net electric field at a point
this the one
in problems of charge q one
splicing factor u two thousand three
and so on and if you have a high charges
it is the sum of all charges
is it obvious that the superposition principle works
does it work
how do we know it works
because it's consistent with all our experimental
so we take the superposition principle for granted
and that is
but it's not obvious
if you tell me what the electric field at this point is which is the
factorial some of
the individual if field vectors
then i can always tell you what the force will be
if i bring a charge at that location
i think any charges always carry in my pocket i take it out of my
and i put at that location
and the charter in my pocket q
then the force
on that charge
it is always q times e
it doesn't matter whether q is positive
then it will be in the same direction as
if it is negative it will be in the opposite direction
if q is large the force will be large if q is small the force
will be small
so once you know do you feel this could be the result of very complicated
charge configurations
the real secret behind
the concept of an field is that you bring any charge at that location
and you know what force
at that point on that
if we try to be a little bit more
suppose i had here
a charge
class three
and he i had charge
minus one
it was minus one
and and i want to know what the field configurations as result of these charges
so you can go to any particular point
you get an effect which is
going away from the past three
you get one that goes to minus one and u
after vector only after two
if you very close to minus one
it's very clear because of the inverse are square relationship that the minus one is
probably going to win
let's in our minds to take a blood test right now
put plus test charge
very close to mine is one so we put it here
even though three is trying to push it out
clearly minus one
is most likely
two with
and so it will probably be enforced
on my test charge in these directions
the net result of effects of the two
suppose i take the same positive test charge anybody here very far away
much far away then this separation
what do you think now
is the direction of the force all my plus chart
thomas if you come here you can do me
just get another chance you take
so everyone has got a pond
now we need to do
within your your pairs
choose who is a and who b and it doesn't matter who's just decide now
use a is b
let we just
you can be
right now very very simple
you have a very easy
a has these jobs
and your job is this
i which is tall
to be
all i want you to do is talk to be
and i want you to say it
however you want to say
you know if you if you want to like this you can still like this
if you need to move a little bit move don't move too much a doesn't
need to move to much to just sit comfortably all the way through this exercise
that's a role b
your job is slightly more difficult
now a what is a need to talk about because we need something to talk
about to give you
just because you need something
so the subject i would like a to talk about is this you believe
that the UK
should join the euro
that's your belief
you know those view from slovenia you can you can inject well it's done so
much for so whatever you're argument is i don't care if you believe in real
life and not or if you care about real life your arguments rather role-play is
the UK should join the euro and sit comfortably don't move too much publicity committee
but not too much
just nice income to be
you're all is slightly
this is what i want you to do is be
at the start of the conversation
i want you to agree
with a
so you agree make sure to two-way conversation is not a one-way communities listening to
a your your interjecting as well you're giving your opinions but the important thing is
there is agreement
the UK should join the euro the other thing i want you to do b
when you start the role when you start the exercise i want you
to visually
and vocally match a
to the millimetre
to the millimetre if a as a is talking if he or she scratches that
b you do exactly the same
you are mimicking
one millimeter
now a
don't make this too difficult
don't purposely do funny things in it
you just be yourself
talk to be comfortable sit comfortably all the way through
your your role is easy
UK should join the euro so be
at the beginning
you agree
and you mimic you match visually and vocally to the millimetre this exercise does not
work unless is to the millimeter
then i'm going to say be switch
b you're going be for different things
i agree and match
second b
and then i ask you
to carry on agreeing
but now i want you to mismatch
totally mismatch a and to give you a demonstration of what i want
so if i'm talking
with the tightest at the beginning we're talking on going to be something like this
obviously whatever whatever he does i'm going to do when i ask you to switch
when i say
continue agreeing but mismatch
thomas days is all be doing something like this
all this
do you see how i mismatching
not not subtly this is obvious if you really want to obviously mismatch you can
even do this
i want you to carry on agreeing
with the arguments continue agreeing that's number two i've got all this ringing that don't
worry i've got this surrender
verbally agreeing
visually and vocally mismatching
number three
you carry on your the same all the way through b
number three i want you
to start this agreeing
with the argument
go back to matching
to the millimetre
so now
number three should look like this
i come back
however it however you want
and i will be saying
i'm not sure
so it's going to look exactly the same i'm going to sound like a but
i'm disagreeing with him or her
and then number four
the fourth thing being is the when i say switch is start mismatching and start
right so to give you a summary
he give you a summary it's it's here
of the
person a you maintain stay nice comfortable position all the way through UK should join
the euro b
you can start the agreeing and match the millimeter vision vocal
then start agreeing and mismatching
in exponentiation is factor of two
so here is really hard to see with this one plus is doing and our
analysis if we tried it
and it's a good idea to try to home see what happens
if you try to do the what i'm about to do with XML
the one possible sort of get lost and you won't get about
can't prove
with the factor two we're in good shape we know how to deal with that
so more
when war when we've actually done the proof
but why we use wireless access for now
the reason why
so this is sort of a recursion acceptance condition on the so that so how
do i turn this into a statement that holds all the time
by by the probability of the event more or less
these events are
are all equally likely i should say not independent that one terms all the others
so how would i had generally represent events in algebra
indicator variables
remember your friends in the random variables of these analyses
use indicator random variables
they will just represent this event
and we'll cause and k
it's going to be one
if the rest of the road has rank k
and zero otherwise
so in particular
the probability
these things are all equally likely for a particular value and if you trial the
values of k
the probability that this equals one
which is also
the expectation
that indicator random variable
you should now
it only takes values one or zero zero doesn't matter
so this is going to be
only one hour and
so and possibilities of what the rank of the roof could be
each of is equally likely because we have a uniform permutation
so now i can rewrite this conditional statements as the summation
we're busy and cazorla only choose what case i mean
we have y and
there is some
OK cake want
the max
OK minus one
quite minus k
so now we have a good friend the recurrence
of it
OK we can really solve because this is the random variable is talking about recursive
random variables so first take expectation of both sides
that's what we really
that's the only thing we can really ground y and could be an square
in an unlucky case
sorry not in square
it could be an squared it could be to do the
be to the end if you're unlucky because xn can be as big as an
the height of the tree
and why and it's two that could be through the and what we want to
is that it's
polynomial in n it's and to some constant we take logs of be log
so we'll take expectations hopefully that will guarantee
this also
so we have expectation of the summation
random variables times recursive
random variables
so what is the first for track
what is the first thing that we do
in this analysis
linearity of expectation
that was easy to remember
we have some estimates put the inside
now we have an expectation of product
what should we use
independence hopefully things are independent then we can write this
then it would be the expectation of the product
and think this put the two outside is not
the sense in keeping in here
as the to like axis i can't even remember that
it should all be wise
very wise
and the variables
why are these independent so here we're looking at the choice of what the really
what rank the route has a problem of size n
in here
we're looking at what the roots
i mean there are various traces of what the search tree looks like in the
stuff left the room and the stuff right at the right
those are independent choices because everything is uniform
so the choice of the sky
was uniform and then
of the doors of quite close
now if you could the
descriptors with the bag of features of presentations we have used in here on this
dataset poses this mean average precision as performance measure
but you can first is that all the baseline this is well known the performance
increases as dimension grows up to point to in this case she obtained for two
hundred thousand components
but you can also see that if you from some dimensionality reduction zen
the performance drops
and actually it's not good seem to have a very long vector you few dimensions
so in this case if you reduce the
i victoriously victor to only sixty four components performances is only forty one on the
best is obtained for twenty thousand components could use sixty four four forty fourth
o point five which is not that bad for sixty four dimensionality vector but
not good enough in all case
so now if you look at the presentation we propose we only a very small
number of countries that is four
low dimensional his final victory you obtain some very good performance of two fifty seven
point five which outperforms the best but features of presentation
and also presentation is more likely to be reduced using principal component analysis
so if you want only one hundred twenty eight components for use that as we
can get fifty one
o point of mass so you can see again is that it is difficult to
the victories i number of components so there tradeoff depending on the number of compensatory
you want to know
you should fix k smallest i
so now the attendees could use their as we have to consider for this purpose
we use recent so that users search and indexing problem as the distance approximation problem
so the idea is to approximate the distance between the query vector x
and the basic to y
by the distance between x and the quantized version
was a bit vector so that the visitor is quantized because there's no need to
to quantize to query so we estimate this distance by distance
this is a vector to code distance in contrast to speak time she says that
brighton is based purely on building
and we compare the both two codes on the crowe's on could be introduced into
the approximation which is not you
the church contains a critical we need many centuries to get for estimation of the
distance where we cannot use the documents approximate k means because we typically want about
two sixty four centuries
to produce sixty four bits codes
instead we are using product contains the idea is quite simple we have to split
the into civic toes on each subject is quantized separately using contains there was a
limited number of centroids to in all cases conveys is still can contain the
risk only if you number simply is this case this example i take two hundred
fifty six sanctuary for each person except contains
so finally when you have vector
to be included usability contest component about a bit index just on taser although it
could use a sixty four bit composition index
now the interesting thing is put the contains there is that you can compute the
squared distance approximation directly in the compressed domain that is we can decompose the square
distance between two pixels a summation of discrete distance between feature vectors each quantized civic
to of the databases
on which is interesting which one would you want to compute the distance between the
query vector many codes of the disease is that
the email in also terms describes the terms in this summation are shared by both
the basic tools that is you first have to the first stage compute the distance
between bishop victor on all possible some treat this is the first this is not
the bottleneck on then you want to compute the distance between the query on the
database because just need additions projects
in the previous example means that you can compute the distance between vector on the
sixty book because using twenty eight edition
we like to mention that this scheme can combine reason i voted for it to
vote is this search on this provide comparable results we research better efficiency
so now you know that the red because of the filter approximation
to first approximation is due to PCA we have some protection we introduce the mean
square your
on the approximation due to quantization based upon the contains
so we can measure this explicitly
so now if you fix
given number of science we get
number of by very major want to use so we use the constraint on the
memory zen can automatically selects the number of components to be kept the by of
the dimensionality of addiction
in this case for example they have chosen sixteenth century from a constraint is sixteen
so as the dimensionality grows for the number of selected components
to partition iraq we use this is not surprising that but the same time we
are small just contains the
so the quantisation error increases
so finally trade of this is my on as the
the values obtained for sixty four components to be kept by the PCA
now let's go to the residence and some standard the set so we first first
use the university of kent in key object recognition benchmark on on this datasets this
score is usually measured as number of relevant images which are quite one in the
first four positions with is maximum for
we have also used in the early days dataset we spoke performance measured by an
average precision
the two first lines of for the baseline of the bag of features presentation on
this on canton key or about three
the mean average precision go from from forty five for medium medium-sized vocabulary two fifty
fuzzy longer larger vocabulary
so now if you look at the most probable work two hours
but you can see that we can reduce some presentation to only twenty bytes in
that case performance is not very good
now if you want to have a better is was approach you must use several
hundreds of bytes on the legs is you cannot achieve the same performance as bag
of features
now is the proposed approach
using only sixteen
two forty bytes we actually outperformed for forty bytes that if you just presentation was
not really unconvincing key on your very competitive with forty ninth of the bone five
one hundred twenty four thousand animals
four slaughter
but i mean think about it really think about it
how many farmed animals have you seen how many have you seen just this week
other sixty five billion how many have you seen this month
how many have you seen this year
how many have you seen in your lifetime
i mean just to give you some perspective to put this number into some sort perspective
think about how many people you see how many humans you see every single day
in the farmed animal population is
nearly ten times the human population
we are are given that these animals body parts are literally everywhere we turn
don't we ever see them alive
we don't see the animals bodies become a food because we're not supposed to
they are not as common as the industry would have us believe living unhappy mom-and-pop happy family farms
i know this is supposed to be happy
it doesn't look like a happy count them
the scary
but it's supposed to be a happy count
but most animals today are not living unhappily mom-and-pop farms as we say in
in english family farms over ninety nine percent of the meat eggs and dairy but make it to a place
come from animals that were raised in factory farms there are windowless shed in remote
locations that are virtually impossible for anyone other than industry officials to obtain
access to
in you did try to obtain access to one of these compounds euclid wide open prison
for example
in the united states we now have what's called the animal enterprise terrorism act
this is eh piece of legislation that's is similar pieces of legislation being passed in countries around the world today
dara lovitz attorney end of the book muslim movement explains about the eighty eight that's
it states that one has committed a federal crime and terrorism they engage in any
activity that may reduce the profits of an animal enterprise
and she says eighty eight legislation someone this is fundamentally unconstitutional for violating activists right to free speech
united states refer to these new sets was ag gag laws agribusiness laws that prevent people
from exposing any part of the practice animal agriculture
so who are these individuals background music industry tries so
heart-to-heart for months
one sheer a short video clip with here narrated by animal behaviourist jonathan balcombe whose
in october of over forty scientific papers sand forty four books on
animal consciousness
in this gives us a rare glimpse into the air in our lives
and you
is the
the first one
it is the
on the
the lower
and some of the scenes reliably on
these animals that use other
the land animals that were
depicted here are residents farm sanctuary which is seen leaving farmed animal protection organizations a
sanctuary for abused and neglected farmed animals in the united states
unfortunately both course sanctuary is home to only a tiny minority
farmed animals in the world today so
in just a moment i'm going to show another ship short video four minutes video
one is
in this example is thirty percent chance of rain tomorrow and people are lost
and that's one would be
so meteorologist
what i think it should be
this means in thirty percent of the days
where we make this prediction of the range of a minimum range
let me give you one example from hell
that illustrates how important
it is for the general public to understand
essential and very simple concepts that have to do with risk
in the UK
there is every seven years or so
a contraceptive pill scare
one way in the following way
the news reported
that women who take the pill of the third generation increased risk of first rumble
and billy by
one hundred percent
that certainly isn't
can be more
many british women
reacted with fear and anxiety panic and stop the pills
which led to unwanted
pregnancies and abortions
what did the study actually show
about which the news reported
it showed that out of every seven thousand women
who took the pill of the previous generation the second generation
let's rumble and polly and out of every seven thousand two
goal of the new generation that increased from one to two
one hundred percent
this is called the relative risk increase
it is
not transparent for the general public
because it doesn't specify a hundred percent of what
the same effect is one in seven thousand that's called an absolute risk increase
this is transparent for most of us
so here is another illustration that risk can become come
communicating in a transparent easy to understand way or in a way that's also correct
nobodies life
but it misleads most people in that particular case
this one was increased
number of abortions in england and wales in the following year by thirteen thousand
and it's not that the british public now understands the difference between relative and absolute
the fraction runs was
that british women lost their trust in the
what we need
in our society is
to change
the next generation
the basic concepts
about risk such as the difference between the absolute and relative risk
and moreover we need to teach them to live with uncertainty to enjoy uncertainty rather
than to feel it
and uncertainty is often enjoyed
when you watch the world championships in soccer games people don't know don't want to
know in advance
what the result will be
and in other areas
even twelve year-olds say american boys know baseball statistics by heart
but they don't don't know anything about CP is a
let me start
what do we do today is
i will
the report about
my own work
was doctors was health agencies
and the patients and this is an area
when you can see how important it would be
that we teach the general public
statistically thank you
now we teach lots of mathematics in schools
but we teach mostly mathematics of certainty
trigonometry geometry
what we need to teach the mathematics of uncertainty
statistical thinking is the most useful part of mathematics
for the world after school
but it's not talk this way
and it's often if it stored it taught in the way
that makes
the students who are curious
who want to know statistics
it makes them boring
and i think they can do
and the two largest area is in my opinion or that statistics is stored as
purely mathematical disciplines
it needs to be told us to problem solving this
take a problem from the real world
just mentioned you and then students can think
does this apply how can i solve that and also need to think about with
the assumptions hold
rather than having
the law of large numbers and then
provide only problems for the law of large numbers coins and was very interesting things
and the second thing is
often statistical thinking is taught with out regard
the human mind
and for some
for instance four
for the human mind some representations are easy to understand and as or not
we need to start with the easy understand representations not least those were mathematically convenient
in order to
that students get self-confident i can solve this and then i move on to the
more complicated what we often do it in the other way around
so let me introduce you to the world health
and i will today talk about two representations that mislead most
i hope also some of you
and then show you know what the representations
foster insight
and the first one
will be
five years survival rates
so and let me start with the summary of what i'm saying
well it doesn't work
i'm arguing that few physicians
politicians patients
understand health statistics
about patients no surprise
but the interesting point is that it also applies to physicians
and then there's a solution for the second
two of the major causes of
but the non transparent framing of information
so much of health statistic is framed in the way they are misled
that we face in school to teach
statistical thinking
i distinguished the decision thinking from statistical rituals
that are performed in the social sciences like p value
computations which are done in a mindless way
we need to teach our students to think is not to apply some
this is the problem
which is the solution
that to time dependent approaches
and also because of this new poetic flock computer so these allow us to treat
this reaction process
so what
what is the goal of these descriptions
so the goal is to have
a description which is as big as well as possible that cannot be completely have
been issued new graph is it's never been issue
because we don't know the nucleon nucleon interaction
so at what time we have
a few parameters OK these parameters are fixed but is not a big issue we
don't start from first principles from city whatever
but we try to do as i've been as possible
but also we want to give quantitative results because we want to have apps
we want to calculate observables that can be directly compared to experimental data we really
want to predict something that can be checked
so and what do we want to predict is everything that is related to the
so we want to describe the properties of the fissioning system so all the structure
for the that label to be sure that we
we really know what we are doing with this fissioning system we want to describe
also the time dependent evolution of the dynamical evolution
and then the properties of the fragments
so that the main goal
two has something going around
quantum mechanics
microscopic time dependent
description of the structure and the dynamics of the process
so what's missing in this description
so when i showed you that you had the energy
you have to go through this barrier
i think there are two things the first is that we don't have time evolution
so this is only something study that does a few
a flavour of what happened
and also here you just have one by corresponding to one fragmentation
but you have you see that you have fragment distribution so you can have different
fragmentation for the same fee simple process
so you can have
this is symmetric fission for asymmetric fission
so having a different probability is OK but you can have all these
process together so you should be able to describe the time evolution
all the different fragmentations
so that's why i presented now there
one of the last study that has been done concerning the description of the fission
fragments fission process
so these are the assumption of the calculation
so what people
i assume
that you can only consider a few degree of freedom in location asymmetry
and you can neglect higher order
vibrations so this is an assumption
but this assumption is we take
and it seems to be reasonable
but you can first consider elongation asymmetry and neglect the shapes which are more complicated
less exotic all our other people are
another assumption that is made here it's very important to be
the fact that you have two different timescales you have
the time scale for the fish and so for the collective motion i told you
that sufficient time is bigger than ten minutes nineteen seconds it's what we call slow
motion so
if we compare this time with the time needed for the nucleons to rearrange in
into clues it's one of the of my metre
so then that's why you can really separate and having two times so you consider
that you have a collective motion
and that it's time of the collective motion
you have the internet structure which is i particularly brilliant
in fact what you have behind you that you have neglecting all the internet citations
so you have the nucleons that
are at equilibrium
so that's why we have such away functions
so we have the wavefunction depending on time
that is the basis of a linear combination of basis states are used for studies
of nuclear properties of the nucleus depending on the different information
and then you do the time evolution
so what you do is the time evolution into a collective space i'm going to
explain that in more detail now
so to sum that to find that
so first you have to study
these cues to the basic state so you have to analyse the properties of the
nucleus when you impose different information like sufficient barriers but then it will be in
two dimensions the same
to c
what happens what is the energy
what is the response of the nuclei when you pose given information
so i presented yesterday the
the approach is just we managed to you
of this approach very rapidly so what you do is based on the minimization principle
where you minimize the energy
by and you impose at the same time some
a deformation here
so then when you have these basic state you have to determine the time evolution
so what you do here
he also minimize the energy so what is important here you minimize the actions
what is important is that you have the thermometer and so that's something you have
to keep in mind that when you
different steps in your calculation be sure that what you use in the second step
is going around what uses the first one so here is the same interaction
so the same
i mean that you have
otherwise you have the country
are you has various models about con thing that you really have to destroy away
so it's better to
to have complete calculation so to use the same
interaction and some ingredients
so then the equations are quite long but what is important is that he had
you have this time dependent equations for the propagation
so you have a collective hamiltonian containing here kinetic there
potential terror and you have here what we call zero point energy
it's because it's coming from quantum mechanics so you have to stations
these stations have here
to be introduced in the senate
this is what what he's done so these are the equation that is done so
other results that we can obtain with that kind of speculation
so when we look only at study
the study results we can have access to all the properties of the fissioning system
we can have also access to all the properties of the fragments
so that's what i'm going to talk after that first you will have to define
you go out you find instances of ravens
and they have the property of being black
and if you have also not of them then you say OK i'm strongly believing
in this hypothesis that all ravens are black
so what you do is
now you can abstract from it so if you see are instances this property b
enough of them and no counterexamples
when you say
this confirms
the implications are implies b
that's what you do in practice
in another instance of this rule
i mean because our nphs
any predicates
so let's look at not b implies not are i mean you just you know
replaced are going to be of formula
so that means that not be instances probably not our should then confirmed the rule
not b implies not because we can plug in for being things like
so next
we know that our implies b is logically equivalent to node b implies not our
so that means
and our
implies b instances
confirmed by
not being for with probably not
so according to the second rule
not be instances probably the
confirmed this rule but this really is logically equivalent to the first rule
these instances conference also
number one
so far so good
so now considered eclectic example so all ravens are black our hypothesis
and our brave and use black
i observing a black raven confirms
our hypothesis
most of you would agree
so now i will rules three
which is derived from one and two
that means that also observing white sox will confirm that all ravens are black
because white sox on non raven
which are not black
so they confirm that all ravens are black
which is very convenient if you live in the city just you know go to
draw and look at all the socks and then you can confirm you know some
biological rule
sounds a little bit of search
so i leave it homework
so what's going wrong here
i mean we care confined to kill also we can do that later
OK let me
formalise before and the philosophical part set up considering so first it's already mentioned you
can follow say that problems can all be expressed sequence prediction tasks
when to classification
it is also a special case of sequence prediction in classification you say a feature
and the class labels
so this
observation and another feature of the cluster features
class label now we a new instance feature vector you want to
predict the class label for each feature cluster to cluster class feature
for the first the sequence for problem
so as i mentioned the focus on maximizing profit
or minimize loss
just by the way we did we did not in the summer school so we
don't make any profits so actually they a new and victor heavily sponsored summer school
to keep the slow
four students
domain experts long-term profit maybe some of you want to come to the phd
OK so
i'm not primarily interested in finding a model
when the true model whatever this is or causal model
but in doing predictions or maximizing profit
one other thing you may ask during the lecture that never talk about noise and
useful data and separating them in this framework you don't need me to do that
so from this highly abstract point of view and this is purely sort of
practical problem
OK so i presented there
last week already
well it's good to repeat that
love to we work in
the one that has many former properties through logical character decisions and then the
the more structure in the examples i have tried
at some point maybe we try to
commercially the moment we are not
this is what happens with this sense of data
you have almost three thousand
but if you keep all rulers that
however the and you're left with one thousand only
and if you kill that are almost redundant you that the very efficient letters
you're not nearly enough to prior censorship was just
two hundred s
and this happened just by requiring that might work
has at least
five percent more confidence than the other is that look that similar to say similar
if you want them personal confidence here and
there's one that have substantially more
advanced understand most interesting ones
we will be
we're working with stuff that computes according to this mission in the
let me go on i promise to go back to the bias variance
the rest of an hour i
will likely
so what is this bias and variance things
and and therefore the other peak of father predictor step a planet mentioned will
sort of
very fast and we come back to it come back to me if you are
there are two sources of prediction error i'm thinking here now we know more about
traditional like task
and i know i'm sorry to say this i think you for this ask not
the method
ask just means that the predictions are real numbers
that's it
then there
several reasons several notches several biases
i don't look at any of them in concrete
looking just at the statement of the desk as simple as possible here is a
number of of observations each of them has an answer responsibility were
what value which is a real number
and the later we can infer that point in which i have to make a
prediction of the random
and i don't
well for the family
the model
one of the risk of making a mistake
is that you may happen to be so lucky
that you have something that doesn't reflect that
values of the
i mean did do make up or of a number of people so finding out
the hate weights and you happen to make europe more and that they can only
assume we his family
then december will not reflect the whole population it is probably too independently higher
not so with
that's too much weight
you cannot go out there is
of course i think there are people in your work
it's but you are the BOSS approach is very low but it's possible
so this surface there
given that the this ambiguity
and the parameters you find from december
not really many closed
so there
clark population value
well this is the variance of the statistic
but in this analysis of imagine that i only
i will give
the weight of up as shown in four kilogrammes
well then i will be committing an error is somebody who is seventy and has
or if i wouldn't be giving the hate of people only in matters
then many people will be one method and many people will be two meters
then somebody comes in and they predict from one of the things that this a
woman in his one forty nine
they they hit
one hundred years because it was
the best i could do but not really because it's
very far away
so they set this kind of
that comes from the family of hypothesis is the hypothesis families
not very wide
we may be the best one is not very well
what do you want of course you want to reduce the risk
want to reduce the risk
and if any point is that
they compete against each other
you want to predict some value y you have some samples s
which reveals some information about the body hard to predict
and then if
your favourite only here it looks at the
and as you might candidate for what is
the output of the estimator on understand
what is the variance
you will be
the quadratic coverage
of the estimator
using as estimator of its own avinash
it's held how far you have
from your avinash
of the two of the estimators
because you need to see all they use only the sum
you compare what you have seen
and the output it did you get
and you are what you would get if you have actual or something else
i expected square
now what's the bias
the bias is even if the estimator with
you know they don't have the expectation of the average surface
wouldn't that be right
maybe the estimator is not going to heat anyway even if all the
seventy one we have shown that washu or something
and note that this quantity is independent of the sample is just expectations and the
outcome we want
also there is a difference of scabies square here is not square here so we