a bunch of different models as the field it's become clear that there is at
least two different things you could mean by that the correspond to two basic kinds
of of learning in graphical models what you can think of as parameter estimation and
what you can think of the structure learning psychologists have have talked about judgement of
call strength which are like basically estimates of parameters in a graphical model that represents
the strength of the relationship
and also judgments structure whether a link exists if you like in in a graphical
model so here's a very simple graphical model for this problem we have our two
variables see e we're going to assume that we that we know that he's into
cause of c and also that trees and say a hidden common cause it's just
either seconds you're it doesn't
that's that's the that's the set of here and there's there's also is going to
be some background variables and background cars which is not observed but but without loss
of too much generality we can assume it's just always present and it has some
strength w zero and that's important because there's going to be some cases when the
cause is isn't present in the effect still happen so something has to of course
so the question is either in the model where there's these two causes what's the
strength of the observable
potential cost c or or more structural question is there link for CD and then
you're asking to compare these two hypotheses
so the
the state of the art say
up to about ten years ago in psychology consisted of various
simple rules that people gave for combining the cells of this two by two contingency
table if you like of these different conditional probabilities there was what one classic measure
basically correspond to statistics that you might compute in traditional statistics three computers to you
compute a statistic on your sample and check whether it significantly different from what you
get by chance and that sort of thing one popular model was called delta p
which is just the difference in the conditional probability of effect occurring given that the
cause occurs and the conditional probability effect occurring given current doesn't occur a lot of
progress was made with when the psychologist had chain proposed this other measure called causal
and derived from interesting set of axioms which now we recognise as basically a noisy
or causal model get the i mean causal here in pretty lights and if you
guys talk about noisy or or do people know that conversation killed it's not that
important but it's basically a model which says the effect happens it's a probabilistic generalization
of of or function effect happens if this variable is present or that girls present
in each one of those urls has an independent chance to cause the effect and
either one or both of them succeed in causing it then it happens
so it's like we know the probability from here plus their minus the product
and what it's not too hard to show that both of these measures are called
strength estimation correspond to maximum likelihood estimates of the w one parameter in this very
simple graphical model
the only difference is what's the parameterisation and there's a slightly strange linear parameterisation which
gives you this delta p but the the noisy OR is is probably the most
natural parameterisation people in bayesian networks have used and that that gives you the causal
power estimate now another approach which which tom and i looked at
was inspired by bayesian model selection and we were thinking well actually none of these
cases the the most fundamental judgement is not
to start off with the strength of the consolation but does the causal relation exists
at all so we
oppose that as the as the following kind of model selection then we said let's
take the model that underlies this this causal
power causal power metric this
this model in which this is noisy or relation and there's per strength parameter for
the cars and then let's compare to a model which is doesn't have that so
it's space this is basically just a simple
coin flipping model
and in the traditional bayesian model selection way we're going to do two things were
going to first of all we're going to compute this bayes factor essentially the log
likelihood ratio under for these two models
and we're going to do this in a way which is just sensitive to the
difference in structure so that means integrating out the parameters in this case integrating out
this what the strength of the back and cars and here also in out the
strength because we're asking in the bayesian sense how much evidence is there for this
structure over that structure independent of the strength of course the stronger the causes there's
going to be an interaction the stronger the cause then the the easier it is
to see evidence for its existence in a small sample and all of these experiments
are done with very small sample sizes
problem is that all you need priors on the parameters yes so here we that's
that's exactly the question so here we we're
it's been so
you can either see this as a problem or serve as a feature
in bayesian model selection
the year year
you're your inferences about which model is correct are going to be sensitive to the
functional form of the model as well as the priors you put on there even
though you integrating out the parameters
it's it's true that it's not it's not purely a judgement about the existence of
of the dependency but it does depend on on your prior and here for simplicity
we just chose a uniform prior but some the recent work has shown like hunting
lu and alan newell and keith holyoak and others having a non-union an interesting kind
of non uniform prior might
might make this better
with david thanks tom and i also showed something kind of like
is that the answer because
but here yes we're assuming just uniform parameters uniform prior over so that you know
in the noisy OR
these parameters i guess i really didn't tell you enough detail to know those things
are in the noisy OR these parameters vary between zero and one because they're just
the the probability that on its own each of these variables would cause the effect
and so the priors is uniform over the interval zero one
OK so when we do that here's here's the results of
applying these three different models the two parameter estimation models and this model selection
model a lot of the bayes factor model for two two data from
a classical behavioral experiment that patching did with mark now so when we talk about
data here in a lot of the experiments and to talk about we mean two
different we could mean two different things there the data that the human learner season
and is the data that we have this psychologist measure from the human world to
the data the human learners across the top here and then these bar bar graphs
are plotting the behavioral data from the human subjects in the design of the experiment
was very simple
there were i think a bunch of different conditions always sixteen trials like sixteen different
mice were either injected with a chemical or not
and i think it was always the mice were injected mice were not injected there
different chemicals in different genes and so on and they varied just very simply and
in steps of probability point two five all the possible conditional probabilities the effect given
the causes of the present and the probability of the event given the cause was
absent so for example in this case here point seven five point two five that
was a case where six of the mice that were injected
express the gene and two of the mice were not injected express the gene and
subjects were asked to judge on a scale of zero to one hundred to what
extent are the very very different versions of the question but something like to what
extent does this
injectors does this chemical cause the gene to be expressed and on a scale of
zero to hundred you get these sorts of ratings these are standard errors
so you can see
well first of you can see the kind of thing that the animated to be
you know literally for ten years in psychology between proponents of these two models basically
each of these models here explains one trend in the data but not the other
so there's an overall effect of increasing delta p that means to do so these
are organised into blocks here that was not transparent to but there are organised into
blocks where there's you know of increasing difference in these conditional probabilities and the simple
delta p model predicts that that's really the only factor indeed you can see the
overall trend but is also this trend within each of these blocks this is decreasing
downward thing here although it's a little bit
not decreasing there but a little more u-shaped but OK basically that that that that
you are you
i nineteen eighty
a lot
there are no
come on as
i mean
and it
we see all of these local
you i
so o
in two
we will
he was it is
o are
all right
the station
i one
all right
this is
one hundred
well on the wall
o thing is figuring out how much money should be paid for that
what is the market price of a given
and so interior mechanism design all of these problems come up in microeconomics shows up
in this problem
it's essentially
computational advertising is this holistic approach to all of these different problems
but they have all these problems mean sorry
so is computational advertising is all of these problems special constraints the constraints which we
just looked at it has to operate on a massive scale and it has to
be low marginal cost to you
and so should be very fast very weak
and it should operate a with huge amounts of
and this is also the algorithms that we already have in the literature forty six
don't typically scales so much
and this is where we have to come up with better algorithms
do all of these things and the massive scale of the
we look at many different instantiations of online for many different ways online advertising works
but overall it's good to have this big picture of what exactly is online advertising
who are the key players in the world of this money flow through the process
and so on
so at one end we had to use it
the user comes to
two some website
looking for somebody particular
and the content provider also known as the website published who provides
the same publisher is providing on the attractors they like one basis to make some
money of of these users
and the other end of the scale
the advertisers
we will show that products
the users they want to use this to know about the products companies they want
to use this knowledge especially on promotions and so on
the users not really
one of the basis for states to
so there is a mismatch between these
and this is one the network
aggregates all sorts of different at different
things from many different places to achieve economies of scale and the massive scale that's
necessary to make online advertising work
and then
at time when the user to content providers
and related performance one going back to the
the weights
and the work can be induced show along quite
just rolled back the user
and if this
that was shown to the user is so successful
the definitions of success
if based on the on what settings to use but if the actual was successful
then there are these these
the of the fraction of the money comes from
so essentially the users have been using a second that as it is happened because
it shows
in the middle man called right at point happy because the money or decide
and there are several examples of networks typically these other search engines
yahoo MSN and so on but they need not be just as changes for instance
there was
i media you say
which was just a big market place
the question is
but anyone can be in at what if the aggregate if effect at
they can represent many different users
again the point
right maybe even aside any england any that's a publisher
it because these also search engines because
search engines can show as in addition to the search results
but it's may not be just the second
but essentially these are the four different actors and this on in using it
the uses this on the related
all stuff
most of them will be from the point of view network because that's where most
of the hard problems
but it can also think of problems from the basis for human soul
and within this particular setting
this broad framework that very nice
seven special cases so for instance you might have heard of
something like sponsored search content match display advertising so i will discuss what these things
are we provide a reasonable reasonably in that background on the advertising industry
and after that
we discuss what we believe to be the
fundamental statistical problems
in this online advertising competition
we need something to several different sub problems
for each image
provide some reasonable descriptions
what people do
to solve this problem at present
this solution solutions score about what the point we point what the challenges for the
open problems
will discuss all of these
o thing was from this and that
business is that there are so many the problems
OK there is a lot of it for improvement and even
and the big business
so let's start with the background knowledge
you need to samples the matrix
you need to get the number of entries which is proportional to coherence and in
fact the number of entries need to be proportional to this geometric parameters the clear
standard degrees of freedom standard factor and if you sample at a number of entries
which is below this number
and then nothing will work
no algorithm on will work
OK so we can assume from now on that the coherence is small so it's
order one
and so when the coherence small that is when we have a non sparse principal
components than what the theorem says that for any method to work i need to
see the number of entries which is the dimension of the matrix times the rank
which we think about as it really number of degrees of freedom
in the matrix times the luck factor
OK so then we know what we can do and then what is it that
we can do well
well so not give me samples at random from a low rank matrix maybe the
coherence is the singular vectors are not crazy so something can be done
what is it going to do
well what i would want to do
that i would want to minimize i would say well you know i'm looking for
rank low rank matrix one largest just rises and try to find me matrix was
minimum rank that fits the data i have just
and that's a very good idea that's what you should be doing
the problem is as i'm sure most of you know
i can i do not have the right to talk about this because it's a
NP hard problem so NP hard
i don't even know what that means minhash announces because the videotaped i know what
i i know what is NP hard
this is this is the problem with state lectures you cannot really speak the way
you want to speak
np hard no i know what that means
what it means practically it means in this case that can also problem when the
dimensions of the metric system by ten
because the best are reasons we know to actually minimize rank under equality constraints
is doubly exponential in n
so maybe you were very hard on the supercomputer and you can do any course
ten what that means you cannot do any cause eleven
OK so we cannot do it so we can talk about it
so what we do instead is we're going to minimize and also norm which is
in some sense proxy for the rank
and that normally is well we can to minimize the sum of the singular values
of the matrix right that's norm is called the nuclear norm has nothing to do
with nuclear physics it's actually harmless norm you minimize the sum of the singular value
subject to the same constraints
had to people know what is the nuclear norm is the first time you see
not because if it's you have seen it many times and i i be happy
to skip
it is some of the singular values of the matrix
so first of all i'm sure
everybody knows what and one norm
and why do we use the l one norm
because it's a good proxy for
l zero
here the same thing it's the l one norm of the singular values it's a
good proxy for the LCO norm of the singular value but what is an zero
norm of the singular value
it's around
so the l one norm is a good proxy for the ranks now there's one
way which is much more sophisticated to see it and i'm going to try to
draw a picture and the picture is this which is that
the way i think about this is the one norm personally
if that i look at sparse vectors
right so
we scored in a plus and minus one so here's the answer for them because
they can only drawing the plane and what the one ball is
that's another way to see that is the tightest convex relaxation of an as problem
with the l one ball is it's actually is the tightest convex bodies contain sparse
and that's why we use l one norm because it's the smallest convex body contains
very sparse vectors
of norm one
the nuclear norm is exactly like this i cannot draw a unfortunately but nuclear norm
is exactly like this and i can look at the well what are very low
rank matrices was is the rank one matrices we say norm less than one i
see what's the convex body is the smallest convex bodies contains among and that's a
nuclear bomb
OK so in that sense the nuclear norm is the tightest relaxation of the
the the rank function
just like the n one is the tightness relaxation of the elves your functions now
it's not obvious that the sum of singular values is the normal and i don't
know if you have a slide about this no i don't have a fight about
this i will say though is that the nuclear norm
the l one norm for those of you know the one norm is the dual
too easy
n infinity norm
and the and the dual to the nuclear norm is going to be dual two
the maximum
i think value which is the usual matrix norms the operator norm and so what
i claimed that the nuclear norm x star
is actually is the supremum over all matrices of norm
and there's lots of things you might want to put their
let me
go back
and mention this is generated other random problem
earth generate
i don't have to have all ones here
for example
the ones that were already in the right sign why worry about them they don't have to be perturbed
those are not to be perturbed this doesn't have to be perturbed
and this doesn't have to be perturbed
i could do that's sure try it
like a star like that because my original claim is still correct for mu large
this is okay
fact my little m you've calculated thing down here
indicates that it's okay
all right now i got lots of ties everything
is that u equals to that's kinda boring but that's the way it is
well let's pick w five is the leaving variable i could pick any of them
the reason i think now is because i look across this role here
i see only one negative number and that's
text field not grow inside of the duty ratios the figure out that x one
would have to be the entering variable
so i click that's
we had all ties and that creates degeneracy
and the degeneracy degeneracy is manifest by the fact that now mu
has to be between two into some rather than being
and was some extent that interval has collapsed to a single point
that's what happens
in this context when you get degeneracy but the algorithms i showed you this morning we could have degeneracy and
we did degenerative it's in
we saw that there could be a problem
rare that a problem
we can have the generative it's here but the algorithm doesn't change so we still
formally do the same thing so i ask myself what giving me this lower bound
and i believe it's this column here because this is to
should be less than or equal to zero this says mu is greater than equal to
so w five is the entering variable and look down this column for
fields that a positive number in the text fields the three and the four candidates
let's see where do already showing here
one minus six plus
three times to a six that's zero that's the degeneracy
that's the choice
so acutely generative because that's the one
and it's getting and because this is the a positive number here this is an
issue we're going to degenerative it
right here
and i don't really have any choice
so it stays it who
because we did a degenerative it and now let's look at this thing
if you're gonna cycle what do you think
it's possible
so we have
minus two
plus mu should be greater than zero means you're is critical to and this means
mu is very common to i got two choices again and
look at this one
this one has all minus signs
o that's doesn't help because the dual pivot those are all good
i this one has all plus signs
this rule right here tells me
primal invisible
okay so this problem a bit easier than it might have been but anyway it's
what is
this particular problem primal feasible
so the point is that of course is that i didn't have to start with
all ones here and all ones there
like a star how i like
sometimes they may be motivated to not totally models to be zero because that makes fewer calculations fewer
these inequalities write down there could be useful
there are other reasons to like doing networks
which i will mention right now
we can put them anywhere we like i just showed you one way
let me
tell you why
the most important reason the most important that the best way of picking these things
pick them randomly
if i randomly pick those perturbations independently and identically distributed doesn't have to be identically
distributed independently of each other are you to the density
well on the real line
so that the distribution you know
i mean randomly like one and two with probably have i mean randomly with the density
on the real line
so that to the mean equals like an event of probability zero
if you pick them randomly and independently so that's
pairs of them being
equal or in given
any given linear combination given being equal to something specific has probability zero
if you do that's
then you'll never
never encountered degeneracy
because the only way you can have degeneracy
is if
you get a linear combination of these perturbations due these particular combinations of his original
perturbations in degeneracy means to rose coming exactly the same there's two different linear combinations
of these
of these random variables in the same value that's probably zero event
so randomized perturbation is
perfect way of solving the degeneracy problem
i totally recommend
and of course as is clearer the perturbations don't have to be small
i chose ones
by default
there are to be small they can do whatever you like
so it's not what these numerical things we perturb
by a little bit
to make things look o u protuberance
and change the problem these provisions are changing the problem because these perturbations galway when mu equals zero
so some some algorithms proposed in for various things will reduce perturbation methods review
change the problem to make it
and the change is fundamental and therefore the change must be small
here the changes parametric and so it's not fundamental change goes away and after melody
and so that the perturbation doesn't have to be small
end in the optimal dictionary the perturbations completely gone so there's no need to do
any kind of removing things having artificial objectives and getting rid of them and this
and that's it just goes away musical those are only just ignore r
those roles in those columns
in some real world problems i will talk a little bit more about this later probably not today monday
and natural perturbate perturbation exists
and obviously i call this slide from my
lectures at princeton and forgot to remove this comment
how but i will
the next lecture
gives a natural perturbations
can also be average case performance this algorithm has an interesting analysis which i will will talk about today
okay there's only six
reasons not ten my mistake
so right when we have reached a fundamental inflection point that's gonna require why change
nobody's told the kids
so i wrote this book
to tell at least to kids
orally and actually free
what world i think they are going to grow up
and the world i said many times when i grew up in minneapolis my parents
demeton finish dinner people in china and india are starving
and i tell my girls girls finish your homework
because people in china and india are starving for your jobs
and in a flat world they can have them
there's no such thing as an american job anymore
so let me simply conclude with
and inside the prison part to be by carly fiorina from each be before she
lost a job
currently got all this actually might not know about the business side but she was very smart
about all this
she said to me you know tom everything we called i ti revolution
the information technology revolution these last twenty years
sorry to tell you
that's just the warm-up act
that's just been the sharpening forging
forging sharpening and distribution
the tools of collaboration
into this new platform
we are not just at the end of the beginning
what you are now about the sea
is the real
i ti revolution
so friends fasten your seatbelts and put your seat backs entry tables into a fixed
an upright position
because the world is
thank you very much
thank you
i know it's time for some questions and left a lot learn
i want favor students if i could so if you're a student you get yeah
so that all this is an important question about the question was unlikely doing a book signing afterwards and
the answer is yes and
thank you so much for asking
no words africa fitting where were always hold underdeveloped world on that until this and
two chapters in the book i just giving you the first you know the next
part about what it means for american last part what it means for developing world
on and for geopolitics
end on
the chapter on the developing world so to and i just go really quickly answer
questions the first is called the virgin of guadalupe there
and what happened was a research in the book like travel the world and i
can have is asking people on where we you when you discover the world is
it's very interesting to me people's answers so
i was in on
come and talk the some
friends the central bank there
and i think that's what the world was
let me know is the next thing is the central bank and
they were on
they so we discovered the world is flat on last year when you know art
patron saint in mexico virgin quite
last year we discovered that all kinds of statuettes of the virgin guadalupe they would be imported from china
when you worried
low-wage developing country in europe patron saint has been imported from china
the world is flat
the point about this i'm trying to make and this is
a serious point
i do the same thing with an egyptian friend who talked about how on
ramadan lanterns which are stable from donkey carry them around around
on the now all the important this is a thousand year-old in egypt going back to the fact
and then i'll be imported from china with a micro chip that plays the latest egyptian folk songs
so what is it about when the world gets flat the slightest variation
you know in your r flatness relative to another country
can take a country like mexico
from being right on the border
a thousand miles away
the country like china
thousand miles away thousand miles away
to write a report
and so what i really talk about in the chapter is
that's what the nineties were about
it seems to me was what are called form wholesale
macroeconomic reforms in your sorry
open your economy to the world trade
and things about like
but really what the two thousands are gonna be about is reforms there was a
formal wholesale is a two thousand they can be more about reforming retail
but what actually
businesses started
there's a wonderful study the world bank is then called doing business two thousand
for actually looked at five categories
one hundred countries
i think i get it right on five questions on how long does it take
to get a license to start a business
take three days are under needed is how much does it cost
how easy is it to hire fire people
how easy is it to raise capital on how easy is it to get a
legal dispute commercial dispute adjudicated how much money this cost and how easy is it
to go bankrupt
because report you easy free up their capital
in order to plant life things and they did a whole scheme is a fascinating
and has no effect because it goes through q and g has no effect because
it goes through q
so it is only one force
after the talk
this radius is or
magnitude is f
in the direction
it's in the back but i'm more interested in the magnitude for now
so i get on
defection of force
must be i all five
i being the moment of inertia
for rotation about this axis will point q
times of
but i can replace
o five by a divided by or
so i get the moment of inertia
about q
thanks a divided by are
this is my first equation
and i have as an unknown
the frictional force
and i have as an unknown a so i cannot solve for both
i need another equation
the next equation that i have is an obvious one that is newton's second law
because i a
for the centre of mass
i can consider all the mass right here at q
we must have because
and so
times the acceleration of that point q which is our goal by the way
he called
this component
he calls and j
sign beta
that is the component
and minus ff
frictional forces
which is the component uphill
this is my creation
number two now i have two equations
two unknowns
i can solve now i can eliminate ff
and i will substitute for f f in here
this quantity
divided by or
so i get any
calls and g
sign data
moment of inertia
point q
times a
divided by squid
now notice
i've eliminated f of f
so now i can solve for a
so i'm going to get a ph to one side
so i get eight times and
moment of inertia
divided by or scraped
sign data
and a now
we have
both sides which are squared
i squared
sign beta
and downstairs i get m are squared
moment of inertia
but the point q
this is my result
all i have to put in now
it is the
moment of inertia
of rotations about that axis
i want to remind you though
it is only through
if we have a situation
of europe
so we can now substitute in there
the values
that we have four
a solid cylinder
if we have a solid cylinder
then the moment of inertia
about this axis through the centre of mass which i've called q
equals one half
and are spread
and if i substitute that in here
notice that all my name's emma squares go away
i get one plus one half which is
one and a half
upside down becomes two thirds
so a
because two thirds
times g
i'm sign of data
there is no and
there's no l
and there is no or
so if i have
two cylinders solid cylinders
was totally different mass totally different radii totally different length and they have arrays
need one wins
very nonintuitive
every time that i see it i find it kind of amazing
notice that everything disappears and
are nl disappear
for those of you
well said that if i take two sort of this is the same as
different radii those of you who said that there is no winner there's no loser
they were correct but even more
amazing is that even the mass you can change you can change anything as long
as the two so this isolet
that's what matters
so if we take a hollow cylinder
then the moment of inertia
about this axis only centre of mass q
if this is really most of the mass is really at the surface
then it's very close to MR cigarette
and then the acceleration
by substituting here and ask where i get to their
because one half times g
sign beta
so this acceleration
it's less than this one
the hollow cylinder will lose
in any race
against a solid cylinder regardless of mass regardless of radius regardless of
and i want to show that to you
the set up here
and i'll try to
so that to you
also on
the screen there
but for those of you who are sitting close
it's probably much better
but you just look at the demonstration right here
i have here
to start with a very heavy cylinder made of brass
and this one is made of aluminum
they have
very different masses same really i seem like should make no difference there should be
no winner there should be no lose
i'm going to start off
at the same time
i hope you can see that there this is
this is the starting point
the lower the little
i will come down
three two zero
and then you can see that they
reach the bottom almost at the same time
very different in masses mass differences at least a factor of three
or dimensions at the same
one zero
thank mister
i nonintuitive for me
now i have one
that has a very small radius
compared to this one this is an small small aluminum wrought
maybe you can see here
television this is way more heavy almost thirty times heavier
would make no difference as long as it's solid
you may no difference no winner loser radio different masses and different
to make no difference
we start the race
two one zero
and then hit the bottom
the same time now
here i have whole one
i i believe that this whole
and all the mass is at this conference
now it takes more time
only acceleration
as you
as you will see
is half empty sunbathe
in munich was two-thirds
you may want to think about it and i like this one takes more has
to do with cause
with the
moment of inertia
but again
can instantiate the dependent
i think that
o point is and again petrol with more details about that
you can now make use of these structure so they lifted inference technique that never
actually built this graph model and
so you just do inference to say on the lifted on the abstract level so
that you get even and service which does depend on the domain size so that
you get a constant and so no matter how many
how many people there are more
on the other hand the other one the weighted CNF is coming from the fact
that already each
it's it's well known from the satisfiability community people have been
work not just using satisfiability problem but where you wait the different
clauses in there
and then giving cost three it and you want to find an assignment with minimal
costs right and of course
they can also be viewed as actor
so this is a a little bit more from the logic with a little bit
of probabilities in there if you have only one way to close this is a
very natural if you want to have a factor of topic associated with class then
maybe the particles in a bit more interesting but in the end you can convert
between right you can always transform between them and again
there's a lot of redundancy in there that you can make use at inference time
the speed
so given that
so what is the current state the state is the following
it's good to combine probability and logic because if a few more compact models
because there are more complex sometimes you can do inference much faster because you can
stay at the club
similar for learning
because you are an abstract level you don't have to learn each rule for each
person again
and then in the long run
you converge and you say yeah i know there
essentially i don't know you you can play the additional constraint test that this rule
for people because of that
well not in any complexity theory it's faster but it may be faster and learning
because instead of bottom-up trying to figure out all these little
potential are identical you go top down and if there's a lot of regularity then
you're actually faster by testing only few of his childhood
and how have people than that well they use what is known in logic and
learning these kinds of logical model the old inductive logic programming where you want to
find these kinds of programs give you examples
like the molecules are mutagenic yes or no and these molecules are complex
these right so you can have as many items and that described here you may
have and you may have one hundred at so you have applied flexible representation and
you one given that you want to learn
these kind of programs for very very similar you can only learn these probabilistic relational
models and even if you're happy to stay with this similar
very basic learning algorithm how would you do it let's have an example edit classical
algorithm ILP inductive logic programming not integer linear programming algorithms
four by quinlan
how is he doing that well very easily
that was no
and then you start really in the down when systematic way you just to redefine
what you have to replace all possible predicate
you can think of in their test
right so so for example you made a c which means that the type for
mother happen at
in the molecule
another one and then using one or whatever heuristic have all scoring function
in our case we may use likelihood
turns out will not work in most cases you may use pseudo likelihood of conditional
likely but you score them and then in the greedy fashion her climbing you select
the best one try to refine you do that as long as you can get
that at some point you stop your your first one
and then you start learning the next two and then you start learning the network
so essentially this idea of ILP of systematic search
in your space of i part this this is also done anaphora of course are
much more improved nowadays that the
but the only difference is that
in contrast to ILP where we are using
we thought that we were hearing once you're essentially looking at the disjunction you're not
dealing with probability right because you assume independence in let's say among year molecules among
year examples so you just have a product there
and then you get something
so that's the main difference because you have let's say markov logic network is the
markov logic network to do score
that's the main difference from the very high level so this concludes
almost no delay
the first part
so the idea now is that many of the things that may be confused with
hopefully reach find by doing the same exercise but now with this concrete specific example
namely michael logic and that's what
OK so christian just give you a very broad view of the few field of
statistical relational AI the goal now is to get more concrete
pick one specific language
and look at the representational gets an inference and learning algorithms
and look at some computer applications
and then i will conclude with a little bit of discussion
so i'm going to do this is i'm going to start from logic and build
towards being able to do logic probabilistic and i will do it within the first
representation and inference and learning
so let's start
with logic
and the simplest form of logic is propositional logic and as an that everybody has
to be more or less familiar with this so this will be fairly brief but
in propositional logic we start with atoms atoms are symbols that represent propositions about the
and they either either true or false
and then out of those lists
small sentences build larger sentences in logic using connectives like negation conjunction disjunction and so
and then
all of our knowledge we call it a knowledge base it's a set of formulas
that state what we know what we've learned
and then we call a world
or possible world or interpretation a truth assignment to all the atoms
that we can form
by by by doing this truth assignment i have just added everything that could possibly
know about the world
what we're going to be interested in here is
probability distributions over truth assignments possible
another thing that we're going to be making use of the fact that every knowledge
base can be converted into standard form called CNF conjunctive normal form
a CNF is a conjunction of clauses clause is the disjunction of literals
and the literal is an atom or its negation
so i can take my knowledge base turn the crank and into CNF and this
makes a lot of things easier
and usually the way we do things in logic is by asking entailment queries
but you asked they also had two lots of interesting things to understand what's actually
going on document isolate parts the head of a research paper to understand what is
the title
who the authors were authors located when was it published
and they also look at the citations section of the paper to recover the individual
citations and build the citation graph
so using information extraction this sort of
i can do some canonicalisation normalisation and you can then see quickly
good referencing this paper and what paper what i like to see next
i will come back to this main actually little bit throughout the talk because i
think it's really interesting applications
the really interesting
ideas and they should convince you i hope that information extraction is going to be
a great driver of things to come in the world but i don't want to
step back a little bit in formalise what i think of
as information extraction and i'm going to use this example which is just as little
snippet of the web page
the a company called buzzmetrics which is the company used to sort of work for
but that list the
members of their of that company
so the the sort of i think of information extraction really having
three components that are sort of probably definable in the first is just recovering the
individual data items are you want from format text rain so in this particular example
europol imagine that you are interested in identifying people names and job titles friends so
you might have
a person name extracted job titles structure and we can leave aside from the
the moment whether those are actually separate things are whether somehow combine together
but you broadly you hope that what you will recover from this green being the
names and orange being the
titles question
on the
right so only a degenerate case to format text is something that comes with no
right and there
what about
i'm going to talk to
the more gifted towards
free text generally if you have something that
highly structured you might use some sort of wrapper induction techniques which are not going
to talk about two much today
but in general even even text that is in ask e
has format you can for example your ICC filings have tables
the presented in straight asking right and there is sort of implicit format going on
there in terms of
rows and columns
even if it's not
immediately obvious even if it represented in sort of a sequence of characters
so the second important thing that i think about for information extraction is understanding the
relations between the fields that you've extracted right so in particular here you have a
bunch of names and job titles but that each data is associated with exactly one
person in rain so in this case we're tracking out several fields of the same
instance and there are multiple instances
you can hear referred to as record association
but more generally in something like that table for example
right there are more interesting semantic relationships going on than just simple records
and so more probably to understand what are the relations between things are extracted
and lastly an important part is the result of those two processes gives you a
bunch of records or more generally something else but
you want to be able to do normalisation de duplication
so for example in the in the previous slide down here this guy james OK
well there are other james o'hara is out there on the web one from IMDB
and this is actually a very different person in this james o'hara
right well this jim o'hara from some random piece of the web
is actually the same person you i think senior vice president you know for VNU
media measurement that close enough
but you ought to be able to put my confidence that these two people are
the same in these two people are different
so that's normalisation yet and deduplication
given that we do seven out talk almost exclusively about field identification which is just
extracting out the sort of named entities are other types of fields you might be
interested in
i know
thank you very much so
you may have practiced exactly my next slide
now two sides from right so
i poses as a machine learning problem and generally for today anyway we assume that
what you're more interested in extracting we know ahead of time sort of told us
so it's sort of a finite set of slots we want to fill
there has been some work more generally sort of extracting
sort of general purpose relations from things like the whole web and the web as
a whole and maybe tom will touch on some of stuff
this talk later but i don't know
so there's a bunch of history how information extraction got about
i don't want to talk about it too much basically started with a bunch of
hand coded rule type techniques and then sort of transitioned into machine learning and there
are the sort of two
approximate parallel tracks one which dealt
now with text-based sorts of things like news articles
and then another track which is more the wrapper induction sort of approach to tell
structured web pages and this sort of
you know what the
all sure
all of work
we can put longer call
so we have
computational model compression model it's idea
what we are expecting to get from data i will give you have you give
you two examples
from this model we are getting some estimation
is this current state of data what we're getting from stream
is it proper or not
and the using something called the
that gives you more probable state less the
and to less probable states small b
in this case average with the average length of this message will be minimal
but if you are doing this
because it forms more
probable states have more states have more short called
and if you have
a real estate using longer cause but there and we don't have a lot of
there is almost a month behind this and you can prove that all the algorithms
are optimal using our assumption
and this second one according to this is entropy
so we have some
alphabet alphabet is alphabet of state
how old data can be present
and they have some probability distribution for a real estate
and they are doing
minimalism corning minimalism b
as out
and again there are a lot of very good literature on this topic beginning from
a very practical one for a programmer how to implement all this stuff out how
to do in coordinates creek models
and ending with a a very very difficult things when people try to
combine this series such high-level philosophical machine learning approaches like minimalist description something like this
but we will consider for example
for example
i have according
we are going so
trying to create a collection
from documents
that i e
that use
very small for i don't know my maybe
some language from polynesian islands where people using small number but i don't know about
four letters and about fourteen little
following system three but OK for matching the
we have only four letters in the alphabet
and the calculated probability of every letter
and as a kid are going to
present all this that and memories such weight
that we are using
the smallest number of b
and what we started to do is starting to do
all our our this over the distribution
so that's a kcnd is less probable one
let's combine them together and create not on the street
so what we have after the
after this we have to be as less probable we combine them to create this
the only one left is a and b portrait created history
now we started
why is this story from left to right and when are going last
we are putting zero
and when are going to write forty one
and after this regenerated generated called well for this for this alphabet
four eight will be zero
only one the very good so
and probabilities
o point six is
very close to to optimal distribution
that there's a dying event
it's of dying is verb done shopping is now
it's the subject of dying the when of the dying in february
nineteen nineteen ninety seven
the dying happened at the age of ninety two
and the dying was from
and the line is related to the infection
it doesn't actually know what did the infection
because i wasn't stated in the text
but that's the kind of depth that are system is going to here
and then we see that the separately the influence of him
is continuing
now over here
representation the facts that are extracted
all the way down here
all the way down to the individual words facts the system knows for diseases and
influence and so on
similarly here is the analysis of surrender he died from pneumonia
at nineteen thirty in the evening seventeen july two thousand five at the age of
eighty nine
so we see that there is a dying event
and the winners or out of the event is eighty nine
the subject is he's
here's when get when that happens the from his pneumonia
and it happened in the evening of july
if we look down here lower down
where we see these the word facts the system is using in the index
we see the pneumonia
is known to be a respiratory disease characterized by inflammation of of the lung
it's also wrote a disease affecting the rest courses to more general level of abstraction
it's a disease
it's an illness
it's a form of ill health or health problem and so on
it's also to pathological state
where is that coming from
that is partly having from from wordnet
so here's wordnet if we look at pneumonia
and we're looking at the
i think we're looking here at the inherited
hypernyms of pneumonia
we see the pneumonia is arrested tree disease
this disease is an illness so
this is showing how we're taking an open community resource
an ontology
namely wordnet
and the system is actually using that in its interpretation of text both the user's
query and the passages to enrich his knowledge and then using that to do a
whole new level of match
now what about the danger of things we ask for a politician and we got
back then jumping well that's actually coming from another resource in this case that's coming
coming from freebase freebase is a website put up by a company called metaweb
and industry related to
other open structured data projects like BPD the people in this community may be more
familiar with
users so
users are able to come into this resource and basically
the fields for all different types of entities and objects and express relationships so
it's again it's like like the motivation behind wikipedia but in this case we're editing
structured semantic content
so in this case you danger paint is a person is deceased person
he has professional politicians
people filled in his cause of death and his spouse
along with the description here
the final results
and the top little bit an overview of
how we can
mind these patterns
jumping emerging patterns
and that i give you
a gene club border differential talk about that
and then the incremental mining algorithms i'm going to talk about that i give you
one real example
we have
you know
well my one of my phd students after completing
he's done some really nice work
applied work he has done
which is making a big difference
in particular
clinical case
and i talk about the tree based algorithms and projection based algorithms
and then
zbdd which is a binary decision diagrams
and the by
bioinformatics applications like cancer study marker and so forth
so there's a lot of work done in this area you know it's not just
group lots of people are also looking at
class based association rules what people have done is
by fixing the
the class has a an association rules
as the target object and try to find out what are the frequent patterns
that that
that determines
the class which is like a contrast patterns but slightly different definitions and there are
what happens that
they don't belong
it belongs to one
one kind of definition of thousands of what so they are not
they're not identical definitions
the very first notion of contrast patterns was
given by tom mitchell
when he did his phd
it's called version spaces but that was done from a from a logical basis in
the sense that
there is no statistics no probability or any kind is used
and i he basically used some kind of theorem proving kind of model
so what you do is out of order more details like
and then emerging patterns that we did our group
and then contrast set mining
was done by
signi just that was
monash university
and oxidation rules and about discrimination emerging patterns it appeared in
again leaves one of my phd students
and then there is the MDL
the minimum description language based contrasts
we're done
two thousand seven the KDD is one of the
premier conferences
in the data mining KDD is
knowledge and
that discovery data mining discovery
and this is sick
special interest group ACM conference
it is pretty tough to get papers and you know
i acceptance ratio is less than seven percent
and people
people think they have a paper that they want
the nobel prize
that's the kind of competition
i all of these things are done
right now but i think it
two possible i think what it means is
artists and making light
and the
paper will go to the
program committee member as a blind
and the results we can
to the
and the manager also to blind
and once the paper stock
then the chief
of the
programme committee of the chair of the committee then reveals the names
o to trying to make it as unbiased as possible
but there are also lots of complaints they say that some nice piece of work
is not submitted anymore because they say
o point because i'm the only one working on
you know let's say MRI images because i'm going to just person
who has access to the instrument
and everybody would know so they want access might not going to publish
it's also happening
people from all the top scientists are decided maybe something more
we just need to join
so anyway the KDD is a couple of friends you know if you if you
have a very good idea
target to this kind inference because
your employment will become easier
if you have KDD all
this is the kind of very top and similarly in machine learning
those kinds of places
if you publish your
using statistical measures for
evaluating group differences in spatial contrast patterns
a lot lots of lots of work is taking place i think no one of
the hardest areas is to look at spatial
contrast mine people are interested
for example in a given city
what kind of demographic changes are taking place
you know for example
can you see
but i want you to work out at home
so you get
electric field
suppose i want to know
what electric field this
at the distance d above the plane
what i do now is
i chose this as my
because of
what we closely
visit intersection with the play
this is my goal
it is a closed surface
three conditions
i have to be met
for you to be able to calculate what the factories
at that location
the first one is
that this is the flat plain here
this is the same flat plane must be parallel to display that some must
you don't do that you can use gauss law
the second one is
these vertical walls that you have here
i indeed perpendicular
put that play
the these are parallel
and these are four exactly food
if you don't make them vertically if you do this
that in one can use gauss law very effectively
and then
the thirty
which is very important
that this
flat surface
is the distance d above the plane
and this flat surface is exactly the same distance below to play
you can already smell why that is important
because if you ever want to use the symmetry arguments
this plane is uniformly charged
the electric field vector year in terms of magnitude obviously must be the same as
their in terms of magnitude maybe not in terms of direction
as long as this is the same as that
that's why it's important that the two these
the same
and the only charge that you have inside when you apply
because this law is the charge which is of course here
the only charge inside that
closed box
if you work this out at home
you will find an amazing result
you will find that the electric flux
through these vertical walls
nothing comes out of vertical wall
think about why that is
the symmetry arguments
but something comes out he or comes in here if it is negative charge and
something goes out here
so you only have two contribution from those two and place
you work on that
you will find
perhaps the amazing results that you electric field
because sigma
divided by two actually non-zero
that is independent of how far you are from the plane
very very far away when you close
it's the same
so this is that plane
and if the plane is positively charged
he will be like this year
and it would be like this year
and it will be independent of
and if it is negatively charged
it would be like so
and it would be like
like so
pointing towards
the plane
and in all cases
what the magnitude b sigma
divided by two
humans or
does it mean if i go very far away from that plane that is still
independent of the distance
if that plane is infinitely large
but if the plane is only as large as the next all here
then clearly
it would hold very accurately as long as i stay relatively close to play
in other words if my distance to the plane is small compared to the linear
size of the plane
but if i go
miles away
twelve corps then that plane is charged looks like a point charge i'm five miles
away from twenty six one hundred if the plane is only as large as this
lecture hall that looks like a point charge and obviously the electric field will then
fall off as one of four square
so when i say the e field doesn't change
was distance it means of course
that you have to be relatively close
to the surface relative to the linear size
of that service
so you're going to prove this
and i'm going to use this now
to calculate for you
a much more complicated
of two
but i use that result
that's very important
and i suppose i have
here a
the plates
very large
nothing is infinitely large of course and it has a
the surface charge density pi sigma
and i have here
the plate
we test surface charge density minus sigma
the separation between these two two plates
happens to be d
the question now is what is the electric field anywhere in space
here and here
i will think of them as
being infinitely large place
and i know use the
so the position of principal
i said to myself hot
displayed alone
get this one
displayed along
would give me
e vector
i stick to my collars
give me vector
like so
and that is
sigma divided by
two actually non-zero
one is also pointing away from this
divided by two actually non-zero
and here is also
divided by two actually non-zero because it independent of the distance to display
what is the negative charge doing
well the negative charge has vectors pointing towards it
so you have an
which is sigma
i'd like to have zero
you have one
that sigma
divided by two actually non-zero
and i have one that pointing towards
the plates which is sigma
divided by two abstinence
i use the superposition principle
i can add electric vectors
and when i do that
i find these to cancel each other out
so the electric field is zero
electric field here
divided by actually non-zero the to support each other they are both in the same
and the electric field here is again zero
and that is an amazing results
of course is only accurate if
government times
applied to be
know maybe the definition is is
so how do i define f
so i ordered by the immediate rewards
the state sort of my
at x
it's just the sort
over y
the that the first inmate are
the the
first wanted you see
so this is the expected of all kinds of one
given you that you spot
at state x
it's about
and what's PFI
so p of bi is a matrix
and i'm going to index it in an unusual this x and y so that
i and j but it should be the same
so this is just the transition probability matrix
plotted in the policy
so there the matrix
so remember that we are saying that
this value functions while
this lack of space
just like vectors
so if you
if you change this notation we have access to be sub acts
and you changed x two i it have a single black
the normal vector and matrix operations
the reason we are doing that is because
you can learn this infinity
spaces in the sky is it's a little bit strange to use that notation
but otherwise this is just vector space
don't worry about it
given this
you can rely a variety of by
applied to the
as the sum of these two quantities so the first one is
we apply
this matrix b by two v
you multiply that so that gives you another that factor of the same dimension
so this is called the
transition probability kernel and the policy pi and again this is called the kernel
you see that the kernel is always is linear operation kind of thing
and then you multiply these going on
and you add
the middle part
emitted expected reward
vector p
so on the other hand so this is a fixed point
but if i spent a lot of this fixed point using this notation here
and i find
i should have
this activation here so this is
and an exhibition for the BFI
i can solve it
we have
so although i isolate
well i have thirty in saying so that all the lights on the same side
of the equation
let's say i moved this to this side of the equation
so when i got out of p
i mean is gonna dance p of pi
that might apply sphere by
right so i is the identity matrix in all this is the matrix that's
all once in is diagonal and otherwise all elements it are there
and then
well it happens that
precisely because of that reason if you're standing some pleasant looking around it appears to
be a flat plane
but it's not as we know now so that the blogical so in the case
of the three dimensional manifold we're looking standing at point looking around and it looks
like three dimensional space for example the space we live in is probably a three-dimensional
manifold where the trees to the way we're looking at it geometrically
of course it can blossom or them dimensional if we include other parameters not only
the space ones
the second ingredient of more theory is a smooth function which is defined on the
manifold m o i was going to say something about what the smooth part means
with a small part in this so we have to
try to work with this part we have two points in our manifold and we
have local neighborhood where this looks like a flat plane and we have local neighborhood
over here this looks like a flat the fact that it looks like a flat
plane actually knew that we have a map going from this over here the plane
which we call a coordinate system so around here the conformal coordinate system and around
here we can also form according to
and now if we look at the combination of these two maps one which goes
from the school system this neighborhood well it's going to take some of the points
to this little intersection and on the intersection we can go to the other coordinate
system with the combination of the maps is going to be smooth differentiable map OK
so we can smoothly transfer ourselves from one coordinate system to the other like typical
atlas which you
a book which is an atlas of the earth would represent an atlas structure on
the smooth manifold which is the surface of the earth
well the other ingredient of morse theory is a smooth function on m what does
that mean that the function is smooth on from the strange thing which is the
smooth manifold well just knew that if we look at the function in local coordinates
so if that they can point over here and presented some press over here well
and if you look at the function in terms of these points here in the
plane then this is going to be differentiable function in the plane we know how
to differentiate so this is easy to define
OK so we start with a smooth manifold and a smooth function defined on
so what do we do so this is the basic idea of morse theory and
it's really brilliant the idea is that we look at the critical point of the
function and
the fact is that careful analysis a systematic analysis of the critical points of this
function which everyone it is so we have the smooth manifold and any small function
on it we look at the critical points and we study them and what we
get back well in return this is the discovery of more's in return we get
a topological reconstruction of the domain m which is simpler than our original description so
we get this domain and described as an nice CW complexes logical model it turns
out but it doesn't have very many cells because it only has a cell for
each critical point of the function so i'm going to raise the
the screen because i would like to remind you what the critical point of a
function is into an example which will explain this
this is a little bit
so c and from some mathematicians can do without chalk and blackboard sorry this is
the way things work and that a so what is the critical point well let
me just show the very simple case of the function of one variable we have
a function f of x which we can imagine by plotting is a graph in
the plane and the critical points of this function are precisely the points where the
derivative is equal to zero for example these are the points where the tangent is
horizontal so here's the critical point here is the critical point and maybe there a
critical point over here which is not on local
extreme but still it it's the point where the derivative is equal to zero for
the critical point in this case are the points where f primex
is equal to zero OK now if we take on
we have
the race for words
is that congress
well let me
you have a quick thing i saw in the case of two variables f of
x y the scale the surface of the graph is going to be a service
over the of the domain of the function which is now part of the plan
and the critical points here are the points where both partial derivatives derivatives are equal
to zero because it would be hard
so f of x
so both partial derivatives are equal to zero and now in this case we see
that there are various kinds of critical points OK we have we can have a
critical point which looks locally like this
this is going to be a critical point this is the critical point which corresponds
the probability to get from p of a given b
it appears to be given aces the likelihood and the prior
but we were not the probability is
deal with probability density
how do we represent the distributions are how do we represent the beliefs that we
have about the skills of players so we have the density p of p over
the skill of the player and we just assume that to be a normal density
with mean URI and variance sigma square
and the
you know if you to look at the joint distribution for x one thousand s
two this is of course this typical gaussians bomb and the assumption here is it's
the unimodal distribution of course is easy to work with that's why we choose it
and the assumption that we make use that people do not switch between widely varying
scales right then we would need a multimodal distribution this is bump shaped
now let's talk about the likelihood
the likelihood of course is the sampling distribution over outcomes given
given the values the skills that you want to estimate viewed as a function of
these skills
and the game outcomes are the permutations including the strong force between between teams
so we we introduce another variable here which is the performance
and we describe the performance given the skill so the idea is that a certain
skill the player has and now he enters the game now
he will not perform at that exact level of his average skill but its performance
maybe better or worse depending on if you had a few glasses of beer orders
late at night or the baby cried all of which i have experienced
and again we assume this to be normally distributed with in this case with variance
beta square
and the mean is given by the skill level of the mean of the performance
is given by the schema level four teams
the performance is given by the sum of the player's performances in the team
so that's very
the simplest assumption we can make really and there might be better models for that
there many people who can play very well together so the sum of their play
is more than than sum than parts or you could have people that cannot play
well together so you would have a different effect but here we make a very
simple assumption that these performances just add up for the team
and you can think of to get the probability of the game outcome given the
skills as
these TI's being in the order of the outcomes
in the game
so here's an example of how this likelihood works
what a plot here is the performance of player one and the performance of player
so the joint distribution over the performances is something that
player one has a scale of two
and player two has the scale of four
so this would be the joint distribution over performance is that we expect to hear
alternatively we can plot the distance with the difference between the two performances
we now have
for the
for the sampling distribution if you like is
player one wins
if a sample of this distribution falls into this region
player two wins the sample of the distribution follows in this area
and we also have the time march and so if the sample of this usually
falls into this then
we have to draw
the probabilities of these outcomes this is for two players we three possible outcomes for
player wins second win of they draw
it is given by the mars
of this distribution
and in these areas that are depicted here you can see if you plot this
as a function of the difference between the performances then the probabilities correspond just to
these areas and this curve and those can easily be evaluated since this is the
gaussians by the cumulus cumulative calcium density phi
so is that model clear you need to get some whole from the skill numbers
two probabilities for a game outcome
and this is the way we do it
let's look at this
again suppose a wins against b
then what we would expect from the performances is that it's a process of a
must have been better than the performance of b and in particular must have been
better by a certain margin epsilon
now if a and b draw
then there are performances had better be with in this
draw march
and of course we using the fact that the ranking relation is transitive
in the case of more than two players with more than two players here a
b c d then
we want the performance of a b to be better the performance of b by
epsilon be better than c by epsilon and also we need to make sure that
c and d are within this margin of epsilon
i will spare you the mathematical details of the derivations which i didn't really enjoy
but i will give you the idea of how we do this in principle now
we're using a technique called gaussians density filtering because we have the problem that for
the likelihood i've just described there doesn't exist a conjugate prior so we cannot
find prior to that
if i take time the likelihood has the same the same mathematical form as the
prior that we use so what we do is we find the best galson approximation
in the sense of the kullback liebler divergence to the posterior
and in order to do that we just need to evaluate the mean and the
covariance of the posterior
and if we have that we can just take calcium with that mean and that
covariance and that's our approximation for that particular posterior in order to do that you
have to integrate numerically in
in kk minus one dimensions where k is the number of teams
and this is the major difficulty in the implementation you can use monte carlo methods
for that we used at first means to method called against algorithm for calculating these
integrals and now we're using a technique called expectation propagation in order to approximate but
i will not go into the details of how to do that but that's the
main computational challenge in dealing with this
so here's an example of how that works suppose a priority that means before we
observe the game we have this the joint distribution player one has killed two player
two has school for and this is the joint belief distribution
about about their
about their skills
now we observed that player one wins
that's what
it's not place
a question
it will change
one point that
don't see it
like the idea
well let's just go through the
the station that we have
from that many new
so what looks like this
now integral point out sequence
from just like you can be
it doesn't
this is
OK so
for the red dots
posterior distribution on line segment things
like this
it is
so examples
neural network
the rest of asia
that is the way
it's one of
from that city
one of my
now draw samples from
this distribution i like this
from problem
one one one
right now in the
this penalty or this can be also hinge loss for spam plus the extrinsic penalty
the intrinsic value
OK so it turns out its
not hard to show that you can actually get actually representer theorem for that problem
and the representer theorem knows the following its fallen versions
it just says that instead of
your function being the sum of kernels of labelled point it becomes the sum of
the labeled points
and unlabeled points
so it's it's
it's a different solution so you have no basically you have some of bumps into
some advances over labelled and unlabelled
and for the case of least squares you can actually figure out what the coefficients
i in terms of matrix inversions
there is this formula
well this is
i mean if you have a lot of unlabeled points this can still be
fairly complicated computation problem but at least it's a logarithmically when simple for the hinge
loss you can also reduce it to the standard quadratic programming problem and you can
run an analog of us family effectiveness
OK so this is basically tells you and let me go back
it may go back
basically tell you how to incorporate unlabelled data the kernel frame
so if i turn this off completely so suppose i this to bizarre
then i'm just back to
this standard tunnel methods
if however i make this small
then my all my penalty effectively comes from the manifold
so now i have this two knobs which tell me which somehow controls the trade
off between intrinsic and extrinsic muscles and
it may show you
it may actually show you a little demo of this
OK so
brad point is one class blue pointed out the class and green is unlabelled
i suppose i do
the SVM with the same them before
and by my
so if i just do regularized least squares
what do i get you
the straight line is expected
i don't this that the penalty often the penalty basically the
the government
and the he
so basically this is the same example as we had before
the unlabelled data basically tells you that the boundary
it has to be nice and small and you can actually play this if you
want it on the web
you can ask you know i
it is somewhat sensitive to parameter so you can
you can try seeing how it works with respect to the parameters basically
works reasonably well
and as expected
it's the one one example
OK so
two labelled points
two red point
the blue points
if i do the ordinary
regularized least squares
this is actually OK so
when you do the lab class well it works along the
it goes along the unlabeled points and if i do
the goal is
no it
it's interesting
it's an interesting features
OK in any case you can imagine what it will go and i can tell
you basically have go to go like this
if you fed gamma a two zero so gamma a two zero let's try this
of world
i don't think you consented to zero but they can make it much much smaller
and so on
yes so that's good question actually why why do one so well they do play
a different role because that depends how much you trust into it depends on how
much you trust your your data right if you don't actually think manifold assumption is
so strong
you might you might think well you know why should they actually believe in it's
briefly described a if you're not familiar with that may
make the challenge of a lot of effect on the the periods of how do you know so the perceptron algorithm works as
follows it starts with a weight vector sequences Europe and uh basically it looks you get a training set X 1 1 I want to extend the U . and you and the way it looks at the
training examples and Computers whether they correct our
correctly internal at random does not just and sequence and for each 1 it looks to see whether the current weight vector so we're going to call this
initial weight vector of its call it way zero mean and stage in whatever stage where at let's say that we at the teeth
stage within a look to see whether this correctly classified that particular turning point able I
mean by that is that the output of the linear function applied to that example agrees in sign with the labels labels all but in our plus minus 1 of the
things you don't think is good looks to see the corrected
classifiers if it doesn't then it updates so it further that is not true of that is necessary to zero-coupon
updates the weight vector to the next part of a weight
vector by adding to its the all a copy of that trade sample but also attracting if
it's a negative examples so it adds to a while I times x i um and a that's it and does that so they should say repeat and to all of you
a correct classification all e 2 so it's was known as a
mistake driven algorithm in that it only makes any changes
that it makes a mistake and uh the changes of a reasonable change it simply adds a copy
of Electronics all to the weight vector but also attracted
it's a negative examples of thinking about a few but right that in you'll for but so
you think you know your weight vector of as equal to in general some golf I
don't x i so this is and you all of the form that you
support in birds talk to carry then we start with
Althusserian effectively in the only change that we have to
make is that uh we can this will be exactly the same except that we can write it
control form if we want to do it will be a why I some Jerry calls 1 of 2 where and the jury from text axiomatic that's just a just a jewel form of
expression that and the updating will simply be health work t plus 1 of
all 4 don't high is equal to the of 2 plus 1 all of the time we
have a minus you sorry class why I don't you I mean that if
you want to baby it's easier actually but Vocalizing here something
like that like excise so that means that the speaker is
just becomes plus 1 is on the 1 hand and culture and the OK
so the what is it is it will be up in a with the support
vector machine the opposite all positive so it's probably
simpliciter the forms of the alpha I mean we're always adding positive examples of the Office get
bigger and the wires positive a more was subtracting negative examples of the wire is
negative and so the opposite going positive context so that
is the that is the perceptron algorithm and uh there's a a
result known as the perceptron convergence algorithm of
fear sorry all the more we call theorem you which said that
the number of out if there exists a w start which has a large in a with all 1 so w start has a 1 and its margin on the training set is greater than are equal to get much more than the number of
up its out of the perceptron algorithm before a convergence
is less than or equal to ask where the over Dennis squared where our is the maximum of the enormous all of the
training examples that you have the right to cover very we can is the only information you need to know about the
problems are clear that we voted on so that I mean I would imagine you know many of you know
this but it but the idea is simply it's a very simple
algorithm and updates by when you make a mistake just
adding the example to the things you can think of it in a dual form like there's just
adding 1 to the power of the vector um we about Novikov
appearances that provided there is a large margin solution
there exists a large margin solution than the number of states before convergence is that most
of this number and this from the from the classification of the of the of the
of the listeners is correct additional stop updating
remember because it only updated make some state so as soon as it's got correct reservation stops exposed
to the visual have very small margin for which we have used the term round of happy without any questions on the content of all right and prepare side of membership of the them but you
know what can I do for a living here if you want to know
how it so know notion with that in mind I think that we can apply the perceptron algorithm to the to
the approximation problem and and return the approximation problem of
classification problems so we can apply the perceptron
algorithm we going to get a convergence in because we know
that the theories a exists a solution which has not in around to that's the original
function that was at the centre of this of essential approximation problem we know that we're going
to get some of the convergence in but most 8 hours squared
over down squared updates so after you ask at most of