probability bound
which means that the grant will be
bonded by
something like this with high probability
which is important
in practice because
you want something that's robust
right you want to grow up to be bounded with high probability versus in expectation
so this original algorithm does not give a high probability bond
but you can modify it
to get one
and all the techniques were already present in that paper that they come manually
so here is the
summary so far
in the supervised in the
full feedback
you'll unsupervised setting
you get full feedback in the the neighborhood of every action
at training time
and the degree that
scales as c
log and
use and standard sample complexity machinery
it's usually not phrased this way because you're talking about this sort of regret per
sample but you can sum over so the standard
way of
sample complexity bounds give logan over c
but when the sum over two rounds that the
to make it comparable to the other brands
you get something that scales is t
and yes it sufficient
so this is the
where you explore first and then exploit the leader on the exploration around
it works in the stochastic setting
was partial feedback
they were the
very good at scale says t to the two thirds
which is worse than routine
and yes it is sufficient
in the number of policies that you're competing with there's no
there is no intrinsic the dependence on the number of policies
because you can use for example
any of learning algorithm to choose the best on the exploration around
you can just be that in into
empirical risk minimization oracle to give you
an approximant
approximately best policy and EXP four
works in the adversarial setting with partial feedback gives you this optimal regret but it's
not efficient because we had to keep a weight on every policy and we had
to update those weights so if you're competing with a large set
this is not efficient
so ideally we would like
an algorithm that is like EXP four but didn't have to explicitly than the weights
on every policy
and this is one of the
important problems in this area to get something
that for example depends on an empirical risk minimizer nor home
so let's switch gears and
so the so that this is our unbiased estimate of the word
right so
you want the argmax over policies in pi
of this as t me
which sounds
or some sort examples where the policy agrees with the action taken of the reward
of action divided by the probability of taking that action
and so how can we
compute that quantity for
reasonable policy classes by
and this is a hard problem in general but we can try to reuse existing
supervised learning algorithms to give you a practical solutions to these problems so if you
encounter such a problem in practice can you use existing supervised learning algorithms to give
you a solution
scores as prime
r b and b is
notation but the simply giving
a previous state
previous action
distribution over possible next
OK here is is continuous if a continuous
probability density function in the discrete is just a big table of probabilities
OK reward function
so imagine that i wanted to paralyze the number of car
it assumed that makes is interchanged light every second
or maybe a bit more
OK let let let's say every minute
and i want to minimize the number of car minutes
car minutes waiting time
OK well what reward function b
and again
so the reward function is reward i get for being the current state
and gamma tells me how it read off reward time
so some over
well get so now
but for for being in estate one time
i i i just some parity and then i can some all those penalties over
all times to get the sum of the waiting times
so i can sum up my local reward
reward as a function of the state
in this case a it doesn't depend on the actions just state
it is the sum over i corps one to four
of case of IQ being
q being the real value
rising how long was
and negative
they get paralyzed
right i saw something i want to maximize reward that paralyzed for every car swinging
this is the single steps
and then what i take
reward at time
zero plus
gamma tend toward time one plus scalar square to reward time
times reward time two
out to say infinity
so let's it arises infinity
h equals infinity
if i really care about car second waiting time irrespective of whether occurring
the weight is now in the future that one gamma to be
does not prize-winning features we now i want to wait exactly the same
the chemical one
there were one is probably not
for various reasons
but but it is just the model
it's first fire model you solve it feels horribly this happen to me
i had income student who did a great job in place for model we really
realize the end
the model was wrong
back to the drawing board OK so you want to model the right level of
abstraction and you can always categories first
the first right
but this is one possible model
state actions observations observation function
not a dispute over states given the observations
transition function this over next is given season actions so for example
what is one stochastic aspect of the transition function
we know that
imagine there are ten cars
ten cars
in two three
now let's let's look at the next
that's in their zero cars here
zero cars here
there are ten cars here
ten cursor
embarrassing to zero
so the only two with with cars waiting is q one
going up
now after one time step where this light is green and the traffic flowing in
this direction
the next time step how many
should be two three
they are exactly exactly they they could turn right
so even if i know that are if i let them do if i find
like label long enough cars the start-up of times that that stochastic cannot predict that
but it if i let the slide stay green for five minutes
guaranteed rate only ten cars but you don't know
that all ten cars went straight so you don't you can nokia three that if
this light is read during this time because some cars could have gone
so you need a transition model that says the probability of turning
i dislike this this time of day
o point four
so you can estimate the expectation how many cars go we try
but this is all the transition function
this distribution over next states based on the current state and actions
i've got these cars in these cues i've got these lights green
you distribution over next
state qx
any questions at all about this if you would not understand a high-level what's going
on here is going to make the rest of the what to called
and if you have this are saying this great because then i realize were misleading
yes it does make competition is it just the geometric discounting is is cut it
is very easy especially in real in receding horizon control you to so it is
going to be to by gamma
and then in how discount everything
right but it also has this justification of
you impose this condition for all T
for all T
In this case infinitely many T you get an intersection of many of those halfspaces
so for each T you have two parallel halfspaces and then if you change T
the halfspaces rotate and it describes a non polyhydral convex set
so it's not polyhydral because you need infinitely many inequalities to describe it but it's a
clearly convex
so that's all we'll need about to know about convex sets a convex function is defined
like this so a function is convex if its domain is convex
the sets of points where it's defined as convex and on its domain Jensen's inequality holds so
Jensen's inequality so graphically it means that if you have two points on the graph of
the function
the value F of X F of Y then the linear the segment defined by those two points on the graph
lies above the graph of the function that's a convex function and if it's concave if minus F is
so other some simple examples
so obviously linear or affine functions are convex and also concave
exponential the negative of a logarithm negative entropy X log X are convex
certain powers are convex for example if X is
positive if that's the domain of F then X to the alpha is convex if alpha is greater than one
or negative
et cetera
any norm is convex
this is a function that's not immediately clear but it's also convex if you have a quadratic function N transpose X
devided by T as a function of X and T jointly where T is positive
that's a convex function of X and T a geometric mean of an a non-negative
variables is concave
log that of the log of the determinant of a positive definite matrix is concave
so it's concave on the set of positive definite matrices so that function will be important
when talk about interior point methods and in the last one we'll also encounter is
the log of the sum of exponentials of variables is convex
of course there's some of exponentials by itself is convex because exponentials are convex but even if you take the log
or apply the logarithm to it you still have a convex function
so there is also a simple connection between convex functions and Convex sets so
convex a function is convex if its epigraph is convex
convex it's a convex set
so the epigraph of the function is simply
the set defined off as everything that lies above the graph of the function the
graph itself and everything above
so if X F is a function of N variables its epigraph is a set in R N plus one
cause T is
extra variable
and the so this is if and only if a function is convex if and
only if its epigraph is a convex set
you can also consider a sub level sets of a function convex function so it's a
set of points X in the domain of F that has a function have a function
value lies on a certain alpha
now sublevel set of a convex function is always convex
and that follows again directly from the definition but the converse is not true there are functions that are
not convex and still have
convex sublevel sets for all values of alpha
so convex functions were defined in general using Jensen's inequality so that don't have
to be differentiable if they are also differentiable once or twice differentiable than you
can also
give equivalent conditions that can replace Jensen's inequality in the definition for
example if
the function is differentiable then
an equivalent condition is that the function value
Of the graph
function satisfies this inequality
so on the right-hand side you see the linear approximation of the function around the point X
so the first order linear approximation of
a function from its function value and its gradient
well if the is convex than that linear approximation must be below the graph of the function
for all possible points where you take the approximation
so this first order linear approximation is not only a local approximation of the function
but it's also a global
lower band on the function value so it's a very fundamental
and if of course you also have second if the function is twice differentiable then you can express convexity
also simply in terms of the Hessian and say that the Hessian matrix of the
function must be positive semidefinite everywhere in its domain
so those are the definitions so the Jensen's inequality and these two equivalent definitions for differnetiable
or twice differentiable functions
in practice one first time process
OK so
example why this is
good for
part two part one is that this inheriting statistical strength effect which was you an
example later on again the second example is this idea of generating
a class of clustering in sort of estimating the number of clusters automatically
so one example is if p of x y given simply because the distribution of
theta i corresponds to the center and the covariance
of course distribution
so let's look at the graphical representation of the same thing as before only that
we only have always one data point for every sample said OK that's only one
and this is the cost distribution
so your for x
it's got students at the centers the the covariances
of course and
in the in so we can do the CRP type something and then we observe
that all the
data points which are assigned to the same table all inherit the same parameter
we can think now that all this data manually generated by an identical thousand distribution
and so we can think of all this data from one class to
with the parameters sort associated with the
elston derived from this is from these data
and so do the sampling we use this data points would jump around a little
bit between the different colours since according to the probability is but if you look
at the incident time there will be a certain number of tables will occupied
and this number will also some fluctuations
go up or down a little bit but on average it gives you a good
indication about something like the true number of clusters in your problem
and this is one of the attractive features here that the sampling procedure automatically gives
you a good estimate of the number of classes in your domain
which of course is sort of depending on the often not change so you can
sort of do a rough tuning by the astronauts you think my domain there's probably
have a large number of clusters of a small number of clusters this can be
tuned by the infinite not but given we fix that there still some freedom in
the model to decide exactly on the sort of correct number of clusters and there
are two ways to
estimate is i fine not and then this is a complete automatic process of automatically
automatically determining so something like the right number of clusters and other methods have a
much harder time of doing that to it's sort of trial and error procedures so
this is one reason why these do sleep with someone
that's what happened
and to illustrate this point
look at this picture so these are
the gaussians which are associated with different
OK with the chinese restaurant in this case we would have
six tables being occupied and these are the data
so this would be a snapshot of the same process this might be the data
associated with this with the stable over here these are the data sources which is
stable over here and these data probably can jump between these tables for that
and based on the data
the associated with a given table we would estimate the skulls
OK surely we don't do it all the time but the officially template this would
be the palestinians would be estimated by the data points listed in the table
so the data points are identical to the customs in this case because there's only
one data point for each station
so this is one of the attractive things about this if we persist it can
do clustering and automatically determine the number of
we can now
come to the last part of the physical section before we come to the station
and there's also
direct relationship to
finite mixture models
i mean
by the related to all of this but in the infinite case we can even
make them
the identical so if you chose
a finite mixture model and you choose as your distribution for the indicator variables usually
process for not divided by our
let r go to infinity
it's actually processed
the last thing is when you got these processes going on
you've got to keep track
and we monitor everything the throughput systems to the temperature CPU use something like three
hundred fifty thousand metrics that are updated every fifteen seconds and we have a lot
of analysis focused on just interpreting these metrics so that we can understand trends plan
accordingly the course systems can also recover ultimately so people focusing on building models don't
have to worry about these things
modelling pipelines is really what is really where the magic happens this is this is
the stuff that we started the company with this with this in mind as a
bunch of things that have been done in terms of the audience inference like traffic
modelling and look like not to touch upon the environment we've created how we develop
models and rapidly get those into production
first of all really important
sort of ten of math team environment is to combine the best of collaboration we
have very collaborative environment we regularly brainstorms as an entire group say it's not a
large group a whole companies about one hundred people
so this so the team and don't know maybe this maybe this twenty scientists also
they regularly get together and brainstorm new approaches we review everyone else's work in a
group every week everyone presents the progress and how their models performing in the new
ideas we share all of our information should work environment and everyone has team goals
but also we're really trying to encourage independence everyone is free
to implement their own ideas
they're free to create new models to improve models to create better metrics for assessing
models also develop new visualization techniques to help them interpret how well the models of
and to do that is really important we have an objective way of assessing progress
in making decisions about you know when is the model better and therefore when can
we stop using the model out in production
we do this you're look-alike pipeline sandbox so
your typical day
there's about ten terrabytes of new data coming in from the internet
and for a given market there might be ten thousand to twenty thousand or maybe
just a few hundred people
that have actually done something of interest to that market let's say that before given
well those converters
actually fit within our training sandbox training set will contain any number of different models
the different groups different scientists are actually work
those models are assessed against typically about half petabytes of of
data so we have a fixed data we can use the training and assessing these
and the sandbox allows us to make rapid comparisons between
models in these text datasets
basically everyone is constantly working on new challenges we want to develop new models to
replace our current here are the current heroes the model is actually out there making
real time decisions about you know hundreds of thousands of requests per second and the
objective everyone in our in look-alikes teams to build model
the can be the hero
so challenges to the production here are developed in the sandbox and once we have
lots of we have lots of data so much data that obviously would be very
careful not to be overfitting one advantage having so much data is you always get
fresh data set and test it out terms generalizations
once the model appears to be
good and relevant it will actually be pushed into production that will go into production
and just take over what actually be run in parallel with existing here
to look for improvements assessment the way these models work is what to developed features
you have you you have your model look across the billion internet users and find
the next set maybe the next ten million maybe the next one million maybe next
twenty million the number depend very much on the objectives of the market and those
with the people who would consider that content that is relevant
assessing model
is really looking at the response we get
our current hero to existing challenge
and we can see here
we have significantly
in this challenge over the here that we're really interested of course the cumulative left
and can be a little difficult to see here one of the things to bear
in mind is
the most products
that is not relevant to most consumers
we're not looking for model gives his level down because there just aren't that many
people are going to be interested in the product and extreme case maybe half the
population will be interested in the product certainly not all of them and in many
cases a tiny fraction of the population
so that difference there
in terms of left left here is proportional to how well does this model compare
two randomly selected people
so the top and here are previous model was about twenty five times better than
random the new model is over sixty times better and that new model can find
its way into production quickly
and that's really important not just getting involved into production but also the rate at
people can develop new models and test them out because ultimately
the building a start-up businesses about learning
it's about discoveries about finding the right way to address market and your learning is
directly proportional to rate of experimentation more experiments you can do the more you can
learn faster going to get to where you want to say so this environment is
so imagine that you have
you have a restaurant with
the really big restaurant with infinite number of tables in the restaurant
and the first customer comes in at the first table
so i mean draw this
so you have restaurant
and you would are
and the first half of comes in and the table
then the
the second comes
and decide between two choices
the second summer
chooses to sit at this table with probability proportional to the customer already sitting there
in that case the probability proportional to one
while with probability proportional to to alpha cuts might sit at a new table
let's say that the second last year
label on
and the customer comes in
with probability proportional to the number of customers sitting at the table
the the customers city
and was
well with probability proportional to alpha the first in this is yet another new people
let's say that the
so we can repeat this in general
and customer when
when the customer comes in
he was sitting at table k with probability and he
offshoot and where n is the number of revisiting it will
and with probability proportional to alpha this
as customer will sit
a new table
so here the customers correspond to integer
and the tables correspond to clusters
basically what it states that the chinese restaurant process xt but
that's being property of the dirichlet process
we can get
from a chinese restaurant process back work
blackwell macqueen urn scheme in the following way
so we first from our
random partitions of the integers one to and from the chinese restaurant process
and then
on each table we will draw
it's a bit on table k will draw it back from a base distribution
then for
that we simply by the i
b they are that i was that i was the table
o which customize
so this construct a sequence of the
which turns out to be equivalent to
the blackwell macqueen urn scheme
and this is actually quite useful because what it says is that the chinese restaurant
process is applied
so there's two things happening here
in the dirichlet process
one is
the clustering property of the dirichlet process which
now cluster value
together it
that's the random variables together
and the second one is safe seats that for each cluster
the value is simply from the base distribution
and what the chinese restaurant process this is the idea to act in
in the first part
the last representation is to begin construction
i will i think i'll skip the revision
but basically what happens is
the following
what happens is that it shows that
are drawn from a dirichlet process
it's simply an infinite number of functions
and the highest
on the point from high is simply
but that it and the other from one minus one one minus if the i
where each base
it it that is drawn independently
from it that one of
so this is called the rate fraction
he has
we can imagine what
so what's happening here in the following we start with the big of length one
and we break this because the point here
so that's going to be all i one
we take the the rest of
and we break at some point again
to get up . 6 that starts to veer off and then asymptotically approach
errf z equals 1 so in fact we can write here from the from 1
equals 0 . 8 4 you can see now it's not linear
and refers to
people 0 . 9 9 5 so what you get out here to your practically
at the asymptotic and it's defined here's the integral is defined from z is the
integral from z
from 0 . 3 0 2 C of E to the minus the square the
so that's that's that's e to the minus you squared e to the minus you
squared as a function of you is the Gaussian error function right that's the bell
curve so this is the area under the bell curve we started x that u
equals 0 we're going to integrate as far as we need to out here and
the integral from 0 to infinity of this thing is rude pi over 2 and
we want to go from 0 to 1 so we put the factor to over
pilots from that when we integrate this from 0 to infinity birth of infinity becomes
1 so er friends from 0 that's the area under this curve so that's why
some people call this the galaxy error function because the gaussian curve is associated with
random statistics in terms of of errors
so this now is the time place this is the template if I have in
any reaction this is all I have to fit using these using these multiplication factors
so let's play Mr. dress up here just use this function to describe all of
the typical of industrial processes only 2 types of processes those that diffusing substance it
and then those that pulling substance out so let's look at the 2 cases so
let's look 1st of all at the 1 that's shown right up there so this
would be for something like outgassing outgassing for drawing many uh many processes involved drying
which is to get the water out of the the content of a of a
solid piece and so as you can imagine you've got some initial concentration seen
you take the surface concentration whatever this is an obviously if you want to draw
something out and move matter from right to left in the surface concentration by necessity
must be less than the initial concentration otherwise why something
so this means this all call the fusion something is you think so this is
a fusion the flux is moving from right to left on the determining here is
seen on is greater than CS the surface concentration is less than the initial concentration
so I'm appear the concentration at C I've got C 0 deep inside and this
is telling me what the shape of the curve
this is telling me what the shape of the curve I just write with impunity
C minus overseen minus C F equals the error function x over 2 routes of
and that's the answer for all such problems and because it's a linear doesn't matter
if I change the in initial concentration to new value I can just add
we can add and multiply because linear equation when functionality but I think you're we've
got some are point we looked at those This is the tabulation this is in
the supplemental tax there's a table of an error function values so that if you
happen to get into this regime beyond that
z equals 0 . 6 shows you have the the values that you need
so let's look at another case let's look at the driving material so that for
example something like on adult
building or tonight writing the opening-night trying carburizing
but if we want case-harden
material will raise the carbon content of the free surface have something that's often ductile
inside alright so for that here's the here's the scheme
there's scheme we have a surface concentrations C
we have an initial concentration
getting crowded with cleanest of surface concentration initial concentration seen on and in this case
the not is less than CS surface concentrations higher so material now wants to move
from left to right and so this is infusion infusion
and what's the kernel look like books like this
looks like this which is simply that 1
flipped upside down by subtracting it from from 1 which I'll show you in a
2nd and again the same general solution applies the same general solution applies with the
sea surface concentration is higher or lower than the initial ball concentration it comes out
in the math here so again we're write see . S overseeing on minus C
S equals x over 2 routes of DT
if we look at to find class
if you want to capital and
then by using n times capital in times of the inequality we can prove that
all functions simultaneously i mean what a large set of training samples
ninety nine percent of the examples for all functions similar to be
the difference will be bounded by this point
and they said we can then apply these two
the empirical
loss minimisation because it will be
part of this
oceans here
we get the following statement if we
use also the
fundamental inequalities that allowed us to really is
the actual
actually these quantities of the supremum already of these on the right
the similarity of these quantities about that
but this place this is problem that
so we get this statement
basically what it tells is that our empirical risk minimiser in these fine class
will perform almost as well as the best function
in the last two and if we knew the probability distribution
plus some extra factor which
it goes like one of those words of small and
and the size of the class winter as the logarithm
OK so this is really
you know the most typical
four of these bounds and you always
i mean you will also see the same exact same here in the online setting
this is really
very typical you always have these
one of the square root of n kind of dependent on the sample size n
log n that depends on the size of the first phase
and this
maybe a not on this little one of the top then here is
the confidence with which is bound holds right so if you want to have fun
which i mean if you want to have guarantee that holds for
ninety nine point nine after training set
then this would increase so that the body bigger if you want to have a
stronger confidence
let's say this does not depend on the distribution on p right this is one
for any possible be it just assumes that
the sampling is actually i so independent
it just rely on the independence assumption
of the training data
an interpretation is that if you do
empirical risk minimization in your class
it will converge to best function in your so that's a nice way
actually solve this problem this learning problem is the estimation part of it then africa
approximation parts
you need to have a class that these regions right and that's where you see
that the slogan might enter because
we have another reason that as well
when the class is small
but when the class is small
we cannot across all possible functions and in particular
if we take you know just linear classifiers well they would be there would be
infinitely many but let's say we take a small set of linear classifiers
then we cannot approximate any possible function with that
we will pay the price of having too small class
not in the estimation part but in the output emission apart when we compare this
two energy star
this estimation versus approximation is really trade-off
better approximation you have
the larger your class
and then there were estimation twenty the
estimation deviation
so again
just to summarise
these bonds are
with respect to sampling of the training data so we have an almost all the
training examples
and you have this one of the world's top and here and this
lochinver over and if you take into this is about one function and then if
you a plus size and
supreme and behaves like the in
these are
the main factor that you should recall from that
one possible interpretation is that
you should consider that the difference between those statements is that
you have some more vulnerability here because the gene is no longer big but also
fluctuates with i mean changes with the data
it is like the discovery that i was showing before
four given a point on the curve
deviations as well
but if you look if you
it changes
along the axis
you in you increase the viability of this deviation you increase by a factor of
OK so now let's see whether we can improve these bounds
we can actually go further
in many ways why is that
i have things inequality if you recall
we used the the fact that we need to apply to any possible random variable
and we use the fact that the random variable was born which is the case
here because the run by wings either zero one that was
we can use more information about be available
the other thing is that when we apply this union bound we can look at
the worst case right we looked at the training set for which all any of
these of these inequalities
but this is kind of a worst case scenario
so when we look at here
we can look at the bottom that is but it's all possible functions in our
and maybe that our algorithm does not just any function in the set and actually
we know that just because one in particular which is the empirical risk minimizer
so if we know
where this risk minimizer might be
then we may have about that you know does not take into account the size
of the whole class but only
the size of this subclass where we know
our algorithm will be the function
let's focus on on the first this part our refining the union about
and what's going on let's have a closer look at how
this a binomial
variables because this and call
is a binomial random is a binomial random variable
it's a sum of variable that is either i mean it's very is either one
or zero and we take another independent and some of the
what is it right
this is really what we call
this the empirical error
it follows a binomial distribution of parameter
n being the number of samples that we have
and keeping being the expected value
like the
the probability that
the loss will be zero the loss will be one
which is actually the more energy in the observation
so energy is a binomial variables of you
the end of that is about
well about
we can actually write precisely
what are the aims
four one function that is
before one function we have inequality not just an upper bound for the deviation just
you know this is
the probability
that if you take
this and
instances are this an independent bernoulli variables
k of them will be equal to one
so you said that you know we said that we assume that the state is
also available
then you could try to just as the mean absolute given
the current acts of t
current AFP
and the next at x of t
this is as if you want a regression problem right or maybe density estimation problem
because the next state could be
stochastic and so you want to know the next a distribution and not just the
mean next state
then you can be out of that
and once you have been the more than just use the technique that shows that
we are given no more than
and just solve for the optimal control
we'll see some approaches that felt like that that that they are shown that you're
given the model we see that
even if you have
if you're given the model coming up with good action is is a highly non-trivial
so surprisingly there is this other approach which is called a model free approach
but you're not getting a more at all
some home actually come up with a single controller it's not magic at all
one very simple way of doing that is that
you see that
i'm going to have this capital as function parametrized with some parameters
the parameters leaving some parameter space euclidean space
and i just view this problem as an optimisation problem i use the gradient
as can procedure
to optimise my parameters
and so that's quite policies so that's one approach but there are some other approaches
and we are going to take a look at them
it's it's very interesting so what's the deal here which approach should be
that we don't know we we have no idea
to tell you the truth
so if you have
a good prior knowledge about the what about the more that might be
so you want to use that knowledge so there is no it's the same old
story if you have some prior knowledge
you want to put prior knowledge into the system and use it
if you
we don't have such a prior knowledge that you can still try both approaches then
you have to somehow this nonparametric way
and the problem that is that one then you're building the more you introduce some
errors and those areas are going to propagate
through the planning phase
and it's not very much clearer
from the point of view of the particle application which approach should be preferred
so i can cannot
have too much so once
same here though
is there
building models rely heavily on being able to
to estimate the state of knowledge the state
and so one problem this is the approach could be that if that assumption is
not met
or is violated strongly
then you're more that could be the
and then you're planning solution is is going to be way off
yes so this is sometimes true
because you can come up with more than three approaches that like to be data
fusion it's it's largely unclear to me if this is in chennai tree
regarding the uniform isolation
we got similar classification for manifold
remember for two manifold perhaps a kind of geometry but here for manifold such thing
conjectured that
there are eight canonical geometry is
and as a special case
puckering conjecture treated with
such kind of stuff
the manifold which is closed compact and the simply connected
it conjectured that this kind of many folks are actually three spheres
and this conjecture has been proven
using the ricci flow
and our work focused on another kind of the manifold which is hyperbolic manifold with
more gates some formulas for the flow
on such kind of manifold and also proved the convergence for that flow
and later some discrete out with arms
was developed to compute this flow and to elastic constant curvature metric
here is a result of the discrete curvature flow for hyperbolic three manifold with boundaries
the figure on on the left
it shows the surface the boundary surface of only on the volume is basically war
with multiple tunnels
and top logic like this is hyperbolic the manifold
the figure in between
in the middle shows the canonical metric
which is embedded in the hyperbolic space
and the figure on the right
in some multiple copy of the new ones actually that's you know it's the kind
embedded in the hyperbolic space
the same animal food curvature flow
we believe that it could have to study of the three manifold john janet apology
because that part away to realize something
also we are expecting that there should be some applications in engineering fields like the
one of my take from transition or shape comparison stuff
i was so
we would like to generalise this flow to other kinds of fuzzy manifold because there
are eight john in in total
i like to conclusion conclude the talk briefly
curvature flow is the fundamental to discover the intrinsic nature of geometry
basically it just deform the metric according to a local according to the
curvature is
it can be scrutinized properly to so many practical problems in engineering fields for surfaces
the discrete curvature flow like them is already allowable for all three geometry is
for three manifold salary
the discrete curvature flow with them has been studied only four
a certain kind of three manifold and the much more work has been done house
is expected to be down in the future
for more details
please refer to on two books one is the computation the complement john tree that
there is the variation of press parts of discrete surfaces
and all the data sets in the source codes in this in this work is
available at the following website
again i would like to thank the organisers and the sponsors of this conference and
also like to thank all of our collaborators from at different universities and different fields
last but not least i'd like to thank all audience here for your attention thank
i think you mean question
OK i have question the think about taking into account some scalar fields at the
same time than the geometry in that apology for instance to make your school take
there is no reason that each of these it is what it is
essentially the the only the the simplest reason that the initial bits of what they
are is those bits themselves
you know there is no more concise axiom from which you can deduce this
so in other words it looks very even it's very it's a perfect simulation within
pure mass of contingent truths
as opposed to necessary truths because like this distinguishes between necessary truths which are
true by reason by pure your thoughts are you know the opposite the contradiction and
contingent truths like the president of france is
you know you don't expect to be able to prove that logically and mathematically it's
a contingent truth you know all accidental so to speak or historical truth and these
these bits even though they in the world of pure thought in the islamic world
of human are perfect simulation they look a lot because because of our finite limitations
like contingent
and they look a lot like independent as a fair coin
OK so
so in and what this shows is that pure math is not simple
the way the hilbert for the pure maths who came from a small number of
ideas that we can all agree on and that's why you think is that because
of beautiful this makes it look a lot more like biology said
even in pure mathematics we have infinite complexity
so this is the message i i wanted to give you focus and maybe it's
time to open the floor to
questions discussions so
i mean i have been taking questions all along does anybody have any thing they
want to comment or ask if not i can go on a little bit more
i think i still have ten minutes or so
i want to disagree with this or let me tell you how the math community
has reacted to this OK
OK well i guess what is the physics meeting and nine and i have not
being invited to jerusalem after thirty years for physics moving really complex systems in physics
right sort of
also in high
and they said don't invite it's crazy
really that's great to hear
well let me tell you let me tell you how it is going was basically
a first class a lot of shock in the math community i mean as a
young student eurasian younger i would be by hermann biological online by other mathematicians they
released goal really disturbed it took away the their belief in the
on the world of ideas in in the that mathematical truths black or white and
provide absolute certainty
and and this upset a lot of mathematicians and then strangely enough such of the
powers of the human mind you know to suppress not think about things that are
unpleasant that complete the math community completely ignores chemical completeness and goes on exactly as
before in a what i would say i hilbertian style believing in formal methods an
axiomatic method or you could say about pakistan if you want to use the
the french school that came from over and and in and and this is still
the official religion in the math community and the math community
the reaction the larger community for example the reaction to this work is first of
all i think it's crazy because they don't understand this concept of program size which
are really connected to entropy complexity to them these are very strange ideas
and to talk about
something that's imitates randomness you know in mathematical logic is heresy because logicians are people
who hate randomness you know that's why they became magicians so so even gonality completeness
is unpopular in the world logic or in the world of mathematics if you look
at the reaction of the larger community mathematical logic community together is very ambiguous on
the one hand they have to claim him because he is the most famous magician
they have to claim about on the other hand if you look at article because
there what obviously says that logic is the failure
and therefore the subject can be
thrown away and you have to teach courses and this of course no logician would
like you to take home as a message from a course in logic you know
that they should file the logics professors so normally books on logic have the last
chapter my talk about computers and of course is you know you never get to
the last chapter when you give course
so these ideas
the you know those physics these ideas are really very close to ideas from physics
this idea of looking for randomness in mathematics randomness selected structure is connected with entropy
these are sort of versions of ideas of statistical mechanics these ideas to physicists these
ideas seem much
more familiar and and and there is a much more comfortable with this which is
why here i am at a physics meeting at the mass meeting so so
so so i would say but but i think
two take stick out to stick my neck out i think that what this really
shows you is the pure mathematics is and is is that is not like theoretical
physics but it's not that different i mean pure mathematicians like to think that they
have absolute truth and you know we physicists i consider myself an honorary physicists we
said you know our preferred just to restrict their on rigorous they're worthless
but you know what my what i really get my
my feeling about all of this is that it's a continuous absolute truth you can
only approach asymptotically you know in the limit and they respect proofs of the kind
of mathematical physicist feels comfortable with that are not rigorous proofs and it's a continuous
you know i don't see a sharp divide between the world of pure mathematics and
the kind of reasoning that theoretical physicist would be happy with i mean it's nice
if you can have a a rigorous absolute proof
what would be the you know what would be the other extreme if you take
a little bit is very seriously you could say i work for i i have
the property of the prime numbers which i talked on the computer
and it it you know there's is a beautiful curve in its fit beautifully by
a very simple equation and his were published this right you know and you mathematician
will say i don't care how accurately this very simple formula fits the curve and
it works out to know hundred billion or trillion you know i need to prove
and so what i'm saying what what happens if you mathematicians have
i have been promoting what they call experimental mathematics is the journal of experimental mathematics
there are a few books on experimental mathematics as research methodology that for example john
for wine has co-authored co-edited these books and
he's not as extreme as i am i think what this does is provide some
theoretical grounds
four thinking that maybe two masses quasi empirical i would say like at out and
let me say that there are cases in the world of pure mathematics and computer
it gives the same result as comparing the partition function of the PKB
so now all that we need to do is weighted model counting that if we
know how to do it model counting we know how to compute conditional probabilities
so how are we going to do that
well first of all
here's the
our level call right
this is sort of like the high-level probabilistic improving routine
what i do is
ptp is the routine i give it PKB and the query
and now what i do is i have query as hard formula right this is
what is zero means that the phi i zero
as far from the to the PKB
and then i returned the ratio of these two things
the PKB i converted to weighted CNF
i could between model count
this is the wikipedia
this is the p can be without you the rest of the is my answer
so i can feel my conditional probabilities by computing russia to partition functions
notice how similar this is
so the basic theorem proving schema in logic i
in logic what i do is i start with a degree in the CBI and
the negation of the query to the KB
and then i returned not of that
and CNN
here i also have created the PKB
in fact i cannot negate on on the get you know the effect is the
the difference is that instead of computing sat i just computes the the ratio of
the two model counts
notice in particular that if i know how to do this i know how to
do this because
sachs is false if the weighted model count is zero
so by doing this in particular we also know how to do you know ordinary
logic theorem proving
finite domains right as i mentioned very previously on monday the finite domains
we haven't done this for different domains and it's an interesting problem
so i'm assuming function free finite domains her interpretation
otherwise things get more complicated
as you know
my question
but you know for most purposes finite domains are sufficient
so we certainly want to solve the problem and we we've made some progress towards
that but you know for most applications that doesn't really arise
OK so now the
next question is hardly the way to model counting
so here's another them to the weighted model counting and therefore is the result of
computing now
it was
this is going to be an extension of the PLO
so like ppll i'm going to start with the base case the base case is
the case where all the clauses are satisfied right so if all clauses are satisfied
then basically all the world's
so it's the former so i just need to compute the sum of the weights
of all the world but i don't want to do that exponentially in i don't
need to because everything factorizes briefly and i can just to the product
overall that happens in the CNF
of the some of the positive and the negative little of that data
so this is a very nice is because it's very efficient
this is the way to get if all the world satisfy the CN
if CNF has an empty unsatisfied clause of course in that case still need to
return zero because there are no satisfying world's next comes the decomposition step
it's actually very important step because it's what's going to simplify our problems
this is the following steps
if you're CNF can be partitioned into sub CNN's
that do not share any atoms with each other
then i can solve the model cont for each of the CNS separately then just
multiply the results
this should be thrown into the relative to CNS don't share any atoms i can
do the model called for the first CNF into the model come for the second
c and f and the total count is just the product of the two
so if i'm not in the basic case is the first thing i look for
is the composition of the CNF into smaller cn eps
and if i can find such a decomposition you know it i mean all in
good shape because i have just bought myself an exponential reduction in the amount of
work that i have to do
of course in and then what i do is i just turned the product of
the individual model counts each of these being a recursive call to to the
of course it will often typically at least in the beginning
things will not decompose nice like that so then what i have to do is
again choose an atom
and i'm going to decompose
my model count into two parts
the model count of the world where the atom is true
and the model counts of the world where the thing is false and only to
notice that these two sets of walls are disjoint so i can just about the
to model counts so this is what i'm going to do
i'm going to return
the weight of the at times the model accounts for the world's where the atom
is true
plus the weight of the norm of the negation of that
and the model count of the world's worst that this falls the and again as
DPLL one says that the and the atom to true i can simplify went to
things and get smaller CNN
and there's my seniors get smaller smaller i'll get into something can decompose
at which point they can get even smaller and then eventually i get to the
base case and you know and i get my result
so this is your basic proposition weighted model counting works
of course we want to do this at the first order level
we don't just want to do this for propositional knowledge base
so what changes
well the basic probabilistic theorem proving schemas there exactly the same nothing trees at the
level again just as in first-order logic
but there's a couple of things that to change
the first one is when i convert my probabilistic knowledge base
two the form of a CNF and weights
now each new actor
i remember i had to define a new at for each formula and the the
and then there shift comes up again
if a lead shift goal
grow to infinity
depending on the value of w right this quantity will become some dominant and so
you end up with the maximum
the stuff that is the maximum distance which you can see an object
so should remind you of the concept of an horizon
so we get back to eyes and later on because our eyes and it's a
concept that comes in over and over and over again in cosmology and it's considered
the basis of what created all their primordial perturbations that then grew and gravity and
created the galaxies the planets and all the structure that was in the universe today
but this is the first time
you meet the concept of the cosmological horizon
OK good
if there is only one component and it wasn't cosmological constant in order to write
equation around to write a fixed function is the the age of the universe except
except but if it was a cosmological constant and then you can to do the
outside with before t to the some power but but hey since it's it's constant
then you're
friedmann equation becomes something like that the whole look
it tells me mean that they are lot parameter is always constant
so if the hubble parameter is called the means that they don't have a is
constant which means that they have an exponential expansion
makes sense
if you have nothing
and there's nothing has got some
the costume often to create more nothing and so you end up having an exponential
remember this equation
because this kind of equation will be at the base of what is called inflation
and inflation is something that is basically tell you
what created the universe as we see today
and it's all based on an equation like this
so let's write down
the distance
some physical properties
and you end up that if you like that in this case
this grows exponentially
these grows exponentially and see all the rage
is much smaller
and it is
so what happened here
you do have another arise
because this is
as far as you can
that any signal can travel
we go back to this again
later on
today we know that the composition of the universe is given by the thing which
we call the cosmic right
and i told you that we have to introduce the cosmological constant and live with
it because OK in this plot is called the dark energy but it it's so
you called that kennedy something that does about this equation of state parameter w that
makes the universe accelerator so it's less than minus one said but is not necessarily
minus one inequality cosmological constant with added to parameters exactly minus one and so on
this cosmic by has been denied by looking at data and actually fitting the data
with the cosmological constant but anyway so what this is telling you and later on
i'll tell you how we got to know the cosmic by there's a lot of
called out there's a little bit of atoms there is a lot of this very
we the stuff and some radiation the base of the
so let me try to motivate there is more than meets the eye
so in the solar system we know that there is the sun and the planets
the planet them shine the sun does
so if you if you were an alien living in on another sort of system
it would see the sun but it's not necessarily see the planets
and the probability of hair the whole view of you or your thread that there
is a lot of work going on in trying to find what are called extrasolar
planets and it's and it's a tough job
if the ball styrofoam but it continues going in that direction
so the european pong ball has actually better being than you found
and then we get all
i'm going to a
who's involved
what we got to do now
some of you the
in the ball position
they latter i invite you to come down to get a little closer
all right now
are you roughly ready
right but there is one other piece of information is very important and i got
to tell you
and that as only falls
for their chemistry professor
of thanks
going to what your
i have all the particle want
and as
i now comes the moment of truth
how many of you had an alpha particle that share
OK now i got it now
so i see
keep your hands up because there's something like that makes a little hard for me
to see so i don't see anybody in the section here
any more
get everybody
at that
six alpha particles that they get OK
so now
we have to calculate some probability theory
probability of backscattering
the number six
divided by
two hundred eighty seven
and that gives me
zero point zero two
here in one extra significant figure
and to find out their probability
and i love this in year
i've already done the calculation i got you find that the diameter
the correct number of significant figures is zero points have
and the actual diameter of these walls
zero point eight
so you guys that's very great job
so i gave it works right
that's how they calculated the diameter of the nucleus
that that
no one or nothing else involved in this edit the principle behind how it was
OK very simple
the principle
behind how
the four was discovered
OK and the five corps was revealed
that's right
we got the problem they to
the scientific community here
in the early nineteen eleven nineteen twelve right after the discovery of the nucleus
the problem is now
we know we have gotten away as we know it began electron
what the structure of the atom how does the
electron and the nucleus
in particular what we have to do
is we have to ask
what is the force of attraction
keeps the nucleus and the electron together
so we're going to talk here about this
o description
and we talk about the force of the interaction works
there are four known fundamental forces
what the force
that is the weakest force
gravity and
what is the cause
that's the stronger force
electromagnetic absolutely
what's the next round of applause
the weak force
and four
all right we can strong force
these are trouble
nuclear forces
with the nucleus
that's what keeps the protons and neutrons in the core
for the most part the weak and the strong force don't
in chemistry
with the exception for beta decay for some radioactive element that's where you need to
think about particular the weak force
gravity also
o gravity
actually has no
non consequences camp
i mean there is one but there is no known consequence
all of chemistry
tied up in the four
the electromagnetic force
now what i'm going to do is i'm going to simplify it a little bit
and just call this the coulomb force
and why is going to do that will be you will more obvious when you
get a o to call it the coulomb interaction
and we know what the the coulomb force law
the coulomb force law
it is found
i have a hard positive time
which is slightly
call for e
and at some distance are the distance now between the nucleus
and the negatively charged particles
which is my electron
i can describe
the four
of attraction between these
the electron the nucleus by the following expression that force
which is a function of the distance between the two charges
was just the man to
o of the charge and the negatively charged particles
nine the magnitude and the positively charged particles
four five one or
we're where
i'm going to treat this force just for simplicity purposes right now
a scalable
i'm not going to talk about the direction
but because this is
the force between a positive and negative charges an attractive force
that's one down here the steps one
permittivity of vacuum
it's in there for
doing our unit conversion correctly
morning everyone
collateral here primarily
accounting this tournament he is number students
has shown
we return to familiar story
this is part two
the empire strikes back so last time our adversary the
the graph
came to us with
the problem we had to find we had a source and we have a directed
graph with weights on the edges
and they were all nonnegative
and there was happiness and the we try and over the empire by designing dykstra
algorithm and you know very efficiently finding a single source for pastors pathway from s
to every other vertex today however
the death star
has a new tricks up its sleeve and we have a negative weights potentially we're
going to have to somehow deal with in particular negative weight cycles
and we saw that when we have a negative weight cycle we could just keep
going around and around and around and go back in time further and further and
further we can get to be arbitrarily far back in the past and so there's
there's no shortest path because whatever path you take a shorter one
so we want to address that issue today
and we're going to come up with
a new algorithm actually simpler than dykstra but not as fast
called the bellman ford algorithm
and it's going to allow negative weights and in some sense allow negative weight cycles
maybe not
much as you will find out
we have to leave room for a sequel
OK so the bellman ford algorithm invented by two guys as you might expect it
the shortest path weights
so it makes no assumption about the weights weights are arbitrary and
it's going to compute the shortest path weights remember this notation delta as comedy
it is that the weight of the shortest path from s to t
as it was called source vertex
and so we want to compute these weights for all vertices little
the claim is that computing from s everywhere
is known
harder than computing as to a particular location these so we're going to do for
all of the
still going to be the case here
and it allows negative weights
and this is the good case but there's an alternative
which is the bellman ford may just say well this is the negative weight cycle
and in that case it'll just say so
this is a negative weight cycle exists
some of the
some of these deltas or minus infinity
and that seems weird so bellman ford it is well presented today is intended for
the case where there are no negative weight cycles which is more intuitive
it's sort of allows them but it will just report them in that case it
will not give delta values you can change the to give delta values in that
case but we're not going to see
OK so
let's start with this
mini tutorial on line learning
this is i think therefore to school i i think in this area
sometimes it happens in other large deviations in the number of
courses and you give me and there was a a peak easier
so some of you may have seen these things may be interesting in our some
place a so
there's gonna be some overlapping with with what i said to bring in a couple
of months ago
the plan is to plan which is managed a little bit of ambitious assignments keep
some something
and this is meant to be a very simple and basic introduction to the themes
certain things in online learning will learn in particularly i will
look at the are binary classification
most of essentially all of online learning has to deal with it deals with linear
and the
simplest is the summit is the binary problem so that's why we will focus on
then i will see a few as a certain number of things on the perceptron
which is the most basic example of online in about for binary classification
and then we'll move on to analyse a little bit in detail in the case
linearly separable datasets and all the possible mistake bounds so that you can prove for
this specific sequence sequences of data
and the further we
want to discuss it with the relationship between online learning and convex optimisation and this
is something that has been booming in in the last two or three years
and i will say very few very simple things and so very basic and that
shows how few concepts basic concepts from convex optimization can help in the analysis of
then i will time permitting i will talk a bit about all the kernel based
on line learning especially memory bounded only conveys the learning and possibly
online SVM and active learning and maybe not outright two took over the
this last
part two which is the relation the weight
you can convert analysis four o four online algorithms to use classical statistical risk bound
for the
statistical learning model which is may be more familiar to many of you
OK let's start with the classification
so the basic scenario the mind when you talk about online classification is this one
you can think of a
a system for providing
online classification of text
documents so you have a stream of unlabelled the text
that documents that
are fed into classification system and every time a new document comes in the system
guesses labelled
which we think of as the binary labels of for instance is this document about
and that the label is given to the user that possibly provide feedback
and if they make a supposed to be the true the the ground truth for
the semantics of
for the category of that document and in in the most general case the label
is actually something that
the system asks explicitly to the user
so the most the most scenario is an active learning scenario in which the labels
might be requested or not but for the most part of this talk we will
think that the label is always provided by the user
so after each classification of the document to the user is providing the labels to
the to the true label the ground truth to the system so this might be
plausible or implausible depending on the specific application that you have in mind but i'll
argument about it so i want to talk about linear classifiers usually
i mean these things so we have
before the online model we have a stream of data instances
is is actually this this is our data
and these data instances are encoded as a vector scenario dimensional space
as usual for many applications for most the learning algorithms and actually for linear learning
algorithms let's say
and then there's four with each data instance there's is a binary label associated with
it which tells the true classification of the document or that they tighter so why
he is going to be the true label of xt
we will assume there is a linear learner maintains something classifier
wt minus one which predicts the label of the current instance with by taking this
the sign of the sign of the inner product between
the with parameter and the current system
OK so that's the picture and of course you you know them
you might know this notion of margin which he's
can be associated with a certain with the confidence of classification of a certain except
given we parameter w
and so the margin is just the distance between the distance of the
let the tip of x point x to the hyperplane that defines that separates the
positive classification of w
if you can see this can read this it's like a power law with exponential
exp with exponential cutoff right so now i'm blocking access to the minus itself five
times e to the minus x lambda
and you know you can see now i feel i feel my data perfectly that's
on in this case
the value of the exponent doesn't basically doesn't change what changes as here i get
this exponential cutoff thing
coming in
so the point of all these being is
one has to be careful how to how to fit
we estimate power law degree distributions
and the last
picture shown is this is an example so both these networks have the same number
of nodes in the same number of edges this is how
the network will look like if the network would be random and this is how
it looks if it's a power law or is
the other if it has the power law degree distribution or any other sort of
foot is that things is called scale free networks and just looking at the sort
of you can see that
in scale free networks try to have a lot of nodes have degree one is
sort of a few
you know this hubs where everyone is connected
and you know webgraphs web graph looks like that and doesn't look like this
and then i'll tell you later what is the consequence is that since the graph
when graph looks like this what can i do that i could do if the
web would be like that
so now we can ask OK what kind of simple mechanisms
would generate
networks of such structures and not such structure
it's sort of
the ingredients that make a lot of this model ceased this one can use the
following so what we think of is that i have a network lowers becoming one
of the time so a new knowledge economy to create and link next to the
existing nodes of the network so now the question is
what kind of simple mechanism can this node use
basically the idea is to have this preferential attachment with the idea is that
the probability of linking to a particular node is proportional to the degree so basically
is proportional to the number of connections the node already has
so for example on the web what this corresponds to is to say if i
create a new web page
how likely you might link to some you know small degree that page versus i
don't agree with the outcome of something that already has a lot of things right
so yes we are more likely to link to hide the web page or in
citation networks you could ask what was basically discovered a long time ago in sixty
five was the proportion of new citations of paper gets is basically proportional to proportional
to the number of citations
it already has so the idea is if you have a lot of citations you
acquire more while if you have few you sort of applied less and less
and this is this model is based on this herb simon result the basic he
called it
basically that power laws
much from his rich get rich get rich get richer or cumulative advantage principle where
the idea is sort of the more than more you have
the more you know the more you are going to have to write like probability
of u getting a link is proportional to how many links you already have so
the more things you can the higher probability of having
and what you can prove is that
such mechanism when applied in the network case we give you graphs that have probably
degree distributions with exponent of three
and what should they also say is that there are many flavors images preferential attachment
comes into
in two modelling networks and there are many extensions so one drawback of sort of
the the the process that i just described is that for example the only knowledge
we have advantage right sort of the older than out the longer it is in
the network the more likely it is to attract edges so he knows will tend
to have higher degrees than sort of nodes are joined the in the network later
and you can
you can forget to get rid of this by introducing something that the people call
note fitness when the idea is that you have some kind of a priority stickiness
of often also on outcomes with simply assigned stickiness in this way we can sort
of make up
forty four for the fact that it is younger not particularly old
the other sort of different model that came from a more computer science
he point of view is is is something that's called the copying model basically the
idea is
that you know realization that picking up node proportional to to the degree is basically
the same speaking and an edge in the network right because i males have more
edges adjacent to them
and then how this model which is to say and you know comes
it selects uniformly at random at a particular node then it links to its neighbour
basically you are getting the same effect as if you would be
making these guys
proportional to their degree
two a
so what you can also do then is to ask this preferential attachment really hold
so if i would have some network data when i see how edges appear over
time meaning that you know
i get to see exactly the edge arrival sequence of of the
just in the network then i can directly observe the mechanisms that drive
evolution or creation of the network
we were able to get this for for online social networks in flickr
delicious answers the game
but basically in all of this we have users that people and to create links
among themselves and for every link you know the exact moment when the link to
link up here
so what we can do then is you can on the road this through evolution
of the network and whenever a new edge
yes you can ask what was the degree of the target where the note that
the edge attached to
and here is the massive graphs
so what now and such go to explain it so basically the exercise side of
this is the degree of the target node and this is the probability of linking
one of the
OK so gnp so not in a graph where i think we just created uniformly
at random then
the probability of an edge does not depend on the degree of the node right
regardless of what is your degree
the probability of getting a match is the same with all the way right so
good evening
can you give me the back
thank you for these kind words and i'm very pleased to be here and to
i think this the beginning we started a few minutes early
i'm very pleased to be here and two
you will little bit of historical perspective
on data clustering it's not a new field
and the large number of
people in different disciplines
who have been interested in data clustering i was first exposed to data clustering in
nineteen seventy when i first took my
graduate course in pattern recognition at that time the classical book by two down heart
was not
yet available it was published in nineteen seventy two but he had the
the draft form of the book
and i learned something from about data clustering from that book
and it's still one of the classic books are so like this information
perhaps give a slightly different perspective on
probably not
about all the different
one which has been done in this area
i'll do my best
so as it so happens
about two months ago
and archaeologist contacted me
about doing some analysis
of the images in and for what i'm not sure how many of you know
about or what these beautiful temples in cambodia
which were lost after the coming kingdom
i went out
were discovered in the
about eighty hundreds by by the friends who were
who had occupied cambodia
and since then many countries japan
franz germany
as well as united nations investing huge amount of money to reconstruct these temples
it's even been featured in the
in the action thriller
a tomb raider by
the lower graph
so the problem pose the following
the temple contains
i was there about a year and a half ago so
i remember the temple quite well
it contains a unique value of about two thousand
who have been depicted in full-body portraits
the full body portrait can see as well as some of the facial images
and this archaeologist and wanted to know what facial bites represented in these
portraits and contacted the number of face recognition companies
and then he was directed to us because we have been doing some face recognition
so the problem is basically to understand
what kind of fish types represented at the commander of the high bar no or
or whatever it is
so this was the problem of how to we cluster the
the answer of faces up to rise a
sounds to me for goddess of theory
and one of the first things we did was to
identify landmarks
on the fission
and then shape alignment in order to find
the similarity
between two faces
and once you have a similarity between two faces can start doing the grouping and
in many ways in which we can compute the
similarity between two vectors can compute the euclidean distance between the points system
there were templates line
energy model in order to to
to align the two sets of points and then you can do in this particular
case started out with ten
ten facial images and you can construct what is called a dendrogram using the singling
out more completely
and then you can
so that showed some similarity value in order to find clusters so if i look
at single link
clustering algorithm
i can see that there are there is a cluster clusters shown in green
brits is
which is this one two nine ten cluster consisting of three insects
and the cluster consisting of seven and eight and four five don't seem to form
in two and
distinct clusters with the point is that these two different approaches of group starting with
the same similarity matrix in
very different
next thing he said is there another way of obtaining a similarity matrix
and this
can be done by using the well-known concept called ordination of multidimensional scaling which was
proposed in
in nineteen fifty or nineteen sixties bell labs and the idea is given in the
similarity matrix like in and these points
in some metric space and this case you ten points over ten by ten similarity
and i can start the system by the similarity matrix and i can embed them
two-dimensional space you can embed them in four dimensional five but for visualisation purposes i
three-dimensional space
so these are the points on and i apply
the well known
clustering algorithm to the data
and then i get three
for last year
shown here in terms of these classes
fairly well that's one of the clusters optimal singling
so the sound a little bit and added top the
the knowledge of the things that this grouping seems to be
to be somehow consistent
with what he thinks in terms of the facial patterns and of
getting a database of two thousand
visual images and we will try to continue
this work
this is just one example of where
tools like
cluster analysis in order to to analyse the data
but a large variety of problems
we need to
i and effectively
utilize this data
and in order to to do that
we need tools for data visualization
and categorisation
and this is the in the form of
that's lots of the form images and video the amount of data which is becoming
available is huge and in order to
i understand or interpret data
we need some tools
and this is where
the field of exploratory data analysis
got started to was one of the better-known statistician who was
one of the first proponents of the sort of basically point system exploratory data analysis
a collection of techniques to gain insight into the data
and what underlying structural generate hypotheses detect anomalies are outliers
solved problem
OK so how are we going to do this we put faces of people as
the columns of the data images within applied this the algorithm
and the algorithm reason will remove all the defects we see in in faces of
images that renders the recognition problematic so if we applied to and three images like
and what we get is we get you know clean face in the middle
and then we get all season on the idea it is like cast shadows specular
points that show up in the sparse component
in practice to make it work though
it's not true that the major faces will be exactly around because to be lower
and they have to be well aligned
and so
the next slide is to say which is due to my colleague and now i
have not much to do with the slide you're about to see the next slide
is to say well
it's only after alignment that you have low rank plus sparse structure so we have
to find the alignment as well
and so the idea is quite simply says well let's try to find
and not an alignment that is the transformation so that after transformation my data set
is as low rank plus sparse as possible
can we can just now we leave the complex world because the fact that we
have to deal find is defamation is is not convex but we can try to
do things anyway
all right
so just to show you in principle
the interest of these methods let's suppose look at the building from a different angle
and then
OK in front of it have trees and so on some shots another shot it's
not enough to try to apply this is find the defamation so that defamation and
low income and low rank plus sparse as possible and to show you the results
here the result is is the way she transforms the images this is a low
rank component which is the building unoccluded and sparse component which is of course this
tree including the building
so it seems to work
quite well in practice so people have done e and his colleagues have done a
lot of work and again it's not mine anymore what you see is you take
people the faces of of people
this faces are misaligned as you can see
and then they are corrupted so i don't see if you see patches that are
in front of the eyes his nose and so on and so you're going to
try to align them so you run this algorithm trying to find for each image
deformations that as a whole you've got as much low rank plus sparse structure as
and so you see the output
the data matrix of the low component is that actually perfectly almost perfectly aligned those
images and of course removed those occlusion that include eyes nose mouth
and so on and so forth
here is the thing that i find the most
i don't actually almost check it before i can talk about that here we so
what they've done in this case it took pictures of the guy
under serious
conditions so is the same person but he is wearing sunglasses here is the car
is has something in front of his mouth he has incentive in from his wearing
hat he again and so on
and then you apply designers and so we're not going to do in face recognition
on something like it's going to be very difficult so let's use this as a
preprocessing step
so use as a pre processing step you the alignment alone can sparse component simultaneously
and what you get out of these cells the low rank component that is sparse
component and so you see all these non idealogies sunglasses issue here then you impute
the eyes
so hats showing here you know you've removed had removed the whig you remove the
hand in front of your mouse and so now
perhaps you can see this to face recognition
as you know if you do for example if you retrieve images of the internet
neural you do averaging of faces to get the typical average phase before you do
alignment and repairing you gonna get extraordinarily blurry pictures it's very hard to recognise people
but if you to applies alignment and repairing the entity performs is low rank plus
sparse decomposition before you take averages then all of a sudden everything gets much much
because you align the right stuff
you have the right stuff
of course you can use it for other applications as well
you can say well you know this is an digit recognition problem you know this
is the way people could ride number three you could say well what if i
my name is high low
and from new york university of torrent all
and the
people going to pretend is uncorrelated multilinear principal component analysis
three successive variance maximisation
so here is the outline of my talk study the motivation of this work
and then i propose the
uncorrelated multilinear PCA anger angry them
and that's the
experimental evaluations we've be presented
and finally
i we try to conclude it
so here is the data that we consider in this work
so it is tensorial data it tends to have the various definitions in very few
the cancer in this work we refer to
multidimensional arrays
and the generalisation of vector and metric concepts so
yes there and most we call it and sold it has
so better
in the first order has and that is a second order tensor
and the tensorial data
it has a wide range of applications
such as applications involving images
we use it this
and stream these all data mining data
and here i chose
two example of tensors the first one is a second order tensor
it has two most
the color special column understand vision role models
the the typical
graylevel CC image
and the second one
it's the third order tensor which is the binary silhouettes its gates
and has three modes
the spatial color vision rules
at the time of
so in the the second order tensor
so the problem we have it
mention entity reductions so why do we want to reduce the dimension of the hands
of this value and a very high dimensional
this leads to the problem of true of dimensionality
so why this is so
it's true because it's still this kind of high dimensional data is computationally very expensive
to handle
and many classifiers
they perform very poorly
in high dimensional space given the small number of
ten years and the which is of often two in practice
but in fact
if you look at a cost of tens of death
they are mostly highly constrained to a subspace
a manifold of intrinsically
low dimensional like the face the game they also
constant right
dimensionality to popular methods
and they also
some kind of feature extraction
the mission of we transform this high dimensional
into a low dimensional space
well this information
raise up to two time two
retain most of the the underlying structure
and the focus of this work is unsupervised dimensionality reduction and in particular PCA based
angry that using the well-known linear methods to produce
uncorrelated features
it retain as much as possible the variations of the original data
but there's one
one thing we should be aware that PC
the lingam method who need to reshape
this time ten tournament to
are you will hire you need to reshape the into vector
so this will result in a very high
the two high computational and memory demand
and another thing that this kind of receiving the really great natural structure in original
so this kind of of
to the development of marketing year
and rhythms
the track features
directly from the
tensor objects from the tensor representation so here are some of the existing work that
is around one
it's probably in two thousand one
and the two dimensional PCA it in two thousand four
and the generalised to low rank approximation of matrices
which is i think the best the
good to know what people
i think that about two thousand five
and of the generalized
he is
and the other one is the cold concurrent subspaces analysis
it's true proposed in two thousand five
and another one
is martin it he's a probably eight is really
the difference between this
in this monument at the linear methods that one property that these kind of monuments