the simplest possible
but the problem is
you can't really defined
first of all you can't really justify that this is this will give you the
best answer
as again as i said before you can justify these
postulates right there is no proof that the simplest answer is the correct one
and second of all
you can't
define simplicity
because it's not objective there are many
the ways in which you could you could measure it and everyone would have different
i mean some people tend to say that the the right notion of simplicity is
what is called come come over complexity
which is a measure of the length of the shortest programme
that can
you know generates a sequence or that kind of stuff
if there is some function but even that
is not completely objective because when you define the length of the shortest programme you
first have to define in which programming language
you're right before
which means that every programming language would give rise to different notion of them
even though
you can prove that asymptotically
they are all equivalent
at least in the languages
complete during combat
in practice on finite sequences each programming language would give you a different notion of
so if i if you observe a finite sequence as we did before
there is again no
no reason to choose one or another
it seems that we are doing right
i'm just saying i i keep saying OK we can't do anything so
what's the point
well let's see maybe we can do something about
it means we first have to kind lower our expectations we want to prove that
something is
the right thing to do or i mean we want to prove that there is
an optimal
one way of doing induction but we can at least try to get some more
so let me now defined
probability and discuss a bit about what probability means because you've heard a lot
probably before in
previous lecture about probabilities maybe you're also used that a lot
but i want to
if you make use think again about what is probability and what it means
the probability
to me is just the way to formalise reasoning under this convenience
we define two assigned numbers three
and it relies on on these
simple actions
the probability of an event negative
probability of certain events is one
and then you have these
like these documents probability that some event if there is some intersection you can just
and while generally you can introduce this
and sigma additivity of the problems probability but it's not really relevant to understand
OK so that that's pretty simple
three convenience can
make it easy computation with these things
but the question is what does it mean
more precisely how you can measure these numbers or how can you decide which is
the right number one
there are a number of ways to interpret these numbers and interpretation here means assigning
meaning to a given number
one of the simplest one is the so-called frequentist interpretation
the the frequentist interpretation
probabilities are relative frequencies
you know
how many times a certain event occurs
divided by how many times you try this
and will get into detail
objectivism is
one is the same and you can say
the probability still frequency but now this because he is not observed as what is
an but it's kind of hostility that something that exists
and you have the subjectivist point of view which is that well probabilities are just
believe is just something that we think is true but there is no way to
prove that it's true
so probability as frequencies
so what you do is that as i said
that's natural
you repeat a given experiment and times
and in the event of interest occurs
times then he overran is your estimate of the probability
and you can even define the probability of the seven as
the game
you can say well if i were to repeat these experiments infinity in number of
times eventually these limit might want summer and this is how i define problem
OK that's kind of clear easy but the problem is
you can't always repeat experiments and also you
i really can be infinitely experiment so you cannot really
i have a measure of these numbers by experimenting because you you can't really read
all right so let's just look at this this prior issue because it actually is
a great great thing to add constraint on i think it's good that people are
you were asking about that
and we've got this notion
over prior
which is
which of these hypotheses which of these lines
do we think are likely before we see any data
we've got some space
we're expecting
the two different classes to appear somewhere in this space and for the to be
some line which
which bisects are classes
then where should they be in are
are kind of
the distribution over those different ways before seeing any data is what we call the
so it's kind of generated from
from a prior
i just realized here i've got an old version of the code doesn't actually do
this quite right so we can
one thing we can do is see what happens when you sample from the wrong
i have code which samples from prior that takes these points defining line uniformly
in a square region including the data
so if
if we run prior to the data points in europe just ignore them
this is i think a hundred different lines samples from our prior and you can
already can see there's this
for empty space in the middle which doesn't really seem
quite what we're interested in we want to have
lines everywhere
and if we
if we put a few more
let's try to thousand of those guys
all right now we can see is definitely something up with this prior
it's under representing lines which which cut of this region here so this is this
is the the mean of our data point right so this is
really the region where we most wanted to be lines and is the bit where
we're neglected
so i
and apparently innocuous decision
so just taking these points
uniform is well taken points uniformly across the whole field and wrong the
worked out the line based on the
the problem the vector perpendicular from this
i mean of the data to that point
actually we that part of the input space there
so we just had this version with the broken
prior to show you but if you look online to find the code samples from
the great
OK so more tricky than it seems getting getting the right product but getting the
right prior is crucial to
being able to this integration
over the
over the whole space of parameters and getting this this nice posterior distribution
all right we could
well we've had so far is
a fairly simple model
and you might notice some shortcomings with this model
so let's think first example for
an example of the failure mode of this particular model
what if the data was not linearly separable
what we mean by linear we separable
it is
this is are
our input space
and we've got to draw the
class one zeros
so there's the nose nose the axes
an example we saw here
it turns out we can draw several lines
in between but what if we've got some outliers
on both sides
all right in this previous example i showed you
there's not going to be any single line
with positive likely it
every single line we can draw
is going to you might nearly separate the two classes
but not completely
so every single sample from our prior
we'll have zero likelihood and we will be able to make any
any progress and inference with that was that likelihood function
the issue here is that
we've got
for all of the
data points
when we're looking at the
the probability of that line
given some data
i'm going to call that
d for the distance
to the
decision boundary
and the likelihood that we have
that we have so far
that is the likelihood of some line
given that distance
actually by the distance
OK sure list let's keep their distance just remember that the distance is given
by a
for some
some input space and some for some
hypothesis some critical line w and b
that distances
going to be given
by the way xt busby positive one side negative on the other
if we
take the prior we have at the moment that's basically
the step function
and we can kind of makes science work and if we
define every class to be o one or negative one say the yes is our
ones know is the negative ones
then this d
if we
multiply all that by the class
this one?
a little more uncertainly there.
that's OK because we've got a probabilistic
models here. so so what's going on? think this as as a math problem, right.
there's this infinite set of all objects, and it's truly infinite because we generated with the
generative programme,
and somewhere in this infinite space of all objects is an infinite but very constrained subset that you could call the tufas.
and somehow you're able to pick out the boundaries of that set. not perfectly but roughly
from just these few points randomly sampled within it.
and we we work on these kinds of problems
whether we're thinking about the  they often arise in language, or, for example, causal learning,
right. so you know again
it's it's a great time to be addressing an AI audience
because of you know the the the
very broad recognition of the work of Judea Pearl that's that's not only revolutionized AI but also
many other fields.
and so we're all familiar now with various kinds principles that can be used to learn causal structure from
observational and interventional data.
but think about the way
that children often learn cause causal structure. sometimes they get it wrong but, you know,
quite quite often get it right
from just, not not even enough data to sort of compute the parents of conditional dependence
and independence that're at the heart of classic Bayesian causal structure learning algorithms, but even
just a few, again, a few data points that aren't even enough to establish a
reliab a reliable pattern of statistical dependence or correlation.
right, like the right kind of spatial temporal coincidence.
how how how are children able to do that?
I would say that the most exciting thing that we're that we're getting at here is
larger scale systems of knowledge, what are sometimes called intuitive theories. not just learning a
single concept but systems of concepts that together describe some common sense domain, like common sense physics or
common sense psychology. so just to illustrate this a little bit, i'm talking about these kinds
of problems and you'll see,
I think, hopefully, the AI relevance of these problems.
let's say we're interested in understanding a visual scene like the one in the upper
left. we don't just want to know what is where to recognize objects and localize them but we
wanna understand what's going on in terms of the physics, like this table of supporting those objects
or certain objects appra must be pro very likely to be attached to the back wall but
you couldn't move them. others are hanging there so they're not gonna fall but you
could lift them up.
right, or looking at that
looking at the at the construction scene, how do you know which of those planks of wood
you could move or which are which, you know, which are free, which are attached, which
are absolutely vital to supporting the structure.
we use this kind of intuitive physical knowledge
to diagnose situations that are
maybe accidents waiting to happen or requiring special care, like this stack of dishes.
and then think about social interaction between people. how do we look at the scene
whether we're just an observer watching one of these scenes or a participant?
and just get instantly what's going on, what what the what the different people in the scene are
thinking, what they want, what they're feeling? how do we get at their
their mental states
from their actions? that's a kind of intuitive psychology.
these are hard problems. if we could solve this, you know, we'd pretty much be done
and this. but these are the these are the problems that we're setting our sights on.
we we wanna get there by backing off to some easier problems. and many AI researchers
as well as cognitive scientists have pointed out that you could get at a lot of these
basic kind of common sense physics and psychology by just studying what small children
do with stacks of blocks on their own building up things or in combination. and
i'll show you some research that's really trying to get this but you can start
even simpler let me show you a couple to other demos but i think are
some of the nicest way stacy
these corps common sense into the physical intuitive psychological theories that work and again show
you these these these mines remarkable ability to make inferences from sparse data
so here are a couple of little movies the first one
is by south gingerbread to developmental psychologists it's from a study with thirteen month-old infants
so just watch this all played a couple of times
and you can see here
well what do you see you see two balls a blue ball
displayed again and a red ball
and the rolling on a green surface with some kind bij obstacles right
but if you want to describe this what's the most natural way to describe what's going on
chasing right yeah that's that's i heard a few different people it looks like the
blue ball is chasing the red ball and the red trying to get away
and while the it's it's an interesting kind chasing because it's also kind of a
slightly dumb chasing right the blue ball thinks he can fit through those holes that
you can't actually write anything stepped back out and go around so you attributing a
goal to the blue ball and also to the red the rebels trying to get
a kind desire as well as a belief may be a false belief in this case
that's he thinks he can fix some holes which you can as well as some
over loss functions to the right delta
OK so that's kind of the core problem the decision tree interface
all right well you get two arguments that functions could be two perspectives on how
to get rid of the unknown you start with the delta x or you start
with the data
and those two percent recall frequentist and bayesian
and that's been my arguments for why there are two of them because only two
arguments of loss functions
so the sum of the frequencies one first so
the frequencies looks at the loss functions as well you get two unknowns there let's
start with the x one try to do something about turning that random acts
into a
into a number somehow
well ran the internet whenever we think its expectation
let's take an expectation of this quantity
the second especially the export
well expected with what respect what problem distribution
well it use the same fate to take our expectation as is the the loss
OK so i don't need to know the truth upper right to say whatever the
truth is i think especially that of this for all theta o look at all
possible true
so we get a risk functional three-quarters risk riskier the function of data i've picked
which state opera or is the truth
but this quantity here this is the data is the expectation
under the distribution indexed by data and its expression over x o x goes away
and we just get paid on the left-hand side i that's the key so if
you need the definition of frequent this is probably good as any that this is
kind of one message i want to get permission a lot of people in machine
learning are frequentist a lot of the work is at least frequentist but you never
see there were frequent there are people people talk about the definition of what it
means to be frequencies i'll hear it is this is the here here's what it
means you take expectation of perfect stated what i was to act and doing that
what you're you're being not bayesian that point you are taking expectations expected other axes
are over the entire sample space
not the exit you saw
but other actors you might see
OK so that's what these difficulties you're looking other possible data could have gone to
the unconditional perspective that's what every right down e in equation and its need to
average over x
you just very with bayesian right you're going towards the frequency of that's clear
OK so that's what the frequentist does get started now this function are
and they said well i don't know what truth is it could be any data
and now i need still converges thing to a single number
how do i convert that to a single number
OK and now there's many possibilities and has been huge literature fifty years the kind
of work on ways to think about turning this into a single number the one
probably the most about is many max
we'll take the
the maximum of the of this frequentist risk overall theta and find the procedure that
has the minimum of the maximum risk
a lot of good work has come out the minimax perspective that's one way to
take the fate apart by taking the maximum over all things and then taking the
minimum minimax but there are other ways to do this if you take subclasses of
procedures you also delta x could be a subclass maybe all unbiased estimators or or
some other in varying or invariant
estimators one and that subclass this or fate might actually have a
a simple characterization you can actually get a single number over some subclasses
and there are many other kind of ways trying to approach i think it ready
be the average over theta
right but when you average over theta you get average some distribution on theta at
that point you become bayesian
OK i tried to think about distribution play so the frequencies are willing to do
so all
you are
you more
all right
they were
so i
now let
i are
one which i
you all
you know which
all it
if you
and you get data
and by
so the the
and these two
it's not
so reason the
can alter the
in the paper
and we across
the model
you time
so they can continue to
they are all the
they not here
first one
and to the war
the was
there are the people or the million
and the
and you
that's nine
hours per iteration
we've done
that's the themes of this search
and i
you here
more and more and you you know
i'm in early on
the latter
from the
they find in red
are you indeed collection today which is human
and then you
well mean
it's here
and you
it's time
you that
and all of
i know
we're only
and you
so why you want to
on other hand
but if you
this is just great
of the american public
continued to take the position
it states are entitled to to use force
quoting if there is
only if there is strong evidence that the country is in imminent danger of being
so a large majority rejected the
a bipartisan
so-called pre-emptive war
and i agree with the recent united nations panel and incidentally also agree with the
former non-aligned movement the governments of the eighty percent of the world's populations but there
are of course
ignore the
dismissed with reason
the legitimacy of these force is not the only issue
on which public opinion in the united states
diverges sharply from elite political culture
to take another current example
which also raises issues of survival
it's commonly reported that the united states refused to sign the kyoto treaty months ago
that's true only if the phrase united states excludes population
who overwhelmingly supported ratification of the treaty
so enthusiastically in fact
the majority of bush voters
i believe that he agreed with the united states should join
large majorities also believe
the united states should
accept the jurisdiction of the international criminal court and the world works
and should rely on the united nations to take the lead in international crises
including issues of security reconstruction and political transition in iraq
most of the population
even believe that the united states
should abandon its security council veto
accepting majority rule
true on other issues
large majorities believe that the united states
should rely on diplomatic and economic measures
more than military ones
in the so-called war on terror
an overwhelming majorities in the past
favor increased government spending
on health care education and other
social spending all of this is in sharp opposition to public policy
studies revealing this fact
were released by the most prestigious institutions that monitor public attitudes
shortly before the
november two thousand four
presidential elections
plainly there of critical importance to functioning democracy
the studies reveal
that both political parties are far to the right of the population and many of
the most crucial issues
they were scarcely recorded
not mentioned in national press
these observations unfortunately generalise
lending further weight to the judgement of the strategic analysts
i quoted earlier
about the crisis of western democracy
a crisis is serious
that turning to
china to rescue us from disaster
washington's unilateral resort to force
was articulated publicly by the bush administration
and its national security strategy member
in two thousand two
breaking no new ground however
even before the two thousand election
condoleeza rice writing
foreign affairs
and establishing journal condemned what she called
the reflexive appeal to notions of international law and norms and the belief that the
support of many states or even better of institutions like the united nations is essential
to the legitimate exercise of power
that she says is completely wrong
referring of course to exercise of power by the united states
the usual
except in real
extremist positions
has long been conventional among the powerful
illustrate of the key to the liberal end of the spectrum in the united states
take one case elder statesman kennedy advisedby matches
in form the american society of international law
in nineteen sixty three
that no legal issue arises when the united states response to a challenge to its
our and christy
he was speaking shortly after the cuban missile crisis
which brought the world to the brink of of nuclear war
two months earlier
as a result in large part of the s international terrorism
turning to the nineteen nineties the clinton doctrine was that the united states has the
according to resort to unilateral use of military power
to defend vital interests
such as ensuring uninhibited access
the key markets energy supplies and strategic resources
is even without the pretext was later revised
taken literally
the clinton doctrine is more expensive than bush's national security strategy
which aroused enormous
here concern around the world
and elicited very harsh criticism even within the foreign policy establishment in the united states
so that the charge cannot easily no
no no no
we don't want any accidents just sit there
OK now make sure that your feet always on this plate
because we need very good
in some way not on the wood
every question
alex alex alex alex is going to hold this in his hand which are ten
you hold a higher
and when eric
when alex
get charged
you will see that the ten cells also get charged
you should hold the
the the tenth of themselves in your hand the metal yes
and so the ten will get charged with equal charges repel each other and so
you will see that the ten cells will start doing this
so that will tell you then that alex's
going to get charged
and i also have ten cells in my hands and so you'll see that i
also get charged
you might be able to tell that this charge
it's the opposite charge of mean that's the conservation
of charge
then i'll touch alex
and we'll see whether
there's any reason to believe that indeed
there is charge moving between us that means
an electric current
you're ready for this
you still not nervous yet
OK man i gotta get a nice bit of piece of cat fur
is a good one
and i will join you
funny you know there
but i am
this is dangerous stuff
OK so holding like test
there we go
ten cells i should have i should have had mine with
i'll get my i'll get mine
just stay a you are right
OK you see and also charged
these charts
look at me look at me
look at me about this you know
one of the torture knows we have to do this again
you have to do it again
OK turned to me
the way one
going to make it worse
give me to ten cells
i have here
neon flesh two
we've seen this before
now i want you to hold it in your hand
under no circumstances no matter what happened
let it go
because it will break and they very expensive
good all this in your hand
and now i'm going to beat you again
and instead of touching you know
i will not hold i'll talk to the other side
and if no current is flowing strongly enough
between him and me
you may see some light
that tells you then that indeed
that that comes later alex
you patients you perfect MIT students
so while i told that that your hand and i'm not joking when i say
don't drop that
i have to set the
the light in a very special way so that we have
i'm going to turn off
make sure i have the
michael's maybe you could help that i will be first
and then at the very last minute
before we do the discharge through the neon that you then turn all the lights
you should well you could do worse but you shouldn't
you don't need to because you just memorize you start to fill in the table
in your head
and so this is some of the things that we can quickly have that kind
of form two you just basically fill in the table as you find out what
the right answer is you you know it and you can write down
they could actually the not not input that would have been five function to learn
why do you say that because you said i don't know twice you've you had
you said i don't know if it is zero and you said i don't know
for the one
it is use
the reason why
so the function that i was just doing is deterministic is that is that fix
and also i let that example off saying it's a function from to be to
cut its sorry i was that when you say constant human you mean like
every time its input is zero it's always one yet to deterministic function in that
example if it was a probabilistic function you could learn the probabilities this two probabilities
well for each one you run a separate copy of this algorithm right so you
keep count of when you've heard zero is an input how many successes how many
failures one her one is an input how many systemic so even though this feels
for silly because you say you know i don't know thirty times in a row
and you know it it's a little more interesting if there's an input involved right
so if i tell you zero you have to learn the probability for zero and
you have to learn probably for one year keeping two separate counts and so you
might say i don't know for a while and then start knowing one of them
and then start saying i don't know again when i give you different parts
it starts of simple but as you start to compose these laws it gets more
and more interesting
i did see hand
partial hands there's a whole here go
so so the game here is if if if we're trying to predict the probability
the thing is supposed to output to me is the probability
right so that probability can be arbitrarily close to the true answer even though none
of the examples you get so you know if it's fair coin eventually should learn
to see something like a half but none of your data was the half right
i give you just zeros and ones is an example as is the case example
right so yes so i could define this more formally but
i'm being forced to do so gradually part
for their hands so we can OK so
so so this is a couple things that we can quickly learn effectively so far
we can just a single coin and
a single coin
conditioned on a small set up a finer fight sort of inputs for example
we separately
we could learn a let's say that the output
this is no input but the output is a bunch of numbers which are
the probabilities and all the examples that i give you are
draws from that
vector so you like it like something
like a bunch of coins almost bunch with coins and coin one is the probability
quite two has from quite probability point three is the probability and the examples that
i give for training are what conflict those coins and tell you which ones came
up heads and which ones tails on each trial but you can start to pull
those statistics and in the same way again so if the output is the vector
r each component is probability
then is always you can look quickly each of the components of the vector you
can quickly learn the entire vector
if the function you're trying to learn is a mapping from a big input space
is partitioned in some way and each within each partition you have to learn
some quick learnable class then you can learn the whole class because you just running
a separate quick learner for each piece of that partition
so these seem like really kind of simple obvious examples but what's nice is that
this is exactly what you need to make a standard transition function in
reinforcement learning right so all that is it's a mapping
which takes SNA is input which to partition the space and then we get to
observe are these these outcomes in was state s seven it came up as a
result yes or no
just with the pieces that we have so far we can quickly learn a transition
function and because we can quickly transition function we're going to be able to make
a PAC MDP algorithm that people already knew how to do that with any quick
learning mumbo-jumbo in between but we're going to start composing them in more interesting ways
and get some new algorithms that had been
discovered before
another thing you can also quickly and the union of two kwik learnable classes to
various ways of composing these things that are that all work out
OK more less this i think already that
they are max algorithm for boston internal what it does lead to say that this
way but we can you can think of it as what they're doing is a
quick learner transition function t and for anything it's not known it assumes that the
q values for the state action pairs have maximum reward anything that doesn't know about
yet because it has visited enough times is assumed to be really high reward nothing
could be higher and so what it does is it goes and visits those if
it can and if we can then it stays among the states that can visit
and gets near optimal reward
so it's a very simple elegant out all it's doing is counting the number of
times it tried to each state action pair when count goes over threshold it uses
the empirical distribution it is found as true
before that point it just uses some optimistic value that doesn't even try to estimate
the probability
all right so
ooh that works to get your PAC MDP bound and the total mistake to the
bounded ahead of before
and that were yes
right so so in this in this particular case what is the transition function well
for some state like
you know
the robot is thirty degrees
so it's discretized so thirty degrees and it's going to try some action
left and we were trying to estimate the probability that actually goes left say well
we've only tried it six times
that's mostly gone left but we're going to try it four more times before we
can say we've estimated that probability with extremely high
convert this state into something that you can apply only to learn
in the based techniques
you basically have to extract finite length sliding window from test sequence so
basically you may correct
for example if your sequences long let's say
one hundred
data instances
and you choose to hear sliding window of ten
you're going
the sliding window then and new according to sequencing ninety one
they so basically this sequence is represented with the new
data set of sequences
for every sliding intervened you basically trying to find
its frequency in the training data sets
and basically using this frequency has to measure for anomaly so inverse of this frequencies
basically the anomaly score if you see in this frequency more
that means that probably correspond to majority became an inverse of frequencies low so it
has long core
and then you finally combined is serving the anomaly score to obtain
anomaly detection score for all those sequences so basically since u
the entire sequence to this sliding windows combining everything two
have the final anomaly score for that for that
for the sequence
can just got everything
so in markovian techniques
more you are trying to use
the information
about transitions from one state to another this is also called state based approaches
so basically
the basics of any
the more common technique trying to estimate the probability
of transitioning between one state and another state
so in this case you think this estimate for the probability of each event of
the test sequence
conditioned on the previously observed steps
i usually try to combine the pre event probabilities to obtain an overall anomaly scores
what about how this exactly work so basically
again here
events so you sequence is combined of serious of events
so right now in the standard final state alternate
event probability is conditioned on previous
minus events so basically for every serious events
you're looking
if i can simple a and inaccessible b and c trying to see from the
how many times i have
the observation eight
if a leads to b and actually be is followed by a or something so
basically from these data trying to compute this transitional probabilities
and then the forces of these events
you have city actually series of transitions
and then you're computing
probable to have this serious of transitions from this kind of probability matrix that you
construct it from the history
so that's
that's typical of a to construct is kind of a markovian
the model
so this standard find state automated you have
if previous l minus events do not occur in training data
that means the event is ignored because you don't have this information in the people
that are constructed because if you encounter new
music if you go to this transition probability matrix you have this information we cannot
what's the probability that so you can just say that this event is ignored i'm
not saying this is normal or anomalous
there are several modifications of this finite state automaton
in his face if it's easy
the main idea is the same as here so
basically but previous l minus one minus events are treated in different ways
if this previous minus one events do not occur in training data
the event probability is zero so that means
it's anomaly because because
so there is another approach
probabilistic suffix trees
again very similar to final state
approaches and the only difference between the support base how they consider this
previous l minus one event
in this case if previous elements events do not occur in the training data
sufficient number of times
very pleased by the largest suffix which occurs more than three some pre specified threshold
so that means
if you have a sequence of symbols that are not occur all from the history
then you're trying to find the
some subsequence of this that occur from the past then for the subsequence you're trying
to go to school
transition probability matrix and find the problem
in this approach we provide frankly
so stop from colombia
they're using this previous elements events do not occur in the training data
sufficient number of times and then replaced with the largest subset
it's not necessarily the subsequent so it can be any combination of the events
and there are replaced their again going to the
this is the first skipping the second which is sort of the same right the
it's the same only the some of the positive terms OK let me just
in all this one not
so this is the difference between those terms and take the product with this difference
so i have full terms in this dot product price one is this times this
this and this and the two
cross terms and
the two questions are actually the same
what you get is the dot product between five x five x
this is the first
then you get mixed with just two over two
times the sun and then the dot product between five x five x i
this is a bit small and then you have the lost
which is
one over m two square at
and then we have a double sum
well i and j
and here we have filed x i
and phi five x
OK so five x five x in the mixed certain two and two
it is the sum over five x come five x i
and the last term is one of them will attempt to square and here we
have the double sum five x i five x j
and then we have three more terms of this form that correspond to the second
part so within the first part now
so if you then
we're going
so if you continue with this
what you get is
you get a five x five x but actually we will have the same thing
again in the second term so that's going to cancel
OK so this one
we can ignore it cancelled with the
corresponding part in the second term
however what we have left is
this term here
this is sum of all negative points and all right this is k come i
x i we know how to compute the product we just substitute the kernel
so this is k of x come i x i
then we have the same
from the second distance right the distance to the positive class
however with the different sign up here we would have another term like this
the plus
and with one
and with some being over the positive points
and here we have the same thing day of x come i x i
and now we have this term here
again all right this in terms of the kernel
so is the sum of all
i and j ranging over all
negative points
so here i have k of text
and then i have the same thing again
of the other class again with the different signs so i have one over n
one square
now the sum of all positive pairs of points
x i x j
OK now let's see whether this is correct
if you compare this to the
combination here on the blackboard
you can see that
OK so here
here we have minus two over two times this kernel expansion it's up to a
factor of two we have this term here
here we have a plus two and one times the kernel expansion
so again up to a factor of two we have this thing here
and down here we have one of two squares
the negative ones
so this this one
and we have
minus one over one squared
some of the positive and again we have this factor of two
which is different so up to a factor of two
in the argument of the decision function
we have the same and of course this decision function is invariant to scaling with
the positive number so multiplying here with the factor of two
this thing the
signed function will not notice it so we have the same solutions
OK so
that's actually see
so now that we've spent quite a bit of time this let's see
let's see how this kind of classifier actually does
so it's
i hope you will agree it's a very simple type of classifier we're just mapping
all points
into some other space and then we compute the mean of the two classes and
take where point is close to the one after the other one yes
OK i'll tell you out in the second
the good question is why is it called thousand windows
OK so
how so little demo
parameters which do
i mean that we learn the structure of them to some extent
and one could use some kind of nonparametric learning in a bayesian set up to
if you really wanted to learn something within about f and g within this framework
so there the the model will be using them to state evolution density
and the observation density in this i'm using this symbol to denote the random variable
to the left is drawn as the sample
is drawn from the density on the right
and because of the independence assumption that i've made the conditional independence assumptions we can
write the joint
density for
all of the states from not t
and all of the data in terms of an initial state density
f of x not to get things started
and then using the probability chain rule we can change in all of the conditional
the state dynamics
times all the observation densities overall times from nought to take
so we can we have this this thing is fully specified so in actually what
questions do need to answer the the the the if we if we want to
look at the conditional distribution for x given some set of observations y
then we won't anything in general about the properties of this joint density even though
we can write it down we know things about its moments and the other countries
that we want to estimate except in special cases like the linear gaussians model
also sometimes use the notation x nor
to be the collect the vector of
data points from north through t similarly the sort vector states wine authority to be
the vector of observations not routine
and represented in a sort of graphical model type thing was so we have the
hidden state sequence proceeding through time
by the dynamics f
so there's a stochastic model connecting each of these conditional on one another and then
you've got the observations hanging of those five observation density g
so just to look at two very simple examples of how you would set up
a linear autoregressive model observed in noise
the the hidden state process i'm going to call z so that two
linear autoregressive model is what is made up of the linear weighted sum of previous
some noise to of t
the observations y
that hidden states that t plus noise w
i will say that a if wt are independently distributed for the sake of argument
argument there is zero mean
gaussians the simplest possible that i guess
just about and variances sigma risk sigma w respectively
those effects and we're not doing parameter learning for this particular state space model set
up although one could in principle append
extra parameters on the state vector within the particle filtering framework
so the is by
they are coefficients the weights on that predictions
and these are also fixed and known just for this set up here we observe
and the unknown is a single set
so former state vector we had to do that by
augmenting z with some previous
state values as in standard sort of state space deterministic state space model
and then we can set up the state space model in the required form
by saying that x t
the the matrix times the previous activities that's the one study zt minus one plus
the noise nets along of t which is a slightly modified version of the beauty
why t the observation that is in there is is is is a matrix b
times the state x plus the noise term w o t
where the matrix a the required
this thing here
put together
so the top row
get it defines the
the fundamental equation
the autoregressive model and then the remaining rows
to people in the previous elements of x to the next timepoint
the observation
the function that is is is is in fact a row vector just putting in
the first element of the state vector x it's the observation
and finally the noise term has the covariance matrix like so so just there's only
one non-zero covariance elements corresponding to the deity that require the model
now we can put that directly then into the former you need to evaluate density
functions and so on because
the density function for the dynamics
is just a normal
density function
t plus one with me given by eight a times the previous state text and
covariance given by
capital sigma
so for excellence and the observation function g of y
given x another normal function centered on bx
with variance sigma w square
so this is the simplest nice most benign type of state space model linear gaussians
state space model well i guess the that's the hidden markov model is just benign
images on the discrete state space but in a continuous state space is the simplest
it's an important special case of the state space model is used extensively to construct
algorithms even in the long nonlinear
OK with things like extended kalman filters and in the northern gulf in case things
like the blackwellized particle filters
these linear models will be a fundamental building block in some particle filters
although we can look at fully nonlinear
this is a sort of benchmark test model was used as a lot of the
early papers in this area so here we can reconstruct some arbitrary nonlinear function of
the previous state to predict the current status and add some noise onto it noise
doesn't have to be added to the you can calculate the you can sample from
the transition density
here it is additive the observation function again can be so
arbitrary pretty well arbitrary linear function of the state
and things will still work and here i just specify the to be
gas w to be independent
galaxy with particular
that's very easy to put into the state space formerly required
basic formulation the TF function the dynamical model is again a normal distribution centered upon
this laser pointers bit
but to keep dying centred upon the function of x
the variance sigma squares and the gene function the observation function as a normal distribution
centered upon the nonlinear function b interacts with some variance sigma w scratch
OK so that's all simple
just a simple example of how to set up the state space model for this
this this scenario the estimation tasks well let's suppose we've seen all the observations
from some time up to the current president time t
i wish to infer the hidden states so the sequence of hidden states running from
not to assure thinking
nice so we only have some hidden states x not through t
and some of the tasks you might want to do with the monte carlo filtering
setubal filtering itself is concerned with the marginal distribution of the current state x t
given all the data
from north korean t
april predictability
regular behaviour
and so
what i'd like to do is to make it through
i'm not going to end up with
as much as with some questions but i would like to point out a few
features of the system
that may be of benefit
two the complexity science professionals
perhaps stimulating them to use the tools
in in ways that they have been considered before
the system in this sense is
has the features of turing machines
it gets in as an input
type of information in the in that
it is the start of the body with the infection trying on pleasure aging
all these
bits of information
that relate the start of the body
and the
this goes in to the immune system and comes the state of the immune response
the immune system is converting
one source
of information tapes
the state of the
issues the body into another
outputs a set of information states
which is the state of the system that makes it even more
so way superior to turing machine is that the output of the system
is designed
or at least leads to change
in the input
information in other words the way
as you see the when it comes to blows he dynamically the situation changes every
as the inflammatory response itself is orchestrated so the output
changes the input in this circular manner and even more power
complicated and complex is that the
turing machine
changes itself the goals
so the we have an input we have an output but the output then feeds
back on the input and actually feeds back on the system you can kind of
learning whatever
throughout life
system is learning from experience and that the brain is so then how does this
computation take place and what might it be able to
teach us about
some of the things that were interested in from the point of view complex systems
it's clear that the interactions
it's clear that there
they they sort themselves out into networks
and these interactions related to or create
now in
it's only an approach that medical science paradigmatic science we
like like in an engineer look for one-to-one relationships and we look for the world
in discrete causes and effects
but when we look at show what i mean we look at what the immune
system is doing
it is organising patterns
and not depending on the one-to-one relationships in fact one-to-one relationship really don't exist in
the face of the degeneracy
if there is something
quite simple
looking at
the architecture of the network architecture of the system
all along from
the weights one complex systems and invited the students
a master student
i think that the cells in the immune system organised
according to
so the occurrence of kinds of molecules that are produced by one so
and in fact
the story than others
and what we did was simply
take cells as nodes and we take the various cytokines
reduce them in way
edges of only
a one b single
i the mutual
and in which direction they go from one user to another immune cells from immune
cell two bodies from the bodies another body from bodies itself immune cells whether would
it was clear that
probably the trustees of to
so the key
it's not for
he a
the problem
while she
he's not just for you
it was you
and that's what
for more than
right at all
so goal
the small
can you
so i think that
it what want you get
so right
get your
the right
he moved
and so on
you get
you see
and from
this is
the decision
so we get
you should be
you it
when you
thank you for inviting me to never seen before i went quantum computing i actually
started out my first year perfectly as a machine learning person so i get to
experience my in an alternate life trajectory here different branch of the wave function so
i'm looking forward to learning a lot
but you know i did
presented them in terms of what i should talk about because you know i could
just give a standard technical talk about quantum computing theory but i wanted to somehow
related more to naps
yeah quantum information in the brain so
my challenge is going to be to speak for forty five minutes about an intersection
of two fields that might be the empty set
however we don't know for certain that it is the empty set and therefore i have something to talk about
okay so
often you know thee case that you know quantum mechanics might have something to do
with our cognition is parodied as the argument from two mysteries you know the mind
is mysterious quantum mechanics is also mysterious ergo they might be related somehow
okay so you might wonder you know what kind of scientifically irresponsible ignoramus you know would even toy
with such a you know and and obviously silly idea
so okay
right so so you know you've made you probably heard about roger penrose he actually
think something you know a hundred times
more radical than this the you know the brain is not merely a quantum computer
he thinks that the quantum gravitational computer
which could use sort of exotic new physics solve touring uncomputable problems okay but moving
on to serve the relative conservatives in this list right so i mean arthur eddington
you know wrote a great deal about you know how
maybe you know the uncertainty principle is relevant to sort of the free will and
determinism discussion you know as did a continent
please you several other these people alan turing maybe surprisingly was hugely influenced by adding
throughout his life and surely wrote you know several times about how maybe the uncertainty
principle you present some fundamental obstacle to scanning the state of the brain into a
okay so
you know even if you know the sort of connection is
ultimately rejected it's clear that you know at least worth considering
you know on the other hand as soon as we start thinking about this you
know we noticed an obvious problem left scale so here is a set three qubits
in an ion trap quantum computer
okay and so with less than one millimeter cross you know and that this is
a regime where quantum effects are predominant eyewear
you know that in fact these ions
i don't even have no definite locations so to speak you know there's just the
wavefunction describing them okay you consider only you know approximately make a picture like this
so you know and then on the other hand here is the neuron
you know and maybe something like ten thousand nanometers across okay and this is any regime r
decoherence predominate so
you know they are the neuron is in a bass it sort of in
contact with the external environment and that's constantly for forcing down its quantum state into a classical state
you know this is decoherence is the basic reason why we don't experience shrouding cats
in the realm of everyday life
now there's an intermediate regime i mean if you look at the synaptic junction that's
you know maybe a few nanometers across and in fact there have been arguments that
quantum effects are important for the you know modelling me
opening and closing of the sodium ion channels are being and the hodgkin huxley equation
okay but you know even then you know there's also a huge problem of timing so the physicist max tegmark
the calculation of you know what is the sort of longest possible time the quantum
superposition might be able to remain coherence is sort of the hot wet environment of
the brain right another generous assumptions you know maybe it could last for about ten
to the minus thirteen segments
okay so
if you look at you know the name
neuron firing rate right and that is orders of magnitude different
you know here looking at you know maybe ten to the minus three circuits
finally last but not least there's the problem of cringeworthy claims so i mean if
u on you know if you think that it's even worth started discussing you know
whether there's a connection between you know the mysteries of quantum mechanics and have
and if thought knew immediately find your allies
are people who
i think that quantum mechanics means that you know you can
create reality by by wishing you can channel some thirty thousand year-old the
cave woman in romford something you know this is from the movie was called what
the bleep do we know which by the way
quantum mechanics doesn't mean those things
okay so far
my view is that barring scientific revolution you know debates about quantum mechanics and mind
you know will just continue popping up like you whack-a-mole
and it's not even obvious that they shouldn't
because you asshole discuss you know i think that are genuinely is something profound that we don't understand about how
quantum mechanics can give rise to
be you know thee definite world that we subjectively perceive you know many people have
claimed to understand that over the last hundred years but you know it's questionable
if any of them have
okay so my modest goal
in this talk very modest talk
okay is going to be to explain you know various discoveries in the fields of
quantum computing and information that might bear on these debates now along the way also
discuss how a quantum computer could help or not help with fewer you know applied
machine learning tasks i could focus the whole talk around that's but you know i
frankly that the application of quantum computing is iterative already oversold as it is i
didn't want sort fan the flames anymore
then also discuss how in my own research concepts from machine learning have actually helped in quantum computing theory
the posterior and the marginal distributions are tractable and can be computed easily okay
and this is what's meant by conjugacy here okay basically it allows us to
to compute the posterior easily com allows us to compute the marginal easily okay
so coming back to our finite mixture model we can now make use of this conjugacy
to actually derive a Gibbs sampler for this so I guess Peter Green has
talked quite a bit about Gibbs sampling already Thursday and Friday right so this
should be ea
easy to for you so
if you do Gibbs sampling so
what we'd like to do is to a basically compute
posterior over the parameters and the latent variables
given observed z i
observed variables x i okay and Gibbs sampler is basically a Markov chain Monte Carlo sampler
in which we update each
unobserved variables by computing its conditional distribution given everything else sampling from that conditional distribution
and then repeating this over all
unobserved variables and just repeating this until you've converged to the posterior okay
so you can we can derive the
post the conditional distribution of z i
given all the other variables and you can see you can derive that the conditional probability of z
i taking on value k
is gonna be proportional to two terms
it's gonna be proportional to pi k
which is the
basically the conditional prior that's z i takes on value k times a conditional likelihood term
which tells us how likely is it that we observe x i
given that it belongs to cluster k
okay and if you normalize this you're gonna get the the basically the responsibility
of cluster k for data item i
okay and this is the conditional distribution for every i for every k you can compute this and you can update
each of the z ies
easily by just doing that and given the z ies we
would like to also get con the conditional distributions of the parameters as well and you
can see that
for the pies because of the Dirichlet multinominal conjugacy the conditional distribution of pi
given all the other random variables is gonna be Dirichlet as well it's
gonna be given by this Dirichlet with updated parameters
while the conditional distribution of theta
of theta k
given all the other variables is gonna be the prior
times the likelihood of all the data items that
is currently assigned to cluster k okay
that's other than this Gibbs sampler is actually not as efficient
as another
Gibbs sampler where colla collapsed Gibbs sampler and this Gibbs sampler works by basically
taking this model
marginalizing out pi and theta
and then just updating
the only variables that are left which is the zets okay
and if you look at the collapsed Gibbs sampler
basically their conditional probability of z i given all the other variables is of this fall
again we have a conditional prior times a conditional likelihood where the conditional prior has changed from
pi k to to to this form here because we've integrated the pi k
integrated out the pi vector and this conditional prior is kind of quite intuitive it just says that
it's gonna be proportional to
alpha divided by k
so that's coming from the prior on pi
the number of data items that were currently assigned to cluster k if you
don't count data item i itself okay
so the idea is that a cluster that has lots of different data items assigned
to it will a higher probability of being
of taking responsibility for this data item i
and then we also have a conditional
likelihood of data item x i given that its assigned to cluster k
and this term here is basically a bit given by the
predictive probability of x i given
given all the data items that were cur that are currently assigned to cluster
except for data item i okay and you can compute this in in the following way
and if you assume that the prior distribution h is conjugate to our
f distribution then this can be computed efficiently as well just as the Dirichlet
multinominal conjugacy allows us to compute all the probabilities efficiently
if we assume that h is conjugated to f we have also assumed that this can be computed
efficiently too okay
so this gives us Gibbs collapsed Gibbs updates
for the z i variables integrated out both pi and theta from this model
as I say
we can obtain the Dirichlet distribution by basically taking this infinite limit of a Gibbs
sampler and particularly of this collapsed Gibbs sampler
well perhaps I should say why we might want to do this okay so we might
want to do this because
we may not
want to make any assumption about the number of clusters in our data set right so
it could be that
when we do clustering as we see more and more data we might see more and more clusters
and the more data
items we see
the more clusters there might be in them okay so what that says is that
in the
true underlying generative process there might not be a fixed finite number of clusters there
really is a infinite number of clusterrs is just given a certain small data set
you only see a finite number of the of them okay so this by taking this
infinite limit of k going to infinity we are basically making that
assumption that there really is an infinite number of clusters
that generated our data but it's just that you know given that if you observe
only a finite number of data items you only see
less than a
the volume on this axis pressure on this axis
one year
the two here
there's p one here
two here
so i'm starting at p one p one and stuff like here
and and and and
right here
shall find that there are many ways i can get from one state to the
draw any sort of line
there are a couple of years one
we can talk to the which we're going to do
the first obvious one
is too
v one two v two
so take this back here
if you want to be too first keeping the pressure constant p one
ninety eight
he wanted two keeping divine constant
all this
one two
ISO ballot process followed by
cost nine
you could also do with different that could do
my initial
final state here
to take
first i can change the pressure
and then changed my
the second process
you said you wanted to
and then you take
this is
both are perfectly fine cats and i'm going to assume that these patterns are also
let's assume that both are
reversible meaning that i'm doing this very slowly
so as a
change let's say i'm changing my volunteer one to v two
it's happening
pressing it slowly slowly slowly so that
at any point to reverse the process without
without losing energy
always an equilibrium
all right i can calculate the work
that's involved with these two processes
remember that
the external pressure support
in this case because it's a reversible process
external pressure turns out to be
four is the same as the internal pressure all
i mean external
was doing very slowly so i'm always in equilibrium between external question internal
can go back and forth
so let's calculate w one
the word for path one
the first thing is change the volume from p one to p two
external pressure is kept constant p one minus the integral
one two
and then the next step here is
i'm going from
this for the pressure is changing and going from
two the two
we think this integral is
right so this is a far easier
this one is also pretty minus key ones
two what one
we want to do minus one well that turned out to be
this area
one might time minus me two
times p one
this is
one year
we can rewrite this as
one times one minus two
getting rid of this negative side
now the
one is bigger than v two so this is possible
so i am compressing
i'm doing work to the system
positive work
everything is for the convention
where the poles and
the system
right at the beginning which is here
then we will show you
the poles
at the end of the line
and then we show it to you again
as it comes back
so you're going to see three times
you do
and this is the now
is close to the end
all right thank you mark very thoughtful
so he was the post that goes in
and one point three micro seconds later between this lines
and this line is a market which is one point three microsecond
the mountain has returned as value
this is the the polls
and this
and then
when it has come back
but now
i'm going to
make it an open and
all right so here we see the
incoming calls
you see the one that comes back is no one point two nine microsecond big
mountain comes back as a mountain
now to something very interesting
at the end of the cable way is open
you see twice
we understand that
i see someone say yes why do we see twice
remember the open street
now the reflecting waves and the incident wave have the same polarity so at the
end they end up together and they give double the amplitude that was exactly the
same situation with the string when we drove in the polls on the string when
the and was open remember
and moved up by twice the amplitude of the individual poles
you see that to you
he has twice the amplitude of this is right at the end
now it is even more
which i discovered purely by accident
well not so much of next
do some consistency checks to see whether physics works
and so i said to myself OK
one point three micro seconds
that's what it takes
the go
make a round-trip through the
for the wire
so it was all the confidence that i have in physics i said well
two l
divided by c
l being on the twenty seven years
should therefore be
one point three seconds because it goes with the speed of light
but when i calculated this
i found
that this is
only o point eight four microsecond
then i said to myself
why is it slower speed than the speed of light
and i decided to ask you
i see and
why is this being substantially lower this is only remember we observe one point three
that's what we observe
so this is only sixty five percent of the speed of light
and one of the as well
i don't blame you
we also two seconds before i realized it
we also know them
OK among the
but it's better to try to that you don't
the new me let me know
expressed in the
effective way
you remember what do we not
that we discussed
that the
speed of propagation v
you seem divided by the square root
of the
index of refraction of the
the dielectric constant
remember that
i did one point
i even showed you how
the dielectric constant is a strong function of frequency of water
well when i look at the dielectric constant of the material that is in here
i found that the dielectric constant kappa e
it is about two point three
and if you calculate one divided by the square root of two point three it
happens to be o point six five so that's why the speed
sixty five percent of the speed of light so you see
also the effect of the dielectric constant which is quite one
remember discriminative company was also called the
the index of refraction
OK this is a nice moment for break we'll reconvene in four minutes
i would like to bring to test now what we have learned
so you get a chance to
some thinking for change
i have here
the electromagnetic wave
linearly polarized
vector in this direction
going to propagate in this direction
and it set up here
the average radiation radar
ten gigahertz
well that's about three centimeters
it's is going to be polarized in this direction you have to take my word
for that
as the the right here
receiver is set so that we see the radiation
in this direction i rotated ninety degrees then it doesn't receive the
that's the different demonstration which we did before
i have a peculiar comb
this is the code
of metal
these bars are not connected you just never bars
going to put it here at the end
i'm going to do it in two different ways
in one situation the con was like this
and then you have the situation
comm is going to be like this
so in both cases
real electric field
of the way that comes in the in this direction
stereo maybe I'll secured stereo if you have a perfectly aligned rig if it ends
up just being finding depth from somewhere triangles very simple math so the story of
stereos really because you cannot get this mechanically to mathematically aligning the 2 cameras to
convert to this problem and then you have another problem of finding the correspondence between
points and that's Saudis shown here this is the processing yet wrought distorted images you
undistorted view align them you crop to the common visibility points so you can see
here that features become a line-by-line so so that point is not aligned with this
the same point in the other camera but after this mathematical processing their exactly so
the the correspondence which points maps becomes the one research that's what makes for real-time
stereo and that's what we use all the robot but this is not this is
an open Stevie it's I think it's the state-of-the-art anywhere you won't find a commercial
product of does a better this is just getting into some recognition gesture control using
histogram intersection just controlling a video and stop there this is the has actually my
father and his 90th birthday taking of glider flying but it's really just matching his
nose so in different techniques of cross-correlation and and somewhat squared difference that you can
see his nose standing up for that this is an example I use this to
the phase detector which a lot of people use a rejection Cascade technique maybe you're
all familiar with this basically it's that you want but you know we have a
classifier to make a perfect say grandmother detector you can have a classifier that just
identifies everything is grandmother and it will never miss a grandmother but would be totally
useless so that's what these notes are almost totally useless but they never miss a
grandmother in this case there was a face but they do rejected the few faces
and as you cascade them you know 20 deep you could you get something that's
mostly face at the bottom and so yeah here is an example run that day
Disneyland per family that looks very much like but if that they get her face
Kansas to kill that I only traded on operate faces but so that's the quick
tour but take on new in open seas had and move it to steepest plus
interfaces see lots of allocations worrying about image tied to the steeple sponsored about anything
allocations no snoring about image type go simplest what is the message and trying to
shift people over because I got huge user base on CD but symbols was a
much better we also know we of resources were actually doing software engineering so we're
putting and unit test build test and all kinds of stuff and these are the
growing coverage of of functions that have unit test directory structure because they were about
about two-and-a-half million downloads so the new structure of open CD is that there's core
functionality that is now a bit got corrupted but now it's pure the structures and
other things that are needed above that's image processing and now every day as it
were trying to start a aligning everything into coherent processing modules least so object recognition
is going to be a stack of all these other things are coming image stitching
that's of Google summer code into visual dormitory room how camera moves and reconstructing is
motions turning to the treaty and treating of to be features along the side is
these helper libraries of them and then and a graphical user interface interface for Ohio
TV itself doesn't care about how you get the image just processes of these are
helper functions on the side that helped get the image we have this machine learning
library that's for recognition that we're interfacing now have a bunch of other interfaces a
full python interfaces replacing the Swig 1 with the handcrafted by phone and then there's
others that are on their way and then again there is that we do we
optimize this library so there's optimizations and SSC optimization soon and GPU up the opposition
than have this user contribute area that I'm gonna model after MATLAB central this is
where you can put in your proprietary patented technique it'll be clearly this explained there
and you only full decision in the sea make file if you say I want
that and then we need that because there's some retains like said that everybody compares
against and it's happened so so now we're separated out you pull and then you
can compare against it but you know if you want use it go talk to
them on their new know whatever deal they wonna make tone I've said this but
we're we're organizing this processing things that plug and play architecture that makes it easy
to give a coherent frame and and easy way of plugging in algorithms this is
a way that perhaps open-source could take part someone has a better Delaney trying another
library I could pull within in this way is dynamically it might be a better
way to combine open-source libraries so here's an example of the start of this the
processing stacked with features to be envision there is this method where you get features
and the description of them so as I move around like a quarter of that
that the air-conditioner I can identified in different views this can be quite a hard
problem but there are solutions so we have detectors these are the names of supported
right now but you can easily write your own and descriptors so you episode made
this interface very simple if you wanna detector which finds it just pointed a simple
implement 1 algorithm there are others you cannibal man or you take the default but
not all you have to do is 1 algorithm and same Florida the descriptors that's
the detector there's the descriptor again and there's pretty much 1 algorithm that you need
to implement for a descriptor and and then you can the other function it you
need it we have the falls for old or you can write your own there's
a you know how to match these things we have a brute force manager a
couple other matching techniques but here you can pour out all of machine learning we
just provided basic interfaced this is where you might provide a much more sophisticated interface
for matching but base it you know these are the basic functions that you get
you compute the descriptors you Adam to the pile vectors and then you can match
them and so you can replace all these defaults by whatever you want and then
what you get is the use nice charge so hoping Computervision that whatever people do
so what i can do look up
in the graph
so that's that's OK that's directed i
basically graph
well this one
it's not the direct sick
the graph and will not be considered as probabilistic
that's mother
so the
the thing that we have seen in the examples
is that
if i have a set of random variables
and that i ordered them such
but in the graph any child has higher numbering than any of of his parents
then the joint probability p x
the of the set of random variables can be decomposed as a product
of the
conditional probability
of each of the
random variables
although his parents in the graph
the fact that that that i can always order
the random variables
in this in this way
comes from the fact that i'm on considering direct a cyclic graphs
so that
i always have
that the child has always lower numbering than any of his not that the
parents has always lower numbering their any of china
OK let's give an example
much more complex graph that shows
john i the
taking the joint probability will only be taking
the higher notes and then
taking the
the law was not it's conditioned on
their parents
and so on
think another concrete examples
well it's now say that
this one i'm going to use for the conditional independence
now say that i'm leaving in the morning
and they have neighbours that have
sprinklers so this seems that for what the loans
i come back and i see that the grass is what
and i don't know whether it has range
if it's the the sprinkler who has what if they have put the sprinkler
so that gives me
four random variables model which i have
if i leave in the morning and it is it's cloudy or not i i
will i would suppose that that will influence the fact that my neighbours put another
sprinkler on
and of course that we influence if it's raining or not
so i have this this graph was the
here it is it's cloudy or not
is the sprinkler on or not is it is the
as a train or not
is the the
the grass which are not
and if order in this way CRS w
and as you can see i can and as we saw before i decompose it
as the fact of this factorisation was
the children already depending on the on the parents
so let's not talk about what is conditional independence and it's various ways you work
going to
to see them in this graphical
let's take a set of subgraphs of the one i just talk about
is it clearly are not easy train not is still rests with or not
if i take the time variety of only is a class the of cloudy and
wet grass
and so that's for doing that i marginalize over
over i some
i some out
the range
and this gives me the probability
times the probability of what just given cloudy
and we see that
that's not there are not independent
the cloud the clouds and the
and the web address are not independent
however if i observe
has training or not
and so i look at the probability of
cloudy and wet
given that it has trained or not
it can be decomposed
in this way
using is
here again his
based on this
we see that we have what is called a conditional independence
because we can decompose this temporary
by the product of
the probability of finding things the probability of the conditions
and on the range
here you mean
directly mean
this human this is not true for any
this it's not equal to this
it can be equally in some particular cases but in general is not true
why would it be
OK OK i mean way
could have been because
we cannot have the feeling from that graph that
they are not connected
did directly
we would like
to see that there their independent they in fact
as as is just writing down the did deal what is obvious
is that
all that i it's apparent of of wet grass
it's just to put it in in relation with that if i observed the range
then they become independent
i mean
well no big deal
you know that
and what you might be able to
well when i was told one by
what there in what was going on what i call the by now
and so on
can i don't want to remain
well y
one friend
from from
how many i can remember all the rest of
from here to here well maybe we can all learn
o for change
but all the so
well maybe
so i hope
about where
if i were that that's the would because
because the number of their hundred square number so
and all that is going to grow
so we're
now what
the role of i
there are all some
roughly one
if there
first of
what really work
so the call
four hundred ninety
right well are
but now we're
and i found the benign
right we're going to run where
forty five
the big river near to the number of
one that
and where they are and what the
my where
really where where one
we have
and that's where
that's a pretty
and then we will have everything i write about
right here right
and one
OK now
were coming
quite right
they allow me a
so i'm gonna get you
and so we will
the right call
for that by where i live where where were only two were we're
one one one one
if there were no
with term with
more terms
the more
and this where the word will be
one or two
and how
how one per day
one more in terms of the
well you were one
in the
so how many many now
now i don't
what we want
so in the
so we're
one hundred
so from one of way
of course if you be one per
and correct for all of
one o one
i wonder how you know
three of the sort
let me say one thing about