new cluster
well it's basically just doing gibbs sampling sizes is exploring the posterior and
when does not so remember this diagram where you have like
i think this is from
carl's lecture one right
so you can for
small model class then it will explain
a small set of
a small
set of data sets very well and they for large model classes
explain the largest datasets but then of course is for us to spread the probability
so so this thing is kind similar if you have a small number of data
then it is it will decide that
if e
you just use a small number of
michelle components
to explain that particular
they well and in crete as you increase the number of data points you
then realizes that it cannot actually use
a small number of clusters to explain it so it just increase the number of
clusters and this kind of doing this automatically
the posterior of the prior
yes you
yes OK it turns out that it turns out that the prior problem the prior
distribution over clusters
over the number of clusters that the model was to use
if you only tell it
and data points
it is going to scale as alpha timeslot
the mean of the number
there is a perfect form in fact well it it looks like
it looks a bit like
something so there's no BLP a lot and
it's not
it's not of the standard format all
it also depends on the parameter alpha so
this private telephone fax is
the larger alpha
the more
it expects
to use
the more the number of components and expects to use
and you can kind of see this
from the slide
this light so it's basically saying that the chance of
any data item starting its own clusters can be large and if have much of
and so you you see more
in in mission model in your post
question yes
yes i guess you could think of it as a kind of model averaging except
the easiest way of of a thing
thinking about this model is not as model averaging
but as
simply have one single model with a very large number of clusters
and then when you run your gibbs sampler it decides not to use most of
the clusters just decide to use
a small subset of the clusters
but that's come
similar to
this car similar to causal processes to right so you're saying that as the number
of datapoints grows
i expect that to be more
information in your data set
so you
i do want to use more and more clusters to explain the data sets
the number of clusters to
in this case it was a lot
any more questions
yes yes
it is
but i think that's what we mean by number of
the number of ways of one one of the is this one
where number of those who might actually be on the
the population of the
so what
the person you're going to
one person
one of
we do that
OK so it's when we said number of
components discussing
not the number of components that is in the whole population but only among the
data points that we see
only among the people that you see
yes i was
you are in the court i just fixed alpha but you can fact place the
priority of individuals so in fact this model is quite sensitive to the to the
setting of and in practice i always put up round of sample that
people typically use the common prior on of
he has
because of the work
pretty well
so that you can imaging model right
actually i should
plus the sum of the covered dirichlet process so
and i will present two approaches that can somehow deal with this problem one is
based on the concept approximation inference
another one in front and the second one is the so-called good common subsumer influence
which is close relative to the least common substrings OK this is what we are
heading for
first of all let's let's recall what the
top down approach for building ontologies actually meant so usually
she read
i mean
early papers on how to design ontology so i would suggest often times that you
start to model your your knowledge base some concepts and putting them in the t
box two
build up your terminology and then when you some confident facility box and think you
sufficiently model covered your domain then you're trying to the a box and populate the
books with instances of three years old
individuals from the application domain
this is in principle fine it's also in the first part
this way of proceeding to fill your ontologies is actually not supported by a standard
reasoner so you can
check whether box is satisfiable you can do
insensitive and you can growing in a box so this is
so the infrastructure for proceeding in this may matrix very good but the made
the drawback of this way of
filling your of the method of filling your knowledge bases
actually quite quite good knowledge of description logics on knowledge representation systems in general so
the user has already too
be quite fluent in description logics in order to
capture the notions that you go into the t watson to go into the a
box in the competent way
but if one
look at the situation
but we have when people actually building the knowledge bases then we have
often the case that the people building the ontologies are actually not experts in description
logics or knowledge representation of the people that are experts in their domain in medicine
biology and fears of course
and for these
if users of the systems it often happens
that the knowledge engineer
as some whole notion in mind what you would like to have the concept in
the t box but
can someone try down description can not not cold the notion you have in mind
and somehow introduced a concept description
for this notion
in in
application that we had a couple of years ago and chemical process engineering we saw
that people actually did not see the way
the other papers suggested many in the top down approach but the people from that
started with populating the a box because they found it more
easy to actually describe individuals for instance instances that they can observe and application domain
and once that kind of sufficient set of individuals and a box they group these
and try to
come up with category for these four similar individuals and what these users did is
they look very closely at what they had in the able which kind of concepts
attached to the
the individual there and
holly into interrelation of the individual
is in the able and then try to come up with concept description that captures
these kind of individuals by hand
people were actually already proceeding to build ontologies in but in that bottom-up pressure many
by starting from the individual but they were doing this in order to handcrafted all
the concept description they wanted to introduce sanity t box
the idea is now to support this this way of proceeding in an automatic or
semi-automatic way
how can this be done of
doesn't look in practice
what would happen
during the bottom up approach is OK the user will select somewhat similar
able to able to individual
something like this and then in the second step
these individuals to pick
i generalized for each of these kinds of descriptions generalise
each of these individual sorry is generalized into one concept descriptions so we see it
a knowledge engineer has found three individuals that are from all like
and system
abstracts from these individuals and generate a concept description
this is not just find name in the box but you generate
the best fitting concept description for these individuals
and then
in the next steps
the obtained concept
then generalised introducing the concept descriptions
happening or
and this
the concept description then subsumes
all of the input concepts
the more general
then the next thing is that this concept description is displayed to the user the
user can
look at the a concept description c without actually
is roughly what he expected always the concept description like you can edit the concept
description and if you like what is obtained then you can decide to name
and thus added the new concept in the terminology
the idea is that the description logics services actually provide a concept description that captures
object instances of individuals
five is automatically and the user can then decide whether to introduce this into the
ontology or not
so the first step of this bottom-up construction the user selects the a box individuals
is not the place actually the domain knowledge of the knowledge engineer comes into play
in picking
f of individuals that are actually like that forms
good candidates to form meaningful
category in in the application domain
the second step if you look a little closer at how it is realized
named is is this generalization into concept descriptions
then we would like to employ description logic reasoning system and
reasoning so that
exactly use of such concept description is called the most specific concept
let's first look at that
the definition of this kind of inference
the most specific concept of an individual
i can be
so the most concept of an individual a and enable
of course a
is the concept of the concept descriptions such that
two kind of conditions hold
it follows from the labelled set a is an instance of c so we want
to have this relationship here
we also want to make sure that some of the best fitting concept description can
obtain the for each
other concept description that we
the dark matter we know the annihilation cross section the dark matter shouldn`t
accreet in the sun the earth the center of the galaxy annihilated producing
perhaps some signal that is distinctive enough that we would know it's way very
high energy neutrinos positrons anti-protons and gamma rays so this would be indirectly detection this
depends upon the annihilation cross section and this is being looked for many ways
today finally there's accelerator production and I know a year from now the cold thermal relic
will be discovered that the LHC let me say a word about indirect detection but
you can look at neutrinos from the sun of the earth anomalous cosmic using gamma rays
from galactic halos neutrinos gamma rays radio waves from our own galactic center one of the
difficulties that is astro physical difficulty in predicting what you would see and that's again
related to the role of halos substructure so if there is dark matter in the
center of the galaxy the annihilation rate is proportional to the density square so uncertainty
about the density actually at the center of our galaxy is very important because it
is proportional to the density square this is an example of three possibilities I should`ve
labeled them I'm sorry I didn't of the density of dark matter in our
galaxy divided by some rho zero this would be the density profile as
that of function of distance and here`s the radius in parsec so for indirect detection
we're interested in the density here and for the same total dark matter mass in our
galaxies there's uncertainty in the density in the center of the galaxy here by a
very large factor this is squared in predicting the indirect detection rate
so you see that it's very uncertain and difficult to predict what the dark matter detection
rate would be so the local favorite if you poll people in Geneva poll people
on the street aside in Geneva and ask them what's their favored cold thermal relic they
would say the neutralino and they say it`s a neutralino because we study constraint minimal
supersymmetric standard models so you don't have to deal with the hundred and five parameters now what
you discover when you do that is that typical Susy models are condemned are consistent
with collided data and another precision experiments have two small annihilation cross section what's wrong
with you people you push the Susy scale to such so high that the annihilation
cross section is low and in generally generically would produce two value to large
valuable of Omega was a terrible thing to do we should never done experiments so
you need some sort of chicanery to increase the annihilation cross section and in fact this may be
telling us something about Susy models so how how can you increase the annihilation cross
section well you can go through s channel residences like through light higgs and z poles
so perhaps as telling us that the minimal supersymmetric standard model the mass of
the neutralino should be close to the s channel residence of light higgs and z
it couldn't co-annihilated with the stow or the stop
there are models if you have a large tension pheta then you can have questionable annihilation
through broad a residences high values of m zero the Universal scalar mass the LSP
the neutralino with Higgsino like and annihilates into W and Z pairs
this is known as the focus point region or perhaps the minimal model is
points generated independently and identically from galaxy and with mean mu and standard deviation sigma
so the joint distribution over everything i've mentioned here is x one through x then
the datapoints mu for the mean and sigma for the standard deviation we can imagine
a model where
we have mu and sigma in the model
and then the the data points x one through x and are generated independently given
mu and sigma
note that that's the graphical model for independence given mu and sigma because
there's no edge between x one x two
david mu and sigma
x one x two it any other axes are independent of each other so that
the graph corresponding to that little bit here this is i i d
and because it's tedious to write x one x two dot dot dot x and
we have this plate notation where we just set x subbands with some
indicator here index so little and goes from say one to begin
so here's the answer the question on the expressive power of directed undirected graphs
so i've already shown you that no undirected graph or factor graph exactly over these
three variables can capture the the independence the dependence structure is captured by the graph
now this graph here
over four variables
is an example of
the graph with no directed graph
over four variables
can represent
these and only these independencies OK so the independencies we have in this rap are
you know
let's call this north and south are independent given east and west right and vice
versa east and west are independent given north and south
and we can do that by
putting in directed edges in any way contrived but you fail
yes it is a big there's going
so you
can use
directed graphs are basically que
in other words you can never have a loop
that follows all the directions of the arrows and also people find that unsatisfactory because
they want to model dynamical systems or something like that but in the dynamical system
variable doesn't depend on itself the valuable at the point at the next point in
time depends on the that variable the previous one time so we we really don't
have loops
we don't need groups
we can always represent things temporarily as chris it for the chest example by
taking time and
writing out the variables in sequence
all right so
i'm going to summarize the first
of this lecture
so we
i should be three different kinds of graphs
i talked about marginal conditional independence
markov boundaries and d separation and differences between directed and undirected graphs
we could take like not a break where everybody goes away
but a
two or three minutes stretch break and that all go into talking about exact inference
and propagation algorithms
and then in following lectures on tuesday i'm going to introduce a parameter and structure
learning graphs and then i'm going to go to slightly more advanced
which will bring together ideas from a non parametric bayesian learning in graphical models and
so on just to give you more interesting flavor of current research in graphical models
that be
one a
now we have
if you region graph
so i think it
OK and the function is a black box
which is an engineer engineering technology applied to to impose two inputs to obtain an
we defined
the output in this way
this function is
as a function of a which we will call
total factor productivity of quito capital of total employment this is a measure of how
increases in k in the in an impact
on output
OK so we are interested in the technology matrix
OK this is a measure of the of canals
it is independent
the most famous production function economics is the so-called come down
from the name of the discovery that the something like this is very simple
OK so alpha is not depend from knn
is not from knn
the sum of these two
exponent is equal to one
this function displays constant returns to scale
it is of much in of degree one from OK is this is some is
greater than one we have increasing returns
to scale
and if this sum is lower than what we had increasing returns to scale
now suppose that we have
constant returns to scale if you take the logarithm of this expression and you have
data for k four and four beta four alpha
and for some
you can have an estimate of
so you can build
time series
of this parameter
which is measuring how technology is applied to that fact
OK and this
this time series is a lot
so we have here is a list of opportunities grazing and there's a a list
of triple tt is decreasing and we are able to have two to understand how
the economy copes with the sharks to the
in terms of the rates of
of of this total factor productivity
and the magic of all the story is that people who
has won the nobel prize look at some and so was able to show that
we have we can model an economy buffeted by a
shocks to technology
which is always in equilibrium
aggregate fluctuations are just the result
of optimal responses
of rational agents
the shock
they face
OK this is the idea
so the business cycle is basically an equilibrium phenomenon
it's not that does not include at
this is termed the economic
basic classical economics
everything is inequality
because people
rationale they are able to respond rationally
two to the environment and the
adaptive behavior
optimally to incentives coming from from
from from the environment
and so what remains is just an equilibrium an equilibrium results
OK so this is the mainstream economics i'm not asking you to accept it but
maybe is it's it's interesting to note
OK this is the mainstream by this problem
suppose we are assuming that these shocks to pretty
are i i d
as soon as we have a large number of individuals
idea fluctuation
fluctuations tend to become lashing
as soon as we increase the number of individuals by the law of large numbers
so that's why is standard macroeconomics we are assuming that there are just one common
getting hold all the agents of the same time
what's the definition of like a shock while the center responses or shock
but we have no shock at least every ten or fifteen years
so it's difficult to explain standard our fluctuations just in time of war
of shocks
so we have to find some different answers to this to this question one possible
answer has been
and applied by a soviet bayesian paper in two thousand five which is called the
ground or origin of irish fluctuations insisting this paper is still working paper no
it's not common economics that you know this guy is publishing the best journals
well different personalities
well we were raised by different parents
and we have different genes
we can tell
my my brother
and me
might share all sorts of things in common
we have the same parents
and the same genes fifty percent same so how do we tell what's causing us
to be like
so to do to pull these things apart
you need to be clever
you need to use the tools of behavioral genetics and to use these tools you
have to exploit certain regularities about genes and the environment
one thing is this
some people are clones
one i got twins are genetic duplicate they share hundred percent the same genes
that's kind of interest
dies i got the twins
are not clones
they share fifty fifty they're just like regular what's
adopted siblings have no special genetic overlap
that's zero percent
above and beyond randomness
those three
groups then become rather interesting
particularly when we keep in mind that by definition
two people raising in the same house by the same parents have a hundred percent
the same share environment
so now
we start to answer these questions
suppose you find my i got the twins are much more similar than dies i
got it twins
well i would suggest that there is a large role of genes
in those traits that you are interested in it wouldn't since the matter
because there are other factors that were for instance models i got twins
look more like
then dies i got twins and maybe they have different and they have more similar
environments because of this similarity in appearance
our minors got it which is the similar-sized about twenty if
and we showed that all that extra overlapping genes doesn't really matter
so i would suggest low role of heredity
are adopted children highly similar to the brothers and sisters
if so
and there's a high role of share environment supposed to bloom children
and there's seven of
all have an IQ of one hundred four
and we adopt three kids
and then attended a those three each have an IQ of one hundred four
that would suggest that and we do this over and over again across different families
that would suggest or something about the bloom family
being raised
by me
that gives you an IQ of one hundred four
on the other hand if the IQ of the topic is had no relationship
those of the biological children it was suggested being raised by me has no effect
really in your IQ is sort of separate
a separate a second final
contrast which is the thing
that psychologists love
identical twins reared apart
that's the gold standard
but you know these people were clones but they are raised in different families and
to the extent
there they are similar this suggests the similarity of their genes
and in fact
one of the one of the most surprising findings in behavioral genetics and the caption
here separated at birth malabar twins meet accidentally
and at the patent office with the same device
one of usually surprising findings from behavioural genetics is how alike
identical twins reared apart are
they seem to have similar attitudes to death penalty
to religion into modern music there have similar rates of behavior in crime gambling and
force they often have been found to have bizarre similarities
they meet after being separated at birth and immediate aged thirty and then it turns
out that be both
given to a lot of trouble because they pretend sneeze and elevators
there was one one pair twins study by and behavioral geneticists were known as the
giggle twins
because they were both would always legally burst into giggles at every moment
even though it couldn't be environment because they were raised together
more objectively
the brain scans
of identical twins reared apart
show that their brains are so similar in many cases you can tell whose brains
i could tell your brain from my brain from the brain scan and my my
brother's brain from my brain from brain scan but if i would have an identical
twin would be very difficult to tell whose brain assumes even if we had no
environment in common
so this leads to too surprising findings of behavioral genetics
this is the first one
high heritability for almost everything
four intelligence
her personality for how happy you are how religious you are
four europe political orientation
there are three your sexual orientation
there's high heritability there's a high effective genes for just about everything
actually not the controversial thing i'm going to tell you
but before getting to the more controversial thing i want to raise another issue which
often gets discussed and has good treatment textbook
this suggests that individual differences within this within group have genetic causes
does that mean that group differences
are largely
the result of genetic causes
so we know
there are clear differences in IQ scores among american racial groups
between whites and asians african-americans ashkenazi jews
it is clear reliable IQ differences as well as some other differences
to some extent
these groups are partially socially constructed
and what this means is that whether or not you fall into the into a
group is not entirely determined by your genetic makeup is often determined by social decisions
so whether or not you can institute for instance depends not entirely on genetic factors
but also on factors such as whether you're reformed orthodox and whether you so whether
you would accept that the child of a jewish man a non-jewish woman
is jewish
similarly categories the african-american and white and asian often overlap right genetic categories and they
don't make
fully coherent genetic sense
at the same time though
there's plainly some genetic differences across human groups
and i said with regard to vulnerability to disease ashkenazi jews for instance are vulnerable
to taste sex
and in fact it had this sort of genetic vulnerability suggested to some sort of
reality to these groups
so you have to ask the question now
to what extent
does the high heritability
in individuals
i mean it has to be heritable explanation across groups and the answer is
not at all
i'm not saying that this means that there is no genetic explanation for human group
differences all i'm saying is the question of the phenomenon of within group genetic differences
does not mean that there's across groups
genetic trait between groups
and so forth okay okay so that process that I've just described basically takes a tree and
then interpreted it as a sequence of partitions where each partition in the sequence it's
a refinement or a  fragmentation of the of the previous partition okay so we started
off with the trivial partition we broke it we broke it up into three
different clusters we broke this one up into two this one into two and so forth until
until every species belongs to its own cluster so this describes a tree as a sequence
of fragmenting partitions so we can construct a prior over trees if you can construct
a prior over such a sequence of partitions we might actually look at that in the other
way think of a linkage algorithm where you start off with all the different species
in this own cluster and then we iteratively merge two clusters two clusters
together into one so this reverse process is a sequence of partitions again but is
now gonna be a sequence of coagulated partitions so each step of this sequence will
take two or more clusters and merge them into one single cluster and this forms a
tree but now in the bottom up fashion so again this is a sequence of partitions
but now is going in the other direction and again if we can define
a prior over this sort of sequence of coagulating partitions we'll again have a prior over
trees so the best nice which I'll tell about is how we might construct this sort
of random coagulations and random fragmentations to do that let's think
a bit more about what coagulations are and what fragmentations are so let's imagine that
we start off with some partition like this okay a fragmentation is one where
a coagulation is one where we might take a few of these clusters and
merge them together okay so and we can describe a coagulation using a partition
as well but now it's a partition where the elements of the partition are the clusters in this
in in  row one okay so the elements here are A B C D
where A is this cluster B is that cluster C is that cluster and D is that cluster and
what this partition describes is a coagulation where we basically merge A and B so this
produces a coagulated partition where A and B has been merged here the reverse process is fragmentation
and what this fragmentation do is basically takes each of this clusters and possibly fragmenting
it up into multiple clusters so the reverse process here can also be described in
terms of partitions but now it's gonna be one partition for every cluster in C
okay so here we've described this fragmentation process as three different partitions one for this
cluster one for that cluster and one for that cluster  in this case the only
non trivial fragmentation is in this cluster here well these two are basically trivial fragmentations so
those are coagulation and fragmentation operators and basically we see that both coagulations and fragmentations can
be described in terms of of partitons themselves and since we already know some prior
over partitions particularly the Chinese restaurant process we can reuse those priors to build random
coagulations and random fragmentations so that is defined what is a random fragmentation
a random fragmentation is simply the following so given C we'd like to build a random fragmentation
row one of C where F one F two and F three are basically partitions
which are drawn from a CRP with parameters D and alpha and if that's the
case then   we say that row one is a fragmentation of a random fragmentation of C
with parameters D and alpha okay so this producers for us a random fragmentation of this partition
C similarly a random coagulation now going from row one to C is gonna be
one where the partition which describes the the coagulation is drawn from a CRP with
parameters D and alpha in that case  we call C a random coagulation of
row one with parameters D and alpha and and and that's it so now with random coagulations
and fragmentations we can now look at random trees by construct them by constructing
these sort of sequences where this might be a sequence of random coagulations and this
might be a sequence of random fragmentations and if you do that then you can
get basically a random trees out of these things any questions on this yes
yeah you kind of have to choose either to look at it in a top-down
manner or buttom up manner so I guess I won't really go into detail for
for the various processes but just kind of  give you a few examples okay so
here's an example called the nested Chinese restaurant process by Dave Blei and this
Chinese restaurant process works as follows so at the top of this hierarchy you have
a number of customers and you sit  the customers around a bunch of tables
right so this is  the usual Chinese restaurant process here we have five customers
we sit them around three tables you take each of the tables in our restaurant
so this one and we will send the customers sitting around that table to
another restaurants where they might sit around a certain number of tables again so we send
this two customers to this restaurant and they sit in different tables we send this two
problem matrix vector product kind thing so that's eight transpose eight times x
so you get this equation
the matrix a transpose they should be invertible
that would be an assumption i guess to do this regression
and you can then solve for x x-bar
is a transposing inverse transpose be that's probably a formula you've all seen before i'm guessing if you've taken
regression coarsening guessing most if you have
support i'm
presume that that's familiar r
let's talk about least absolute deviations
it's similar
to the kind-of pearl we had with means and medians
so now we have the sum of the absolute values instead of the sum of the squares
so we dusty el one norm if you like so we can write that way
and so it is the function of which is the sum of the absolute deviations
i do exactly like before i take the derivative
but now i'm taking the derivative of the absolute value function
and chosen the right there in this way
the derivative of the absolute value of x
the derivative
the absolute value x
can be written as x divided by the value of x cosmetics pos positive that's one
when x is negative that's minus one and we're not going to worry about
little places where the drug doesn't exist
this is the derivative
the sum of the derivative at which is this expression here and by the chain
rule would take the derivative inside were looking through the spectre x kay
this is a concept that doesn't have that gives us nothing that we get the
minus sign and as i take this someone jay
all these are zero because the x jay-z except for the one jay-z equal decay
and then i get a-okay so that's right here is the derivative inside the sum with respect to x kay
so we want this derivative to be equal to zero
the value of x that achieves that's cortex hat
to distinguish it from x-bar
so there will be leaving analog and the median will be the least absolute deviation regression coefficients
that's what get with x hat
end again we break this up into the two pieces just like i did before r
the beast stuff on one side only
and any x jay stuff on the either side and i get an equation that looks like this
kind of good and bad
it's good and it almost looks like the equation we had before r and in fact
if we are careful all i should say these epsilon denominator
are just these absolute value expressions here so i just summarize that's as abseil on
i guess i forgot that
mentioned on the slide here
except for those abseil on this is exactly the same thing we had before r
and if i write this a matrix notation this is how this appears to be
epsilon i because this depends on i goes between me and the baby
because that's eight transpose kay i that distance be i i and similarly
o i forgot they either to titles
yeah thanks
this is supposed to be
epsilon so i also and it goes between e eight
okay i transpose they i j goes in the air
and so if we write this in matrix notation it's eight transpose
that's had times be
were effects had is a diagonal matrix with these apps epsilons along the diagonal
is the inverse the matrix
as the diameter one over epsilon s on the diagonal that's exactly accounting for
this factor here and the same thing appears on the right-hand side it appears between a transpose and they
so again assuming that the matrix multiplying by x is invertible in this case it's this thing
we can solve for x hat
x hat should be equal to the inverse matrix times a transpose e all x had known
that's the problem isn't it
x have appears on the right hand on the left
and i suppose this is part of the reason why statisticians like
least-squares better than least absolute deviations
we don't get a simple formula here we get of well we don't get an equation we get a formula
this formula must be satisfied
but unfortunately it's not equation doesn't say x at equal something
that doesn't involve x at rather
this is just some
something that's true and
equation is true we are fine you except that satisfies this there's two is defined
i'll give you a simple algorithmic way
and also tell how defined by linear programming
and we can debate which way is better
so here's this simple methods that
avoids directly using linear programming
it's called the methods successive approximations
comes up
many many many places on
whenever you have something like
equals some function of x some implicit function like this
you can always consider solving this equation
saying okay i'm gonna start with x being equal the sum gas
what's the simplest gas
anything you like
i'll just say zero
this will be my first guess
and then i can update this guess
i can say well look
maybe that's a better guess x one let x one be apathetic zero
you have to prove that it's better might not be but it's certainly reasonable
thing to do
data suggest
and then maybe if you keep doing this maybe gets better and better
keep doing this forever
and take the limit
and if f is continuous at the limit the x's exists
then you would have
this equation
which we say that x infinity is the thing that you want
so requires us to assume that f is a continuous function
requires just assume that we can prove that the sequence of limit and if you
can prove those two statements that this process gives u
was given by this expression and this also is a way to specify time
now the expansion rate of the universe is a key quantity
and again let me emphasize that the expansion rate of the universe comes from the
zero zero component of the Einstein equations
and In terms of a ratio to a critical density
we can write the Friedmann equation expression expressing this expansion rate as a function
of redshift in terms of a couple of parameters which we can measure
so one thing we can measure today is the present value of the expansion rate or Hubble's
that would be value
now how it scales with
with redshift
there will be a contribution
of Omega radiation which scales as one plus Z to the fourth
a contribution to matter which scales as one plus Z Q
a curvature contribution which scales as one plus Z squared
the contribution in radiation
can be very accurately measured from measurements of the cosmic microwave background radiation
Omega in matter can be
tolerably well measured by several methods looking at large scale structure in the universe
this curvature turn one minus omega total can be measured to pretty good accuracy from the
then there's this other turn which looks like a fudge factor
so this is the expression for the expansion rate in terms of things we know
if this doesn't fit the data then you add another term and call it dark
naming is not explaining so the origin of this term is you measure H of Z
and if you can't fit it with these three terms you add another term and you
say you've discovered dark energy
and I've already described the equation of state parameter
now in terms of dark energy and acceleration
they enter into
the dark energy ventures into the acceleration
recall the dynamical equation for the acceleration A double dot over A
it depends on the energy density plus three-times the pressure
so there is a Newtonian contribution the acceleration is equal to minus G rho
is just a Newtonian result that's what you would expect in a Newtonian world
however there is a relativistic
correction that involves the pressure
and you can think of the origin of this
by the idea that pressure is related to kinetic energy density
and Einstein says not only does rest mass energy contribute to the stress energy
but kinetic Energy does also
so the acceleration is not minus G times rho as you would expect in a Newtonian world
but it is minus G times rho plus three P
now in the standard cosmology before nineteen ninety eight
expected the universe to emerge from a bang thirteen point seven eight billion years ago last
and to evolve in such a way with the accelerate with the scale factor decelerating
so it is curved in this direction
because A double dot is minus G times rho
if you would expect rho plus three P to be positive
so you would have A double dot negative you would have a deceleration
however if you measure evidence for an acceleration of the universe A double dot greater than
within this framework you found evidence for rho plus three P to be negative
and to do this you require that the universe is dominated today
by a fluid
In equation of state parameter
P over rho smaller than one-third
here are some
solutions for a flat model for K equal to zero
for whith showing a universe without a cosmological constant just with matter in purple
and whith values of a cosmological constant that has omega lambda of point seven or
omega lambda of point nine
so if you can somehow look out in space back in time you can trace the
between these different types of solutions to see whether the universe is accelerating or decelerating
and within this framework you can find evidence for omega lambda
you can also do this by looking into the future
but that requires a lot of patience so if you can look out in space
back in time far enough
you can see the difference in these types of solutions to see whether there is
evidence of a cosmological constant and you see if there is a cosmological constant dominating the universe
is accelerating
also notice for future
the age of the universe depends upon the value of lambda
if there is no cosmological constant
for a spatially flat universe
the page is less than ten billion years
this will be other evidence that there should be a cosmological constant to push the
age of the universe
so the program we want to have is to look out in space back in time
to see which track we're on
to see whether there is dark energy and this program was started by a
University of Chicago alumn
so I'll talk a little bit about our university of Chicago alumn
and I went into the archives at Chicago and red descriptions in letters of recommendation
of this famous University of Chicago alumn and the description of this person written
by the professors at Chicago are pretty strange they talk about his physique they say physically he is
a splendid specimen he has a magnificent physique he's manly and he has a
lovable character now I know when you think of a University of Chicago alumn
that this describes you immediately think of Jack Steinberger but in fact it's also Jack of course
what's actually is description in letters of recommendation of Edwin Hubble
who was manly in fact he was a basketball player at the University of Chicago
a member of the last decent athletic team that the University of Chicago the
nineteen-o-nine national championship basketball team
and Hubble measured the veloc the present velocity of the universe and this is a graph
from his discovery paper of the expansion of the universe in nineteen twenty-nine
so you notice a couple of amazing things about this paper first of all
the units for velocity are wrong he was at basketball practice that day when they talked about the units for
run times
this is an old algorithm that
so all the ends like formulation directly and i can see
the number of constraints keeps growing with the number of training examples
and the new formulation not only the bound tells you us a constant number
but actually empirically pretty constant numbers one
and you can see the here we have to solve quadratic programs in the old
formulation like hundred of brain
years of is less than
even before
this is one HMM state part of speech tagging problem like almost a million words
and if you look at runtime
compared to the number of training examples new actually really has linear
we have
very efficient way of solving it
step back again
so not only do we have
formulation is probably also have a very general out
in particular if i wanted to apply
this method to a new set of problems
also in terms of implementation
i can we use lot of work
comes from the general framework although we have to implement a new loss function
a new representation
methods for solving these two are not a problem to me is actually
this is doing
fiction this is we're doing this separation oracle find the most violated constraint
and all the rest is just a c
if you want to try to actually is the general grows on my my webpage
called SVM struct
so in a sense it's kind of the place at the right
and we want to demonstrate in the rest of the talk is how we can
take this general was and just like in
by keeping actually most of the code the same
so the article i want to talk about these three
sequence alignment classification of search results unsupervised clustering
and so
what i have to do for each phi loss function specify representation and that you
let's start with the sequence alignment problem and see how it goes there
the holy grail
one of the holy grail in bioinformatics is
given the sequence of amino acids predict what this structure
well it would be nice if you could directly solve the structured prediction problem but
i don't know how to do that
the problem is that the search space structures is really big what we have a
good understanding of physics
it's just too expensive to do is search directly
so what people typically do
one of the methods that uses what's called content modelling
you have a set of known structures and it turns out that proteins
i've come in families and they don't really fall into
a folding arbitrary structures like
kind of a couple of ten plates that can fold into
a few thousand
the way that you can
do structured prediction then is an efficient way is
the first kind of trying to predict
which family the structure this sequence like
that a binary classification problem
you take the sequence
and you try to read it
into the structure
how best fit
and then hopefully gives you good enough starting point to do local search from there
and actually find the correct
so what i want to talk about
here is the second task
given the sequence and structure
predict how they
related to each other online
this becomes an line problems so
and just a quick reminder on sequence alignment
typically formulated again as argmax over linear scoring function
let's say we have two sequences s and he
if we align them in in this way so that the line it was the
was a he was he
the way the alignment scores computed is
we have a matrix that tells us what's the score of lining in a within
a ten
here realigning and a with b
look it up the people of that neuron
he within a that's zero
he with the
given score ten
and the with the
gives score minus
so the overall score of this alignment some of those and it will be zero
here's another alignment that have gaps in it so that we have a score of
line he with the gap
the gap mine five
and so on
over all possible alignments
we solve the argmax problem the score and returned line has the highest score
and again to cancel that not
well that's
straightforward sequence alignment will just the character sequence
but the alignment problem in this reading problem we're reading sequence infrastructure is more complicated
because what we actually lime lining here is
sequences of feature vectors
so for example we have sequence here that describe each
in our structure
what's the amino acid
what's the exposed surface area
what's the secondary structure that
position in the
doctor and so on so we
just have a single
character but we have these features
the same thing for the sequence
what's the predicted secondary structure position one
we really aligning
feature vector
and then it becomes
kind of hard to describe down on the table
know of alignment for
we need something more general scoring
let's start with rapport
i think of it i think the time
and your own experience where you were
in synchronization
with another person totally
connected with another person
how does that feel
it feels
you feel confident here
how also fail
because this is what rapport is rapport is when you feel in synchronization with another
and you almost start feeling
and i want to get to sort of
this existential lauzen like almost are feeling you know at one with the other person
and this is this is my belief my belief is
that if you don't have rapport
with another person
then whatever you're doing with this person whatever your communicating however you're trying to persuade
this person
is pointless
you could you could go into a meeting a business meeting and have the best
on the situation
if you don't connect with the other person
it all amounts to zero
so the overall quality of communication is is equal to the quality content yes
multiplied by
the amount of reports of the rapport is zero the overall
equation is zero
oppose important and i and i hope to be able to prove the city
rapport sur connection
we feel
in sync with another person
so without looking at the
the notes that you're given beforehand
how how do you do this
how do
you build rapport
with another person
OK you try to understand them
how else
do build rapport with people
just be yourself don't try to act
OK so looking for mutual things too
talk about
neutral subjects
i was to build rapport
the connection
yes you've got to be very sensitive to what's coming back at you
both verbally what the person saying that all the other things that we talked a
as visually vocal just just sense what's coming back
being just a little bit of a careful of not being too conditioned by by
the first impression i think is an important is it
is it easy not to be conditioned by his vision it's quite difficult isn't it
and again research suggests that we split we it takes is very short amount of
time to
decide to make a decision on another person
whether we like them or not very short amount of time usually
we use intuition
a lot
but we've got to be just mindful that sometimes it's not right
it is
yes it you
and it comes back to being appropriate and maybe in a business setting and what
in talking about relationships and forming relationships over time
it's a step sequence so you know first meeting
let's just try to achieve this second meeting let's go a little bit and when
you get to know people that then it starts opening up
to be a little bit realistic about the
the border where you are
you mentioned we find something common to talk about you can have to forgive me
now a gross generalization one men
who've never met each other talk about two
to build a connection with each other
sport come along of course
did you see that they can kick of maison
and we have sports teams that we go mad about and we
what do women talk about gross generalizations
whatever whatever you find something that's the important thing but you already had one in
the UK where the terrible we don't have any fashion sense so we do talk
about the weather
you find common something common to talk about now in a business setting usually you
have something common to talk about you both have an objective but verbally we need
but is it you can go beyond verbal
what i want you to do is to have a look at these three
and then
choose which house
you prefer
there is no right answer but
so the preferred if you had to choose one if you had to choose one
who which is house number one
OK interesting who would have to choose house number two if you had to pick
and who which is house number three
he had become OK it's got nice
nice mixture in the
in the room
when you talk to
to people
you can
pick up what we call
representational channel the preference
four representational channel there are three primary channels are actually five six but the primary
representational channels are
something that we call auditory
good morning
i introduced myself yesterday many the
i will be teaching a course on multiple regression analysis
you got some details were
we're currently located
all the
yes the details you might be interested in will
give to the group that
i will
join me tomorrow
thank you for coming for being interested in addition to
this course
here's the thing you are asking
he teaching assistants the courses taken the course last year was put off but decided
do it again but now in more to change the way
great thank you very much
and six
well that was in the next one of ours
so here is a tendency to one
and the conditioning will be fixed or not
so what is multiple regression about
many people are using it and if you take
any the issue of
one of the well known political science journals of sociology journals
you will find that about fifty percent of all articles published in their use some
variant of regression analysis
and it's one of the most important tools
the but most important the most widely used tools in the social sciences
and being the most widely used tool it's also one of the most misused tools
and the aim of the course will be to be able to judge
and misuse
so what is multiple regression about
it's an art
to summarize relationships
this is another way
summarizing relationships
but it will not be
regression analysis
taking this past this is more something for the our friends at the grounded theory
or interpretive
picture analysis
and you can probably tell a very very long story about this simple situation
we do the same thing
i talked about fitting a straight line to open an
this is the solution
you simply look at your object from a variety of angles
this one angle
from which it really looks like
being representable by a straight line
from which perspective should you look
what would you consider
when taking that perspective
and what lenses should use
the course about
so normally we just we don't just take a banana
for the straight line or take any
out of a straight line
the doing of it
the plot
in panel data set with
nationally aggregated data services each dot represents a country
at a certain moment in time a year
we study
the replacement rate already effective to replacement rate on employment in private consumer services
so what is the replacement rate the replacement rate is the percentage of
you're income you receive after getting unemployed
the percentage is the number
zero and one hundred
so this is normalized to zero one
and you see that there's variety
country time units
where people hardly receive anything
and country time units were to get more than ninety percent
and here is a former prime consumer services resistance
it's just lines like that's right so basically it's just your neighbors you can make your neighbours
so definitely there the same
one dimensional input
the energy bill then you optimize over these axes and new learn the structure you'll
learn the neighborhood structure which is the hard thing that was point one you completely
ignore and spectral methods you just take the data
but they're very related from their perspective and also we then visualized x directly we
don't need to do and i can value problem we just look at the x
we have we don't need to do any visualization and the graph structure
there you suggest a graph structure parameterised and visualize it hear
you could derive a graph structure from the late positions you get
but you've already got visualization new short-circuit the visualization part
but because the learning the neighborhood it's lots of local minima
and then the last thing i'd like to just show you
the guy lots of things i could show you
is this one
i don't think that manifolds along other right way modeling things
i think that manifolds class conditional independencies
now would be the right way
so this is the main altar what they send deep learning
i don't think deep learning the be all and end all
i think but i think it's right
the broad sense that actually what you need to do
is land the structure of your data
by on
trying i figure out what's connected to what so the problem with those walking examples
i mean i think there i still say if they are that you will be
among those data i'm not an expert in vision but as far as i know
nothing beats that's
so that's great but those models have real trouble if i'm walking along if someone then waves
back confuses the model because it's never seen someone waving before
so you could learn on data with people waving fine
but what if someone might be either are okay data on any other run
but what if someone decided other john cleese city water
you know you know all those things in natural why do you think that's natural
you see me waving like that's
you know you could learn
if you see me if you see if you miss individually walking like you can learn these are natural motions
you also don't mind if i want anway way
okay i'll call over if i continue but you get the idea
what's going on is really bad arm can live on a manifold in terms the natural things it can do
i would say what it can't do without my painful
but i
it still is on a manifold so that's the manifold here
and the headlines on a manifold and the left arm moves on the manifold and then
they're being controlled by something else and the different motions they're being coordinates in different ways so
i had this idea
my students andrew more the hierarchical decomposition of the body and actually works really nice
i don't think i can run the devil trying a moment
i don't think i can run the demo here but it's basically you have to specify the structure
but we working on learning this structure which i think would be really cool
so u this this guy guy's modelling a little manifold learning the right on this
guy on the left on this a very similar but they
they only know about each other through their shared mother of the body
shared body what
model the body is and what he did you know
that's the money
and this is the
so these legs and you you've got me banned
two motion so there's walk and run right and so the war is green and the running red
so not surprisingly the walks sits inside the run
but the sharing information
about how humans naturally so this
doesn't know
about walk and run it just knows what is being told today from about what seen below
and when it gets old from above a slightly different form walk and run so
learns about leg motions in general you switch in the walk and run model
and then if you want to locate this is bound not to work because i
didn't test this so let's have a good faith here
i don't even remember the name and the demo is but let's see if we can find the demo
i think it's not here now at amazon goddamn away you can move around controlling
for those parts separately by having run in a while
and i think that's why model is really the sort of thing you want to
be doing and the suggestion is that you could even back so basically you've these
models the some parts of the body
hand if you see what someone's doing you try model with something at the top
but it doesn't work you just replace those controlling model something more diffuse
until the the worst case you've got several models what legs to
arms to and had to
and we had a paper
be and see
on doing not news tracking so
you don't use use the hierarchy to back down say okay well if he's walking
i can i can model this level here
but then if he's doing a roly-poly then i've never seen before so i'm all
this level here i mean that's not very much so the deep learning type provided
and we we know how to do with at
we think and learn structural we've got a way of doing that's we don't know if it's gonna work
but hopefully it will so that's that's what the that's what my student unrest damian
you can take are
o point one metres
and then the field strength of the b field right at the centre of this
but i found is in six times ten to the minus four test lab
and that would be
six gauss
it's clear that if you want to put in some
field lines
magnetic field lines the result of this
current going around in circles
that the fuller center there would be if you like so
if you're very close to the wire here which goes into the blackboard want you
to see this three-dimensional
then the magnetic field go like this
the current comes to you
so will be counterclockwise
if the magnetic field lines you like so
and you have it to scroll up
and clearly i expect them to be here
sort of like so
like so
this is the kind of
magnetic field line configuration that i would expect them
in the vicinity of
such a
current loop
i want to show this to you in a little bit more detail
i have here
you see there
on the right side
goes into the paper here comes out of the paper is circular
you see the field like configuration
after different whatever the blackboard there
very close to the wire is of course
you get circles
one of our
dominates there is so close to the wire that the one of our relationship
make it come out like circles and here too
but then
far away you get configurations
like i i have there
when you very far away
from a current loop
magnetic field
is very similar to that of an electric dipole
i can show you that
in the following way
let's first look at the electric dipole that you see
there is is the positive charges the negative charge
don't look anywhere near
the charges don't look in between the charges look far away
using electric field lines
now look at your current loop here
the current is going into the paper here
out of the paper is a
i hope you see the same configuration
field lines
this goes like so
this one goes like so
here the electric field lines coming in
magnetic field lines are coming in
electric field lines are going out
that field lines are going
they look very similar
gauss law tells me that the close to the surface integral of the
electric flux is the charge inside the box divided by epsilon zero and so if
you have a closed surface here
looks like a line but i meant to resurface
then that closed surface interval of electric flux is not zero
because the charge inside the box
no matter where
in the magnetic fields
you make closed surface there's never
magnetic flux going through
that surface
never unless you come into twenty six one hundred and and show me the magnetic
one of
only then will the be magnetic flux coming out of a closer
if we put the magnetic monopole inside
this now
brings us
the second of the four maxwell's equations
the first one being
gauss law
the second one
is that the closed surface
closed surface
of the don't the a
always zero
unless you come with the magnetic
so we now have two of maxwell's four equations in place
historic day
i want to show you the
magnetic field
in the vicinity
all the while like this
i have to use a few hundred and useful wire
i told you why because magnetic field falls of clyde rapidly
and i did was i one file
but i will sprinkle around the wire and these magnifies
o orient themselves
in that the magnetic field
and then i will try to also make you see this field configuration
by having won why going into
the paper in one coming out of the paper
so let's first look at the
their behavior
so they they were looking at how people behave and they started making themselves and
modeling their behavior and what they found was
they became successful as well
if you look at someone what they do
and you really get a detailed idea of what they're doing and you start doing
it you have the same results
this is the finding
and out of this finding the whole field of neuro-linguistic programming has has grown
and this is the model
what they found that these people do firstly
these people very effective communicators
firstly they know what they're trying to achieve in interaction very clear
one of their
in the last role-play
clary you were
about what you're trying to achieve
the more likely you are to get the result you want
and that's why i kept on pushing
you know your reservation price no you'll know when you're going to walk away know
what volume you really would love
get clear as you possibly can before interaction
and you're more likely to get
make sure that your your goal is stated positively all the time
it's not a negative goal positive goals
so don't go into
a negotiation with the goal right i mustn't i mustn't fail
that's not to go
because as i mentioned yesterday if that's what you're thinking about that's what's going to
happen your brain won't register the word mustn't
it will only register the word fail
so be very clear about you goal we all of you
clear in the role-play what your was
you knew exactly
your reservation price minimum price in exactly the volume that you want to yes
should have been you should have been clearly had long enough to prepare
the other three things that that will class communicators do
they build rapport
with people that are communicating with
i think we mention this word yesterday as well just remind me what
does this would mean
if you had to guess if i if i say you know we've got a
good rapport what does that mean
relationship and at an even simpler level
rapport means the connection
when you have a connection with someone
so a b
when you feel mutual sort of sense
some people have a rapport with some people you just
you know you've all the people
you know you shaking their hands and there's just nothing is known
mutual feeling at all
and so you do not in rap also to good communicators have rapport this two
other things are good communicators to firstly they make it that they
i spent a lot of time understanding the other person
all the other people so listening and understanding and was going to talk about that
and the final thing will class communications doing will cost persuaders
they are
they behave flexibly they are not
you can't really
get anywhere if you are so we can use this model i would like to
do is i'm going to go through each of these i'm going to leave the
because the goal was very situation depends what you're trying to cheat i want to
focus on the other three
and we'll see how you can become better
these three things to building rapport with people
improving how you listen and understand people and finally improving how you behave flexibly
with people
one of the few small role plays and exercises as we go through
any before continuing to comment on this
very simple
straightforward model
simple and straightforward
let me let me give you an example of
someone who doesn't do this
the sort of person who doesn't
following this model is the typical
english person who is traveling
two new country
and of course being english we don't speak many foreign languages so imagine an english
man who goes to france he gets lost in the french countryside doesn't know where
he is and he sees the french farmer you with the error in a few
onions around his neck and he calls the farmer over and he says the farmer
excuse me
where is the railway station
and the farmer says
chen composed by merchants
what does englishmen do
louder slow where
it is yes
he didn't understand first time what what do you think is going to understand seconds
this this
this english full is is not
doing this he didn't listen
and understand the response to the french farmer
he didn't behave flexibly all did
the behaviour that he had this time right
just a little bit more
a bit slower and louder
whereas if he had seen and listened to the responsible former
just about
he could have what can be done instead of speaking slower and louder
two true
well i guess we
be a flexibly and is it's not that easy to do because we are also
used to behave in the way we do
some nifty ways that we actually use a big o notation
is using the semantic
by the way and we have a lot to cover today and so i'm going
to go relatively fast if anything is unclear to stop questions that i will slow
down otherwise i'll take this is all completely obvious and i can
going at full speed
OK so the convention
this is
intuitive i guess if you do
macro programming or something
but it's a bit more mathematical
so we define big o notation and the equals big something
and so we only to find they go
on the equal sign we had to go some function
but it's useful to have some general expression on the right hand side that involves
so for example
let's say we have
after there is an q plus four square
this is attempting to get error bounds say fn is basically and q but there's
these lower-order terms that are big o of n squares
so this means
there there's function
shorthand for function h of and which is in
the golden square
four equals golden square
such that f of and calls and q
class h
so saying there's some lower order
terms that are bounded above by some constant times square for sufficiently large n and
that's what's here and then f of x equals now this is the true equality
and q plus that character
so this is very useful here essentially expressing what the customers is in the same
other stuff and is almost square
but saying that f of and therefore is also order and q but it's a
bit weaker state
this is a bit more refined what he chooses to often but it's useful sometimes
seem like in my class we even had a big o inside summation so you
can use them all over the place the players to represent some function
in that sense
a bit less intuitive
this is more subtle
is what it means to be go on the left-hand side
it means the same thing but
there some convention what quality
can this is what call sign
is asymmetric
he calls means it should really calls like is
so is means that everything over here is
something over here
so there's an implicit for all on the left side there exist some
right hand side this is a true statement anything that is an squared plus bigger
than is also the golden square
but not the other way around this is a bit is symmetric
this if you think about this is pretty intuitive
i want to be compensated for their work
if i climb
this mountain
if i climb five thousand feet
and i have to do extra work
which is ten two six two
you gotta eat more
now you would think that you have to eat only ten percent more than you
because you say ten two six is only ten percent of ten to the seven
but that's not true you have to eat a lot more because the conversion from
two mechanical work is very poor something like twenty percent
so you may have to eat forty or fifty percent more you normally do
in one day
suppose i wanted to take it back and i want to calculate how much
energy it takes
to read about
a wonderful thing
to have
well we know how to do that
q is the number of calories
times c
times delta t
that's equation
about half will contain about
a hundred kilograms
of what
that is about twenty eight gallons
and let us assume that the temperature increase
is about fifty
degrees centigrade which is the same
as fifty degrees kelvin
we have water and so you'll find
q then
becomes roughly
five thousand
you look at least that's how much energy it takes which is two times
and two to seven
so that's the energy that is needed
to heat up
and joy
that pleasure
go back to this
that's very shortly
there are many forms of energy
as we all familiar with there is electric energy
this chemical energy
i mention that already gasoline burning there is mechanical energy when we
move things gravitational field
and there is
nuclear energy
a waterfall
his mechanical energy MGH
you can convert that
you can convert it
two heats
will power
coffee machine
it will power your TV
if CRU electric toothbrush
everything it may power your electric blankets if you have one
electric blankets
is only fifty watts
compare that with human beings
on the what
what's nicer
have a human being which you in bed then one
electric blanket believe me
nuclear energy
can be converted into heat
and that can be converted into mechanical energy
and again into electricity
chemical energy
fossil fuels
can be burnt
converted to heat
two electricity
i have here device
allows me to convert
mechanical energy
electric energy
and i would like to invite a student
to come up here volunteer he or she
we going to going to show
how he or she can convert
mechanical energy
in two
electric energy
will have the
special like conditions so that we can see it well
so who wants to do that
please come
there's twenty watt light bulb here you've got you will see it very shortly
and this man
as a lot of power i can tell
more than hundred watts
go ahead
but with a twenty watt light bulb with your foot on the
it is easy a
quite impressive
OK now will the not so little new
here we have six of them
so now
go ahead and now you are
trying to generate hundreds
watts of power
things you can do it
they look really them to be
non-linear keep going and keep going
you're not even at the level of on the twenty watts
it's hopeless
you can do it
and even if you could do it
you would have to do this for forty eight hours in a row
two he did my best
think about this one back
forty eight hours but you can even do it on the twenty what is too
i don't blame you i can do with either
there are better is
batteries convert
chemical energy
two electricity directly
we use these fancy dry cells
but in the old days and still nowadays in your car
there acid batteries
if i have here beaker was as it
which most commonly used sulfuric acid
and i put here in
why i here in
copper wire
then this is a better
i believe this side of the better is positive and negative
we have them here we have this
so if you as it and we have zinc and we've got but if we
use only one cell
then i won't be able to light small
just like
we see you flashlights that you have at home you sometimes have to put in
several cells in series
to get a higher voltage so that you can power
it's more like the light bulb that we have here
only a few watts it's almost nothing
i will still try
to get it lit which is not so easy because these battery
has a self-destruct in at the moment and i put this
zinc in there
i get very violent chemical reactions
the fumes are awful you may actually smell it the first row very awful
and the better it works only maybe four
lives in according to its distribution function and just and just evaluating g at that
so the basic stochastic approximation scheme it you just take a step in the direction
of big g
that's it
notice by the way i get again the critical issues had choose the alpha just
as it was only and we're going to talk about how to do that
i just noticed in passing here that the
obviously it's time run this you gonna get different results because you're going to be
sampling and picking a random because i k every time
and obviously xk plus one depends on all the size you've encountered so far so
it's a random variable
it depends on all those eyes encountered so far
now here have actually been adventurous and against the advice of my students left the
analysis in here
i figure that even if you could follow
in real time if you're interested you could go back and look at it
the reason i left it in is it because it's so simple really literally fits
into three slides
and so i thought it was worth putting up
now what we can analyse in this case is is the expectation
of the error in hex
so i define this little a k to be the
two norm x came under six task with the expectation that
the assumption is going to make is that my subgradient estimate is inside has sort
of bounded variance
OK and this can be guaranteed lot of cases of interest that if i take
the expectation of the square geo site has bounded by some m squared
now let's analyse it converges to remember this is the step taken here
so i'm going to look at what happens with the areas that xk plus one
so i'm going from here to here i'm just plugging in the definition of xk
plus one
and now i'm just expanding out that two norm squared to and i get xk
minus six start term here
i get this
which is a cross between x came under six dark energy term
and then i get alpha squared times the two norm g well just had bound
that an expectation so when i take the expectation of both sides
this gets bounded by m squared that's easy
the slightly tricky one is the expectation of this middle tier
and this is where you have to be a little bit careful because as i
pointed out earlier the xk depends on all those random variables like you've encountered so
and the expectation of g with respect to xi k is in the subgradient so
you can sort of use those two facts
some conditional
expectations again you know really not
to figure out of down on the middle middleton
now it turns out to be to be the critical thing
and once you get down in the middle term you find out that
going back here
we find that i k plus one is just a k
minor something nice here
in fact that something nice is just to mute times alpha k times a k
you can show
and then we got this last alpha k squared times m squared
so i've got a nice
o thing here which kinda gives us some hope that a k is getting smaller
the expectation here is going down here you can see this multiple here is less
than one so provided this isn't too big i'm going to be able to decrease
a k at every step
so the critical point is how do i choose is often case to make that
well it turns out the magic way to define alpha k is one of the
k times mu
where mu is the modulus of convexity in case the iteration number
so this is where i believe this is an exercise for you
if you want this into this
and do about four in could go through a sequence of four very very simple
inequalities you can show that a k is bounded by some constant over two times
with constant depends on the initial error
bound on the variance in the modulus of convexity so you get in expectation you
get sublinear convergence but to one of the k right
now that's really pretty amazing because when we right back at the start of the
i gave you steepest descent short step steepest descent method
they go to one of the k right
and here we get a one of the akira even with this
very crude estimate of the gradient we don't even need an exact gradient
we do however need strong convexity in this case
but we're still getting the same right
OK so what happens if we don't know newfie don't have a good estimate or
if we're not even dealing with strongly convex function what can we do in that
well it turns out that we can patch up what the method i just described
and factors this paper by nemirovski and yudin ski appear on land that appeared last
year and so
where they describe this and you can recover one of the squares k right so
i mean
i have three and five regional
but i
i can
what not
really like
it's a lot
shot and
you know i
in fact
project ten
and as
it's going
you can a
i mean that
the picture
the rate at
unlike anything
i'm sure one
that's how can
OK i checked out
but i want to
you can
things like
the character
and if i can do
you can try to bring
we should satisfy
i will try i to can
i actually
that's right back
you see some activity building up
and if you
look at this is the left index finger and this is the right index finger
so you see that it's control lateral on this hemisphere
this is the right foot and just this
so if you
now look at
this plot here then it's much more so so you if you so to say
a few on on different hemispheres then things are easier but if you're starting to
be in the same hemisphere it would
much more complicated
as an example
if we
goal really in the middle
to this fisher his you i don't know how to pronounce it in english
this word here
and fisheries so it's not
the fisher from fisher discriminant but the other so anyway will go into this
and look at the left foot on the right foot the very close together
and you see
these activities may be i
so it's
very close by
and it's so if you would like to distinguish between left foot right foot then
this is average data so you see that is very blurry and that on the
single trial level this might be
very difficult to see
another thing is discriminating between the fingers so now not
between thing is different
hands but on the same hand
so singapore again thing thing two again finger five
you see that is
quite blurred
the way that it activity builds up
he compared to the other finger so the representations of very close by
so maybe
centimeter or less than a centimeter apart
and e g only has the resolution of centimetre so for this reason if you
classify on a single trial basis not on the on the average then you get
only thirty percent
the then you get thirty percent error instead of what we had so far five
or ten percent
so just to
show you this
there's a difference but you can see that it's it's only small
but if we would like to two
you know i understand
you know if whether somebody's typing something into what what thing is he's using but
the essential question that we should be asking
well it's not really
subset i mean it's these two fingers so you know if you have to do
thank you like that
i mean it's it's just that the representation representations very close
and this is one individual so you know the image is slightly different seems to
me it looks like that but it's not
it's not true
one i
well i mean i think it depends on
depends on the subject i find it very complicated to actually
you know
this figure fell in this
but anyway so so you see that
well the limits of this to me in fact
this is just this is really movements still
so this is the right side of the story is easy to get a letter
so some slight differences in the extent to this region
but again it's thirty percent error
the one of the questions that i raised was was in the beginning was can
we actually do
do something with this paradigm for
we have billy tation
and then there was the study
it so so maybe you don't find all these these pictures in you
in in you know it's this because they are rather recent results and some of
them are not even published
this is just you can
relax and enjoy the results so so the one of the things was one of
the the paradigms that we followed
and the more clinical setting was weird arm amputee is
so they would do finger movement
with the one on that they still had
and with the other are on that was norm
they they were thinking about this movement while they were intending it
but of course they could move anything
and the question which was
not really solved to this
o point was was whether
this representation that we've seen
with the by tufts potential