it was
you can
it's not for
he or she
in the early nineties you
i only
i q
there you where one
now i will
all right
yes your
you call it
you always
per year
the two
all right
i mean
he variety
you all
it seems that i
in the world
you i
the area
you have to be very old
were already
three he
he who are
and then query
all you know
we want
well for
or or
a of
so are
the last of
you all
in own
and in
if i have here a traveling wave
which is moving in this direction
as tension t
mu is the mass per unit length
that i can write down
as a function
x and t
i can give it a certain amplitude a
by signed
i can write is now in many different ways but let's write it down
this form
i x
you know this
that the
it's call it squared
provided by new
so this is the traveling wave goes into the plus
x direction
is anti-matter moving in the plus x direction no
but is anything moving yes
it is moving in the y direction
so since these particles
i mass
and they moving in this direction
there is kinetic energy
due to the motion in this direction not to
mass that moves along no mass moves in that direction
of here
suppose i carve out here
this is the direction of x
take a small section dx
then the
kinetic energy
the economic
find a little bit of kinetic energy
is one half
times the mass of the atom
times the velocity in the y direction square there is a one right kinetic energy
is one half squared
never confuse this v
with that we
that is the
velocity of propagation
this is the velocity of the string in this direction
so i can write this down
b and is obviously new times dx if i have length dx
and i haven't you
kilograms per meter
so i get here one half
i'm px
and for this
i write down
why did he quit
the velocity
why reactions and i use partial derivatives because i do it at a given location
four x
so what is the t
that's easy that's a piece of cake
there's my functions
so i get in a
then i get k n minus the
so i get the minus
and if he
and then the sign becomes co-signed
so i get a
and x
lines fifty
should put brackets around two that self explain
and now i want to know what the creator of this is
his credits
now i can calculate the total energy is kinetic energy in one wavelength
i'll have to do is integrate now
from zero to allow them to get the total energy in one way
so i'm going to do that right down here now
following closely i have half
then i get the
BYD t square again a square
i got case great
i get these grants
then i got into rule from zero whether of this function
why we teach
and then i have no idea x which is this the axon
that's what the integral is the direct effect
thank you very much
course credit
what is this integral
maybe you don't remember but i've done is often enough that i don't know
in the goal of cosine square of that function
is land
divided by two and i'll leave you with that it's very easy
i can also
take this out and right for that t overview
so you can add it now
and this is in one way flight is my shorthand notation all i'm calculating for
you now is how much is in one wavelength
so you're going to get now
one have mu
a script
the case grew i can write down
four by
divided by let that square
for the square i can write down
divided by new
and then i have my lab
of the two
well this new
girls this new
this too
this for this too
in one that kills one year
now we have the final result
that he
in one wavelength
a script
by script
time t
five by land
if you look at this
you ask me is that obvious
i would say
what do we
there's team that that
my goodness and i can also
cocktail the whole thing i can get the out and get feedback in again
i will admit
i don't have very good feeling
for this function except for one
i don't know
always the energy in the wave is always proportional
so the amplitude square you going to see that when we do
electromagnetic waves in eight o three is always proportional to a square so that's the
only one for which i may have a feeling i know don't be there
and the rest
i leave you with that to see whether perhaps you can talk yourself into understanding
why you see the symbols
where they are
now clearly
there is also potential energy
because it takes energy
was to make that
straight line into curve
and that means work that you have to do
you have to squeeze
two stretch its there's attention you have to stretch the
so we have to do
work to just get the shape
and that is potential energy
and the potential energy
four waif-like
i want you to do on their own it's worked out nicely in french
i will not do it today
happens to me
exactly the same
as the kinetic energy which is by no means obvious
how that's how that is possible
imagine that i have two subspaces
here i'm planning to lies in three but what it really means to subspaces of
dimension in know an in space that could be a very very high damage
well you can take
those two lines projected into a plane
in the number of groups is preserved
and the dimensions of the substances
are preserved
and therefore you don't need to solve the clustering problem in the original space
you can solve it on the projected space
the dimension of the subspace in which you need to protect on two is whatever
the maximum dimensional subspaces plus one
and a few feet this robust you can also of this is this affair
essentially you can pick prediction around the
and it will work
of course there are some that failed
for instance in this case of two lines if you pick a plane that is
perpendicular to one of the lines the lines becomes the origin
and so they can disappear
but the center of projection but failed is enormous that in it so i random
projection do but of course you know
different projections will give affect the quality of the clustering and an open-plan room here
really is how to choose a good prediction and that that's something where
but for most of the applications we just using PCA
and it seems to be working in various application but i'm not saying that is
necessarily the right thing to do
so this is a summary of the algorithm
this is what it is you take your other points
you embed it
with polynomial embedding
to form what i call the embedded data
useful for the null space of this matrix to get polynomials
and here is i'm striking here all the set of problems that i could potentially
get from the null space
once i
have computer polynomials i take derivatives and that gives me
the basis for the normal to subspace
and then the dimensions of subspace is just
they and the mention of them in space minus the rank of all the possible
and then there is an optimal way of choosing the points where to avoid this
derivatives by a certain distance function this is the distance function before it was the
ratio of the polynomial by the derivative here's some more complicated formula because here i'm
using multiple opponents at the same time but i i think you get the intrusion
there is roughly speaking the ratio of the value of the polynomial by the truth
connection with spectral clustering
how many of you are not familiar with spectral clustering
about thirty percent
so spectral clustering
this another technique for doing clustering
which is based on the following idea
imagine that
for every
a pair of points
i could build some sort of measure of similarity that tells me how close
four house so how similar these two points
and the idea is that if two points belong to the same
the similarity should be one
any if two points belong to different groups dissimilarity should be easy
so in the standard clustering problems for instance where i have data that moves around
the cluster centers
i could take the distance to the euclidean distance between points
right they being handled pointer
close by
have small distance
so they belong to the same points that are far apart how large this so
you just been into the minds of the distance that will give you some measure
so has been the question of how could apply
technique to
clustering subspaces
and the key
problem had been that it was very difficult to define
a similarity measure for instance
these points right here or
who thinks is going to be between seventy and eighty percent
OK about three four people who you think that is going to be more than
eighty percent
nobody that's good you're going the right direction
OK so i see you all
not all but i see some of you holding pens and sort of itching to
start writing some some equations on so let's it together
OK as
steve gunn is very illustrious bayesian would say
you have to always write down the probabilities of everything
OK so so let's let's give let's give names to things
let's call c
so actually you see nom already doing this thing of skipping the
the proper procedure if i were to do the proper first procedure i would define
the random variable called small see for example OK and then you can take the
value either big c or c bar OK that's the alphabet but in some sloppy
i just skip that step and go directly to the alphabet right now we call
the presence of cancer and c bar no cancer all right and we do the
same for a positive mammography and and a negative mammography and bar really i wouldn't
have to define other random variable small and here that
it takes values from an alphabet of size two or already
OK so now let's let's formalize things
the the three
things that we said earlier
were that
p of c or p of small equals big already is equal to one percent
OK that's the first fact
what is it about
you see that
none of
so it's again what is the
correct yes
o one percent of its own and no no no no no no what i
said earlier this is one percent of scanned women have breast cancer breast cancer so
you can always condition on being scanned here
OK everybody is kind
so then we can just skip OK so p of c is going to be
one percent than what we said is that
is that the probability of detection so if if there are if there is cancer
the probability that the mammography will pick it up is eighty percent
all right
and now
now if there is no cancer
the probability of false alarm is nine point six percent OK now we formalise things
a little bit
so and what was the question again that we ask
the question was
one has a positive mammography what is the probability that she has breast cancer
we can also write that formally as what is what is p of c given
and again i apologize for sloppy notation
this should really be
p of small sequences given
small r equals began
we can sort of see this very messy to hold sequence and all over the
so now if i give you a bit of time i fear many of you
will have solved is already so let's let's
let's move on
so an easy way to an easy way we have two random variables and they
each take two values so it's almost like we can really
they can example
and raw table right and things are a lot easier i mean counting
it's actually easier than than anything right
let's just this issue very concrete treatment let's take this mistake ten thousand subjects
and so now
in which categories with a fall given information that we have
OK let's take first
let's assume there is concern OK so let's take one percent of them so one
percent of ten thousand is one hundred OK we take that and now we divide
them into groups we can do that now because we know that
the probability of the mammography being positive for this group is eighty percent so eighty
of those hundred people are going to get a positive mammography and now we also
can't obstruct right so we know that twenty
percent actually
do not get a positive mammography OK so this would be a case of of
non detection OK when the system fails to detect the presence of cancer
ten thousand minus one hundred is nine thousand nine hundred so now let's let's look
at what happens to
OK fair enough
so p of c bar would be ninety nine percent OK so this would be the the
the subjects that do not have cancer now how can we divide them up well
we've been told that for the people that do not have cancer the probability of
still getting a positive mammography is nine point six percent so we just do the
math and we get the nine hundred and fifty percent of those subjects actually get
a positive mammography although they didn't have cancer
eight thousand nine hundred fifty
that's basically
this number minus number get a negative mammography and they do not have cancer so
now we can go in and do this little tables
and we can put all the numbers in
in our almost done
so what we're going to do now is we're going to obtain bayes rule in
the very very intuitive way
let's remember what the question was
the what the question was what is the probability of c
conditioned on the fact that it's OK sorry that and the mammography was positive
so we know that the mammography was positive so we can almost ignore this column
so what we need to do is we need to go into this column and
divide this number by the sum of these two numbers
and that's what's going to give us the answer and you can already see that
is not such a big number
OK let's do it so the first thing we need is is the denominator right
you can also put it in words so of all subjects that have a positive
mammography how many of these actually have cancer that's the question that is
what is p of the given OK
so the the first thing we need is always p them but we've seen before
that there is a rule of marginalization OK so if i have the joint distribution
i just need to add up to sum up over and over the thing that
doesn't interest me
so i just add up over c and c bar OK again the notation here
actually hurts to a little bit because here you would really want to say p
of small n equals big n
OK and then i sort of
marginalize over the values that small c can take so small so you can take
the value big c or c bar OK
but i think if you look at the table it's actually much easier than the
this image is supposed to here
like this one
in which you have to do with this
this help the
what happened the and
what was the model
you can consider
so we might call
because that would the
so on
i could change
if you don't
with the middle point
so it's been that way
how many
and this is the second dimension to those
and because i should say that this kind of mess
it depends on the point challenge because
you have to be made
which are like that learning
that you o
because the in central
in that
and that is going to play
what about
but the main
that we
so far
all right
that's because
wait wait
the main
just to
o point that you
so this is an example of this
o point
how can
some but this one
between the
neighboring pixels
the that
four one
in the same way
my the that
one of the
this debate
this one
so what
o this that
while she won why
i talked about before
so how can detect one more
we apply my all pixels of the image
and the two
response to the model
we know which one is the stronger
we can understand which like we have this part of the image
it is also possible
one particular direction
they should not one particular one
give you the strongest
line which i want to
the great
it is
like this
by the way
and this one one because they
one night
you also the right
but this is
a little bit like this
the fact one
why the image
i just want to return to something
which you pointed out yesterday search again i don't know
you will proving one half of the correspondence lemma
if w forces all instances of t
in our is reflexive
we went through the process
and what i said is OK suppose one is true and not too
in other words suppose wlr forces all instances of t
but our is not reflexive
hence there is some irreflexive w in w
in big w so
i said that
OK that's little w
and it's a reflexive phenomena
indicate that by saying that there isn't an arrow
from from w two itself
then we built to model and we found that there was a contradiction
what you suggest is
we could just forget these
right we just delete these guys and make w dating
because then it would make box
not true OK we can do that
because we given the model were not allowed to fiddle with the model
so we given the brain were not allowed to fiddle with the frame
OK we can add whatever evaluation we want to work but you can't go around
ah OK so that's why i wasn't fast enough to pick that up but i
thought about it last year why not do that you know it's as simple as
OK there is there isn't OK so that's just
one point now
i finished off sort of giving a little cook's tour of various
the frame class
that's the class of kripke frames for which
this logic is
seven complete
and the first order condition and a lot of that right so
why reflexivity remain
that w
reaches itself
and what we saw is that there is general
theorem which says that you take any one of these and have them as shapes
to you all
then you get an appropriate hilbert calculus which is stronger than k
because you can prove all things
and if you take the appropriate
the union of all of these conditions you get a class of kripke frames
which satisfies all the conditions that you've taken the name the correspondence between these two
that's the soundness and completeness theorems still carries through
so what i want to do now
in the first just i want to do it briefly but i want to give
you a tour of
what is known about these three notions
you would calculate the kripke frames and the condition
and the first order definable here
the fact that something is first order definable is called correspondence theory about the shape
corresponds to a first order formula
the fact that there is another condition which captures the shape and vice versa is
known as the incompleteness of the
to some definition
i will say that
a normal modal logic l
is determined by class of kripke and so some frame plasticity and determines the logic
every frame validates five if and only if phi is a theorem
OK every frame validates five if and only if i is deducible from the empty
remember i defined
logics into a nice that you can define logic is all the validity
all the things that a logical consequence of
two doucet
all the theorems all the things which is deducible from the empty set
what i'm saying is that when the whole
for frame class and the
the logic you say that the frame class determines the logic
unfortunately there is another notion of complete which is that
they said that the logic is a
if some frame class
the terms
that logic
and normal modal logic is canonical
if it's determined by its canonical frame so remember we did this canonical model construction
using infinite sets of formulae
and maximally consistent extensions of our assumptions gamma
that gave us the frame and from that we build to model by saying something
is true in the world if it's in the world if it's in the set
associated with the world
so if the
canonical model
if the validities of the canonical frame
are exactly the things that deducible from the empty set and you save the logic
is canonical
as it
very general theorem notice of course
i can't go into the details because
otherwise you know it just takes up the whole lecture
so this is shape there's a particular class of formulae called sulcus formulae
you can find a very good proof in blackburn roc and venema
two can't
really OK
can i go on
and then there are these three theorem
these three theories are more which are going to be an admin
you have a solid with formula five
and you know that corresponds to some first order condition on frames
and that's effectively computable from five look at you you look at five
and there is an algorithm which i'll compute the frame
so for example
you know if i give you five
shape five
and there is an algorithm which you can crank the handle and little bit out
five five corresponds to this
moreover if a is the sole course formula
or if they want to assault formulated and we take the shapes
then the
hilbert logic
OK i one a case canonical
in other words
its canonical frame the validities are the canonical frame are all the things you can
deduce from the empty set
in the other half is
this is
it's determined by exactly the union of all the conditions right if you give me
of course for the say a one i can compute some condition
in general for example if sigma
is the diagonal covariance matrix that says that all of these these are independent of
each other
the way you get
interesting structure in this vector t
it is by assuming that there are
nonzero elements on the off diagonal of sigma
so that's for now just imagine that
the elements sigma i j
of this covariance matrix
is going to be some function of i and j
OK so i think of these points is being order
t one through t and then i'm going to make the covariance of neighboring points
be higher than the covariance of points far away so i and plus one have
higher covariance ironi plus ten are going to have lower covariance and now we can
just draw random samples of this vector
and see what they look like
and we're going to draw these vectors as a function of the index going from
one through n
there are different ways that i can make the
covariance depend on
i and j the covariance between the he i t
can depend on
the difference between i and j
say it could be e to the minus the difference between i and j squared
with different length scales in other words it could care about the distance between i
and j
more or less but you'll see that the examples
let's pick one for this covariance function and draw
one sample
of that
so here it is drawn a hundred dimensional vector
so t one through t hundreds
in order and connecting up the dots
and this is for covariance
function that basically relates i and j with the particular length scale and you can
see intuitively what that length scale is it's sort of the skill with which this
function wiggles
OK now i just switched to talking about this as a function
even though this is the vector from
one two hundred
and in fact it sort of looks like a function we can think of this
space now instead of being the index that goes from one two hundred as being
some input space x
OK so this is the function of x which happens to go from one two
hundred but it could have nominated known non integer values here
and one draw this function looks like this let's try
remember this is again
distribution in hundred dimensions
and i just wanted it i can draw another sample from exactly the same guassian
distributions and put on top of that
that sort of in green right there
i can try another one
and if i draw a few of these samples you get a sense for what
the functions under this
calcium prior over functions look like they're sort of functions that have variants of roughly
one and a wiggle about with someone scale
OK so if i draw even more functions you get to see
just like typical examples of this
essentially an guassian process what you're doing is you're generalizing the multivariate gaussians distribution
over these vectors to be
distribution over functions of
these are just examples of draws from that a distribution over functions
they have a particular properties variances lengthscales and so on which you can control
so i
as an example of
another covariance function
i drawn examples with a particular different length scales
and you can see that these functions
now we go last
as you vary the input dimension
so they have a longer length scale so really i could draw
functions with
shorter length scales or i could draw functions that have difference different forms of the
covariance so instead of
the covariance going down
with e to the minus distance squared it could go down with e to the
minus absolute value of the distance if i do that
i'll get
functions that look like this they're actually quite rough
these are
the special case against processes they are given by things like brownian motion
so here are just some examples of these kinds of functions
and this relates the second way of thinking about downstream processes
i can also
i think of just linear functions as a special case of gas processes
sorry the weekly
and that's the numerical issues should be a straight line to measure the
i played around with this look strange
this is just this this is just a random draw of the straight line
OK to ignore the wiggles that's just bad numerics on my part
here's another random draw the straight line
here's another
you know here five more
there are twenty one
so these are also examples of
draws from guassian process which happens to have a particular covariance structure that gives you
straight lines
these are fairly easy to define once you familiar with these covariance structure
what do you do with calcium processes
what you do is
use them for learning is for learning about functions so essentially what you want to
do is you want to get examples of function
are examples of data points from the function
and you have a prior over functions and using those examples of inputs and outputs
we can infer posterior over functions which actually also happens to be a guassian process
and then you can make predictions
so let's do that let's imagine that we had
these input output data points
now i'm going to
fit guassian process for do inference under guassian process with these inputs and outputs OK
and what this shows is
the boolean function
and the standard deviation of the function or maybe two standard deviations in this case
so it shows you the sort of posterior prior functions had all those different kind
of weekly things the posterior functions is going to look like it goes through the
data because
you know the power like that gives the posterior
you know somehow manages the data
and have some uncertainty in the uncertainty is going
as you go far away from the data like you would expect me that's what
let's go back to the talk
so that's the perspective of gas processes just starting from gas in distribution we go
into more than math but i think the important thing is to get the pictures
observing the entire sample will be the probability of observing
each individual
for example if i have
one show a collection of images
in my
database the collection of images the probability of that
observing the entire collection
is the problem of the probe into absurd
each one thing which is independent
by doing that i will think these
expression for the probability of observing an entire some sample
in this case the statistical definition for some series of observations
if i have
at hand to make statistical inference
when we see
these object as a function of the the these hasname is called the likelihood function
the likelihood function is a function of the data
it tells us
for a given sample packs
which feed those are more likely
to improve the at that
let's give an example
any questions
please feel free to drop
let's assume
i know that my observations follow
part of the gulf distribution
in these
what about x here
and now it's time to observe one
what i observe one observation here another here's another here
other here rather here
the here
another here
on the other hand
that's all
i ask you to
tell me what you think when you think that every of gaussian distribution lines
this is just observation
concentrated in this region
some of them are far away
but most concentrated
for tell OK give me
what you think is the gaussian distribution that's generating process you possibly tell me well
maybe something like this
there are many observation region so probably the mean of the girlfriends over here
so this is what people want
which has given
i mean
in the given
standard deviation
and this
now for the same sample
for the same sample x x
this particular sample here
for the same sample i proposed this model
these blue model
which of these two models think it's more likely to have generated the samples
the red one
so there's something
about the red mullets bad about the problem of what is
the likelihood function
because you mooted if you multiply
these values of this function on these observations
you will get a larger number than if you multiply the values of these of
observations according to this distribution
so actually what we are
doing is we're fixing these sample x
and you ask you which of the infinitely many possible
gulshan function
the gaussian function that maximize
a function which is the product that product
now the only thing we know that it is that we have
got distribution we don't know the parameters the question is what are the parameters
but the mean and lots the same of the gaussians such that these what is
you may think that this the reliable criteria or not
this has the name is called the maximum likelihood estimate is functional
that produces
feet according to to describe what is called the maximum like this
it's probably one of the most common ways of helping us to
mean this marks like
no particular focus on this
this is its most popular
so the goal is we're going to observe observe some data
and we want to maximize expression with respect to people because we want to find
which to maximize like
the same way as these functions the best describe is that
we want to find which to to maximize just like any questions he
emma going too slowly for you please you can calibrate
who who who think i'm going to be
you have different
OK i was thinking way too fast
well in the data
feature or you are very good liars
but anyway let's go
so the negative
OK so this is like the
we're going particularly to be interested in an object which is
like function to maximize function or minimize the negative
of these
like function
it's complicated to maximize or minimize product so we just take the logo
of these products
producer some
because if you have any function
that you want to maximize or minimize
the expectation of y is just a
so we generate we generate all the samples side
we for example we defined new random variable y i the expectation y is just
the entropy
now by the law of large numbers we know that we generate a lot of
then this average must converge to its expected value
so when you generate a lot of samples
the sum of the y i was going to look very close to it
what does that mean
well it is the sum of the y arises within epsilon of a
OK this is so so this event is going to happen with probability one as
you increase the number of points
well the sum of the y is has a very nice form the sum of
the y axis is the log
the log of the probability of x one plus log probability of x two plus
log probability of x three
therefore it's just the log one of the probability the entire sequence
the point so-called independently
and therefore the stem cells
is that the probability of this particular sequence
it's going to lie within
within epsilon of what people call calling the typical probability
it's going to live within two to the minus end
h minus epsilon into the minus an explosives
OK so this is that this is another way in which this
in which and it turns out to be very natural
which turns out to be a natural notion of randomness
OK so let's return to our main question and c
now that we have the notion of randomness we can actually try to formalize this
question a little bit
OK so we had a large set which in this toy example was just english
we measure the bunch of features for each word
because of its where we define security features
the first feature was just that the word has made more than five
now we wanted to find the a distribution over and over s
i wanted to find an assignment of probabilities to all the work
that satisfy the constraints we'd observed OK we observed that you know thirty percent of
the words having more than five so that satisfies these particular constraints but otherwise is
is as random as possible
and now we can formalise that we can see that what we want is something
that has maximum entropy subject to these constraints
OK this is called the maximum entropy principle
so now we actually know notion of entropy we can actually formalise this is an
optimisation problem
OK let's see what the problem looks like
so we're looking for a probability distribution p
it's over a set s which is english words OK
we can think of this probability distribution is just a really long vector so
the fifty thousand words it's just to vector with
with fifty thousand entries which all probabilities and so they're all you know greater than
or equal to zero and add up to one
OK so we have this we have this vector
its entries are these effects that the probability of x
we want them to add up to one and we want them all to be
positive is of sort of a reasonable probability distribution
we want to find the thing that has maximum entropy
subject to the constraints we observed
and the constraints with the expected values of these features had certain
certain we put something OK so for instance feature one that i equals one
i was simply one if the word having more than five and zero otherwise
and we wanted it to be the case
the expected value of that feature
the average value of that feature according to this distribution was point three
so i you about this this optimisation problem
you know we have the notion of entropy we have another reversion random we can
write it down precisely
so the nice thing about this is that the constraints turned out to be linear
the thing that we're solving forest
OK with solving for this vector
these are linear constraints this is this is just a linear equation over here
so we have a bunch of linear constraints
these define some sort of policy group
and the function we optimizing is a concave function
so this entire thing becomes convex optimisation problem
so a convex optimisation problem is just the generic
and so
this now is a plot of phi one against fighting and we can now just
divide the point
again we add a third feature for the bias that means that plane doesn't have
to be through the origin
so in theory
given any dataset
if we come up with the right set of basis functions we can construct a
new dataset
which is linearly separable
so maybe it's going to be easier to do that rather than going back and
writing new code and doing
more complicated decision rules don't deal with planes we just about the data and total
the simple temporal what's the planes will work
not always the right thing to do but it's useful trick one you'll see come
up a lot
there are different areas machine learning and one larger the people often identified school supervised
learning or more particularly sort of batch supervised learning which is the setting where you're
given a training set to a data set of x and y you get to
look at it for long time you build your prediction machine and then you can
deploy that to make predictions on the future and i talked about one particular version
of that which is this binary classification
within supervised learning is also
a whole bunch of
tasks that you could imagine that match the same story if you're
given the batch a whole bunch of examples that you get to look at build
the prediction machines the predictions are necessarily plus one minus one
they could be
other sorts of prediction so
we've already seen multiclass classification the land usage there could be multiple different labels nearest
neighbour it was obvious how to implement the decision boundary
let's say
we might also have to predict
a real number say if we wanted to predict properties of concrete or well
well sourced material than a strength or slow ratio or some property of the material
involved in the real numbers is not going to be plus minus one
netflix movie ratings are stars i give this may be one to five stars and
that's what's called ordinal regression so these stars one two three four five not really
five separate classes because we know they have an ordering two them and we should
take that into account say
it's special prominence have a special name and your continued unmolested sort of different types
outputs particular applications have particular names for the sort of thing we have to protect
now i don't have time
sadly to go through sort of how you would solve all of these different types
of supervised learning
problem but my promise was that a lot of the ideas that i already showed
you binary classification to extend these other cases so i'm going to look at one
of these cases real valued regression
to show you how these different ideas apply
to this problem and then hopefully
you'll be in a better position to see how you would solve the other problems
as well
the real valued regression
we now have inputs so we've got to inputs again but the output now
is the real numbers so i can't just
draw two different colours blue dots and red dots a
the three d plot now where the red points of the data set have different
real valued type so this could be
amount of sand in my concrete and the percentages some aggregate i'm using and many
OK and
just as with classification
when we want to sort of fit what's going on we could make a parametric
assumption we could say
maybe we could put a plane through this data set
and for that plane and maybe that will be useful thing to do
you need some algorithm for
discovering the plane because we don't have to draw by hand
and there are many different ways you could do that
but really standard way it's called least squares
you see all of these black lines joining the data plane
those differences of the residuals of the errors the sort of mismatch between model and
the observed data
if we
square all of those are terms and add them up then we get square error
and we could find the plane for which is that error term the smallest possible
that's called least squares
it's very very important and the way you can tell it's important is that this
is the matlab code to implement it
so if it wasn't important they went to
got one symbol that would do this for you in one line like that
it's very fast you can do this for a very large datasets almost immediately
and that just gives you the answer
you might not be always what you want to do but it's important to know
that's one of the things you could do
and now we could go through the same progression
questions we asked about classification so one thing one question is
my data set isn't going to lie on the plane i think the nonlinearity in
my data so all real datasets have nonlinearities
the strength of my concrete for this amount of aggregate is here and the strength
of my concrete this amount of aggregate is here is not going to be the
case that if i add more and more aggregate strength goes on forever i'm not
going to be able to build concrete with infinite strength at some point it will
saturate and for almost any sort of physical
real system things don't go off to infinity so
make assuming that
linear trendlines will extend forever is always about assumptions the nonlinearities in problems
here's the fake data that the linear
and the code i used to fit it
how did this happen
i invented new fake features so
i had my data set of inputs and i had one input in this case
and the bias term
and then
to the ones on the input features i also added the square of the input
from the keyboard the input
all the way up to
the sixth order polynomial of so now and pretending that my data set has seven
columns and even though it's really only one dimensional datasets
and then
completely determined by electrons
because they are the so-called majority carriers
so i hope that now you
i understand and i have a feeling why we call it majority carriers because there
fourteen orders of magnitude the concentration is fourteen orders of magnitude larger
the of electrons then of evolves
of course this is also
illustrated in the so-called band diagram by shifting the fermi level
towards the conduction band and intrinsic material thing to say
the fermi level occupies the position more or less
in the middle
of the band gap
making the semiconductor
mark period and type the fermi level
two words
the conduction band and why
do you know what this
fermi level
or fermi energy
represents the semiconductor material
it actually tells you all the
the energy of electron
in the material is
of the valence electron and so you can understand when we have more electrons
the higher
positions when we put them
in the conduction band was high energies and also the average energy of these electrons
will go up
so the
this is represented by fermi level so the fermilab has to go up
of course when we do it
the other way around italy
have these holes
so actually what we do
we have
so let's now take a ten to twenty so
one thousand times more boron atoms
in this example phosphorus atoms
then we know
what the concentration of always will be ten to twenty
from this equation we can easily calculate
how many electrons we have in this material you see around two
it's almost no free electrons in such material
so it means
most of the electrons now
see in the valence band
so the average
the energy of electrons will go down and we will see it by moving the
fermi level towards the valence band is this clear
which one
no these are not random random
OK you see this is the distance of the firm level from the
the maximum energy of the valence band
and it depends on the concentration so once you change the concentration
then also this distance
will change
so now using again this band diagram is a nice model to illustrate some of
the processes
we know that the band gap of
for example crystalline silicon is one point one electron world so when we have a
photon with a certain energy
depending on the energy of the photon
electron hole pair will be generated or not
so what is the
limit for the energy
it is the energy of the band gap
now again
in reality is a little bit more complicated because you probably remember we have direct
and indirect semiconductors indirect semiconductors photon energies enough
generate electron hole pair in indirect semiconductors where the
maximum of the energy level
is above the minimum of the conduction band in indirect semiconductors this is not true
so we need also the phonon interaction it means the interaction we
semiconductor lattice is to get this
electron hole generation but schematically we need the photon that has at least
the energy of the band gap of the semiconductor to generate these electron hole pair
when we have a photon that has for example free electron world
two electrons was
electron was more than the band gap of silicon
it will generate
electron hole pair
which at the beginning has
the difference in energy free electron world
but in interaction with the lettuce electrons want to go to the energy which is
and the holds also the minimum energy for holes so actually they will come to
see in the energy
that are the
the bottom of the valley the conduction band and the top of the valence but
so finally these electron hole pair will help
the energy only one point one electron what so we are losing almost two electron
world by
with respect to another one
but that's just not very helpful
o use english
these services which have
how does this is
so in space you can define measures on hilbert space
but what you cannot define is a measure that
basically does does not change that is that is flat that does not change no
matter how it shifted around
can years
what we're
so basically you need to finite dimension
and kind of as an intuition for why it doesn't work in
inherit space doesn't immediately say anything about translation invariance but the problem was volume in
infinite dimensional spaces and say you have
so you're looking at
and q
it was actually angst say one-half so in one dimension that's just an an interval
the volume of that is
one half
in two dimensions it directly or it's a square
and the volume of that is
one four
three dimension the volume is one and so on
so if you take let if you keep the edge length fixed
and let the dimension go to infinity
that converges to zero
or anything that smaller than one any the edge length smaller than one it converges
to zero
for one it always stays one for anything larger than one
it converges to infinity
and if you take any finite dimensional
you always get a well defined notion of volume but basically if you take this
if you take this this limit to infinity
then you have three kinds of cubes in three dimensions right those is what the
results when one of those things that one
and the olympic measure basically what it does is it's defined in a somewhat similar
manner two
to the way that the riemann integral that you all know is defined in terms
of step functions of limits of the functions and basically what it does is conning
and but in a limited sense so if you have a smooth volume and you
want to take the measure of that
the new approximate that william by bye cubes to make smaller and smaller
but this whole notion of the volume of a cube is is a big problem
in an image
more questions
please don't feel intimidated by the name of the theorem OK it's it's very it's
very simple and very useful here
it's not necessarily simple to prove but it's it's easy enough to understand so that
the question is
when you when you look at this the question that arises immediately is
if we have these two measures given
is density we
repositories matters so if their density that transforms one into the other
and the theorem here tells us when that is the case
and basically what it says it is
if you
you have to make one
kind of basic sanity cheque and if that works out there is the density
and that works as follows so if you
if you think of of this
of this reweighting idea as you you generate one measured by reweighting another one
and that means that
if if this measure here is zero somewhere on the set
then this measure you must also be there
because you can never transform something that is zero by the that's that is zero
into something nonzero by reweighting with something finite that won't work
so that obviously can't work if this measure somewhere
where this measure is not then they can't be a density
that's a very
basic observation
and now what is identical in theorem tells us simply if unless this is the
case there's always the density
so that's very satisfactory that's the kind of result you like to see
OK so what it says is if
this this kind of property years is formalized with
was fancy symbol and it has name is called absolute continuity
and i i wouldn't bother you with that
if it wasn't so so only present in the literature so if you're looking to
the literature and you see absolute continuity all it means is simply simply this property
this measure is that this measure mu two is said to be absolutely continuous with
respect to the measure mu one
if this doesn't happen
whenever this measure zero this one is there as well
yes there is
there is a connection to the usual notion of continuity that's right and there's also
in this
in this notation here there is some connection to the usual notion of differentiability
i would rather
take that offline
the the reason why
why you never see a bayes equation
for the dirichlet process
it's because between the prior
the posterior of the dirichlet process
this relationship breaks down i would say more on that later
now after about ten minutes left to tell you
how probability is formalized this framework we construct stochastic processes in infinite dimensional spaces and
how to construct a gaussian process
the idea how that works is the following
we have some
we have some space over here
but you think of my station my hair
as per unit it may only illustrate that
if you if you want to convince people that you seriously injures theory then then
you do your illustrations with x fig
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his visit MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
let's get started
one announcement
one announced test three
the celebration of learning
it's going to be on wednesday
which means no lecture
the lecture one stansted the celebration
please go to your rooms as assigned here you're writing eleven o'clock
probably in this room right now
and those in the room assignments
they are the same as for test two
not the same as for test one we move
more people out of ten to fifteen give a little more room here
and there's plenty room of these others
those the right at one o'clock not go to the normal lecture room six one
twenty were writing and twenty six one hundred
and the coverage is right here
upon the the website so
you should know
what we're
going to be
examining you one and the same comments made before
you know i want to
give you feedback let you know how you doing with your study
methods are effective or not it's an attempt to
re-test admission to MIT or anything like that if you've done your work should do
very well
if you haven't done your work
you shouldn't do very well and will be able to tell you so
so just remember what we've said in the past please take some time read the
whole exam
do these questions for you
the ones that you find easiest to those first
but let's let's be honest with you know this is high-school anymore
so i mean some people tell me after the second test your head have a
cheaper hardware used will think about it you think i want to give you an
and give you a question
that requires you to take something off the age she transferred to the answer page
it's not pattern recognition
this is the medical school for quite a while you know you've to think here
you've got to think
you know in what is now the third test
it's going to be more and more thinking and less and less
role although will have some confidence builders and they i don't want to knock people
after a balance
so work work parametrically
try not to immediately start punching in numbers
and if you don't do question in great detail
right you know tell me what you do quite some energy is
minimize something to maximize something
give us a sense that you have
graphs with the material
keep your eyes on your paper
our effort is going to be to get those graded on wednesday in bacteria recitation
on thursday
i think that's an remember please bring bring your five items we're we're having more
and more people showing up minus
periodic table
table of constants of something to write with that people ask me for pounds for
no one has asked me if renergie sullivan
and had to help anybody on that one
good well today what i wanna do is
started new unit i want to talk today about organic chemistry now this is this
going to be the the most minimal introduction to organic chemistry with reason we talk
about organic chemistry all is in order to prepare ourselves for more solid state chemistry
specifically talk about powers and ultimately we talk about biochemistry
because even though this is solid state chemistry we as
beings are solid state devices
were made of soft matter
this is the polymer
this is a
semiconductor band gap of two to three electron volts but it's not made out of
three five semiconductor
nature's figured out a way of doing this without
in organic
so we need to know a little bit but if you really wanted organic chemistry
we have to take five twelve so i can't teach one fifteen minutes with people
in one semester so let's get a few definitions under our belts
organic chemistry is the chemistry of compounds containing both carbon and hydrogen
not just carbon carbon and hydrogen so diamond
graphite or not organic
because they contain carbon hydrogen and what makes these two elements special that
that they figure so prominently in living
organisms first of all hydrogen hydrogen is the
element with the lowest atomic number
lowest atomic number and when it loses its electron it
changes character dramatically we've talked about this in recent
lectures were we have simply a proton
if is capable of forming covalent bonds but when it finds itself in a compound
forming a covalent bond something that strongly electronegative it's so denuded of electrons even in
often don't do much better
maybe a little bit better than a lot better
and the new methods
and the linear methods are immensely much faster because instead of having to compare
of image each window to maybe a thousand or two thousand kernels
we simply dot product that the descriptors to extract from that
with some simple
that causes the detection school
so the nearest theme tend to dominate
these kinds of detection tasks you're evaluating things lot
many many windows in each image
a lot faster and they work could roughly as well as the new ones
OK so this is the detector when you're running it you do the same thing
scanning at multiple scales for the support vector machine tickets detections out
so that's
pretty straightforward
now if you look at a few run linear SVM you can look back and
see with coefficients for large
in figure out from that which the wavelets were important
and work out exactly what it is to detect actually chewing on tobacco detections and
you find that fact what it's doing is simply doing kind of
approximate ten plate
matching to the rough out of the silhouette of the person
so in fact
even though the support vector machine and use different descriptive we're not doing something is
very different from the previous methods
but that's OK we've got you know maybe slightly better learning method
probably the performance is slightly better but it's not it's not very different
that happens quite often just moved to actions of
another kind of message
so this is
face detector was made about a decade ago now
what it does
is in each detection window calculates the set of wavelet coefficients
a large number of positions and scales
and that's it
it's the probabilistic method rather than a machine learning method builds distributional model
the distribution of responses you expect on the positive class the negative class
tries to use that to do
the problem with that is that if you have many coefficients many ways it's in
calculating very high dimensional distribution you need to work on that
you can't
you physically counterexample build histogram that distribution it just has too many regions if typically
got the only features the right here but there certainly hundreds if not thousands of
each of which is the real numbers you can't physically stored table with thousands of
OK so
this detect so so so the classic machine learning way of dealing with best so
can use my i naive bayes
so i do something with each of the individual
maybe all histogram some probabilistic model the it's responses on the positive class is this
is the negative class and that will give me my first initial model which we
you can do that it doesn't work very well
it's it's too simplistic car the wavelet to to correlated with one another
so what this detector does is it makes a kind of compromise solution
this is OK
it's a that i want to build histogram based distribution
so be sampling everything of building tables over empirical
positive and negative and i want to build tables which are kind of
a size it's convenient to fit into memory but is going to be big enough
to have a lot of discrimination and that
so the size the talk was about one hundred thousand cells
what can you do with that well if i quantise my descriptors very very coarsely
maybe into just two or three values
then i can have some power of two or three to whatever power gets ten
thousand cells it turns out you do the sums you're five to eight
well let's see you can include the single histogram
and still build a probabilistic model that will fit into memory it will fit into
we can evaluate it quickly without too much too many problems
but it will it will capture the joint statistics of those five to eight life
so this is what the thing does
it takes its of wavelets
in fact it looks
OK so
but first pieces
i want to look at the OCR collection of science magazine from nineteen ninety to
two thousand so
just to give you an idea
of what the status
is the basically
have you all seen j store
that work
OK so j store is a an online archive of scientific articles and what they
do is an amazing project is they
take the original bound articles and they scan them and they run them through optical
character recognition software and then the index the original scans the the output of the
so the
it's cool because so you know it'll screw stuff up like this is two columns
and maybe they're OCR software can handle two columns and it may be it doesn't
get all the words right but it's pretty accurate and maybe the punctuation is totally
bogus but that's OK but for
doing search when you want to search for word like
you know phenotype then as long as they got phenotype a bunch of times in
the article you're going to get the right skin back and since you never interact
specifically with the noisy OCR very effective system for
searching online for searching articles online that are archived and they have signs all the
way back to eighteen eighty one taxi that later on
OK but of course
j store has problem which is that they have millions and millions of articles but
they're only organised by journal and by day
and what they want is a system where people can can go through and browse
and examine these articles topic oriented way but simply have skin so many articles etc
etc out of the question to to annotate the scans of keywords moreover and they
want to be automatic they they don't want to have to read every article and
assigned keywords the whole point is that you don't have to do that you can
just put them through machine and then led scholars use them effectively so there are
interested in looking at the kind of topic the composition of their archives so here
we're taking their collection of science magazine for ten years looking at seventeen thousand documents
this is eleven million words and we used a vocabulary of twenty thousand terms basically
a practical point you typically remove stopwords words like that of but or and and
very rare words which don't affect inference model
or somebody recently told me might affect the inference that we talk about that later
but the so this is the doctrine for analyzing we theta one hundred topic LDA
model using variational inference but could have been
OK so here's that same article that i showed you
i should say that this article was actually in the test set so this article
we didn't
we didn't fit with
this is the article how many genes an organism to survive in an evolutionary sense
and using posterior inference so here the wt and for this article right
i draw my here the WTEM's
and with posterior inference this is the expected value of the data given those w
OK so
termites the which is just expectation
given w
one and topic
that we
o i think
that's it this is an approximation of
so this is like the
you need to sort of make assumptions on what the correlations are across
across samples across data points
so you could then you could then sort of right the whole thing
is a very very long vector where you would sort of
you know if dataset was sort of an n times the matrix
you could then sort of
you could then sort of stuck it all is very long vector
and if if there wasn't if there wasn't any correlations
across data points across the the and so on and so the point i mean
i mean the vector y or x y and y j
if there wasn't and all the labels the dimensional OK now if there wasn't correlations
between them
the covariance matrix of the very very long vector that's and times the
it would be a block diagonal alright and you will have this little blocks
we then dimensions for a specific data point and then it would be easier across
the points so that would be a simple way of of dealing with non i
i d
case there would sort of make a strong assumption
i mean he's
there is a correlation shows
anyone wants making it comes from the
so far
so you think you are right
x y
there are
i we define it yesterday
you can think of correlation as
given that you've observed
feature one
is that informative about what the output what the value of future two is going
to be doesn't tell you anything so if you were to would you be able
to for example one of them
condition on that
and then sample independently the other one or or would you actually have to take
into account what the value of of of that of the first one was or
now for example whole vectors here you're sampling here you sampling
vectors set out of size two times times
one right so this is
vectors with too little numbers in in right now
and sampling one of those vectors OK and i know that the values
in the vector are correlated so what if a simple one of them if i
this one here and it turns out to be here i have a strong idea
of what were the other can be right and actually i just wanted to cut
a slice of discussing here and you will see that the other one the conditional
distribution actually depends on the value
that this one took
if there are correlated otherwise it doesn't depend but now when i when i'm done
something that one what i'm not going to sample
a second point in this plane if i said that i'm sampling them independently i
can actually forget what i wanted to sample it doesn't depend all
they wouldn't be independent if
if you were in the was saying if my sampling scheme actually
sort of took into account what i just sampled OK
so i'm saying here is the independent
everyone happy
so now if we wanted to if we had seen the data and we wanted
to estimate the mean and the covariance matrix of the gaussians we could do the
usual thing right so we maximize the
likelihood and this is the thing that we've got since it's done most comfortably if
you take logarithms first right
if you just the math
i suppose
it doesn't come as a surprise to anyone that
the estimate of the mean is the sample mean and the estimate of the covariance
is just the sample covariance
so if you remember
if you remember
what we said yesterday in the lecture any
think now any element of this matrix here OK what is it going to be
if i if i just concentrate on a single element
if it wasn't diagonal elements is quite quite here is just i go
i take these dimension of y is instructed the component of the mean and that
square that i some right
and if it's an of diagonal elements just to that for forty two
sort of dimensions involved OK
right so i remember yesterday when we were talking about tossing a coin and we
wanted to estimate what the probability of heads
i was going to be right
and were saying that the maximum likelihood estimator
i simply said number of heads divided by number of trials or right
i we sort of discussed now what happens
if i toss the coin once
is the maximum likelihood estimator a good idea
of the vector w and the separating hyperplane should intersect this connecting line half
in the middle
now one thing that i haven't told you yet if you
look again at this definition of separating hyperplane the hyperplane satisfy this equation and that
the right this function is negative and positive but of course i could multiply these
hyperplane with any
non-zero number and geometric location of the set of points satisfying this equation wouldn't change
so there's this scaling freedom in the separating hyperplane if i have some non-zero constant
then the set of points equal to this one
so this thing here
parameterisation describes the same hyperplane this one
and to remove this scaling degree of freedom will say the hyperplane is in canonical
form with respect to some set of data that top points if the minimum value
of this function here
is one
so will take the modulus
but real valued quantity here we asked this modulus b one on the closest datapoints
this means on on these points here
the modulus of this function should be one
so let's call it the canonical optimal hyperplane
the nice thing about canonical representation is that we can all relate to the margin
of separation to the size of this weight vector w
so you can see this as follows so here we have the line with this
function takes the value minus one hand we have line plus one and let's consider
some points that lie exactly on these two lines x one x two
so we know that x one satisfies this equation this equation x two satisfies this
so we can take the difference of these two equations and again use the linearity
of the product of x one minus x two here
and then we can divide both sides by the length of w
and what we have on the left side
this is just a unit vector in the direction of w so taking the dot
product between this vector is a unit vector means simply measuring how long is the
along the direction of w
this is the one connecting x two to x one we take this vector projected
onto this direction of w and measure how long in other words we exactly measure
the size of this margin orthogonal to the hyperplane
along the direction of w
so this
this is the size of the margin and on the right-hand side we have two
of the length of the so we can see
the the size of the margin is inversely proportional to the length of w if
we want to maximize the margin of separation we would have to minimize the length
of w
while ensuring that separates the data and then it's in canonical form
so we're going to do this and the
the next slide after this i guess maybe two after this before i get to
i just briefly want to
give a little bit of motivation why we should actually
maximise the marginal
of course you have much more details about this in the children talked a lot
about statistical learning theory
so i've deliberately skipped all statistical arguments for this kind of try to give you
some intuitive argument
one is this motivation in terms of noise on the patterns you can imagine if
you had a separation of two classes which has a certain margin indicated barrows sometimes
people measure the margin from here to here but usually is actually just from the
from the hyperplane to one side
but it does not just a factor of two
so if you have such a separating hyperplane you could imagine that even if you
put some noise on your patterns
if the patterns well separated with margin if the noise is smaller than this model
you would still classified incorrectly so you can think of it as some kind of
robustness with respect to noise if you want
another way to think of is the following
suppose you have some events in data points here of one class here's the other
class and i suppose you moral have computed the smallest sphere containing data points
it's called israel are
for simplicity we assume that
separation goes through the origin if you then want to
encode the direction of the hyperplane in this simple two-dimensional example
what you would have to encode is this angle
however if you know that
margin between the two classes at least rho and you can also work out with
which accuracy you would have to code come out
it turns out the largest margin is the smaller the accuracy will come up that
you need to have the largest delta gamma this lack you can allowing the coding
of gamma
so this can actually be related to some
compression ideas the larger the margin separation the fewer bits you need to code the
direction of the hyperplane in again this can also be related to ideas of learning
but i'm not going to go into detail and that's just a little points on
the side
so we going back to the
formulation of hard to do the optimal margin hyperplanes
remember here
so we have to max minimize the length of w subject to the constraint that
we separate the data correctly and we have a canonical
the right this is false
let me just to that once more
remember lot of positive points
function here has to be plus one allowed for the negative points this function has
to be minus one of smaller cities of extreme ones it was plus one minus
one but the ones further back here it has to be smaller than minus one
in the ones
a lot over here it has to be larger than plus one
so we can actually write these two constraints compactly
if we multiply them with the class labels so here the class labels plus one
so multiplying this with the class labels doesn't change anything
but if we multiply this one with the class label actually turns out to get
exactly the performance on the other side so we have a compact way of writing
these constraints
and then both constraints can be written
this is
so what we want to do is we want to
the output
is a
is a spanning tree
by spanning tree we mean x
all the vertices
k is going to have a minimum wage
OK so we can write
the weight of the tree
is going to be
by that we mean the sun
overall images that are in the tree
of the way the individual edges
here i've got a little bit of abuse of notation
OK which is that instead of writing when i should be writing his w of
the edge u v
because this is a mapping from edges
which would give me
a double parentheses
and you know as you know i love to abuse notation
some examples that extra parentheses because we understand that it's really the weight of the
OK not the way of the ordered pair
so that's just just a little
notational convenience
OK so one of the things when you start when we do that take on
examiner notational convenience can make the difference between having a horrible time writing upper problem
and in time
we're thinking about what kind of notation you used in writing up
and writing up solutions to problems and so forth
OK and just in general and technical communication
we good notation people understand you you have to poor notation
nobody pays attention to what you're doing because
they don't understand what you're saying OK
so let's do an example
OK there's
here's a graph
think for this somebody asked once if i was inspired by biochemistry or something
OK well i wasn't just writing these things down
so here's a graph must give us some edge weights
there's an edge weights
and now we want is we want to find a tree
so we're connected basically square
such that every vertex is part of the tree
it's kind the minimum weight possible
so can somebody suggested me some edges that have to be in this minimum spanning
yes and i'm good
nine has to be america's y
is the only one connecting it to this vertex
and likewise fifteen has to be in so those both have to be and what
most likely
but this means that the needs to know
to get drink
so this thing is a little bit too complicated right in so and so
he many times
again listen something this
OK you don't worry you know you're right on complicated things you know you taken
and sometimes things simply
in this case in general they didn't as far as i know i'm i struggling
to a
what you can do is going true
your was the current right is the last straw
we call this lasted minimax
so now the situation is
i so the current right the last row so only one in so left
and the kernel parameter that i'm going to pick
if the are in so
what is this
will also are
miners in
and the previous ones goldman simplifies to this so i'm left with this thing a
very simple formula for this in
so it turns out this thing
can be analyzed in many contexts
and this very simple motivation without divergences are already gets you
some of the fanciest algorithms that i
using divergences
got into four algorithms for
gulshan in linear regression
so after seeing this i have high respect for this game theoretic stuff
OK so it did the right thing for governance linear regression
let's talk about the elected
these kind of problems have been studying
you know fifty sixty years
it turns out
if you look at them in the worst case into this very simple things
you get better
so i just want to give you this kind of little examples that you might
i have seen before because
they show the subtlety of this analysis
the forward algorithm is kind of just adjusting the counts and one of them is
coming up
there two versions
you put in the second last would be the one adding the one count here
s is the total number of this we end only case so we have a
conflict so this is the total number of
one is heads
total number ones and then you have half
he might buy
number of letters plus one
this is sort of the best algorithm in this context it turns out
they is that if you go to the last minimax it has this form
which is seemingly completely unrelated
or at least not easily
related to anything of this type it so not related to maximum likelihood kind of
estimates in the exponential family
not obviously at least
the worst-case regret bounds also law people one placebo now the constant is slightly improved
whenever you have an application
that uses these counts well what if you try this out
and see whether it's slightly better
so this was
the fancy of this last step minimax
and in some cases
you can even analyse this
is that we're going to the following test time
we're gonna take the hidden units we've learned
and the training time we dropped them out with a probability a half
the test time we just half their outgoing weights
so the expected value coming out one vision that stays the same training and test time
hand if we do that at and we have a softmax the output we are
exactly taking the geometric mean of all to to the edge models
just dropped out the math
but means that
making the model is just a factor of two big test time
we can get the exact geometric mean all these models
and that's that's basically what we couldn't do with neural nets before we couldn't train
also different models and then has an efficient and test time
if we have more hidden layers
we just you drop out and a point five in every level works better on the whole
ant with more hidden layers if youhave you going way to reach in unit test time
you're no longer taking the exact geometric mean what you've got
but it's sort of like mean field you getting approximately that's actually works just fine
this shows my deep respect for mathematics
if you have an input there
you can do the same in the input layer typically it's best not to drop
by half a drop less than half of them
and that's already been discovered was
done in yorkshire benches lab by
yes sure and she got pascal vincent
got a french pascoe vessel
ants i think some other people
they discover four autoencoders it's a very good idea to drop somebody inputs
and we just doing the same thing but for the hidden layers as well
now all if you're familiar with dropout
is very well known that it works in one special case
suppose i'm doing
logistic regression
and i have a large number of inputs suppose i have say a billion
i wanted to google over the summer
have a billion inputs
and i only have say a billion training examples
what we could do is we could drop out all but one input
and then fit a logistic regression model
and then test time
this isn't quite the same structure a similar a test time what i could do
is just divide outputs all these units by end if end a number of units
if i forget to do the division by that's called naive bayes if i do
the division by and get the same maximum here two possible answers
so naive bayes is just a version dropout was very similar to drop out
and it's well known that it works if you've got if you're liable to overfit
it works better than logistic regression
so averaging all these models together which is what many basis during
is a good idea
so the question is how well does this drug work if you try some big neural nets
obviously for a neural net is not overfitting
you don't need a regularize like this
but if you and your nets not overfitting that means you're not using a big enough neural net
this people who say you know you also data so now we don't need to worry about overfitting
they just don't understand how the brain works
in the brain you have many many more parameters and have training cases
you have about ten the nine training cases
fortunately for me it's about two times ten to the nine
you've have about ten to the fourteenth parameters
and that's because synapses are a whole lot cheaper than experiences
and so you want have lots of synapses per experience and i'm gonna get overfitting problem
let's look at one experiment done by matisse stressed over
and he did lots of experiments and drop but this is one of them
he took timit
he took a chaldean implementation done by
and with them over software
anti trained a standard acoustic model
i'm sort of deep nets acoustic model and it gets twenty two point seven percent error
on this particular version of timid
when you find in the normal way which is just by using a small learning
rate and backprop if you fine-tune it using
um dropout
then you get started with again of small learning rate but use dropout stand nineteen
we said so that's a ten percent improvement
or something like that's a small subset okay to really get like ten percent improvement this
at the time
but with the record for sort a speaker-independent emit
people have since cut down to eighteen point seven percent
and actually someone in my lab got down to seventeen point seven percent
if you look at what happens during the fine tuning
this is the standard thing you do with neural nets before
you would
do some pre-training then you start fine tuning and i showing you hear these frame
classification right not the owner which what's different numbers
and you see the classic early stopping curve
comes down and then it fits
this is just various different size models
if you don't use regularizer
u overfit
anne so you should do early stopping and get this
a minimum here
but the point is if you drop it just keeps going down
and actually for the same length of time it gets to about the same place
so it's not actually slower than early stopping
it's a but it just keeps coming back and it doesn't go up eventually slightly
in the end is a bit like boosting which for a long time people didn't
get what it does get worse in the end but much
the very gently compared with this
so there was one very nice example
there's another example you've heard already but i can't resist mentioning it when you got
a good result you just have to keep saying it
there with this competition on recognizing objects in images
whether the classification task is to