i have a
you will be
although he
one of
on the long run
in proc
it is
this the result
which a
all which is
so far from home
he or even more
and this is the
we're going to do
i mean
are you
and all of
o o o
well the
with the mass
this is just
these are
according to
one of the
belong to a class three or
of the problem with
so we
there are some also
let's rewind
so the first question
first question is do
we do six six five o five
so four
this is three kilometres one the possible outcomes
and this
so that's the random variable with alphabet three
possible values
and let's shorey
that's right down the probabilities are
of those three outcomes the different things you can do a few a six against
six what's the probability that does that zero
by symmetry the other properties must be high
high if you a four against before leaving for
balls on the table
what's the probability that does that
it's got to be one of the four you left on the table has four
of them is the third right the probability that balances
is the third by symmetry is a third of the
this and this
what's the probability let's right this another way we could write this as
six twelve six twelve
this is
four twelve
so we define against five live two
on the table
what's the probability that balances
as the number we live on the table over twelve fairly obviously six over twelve
ten twelve and then the remaining staff divided into five
three o twelve three
two thousand two
one hundred twelve
the twelve OK we need a little leonardo only we need to know
how do you maximise the favour probability distribution
so have attached your neighbour if you've got to pay diffusion and so as to
maximize entropy change your name
one over i
for all i
and you are not agree with uniform and on agree with for a brilliant so
which of these has maximum entropy
this one
four against so shannon tells us way for against don't bother looking at other bits
this is the way to get max information so we chose to wait for the
for john get
and now we
struggle possibly with the next step
so let's look at these let's work out
what's the probability of
and this
OK so suggestion number one was
during her home on k
so how do we
think about this let's think about the
probability of a balancing first it will balance
if one of these actually about
and the three candidates
and the total number of candidates that could be that is a moment so must
be a three
a chance of
what's the probability of
of that could happen
this is the bad guy and is having
if this is the bad guy and his life could happen in any way
it's and then let's just checked that adds up
how could this happen what happen this or this or this is the bad guy
and that's all that's three a and that sums to one of is a good
way to check yourself
that's impossible strategy
let's see that anyone yes this is a good let's look at three
what's the probability
this will balance if you go strategy three as your second
for over a
what's the probability that all the
four right
what's is the probability that will do the other things
what's the entropy
of the distribution can you do it in your head
one bit
OK so we this
is one that
we actually don't care exactly what NPOV just maximizing
how does the entropy of two three three
compare if you want to share a piece of cake between three children is it
fair to given for four there are three three two
i think you get the three three two yes so this is not entirely
people often get the second stage of this wrong they do four against for first
and then the second step
they screwed up
and they don't get
three three two
is very common that this is an extreme case will be quite often people do
four two two
that's a fairly common thing for example let's imagine the first outcome was a balance
so balance as long
and so we know it's one of these four on the table but we don't
know which one
about carla
we call that she she was an undergraduate students
o for the nice
we see something very similar so these also student but in student and you have
not seen and you have different advisor namely e
for these
two ladies are related to you in our in our
ables already
and for the supervisor of color we have also something already stated in our
you know a book namely
eve is an assistant professor
OK so to make this
i think he also look what we know about fiona we now know already that
she has supervisor of nice but we also know about feeling that is a full
OK when you want to compute the LSE
what is to be what is taken into account is
also the concept definitions that we might already have on the tee box
so if you look now at the taxonomy and the concepts that we have to
find them
then we can look at
the graduate student for instance we know that ten is a graduate student and
take a look at how this concept is defined so what we see here is
a lot of information so the credit student has told primitive divisional head
definition from the user that
it is
the kind of person
this is something that
it takes the course and that is a graduate course
and also get some other information about synonyms and parents and children which gives us
information about the taxonomy but this doesn't interest us from now
OK so what's
the expected to seek to be taken into account and then have to look quickly
who was the r v evans assistant professors so we can also see
what we know and that he was only about assistant professors
we can describe this concept and say
see that
look at the description of concept and see that this is an professor is actually
kind of professors and
it's actually collapsing with our coinciding with the content
for now
if you are interested in
and seeing what
happens if we generalize this these individuals so we know the is linked if you
know which who is kind of professor then we can simply is beautiful but in
here which computes all which invokes the evening service and generalizes now this kind of
individuals into concept description
so we do this now
and we obtain
carl is the kind of undergraduate OK this is something we have
directly attached to to come forward speak and and then comes something that boils down
from the definition of undergraduatestudent namely that you the person
and there's something
today the because which is the cause
but there's also more that is being discovered by
by sonic by has been found out by the system
namely that you have some some kind of advice OK we said that's the feeling
as her advisor but
also the things that we know about fionnuala coming into play and you see that
if you know the full professors and
see also things that were used in the definition of full professor
and this is an also contributing to the most specific concept that you find out
about color
often not have done that
OK so here on outcomes
OK now comes the window where we can actually edit the concept description but for
now we
we take its own
when i would take it as it is
so we say maybe
with the concept that we cut out of college
and this is our carla concept
you should also
at the correct namespace is really useful
again the
and our data
you can click OK
and looking at in our
well this concept shows up and we see in fact
we have now
find the kind of undergraduate students
of you
we have found another kind of undergraduate student which is
the color concept that we have a right derived from the individual
OK i quickly just do this also with the other individuals
so for the nice
the also say want to see the MSE
even if it's
having the message
and if you recall the needs of infected graduate students q OK
and here we see also literary adviser is the kind of assistant professors are not
full professor in the other case
and you can see
we can then this
against the correct namespace
constant OK and we added
to knowledge base is standard step into this also for the other guys
and the see OK find out about you basically what is captured in the definition
of assistant professor associate professor
this number of issues
then faculty and person and she works what kind of organisation
which in this case most likely is the university
unions also quickly
the eve concepts
we do this for the fourth one
and here we see OK we find again what what has been
supplied by the definition so for these
if you look now again detects enemy
we we see that
actually these quantities
refining our gradient student and the colour concept is refining undergraduatestudent
but see
that he
really surprisingly the concept of assistant professor coincides with the if concept since we didn't
know anything more about it
but the chief in system professor cilliers was again attacked by the c
this was is easy
that we were trying to optimize i can actually write an upper bound on the
scene now
which is now linear
in terms of the
observations here over all possible lives now this is great i can perform just simple
dynamic programming programming pass in n compute the optimal weight updates for or can't compute
dizzy value for all part or all features
OK and because i'm trying to minimize this now
with one part one dynamic pro programming has i can actually find ways which of
feature selection include it the situation into my own somewhat
and when i have the value when i have that feature
finding the optimal weight update is just an analytic computation
now one problem with this is that it's in sequences these upper and lower bounds
are can can vary from negative that the negative of the length of this sequence
to positive of the length of the sequence so this can be say minus forty
to forty and this this found is going to be almost useless very it's going
to be extremely
one alternative is instead of this
this nearby we can have a piecewise linear bound that is defined in terms of
each sentence now so if we have various sentence sequences of varying lengths then we
might we might actually have much tighter bounds
so what we can define a piecewise linear bounds now the problem is we don't
have an analytic solution in terms of the
optimal weight updates by the this is just one dimensional optimisation problem and it's
really fast college in a couple of iterations you can in a solution
and a
a better approach is what we have selected which feature we're gonna use we can
actually go back to the order of
the optimisation problem the original z
and finally the optimal way of a new
on that the function OK so we can we can perform an exact optimisation maybe
the that we've selected is not optimal one but we can we can at least
for the feature we have selected we can at least take an exact of
updates that
OK it's it's it's too real
general is that it is very trivial to show that the structured adaboost approach maximizes
the number of training instances with large margin as the standard adaboost has been doing
if there is a possible positive margin achievable
and we can also show that the generalisation bounds
the generalisation error can be bounded in terms of the the number of training instances
with some margin plus a term that grows linearly with the length of the
the with the size of her structure
all right i'm going to going to
some experiments but one one
method that i'm gonna compare
the second the structured boosting
it is
is this approach here so here we are considering a sequence matter and i will
be presenting experiments in sequences in this work will be
and we should bear in city centre had proposed training new boosting
so in sequences we can actually use
we can actually ignore
any sequence information rate and train train a classifier for each position in in your
so this will be knowing any any sequence information it in more advanced approach we
might consider OK
during training
you know what the correct neighbouring of what the correct neighboring label is so i
can use that is given to me and then changed my stance classifier
stable state and then during testing now i don't know the correct label but i
can do if itterby like optimisation
right and this is the method proposed here and in their experiments they actually show
that this approach performs worse than an independent classification approach so if i were to
completely ignore the sequence information i would have gotten the better
better results the reason here is that
during training and using some information is not going to be available to me during
testing exactly
i'm using some some
information that i'm going to be predicting so it's going to include some nice and
this line is actually ignored during training
right so this this group discrepancy results in a worse performance than
well considering any dependency information
and one
one of previous work than than the one that i just presented its causes approach
where he uses an external classifier
so to select some best labels
in this case he works on passing so he uses an external passing to select
and best parts list and then changes standard boosting algorithm
now this approach has the advantage that dizzy now can be computed exactly because it's
just cook it's just accounting
meta rate because the sum is over a small subset
the sum over c
over the labels
in disease now or in limited set
so it is going to be more efficient but the disadvantage of this approach is
that it's going to need an external classifier so he uses his already very good
of p is a PCFG parse
you know in general we want have such an that we want having access to
such a classifier
so let's see the experiment some pitch accent prediction
so i'm saying independent of boosting classifiers
and i get seventy one percent class error
o accuracy if i if i change
of the metadata just described in hackney at all paper is you see a a
lose some accuracy in the worst and then
you know just ignoring the dependency information now i look at the CRF model
and it does pretty well OK
computing the
eg exponential loss exactly using some of the shelf gradient matter it does pretty well
and so the structured boosting also does
equally well the advantage of the boosting is obviously that is going to have a
sparse representation and if you look at it on
ten percent of the features are selected now this is going to be important for
four tasks were
the the prediction time is is really crucial
so this will be an event stages
method for for such problem
for such a task
all right i'm going to show
it's the
it's a logical sort of importance
OK now the basic postulates and usually we have another two supplementary PUS let one
sort of explain now but essentially what they
are just generalizations of some of the only apostles for
OK now in particular good in the following
i want to give up the sentence inside
it's sufficient for me to give up one of the two
so if i want to give up the conjunction phi and psi will adjusting them
to give up five or any to give up so
on the other hand if i want to give up the disjunction five also going
to give up both file size because if i leave one of them around will
phi implies file size and sign players file size so i can leave either them
around going to give up
just keep that in mind because people get find side give give up but now
it's not
that literally
you want to give up the conjunction you gotta give up one of the other
the disjunction have to give up
OK i'll leave this here for you to look at some consequences of those properties
and escape to because otherwise like
OK so
and then we got a set of properties and they seem to look reasonably intuitive
i hope
and i have tried to sort of vaguely argue that they also satisfy those rationality
now i want to do is we want to see
how can we obtain the function
that actually satisfies those properties was laid down on the properties of the function should
NASA the states we're not interested in just figuring out one function like we have
for expansion
we're really just interested in sort delineating all circumscribing the class of possible functions that
satisfy this property may not be one
OK so
how we can construct such a function we can store all the possible mappings
the first idea is just to look at the beliefs
and try and look at a set which is
as similar as possible to the original beliefs
but doesn't imply the formula that trying to give up
can we can formally with this
the notion of remain the same
also go through a very briefly but the idea is that we do we define
the set k primes in a sense what k prime is is so small it's
sort of the largest subset of k
it doesn't imply the former trying to contract
so if we're trying to contract by phi
it's the largest subset of k doesn't imply five
and you can formally defined in the following way it's OK prime must be a
subset of k
five can be in k prime and furthermore
properties equivalent to sort of saying that there is no
set which is larger than k primes
and smaller than k which also satisfies the first two properties
of course
from the examples that we've seen already it's fairly obvious that more than one candidate
so there are several of these candidates
the largest
subsets of k don't qualify
we grew all the possible subsets into this cave bottom five
which is the set of all blacks nineteen playing subset so these are all the
subsets are as large as possible
yet smaller than came down platform
now also what we do is we've got this notion of selection function that can
select elements of k bottom five depending on
the city which were
if if
this selection function selects one of these maximum implying something called an opinionated substances
sorry opinionated selection function you see why
i the first ideas this notion of what's called maxi choice contraction and essentially what
makes features contraction does it just takes
one of these maximal implying some this is the one you're is where you get
and that
is that because it answer reasonable
OK go to figure out which ones OK we're going to delay the choice which
is going to prove which is going to choose one of these maximum points some
we have that
what sort of reasonable right because we giving up as little as possible
six away five so it does make some sense
and sure enough
if we got function we defined in this way it satisfies properties
but we have a problem here
the problem is the following one
OK it's going to take quick digression if we
want to look at
if you want to try to find the revision function
one revised k by fire rather than just
contracting by five
then one way to do that is to apply what is often called believe identity
and the basic idea is to take your sensibilities
and remove any impediment to you believing finally any impediments to you believing final five
because if you retain not five accountability not find you retain
then you can end up in an inconsistent beliefs
so what you do is you may not find
once you may not find well you can happily just fine
OK so one way of defining the revision
it's just by saying look
take away not five
and then i can easily just that financial will be consistent
while remember this is that the closer there's going be no way in which this
is going to run
close contradiction which are not for
OK now if you
if the minus the use here is maxi choice
then we end up with the following problem that one week one we define revision
operator in this way
and if i take any finer revised k by five
if i look at any other sentence in my language
i'm going to end up with the revision in which i believe that sentence or
i believe its negation
which so i'm sort of at the end of his favourite think this sentence being
light source so
for any sentence i'm going to end up with this possibility either
site is an element of k stuff
it's an element of
OK so that
that look problematic
so look back
you see why this might be a problem
well it might be a problem because initially i might not have had any opinion
size any former remember
i might not have had any opinion about with this i was true not suddenly
i have an opinion
not only is to whether size true because as service this happens to be the
case for also suddenly i have an opinion as to the truth or falsity of
every sentence in language
certainly believe that it's either true or false
so from perhaps you know not knowing very much suddenly belief that everything that's why
this selection function is called opinionated because
from having maybe a few opinions now you have an opinion on every
i think it depends on the prior to
second have a uniform prior
so you think the answer depends on the prior
i mean you're right
i mean this paradox there i mean it's there
look like fun but i mean if you if you
can you know so this simple problem from in
how could you
single for the more complex problems i mean people i mean to do something and
sometimes it works i mean that
it's also an approach but you know maybe you really want to principle way
and let maybe you have some proof that works
OK so
let's come now to the bayes mixture distribution
with the smallest evidence or the marginal
and so on
assume now you take a sample from the distribution and this vision is called move
my talk
but this distribution is not known because it's known everything
OK so the bayesian approaches that more less you're place
whatever you do
is true unknown distribution by a bayes mixture distribution
so what you do is you
take some set of distributions for several months
i confine myself to countably
a to countable to countable sets
and you also assume that your true distribution in this in this class
so that means the class should not be too small
so what you do is here
it's just a new notation written so new of x that is the probability of
on the hypothesis h nu
times the prior
w nu is the prior probability of new edge into some of all hypotheses and
then you get the evidence
it's an economy based mixture distribution
and the prior of course is the sum to one another also assume is that
the prior probabilities never zero
because you know i mean if it's theory can drop it out of the set
the prior can be interpreted as the prior degree of belief that the true environment
is nu
i will come to the very briefly later
if you take the logarithm of i mean you know
if i have a probability distribution anything
minus the lock
then there is always a code of your data which has this code length so
you can regard log probabilities called length and code length code are related to complexity
so we can regard the log of the prior as a complexity penalty
dixie itself is based makes this sort of the
belief probability in observing x integrated out
just a little bit notation here at this point
OK so now let's it's proof something
so again we have a sequence x one up to and for convenience property minus
one and they want to predict t
and the expectation of functions defined as usual
well that he was just some move x for example or
so if f is a function which only depends on the first
time instances
the kullback leibler divergence
the most common
distance between probability distributions so you have the true distribution here
it is based makes the distribution fee
and you take new lock
mu divided by c
some all arguments
which is the same as taking expectation of l and divided by x
the second level divergence between a and c
in this case you can easily show
it is bounded by loch of the weight to the minus one
the proof is very easy
what you do is
so we have
c o x is equal to some w nu nu x all new and
since we we assume the true environment in the class
i can drop to some keep just one
i commend
w nu
w nu nu that are sorry blue one
and then i divide vaccines or have mu of x divided by
the x
it is bounded by this bring to the other side that minus one
i take the logarithm
and i'm in the right hand side is independent it's text expectations bounded operators
so this is bound so is very easy
what we really care about is we want to use now
so ideally we would no movie was use it for prediction so we have our
past data x one to t minus one and you want to predict the probability
of sixteen of a given history
you can't do that
because we don't know movies use the bayes mixture
but prediction so we take the conditional
and now we have to go copy
what we really would like to do to what we can do
and you can find several distance measure
for instance i choose here the hellinger distance the most convenient mathematically so the difference
we have
the some overall outcomes and the hellinger means that experience here
the point is that
its parents
just for technical reasons
what you then can show is
so that's HT omega t minus one is the
the difference between the predictive distributions of music see at time t
now take expectation over history
and some all type instances from one to infinity
and what you can show is
in one page so
that is that there is a clear is that that that that holds
nominate I don't want to lose it so this was a case where a mixed
strategy was right
so that the
for both of them
let's go back to that what what was an easy case of the story
and and and just think it through again so again are C and that we
that I have something like say 1 2 4 7
and then what were the best strategies
for this game
that this was the easy game remind me what what should are in this game
2 wrote to all the time so fraction should be 0 and 1
and what should see do all the time
which runs from 1 so fraction should be 1 0 so this is why 1
should be 1 and X 2 should be 1 so there is a case in
because we were bumping up against the limits the 0 1 limits we didn't
we can find a mixed strategy this was this was the this is like the
key with this inequality constraints either you're kind of in the middle
is we're in the middle and you could go either way a little more and
column to a little more on column ones
when you there it's like being in the middle of functions
saying like this
like like minimizing when you're in the middle
you going way and the derivative has to be 0
but if we were maximizing the function what over this interval what would be the
the maximum would would be an
and the derivative isn't 0 there it's like
you have an inequalities that can only be a winner
for the for the guy who's
the derivative is positive because then you would wanna come
you wouldn't wanna come again which is what we only direction you would be allowed
to move that this is
this method is so we're talking about maximum minimum optimisation with constraints that that if
the constraints are active if you're at the edge of of the constraint is an
inequality constraint because there's only 1 way
where if you're at the center
the constraint is an equality constraints and derivative has to be 0 could you could
go both ways
so this was a case where you can go both ways
so equalities had all we had the equations like this would made a week we
made it so that C had no reason to prefer 1 over the other because
it could both ways here
well we're facing see whether choices
that that losing for all the time
that started we're at the edge of the of of the of the would like
chooses even less
but it or even sort is well anyway where we're 1 0 situation for both
of them in fact so that it is imminent saying that that are is not
presenting see the equal choice if they forest keeps choosing this this
sees choices to lose for 7
so we always pixel using for
that there was a case there were rumors that there was a equality of 4
was less than 7 therefore they're all the marbles went on column 1 this was
a case where in either direction it didn't matter and we ended up with mixed
maybe that's the
the theme of
of the uh optimization with inequality constraints
and may be I express that now
it in a in a language that's not game theory but but a typical problems
of minimizing some cost function
subject to some
In the equality constraints so now I'm really these last minutes
speaking about optimisation as we really know
when minimizing something that's optimisation
there are constraints they can be non-linear that can be nonlinear
and this
and they can be an equal
or equations so that there is like a general optimisation problems
and how would you handle such a problem
that's not an easy problem
because you don't know
if you know if the if if you
so the best X and looking for the best text
X star the winning where
any number of dimensions and we have any number of inequalities then
if we know that the best X if we know where it was hitting the
boundary if we know in which components a of x star was equal the corresponding
B and which components it was last we would we would be golden
because then we would have equations you say that the unfortunate we don't know that
so so that x is
and at end different numbers so you got any numbers to choose a and B
is and different numbers forget and inequality constraints
and that the &
might my point is that if we 0
which is where the qualities were
then those would give us some equations for
and then in the end we knew the other ones were inequalities then we would
know some derivatives in those components or 0 because we would be in in those
components we would be able to go left or right and therefore a derivative with
respect to that would have to be 0 we would have a set of equations
we itself but we don't know
which constraints are active in which enough that's when it comes to
an active constraint is 1 where where where you're pushing that where equality holds right
up in my picture here there is an active constraint that the X can't go
beyond that value
at forcing us to be there and if we that once if we know that
we there
if we knew it didn't hold we can look at beyond the maybe but
kind of people are up to
so the the representer theorem is one of the central theorems in
because of the following so we are given some kernel
given a training set of point
and this derivative this quantity here and some objective function so suppose our learning consists
of minimising this objective function so the objective function here has the first part which
is some
function we assume it's strictly monotonic we'll sorry it's it's an arbitrary cost function c
which takes all input points
all outputs
x y of the all the points and also
the function value
of the function that we're estimating on those points so typically learning consists of making
sure that f of x i is equal to y i but in principle the
most cost functions were just say to compute the square difference between this thing in
this thing but we can do modern also let's say of course we can depend
on all three and you can even depend on the whole training set in some
complicated joint way so this is the most general cost function you can think of
and in addition here we have a more important part which is the regularizer
and this is known in europe producing company but space induced by kernel
if f is
an arbitrary function of all from our previous encounters space and we are allowing to
somehow transformed is known
with a strictly monotonic function omega so they could be for square you could be
squared norm
and we're saying if we optimise this thing over f
arbitrary functions from our space in this space can be big can be dense in
the set of continuous functions then it turns out that the solution can be written
like this
kernel expansion and the crucial point is that the solution will have and will only
need kernels
sitting on the training points
so this is optimisation problem in potentially infinite dimensional space and it turns out
the solution for or a solution can be cases where is not unique but a
solution which is as good as any other one can be written
as a convex function centered on the training points
so this reduces the infinite dimensional optimisation problem to the problem of just finding
coefficients here so n dimensional problems
so that's kind of surprising and i remember also in the in early days of
kernel work we we knew that this theorem exist it's increase while last book but
somehow it was very opaque and nobody clients didn't well maybe nobody bothered to go
through the whole book because somehow complicated proven at some point i just thought maybe
maybe easier to try easier than trying to understand grace as proof is just to
try to prove it yourself and it turns out is a very simple proof and
briefly show that
proof is simply probably is essentially the same same idea
just with less code take an arbitrary function from the space
decompose into part which is in the span of the training points and the path
orthogonal to it
so these are decomposition we know the the orthogonal part is in particular orthogonal to
each individual kernel sitting on the training point
now we apply
our function
to some arbitrary training point
so we're interested now in this
the first part here because here the function only sees the training points of course
the loss something that evaluated on the training points so we want to see what
are these values here
so we apply a function to an arbitrary training point substitute this function in here
get these two terms we know that the second part gives us zero so this
in fact lots of works you do you do you want to study really are
quite big whatever that turns out to me so so lot literature you'll find
networks being talked about in the limit of
number of nodes just getting bigger and bigger
so what you do that it has for the for twelve
random graphs
how does when network
as we seen expected number of edges is
it is written as k in pointy brackets is is number of times probability that
we don't want to blow up the standard to just hold the whole the
mean number of connections per node fixed and scale p
like that in which case you can you can then
increase the number of nodes but you get the end up with a kind of
of a standard finite fixed finite mean number of nodes mean of connections per node
and in in a large network
limit this
OK basically
completely specified model
just i'm going to mention this point and will come up again later but the
completely standard way of doing this for for australian network how to scale the parameters
you get to sort of reasonable
network in the large limited is not always that obvious it's not spatial networks as
see later
now we're going to go counter what is probably the the single most important statistic
associated with random
ensembles networks
or in fact single networks which is the degree distribution
the degree of node being simply the number of connections associated with that node is
perhaps most study most striking feature the most obvious feature to look at the bus
network it doesn't describe the network completely but it is
so important was it's exactly what we mean by
that is k is degree of just pick out some node random boolean network what's
its degree
and we get some random variable k
and pk is probability
that will find a node with that degree degree k
a couple of things to note about it
k is a random variable
this makes sense for single network as well as an ensemble you just
pick a random node from single network
it's ensemble
what you possibly want to do is to pick
a network of the ensemble sample network from the space that your your networks and
then pick a random node from that
but the warning here i found some very confusing the network literature which is is
often not clear whether people are talking about if you like an ensemble statistics all
statistic for single network
that's particularly vexing because sometimes
it doesn't amount to the same sex
anyway important
the most important quantities mean degree simply the expectation of that random variable the statistics
associated with the distribution
this would be the variance of the node degree as you
one day around the network
and again that one for instance
and the different things like for a single network of an ensemble and and how
average might become significant
so we go
for the degree distribution for the
was really network is binomial
and that
and in the large network limits
he comes across on distribution
and hence
hence the name basically
and if you like the cross on distribution reflects the complete independence
of choosing connections between nodes
next interesting thing is
in general connections are not independent they are not just read the model but
generally they're not going to be
for the degrees of difference nodes are not going to be independent going to be
in particular what you might want to know about network is if i have
neighboring nodes
what is the relation between the degrees of the nodes which happened to be connected
so what you might want to look at is this conditional degree distributions which says
basically if i have to given that they are connected
what what is the degree of that once a given that happens to be connected
to a node of another degree
that's the characterisation of
the to the degree distribution if you like
psychiatry division that is
given the network is connected to another
in this case a degree five what is the expected degree of node going to
be given that connects to the nodes that degree
and there's some terminology here core network is sort of
is that expectation increases with
with k dash not is for instance
the high degree nodes tend to connect to other high degree nodes or in the
case of disassortative vice versa
but also text speech and things that type
us but really what deep learning is trying to do his learn
the problem with we need to solve with deep learning is learning
representations of the world and this is all about height high-dimensional
data representation so i read how do we learn about this additions
of the world but just observing it does or does the question we need
to answer this question neuroscientists have been as the
cells so for long time how does the brain does that
do that so the visual cortex this article we on that for
are quite some time the the notion of our as in the visual cortex
are not exactly equivalent to the notion of layers in a neural
net that sort of and it's the fact that or on as feed-forward is
the is a good simplification of really the architecture that
biology uses which has organs feedback and lateral connections
and things of that type but this is sort of a sense that for
very fast perception or the visual cortex is essentially feed-forward
process because it just goes to fast for any kind of feedback really
have an impact this something we're not modeling you know in our
feed-forward recognition system which is that the cortex is really
has to to different pathways one that is used to
recognize objects independently position another one that's used
to localize objects independently where they are
so the second one helps when you're navigating in avoiding obstacles
grabbing things look at the localising things
rest the first one is just identifying
this of course talk to each other so i'm going to use prophase
some some of the things that are neurons talked about
this morning which is the fact that
a good way to kind of build a stage that ends up extracting features
is to have have to do a sequence of two operations that's
really very old idea says or not so you know something that
was recently arrived that from the deep learning side it's very
old idea for parameterizing functions
you have any vector you have first
layer that essentially is a non-linear mapping to a higher dimensional
space expended mentioned nonlinear way it's very important
this non-linear and the role of this of this stage is to as this
layers to actually essentially break apart
regions of this based on semantic is
dissimilar that need to be classified as different things
and so you break things apart and then you have another layer that
reduces the dimension that essentially we aggregates things
that are semantically similar to happen to have been working apart
by the for stage ok so bec things apart non-linearly and then
group rhythm back together and so you have this sort of
expansion or reduction which is similar to
this is the basic module lawns was or was talking about this morning
where you know it would have know are real business functions
here or gaussian or bones whatever but you can do whatever
you want ok so to build our architectures by essentially stacking
stages of this basic sequence of operation
first there is optional normalization in fact in practice
we don't have that very often then well have a linear dimension
expansion in the form of a filter bank for images for sort of
array signals in general but but figured as just matrix
then with have point-wise non-linearity
there's all kinds of arguments for why it is just fine it's as nonlinearities
point-wise this point and stiffener have
argument about this and then this feature pooling which is places
world of abrogating features over space or over kind of variabilities
of various kinds by sort of reducing dimensions so very often
in when things like commercial net but also in other types of
of networks this feature pooling fixed there's no rule
learned parameters in this all learned parameters and filters acts
as you take those stage the repeated multiple times to
stick classifier on top in fact classifier is nothing more than another
stage of those filter bank non-linearity actually so that
but i think of this as kind of a different
or as different in nature from this is just another one of those
the pooling operation is very often nowadays a max operation although
people are doing other things and the non-linearity very often
if there is one here is a max of x zero that's half rectification
this technique by in goodfellow and this collaborators in toronto
where they actually do they do away with point-wise on narrative
here and the pooling directly doesn't max over multiple feature
types and over space that seems to actually work quite well to call
that max out
so that's what a a deep norm that are sort of modern day practical
deep neural net look looks like it's a stack of linear operation
interspersed with max max is essentially you can think of max
kind of which this which is between zero and executes value or
between the different values and taking the biggest one
if it's max pooling
ok you train as with backprop that's just
application of general essentially compute some gradients
functions you have to optimize when you do this and being very highly
non-convex there are tons and tons and tons of set of points in
fact that combinatorial number of set of points
and local minima there is a picture that emerged that a lot of
us knew of non for long time intuitively but not not really have
been able to figure one which is that
you never have local minima problems with deep learning systems
whenever you try to your is get solutions that have the same kind
of performance the system as we know have combinatorially large number
of on the map but what local find is always kind of the same type
of performance they always to those different but they always the
same kind performance so you know there's two different types
among convexity there is national complexity and not going
to get deep learning systems particularly they all over sized
is not nasty sensei doesn't matter which
find but echoes also have lots of cell points whenever you have
to local many others so the point in between
or perhaps multiple because it's high dimension
and and back it's kind of landscape this extremely complicated
that none of us really begins to understand so
i hope these people in the audience you can
get interested in this question this is complicated for me
so right so let's think about a deep network with you know max with
values max what does it do so let's say has a single output
you could write it as you can take a single
path in that network and what the influence of this path from the
output ok and this class so it's actually take an input multiplied
by the first weight and then by second weight and by the third way
and you accumulate that the output and if path is active which
means if all units are in there are in their linear region
ok the value this is this this fast contribute to the to the output
and so you do the some of all path all contributions and you get
the input that relations what's going to happen is that some of the
path to be turned off because the corresponding
unit is in the flat spot or the the max which have been selected
ok so essentially think of it as a for these sort of switch path
have one
because then the
this person procedure does in the
of course
trying to win this i would like to
the first people
the probability of the data so actually there where is
and the
it is
my part the
ten which much like the way
none of these
imagine you're going to
depending on the same level
the line
that that
the pixel in the image
so you can when
and the like
because when it was one of the most high
that is this one
most like
course the white
so you can select the big because
that a
you know it's like
so we have
the whole and this is what
the amount of one
first of all
part of
will be filled with water
and the
will they
so here
so it was one of the the
that's one of the first one was what
these are flanked by the
don't like that be same
it is more
and finally we have
high image
by the one
problem we
some threshold a wall
one man the
two different ways of of life
i j
we don't allow them to do use
some walls
and here lies close to what you should do
and i will have only one child one
one hundred
the pixels which is what this one
then the
the following
this that
he was
but how draw
with believe that
in the next slide
and to use some predicates with them
you've all heard
change the
and somehow
the walls
one of them
to build on average
and the way it or they
how do the one that should be quite good at this point
they have local minima are mark more than and and that they start with one
went to
well first of all you have what ever and
and we want to obey
at some point
when a of water
every single under the waters of the lake to black one lake
so we have
this is
but at
we also
so in the end what
one way
which should
after this
what need
the result it is that we had to
and started to apply variational procedure what is
and to get my
we must always you
and we'll see you all the
because of of the
we want to
here we have the most
first of all the lakes will be like this is great
this image we
so we have
the which
so this section of the math was selling
we can
put down here
and at the the
pixels of the
the later
but also neighboring pixels like this one
and then what is great
we can put down here is the centre of the because your
and in this case of the pixels of the image
so that is what
and so on
after the first
little big lake
like great
we way so we can apply our donations procedure for the first
and we
the you
during that
two people
so it
it the distance
services so the distance between between people
the function is always
we a so
we also
so this is what
is sum of all possible solutions to the issues
you know
one used
so really gesture
so here
we want to do
we want to do with respect to the
the to
so the projection of the way
it's always the case
it is will be
we do
so this is given
she which also
we want to do something with
he was small
the reason
well you
two minutes
we see
with respect
these constraint
it is a lot
this is
the rule is
we this
we're doing this
this where it all
so i fail to see where we all
it is
so all the
i j
do you want to say
that the true something
so in sense
so why true
to you c
so so
what i want to give you
this work
we want to said
i mean it
great rooms
refused to really
in the world
through the radio
you to
it is
you do
you to do
it's zero
o two
the solution in
so a great read
so four
you've got all these
given any
allocation of the variables if i swap one of them
for another variable
how much can the value of f change
and what it this is requiring is that if i change the i've been put
it must be bounded by c
so by
so it provides band on if you like the variability of s
as you change individual elements
but it's assumed over all possible
choices so it must apply whatever the other variables are
if you change this one you can't change it by more CI so it's quite
a strong conditions and much of the advanced tab concentration inequalities are about weakening that
condition and using other estimates that indicate the range of change in the slightly weaker
OK so
the first question i guess is
you know
how does her fifteen
come from this
and perhaps there is something that you might want to just spend
two minutes commencing itself a piece of paper if you've got one
you know what what making substitution that function how do you actually get back to
what thing
OK this which was that
so one
but just to minutes small
so there's
it's just the
the average node is it's one over and some of its side critical
what you have to do is work out what CI is in the case of
how much can the average change
if you substitute
the i th component
remember the i th component has this
rangebound AIP i
so if we substitute that song
the functions you just replaced by mindset and you can actually get both inequalities holdings
so that you actually compounded from both sides but i won't go into the details
of that OK so that's where the two come from
and you can apply the same technique with climate
and put the absolute values here
and put it to here so it's just a simple union bound to get that
now the next thing i think is worth looking at briefly as well
is inverting this
if you imagine we're getting sort of used to doing this now
whenever we have these sort of bounds on probabilities of things going wrong over oversample
so notice i should emphasise again if i look at this here this actually is
a mild irritation peter the end you know this is a sample probability here's the
probability of the whole sample
doing something
being less than this well we know what we always do with that we set
it equal to delta we invert right i mean just that hands that so we
just plug it in and do it so if you plug that in equal to
delta here
do the usual thing take logs
take the minus sign over you get log one over delta
you get two ones some CI squared here
you bring over the some CI squared
and the divided by the two cigarettes one squared is some CI square over two
log one delta
and the only difference got here
that we didn't have before
is that steps long squared not up
and that's where the square root comes from the indicated in the
if you remember the
in case of errors in the
in the
dimension case so that
corresponds to the square root entering in on the right-hand side here
some CI spread over two log one delta
we also bring over there so you can then bound for the particular sample is
less than the expected value
of the function class
this sort of
the term that involves like one of the delta
and now we can that applies now with probability one minus delta so it's the
usual idea
we bound the probability of things going wrong
you know they were too far away from the mean and so with probability one
minus delta we're closer to the mean that
so this is almost always the way in which one wants to use things in
the learning context
frequently we in our case will be using
a sample in which case these will be identically distributed
typically therefore the CI will be the same and very frequently also it will be
something like c divided by n where n is the number of examples
and if we just plug that in
we can see that the whole we get then is this
when the end comes on the bottom now because the sea square was on the
notice that the we had one of n square had
the sum is from one up to and so we get n copies of c
and one of the inns therefore cancels so we end up with c squared divided
by two and
now that's
always the former again again with the square root in the rest of
in the segment a b
and that the expectation of any function f of x is what what's there
the integral of f of x on a b
divided by b minus
another distribution that you'll find all the time is the gaussian distribution
it is defined by its it's totally characterised by its mean and its variance
this square
i write this as an of
and square and it's defined by its probability density which is exponential
of mine is the square of x minus an
there's an x here that to the definitely should be there so
the density is exponential x minus and square over two sigma square
and this term here
the normalisation so that
the figure of this thing is exactly equal to one so it's a probability
the random vector that's you learn that that shows in an
countries where are
ghost victory
we use the same location as before with no being
of the means
of of of the gaussian vector x
and sigma square is the covariance matrix
i feel gaussian vectors
four gas and you just need to compute the mean and the covariance matrix
and you've defined the whole the probability of the whole of the
of the gaussians vectors
now there
the probability density is similar to the one before you you have to
here i use matrix and the matrix vector notation so x minus
and in the vector
because sigma is the covariance matrix
of size d times
and so you are you have to inverting matter to find the pdf
in in
and no once you have rendered images random vectors
you may or several unavoidable you may
think about studying both variables at the same time since and so that would be
using the joint
again if you assume that you have to go into that are independent
then you may consider
you may want to consider the
the during the vector x one x two
and wonder when
again was to the
probabilities are on this random vector
than if x one and x two are two independant condenses then you see that
the probability of a
that is being basically
the product of the two provinces of x one and x two
OK so the joint probability
is the study of the joint probability of x and y with x y and
i are
two random variable is the study of the problem is the probability of the the
two events at the same times and if you have independent
random variables then do for it is really easy because it is the product of
the two to probabilities
now when the variables are not independent
and this decomposition of the joint probability into a product is not true anymore
and that actually happens in most of the time right if y
is that the random parity viability
sorry if y is the random variable
it doesn't matter whether someone is sikora is not sick
and x is the random variable that measures whether the best on on this pathology
has been positive or negative
i write here the total numbers
for each
of the columns in rules
then you may see that the
to be positive
to be that the test is positive
this one the probability of being sick
and again
it this problem
so this is an amazing way how we RLC circuits
you can do wonderful things because you can manipulate omega because zero very easily by
chasing alan c
you can manipulate
the driving frequency
also very easily
so it is clear that
response strongly
when they are exposed to the resonance frequency we've seen that full pendulums
we've seen that first springs
we've seen it for wine glass
and we've seen is now for an RLC circuit
so these systems
at resonance
absorb a large amount of energy
unit time
out of the driver
i have here
two tuning forks
which have
extremely high q
my attempts to measure it i concluded this way larger than even a thousand
and they have exactly
the same frequency both
two hundred and fifty six hertz
this one noone this one noone was one of six and that's the way they
are designed to a high degree of accuracy
better than the fraction of one hundred
but the queues are so high
that if you were to plot
drive these tuning forks
you want to plot here
his average power
as a function of omega
then you would get something like this
the things
you have to drive it exactly at the right frequency otherwise
it will not
going to residents
well we know how to get this going into baggage that means you don't spectrum
on it picks out if we consider the lights
now i'm going to show you something remarkable
when this one generates two hundred fifty six pressure waves
this one
feels the pressure wave
and he was it
because it just at the right frequency
and so it starts to oscillate
and so when i stop this one
hear this one
that's called
let's do that first
you must understand that the sound waves go from here
two there
not much
power reaches that point
so when i stop this one
you sound but it's not
we have to be very quiet
la niemi move and i can do the same by hitting this one and this
one will start to resonate
the to noon
if the driving frequency
is off by a fraction of the first one hundred is enough
one hundred difference
because the q is so high
and this system will not be able to get this one go going
and i can make this frequency a little more than two hundred and fifty six
by pulling his weight on here
we have measured
the frequency
loaded way
it's roughly two hundred and fifty five
you somewhere here because it's so narrow
resonance absorption peak is very sharp by the way
maxwell's equations
the victory for maxwell
maxwell was not only able to predict the existence
of electromagnetic waves
but he was even able to predict
that they would move through vacuum
with that speed
what an unbelievable victory
well you come to think of it that actually non-zero
can be measured
in a standard way
it follows from coulombs law
nothing to do with stability have nothing to do with the
has nothing to do with traveling waves
actually non-zero
is about eight point eight five
times ten to the minus twelve
as i units
museo is equally static can be measured from the force which two
why is which on the current attract each other
note ability no the immunity
it's nothing to do with electromagnetic waves
it's about one point two six
times ten to the the minus sixteen s i units
and if you multiply them
substitute in this equation
you'll find that c
because two point nine nine
times ten to eight
per second
believable wallis success
it always baffles me how two quantities
so static
and seemingly so related to
moving away with you
it is indeed it is all over the place
how they
can predict
the speed of light
suppose i ask you to measure the
pressure in your priors of your car
and i would ask you to also measure the voltage of your battery
and then to predict the speed of the car it's almost something like that
this bizarre
but it works and it was a great victory and of course it justified
and finally
this one term
which is this displacement
current term
together you and i
the proof
this is indeed necessary condition
so these equations satisfied
maxwell's equations
we'll do it together i will do
fifty percent
you will do the out of fifty percent
and assigned number nine so we split this bill
fifty fifty
o making new drawing
and i will do something that i really have to do in lectures i will
give you
eight minutes of hardcore mass you hate
i'm going to make a new drawing
which is
not too different from what you have there
this is the
this is diseasex
and this is why
and it equal zero
i'm going to draw here
the electric field
like so
this is a zero
electric field
the strength
and i'm going to apply to MP's law
part the bargain
close to the integral of the delta
you see there
equals actually non-zero
times new zero
time the phi tdt
we're dealing with vacuum
so kappa is one
and the dielectric constant is one
and there is no such thing as a current i because we are an empty
space this whole term does not exist
what is law
it close to
and i need to surfaces i attach an open surface to that close loop
i'm going to choose
close look
in the plane y c
and this is going to be like
closed loop
this year
it's going to be my close loop
this length is l
and the length
what do we
this site
is land and divided by four
i have to close to integral of b delta you know i will do that
i will first go the hardest part
which is the time derivative of the electric flux
through this surface
the problem is that the electric field is not constant
the electric field is zero here
it has a maximum here and falls off in this way so i have to
do an integral
so i'm going to make a slice here
and this slice here has the right disease
and a very narrow slice
the electric field is approximately constant
right here
electric field
has this value but everywhere in that slice
it has the same value because remember the plane wave
and so
i draw your aligned
and so everywhere in that slice
electric field
has exactly
this value
and that value is given by this equation you tell me what you see is
time people zero i know that value is
that's this fellow
so now i have to calculate
electric flux
so finally
i have to take the dot product between the a and the
electric field remember fluxes the dot product it can be a little too would be
a out
because he is also what makes life easy
i have to remember that later than when i did close the integral of e
dot pl
then looking from below
i have to go clockwise because i remember the
right hand corkscrew
so i get all my mind signs of plus signs just right
so the a and b are are in the same direction so what is the
a of this little slide
that's is al times easy
so i get l
i'm thinking
one is the local electric field in this lies well that's
that equation
so i get a zero
times the cosine
of cases
miners omega t
this actual of course is gonna
so here amongst all the choices i find the closest one in the set and
that's w star
now pick any other one in the convex set
sort of compared to
and if you do that
then this relationship holds
the distance
from here to here
it's the same as the distance of this
last is now use distance and this is actually quite wrong
it's not the distance because the triangle inequality
doesn't hold should use divergence the divergence
which is just another term we had to use because this this is misleading and
the term closest is also misleading because its distance
so these are
not distances with mistress that the divergence from here to here is at least as
big as the versions from here
clustered versions from here to here that you take euclidean distance squared
and your convex set
is a line
then you would have a right angle here and you would have to normal per
factory in theorem with
the quality
you would have
euclidean distance squared between this and this is the same as euclidean distance between this
and this
thus this and this
if it is convex
set it becomes an inequality even for euclidean distance squared
so in the picture here
i sort of
the euclidean case at least pictorially because i drew circles around here
you see which is distance
and then he is sort of a right angle
if i take other divergences these curves are not going to be straight lines to
gonna be curves as well and all kinds of fancy things
the beautiful thing is that this holds in great generality
examples so my take is my convex function now have this picture in mind again
this is the picture of mind right
and i take as my convex function
euclidean distance squared over two for convenience the derivative now
it's just a linear function
and then the divergence would be
the apply this function to the first arguement minus applying the function the second function
w two w times the gradient which happens to be this
and then you can simplify this and get euclidean distance squared
i magic
good know how do you get the relative entropy this is not additive rhythms
multiplicative updates additive multiplicative OK entropy entropy now
you take this kind of
convex functions
derivative of this is the logarithm of w this is a vector so it's the
vector but you apply
the logarithm to every component that's what this means
so it's the logarithm
and if you plan this and then use the same kind of former
that we always use f of w
twenty minus f of w minus w two minus w times the gradient
you end up
where the unnormalized relative entropy
OK so these are just examples
of this general bregman divergence
their fancier ones if you
the p p m algorithms are going to be motivated by this if you take
PMQ's that sum to one you take this you're
function this is the gradient
then you're bregman divergence happens to be this
thank you
p classic using a half then this is the euclidean distance as you see here
and this algorithms associated with each of these divergence they call PM algorithm for two
it's going to be the which are half gone say
another example is the balkan trippy
you take issue link as you as you convex function to be the sum of
the logs
the derivatives are going to be minus one of the w again vectorize
and then the entropy is going to be this kind of thing
this corresponds to the relative entropy between two
gaussians when the
axes are aligned
to be the unit axis
turns out you can
all these two online algorithms and the motivation using bregman divergence recently has become
very important because we
and now sort of
beginning to understand
how you have to change the when you go from ectopic to parameters to matrix
parameters so so far i kept always vector of
comm one of us
it's also here it's the same notation
it's componentwise
thank you so
so far i talked about parameters being vectors
of weights
the m and imagine that you want to update matrices
and then there is
nice generalizations of these divergences and the corresponding at different multiplicative updates long story talk
about some of the stuff in my research talks
i just want a flash of what the corresponding divergences are
this is something something called and we got the divergence
this would be a function this would be the
let's now
these are all matrix operations in other words
this is
and the logo for matrix is you take it stick i can value decomposition apply
the law to to the diagonal
and a density matrix is the generalisation
a probability distributions in the following sense if you look at the
i do additions to the right
in nineteen ninety seven
so one
what would you like
one two
we use
this is
this is a
i was
this is
we call
but i'm not sure it's necessarily need another one
so if you think of an answer i would just come along and i will
talk about it afterwards
my story about
abacus machines
and we introduce abacus machines purely as a technical device
helpless prisoners there
trying really to show the the turing machines and recursive functions are equivalent
and we do it by means of this intermediate arts
really that's the only reason
so again
consider anyway
the possibility of trying to show that all of these forms of computability sign
it turns out the way to do that
to show that we have this machine to turing machines
for every abacus machine is an equivalent turing machine
every recursive function
is equivalent abacus machine calculates that function
and then what a little bit messier hard
it is to show the
everything it you could do the turing machine
could is a recursive function
that completes
little circle of is if you like
various different people responsible for this
this is not the way
OK go
fruit is there OK let's we're heading to
it's this is all
stuff happened afterwards
to try to figure out how it all works
look in
here is that girls original papers translate
his collected works volume one or something from oxford
you can look in there
you want to see this sort of stuff
but this this is the sort of cleaning up that occurred
in the years afterwards
well the question computability was also lives well from turing
it was
not necessarily working on the same issues
we're going to have a look at the way for
three things god
this is stuff we talked about yesterday soldiers quickly go over
you don't just studying on an arbitrary turing machine
he really starting on the first of all by cleaning up during the shape
and producing what
this was officially called the canonical form OK
so we try regulate lecturing machines so that they
do specific things in specific ways unless we can get control the arguments
because the
first really really
internal first step is to reorganize the work in any turing machine
and this is actually how talking about yesterday
things like this that
we're trying to compute binary function
and the arguments with the numbers set up in black box ones
OK just a single link between them
and when we computed value
that will just be a single block of ones and that's what we understand by
nothing in the original definition turing machine
he said that you had to do this way just this is the cleanup
we could space arguments and values and computations how we want we don't do that
it's just too hard to argue that things
what we do is decide that whenever we have a turing machine
we always start and stop at the left must the number of ones
so receiving
there must be
but is only superfluous zeros here
and this is the first one coming in from the left
that's how we started with their arguments
and the blank
another argument
generally turing machines don't to like that can be
reorganized away like
if this is just an a number of finite number
then indeed the right hand had this will also have superfluous here at some point
in time
it's funny
at the end of the talk this is where things start the end of the
be someone's
the machine the left most of block ones
was superfluous zero
not going use this technique today i'm just trying to say we clean things up
we do not have to work with an arbitrary conception
so that's the sort of stuff we do here
we also do the same thing with abacus machines
it specifies standard configuration in canonical form if you like for abacus machines
so abacus machines might be calculating
some function of
n variables x one to xn
what you do is you put
let's talk sorry put x one xn
the arguments in the first n registers
or adjacent registers
if we encounter them
is an infinite number registers just like in adjacent bunch
so now we have a picture
of some registers like this
and we put x one and here
two songs the end actors
have a flowchart to control chart that
operates on those registers
all remaining registers are empty
and the results
just death
mike to be definitive that the result in some particular nine register might be the
next register back from all these
and that this will be the result
we can do that sort of thing
just those ideas this is the
proof idea for
proving that all abacus machines that during all can be represented as turing machines
the sort of says that there i guess
the idea of the proof
it's just that we're gonna take initial configuration of an abacus machine translated to turing
and that
and then translate each of the operations into things that you would do to a
turing machine is equivalent
i'm not going to give you
all the details even really
a great amount of the detail of the bits we do
but we should look at what happens with had to register and take from a
register which i think i did a little bit about
so we know that somewhere inside this
abacus machine description
they'll be
the case where we
added to register
and we've started translation
translating this abacus machine into some
specification of turing machine just like that the exact humans instead of them being registers
they can be whole series of
blocks separated by blanks
to look sort of like cross entropy
there's always seem like magic but it follows certain
once you have the routine it's OK
and people have done this for a long time they wrote books and books of
these exponential families and
basically they were too hard to read for me
so i got rid of them and use bregman divergences which asia
what's on another famous case
instances are natural numbers this is the distribution eroded again in terms of the expectation
the natural parameters log of the
if you write it
as function of the natural parameter becomes e to the linear minus to the data
this is your convex function obviously the exponential is convex
the derivative of this function you get it is the seat of back
and now
inverse of e to the data
you get a logarithmic
so you take e to the state sequence itself munich at the other function
it's an integral that
is the convex conjugate function
these two
is simply the log of this
and this sort of looks like unnormalized cross entropy
i will make all of this sort of more
that's the moment so this is part song
only process all
let's two
a more general observation
how these two relate
OK so you whenever you have a distribution the only
a reasonable measure of divergence between the distributions relative entropy does the coding theoretic interpretation
in terms of the
this local complaints if you take the wrong code available are a little bit too
much it's this
it goes back to shannon
you can read the first couple of chapters called this book
so this is the relative entropy
and then measure the relative entropy between
two distributions from the same family characterized by g
parameter theta
one parameter theta twelve and what i'm going to get out of this
that this is a bregman divergence this is familiar bregman divergence
how do prove this
this had this e to the linear form right
and e to the linear matches with the log because if you take logs the
linear pulls down and what have you know how to do a linear
e to the linear log only to the linear that's this part
the reference tends to cancer cells
minus log either you to the same thing
becomes this piece these two terms
and i have an integral over the evidence understand the step from to here
OK i just plugged in
the e to the
linear form until clocks
so i'm here
i distribute
over this whole thing because everything is constant except x so i have
i have here
the integral only staying over the x but this is an expectation
so that is only
and while i was actually need your data
so this year
is our normal form of the
which you should recognise now
for this relative entropy it is
convex function minus the linear approximation where this is g of the time
OK now if you take
line here and plug in the definition of convex conjugate
four different function
then the
transformation you end up with a very similar looking formula
we're now
you use the convex conjugate function as the convex function
twenty minus the linear approximation and here this is a little f of
so this
is the same as this
everything comes in pairs
it's related to the in some sense convex problem all of the dual problem the
dual of the dual is the original
and you see here
that as well because
if you take the complex conjugate
conversely operation applied twice you would go back to here and then this argument would
switch once more
and go to the other domain and you would end up here
so you can kind of see
that if you apply twice to back to the original
so this is equal to this
so what i have i would have i done so far
and i'm going to go through examples again
the moment the same kind of example i defined exponential families division very simple form
this is the convex function to characterize the family to make sure that things integrate
to one
i defined another parameter the expectation parameter which is supposedly the derivative of the cumulant
we find a second convex function convex conjugate
differential case you don't need to so you have an explicit formula
and again went through a bunch of examples and then established this relationship
if you never ever comics come a exponential family if you compute relative entropy is
you get
bregman divergences
but it is not true that an arbitrary bregman divergence corresponds to an exponential family
not all intuitively what you need to assure for it to be an exponential family
is that the that
the there's some kind of probabilistic interpretation and something integrates to one
for arbitrary bregman divergences starts to start with a convex function
this form
this form of the bregman divergence convex functions linear approximation was popularized by bregman
and i actually
discovered or rediscovered this family
in a different way as an integral
it turns out
if you write down the sigmoid function and you compute these kind of integrals underneath
the sigmoid to become relative entropy is and i was
that's how i rediscovered this in more general terms
if you have a little g function
and integrate from
theta twiddle
see table is theta here
integral on the nice happens to be the bregman divergence
this is the kind of the matching loss type
motivation that i talked about already
before but bregman divergences
and even convicts conjugacy in all of these things
i this version there's very intuitive version of