we have all of the
we have to add in
but all the lists together add up to just water and
all these add up to order m squared plus
they and
so this is how much
by at all this together what is this asymptotically
as n log n
OK so the team is actually bounded by in n
so we're lucky
those people guess lucky right
o one ten to nine ten split
is asymptotically as good as a fifty fifty split
in fact we can lower bound s
by just looking at these things here
and discover that
in fact
teevan is lower bounded by
log base ten n
plus water and
so tmn is lower bounded by also
asymptotically in logan city of and is actually data of n log n
this is not really approved this is i generally recommend you don't do this kind
of thing for
to to do approve this is a good intuition recursion trees the way proved this
is one
substitution method good
OK so what you do is use this
to get your gas
then use substitution method to prove
your guess is right
because too easy to make mistakes with this method
OK very easy to make mistakes or substitution method
OK it's hard to make mistakes
because there's just algebra there are cranking through
so it's easier to verify rather than dot dot dot trees that drew improperly and
road in wrong amounts and so forth OK
so this is an organ so that's pretty good
so it's or log and we're lucky
so now let's try another one
suppose is offering tuition
because i tell you by the time we get to the end of this class
you folks are going to be all things to the door
OK because you going to some good map today actually it's actually fun math i
think but
it is challenging
so it's not away
can still sleep now
tell you want to wake up
one more bit of intuition suppose that we alternate steps
suppose we do that
the partitioning thing and we it happens
where we start out lucky
and then we do
have this partition step that's unlucky
now we have step that's lucky
this step is unlucky
we do that all the way down the tree
OK so i suppose
we also
so we lucky or unlucky if we do that
OK so everybody voting doesn't matter what your answers
OK everybody has stake in the game razorlight like course racing every watch racing is
really boring
you probably money down
OK will stay in the game
OK suddenly is interesting
OK so the same thing here in case i want everybody
every some skin in the game who thinks this is going to be lucky
well who thinks you can be unlucky
well OK
who didn't vote
you guys
no skin in the game
OK so let's analyse this
so we can once again writer recurrence
unlike step will have l of and b the running time on the left step
size and that's going to be twice while the next step is going to be
unblocked those two unlike things over two
i was wondering and
that's all i can
the key step
we already have that is essentially going to l of n minus one can be
lucky in the next step were
but unlike
cpl i've described this behaviour with with a system now of occurrences
OK that are dependent where the boundary cases once again which are unstated is that
the recurrences of constant solution
OK with constant input
now we just do a little bit of algebra using substitution l of n
is then equal to well
i can just plug in
or you have an over to plug in
the value of you of an over two
and that gives me a
l and over two minus one
plus they are
first the
so see how people see what i did here
very simple plugin
three you have an over two i plugged in this
recurrence in fact technically i guess i should say here's data over to just make
make this substitution more straight for the same thing
just to make it
not to skip this step
skipper step
so that we can now crank through and that's too
l n over two minus one
and now i have to say to
two years plus another one
so all that is just water and
what's the solution that current
n log n
and log n
they receive
they then again so
basically just once again master theorem
and education for management
we never thought
for one parliament
how we actually educated professionals in our country
we never thought
just putting doctors into classrooms
for two years we shouldn't have some real patients
we never thought of putting architects
two clusters
for two years without actually
so you know what buildings
you know how you constructed building and how you could calculate stress things and so
on and so on all professional and individual countries but in our country all are
little of formed as the french were but it
by mixture of classroom education supplemented
supplemented by two to experience
in the real world
on the don't think doing the same
the managers
why we so blind as to think that you could translate things and transport things
from one culture
to another even though we both supposedly spoke the same language
but that's not true course speaker very different languages with
so indeed the math you've been hearing this morning
i don't believe that what we do in the UK
o if did
in america is the right thing for you in fact i don't think it's even
write for us
we actually also sort
because of our experience in american schools and tradition and so on
but actually management
could be
a sort of science
the mixture of
you know formulae
and matrices are numbers and things like that
it could be written down
and translated and transmitted
two other people and that would then equip them to go forth into the world
and manage other people i don't think that's true for
this the process can be reduced to the
as i say in due course but that doesn't turn you into a manager
i also think that
we've got seduced by our clients
we get them what they wanted
we became translators
much more than we were inquisitors
what we did was we went around we saw what
what indeed the leading businesses were doing and we codified that in some way
and then we passed it on
so in a sense we were always out of date
he was talking what people did by the time he codified it was another year
so we were always passing on what we thought was the fastest
never query
we never said why
if you do this
you know
we've seen
i would just killing of the CEO of enron went to the harvard business school
with all the lights went out
the professors clambered around him
desperately anxious right yet another case study about this wonderful company
nobody query that business plan
nobody the questions
i became ashamed at the london business school actually we never questioned any of the
practices of businesses that we were just slavishly wandering into copying the stories writing the
case studies party the models except was
was that our job
was that hard job
just accept what the world was offering
codified and pass it on
i think we were we were very wrong very mistake was seduced by times
we were business
we get the clients what they wanted rather than what they should have had it
wasn't education and really any real sense of the word
well i have to say
that after ten years
i left
a disappointed man
i run the programs
first loan program full-time executive program for nine months that was situated created in in
around the MBA program the for cup three years or so
and after disappointed man
i realize that actually
i been training consultants
i've been teaching young people
how analyse business problems
analyse companies
they went forth and they were brilliant consultants some of them became bankers one or
two and became corporate planners corporate strategists
very few of them actually managed people
it didn't out to that they had no experience with that
they just analyse things
that is not what i came in to change the face of british management for
to read a whole host of consultants they were very grateful and a lot of
received the times that he
you can set up this recursion
between the
the thought that it turns
so the thought internet ten times that he
is nothing but the man turned
received at time
glasgow times
the that occurred in time step t plus y so that simple that follows from
the definition of SLT t
and once you realise that the next thing that you could realizes that
the value function of the value function would be perfect
you could even improve these estimates by replacing st plus y
by the value of state
at the next time step actually plus one
so the value function with perfect that would be even better
the a function might not be perfect but it might be a good good enough
estimates so why not trying to use
that value
and the computation
so that's the idea so
the simplest temporal difference target misty zero
and it is that this is enough using as of penalising this incremental computation if
you this as
solve the problem
you're using this this is called the bootstrapping idea
so use your estimated values is that the true value because you don't have the
true values so you cannot use them
sample trust them using those values
in europe dates
so this might be unsound or some
but one thing is is that she so mimics value iteration so this is like
an incremental version of value iteration
so in value iteration you would really
just update
according to the expected value of the bootstrapping
so this value iteration this is just another way of writing by creation so you
do this in command of a iteration saying
so again dynamic programming is is strongly influencing the ideas here
and luckily what you can prove
is that
if you
use these are in a finite MDP are following a policy pi
and europe visiting pretty much every state
infinitely often and the learning rate of state something fairly by the way
from this it follows that you're visiting states in fact of
so you're learning which should be set to zero if not visiting state
and the
the sum of the squares of the learning rate is finite so these are called
the robbins monro conditions learning rates maybe you want to remember that it's used a
lot in this literature
so if you have these two conditions matter
then the sequence of a function is generated by this very simple target and he
it's called matching to define a function of p with probability one
so why is this manifold called TV medical devices called temporal difference method
because when
so the idea is that you have these areas
so that the the
an estimate
maybe you noise one of the true value and your current estimate you compute the
errors in your edits are based on that so you are trying to reduce that
so that's the idea of all these arguments
then you are plugging in as the prime minister the SPD
what you get years
glasgow times the
that x t plus one
minus the text
so that the BBC had actually use in europe
so i just planet
as the prime
and this is called the temporal difference
why because it computes an adder between successive time steps
here this is the value for
time step t and this is the value for times t plus one
so the the temporal difference
so the
you can prove this
conventions in various places i'm not going to go into the this because i have
much time if you're interested country
the question is efficient use one to color TV
so the advantage of TV is that it can be fully incremental
you can learn before knowing the final outcome before reaching the goal state so that
seems like a pretty good advantage if you
if you're problem doesn't happen goes this you don't really have a chance
other than that it uses less memory LSP computational and maybe these are not that
much interesting and this times
then computational power is just
trying like
chris rate
so the advantage of monte carlo is that well
this are given
might not work at all
if there is some sort of a violation of the more common assumption so
you call something as they but it's not really state
then these are my screw
and it could be a problem
and we'll see how that might have
but you want to decide about which are going to use that and what you
want to compare to the rate of convergence
and it turns out that well if you if you are in the situation where
you can tripl saga and so it's not because of candy the rate of convergence
is decided by the variance of the totality turned
so the various other proprietary small
the monte carlo could be better than the TV the variance of the totality turn
is large
then she the TD methods could be better than monte carlo
so one is the variance of
i thought that it turns small so there's an expression
so one example that we use a lot previously is that all the rewards as
a little
with me
when you reach the goal state
so that was one example
that was the port of this contd
on the return
it's bonded to be
two lie between zero and one right so
you don't have that many terms because
although the term suggests that you're summing up
so you have a single line multiplied by government to some power
so the very first of these is not going to be really high
so monte carlo could be a much better choice if you have such as war
on the other hand if there is more to advance
like at every time step you just receiving somebody war
could be positive or negative or whatever
then the TD at or could be much better because in that case the variance
the region could be much higher
so that's something to keep in mind if you want to choose between the two
in this situation of not having too many data treatment might be more appropriate and
he said before full bayesian treatment we need prior probability
the parameters under consideration in this case it is probably the prior probability of the
vector g given some hyperparameters i star
and the clinic that distribution to multinomial distribution is a discrete distribution
and it's like this give the distribution given
the set of parameters specifying usually distribution again is the normalisation term perhaps the product
of g to the k to the part of pakistan minus one
interestingly here the
likelihood function and
prior distribution very similar form
and we can think of this as being something like
trivalent collins
cool to our prior knowledge before we see any data
so this is now a function of
gene we have to specify here probability for
every combination of
settings of realizations of of tk and some of them will be more likely someone
some of them not being very likely and i've come to an intuitive
explanation of the formula in the moment first of all this is a number which
is non negative
but it doesn't have to integrate sum to one
so it's not normalized but sometimes it makes sense to normalize this quantity so we
calculate first the sum over all the first star case and then divide the first
i mean i first OK but by this time i not observe something which
now sums to one
so if we do this we can write this expression over here in the form
women now explicitly of the product of i've not for k
and this makes sense for many reasons one is that if we calculate the
the probability of observing a certain result in the task in the private sector i
first time we have to solve this into and we obtain the normalized quantity of
so if you do this normalisation by dividing by ivan not
we obtain the expected values
of what we would observe before we have seen in the data we just have
the i
stop parameter given and we do it we do it us then we would observe
these quantities
in terms of the probability
so so in
in some sense the i k indicate the distribution you expecting
and i have not put weight on the expectation so if have not very large
we have a strong about believe that these are the correct abilities not just a
small then we are not a certain about these probabilities and the problem is we
are certain about this other cases numbers normalized
we can also calculate the posterior distribution by sort of
applying this formula
to the product of the likelihood and the prior distribution the probability of the parameters
given the data and
a query parameters i first
it's again it usually distribution where
here we now have two at the first stars
with the corresponding columns
this is the property of this
the fact that we used
conjugate priors
one of the properties of the situation that the posterior takes on the same form
as prior with no surprise that the posterior distribution is also usually
and now we can calculate the probability of of the tasks of the next
given our prior assumption given the data
and again we can calculate the integral and the result is
very interesting very important it's quite definite facade plus nk normalized
what we see here is that if we
have observed
so now resides in the past they often the probability of observing this reside in
the future will be very high
and here we see also that i not exactly has this meaning of specifying the
belief in this prior assumptions about the distribution of acacia people like
so this is also quite an client intuitive there's
and of course you also observe the and becomes a very large we can sort
of ignore this time and again become tend to reside the same result we would
have obtained the maximum likelihood approach that the empirical collins
i determine the probabilities of future events
know we have to look to take a look at club level closer look at
this usually distribution which is has some interesting features
so this is the definition again
this formula without first past and now we can plug in different numbers this is
the case of the three-dimensional distribution c
plotting here two of the dimensions of the third one is the one of thought
orthogonal here for sort of this sort of thing you this is the place coming
if we specify
first of all it is one one one
and here's is one minus one so this is that due to the zero and
everything becomes a uniform so any
parameter value
so she has the same value in this case
then we can increase
i for not factor which means lighting these multiply these numbers with a large number
the two two two ten ten ten for example we see that the probability mass
gets more and more concentrated in the central region here which should be
situation point three and point three so
we we implementing our belief that we were dealing with a fair dice
all the probabilities of the same and the weight and this belief
also increases because the probability of this distribution point three point three becomes larger and
we could also implement an unbalanced prior belief
so this would indicate that you believe the second
the second reside in the person the dice would be very high probability the first
one is low and the
one would also below
and this is an example where
the third dimension is very high
i really like that
and so
it's the
on the
so much more reliable way
it's easy to find
OK so the
so this is the
optimisation you end up with a strategy
the decision problem and the reason why he should not be something
it's actually called
and people all these things
all that
now specializes in charge
she she found that
so i mean this is not my
is no
he has
this is a very high dimensional spaces efficient which
as already mentioned to read recently caption
some more specific examples of imagine
as vision of it based on
so if you want to select of the
in addition to the
the original input and not for that trick
well we
in the rule head of
features which is that this is the
five were that each
the truth the we
this is used to actually represent the fact that you
way as a combination
so if you try
five new example which is the way that we need
projection for example in the space
these are
it is
and just to
so i
actually not just in between training and test data
so this is the only known making
we need to do with
prior to compute efficiently
the three projections of
training and testing
he basically really want
should have computing
this composition the projection
together with the
you should we need to on the
and the same thing
that's we
just right
you the first one to
we seem to go back quite
two weeks ago
i was hard pressed
it's essentially the
and when try to solve
and you finally the norm for the way
in this space
this is all i
so actually
so what
so really all
however i well
and this is what
which is the
the expression the
the second one
this is actually the
problem of
and i
do you actually corresponds to the dual optimisation problem optimisation is actually
and the thing that we
do it
today we
projections of
we have efficient ways to compute
need actually
so that's the only so we did we decide is
you should be aware that we saw this situation
and we
i actually work
here's an example
so you actually
well i they all pairs of features
get your
in fact
and so on
is actually
from p one to two
all we get from the same
there is a high j
multiply correspond to make some
number sign just
more about this
this this is quite operation
so i would like to query
query operation then
it's the same thing here
much more efficient and this is the only one program
three years
you know the rules of operation it was six hundred one
so you see
we actually want to
o thing to do this
classification based
we actually yet
controlling generalisation
between the perturbation and if there is an instance oscillating at the coupling distillation freeze
and the photons travel to you
and you see an imprint of these fluctuations so
one important points to remember is that the for the rise the size of the
last scattering surface face
it's a very important quantity to keep in mind because it defines a fundamental more
these are sound waves
and you have a specific scale define which is the eyes and size of the
last scattering surface is a little bit like when you blow into upright
right you can create the fundamental modes and you can create overtones
and these are the kind of thing you should be able to see
in the past tense of those perturbations in the cosmic microwave background
so all this
o station going into the universe is cool enough to hydrogen combined for them can
travel freely to us and then was the father travel freely to us give us
an option of how this all
all this
acoustic oscillations were going on
and so all let means
keep through that and ask whether we can see this in the sky
and indeed we can this was produced by the wmap satellite in two thousand three
and all these
blood that you see hot and cold despite there is some small is the will
of the galaxy that have been taken out of the country difficult to well next
to the galactic center so what you seen you seen sounds
and this has been called the cosmic thing for
so for me when the first the particle accelerator with a maybe we're trying to
explain what physicists particle accelerators is like taking two grand piano this out of the
particles we have that we believe are complex and made the more fundamental particle smashing
them together and then what come out of the collision from there are trying to
figure out how the piano was made so what you are trying to do here
is from this sound
of the university of trying to figure out how the instrument is me
and so
let's see how this works
let's means
into another density
and then gravity takes over
the activation started growing up in the equation
galaxies and stars four min
gravity keeps you know
doing his job
and then you form the large-scale structure of the universe and when you satellite to
look at the last scattering surfaces sees it to all these cosmic structure in front
again we need to use some statistical property to describe all these and the idea
is to do of power spectrum of this temperature fluctuation but seems to now
you seen on the surface of the sphere because you have seen
on the plane of the sky
then you need to use the spherical harmonics and probably have you seen the spherical
before and this is a reminder of
what you've seen but you can always characterized then this small fluctuation over these three
kelvin temperature has an angular power spectrum now remember this is challenging because the temperature
of the cosmic background exactly kelvin but what you want to see
is the fluctuation that taverner mass of one part in ten to the five this
is really really challenging imagine how much you need to cool your detector in order
to be able to measure something like that
remember that the universe is so pervaded by
these kind of you
its top
let's keep going
this is what we've seen in the data the angular power spectrum as a function
of multiple moment the smaller scale larger scales
what you are seeing here is this fundamental model that was talking about things this
is the power spectrum is the square quantity compression satisfaction
it all looks like fixing here
so these correspond to compression this is the dissatisfaction this is the complexion and so
on and these are the acoustic peaks of this sounds of this cosmic symphony
so this is the fundamental mode
and these are primarily reports
why do i say that these are primordial reports
just the second mark
so all
this size correspond to this fundamental model which is the size of the eyes and
the last scattering surveys face
now you have a standard ruler if you can compute what was their eyes and
size of the last scattering cell face and you see on this skies appending a
given angle
remember there is a relation when you have some
a standard ruler and you see it and and angle you can learn about the
geometry of space in the middle withdrawal largest triangle uconn and so this position can
tell you about the geometry of the universe the height of this speak tell you
about the height of this potential well that tells you something about the matter content
of the universe
i remember whenever you have this sort of forced to dump oscillator
if you were to
leave the potential well the same but increases this masts then you've changed the relationship
so when i get there
the following i get omega s great
upstairs which is this one
and all this comes downstairs
my is only gets credit
because omega zero square
plus omega as query
we agree that the first equation i simply
written in c one divided by c two i can always do the right thing
is he wants to one side c two to one side and the fight
that space
and i'm going to do the same with the next iteration
i think this one two to right side and i have seen ones dan c
two see here
now this becomes up there
is omega
plus omega zero screen
please omega as script
and i go downstairs
omega as square
i have eliminated c one and c two
because if i solve this equation
i get my solution for me
is this one equation is one and only that's omega
gotta admit
and the about of the two solutions the better omega minus and the better be
omega plus coming out of this
untouched by human hands i must find two solutions
first make sure
this is correct
and the answer is yes
so what i do now
well i'm going to simplified one step further
which is not very easy
multiply this by this
this was this
so we get a omega s
to power four
is omega
because omega zero
because omega s creates
one equation
one another
you know
take the square root left and right
get minus
omega scrap
because omega zero create plays omega s great
or minus
as square
do not forget the plus or minus
the square root of
omega has two to four
this process might is omega as great
great see
the light of day you won't believe this
growing omega on the site
and i get omega zero square
because omega s great
minus class
omega as script
and the simplicity
is overpowering i feel it over my whole body
it is unbelievable
well they have a minus sign here
i find that omega is omega zero
that's my only go minus
that's the one
that's why omega minus
when there is a plus sign here
i find exactly what we predict before
i find it only got plus
is this square root
of omega zero
process two
omega s great
because the plus sign
make this too
and the beautiful
so they just pop out
and i predicted that there will be two solutions
we have both
so by substituting this in there
automatically come out two solutions
well now c one or c two
seven so for that
you can always sold in terms of riga
and in terms of c one obviously two
many volunteers look at the blackboard
somewhere in in those equations
that's repeated
three times
in one
get sent as one one-on-one
and we call this are three
and i expect you could call this repeating it twice because you send new repeated
price but i'm going call it repeating three times okay that's my
anne i made one of those earlier
and this is what it looks like
we've got a pilot ten thousand bits on the left and then we repeat it
three times i've actually reordered the bit so that first bit is sent
after the whole file has been sent
we repeat the whole file three times
logically just the same as repeating it
let's give ourselves a source file
and the full file could be the string zero one one zero one
and transmit
zero zero zero one long
there is one one
so that's how we encode the file
let's not give ourselves from noise and start talking about
and will start with a repetition code
so let's have a noise vector and the whale represent noises can be zero if
no flip occurs in the can one flip
so here's the noise vector that are
binary symmetric channel
could produce forest
and that would mean that the received vector
differs from tea
in some of these places so the hero
this was split so we get a zero one one
one one one
one zero one
so that's our received
so what i do there i added
the transmission
the nice and i did the addition modulo
two so one and one is zero
how should we decode this
the decoder
a system that reads in
and speaks out against
four tests
in general
how should we
of three have a habitat you neighbour
okay any suggestions
how in general yes so back
okay so take the mean
at each group of three is our main so really real time
andy say
is the mean above it close to the one or two zero
is did anyone else have another way of putting the same concept yeah
best-of-three all majority vote yes so
we reckon that sensible decoder is
the best of
here three
and the length of this block transmitting
or majority vote
right so we receive zero zero zero we say zero activities zero one which they one
if you actually one zero
we what
they want
and see the
want to say
to chip if i make a
okay so studies eight possible received vectors and here's what we do according to this
decoder and if we apply the decoder here
then our comes at a zero
and what we can notice in this case
is that some good things that happened
so here
i flip occurred
with the flat
and it's been cleaned up
because this is the same as this
and so that makes us happy
something else has happened
there are two flats in a block
and this has been done one and that's actually an error so that's not good
so a bit sad about
fair enough
this decoder
does improve things
if we apply the majority vote decoder
this is what we get
and if you compare thee
this source file and these
decoded file there
you can see it's improve things we have reduced the probability of error so this
repetition code kind words a bit
but it doesn't actually get
just ten to the minus fifteen
he is
some value k
he's fifteen say
lancelot fifteen
if the element is there
as the elements
it's not in the set
it's now
a very simple data structure
just go to that
and set the value
to the inserted value for deletion just from here to looking up
just index and see if see what's and that's what
very simple
very simple data structures
all these operations therefore
in the worst case
as a practical matter
places you can use this strategy are pretty limited
why is wise
what's the issue limitation here
OK so it so that's the limitation surely
but there's actually more severe limitation
was that i started writing
minus one can be a huge number
OK like for example
suppose that i want to have my set drawn over sixty four bit
OK the things i'm storing in my table is set of sixty four numbers
so maybe small set
we only have
you know
a few thousand of these elements
but there are drawn from the sixty four bit value then this strategy requires me
to have an array that goes from zero
two of the sixty four minus one
i think it was sixty four minus one
it is like eighteen
twenty million of
things like
it's it's literally because it's like it's beyond the
billions we normally use OK
another billion or trillions
point eighteen twenty million case that's the really big number
so or even worse
suppose that is were drawn from character strings
so you know people's names or something which is the optimal way to have to
because most of the table would be empty be for any reasonable
set of values you would want to keep
so the idea is to try to keep something is going to keep the table
while still
preserving some of the property
and that's where hashing comes in
we use the hash functions
which maps
during the course not crazy random
in two slots
table t
so we call it should be
each of the array
indexes here slot
this seem just sort of think of it is a big table you got slots
in the tail
restoring your values
and so
university's school that you
we have our table over here
we set up
he has
m slots
it could take
we actually have been set we're actually try to represent us
which is presumably a very small
piece of
the universe
and i will do as well
take an element from here and map two
it's a to their
can take another one
we apply
the hash functions
one was is that we characterize exactly stability clear k means
we know
what it detects
and we conclude that the
the success of stability in practice is only coincidence it is not a general rule
so it's a very funny situation with something works in practice it also some very
artificial that when you analyse mathematically
but the the characterisation and argue that this characterization shows that stability should not work
in general so
he was the characterization
we said that a stable if at the limit the sample size n goes to
it because the instability becomes ill
so that they stable when you take large sample sizes it becomes more and more
of them
and we could prove the following
that if your algorithm is cost minimizing like k means you're trying to minimize the
k means cost that's what your algorithm is striving to get it at the cost
minimizing i would
it is stable on a data set d
if and only if there is a unique minimizer
two the function you're trying to optimise
if and only if there is a unique partition that achieves
the optimal value so rather than finding the correct number of clusters it detects whether
there is a unique optimum solution several optimal solutions is if we go back
if you go back to this picture
here if k equal to that many
possible partitionings that will give you the same k means but
but here for k was to be the only one partitioning gives you
the minimum value of k means
and what we found out disability exactly the text this thing the question whether there
is an optimal
unique optimum solution o
multiple optimal solutions and now we can i ask ourselves so
i would say that said the for is the probability distribution over some domain
and that many
could be infinite to find probabilities we know so the main you can think of
it as the a fundamental uniform distribution if you want
and then the question is you're trying to optimise some
cause instability detects just is now
i don't think i have time to go into the proof
i mean this is the proof idea
and the idea of showing you the proof is just
convincing you
that this is hard proof so you should accept it too
whatever your content is the proof is hard
OK so
what what is the conclusion
the common belief
why that a is stable on the distribution p if and only if the algorithm
picks the correct number of clusters
that was the common belief that was really the way
being applied to all of
many domains
the stability is only a necessary condition
for good clustering not sufficient condition for class
OK you right
it's only necessary condition now what i would do it is
i have what we have is complete characterization
and if there is that you know
if you if you are
is trying to minimize some notion of cost somewhat defined notion of course then
a is stable on p if and only if there is a unique solution unique
solution for this dataset
so we have a complete characterisation of what be
and the question is
these two notions is saying is correct k
the same thing as saying we have a unique solution
and we already seen one example where it doesn't and i can show you now
some more examples which really show that it can go wrong in many many ways
so here are some
very simple example so
assume that all the time in my examples now so now
what i want to do is show you an example that those two notions of
correct number of clusters and having a unique minimizer for the
cost function are not the same
here is an example of a simple example all my data sets will be on
the line and these are just the density function field density function is fifty percent
of that is here and fifty percent of that is here
what you think is the correct number of clusters
if i try k was there will be stable
because there is a unique solution
so if they can try
so sentences stable because the unique optimum solution what happens if i try cake was
would it be
stable it will not be stable because
we have to
sufficient x same course meaning optimizes this is one of the most
and another optimisation
is this one
both of them achieved the same cost
so i i have
nine numerical optimize
OK was three
so the conclusion is
three is not is unstable too stable instability did a good job
four former is going to be stable again you know that the that
pushing my next example right right before the stable again right so far maybe good
here's another example now i changed my example only a little bit i put here
fifty percent plus epsilon of my weight and here put fifty percent minus epsilon
of my weight now
we can see what's the correct number of clusters we will agree that this two
with k equal to will be stable or not
it will be stable if i just have to points
it would be stable there's only one optimum solution one in the center what will
happen for k three
it would be stable for k tray because OK constraint we have a unique optimum
solution we have put the two here in the one because this highly
a weight so we see here that
if i use stability is my indicator to what the correct number
clusters can distinguish between two and three although
in terms of our intuition
two and three are clearly distinguishable there's no argument here
are on average more similar to each other
each is through its own cluster
i want to be the case that
so it's not the case that this guy
is more similar to here and there
and this guy is more similar to their
so if you think of the similarity
i think it's helpful to think of similarity attraction
OK i don't want this to be more attracted to this set here and this
that the more attractive than here i go off together to form
the stable marriage is like this pair
so that the conditioning what they might be natural one similarity function has the property
so similarity measure the proper is like a piece of one cluster in peace another
cluster both more similar to each other and each is to the
so that turns out to be weaker condition and the first one was still sufficient
to get bigotry although in this case you can use the same out
i really here is just a simpler version of this where
the stable marriage condition is it's OK if this guy wants to run with this
guys guidelines this one doesn't want to to have that or vice versa but is
the same in either one side conditions and nobody wants to run off with any
each that's more to this
there's more to k
you might say the average similarity
a this is more similar to this
and here and then also require this is more similar
this is simple addition
it turns out for this case actually for the case in the last slide instead
of the the
cross called the standard single linkage and average single linkage works so
the here and now with the work is the like before but instead of merging
taking the
the two most similar points emerging clusters we took to another way to think of
the previous algorithm is free clusters we define their similarity to be the max overall
points here all points here the similar now define to be the average is this
more similar the average someone will merge pair of clusters whose average similarity is highest
if we do that then you can show this to sell more
and you can analyse any point in time all the across you produced are what's
called laminar with target they're all either pieces of the target cluster or there
equal to the power posterior for the union
i'm not going to do the analysis
done the proof
but it turns out this version
the interesting thing just kind of q is that if you have a similarity function
it's not symmetric
then this algorithm breaks down
right and so
give an example showing how breaks down so nonsymmetric also i think is you might
think why should you ever have a similarity function is not symmetric
so i find a OK you might like if you think this attraction
a you've seen before i extracted the fact see is that the
he fact a
doesn't even light cycle
nothing wrong with looks like
so then the algorithm can break down so you have an example of how can
break down so imagine you're similarity for like
OK so
imagine that this has point
so imagine that this a similarity from this to this the corner here here's quarter
this is only point one similar to here at this point five somewhere here is
perfectly consistent there's no piece that wants to join piece
but symmetric and the problem is that this average similarity is higher than this one
so the average similarity thing with merge this with this which wasn't we want to
so it turns out that you can do something all the difference in this case
you can run out elements inspired by the minimum spanning tree algorithm corporate because out
where what you do
it's very cluster you look at very piece you have in your algorithm
you currently have u
pointed to the piece is most similar so do that this piece points to hear
the piece point here piece points to here he is walking to get into cycle
everybody's playing somewhere you have to go into cycle to start somewhere in all the
errors while you're sitting in the cycle the can prove that legitimate thing to merge
so that's a slightly different
then we can look at more general conditions so if you
take the previous one
we're quite stability but if we imagine there are similar function might be noisy maybe
there are small sets the tone of a and hopefully the large sets still and
then you can look at different algorithms for this property we don't know if that's
we know flow algorithm and fast
if we took examples as in the previous property and noise large set still behave
bottom-up algorithms start from p says might fail because they might make bad decisions at
the beginning
we know is slow algorithm that works here which is you start taking some points
random you guess what topics they belong to and use that to produce candidate cost
and the reason the are
we have slowed to its is depends on how many
topics there are with the exponential number of topics career take initial sample guess what
topics they belong to use that to produce candidate clusters and so we have to
try a bunch of different possibilities the into
trial but cannot clusters to produce a huge list of candidates and then the second
testing step that will compare these and see the extent to which search
conditions implied by this property is satisfied if things up into a tree
so so the running time for depends on top if you're talking like two topic
three topic not so bad but this algorithm ends up being exponential time
OK and so
just to and
if you're familiar with the pack model and learning in the PAC learning model we
try to study are quite sets of functions a concept class like
the set of
conjunctions and functions or linear separators or
degree two polynomial the decision trees decision unless you look at the set of function
and you say d which is the set of functions are learnable and by what
algs twenty minutes as i believe the world is and function without actually i believe
the world linear separator
the target functions were separated without actions by believe the target function is small
think of an example suppose i've got this way for silicon we've talked about doping
talked about doping suppose i want to render it p type so i want to
as i want to
confuse this with a surveillance
open such as boron so how do we do that we smear this with boron
and just wait
what's the process
let's take a look more closely what we can do is is we can take
our wafer
i'm going to exaggerate the dimensions is colloquially hockey partner
the silicon wafer so here's the silicon or to put this in a furnace and
we want to get boron into the wafer and we're not going to do this
by melting
we're going to do this while the wafer is in the solid state that's why
we're over here talking about diffusion in a solid state process
what we do is
a form of boron over the way for
as the gas di boring
and the di boring passes over and on contact with the silicon
it decomposes to form
which goes into the silicon
plus hydrogen
and that hydrogen course remains in the gas phase
and we can even moderate cost because the chemical reactions decomposition and i boring into
hydrogen and boron and we could even take a guess that maybe the rate of
this i haven't measured but the rate would go as some
a relationship involving the concentration
di boring to some power and
so we've seen that
now what i want to do someone asked what what's the process by which boron
enters the cell
so now i want to zoom in here to the
to the near surface and here's the free surface of silica
this is the surface this is the inside the wafer
and i've got boron the decomposing and dissolving riggo's in substitution only sitting on silicon
sites so now i'm asking how does the boron
how does boron into the cell
what are the kinetics of the
in graphs of boron
that's what we want to as rate ingress
rate ingress of boron
through selection
russell as we wanna look
this is not some kind of a cooperative process
because the silicon solid so individual atoms have to move step by step through because
it's substitutional solutions forming here
we can take a guess at it
if i know
make this the coordinate system
make this the coordinate system called the free surface
x equals zero
and this is
moving down into greater
i can make a plot of
ingress of
born into silicon so this is the next which is depth from surface
this is the free surface
at x equals zero
and i'm going to fix the concentration of di boring in the
reactor so the concentration of boron at the surface will be fixed
as long as they keep the concentration of died boring fixed concentration of boron the
surface will be fixed so what i'm going to do is to plot the concentration
of boron into silicon
as a function of depth from the surface
we know deep inside the silicon there's no more
so here it should be zero we know what the surface is constant the question
is what is the shape of the curve
just as i showed you last day
we talked about the first or second order what it boils down to is what
is the shape of the curve we know it's going look something like this
doesn't look a lot like
the attenuation curve for
the loss of matter in the chemical reactions
it starts some constant value trails off asymptotically so really the question is what is
the shape
what is the shape
are we answer that question we can look at this and i instead what we
y two w
my so by
by multiplying three matrices together
a nested so so the out of some of some of the y two
the inner sum is some of the y one
but that's just what i mean by double so some of the y one and
y two
and i have
inside the sum i have the exponential of the g one function plus the g
two function plus the g three function
so by multiplying three matrices together
i'm summing over all y one y two
well if i am i
and i can continue
so i can
if i have multiplied together
all the matrices one two three up to n plus one
and i can
look at the start
entry of this
combined matrix
it's going to be
of the y one
after y and
the exponential of
g one start
what one
class g two
one y two
g three
y two y three
so on
up to
g and plus one
y and
and and
this summer
this is exactly the thing that i wanted to evaluate for the partition function
it's the sum of
all possible
assignments for the individual y i of
all of the numerator
for those particular y i
and and so
this algorithm is that the the the previous our that has
well as the name the viterbi algorithm and has a category of algorithms that falls
into the dynamic programming and this algorithm
the way i presented it
it's a matrix multiplication already so to do to implement it all you need to
do is create is an matrices and then multiply them altogether
so that's computationally very easy
it's so much
it's actually
we a special case of a more general class of algorithms called forward backward algorithms
and i guess i'm not going to try to explain why this is called forward
backward algorithm that if you have
if you're familiar with hidden markov models they have forward backward algorithm also and what
explaining here is just a very very narrow special cases solves exactly the problem we
are interested in solving here
but still this is still general for
a linear chain conditional random fields
those are the
those are the two important and that we needed we want to use conditional random
now we need to talk about training conditional random fields
any questions on the
going to use them
stochastic gradient
the second or as and the maximisation
so much
so much so
the model
as a log PY given x w
it is
so we have the normalisation constant
of some of the j
my fj
x y
and so to them
to do stochastic gradient we need to evaluate the derivative of my
this so this is the log probabilities so
that's the objective function to maximize for single training example so we want to evaluate
its derivative
model so
i did wj
log p
OK sorry so
this is the p function
so only the log functional log of this
and what i want to do now is the
derivative of the log p function
and so the log of this is the logo of the numerator minus along with
the nominator
divided wj
some of the j
wj j
x y
divided wj
xeon x
what's this
so i suppose we have which required three
and value x want to insert
it is the algorithm
first we instantly pst you know
then we color the red herring
is slightly more precise notation
color field x
and our and walk away up the tree with a while so we get to
the root or
until we reach a black
so in general x initially is going to be the elements that we inserted but
we're going to move x up the tree if ever we find xs of black
nodes were happy because maybe it's turns red
maybe it is and i don't care black can have arbitrarily coloured parents threaten as
that we worry about
so x is red we have to keep doing this
further around one while the color is red
we're going to keep doing this
so there are three cases
well there are six thing and her account that's what makes this a little bit
tricky too
OK but there are
some symmetric
what we care about argued is between x
and it's grandparents
so i'm using POV student parent of x shorter so p of p of xis
xis grandparent
left of p if you have access the left child so what i'm interested as
i look at x
and if i don't sign any directions in x is the child of some convex
p of x is the parent of is the child of the grandparent here p
of x
now these edges are vertical there either left or right and i care about which
in particular
i'm looking at whether the parents is the left child of the grandparents
so i want to know
does it look like
and i don't know whether x is to the left or to the right of
the parent is a parent of x the left child here p of x
or is it the right child
in these two cases are totally symmetric but i need to assume it's one way
or the other one other otherwise i can draw the pictures
so this will be
it's called category
this is category b
and i'm going to tell you what to do in category a and category b
is symmetric just flip left and right
so this
this is a
within category a there are three cases
i would think it would be is the same case is just reversed
well we're going to do
is look at the other child
of the grandparents
this is one reason why we certainly need know
which way we're lucky
if one of x is the left child of the grandparent going look at the
other child parent grandparent which would be the right child of the grandparent call that
node y
this is also known as the uncle or the art of x depending on whether
the origin
that is
defined here in terms of articulatory features
and so i have done in the lower left-hand corner
here the
these sort of the key here is that each that each state
it is defined by sort of the presence or the level
of a multi valued articulatory feature
so the articulatory features here are some of the the
i guess
different from the elements that we talked about earlier and in terms of their specifics
but the let's the tongue body of the tongue dorsum and the the valley and
the larynx so these are sort of the articulatory positions
and i guess lyrics would have to do with voicing and so on
so for each i will withdraw and this figure is a little sort of an
example of what they'd intended that is the yellow one yellow box here corresponds to
the phoneme t
the other corresponds to the phoneme and i have a each one of these sort
of squares or rectangles here is a represents a state of the model
in and each state is characterized by
the level
of the feature for of the distinctive feature
houses houses arrived at well by hand
the designers
basically i went through their own and specified sort of micro segmental features
and you can see for example that for t
oh i forgot to mention here
this allows for speech at feature spreading
this indicates the are nine here indicates that the influence here of the
this tongue dorsum that value over at the right is allowed to spread into into
the states l one would indicate that the time that the tongue body value of
one hears is can spread into the state so
so basically the notion of
of of
assimilation we we talked about how context can spread from one
one forward to the next is characterized here
and i guess
we were basically allowing context to be directly defined in our articulatory space
what are some of the potential advantages here
well one in particular is that we could think of before going to do that
we've discussed this earlier for going to do adaptation
we can perhaps do that very efficiently we can adapt along this particular articulatory dimension
most schemes that we do in way that we implement for adaptation in existing systems
of apply some kind of perhaps the matrix transformation or maximum capacity or a assumption
and updating the means and variances model but they
can be inefficient and that they may require a lot of data
part of that is because they're not really adapting along any sort of physiologically plausible
OK this makes sense
right so
think of them as it states of your hidden markov model
that's right decision would any other hidden markov model
kind of
yes exactly right
think of it that way
so we're not so that's the key thing here where you got your system sitting
over here in your desktop and there it is and and how would you have
to change a system to implement this well the first thing is you completely redefined
the topology of models you're incorporating
as shown here you incorporated mechanism to allow
you know states here two to migrate is shown this that that is a bit
of a change in the other so you wind up then with the state space
here that's described in terms of
these articulatory sort of
and then but otherwise you have real you haven't changed your hmm system
in in a significant way
so the so the thought is that while the state you know the
you're you're existing hmm system has states in the hidden states could associate with each
other and you don't really have a way of
saying what those states represents
you can kind of in hindsight go back and look and say well look if
i decode the state tends to correspond to this
you know this general
spectral a homogenous phenomenon but that's about it
so the idea here is you can say all right
i'm really as i move to my state space i'm really moving through say
as we want you to be able to use the basic tools of computational thinking
to write small-scale programs
keep coming back to that idea call computational thinking
and so you can write small pieces of code
small is not derogatory or by the way just says the size of things are
going to be able to do
second skill we want you to have at the end of this course is the
ability to use the vocabulary of computational tools
in order to be able to understand programs written by others
want to be able to write going to be able to read
this latter skill by the way
is incredibly valuable
because you want to do everything from scratch yourself you want to be able to
look at what has been created by somebody else and understand what is inside their
whether it works correctly and how you can build on
this is one of the few places where plagiarism is an OK thing is not
bad to few like learn
from the skills of others in order to create something you want to write a
come back to plagiarism is about thing later on
third thing we want you to do is to understand the fundamental
both capabilities and limitations
and the costs associated with them
in that latter statement sounds funny i don't think of computation having limits but they
there are some things that cannot be computed we want to understand what those limits
it's going to be able to understand
abilities and limits
and then finally the last tactical skill that you're going to get out of this
course is you're going to have the ability to map scientific problems
into a computational framework
to be able to take a description of the problem
map into something computational
now if you think about it
so it sounds like grammar school
the teacher read
teacher right
the teacher to understand what you can and cannot do
most importantly we want to try and give you the start of and ability to
take a description of the problem from some other domain
figure out how to map it into that domain of computation so you can do
the reading and writing that you want to do
OK a few minutes when start talking about what is computation how are we going
to start building those tools but that's what you should take away that's what you're
going to gain out of this course
by the time you done
now let me take a sidebar for about five minutes to talk about
course administration the ministry of things that we're going to do in the course so
you know what the rules are
right so classes
two hours electroweak
you obviously know where you know when you're here
two seasons there's a eleven
one hour recitation week on fridays come back in the second home to set up
for that
nine hours a week about side the class work
nine hours are going to be primarily working on problem sets and all the problem
sets are going to involve programming in python
the language is going to be using this term
i think this is the first problem it's pretty easy actually is probably wrong john
they're very easy and we're going to ramp up by the time we get to
the end of the term is going to be dealing with some fairly complex things
so one of the things are going to see is we're going to make heavy
use of libraries or code written by others
it will allow you to tackle interesting problems of having to write from scratch but
it does mean that this
scale here is going to be really valuable you need to be able to read
that code and understand what was right you're wrong
two quizzes
during the term
the dates have already been scheduled john i forgot to look them up i think
it's october second in november
fourth it will be on the course website
my point is go check the course website which by the way is right there
if you have if you know you have a conflict of one of those quizzed
states now please see john right right away
will arrange something ahead of time but if you
reason saying that is you know you know they are getting married that day for
example we will excuse you from the quiz to get married expected to come right
back to do the quiz by the way but the
four tough crowd all right
if you have a conflict please let us know
the second thing is if you have an MIT documented special need for taking quizzes
please see john right well in advance
these two weeks before the quiz again will arrange for this but you need to
give us enough warning so that we can deal with that
OK the quizzes are open book
this course
it is not a book
how will you can memorize facts in fact i think both john our little sensitive
to memory test given our a john
this is not about how you memorize things is about how you think so the
open up open book is really going to test your ability to think
grades for the course will be assigned roughly and i use the word roughly because
we reserve the right to move these numbers around a little bit but basically in
the following percentages fifty five percent of great comes from the problem set
the forty five come from the quiz shows that two quizzes in the final exam
i forgot the final exam during final periods of the quiz
percentages are ten fifteen and twenty percent
mix of the other forty five
OK other administrative you
just look through my list here
the first problem set concept zero is already been posted this is a really easy
what we intended to be really easy problems it is basically to get you to
load up i found on your machine to make sure you understand how to interact
the first problems that will be posted shortly it's also pretty boring somewhat like my
lectures but not johns
and that means you know we want to do is to get going on things
don't worry we're going to make them more interesting was to go along nonetheless i
want to stress that none of these problems that are intended to be lethal
we're not using them to we due out we're using them to help you learn
so if you run into problems that just you don't get
right to seek help
could be psychiatric help
could be t eight i recommend that you
my point being please come and talk to somebody
the problems are set up so that if you start down the right path that
should be pretty straightforward
to work it through
if you start down a plausible but
incorrect patterns you can sometimes find yourself stuck in the weeds somewhere
and we want to bring you back in so part of the goal here is
this should not be
and in ruling exhausting kind of test is really something that should be helping you
learn the material if you need help as john myself for the is that's what
we're here for
OK we're gonna run primarily a paperless subject
that's why the website is there please check it that's where everything's going to be
posted in terms of things you need to know
in particular please go to it today you'll find the form there that you need
to fill up to register for or sign up for other recitation
recitations on friday right now we have been scheduled nine ten eleven twelve one and
we may
drop one of the recitation just depending on course size right so we reserve the
right unfortunately to have to move your around
my guess is that nine is not going to be tremendously popular time but maybe
you'll surprise me
nonetheless please go going sign up we will let you sign up for whichever recitation
makes sense for you
g two
of the w
notice this is starting to look a little bit like what we want
because what we want is the sum of the y sequence
the product of exponentials or the exponential
one of the sub
and here i have it's not the sum of the whole y sequence but is
the sum of
to sum over single the
the some of the g values
so i can call this
some of
y one
so the if i calculate the matrix and one two
and i look at it and to a start w
that's going to be the sum over all y one
exponential of g one
star y one class g two of y one w
so i can continue
one two three
so now multiplying together and one and m two and m three
of money
and i look at the
entry in that
and it's going to be the
some of the y two
and one two
y two
and so we
y two w
is the
some of the y two
so now i'm going to plug in here
what i just learned from here
some of the light two
some of the
y one
exponential of
start y one
g two
y one
y two
then i heard
i have a history of y two w
so that is the
g so we
y two w
this is
some of the y one
and y two
g one start
why one class
g two
y one y two
g three
able to deal with weird functions two
for weird functions
this this measure the set of values of time in which the function is in
some tiny little slice here the measure that is going to become rather complicated
and therefore we have to understand how to find the measure of some pretty weird
the bank went on and said OK
well defined how to find measure things
you know it's all very intuitive
have any real numbers
a and b
i two real numbers i might as well say one of them is less than
or equal to the other one so y is less than or equal to b
i want to include minus infinity and plus here when we say the set of
real numbers
we don't include minus infinity and plus infinity
when we talk about the extended set of real numbers we do include include minus
infinity plus here for the most part when we're dealing with measure theory we really
want to include minus infinity and plus than the also because because they make things
easier to talk about
so what makes said is for any interval
the set of points which lie between a and b
he started out with the open interval namely the set of points not including a
and not including b but including all the real numbers in between
the measure is that is what we said before and none of you objected to
the measure of an interval
what to be the size of the interval because
after all the big was doing was taking size and putting another name one
because we all
because we all thought of as being size so the measure the interval a b
is b-minus
analysis engineers we all know that doesn't really make any difference whether you include your
don't include a and we're trying to find the size of the inevitable so he
said OK it's it's the size of that intervals b-minus a
whether or not you include either the endpoints
then he went on to say something else the measure of a countable union of
disjoint intervals
is the sum of the measure of each interval
the sum
and we already
i said when we are trying to figure out what to the beginning rule was
but if you had several
intervals the measure
of the entire interval namely the measure the union of the centre of intervals ought
to be the sum
the measure of each interval
so all these adding here
is let's go on and go to the limit and talk about
and talk about a countably infinite number of intervals
and use the same definition
now there's one nice thing about that
what is it
if we take
and so on
they are the countable set of things
each of those things is nonnegative
so what happens when we take the sum
of a bunch of nonnegative numbers
there are only two possibilities when you take the sum
even a countable set of nonnegative numbers
and what are they
because it goes to limit or goes to infinity yes
and the base said well let's say it if it goes to infinity that's the
limit offset
so in other words are only two possibilities the sum is finite if you can
find this out in the sum is infinite nothing else can happen
so that's nice
and then look back said one other thing about the mathematicians trying to deal with
did different things
when they were trying to deal with very small sets
and some of them said well these very small sets are measurable
others and part of the bags genius was it is said if you can take
a set of points
and you can put them inside another set of points
which doesn't amount to anything
then this is smaller set of points to have a measure which is less than
or equal to the bigger set of points
so we went on
so so that that says that any subset
of something that doesn't
it has zero measure
what also have zero mean and we look at some examples you'll see that that's
not quite as
as obvious as it seems but anyway he said that
and even nicer way to put that
is when you're talking about weird intervals
try to cover that come try to cover that we're set
with a bunch of intervals
and if you can cover with a bunch of intervals
in different ways and the measure of the bunch of intervals the countable set of
yes you can make it arbitrarily small
then we also say that the set has measure zero
so any time you have a set s
and you can cover it
with intervals
which have arbitrarily small measure
namely we make the measure the intervals the small you want to make that we
say bingo
as has zero measure
now that's going to be very nice because it let's get rid of an awful
lot of things
because any time we have some set
which has zero measure in this sense when we look back to what we did
with all the beginning
it says
good forget about
it has zero measure it doesn't come into the n at all
and that's exactly the thing we what we'd like to get rid of all that
number one to get rid of it we have these
sets which have made zero they don't amount to anything
and we're not going to worry about them
OK let's
let's do an example
a famous example
what about the set of rationals
which lie between zero and one
OK well what were rational numbers are numbers
within the perceptron algorithm um
you do end up with a reasonable solution if you if you there's a learning
rate and if you reduce the learning rates
in a slow enough where you will actually find the optimal
hyperplane this is the thing that was known in nineteen
well it was known easily by the nineteen nineties when i came in the field
the algorithm is basically
the weights
and new ads the weight some learning rate times the label value times the data
point very what that's it so if the so u iterate u
make not increment kay increment
and you select a misclassified point you ignore
there any points correctly classified so for example
if you'll hear if you
wait solution is there
in all these solutions are fine it's only this one they are infringing seems like this guy
and you update in that direction
so many of you may actually go beyond you don't do anything intelligent
you just take a learning rate i guess in e
i don't really understand of in the simplex method to understand the
you could it perhaps the case that
you're doing something definitely more intelligent simplex method you want overshoot i'm hey you could
potentially overshoot but then you look at this one and you go back again
i've got a little older
visualization about this is all historic stuff
so here's is a simple dataset and what we do is on we select initially
some data point and we build these initial decision boundary based on the data point
only so
we start with the weights being zero
and for the first iteration we set the weight vector to one the data point values which in this case
selected data point i circled
and that's the result
so we don't multiply being observed
the value of the data points
m times it's
then we go through selecting incorrectly classified data points are circled one there
which is incorrectly classified and we do this all day we multiply the incorrectly classified data point by its label
adjust the weight vector
now very often
this converges very quickly
so this at one green point there
there is no incorrectly classified yeah
and then
all data now correctly classified now that's just an example i set that is separable
has to count in the galapagos in distributions
the feasible region would be
any region in hand we can bend at
o point and not without misclassifying that's all misclassifying that's so there's a small feasible region that we could find
the support vector machine work is about
making that's solution unique
by adding a quadratic term so that you get a quadratic programming programme with linear
constraints and you look for the maximum margin of separation
now the funny thing about rosenblatt when he specifies this learning rule
is i don't think he's
well i have read the original paper but i think it's just an intuitive learning
rule that you know the usual if you've got something wrong you should look at
the thing you've got wrong and you should add it into your r weight vector
but it still works at least things like hebbian learning
which people use for hopfield networks but they were and hebbian learning is something that
i believe there is some evidence for existing between neurons in the brain so
there's a nice connection there
so regression examples
predict why given x
in the why given x we define an error function now which is
so we have some
in the linear case we say that we've got some function of x which is
gradient plus an offset
and then we might define an error function in a case which is the distance between theorem
data an hour target function
we can add a portion of the air to the bias and what we there also trying to
is adam
uh somebody area to these gradient now this we can do iterative learning these things
by updating the bias and set a very similar way to the perceptron
you get the same so the fact is we select every data point in time we can actually update
a linear regression now you all know that this is the standard way of doing
linear regression but this is a solution
gradient descent version of linear regression so we're updating and actually an underlying error function
now but i think people didn't think about that's so much in the early days
machine learning so
you do it until
you have a solution that fits now of course that's solvable
with a little bit of linear algebra and that's how we'll do it today
but i think in many machine learning those people
we are interested in learning rules
more than they were interested in the objective function
because they want to know how neurons
more updating their own ways
and the course we can go to nonlinear cases
so if the x is not linearly related to why don't we create a feature
space and you've already seen me do this before so hear
we've got a function
x which is equal to the sum in a product between the basis functions and the
i weights and if we apply the same the rules to those weights
we can also do the perceptron so here's a basis
this is a quadratic basis
so it's got three different parts
um and we can sample
from the quadratic basis by
so we can look at
as i was doing in the canopy shimei lecture we can say world for some random values that w
what's the functions can this produced and there are obviously all quadratics
so we sample three random values and w here with sampling
w one which is the offset is point eight seven
w two is minus one point three eight three five and w three is minus two
o point five eight and
these are the basis
and this is the weighted sum of the bases so we've got a
some positive
weight on w one s o point eight seven so
around there
so that's value should be point seven
zero there
we've got a very negative way
linear function so it's slightly negative going down in this way
so you can see that this side of the quadratic is actually lower than this site even though
the axisymmetric
and then we got a negative weight minus two
on the quadratic term so there
quadratic form is showing quite strongly
double what it was in the first one was should be could report something so
that's about point seven or something
so it's been and then it's gone in termite to be lower still
and we can some those three things together we get a function that is non linear
and that's what we think of as the feature space
and not talked about that's
and that's what did so here actually
so in this
you don't
this is an example of this sort of
demonstrate the principle behind if you actually read the XSLT script to automatically convert policy
this policy documents into our hearts to reason over there
so here we have two different kinds of despair sort of search so we have
that led to another trying to succeed
we also have the cost security these are two separate domains that you might want
to model
time for i two
this is a
one question for you
it seems reasonable policy constrict things
so now we try to combine them together
here this is all
this is
i see
with the underlying message the the mapping that we bring over and
so what is this good right this is only a little later in some sense
it's a little data
if we look here
you know the policy you will have to for for the operators anymore so we're
losing it's like you know we're you're looking at here is
this was the
course you find
so these
reading the origin can see all all the good news
but not always completely unconstrained here the all disappears
in two
the intersection of
what's happening because it disappears into the intersection of we can actually do something useful
so for example when i turn on the reason
when learning new things about this
so what i learning
so again because
o five hundred the one
so how right now some fifteen
what is the subject of
some of all
all of the
one of them
all three
he and he said of
so now you simply multiply also inspired by
one more restrictions but still maintaining one of
more specific more interestingly maybe it's getting because we have incoherent policy
so here are defined policy
that is unsatisfiable
which you can do
they played
and all this one one five o sixty four million so nobody needs this also
to test this to find i can do it strictly by
so we get all we know what to buy
but of course processes we can apply different services we have to define policy knowledge
so all forms of all
high pressure was of interest for instance of the class
o can tell us that
one of the whole thing looks
during the disjoint
which we can do
i'm posting here
the problem of these concepts
now all are of
it's actually pretty big deal and the encourages you so one of the things that
you don't have the holes w possible trying to get
the story
is this notion of having more or less general
we're looking at for the
so what
are more like
the war
o four
policy so i can start adding multiple hierarchies
post that
post post
very often described in general terms
so looking at the average
people based on what people see what also or
one of the things i mean this
these two
one of them tries to make our work as if it were xmlschema
right we have a lot more
so the small scheme but i do
in this particular example we are extremely fortunate that there was pretty exact mapping between
the languages for the contract of one very onto the contracts and they were able
to discover
that was
this surface the of
in the policy there's no
there's no sign of the idea that we have made
or five
but generally
one of the more general
there's nothing like that in
we also he's going on to do this work for example to a role
access control
also just
the figuring out what's going on
you a COI
of access control or or four WS policy
we get all the services we offer
all of the data
class iteratively
by the or
two weeks
tom also starred in general all CI phi phi phi on the side of the
more than one of her cigars and these
techniques are our
we know the right people were a huge hole in the very heart of bottles
and then
what are
that's the amazing thing
and to be able to do that mean one of these theories
these are the really
it really truly is nice when you can find actual when just pull the syntax
the whole
it's not going to be able to be sourced
to all of
on the left