all right
and also
she is wrong
so far
there are small
well to
o were
it's a
the expected value of AUC
in that case if i tell you here is the value of accuracy with a
uniform distribution your best answer would probably be well i guess you see is the
but again is lot better
because it was possible rule that point be this one
which as you see is square
the best possible wrong because
the point is this one which has a UC one minus
one of the square one
so again there is some some new relationship but because the we we exploit this
if we have situations like
adaboost seemed to optimize a senior SVM what the montecito we need model specific to
to explain the point and as i mentioned was very nice here which is that
for SVM
so moving into the final which is about relation between
probability estimation
what need help probability s
i like to say that if my probability estimates are not calibrated in some sense
in fact we don't have a problem with this image though we have already
i like to say that space is is not the probability estimate that happens to
have number
zero and one
one day
if you want probabilities you
so that's what we're going to talk about that here
and the reason why you want to write a probability estimate is that you get
your justification differences which are special point four
if you probability estimates are not the right there is no justification for such a
special afternoon session
so what you essentially means is that because i have my model and that's a
report of the predictions of the model that and now i look at the examples
that have particular predicted probability
it was generated by the proportion of
what this
next to correspond
and the fact they should be examples of the problem five
for one classifier expect
as many positive
the next
and actually without going in the world details
basically this proportion of positive to negative is essentially the sole of wrong
so well calibrated classifier which uses it for all the segments
of the ROC curve is the score corresponds to the slope of the second
that means that convex
because this corresponds to increasing along the and then
slopes monotonically
this is a very simple you
because there are many is convex constructed
whole which essentially means introducing ties in the ranking and then we can just read
the probability from the cell cycle
now this is what is wrong with machine
so what this the the machine learning that is easy to pick out the good
news machine learning because
get invented reinvented over and over again this is all the more so
one is not only by itself that is if you already exists under the name
of these regression which why
that by itself to get some fifty to sixty was introduced to machine by charles
the connection
with the royal of was
first of all alex niculescu in the rest of the band which she during the
just beat me to it on honestly the same thing they get because the
one of the things i like to do this if i see something that's against
my opinions then then i'd like to try and evaluate completely my opinions and become
very uncertain the
the way these models bayesian inference will do that but not with most of the
classically constructed model most of the time get more confident as you see data so
that something can be quite wary of and the actual property is the log concavity
of the likelihood if the likelihood is log concave that's going to happen if you've
got in on log concave likelihood you can get this nice effect and for example
robust regression is an example of that is in robust regression if you see a
data points
a lot further away
from where you expect it to be
then you actually increase your uncertainty about what's going on because the like this user
not log concave
so the final example is because there was no election on last night and this
is how left or right wing you are
so on the left wing your voting labour
this is you probably know these parties if you know english middle little americans may
be surprised to see that with the liberal party is in the middle in the
united kingdom and most of europe norway on the left the liberal party and the
conservative party
the observation in this case you think someone is left with but then they say
they voted liberal
and so you observe this medal thing
so you want your opinion they become more right
and again
that's a nongaussian like this you can update it with the gas
i was really hoping that i was going to mention kernels in his talk given
kernel methods in the title
and he wrote the book on it but
he did mention kernel methods so
i'll have to
have introduced a little bit on this respects the kernel method
so the likelihood we have the full regression what we can do is we can
combine it with the prior density of the parameters in this prize just saying we
don't know very very slow
the product is equally likely to be the same size the spherical gaussians prior to
the identity matrix and the covariance independent and based some scale of these parameters that
will eventually affect scalar function now
what i'm not going to show you what you can do this integral
and you recover
because of counting dousing doused in fact
you recover the marginal likelihood for model
is calcium
and you're recovery projections
the elements of this new covariance is zero mean
because your prior over w zero means even though you had to me here
this prior is zero mean and effective that is to make the final marginal likelihood
zero mean that this was independent and this independency but looking here this is not
independent so basically this is the covariance matrix that says what the correlation between different
observations are and in fact it depends on the axis so
elements of this covariance matrix which is giving you the correlations between your also the
training points are given by
this inner product between your basis functions and this is where i hope not
i talked about kernel methods because
we talked about these basis functions as fixed set
if you remember that i was using three
the polynomial all
the RBF squared exponential basis
and then we got some coming from the noise so it's some sort of ten
coming from these some across these basis functions times the scale parameter here
she's giving us the overall size covariance plus some noise
now this is what i would call accounting process but you could also think of
this as the can
this is an inner product in infinite dimensional products and kernels then we wouldn't be
one of the clever tricks you can do
you can replace the inner product with the so-called covariance functions all kernels mercer kernels
which allows you to consider
infinite basis functions that's really fun
because instead of having to choose the number of basis which is one question my
ask how many bases you're going to use you just say i'm going to use
infinity of them
you never have to compute these infinity basis functions because it's an inner product between
two infinite things and you can prove this relationship that's what mercer's theorem allows you
to do
so this is the way of thinking about
the your current account is sum of infinite basis functions computed at
these two different training points
it's the covariance of your training data so the covariance between two different training points
is the evaluation of all these infinite basis functions of those two different training points
the thing about that i think is a bit of mindset change for some machine
learning people is when we so and i emphasise before
noise is i i d
the noise is i i d because there's no crossed dependencies the kronecker delta that
so just to
summarize we've got a distance which is something which is saying i take some elements
and the closer the smaller
and then we got a metric which is what we got
i reduce the five equations into three because they can and you obtain these three
OK so what can we do with strings
that's you know just so codeword would of conclusion pros and cons a distance in
the general sense is more flexible when people are working on applications people are going
to try and find you know things that seem to work that corresponds to what
you what they feel the problem is is that that was mentioning earlier on how
you are choosing the features so that the corresponded to what your intuition of the
problem was
so the same here choosing the distance so that it corresponds to what you want
the same with kernels kernels you often choose because you really think this is sort
of property of the kernel you need for this application should have
but then at the same time if you need algorithmics while you're probably going to
have to have some symmetric somewhere
so if we back to big back to strings we're going to say that there
are four types of distances and that there's only three points no these four types
and this is the first
so we're going to go through four different ways of building distances the first way
is to say well i'm going to try and see how many modifications i need
to go from string x to string why somebody count how many changes how many
individual changes i need to be able to get to transform string x to string
why if you're more interesting trees you can think trees more interesting graphs you can
think graphs on long vectors of numbers that's clearly not offering numbers that's clearly not
indicated but on what we're doing it is
so you're going to try and do this and you might think about normalizing say
yes but i mean obviously if my string is of length several million then i
mean i have to do some changes i would like this to be normalized taking
into account the length of the string
that's the sort of idea and the most typical and the one that i want
to tell you about all of these distances is called the edit distance
but before tell you about the edit distance and you can run through the other
the second one is to say well we're going to be able to compute some
sort of similarity
using another way time looks word about the kernel if you have an answer is
something even looser a similarity between two strings that idea of similarity being
the more things are in common then
then the larger the similarity
and then i'll try and find some way to be able to convert this similarity
between two strings into
a distance
and this leads to methods i know of that can can can do this
so the first method is to do the following is to just take as the
distance between a and b two to the power set minus the similarity in a
of a and b
in this way so the more they similar to minus is going to make it
so we're going to have distances that are really going to be a
of this sort one over two one over four one of the great one of
six in of mathematical made reasons this is OK for practical reasons is not it's
never used romanticising saying it does exist and we relate with some sort of kernels
so typically the people that use the prefixes well i would say well how what's
the length of the longest common prefix of got between two strings we take that
in common we look at the length of this prefix take two
two the powerset minus this length and we obtain the distance
o with just one city located everything is in common then we would say that
things uncommon and then we say d if a if b is equal to zero
which allows us to student to find what want
if you could
if a equals b then div a b would be something like two minus s
of infinity
so about
that's why we're doing it that way but i mean saying is infinite the similarity
being infinite on finite strings doesn't make much it's more like a trick to be
able to do a deal with this which is going to decide that it's simple
you should be saying OK ways the length of the string itself
but so is too but that would make it known not equal to zero
so that's the first method the second method which is the one that is used
more like by kernels i will check this i actually wanted to check it but
the idea is the following do the distance got as well which would be some
sort of kernel
typically the people that use kernels do this sort of way and what they do
is they
well they take the similarity between a and a plus the similarity between b and
b and then you've got to abstract two times similarity between a and b it
symmetrical and if not i just in this way like this
so this is sort of way that is used if you're writing it down put
a question mark because i had to check it on some slides by somebody who
possibly this i didn't check also the conditions about this yes is the x is
equals y and yes this the triangle is the triangular inequality only holds when certain
special conditions over the summer activity held but people for the people that to do
kernels will try and transform the if needed the kernel into a distance
if somebody you can look at that also in an exercise session
so the third way of doing that distances right is to extract some features so
we saw that this morning and to say well we don't want to manipulate strings
tall because what we really know how to manipulate of vectors
so we're going to take these vectors
and we are going to
measures some of the system takes measurable features to decide on the length of the
vector and we're just going to compute this numerical vector for a another numerical vector
for b and then we can use some distance between the many distances many norms
and got over or to the end i worked directly on the vector representation of
the strings so you can think well you know why study westerns if we can
do this the problem is that usually by doing that by choosing this the
the features we to do something about about about the strings themselves
so there are cases where you want what you call the people that are working
on say a natural language processing on translation issues they're going to need long-term dependencies
things like that which are usually going to be lost when we go and extract
thanks for inviting me happy to be here
i'm going to be talking about
general purpose image segmentation
using random walks we've heard a lot about random walks on graphs
over the course of this
the conference
i'm going to be continuing that and
talking about uses force image segmentation specifically
so here is the outline of organ be talking about
first as francisco mentioned i come from siemens corporate search one to give a few
slides but who we are and what we do
then talk about what i mean by general purpose segmentation
and then introduce you to a particular algorithm that have been developing for the last
few years now called the random walker algorithm the going to go through the the
concept the properties of the behaviour of the algorithm the theory
numerics look at some results and then talk about some more recent work
the up of conclusions
SCR are siemens corporate search is located in princeton new jersey USA
we have about two hundred full-time research staff and about
the size of a little bit about
eighty two hundred people
at the phd level working on computer vision
basically siemens we are trying to solve
practical computer vision problems mainly in the area of medical image analysis
are funding models such that we
about one-third of our time and basic research about two-thirds of on actual product development
the goal of clinical imaging of
in computer vision the medical domain is generally do
enhance therapy or provide more information to
radiologists that would be
look otherwise looking at the images
and obviously ultimately to save time and reduce costs
are our core interests basically
fall on the three
major lines the medical imaging community segmentation registration and visualization
we also work on interventional imaging
in which we can put people inside MRI's and tried to help surgeons work in
real time in order to
extract organs and and tumors and things like that
there's a lot of problems here associated with segmentation registration and real time analysis
so that that's who we are it seems copper research and we're always taking
interns and
staff members and if anybody is interested in sending students or or common cells you
know please be in touch
OK so now
my research i'm going to be talking about general purpose segmentation what i mean by
the goal with general purpose segmentation is
simple or sounds simple
important image and output the desired segmentation
obviously the problem is
with this desired segmentation because two different people
two different users may want different objects to be extracted of an image
so from our standpoint sometimes with actually like to provide a general-purpose tool like the
magic wand and photoshop
that allows somebody to
on any given day extract you know
cousin from the photograph put them somewhere else or
especially for product standpoint if we build a segmentation engine to segment say livers and
tomorrow we need to segment kidneys
we'd like to be able to reuse the core segmentation engine and not start from
this problem though of trying to
return the object that a particular individuals looking for
requires some interaction
in other words
if we really have a general purpose segmentation tool
the user has to indicate to the algorithm which object it is they want to
extract or reduce the desired segmentation
and there are basically three approaches for this in the literature there sort of the
which might call classical approach in which all the objects are segmented automatically from the
out from the image
and then a user just go through and select the object that they were interested
another approach is to
provide pieces of boundary of
an object or a nearby boundary in and of all that
boundary to the desired boundary
and that's the approach of
so stakes level sets intelligent scissors
more recently people have used this approach in which
mark some interior parts of the object and some exterior parts of the object and
then allow the the system to generate where the boundaries
this is the approach of graph cuts at the magic wand in photoshop or region
o thing about these atomic methods the ones that automatically segment all the objects in
the image is that
the atoms must be
subset of the true segmentation
if they're not then if the user wants
half of one of the objects that's been segmented they need to come up with
some way of supporting those objects
what they want multiple objects any to come up with ways of merging
the boundary methods have typically been easier to incorporate shape priors and they can be
used to improve the segmentation algorithm
traditionally what's in the literature has been iterative local minima
it's very difficult to initialize boundary methods
in higher dimensions or an abstract spaces
in contrast the seeding methods for
the third kind here
generally leads naturally to steady state and graph based algorithms
and it's easy to see to provide points that are inside and outside and objectivity
in arbitrary dimension
or other
data structures for example if you want to segment the surface mesh or non uniformly
sampled data
some general clustering problem
so it's this third type
seeded methods that we're are going to be looking at
the classic seeded algorithm is is region growing
basically you start one seed and you grow
a measure of distance of contrast
is is meant the nice thing about region growing is that it's
simple to code and it's fast
many millions
practice so many millions and patterns of zeros and non-zeros on the off diagonal the precision matrix
and the nonzero elements across the time varying
we evaluate posterior probabilities approximate posterior probabilities and this is a heat map those probabilities
you can see that a lot of these edges have black very surely there
there's a bit of red and yellow there are few uncertain edges this is probability point to deprive
and the rest is white so they're really not there at all
so this is this is a region of the posterior over the structure of this particular dynamic bayesian model
in terms of sparsity
which is
really finding lots and lots and lots of
model structures
that have the same components
and this graph
is really
and i s wave summarizing
the statistical
probabilistic and the decision implications
office building sparsity into dynamic models in this kind of context it's a nice picture
what we have here is just
two hundred graphs these that
a collection of two hundred high probability graphs
log probability okay so these guys appear really dominant this is a huge there and huge market these are negligible
what we have a here is sparsity in terms of the percentage if you have a quite
i'm sorry the percentage black the number of edges that are in
relative to the total
so these graphs so lived sort in that ten to fifteen percent sparse ranged is a highly sparse graphs
so there's a lot of zeros in the in this precision matrix
this fellow at the back
is down here to about minus two thousand on the log probability scale
it's on the backplane and sparsity that's when you have no no no no no zeros in the precision matrix
that's not a very interesting model structure
this axis shows this risk these models are used in one step forecasting to with the same portfolio utility function
to revise portfolios and see how much money was made
and on this axis we've got risk on the
standard deviation one step ahead portfolios
i risk is bad
i don't like to gamble my own money
if it's in my pension
find i don't like to gambling
low risk is is generally good so low-risk portfolios
have high posterior probability
and tend to be associated with sparse grass
sparsity is good from both the point-of-view
the statistical point of view
i probability
and a piece the decision theory point of view
lower risk okay
the color coding is the fourth dimension
the colour coding
however this period of well we we did an out-of-sample predictive portfolio analysis
o repeat whatever period of time we talk
this shows that the risk the return on the portfolio
for each of these model structures
so red is really good so you see if you don't mind taking a lot
of risk you can make a lot of money with sparse graphs but they don't
tend to be very high probability
there's a lot of red appears so there are a lot of high probability graphs
that that that that make money
that a risk these are interesting model structures
there are also
some graphs appeared that don't make so much money that have high probability it so it's not a given
the posterior probability
is the way to search over model structures if what you want to do is select a model
all select a few models
if part of what you are interested in is is using these models for decision
making then you've got a factor in utility functions as well
and they can be due in different parts of the model space
okay to more check
that's good
that's going on one time
a couple slides and i'm now fast-forward and even more
just to point out a couple of areas based in dynamic model
modeling that are topical in that i know a lot of people are interested in them and working on them
am i find topical
on the sparsity theme
so what we've been talking about there is taking a model structure
whether it's not autoregressive parameter matrix of the precision matrix
a volatility model
or dynamic regression coefficient matrix or something else
anna's dimension explodes
we want constraints and some of those constraints will be saying that's zeros in their
let's find out whether the data doesn't argue against their
well i think that's a good strategy and
we all do it we'll do bayesian model selection and d
use prior distributions that white parameters the zero if if they don't look interesting
but in a dynamic context in a time series context this time as a covariance
you might have a model where you've got a particular set of zeros in the precision matrix
and it's been working fine
but circumstances change
and this is part of the power of language
the syntactic rules are complicated and one of the puzzles of syntactic rules are one
of the big issues of them is that different rules
can conspire to create the same sentence
so you the sentence
why this is the classic white from growth remarks i want to an elephant in
my pajamas
how would got to my pajamas i'll never know
and the humor such that it is
revolves around the ambiguity of of rules are generated like this
first is like this
to illustrate issues of ambiguity people have collected
poorly thought-out headlines in newspaper reports that play on that inadvertently
have ambiguity
complaints about NBA referees growing ugly
universe structure
kids make nutritious snacks
no one was injured in the blast which was attributed to the belief that one
town official
last summer i was in seoul
visiting the visiting korea university and the big headline there on front page was
general arrested for funding private
there actually is
ambiguity is that it is actually quite difficult to avoid
in the construction understanding of sentences
it's one of the one of the ways in which is often difficult to write
and in fact as a whole
subfield of the law
the use of linguistic theory to disambiguates sentences both in
in the constitution
in in in legislation and legislation
as well as in some criminal cases
there was
several years ago very serious
criminal case that rested on the sentence
and here's what happened
there were two brothers one of them retarded
and they get into a robbery
police officer
system and points the gun at the
one of the brothers
points the gun
at the police officer
the police officer shouts from the brother
the non retarded brother
to drop the gun
she said give me the gun
the retarded brother showed
we don't have it
where upon brother shot and killed a police officer
but rather that the shooting was planned murder
what about the brother who show to let them have it
it depends
on what it on on how you interpret that sentence
sentence is beautifully ambiguous
it could mean
should have learned
or it could mean given the gun let them have
and in fact the try which i think somebody could if people that know about
this please send me an email my understanding was he was found guilty
but a lot to turn on the ambiguity of the sentence
i want to shift now
and talk about where
all this knowledge come from
but all stop and answer any questions about material so far what are your questions
syntax and the question is how is syntax different from grammar they're exactly the same
syntax is more technical terms but typical but it means the same thing as ram
yes i'm glad i'm glad you actually asked me about that because as i said
i realized it wasn't quite right
the point i was just raise serious
i've said before everybody neurologically normal comes to acquire
and learn language
but what about people who
are neurologically normal but they don't have language around
and in fact have been historically some cases of this
there's been a probably apocryphal stories about children who are raised by wolves are by
there are stories horrible stories some in some in the twentieth century about children were
locked away
by insane or evil parents
and you never learn to speak
there are stories of deaf people
who are within certain societies were nobody
science to
and so there what's known as linguistic isolates
and they themselves never learn to speak
the probability of the the next variables given the previous one like it always i
can always back to factorize the distribution
in that way that doesn't require any particular properties of this
now i have written
my joint distribution
the product of some one-dimensional
distributions may that's helpful
o point understand
what is it that give rise to particular
form here
but not use this in a constructive way that you construct the joint distribution here
by simply
i simply writing out the terms of support
what with the individual terms look like
the individual terms are just conditional distributions
all single variable given
given previous variables
the conditional distribution
of the joint gaston is again again
the actual rate expression here the joint distribution
the joint distribution again this particular form
then the conditional distribution of x
given y
as this sort of longish only looking expression but it's just it's just come out
so we can actually we can actually write down these things
because they only depend on
that means that the entries in the query
OK let's try and let's try actually do this
OK so so in the those in this but i'm going to try to support
a random realisation of political process
again i'm going to have a one-dimensional input x on this axis and the function
values on the other hand
anyway i'm going to do is i'm going to select xis doing was going select
and then i'm going to talk
what the
distribution of the corresponding function values are given that x and given the previous value
and one start from nothing
he and number to use this one is the part right now there's no there's
function yet but the the function will be drawn in here
and the
so here is going to give me
the area in which is likely to find the function value
the first thing i choose the next random happen to be an here
now just indicate where the x by this red line
now i want to sample
from the conditional distributions
of the function value
given the previous one
which of which there are not not even anything
so i just one sample
values at random
from this skeleton distribution happens to be concentration has done division of one
i think the ninety five percent confidence intervals which is roughly between minus two into
but i know i draw a random sample
from the distribution
so i happened to draw something
i know that my function has to go through the point
so now i move on to the next variables
the next one i happen to choose was over here
now you can see that the
the conditional distribution of of the
the new variable
now conditions on
the other parable
i'd like to change ever-so-slightly
because of the relationship between the two function values through the
correlation which is induced by the covariance
draw random sample of value
i happen to do something
of the random which was larger than the mean
and in the that process
now i notice that
this is actually change the distribution over here right now it's very unlikely that we
get but i'm going to talk about value down here
five because conditional on already having observed the functions
we rather positive function values would be very unlikely to get something which was a
the good the portfolio vector for we'll be banned
i strongly on the priors p
here's the log optimal portfolio vector is characterized as well
john was an arbitrary functions you're of and mine with one variable
and calculate
the conditional expectation of the lottery or b
the portfolio choice
given the parts they played means that x one x two x minus one is
the shorthand notation
so for any function b
let's get qualities is conditional expectation
and search
for the function b
which maximizes the conditional expectation
the conditional expectation q one x one x two x minus one
is a function of x one x two x minus one
so for any function i can probably needs to be a random variable
but for any function it is a random variable depending on the part of the
function b
which maximizes the conditional expectation is the the definition of the start these part the
function which maximizes the conditional expectation
if the market process is independent identically distributed
the conditional expectation is equal to the expectation
he is
OK as get back the original definition of the log optimal portfolio then we we
have to find a big portfolio vector in a big vector which maximizes the expectation
but if we had just stationary market processes that we can do
much better but it is that a random variable is a function we make a
within the
functions of mind one variable
at the start is the function of each maximizes its conditional expectation later on i
will return to the this definition because it it looks great but otherwise people
but the first round it's not so easy to be
why you should be a good idea through
that if it is optimal
but this has been discovered by paul on the phone call over
is that for
and optimality is characterized this
let s start the new
the amount of money at the end of the
and creating video using
b star
or that are
less as and
and every theory
they can be solved
four and very portfolio strategies
and then compare
the average growth rate
of the fire
the other
the average growth rate
here it is not obvious that any of the
the growth rate average growth rate
our coverage
here it that
that if you compare to average growth rate
then we have very
the growth rate of the very portfolio selection
any strategy
the average growth rate
the average growth rate for all around
can be larger
the average growth rate of the other one
if you have a lot of large numbers if if the sequence is an ergodic
it is possible to calculate the best possible average growth rate but is so complicated
we have
i it
it was full of expectation
i couldn't sleep all night
there's the elephant
there is no evidence whatsoever that p of l
really large for the elephant for the mouse
vertical bars indicate
my uncertainty in measurement of thickness
and the horizontal tail which is a logarithmic scale
the uncertainty of the length measurement
it is in the thickness of the red and so there's no
need for me to indicate that and further
and here you have your measurements
in case you want to check
and look again at the mouth and look at the end of
the mouth
as the only
one centimeter length of the femur
and the elephant is indeed on hundred times longer so the first gaining argument
that s is proportional to l
what you expect to live in this about larger in size
but when you go to be over l
you see it's all over
the overall for the model
it's really not all that different from elephant
and you would expect it
with the square root
one hundred thirty were expected to be ten times more
instead of about
the same
and i want to discuss with you
what we call in physics
and that was it
i will ask myself the question
if i drop
and appl
from a certain height
and i changed the height
what will happen with time
forty apple
two full
i dropped the apple from
hi h
i want to know
what happened was the time when i change a ge
so i said to myself well the time it takes must be proportional
the height of the ball for
pretty reasonable if i make the height larger we all know that it's longer forty
i said to myself well if the apple has mass and
probably is also proportional
the massive
i said to myself if something is more mass
probably take less time
so maybe
and some power but i don't know if i don't know better
then i suggest there's also something like gravity is gravitational pull
the gravitational acceleration
so let introduce that two
let's assume
at that time is also proportional
the gravitational acceleration is an acceleration learn a lot more about that
the power government
having said this
we can now do what's called in physics a dimensional and that
on the left
we have time
and if we have left on the left side of time on the right side
we must also have
you cannot have
coconuts on one side and and oranges only other you cannot have seconds on one
and meters per second
sort of dimensions left and and right have to be the same
one of them mention here
that is cheap
that he
it must be the same
the power of
time math
the power data
remember still there on the blackboard
as i mentioned l
abided by times
and the whole thing could have all gone however godlike have gone
this site must have the same dimension
that is non-negotiable physics
OK there we go
there is no and is only one year
so bad must be zero
there is here
well to the power of l the bubblegum others no l year
sewell was this year of
gamma must be zero
people power one year
and there is here to the power miners to go my mind because downstairs
so one
must equal minus
it means grandma
but minus one half
the gamma is minus one
of the world
and my dimension that
i therefore
the time that takes
for an object fall
equal to some constant which i do not know
content has no dimension
i don't know what it is
this there
defined by g
data is zero there is no mass
eight or one half of the that year
and you have a minus one
is proportional
this rare
eight is given and c is given and i don't know c
i make no pretence
i can predict how long it will take forty four
all i'm saying is
i can compare two different heights
i can drop an apple from eight meters
and another one from the leaders
and one from a just will take two times longer
and the one from
two meters
h two
for which we put one right if i drop one of eight metres
another one
and the difference in time will be the square root
of the ratio will be twice as long
and that i want to bring
two test
we have set up here
we have an apple there the height of three metres
we know that q
thanks to an accuracy the hyperbolic three millimeters better
and here we have set up by the apple is about one and a half
metres about above the ground
and we know that toolbar
also in that is no better
so let's set it up
i have here
something that's going to be a prediction
prediction of
the prime
it takes one of the line by the time that it takes
we at all
h one
three metres
but i mean there an uncertainty of about
three millimeters
and any better
and h two
one point five metres
and was going to be
the many
so the ratio it's one of eight two
point zero zero zero
now we have to
that is in response to us
since sit situation or stimulus
and a lot is known about that in the typical textbook on a i
will have
long sections about various modern forms of machine learning
and you can look at those and
i'm sure that those are useful
like before i say anything more
what i want to say is
that i may sound very critical
about these things
how come it in white
but in fact all of these methods
are very useful for certain problems
what we don't know in in general is
for what kind of problem is it good to use statistical inference system
for what kinds of problems
what kinds of problems are ones that can be learned and handled by neural networks
or by genetic algorithms or by
what i'm proposing along with
gerry sussman and how labels and
is to develop a new kind of a i system
it has places in which we can insert all of the useful results that
tens of thousands of a i researchers have made
this hasn't been done because of commercial reasons largely namely
each researcher
find themselves trying to show that
this particular learning algorithm is very general and if it's run long enough on the
big enough machine
we'll do everything you want
and because each person
has the goal of showing that he has the
a great new unified theory of intelligence
it isn't true
well each of these systems have limitations and there's been very little theory
about where they fail
however but if you have
investment capitalists supporting your researcher companies financing it
you feel uncomfortable about say by the way this will work or this will work
for x or y
and so we're having a little trouble
in that area
anyway each of these methods works in certain areas
and my goal is to find a way to combine them all so that we
can get a machine that can do the broad range of things that children can
let's take one example
a lot of people are interested in the idea that if you have a problem
to solve
why not make a
and evolutionary ecology
program a lot of machines to try to solve the problem
maybe have a marketplace where they compete you give them a lot of these little
which eventually replaced by successively more difficult problems
and the
programs that get the solution are allowed to survive and make mutated copies of themselves
and the ones that can solve it are wiped out
that's evolution by darwinian selection
and there's a lot of excitement about that because
many such programs have solve problems that look pretty hard
there are some designed little circuits that were
i used fewer components than anybody expected
for example
well it's evolution a good thing
no it's a very powerful thing and given a hundred million years
it's amazing
and quint billions of individuals
all but a few of whom die horrible deaths
it's remarkably successful
but we cannot usually afford
that kind of time and energy
there's actually something
several things fundamentally weak
about darwinian evolution
one thing is that they don't know what they're doing they don't have goals
so most mutations are bad
and we computationally flat in the visual cortex so this is a region of cortex
around the one first primary for the first station of cortical processing visual information
and you can see here the the activation of course in this class cortical representation
kind of amulet stimulus
and here are the different boundaries between the different visual regions and now we can
zoom into one of these regions and look at the orientation preference of each work
on the flattened cortical surface and you can see that here so the grayscale codes
whether voxel prefers the left or the right of the orientation in which you can
see here is that although
the scale of the orientation encoding and the fmri signals is is quite different is
about a factor of eight to ten
still were able to capture some kind of pattern signal that we can then analyse
using multivariate techniques and one of them is of course a pattern recognition but
in this case is just two times orientations but i mean others have done with
more than two types of orientation from that you can you can increase the number
of orientations with problem and it works quite similar it's just not so easy to
you have to use different color featuring tation
people have done with more more than two orientations but i mean these are it's
important to these aliasing patterns is like an old computer screen where you basically the
screen didn't quite match the display grid by the graphics card and then you have
this kind of more patterns and stuff like that so it's a very similar process
that we're using here
for this kind of sampling patterns you can observe the other cases as well so
we've observed in visual cortex also so here red and blue ridge refer to cases
steve subjects seeing the blue versus red stimulus and you can see again but there
seems to be some kind of information
individual voxels related to that already in early visual cortex so this is the region
of the one again the first processing stage so there's information related to the color
and you can see that carries up into the visual stream so if we go
up the visual stream from the central region here we can still see that we
still get these biases so we get a pattern reliable factor also for colour selectivity
and we also get some robust pattern for i selectivity for example in the we
know on the and that there are layers the monocular layers and if we sample
these monocular layers using the fmri voxels what we can see
is that if we stimulate with the right or left i ultimately what we see
is that these voxels have a preference to either the right or left eye and
what the voxel preferences randomly distributed we can get a handle on all these fine
grained neural topographies
one thing to bear in mind when doing this is that we're seeing this
map through the vascular
chair because as i've shown you on one thing we're measuring nearly measuring vascular signal
it's to do with the oxygenation of the blood so ultimately we have to still
feed this through some kind of model of the vasculature which is going to again
downsample the resolution of the of this map
we might increase the lower spatial frequencies for example another possible source
i showed you this model of kind of by sampling model of how we obtain
information pattern information of these high fine grained topographies there are other sources that might
contribute to such biases for example one hypothesis is the core development the functional and
vascular architecture so the idea is that the vessel followed similar
columns with similar preferences
another is large scale biases for example there are people who claim that some of
these orientation by biases are actually due to large-scale biases like radio tangential effect
visual processing but i mean the key thing to bear in mind here is that
we can get the using these larger fmri voxels
OK so the next i'm going to show you how we can
compare the output of the decoder so what we're trying to do is we're trying
to decode orientation perception using pattern recognition algorithms and comparing that to the perceptual accuracy
of the subject
now the problem here is that of course the decoder the fmri decoder will only
give you a lower bound of the information present in the neural system because ultimately
we down sampling the neural systems seem through very coarse resampling grid so it's not
about the information so if we know this information then we can say that likely
and that's equal to m
they are
which is just
the size of a ge divided by
that completes the proof
so there are other universal constructions but this is a particularly elegant line
OK so the point is that
i have m plus one
so are plus one degrees of freedom where each degree of freedom i have m
but if i want to collide
they once i picked
any of the
what i picked
are those
possible choices for the last one is forced
if i want to climb
so therefore the set of functions which to clyde's
there's only one of them
a very slick
very slick
everybody with me here
delist too many people question
part of it is actually this is a quite common type of thing to be
doing actually if you take class so we're following classes in
and so forth and this kind of thing of taking
dot products modulo m
you know and also get what fields which are are particularly simple finite fields
and things like that people play with these all the time OK
so galaxy also like using exorcist here
so it's the same sort of thing this except these two
OK and so there's a lot of study this sort of thing so people understand
these kinds of properties
but you know it's it's like what's the algorithm four
having a brilliant insight into our site
i wish i know that i just turn the crank i
but for that easy
i would be standing up here today
so now i want try take on another topic which is also i find it
i think this is astounding
it's is beautiful beautiful
mathematics and big impact on
you know your ability to
build good hash functions
now i want to talk about another one topic which is related
which is the topic of
perfect passion
everything we've done so far does expected time performance hashing is good and expected
a perfect hashing addresses the following question suppose that i gave you
a set of keys
i suggest build me a static table
so i can look up
the keys in the table
with the worst case
good worst-case time
so i have a fixed set of keys
it might be something like for example
you know a hundred most common thousand most common words in english
and when i get a word i want to check quickly in this table
OK is that what is the word that i've got one of the most common
words in english
i would like to do that not with expected
performance guarantee worst-case performance
is there a way of building it so that
so that i can find this
the problem given
and he is
static hash table
there's no insertion deletion or come put the elements in there
he calls an
so i don't want it to be a huge table
i want to be a spy
table that is the size of my keys
table of size m equals order and
such that
it takes o one time
the worst case
so there's no place
in the table were going to have
i know in the average case that's not too hard to do
but in the worst case
or make sure that there is no particular spot where
the number of keys piles up to be a large number
OK i in no spot should that happen every single search i do should take
water one time
they shouldn't be any statistical variation
in terms of how long it takes me
to get something
OK so really understand what the puzzle is
this is great because this actually ends up having a lot of things
you know you want to build the table for something
and you know what the values are the company
you don't want to spend lot space on
and so forth
so the idea here is actually going to be to use the two level scheme
the idea is raise it to level
with universal
at both levels
so the idea is we're going to harsh
the hash table and hash into slots rather than using chaining
we have another hashtable there
reduce second-hand
into the second hashtable
and the idea is there when have
do it in such a way that we have no collisions
at level two
may have collisions at level one will take anything that clyde level one and put
them into
hash hashtable
the second level hashtable but that
hashtable no collisions
well we're just gonna
cash right in
OK just go boom to its
was so struck picture this
illustrate schema
so we of
zero one six
because there's the logicians
and there's the statisticians and there's not much in the middle
this is in itself a problem because you the that's the people at the technology
don't care about it
just use bayesian networks and made
do the job
they can do the job to some kinds of problems
who forgetting about the uncertainty is the logic and solve some kinds of problems
you smashing together
one of the things happening at the moment in fact machine learning leading this
there's a field called statistical relational learning cities statistical means that graphical modeling population means
logic part
and learning is putting together
so there's a community this working
in between those two
in fact the the part of the community is really exciting stuff because
you need the logic for knowledge representation
in a dance the probability for handling uncertainty
but in the formalism to put them together in this way
i yes i think i is waxed and waned
there's no doubt that there was
there was the point where many big companies had dozens or scores of people doing
i research this was
in the early eighties
and there was thing called the winter
they didn't deliver died
i think
the future is extremely promising first of all
if you add up all the research that the gained all the AI conferences
from from this the AI conference in machine learning to
national register the
there are thousands and thousands and thousands of feels extremely strong
the second thing is that
what we talk about human level intelligence and all the rest of the
we are very far from the what's actually happening is the technology is getting embedded
in the systems being used
let's take a typical example that was developed in this campus
this technology the traction right
it's going to say the killings of running industry when they
so the traction rising metallurgy
just going off to sleep
it intervene somehow
so that's the vision technology this cameras is watching this is a technology was developed
by vision people think on this campus
other places
people i think about this as being i i that technology embedded into systems there
are lots of examples like systems that
the test when you try and get your credit card
many liberals
answer questions to see whether any credit or whatever else is computed in deciding whether
to give to you
so there's lots and lots of applications like
at the level of
human level intelligence itself it's lovely stuff you can talk about the idea professors against
you can talk about it was a long way off
in terms of practicality
i i was having a big influence
i think
i think the answer is that
i i arrived it's proved to be successful and
most of the interesting applications we want to solve in the future like to be
i kinds of things
so my guess is probably the features
pretty rising
before i get into philosophy
the other thing about i always sits at the intersection
a whole bunch of other fields
in fact if you get to when i are conference specializes conference
you'll see this
people come to this from lots of different directions
and big influence from all of the fields that i mentioned there
i mean obviously
on the one hand i i has
benefited enormously from things i mean
done in other fields
on the other hand
it's made a huge contribution itself and the contributions come from my eyes the computational
many other people
work in these different things for example statisticians
but the statisticians do
so theoretical kinds of things
and they do some calculations but perhaps not a lot
the computer scientist the statistician got together
and what are very heavy computation component
and change statistics the same is true of physics is the field now called computational
is to be experimental and theoretical
this computational
admittedly this is probably not much of so the computational components really important
so if you take this fields for example game theory
thanks very was lively development economist
in the nineteen forties
online and people like that
but the the agents communities brought very heavy computational components that and the using game
theory computational game theory regions
so if you get down like going
i mean the community so i won't get through that almost feels but
and all of those cases
you can see that there are big ingredients that have come from those different fields
and the
artificial intelligence and a few more generally
use those things in the system
well there probably relates back to the BDI
so the practical reasoning
insensitive psychological theory
how humans do
practical reason
well this going backwards and forwards
with mention something else e
this two from eyes looking at i i you can have two different view points
of view
you can either be interested in
building intelligent systems
and getting hints from psychology and other fields
or you can one and how the brain works
so be inspired by the cognitive science
so the psychologist one and how the brain works
benton actually build intelligent systems
the i engineering kind person
most of the intelligence system and it is what the way the brain works OK
OK but there is an it is an interaction between these two
this the computational science psychology because you can have cognitive models
that the computationally driven
somehow model the process the going back in fact all right at the bottom or
by the end of the neuron
in now building
computational models
after thousands of neurons making tens of thousands of low-level creatures
low-level organisms
trying model so the doing computationally so this
in this way the more general case where psi is to say some of l
two like you get grouplasso if you got a bunch of separable groups in on
denoting the group c by
square brackets little g
where g belongs to some index big g
so if the
if the
the the subgroups are disjoint if that if you got non overlapping subvectors then it
is equally easy to
so the shrinking operator explicitly to evaluate it explicitly in the formulas almost identical to
the one i just giving you
OK so it's just as easy and non overlapping group
the last case
moving to matrix unknowns
if you're dealing with the matrix and on fuzzy and if you're shrinking if you're
a regularisation operator is the nuclear norm as the sum of singular values then the
shrinkage operator looks like this
the two norm gets replaced by the frobenius norm
and his you're a regularisation term it turns out this has an explicit solution you
can get
by doing the SVD of like you
sigma the transpose u and v are orthogonal
orthonormal at least and
and sigma is the matrix of the singular values
given that you can operate on
singular values in much the same way as you do in the l one case
now you subtract out times alpha from all of them and cut them off if
they go below zero
and you get modified sigma you plug it back into
multiply by you and the transpose and you get the solution to this problem so
this is not necessarily cheap to compute certainly straightforward but it's not cheap because of
course this operation the SVD can be quite expensive
but you can save some money by
doing some sort of restricted SVD using some iterative approximate SVD
just focusing on the singular values that for which the sigma i minus ten times
it's still going to be positive OK you really don't have to go to the
trouble of computing the sigma rise if you're going to chop them offered zero anyway
so you just focus on the positive ones
so the paper by candes and some collaborators with a
take that sort of approach
so how does generalise what i've been talking about already well very very closely related
to the methods that i talked about in the first part of the talk
you can recover gradient methods for unconstrained optimisation simply by setting the regularizer to zero
then what you get is simply a gradient descent method
it's also related to methods for the constrained problem if i take the regularizer psi
to be the indicator function for these constraints it may indicator function is the thing
that zero on omega infinity everywhere else in if i plug that into the definition
of the shrink operator what i get is the projection operator
OK projection operator of war
the projection of y onto omega is just the vector in america its closest to
y the two norm
then you get exactly that
and so
but really this regularisation setting
in a sense is a generalisation of a couple of things that we've looked at
so far
looked already
i've already mentioned that last so and this was the subject of this morning's tutorial
there was a lot of talk about the constrained version of this name the first
one here
we put you minimize the sum of squares objective subject to a ban on on
the one norm of x and as was mentioned there you can come up with
an equivalent formulation which is the so-called l two l one formulation
we put the sum of squares and the one norm into the same objective and
wipe them off by this thing ten
it's actually kind of hard relate how to t but theoretically you can do that
if you doing grouplasso you replaced the one norm with the sum of groups
i just mentioned it when groups overlap is a technique that cropped up in the
literature in the last few years when groups overlap
one thing you can do is just to replicate variables that appear in different groups
and get get yourself an expanded variable set in which the groups don't overlap anymore
and then you can use these techniques on
compressed sensing is another thing i think there was a short tutorial by candice two
or three years ago in this session where you are
it's the last time a problem but the matrix a has is assumed to have
a very special structure
it's assumed to have this restricted isometry
property and that is that all
a tall thin column submatrix of a
where the number of columns in the matrix some pre-defined quantity
there are assumed to be nearly orthonormal
and it's known that certain random matrices have this property matrices where the elements are
i i d guassian all matrices the random roads from the discrete cosine transformation or
something like that tend to have this property
the algorithm compares a bit different in compressed sensing because there you usually dealing with
you want to know what's the performance costumes music and it turns out you can
bet this at ceylon
and this result tells you
how many times we need to observe certain transitions and observation
in order to have epsilon precision
so don't worry about the
details of the expression but you can use this result to figure out how many
times you need to see
different counts
to get an epsilon optimal solution
in general the answer is a lot of these are really who's found you need
a lot of counts before these things you really get abseil on approximate solutions let
tell you a little bit about how we can make these
a bit more practical in terms of real algorithms for tracking the belief and planning
the first problem
is how do we maintain this belief how do we deal with this mixture
to reach like components
in particular the different possible count vectors
and we
use standard machinery for approximating complex distributions over beliefs
particle filters are really the way to go here
the only thing is we need to figure out how much of these different count
vectors to maintain it's really this is the number of count vectors you need to
maintain that grows exponentially so we're going to limit that decay different count vectors
and if you use a simple monte carlo the ability to perform belief update will
start with a mixture with key components will protect them forward one state according to
action and observation that was see and then we'll pick keep k of those so
we always keep k samples that every time it grows but we always bring it
down to k of them and you just randomly pick up
if you want to be a little bit more sophisticated instead of keeping take a
random keep the k with the highest probability
always a good thing to do it doesn't cost too much to calculate the weight
and to keep that
but since we spent as defined in particular spend so much time working out these
theoretical results
maybe this would be a good place to use of
so what the distance metric does is it says OK
i have my k different count vectors
i project them forward based on a possible action observation
i have a lot more of them but i want to keep only care of
they can
which best fit the posterior
according to the distance metric
we had in theorem one
so all of these different terms of the counts
look at these part are these more than k particles
and pick the ones of them that best span the space
and theorem what we had was the distance metric in terms of different count vector
so we can use that readily here
this is more expensive to compute
not more by the exponential factor there some kind of linear factor but it is
definitely more expensive than any of these
maybe it means we can maintain fewer particles but maybe it gives us much better
remember that here we're using this belief for planning
so it's not a standard particle filter where you really need to keep good density
of you believe you really need to keep the set of beliefs which characterize the
possible things that could happen so that then you can create a good plan
so this is what this does is really characterizes the distribution not necessarily proportional but
it characterizes in way that useful for planning
now that we have a way to do
belief maintenance in the system we also knows need some way to do planning
there's a lot of pompey planning machinery out there has been developed in the last
few years
we use something a little bit simpler which is just similar to receding horizon control
we assume that we do forward search
this is just the forward heuristic search
in the space of beliefs
well when you think believe you have to think physical state and counts
so if i have a certain physical state and initial counts i could do this
then also this observation and they'll take me to this distribution of counts and physical
so this is the forward search in the space of these beliefs
very efficient depending on the branching factor you may not be able to go very
far and in this is often what happens to us
but the belief tracking
approximate method i showed the previous slide can be used to cool off some of
these branches
so this is what we do this hasn't quite made it onto the robot or
the medical devices yet we worked with a very
simplified problem inspired by human robot interaction the idea here is that the robot has
the following individual within some kind of known
discretized environment but it turns out there's two different individuals that the robot can follow
in these individual really differ in terms of their motion model one of them is
graceful able to walk that walk good speed and the other one is more handling
and walking much slower
robot knows two individuals but the robot doesn't have the preset
model of how these people
so the robot simultaneously has to
track this individual without losing track of
learn what is the motion model of this individual also so take actions that are
able to do that
you might not want to learn the model perfectly if it happens that the two
of them move in similar ways that you can aggregate model but somehow do this
simultaneously learning and planning and so the bayesian framework is quite good for this
what i show you here is
the effect of the the choice of belief
belief maintenance approximation algorithm
so what happens if you have the exact model
and you use simple from the planning on this site that bigger problem you can
do that quite readily
and this is the optimal return
now if you take your prior model and don't do any learning
and just plan based on your prior model
this is how well you're going to do
model on
twenty news group data four categories autos models that we have
each taking on what is the document
and in this case politics classes so we know the class location but we don't
have a lot of about classification and we get a reasonable
recovery of the
extra classes based on the clusters
so it's not perfect
which should answer can be
another markets there there is a similar model for this was developed at the same
time the group of john blanton but they instead of using the
marking the location they face model in the truncated stick breaking
the procedure
so slightly different unfortunately it didn't compare it to clean the different approaches
so there are a lot more work also in machine learning community about these
one is again focusing on the issue of determining
automatically determining the right number of clusters in the domain illustrated previously in this example
the gaussian mixture models
and this has been explored the first by congressman who infected this infinite mixture of
in a minute
then this can be extended to infinite mixture of many things like also processes which
was the paper as most money and also in markov networks
the money
in two
so you again
it was not so much the sharing states effect it was small the clustering
one is interested in
and then our own group has
studying the application of this idea to relational modeling so we see later modelling is
sort of a generalisation of a hierarchical bayesian approach and the idea of a relational
modeling is it useful to find the truth for representation of data data structures represented
for example in relational databases
so you want to some of the
the probability of relation between objects
you want to predict attributes of objects sometimes also as discussed by thomas hofmann
tell you much more information about an object then the properties of the objects which
is for example used in ranking algorithms
search engines and we applied to
two to medical domain where you want to predict the
assignment of patients who procedures of patient diagnosis based on primary diagnosis and procedures which
have been described already we've got quite good design so we were most interested in
shown strength suspect that if we have similar patients in the database we because expect
they also tell us something about the procedures and diagnosis for the active
we're trying to predict for that another group
and obama co-workers have tried to use this
as the clustering approach to the clustering effect of these processes to cluster database based
on the relations of the data center again that is not that actually works out
meaningful but maybe relations between objects are more relevant also for determining
think this is a very
and research
in particular
commit combining these relational models
was prominent modelling be quite interesting idea because you have a lot of relations you
can explore and a lot of the prime minister he inherited between the different stations
of the parameters
the basic approach is based on the probabilistic relational model approach that color which showed
translate these data from relational database into probabilistic model
o or already conclusions
so one point is that nonparametric bayes modelling allows for a flexible models
and development
hierarchical modeling effect showing strains between models and also
they have been application is the
clustering idea of them executed being able to automatically determine the correct number of clusters
the most important thing is usually actually a mixture model
we don't observe samples of
itself derived quantities like data
the model
a large set of history on
nonparametric modeling
and statistics and this is something
one can explore further
the only thing conferences
but based on decisions are typically concerned with a low dimensional problems and the challenges
in machine learning sort of to get these things to work also for
for high dimensional problems and that some some problems
the machine learning community and the
o thing
actually i think that the new was the first one two
pay attention to these type of models and that
rasmussen and williams
the money these people develop is infinite mixture models and then and now it's becoming
more and more
i don't think it's become mainstream but the larger group of people interested in this
case they were there was a makers on the last NIPS conference which you can
on the web and which is
a lot of references to different
work in statistics and there's also a good time by so big
money available on the web
which is a little bit
easier to follow
the most comprehensive
there's also a paper
three quarters of introduction to this
the main
so it seems to be the still growing into
businesses going and of course people of a creative develop a lot of
different variations of existing approaches
one big area of research believe
to be able to provide the same thing
which in
many interesting one very difficult to to to mix well
and now
what we what we
OK with
wrong here this be of HIV given
hi h the
the reverse of the of the problem here your h i for about
should here it i even be the
i had about this just happened to be the posterior probability for the parameters for
each model
OK so the same expression as before except that now everywhere conditioning on a
and now
the normalizing constant of the we had four here would just be given a child
which again is called the marginal likelihood or evidence
four four model h i
and what i want to know is i want to know
what is the probability of the different models
my observations
and i use bayes rule against the swap around
the median age was going to be the
marginal likelihood
for each i
now he of HIV one of my prior
over time but maybe that before i start
i actually think that one of the one of the model
there's a lot more likely to be true then the other one
they can rule the other one out maybe the data
really say one then maybe i would change my mind
i can encode
again my my
why prior beliefs using
using the prior year
and the and the and the marginal likelihood here is just the normalizing constant
of the
all the previous stages of inference
and the predictive inference just just the normalizing constant of the likelihood that the part
we're trying to do that an example
OK so
so this is going to be this boring example again we cannot compute everything
now we have two
different models
two different learners
i call them to do to be able to machine learning
the one that i believe that the coin is fair actually not really a very
good morning
just believe that the coin is fair
one of the i believe something to learn something to believe that
all possible that all of that is up i mean one
are are equally plausible
the particular kind of prior belief that the right belief written as the probability distribution
would look like this all about higher equally likely
it turns out that it's convenient to write the prior distribution in terms of of
the probability distribution
turns out that uniform on the interval like this
exactly what don't answer
so beta one one distribution or the distribution are written down expression for beta distribution
was very closely related to the the the and only random variable
so it is the normalizing constant constant here depend on high
it just makes
probability over time integral
one of the problem problem
and then eventually hide some power
minus one where the problem of the distribution
one modified power
so what want to talk rather than b
these distributions can look in various ways it by five
you know any value in in the central area
it is reasonably reasonably
and that values below a o point one or o point nine
quite unlikely
you can also have
you can hear think that that is about o point eight quite like the sort
of things are
so the the the beta distribution here is called the conjugate prior
because it has the same form
that makes analysis
are you
all right
so let's try to make them up
so i made observations i got
may ten observations of b
we had been
and seven tales
now question is what to my to learn what they want to do
there are no it which was really not perfect half again the north central
what about what about one of the
i should like to do is actually work out the
the posterior distribution
i got by multiplying the
which was that beta one one
with the
with with the likelihood
the likelihood here
it's going to be bernoulli likelihood so it's high
the power three
woman by the power set
the product
amounts to saying that k is what people call a reproducing kernel
so you
take the dot product with k between k itself and you can get k
it's the reproducing kernel property and that's why these spaces will be called reproducing kernel
hilbert spaces
so these are some interesting special cases now let's go back to
proving that the dot product
this is something that i'll show you on this slide it's a little bit more
tricky so i wouldn't put this one is an exercise
and it works as follows we first show that this thing is a positive definite
on the set of functions
and then since we know some properties of positive definite kernels
then we can show that is actually
dot product which is a little bit more than a positive definite kernel
OK so
i define a set of functions which looks like this
so linear combinations of kernels sitting on on
some points
o six o
compute this quantity here so i'll take some different functions f five j coefficients gamma
i gamma j i think before when i find positive definite kernels i was using
a different notation
let's just go back
this show is the same
and inequality like this one so substituting the kernel that that have to inequality and
my positions are not common
and we have a situation where
my set x is actually a function space but nothing prevents me from doing that
so my my set x minu ctx x would be this function space don't confuse
with this one
and i'm going to check
this quantity here
so first of all end
very much a laser pointers dying again this quantity here
this angular brackets denote the thing that defined before
this thing here so far we only know it's symmetric by linear form
so i'm going to use this image by linear form
substitute the function five train hit a coefficients gamma i gamma j
i know it's by linear so i can put these coefficients insight into some inside
and then again
i get an expression like this
now this is a certain function that's actually the same function written with different
some summation index or call this function f
and this is this is actually
by linear form evaluated on f and f
now we know
these functions are my set of functions can be expanded in terms of kernels
so i'm going to expand the function f in terms of kernels
expand this function and i'll expand this function
same function were named one of the in this is in the j
and then again
use the linearity of this idea of form
and again this is this
quantity here so
converted this
top thing
into this one here
and this one of course i know is nonnegative because
i'm assuming that k is a positive definite kernel
so from the fact that k is a positive definite kernel it follows that also
this thing here that so far we've got the symmetry by linear form is positive
definite kernel
the only difference being that k is a positive definite kernel on this domain x
this thing is a positive definite kernel
one some function space
in a little bit confusing but actually it's quite elementary
now that's nice but let's go a bit further so now we know it is
symmetric bilinear form and the positive definite kernel
for the product we just need a little bit more we need the fact that
it strictly positive definite so we need to show that if there is a function
when we
take this
symmetric by linear
come up with itself
it gives the value zero then this function has to be identically zero
if we can show that then we know it is strictly positive
and to
to show this we proceed as follows we compute the value of the function at
some point x in square it
next i'm going to use this reproducing property so
the value of the function at some point x can be written as the
these angular brackets of the function with the kernel centered on x
i'm going to do this and the next slide
right f of x is this
the angular brackets thing that i'm not allowed to call the dot product
and because i still have the square next i'm going to use the local she
schwartz inequality that you've proven before
so the question is what inequality gives the way of bonding this quantity here
these records of f with itself
and the facts between the kernel and the kernel
now the back between the kernel and the kernel
again just gives you kernel
this the second problem the second property in this slide can with kernel gives you
so i will do that
to get to kernel here
and now let's step back for a second
what does this show
this shows that whenever
the angular brackets of f with itself
is zero
and the right inside his completely zero then f of x squared is zero
therefore f x is zero
and this is independent of which point x i choose to four points x i
could choose f of x is still
so this means whenever this quantity is zero the function f is identically zero
this means it strictly positive definite so the dot product
so we have now constructed let's just summarize little bit we've
difference with defined and that in the space of functions
we defined the product on this map the dot product has the property that
the kernel corresponds to the dot product between two points mapped into that space
the problem that the dot product
so we are now in a dot product space
and the only thing that's left and we're not going to worry about this is
to complete the space in the corresponding norm
and so each dot product uses on and then you get what's called
hilbert space
and if the reproducing kernel hilbert space so
so this is a particular kind of hilbert spaces the space point evaluation is a
continuous function and can therefore be represented as a dot product
so we'll come back to use this later on this kind of point evaluation expression
now let's go back to this example from before and do the same thing in
the feature space
so now we want to classify points match into the feature space again by computing
distances between a test point
and the mean of the positive class in the middle of the negative class if
we do this and we work it out again so this is the separating hyperplane
this time in the feature space in the properties and kernel hilbert space and if
we work it out terms of this is a nice expression in terms of kernels
the decision function will be
thresholded version of a kernel expansion with kernels sitting on the positive and negative points
and it would be such that here
this thing if k is the density differences and we can think of this as
a thousand windows estimate of the positive class and we can think of this as
possible in estimate of the negative class
so this is the parzen windows classifier based on a plug-in estimates
one thousand windows of the two classes
the support vector machine is
quite similar it's also separating hyperplane is such a feature space
which solves the nonlinear classification problem in the input domain and
depending on what kind of come we use if we turn off the nonlinearity the
decision boundary in the input space will become increasingly nonlinear
so you can see the behaviour is a little bit similar to these behaviors that
you get if you change
regularisation constant some of you who know this kind of work
so far so good
let's talk about some applications
hopefully this will get a little bit more interesting field
so the application that i want to focus on in the next ten minutes or
so is a applications in computer graphics starting with the problem of inferring implicit surface
so here we have a sampling of the surface
surface to typically living in r three and sometimes we have crisp ending so surface
normals and would like to construct a function kernel expansion whose zero level approximates the
surface where the surface is the function is supposed to take the value zero inside
of the object which is delimited by the surface the function should be negative should
be positive
and a number of support vector approaches have been developed for this problem some building
on one class support vector machines some of the building support vector regression and it's
possible to approximate objects with this kind of approach and also to estimate was called
the signed distance function so the sign distance function is a particular such function with
the additional property that the value of f should ever always be equal to the
from the surface multiplied with the minus one if we inside the object
once we have such implicit representations we can do funny things like intersections of objects
and things like that and one can solve such problems also in on fairly large
scale so this is some work of of species and christian walder who has sold
for instance this
approximate this object which is a standard benchmark in computer graphics that has fourteen million
training points and it so that's pretty fast if you also
and he developed a multiscale approach where we don't just have a single scale of
kernel which but you have multiple scales so you can you can do things like
fuels where you don't have the time if you have the skills accordingly and so
so there's another few examples all these things are
with with a grain of salt
hyperplanes in some feature space associated with the company in the input space that look
like this complex objects
now if you try to apply this to videos the first thing that comes to
mind is to take a video and you fit such an implicit surface representation frame
and if you do that you get this kind of solutions
so you see each
picture is reasonable but from picture to picture this and jumps which is because you
do in in each of them separately newtown regularized across time
and if you extend this approach to it for the
you get a solution which is not smooth in time
and which also has some interesting properties in terms of interpolation with christian tried see
deleted some frames in this video
the shown in red so if you see something red there were no training points
and the right thing seen is purely filled in by the system
now one could come up with the idea of trying to use this to interpolate
between different shapes not just the same person at different times but really different shapes
like princes this monkey in this human
but it turns out this doesn't work very well
so the deformation states are pretty ugly and i don't want to claim that the
final human is beautiful but the things in between probably even worse
so we
we try to think of something different and some different approach that more directly tackle