is some
this sequence
x y
of the low-level feature function
what little fj
these low-level feature functions
my often more into it when you talk about sequences the low-level feature functions can
be more intuitive than the
high level feature functions
a lot
well the
i might have for example
i have twenty eight
why i minus one y i
x y
it would be
why i minus one
why are
because zero zero
and text i minus one x y
t h
if my problem my task was hyphenation
and i had this is the low level feature function
so to two consecutive tags is zero zero
number zero means no hyphen
and the two corresponding consecutive letters of t h
so only
this is
an instance of this type of feature functions
and and it satisfies the money
destruction that i'm only referring to two consecutive attacks
what's the summer
by supposing
that this was my low level feature function
and this is my corresponding high-level feature function and this feature function had a on
positive weight what would that be saying
that when you have t h you don't usually
you don't usually hyphenate
yeah i guess you
it just choose the convention does does the zero mean hyphen not allowed before this
letter the zero mean high not allowed after this letter
but if if
by convention is that the attacks refers to the hive and after the latter
zero zero means no hyphen after the t
no hyphen after the h
and you know most
most english words that contain h they don't have a hyphen after the after the
this is the feature function that you expect your training will give you a
the positive weight
for the
the corresponding feature function began
you see when you do this
this is an indicator function is low level feature function is zero one function
but when i summarise
over the
the whole input
then it becomes a real valued
you can
the only restriction is that you can
that you can't look at more than two labels at the time
but i could
for example say
x i minus two
x i minus one
because t h and
you can actually look
because you can look at all of acts
and you can look at two two wise
you could
you could look at my
so you can get anywhere in acts
well you can't do is look at more than two
my tags at the time
so if we work if you think back to the example of multi label
using a log linear model for multi label
the corresponding limitation would be that you can on you can look at anything to
do with the document
but you can't look at correlations between
more than two labels
and here
we can't work
look at work in his an example of something that would not be allowed
after twenty nine
why by exp
why i minus two
why i minus one y y equals
zero one zero
and x i minus two
fits into the definition of the feature function in general
and it's saying just looking at
how many zero one zero sequences are there
but but it's referring to more than two y
two wives and so it's not fitting into this
so but he is he has of his a low-level feature function that would be
very useful
why i minus one
ten thousand megaparsec down to small scales of about a megaparsec today
and everything's consistent with this power spectrum
and the shape of this power spectrum depends upon Omega matter
and using omega matter of point three
is the result that's prefered
now I didn't pick this up in a later lecture just let me show you
things that I won't have time to talk about today
one is the determination of omega baryons of big bang nucleosynthesis and from
W map it's a omega baryon H squared is about point zero two
H squared is one half so Omega baryon
total is about four per cent
I would talk in the dark matter lecture about neutrinos the contribution of neutrinos to
the total energy density
and the age of the universe I'll just mention here
the age of the universe can be determined by white dwarf cooling and nucleo cosmo
chronology and globular cluster evolution
there is a lot of uncertainty but it's consistent with about thirteen billion years and
if H naught is seventy
predicted value of the age of the universe depends upon omega lambda as we
saw from an earlier graph for a flat universe
the age of a flat universe with H naught of seventy is nine point three gigayears
which is smaller than the observed
age of white dwarfs
I think in consistent cosmology you want white dwarfs to be younger than the universe
so this suggests that this model is not correct if you increase the cosmological constant you get an
older universe the age of the universe is also evidence for a cosmological constant or dark energy
so today we had an introduction of a little bit of theory discussing these cosmological parameters
and the power spectrum
and all of these fit together the precision measurements here
the theoretical constructions of power spectre with the consistency of the Standard Model
of lambda CDM and again in this standard model of lambda CDM most of
the universe is cold dark matter and dark energy which will be the subject of the
later lectures
I have this talk of course is available on the Web I have some suggested
that will help you in this introduction and tomorrow I will talk about inflation and
on third Wednesday and Thursday
about dark matter and dark energy thank you I'm happy to answer questions before lunch
yes when did it really become clear that the expansion of the universe
accelerating which was the decisive observation the question is when did it come become clear
that the expansion of the universe is accelerating and what was the decisive observation
now in the last lecture I will qualify little bit the statement that the universe is accelerating what's
observed actually is that the Einstein de Sitter model does not fit the observation
In other words that hot for instance high redshift supernovae are fainter than you would expect
in that model
I don't think
there was any
in hindsight the original evidence in nineteen ninety-eight
was pretty good but it wasn't compelling to me in nineteen ninety-eight I think it is
Over the years in the past ten years not by any one eureka observation
saying that this really proves it but a series of many observations that give the consistency
to this picture
the lambda CDM model fits in
again it's not just supernovae it's age of the universe structure formation and I'll talk
later about baryon acoustic oscillations weak lensing all of these different methods
With different uncertainties arrive at the same result so it's not any one observation
it's a series of observati different types of observation that's all consistent with this cosmological
standard model so
for the first six thousand years of cosmology theory was held of ahead of observation that they
had many more theories than we could exp
test by observation and for the first time in the last six thousand years perhaps
OK can you hear me
it is better to check all this
poster art equipment it's
so much so many cables so many
o devices OK
now before going on with the genetic algorithms and genetic programming
a bit of illustration of this
now in
discussing search and optimisation
it's often
described as searching to certain areas and usually use examples of test functions defined certain
surfaces and here is one example of searching for a minimum of these
so what
i hope you can see this is
certain shape and at certain points
this is the starting population it's not important now what technique use its
as we can see
they are
slowly converging to a certain point
the idea is to
read the value of zero here
this is actually the lowest point in this
and as you can see
the points for the this population is exploring the space and converging to this value
this is actually performed by genetic algorithms that use
explain now this is just to show
one property of stochastic algorithms related to the question we had before
how do we set certain values of the algorithm
one specific value set to this algorithm is the number of
o points or the number of individuals that perform search
it was set to nineteen
in this case so if i
let's say two
fifty or forty nine
OK fifty one it's not important we help
and another and
initial configuration now
if i ran it again
what do we see
it was
they they approach the optimal point foster they didn't didn't they
so it's
you see this is one
question how to set
the population size
we saw that it was less
that's a iterations but it's again higher number of individuals so
this is rather quick here because this is a test function that is
well specified analytically
the evaluation of the single solution is done very quickly
now you can imagine more difficult problem
if you were optimizing something
and it requires the computational processes that is not trivial it may take
i mean it's ours
evaluating solution would take that much time and it is then very important how to
for the two
converges quickly as possible will come to one such a practical example later
and the other
o thing to be illustrated here is the following
this landscape is rather
as you can see we can turn it around a bit now if we go
to the more complicated functions
like this one
this is
a good example of what we called multimodality at the beginning of this lecture that
is a lot of local optima so this is really specially tailored function
with many
well misleading areas and if we
position it like here
we can see that there is a really
the global minimum is at this point again the value zero
so if we
formal transition in this case i would start with a smaller population again a sixteen
individuals or maybe
twenty twenty one
OK they go into the twenty so if we turn this around
we can see that there are playing
around that global optimum but it takes some time to reach it
OK something is happening here
and this is mentioned again reach
but these goes rather slowly
if i
increase the population size
let's say a
sixty nine in this case
we start
that whole cluster and
you can see that these very
global minimum with a value of zero
is approached foster again
OK let's stop it
the next family of
algorithms this is genetic algorithms genetic algorithms are
another representative of evolutionary algorithms may be the most popular
one they were proposed or developed by john holland from the university of michigan in
nineteen seventies
and as
we are a bit familiar evolution strategy we can
described genetic algorithms
in the way they differ from evolution strategies so the most remarkable differences that they
usually use a stream based representation of solutions so it's not
not always but the the initial approach was to use thing based representation usually binary
these encoding or this representation is again motivated biologically this is done after the war
meant to resemble the discrete
nucleotide coding that we know from genetics
so in this case
again what other operators mutation is
flipping bits with certain probability
and the recombination is performed by an operator called cross-over
you can imagine that if a string let's binary string enclose your solution it may
the cosmoillogical constant so it's illogical for two reasons one is the magnitude of
the cosmoillogical constant and you can think about contributions to the vacuum energy and contributions
to the vacuum energy that you might imagine includes the zero point  energy of quantum
fields all fields are harmonic oscillators with the zero point  energy so in field theory
you can calculate the energy density of the vacuum you sum over all particles and
it's plus or minus  depending upon whether it is a boson or a fermion and you just
integrate over over a phase space of the integrate the energy over phase space now
what you find of course is that if you don't have a cut-off the
answer is infinite but relax it's field theory as we know from graduate school if
you do not get infinity in the field theory calculation you haven't done the problem
right so you introduce a cut-off and you introduce some cut-off here and you
say the momentums cut-off  at the in the ultraviolet  and what cut-off might you put
you might put the plont mass saying well we don't understand field theory in the presence
of quantum gravity and if you do this you get ten to the hundred and twelve electron volts
to the fourth the answer that you wanna get is ten to the minus
sixteen electron volts to the fourth so you're off  this is the worst pre
worst  calculation in history of being wrong so you might say aha you
might invent a symmetry some crazy symmetry that would cancel between fermions and bosons
and this crazy symmetry of course is supersymmetry but supersymmetry is not exact supersymmetry must be
blo broken  so you might put in the supersymmetry breaking scale in here you have improved
the calculation by sixty something orders of magnitude but you still have another  sixty orders
of magnitude to go so we get you  halfway there in the logarithmic  sense
but that's not the complete answer either so that's one of the reasons it's
the cosmoillogical constant you can imagine contributions from zero point energy but they're just enormous
you can  also imagine another contribution from spontaneous symmetry breaking energy of the vacuum we
know in QCD in the electroweak theory the vacuum is a complicated object and there should
be contributions to the vacuum energy from gut susybr from gut symmetry breaking
ten to the hundred electron volts to the fourth susy  symmetry breaking electroweak symmetry breaking chiral
symmetry breaking all of these are just enormous compared to the value that we
need there's also  something that's rather odd that's the illogical timing this is a graph
of various contributions to omega from matter and radiation and the cosmological constant so if
we were astronomers in the far distant past we would not be able to deduce
the existence of a cosmological constant because the matter in radiation energy density grows if
you go back to earlier time and the vacuum energy does not so it would have
been very dominant and in the far distant future lambda will dominate and  matter in radiation
will be in will be insignificant isn't it a convenient time to be an astronomer
it's the best of times because we're right now there where we can determine both
of those and when I go to Washington I tell the politicians that we have
to do astronomy now because in the future the these things we observe are expanding away
from us we're not going to see them in the far distant future it's compelling
to do it now that doesn't work  now so the evidence for dark energy
is more than just the Hubble diagram  for every astronomical measurement there are uncertainties
they're  observations they're not experiments and I think there's this sort of a difference between an
observation and an experiment in an observation you just see what comes in an experiment you
can go in and change triggers you can put your apparatus in a test beam you
know you you have more control over what you measure than just observations so there
are always systematic astronomical uncertainties that we're just not going to get around so it's
important to have other information I won't talk about cosmic subtraction I did that in
the first lecture that's indirect evidence today in a little while I'll talk about other
emerging techniques baryon acoustic oscillations weak lensing galaxy clusters I won't talk about the
information from the age of the universe but in the first lecture I showed that
in order to fit the observed age of the universe it fits with the cosmological
constant in this model and not without and also structure formation  comparing the simulations
to the observations require a cosmological constant so let's step back a minute and ask how do
we know dark energy exists I often hear my colleagues say we know that there
is dark energy and whenever I hear a scientist use the word know I get sort of
itchy I I don't think that we should ever do that I know we
shouldn't so he here's the argument about how we know there is dark energy
we assume a model cosmology the Friedmann Lemaitre Robertson Walker model leading to the Friedmann
equation we assume an energy and pressure content of the universe and then we input or
integrate over cosmological parameters we can calculate the observables luminosity distance angular diameter distance
expansion rate as a function of redshift everything is fine so far then someone had the
crazy idea to compare with observations when this was done it was discovered that this
model cosmology fits with a cosmological constant but not without so it is important to
keep in the back of your mind that all evidence for dark energy is indirect
the only effect of dark energy is on the expansion rate of the universe and
what is observed is that the expansion rate of the universe is not described by
that calculated from the Einstein-de Sitter model again the spatially flat matter dominated model
let me ask you something yes dark energy is behind the expansion rate behind the expansion of the universe itself I ask so the the  universe is the
universe is expanding and the it's in the Friedmann Robertson Walker cosmology the expansion
the one over our
is an obvious thing is a consequence of the conservation of energy
because the poynting vector
is proportional
to e square and because it proportional to e crosby
for the poynting vector is proportional to its great
so imagine now that you have a sphere with radius r
you want to know all the energy that flows through that sphere we have to
integrate over the entire sphere
but if you double the radius the surface area of that sphere goes up by
a factor of four
so the only way to energy can be conserved at the same energy flows through
this small small sphere then flows with large sphere is
that the electric field dark
by a factor of two
so that the poynting vector goes down by a factor for the surface area increases
by a factor of four
the poynting vector goes down by a factor of four because e
goes down
by a factor of two
we have here an eighty megahertz
transmitter we've seen that before
wavelength three point seven five meters
and i demonstrated before show you that the radiation
is linearly polarized
and i demonstrated by having this receiving antenna
and by rotating it like this when the lights went off and wrote it like
this when the light goes on today
that's not my objective
today i'm interested in the sign square stayed room
for which i need a little bit of assistance from someone
so i want someone to hold this year
and will see that the light will be on and then i will rotate to
so that the angle of theta
if i have a year i have maximum because the city did the charges
i say accelerated in this direction
so this angle estate on ninety degrees that's optimal
the state is zero
ninety degrees that optimum
but the moment you rotated ninety degrees or that you wrote this ninety degree
then it
zero and that's
exactly what i want to demonstrate
so i need assistance can you help me
material here if you don't get electrocuted
OK so you have the choice
all of the above your head
OK now you see the light is on
and so now
this is the direction of acceleration and i'm going to want the direction of acceleration
towards you
if the exoneration is like this there's no radiation going in this direction and that
light will go on the
very slowly and carefully already deming
so any dimming
now we now get back what goes on that goes on so that
become a little closer than the light is a little brighter more
although the little further down a little down
that's one of the once more
i think the angle theta going down and out and
good luck you survive this one some students don't
so this was very qualitatively
to show you the fact
of the sign
it's quesada relationship
in order to calculate the total power
that is
produced by the
total power in the electromagnetic wave that is produced by the
oscillating charge
you will have to integrate this poynting vector over one complete sphere
which is not the total trivial integral because the the poynting vector changes was signed
square theta
so i'll leave you with that exercise
but i will give you the results which is not so surprising at least it
is not surprising that
the quantities that you will see
and most of you see this part of the record
so that would be better there
well i can raise some
the re some here
so this is now
integration of the poynting vector over complete sphere i put around the charge
and the result then is that
the power which is no longer well prescribe metre per second but is simply now
in what
how many
energy flows per second through sphere
and that now becomes q squared
it's no surprise because
q is in a in the vector in q waiting to be vector so you
get a q square
you got a script you know surprise because the age is in the b and
a is in the
and then you get this divided by six by
actually non-zero
and i think it's safe to power
but you see my hesitation
finally arrived at c square
it really is he to to power three sort of downstairs is not squared with
c to the power three
sorry for that
so this is the famous larmor result
it takes energy
to accelerate single charts in vacuum
and i'm not talking here about kinetic energy in terms of one half MV squared
but i'm talking here about the creation
of electromagnetic fields due to the motion
of the
now comes the question how do we accelerate charges
and i thought about that for a few days how i was going to tell
you that
and that i have to give you a little bit embarrassing
and and that is
we accelerate charges by exposing them to electromagnetic radiation
and then you say well is in this catch twenty two
because you have to accelerate to create electromagnetic radiation how do you accelerating well you
have to create after exposure to electromagnetic radiation
for whatever that's worth
cause there is electromagnetic radiation
that comes out of all kinds of sources
and so
i'll show you now
that if we take
the electromagnetic wave with a convenient polarized travelling wave
it would have been surprising up to
my name is story great though i'm working for microsoft research in cambridge
and a couple of years ago
we started in the group there which involves the combination of machine learning and games
originally the group was designed to deal primarily with computer games
you know microsoft is engaged in the in the computer games market through flight simulator
in PC games as well as x-box games that when i care came to the
group we also started this other interests which is in
general games and in particular in board games
so that's basically we're coming from
and so i'll talk about various at aspects of machine learning and games
in fact you will not find very much material in the little booklet that you
have because
i just recently prepared a lot of stuff
there's a very close relation between games and learning which i would like to point
out to to start with
of course people play a lot of games in order to learn stuff in particular
children and you can also see it in the animal kingdom that the first basic
skills learned by playing if you think about it
most humans play for the first ten years of their lives if they are fortunate
they play for another ten
if they started they place
possibly for another ten
and so we will never stop playing maybe not such a bad thing
so another aspect that some of you may have experiences that in order to master
certain games that have developed over the centuries or in recent years you have to
put in the lot of effort and you have to learn the game so there's
another relation there
another interesting aspect is of course that games are not just arbitrary sets of rules
but what they usually constitute a little simulations of aspects of the game of the
world so if you look at children's games you will always see you know if
they try to catch each other that has hunting aspects to it if if they
play simple games then usually there some kind of element of
of spatial reasoning involved and there is in general this aspect of competition which often
turns out to be quite important in life so
the key idea here is that games are not arbitrary games are related to reality
and that's makes the last point quite important we can study games and behavior in
games and thereby learn about a lot about the real world but the nice thing
is if we study these aspects in games then we can
abstract them in no way
away from the world we can ignore certain problems that we would encounter in real
world learning and focus on the problems we've seen examples of that one thing for
example is
if you compare real world robotics
the construction of robots or bots in games in real world robotics you have all
the mess with the sensors and the signal processing and the noise while in games
you can just focus on sensor readings that essentially come from your memory come from
the simulation
and thereby
you have data available that you would never have available in this form in real
world robotics that makes it easier
to treat the problem in the simulation in the game
but the hope is that you could still enough of the properties carry over to
the real world and so maybe we first solve the problem of simulate simulating good
behaviour in games than that may carry over to
to real robotics for example
so here's the structure for the course
i start with a general introduction to machine learning in video games because that's one
of the primary areas were working and i think that's a very interesting direction for
future research because there's appears to be a lot of potential when i was preparing
these lectures sitting
more and more things were we're machine learning could usefully be applied to computer games
and i think this is really sort of growing market that could be of interest
for many of you
in the subsequent three lectures i more into specific ideas and projects
so on tuesday i'll be talking about bayesian ranking system that we developed another essentially
trying to view the spirit of bayesian inference first using some simple examples
and and then talk about
the problem of ranking and matchmaking in games such as chess or in online computer
games on wednesday i'll talk about the application of reinforcement learning to various games it
turns out that games are you know way i mean maybe some people would wouldn't
allow me to say but i know the only successful application of reinforcement learning i
mean there been others but it's really been successful primarily in games and really only
in very few games so we're talking about those and others
and finally on thursday i would like to take the opportunity and
let you give you a lesson in in the ancient chinese or
later japanese game of go
so we will kind split the session into two and during the first hour i
would like to encourage you to to try out to play the game of go
or if you already know it may be held few others to pick up the
the addition of a second speaker is where a change on decision tree and instance
based learning for label ranking
OK i hello everybody
and i'm here now talking about different kind of learning problem
and then we
i want to use is local learning approach to solve label ranking problem
i will talk about how to use this century
and extend this learning from a ranking
OK and this is a joint work with my colleague is here and my advisor
i can feel my
OK let's get started so consider you have cost or new
selling different types of cost
you have different customers and the different customer we have different preferences different type of
obviously that
if you have a new customer you like to know that what is his preference
this different types of cars
so here the output is a ranking
it's not like classification which we are only interested in the top
but the interesting total ranking
sometimes it's more convenient to present this problem
in terms of computation
this label ranking problem
can be found in this way
OK we have a set of training instances
and a set of predefined finite
the set of labels
and for each training instance
however set of pairwise preference that tells you which enables better than which later
then the goal of this problem is
we want to find a ranking function
which is the mapping from this feature space
to the right space that can maps each
it turns to ranking
of the labels
and of course
we like to generalize well in terms of pre-defined loss function on rankings
OK with this talk we concentrate ourselves skeletal disorders
and this is a rather interesting problem
and there already work on this problem
so here is a list of representative approaches
and i want to go into details to of these metals
i want to say is that
all this might also works so the performance of comparable
so far we all the three
apologies reduces
they were problem to classification
this is
quite efficient
but may have some problems for example
becomes always lost information due to his transformation
most of the models most of these approaches
has some holes from model assumptions
so does come along with
so let's by OK
due this bias
the lack of flexibility
and last but not least that
most of the parties of black box OK
the what is black also sometimes have problems to in presence
o say
all right
today i want to talk about you the local approach to solving this problem
o talk about the mislabeled
and as well as the dissident report which
we don't create a global model
instead of that the target function
it's estimated a local way
because we only consider a local region
so we can assume that the distribution of the ranking that region
o is constant
the problem is how do you estimate is locally constant model
so to be more precise
and we consider the all the ranking
instances generated
according to an underlying distribution
and this distribution is at least a possibility
constant within the local region
so other preference nearby
also generated by the same distribution
so basically we can just using the principle of the muscle like principle to solve
this problem
i said the there is the probability distribution over entries
what should this distribution look like
OK so here i would be more explicitly that to show this one particular way
to model the distributions
here we use the so-called models model
that's right
the main page
then to describe this one
is one
so much is
we will
and we have probabilities
so if there was a spot would have been
great white
and was low amateur might also in this section
to describe
well i think
and actually this club
the most
the text image retrieval
so here we all edges
four has made
i am
it turns out
some kind of the cosine derive
of complex fluid and
and the end of the first
so this is
and i
on the this
all possible steps to future the kids disease
i guess you were going to try to describe the time so it
talk about the most well-known one actually
she popular which killed
about ten years
but the
and many others system
but recent research shows that
to show that
pictures like there's actually no more than one of the most popular ones
and i don't have a little bit about
so called
i have a chance
and we'll start
to do this
it's also
like something from the discrimination texture
as a
i just don't know this because the
so we we can quickly
the people can quickly
the first moment
just or or the whole image or
many of the image
depends on which part of
and the
quite well
well then the whole
so for example one
o thing
equal whereas
when it
when all in the lead
people to each other
well you because it anywhere
in the
for many use
the clothes are one
histogram i
they tend to level equally distributed according to a lot of
so what
this is because
just to to remind you
one hundred search
and now
one the
that's parameters like average level
all that she
quite different from the previous section
also in you
and you can the really
exchange is very close to
and then have a lot of changes before that station
is a little bit bigger
and they all
i was
this was done
so this don't
so i'm just going completed texture
factor of three and so you gain factor three in light of course you gain
factor three three times more sources you get three times more likely to see there's
violation of the conservation of energy here
and i want to demonstrate
this to you using a red laser which we have used before
and i will use
what we call a grading
grading is a
plate which is specially prepared to transparent plate which has grooves in it
and the one that i will use has twice twenty five hundred
grooves we call them lines
per image
that means the separation the
between two adjacent groups
in my case is about two point one six microns micron
ten to the minus six meters
and the wavelength that i'm going to use these are red laser
which is about six point three
times ten to the minus seven meters
and i'm going to
but the whole thing they're going to make you see the edit distance l
which is about ten metres
so there's a lot of me now
to calculate
where zero order fall where the first order and second order will fall
we call
when n is zero
recall that zero order
so this is zero order
when n is one we call that first order
and when n is two
recall that second order
and you have of course the first order also on this site and the second
order also on this side everything that you have here you have to also think
of it as being on the other side
so i can predict now we had a zero order will be
when n is zero
that is zero degrees
that immediately obvious i use that equation if ten is zero
the zero order is always right at the center
provided that all the sources are in phase
and there will be in phase because they use plane waves
so hogan's will tell you that they're going to oscillate exactly at the same time
they produce the same frequency they produce the same wavelength and they're all in phase
with each other so maximum one equals zero then there will be a maximum which
i calculated to be three point five five degrees
i calculated from this equation
and then stayed at two will be roughly
seven point one degree
if you want to know
how whites the width of this peak is going to be
then you have to know how many lines of migrating i will be using
it's like so
you i have these lines
not unlike degrading the you have new optics kit
there are twenty five hundred of those lines per inch
and my laser beam is roughly two millimeters in size
but this is about two millimeters
that tells me then that cover about two hundred lines
and if i have two hundred lines
i can now calculate
how white line is going to be
because this factor of and enters into which here
and if i
expressed in terms of that angle delta theta
then the angle delta theta
going back here
so delta theta
is that the three point five five degrees divided by three hundred
that's an extremely small angle
that angle
it is approximately one
arc minutes
which is sixty times smaller than one degree
and if you want to translate that in terms of
how whites that spot will be
if i see it on the screen
ten meters away from the and if you want to call that delta x
you wouldn't even to predict
the delta x
is something like three millimeters
and the reason why i say naively
because you will not see that three millimeters it will be extremely narrow but it
will be more than three millimeters because the limiting factor is always the divergence of
a laser beam
so the divergence of my laser beam is more
then one argument so i don't get down to the
what i mean it
narrow beam
i'm not too far away from it though
so this is what i want to show you first
i will turn on the laser first
and then make it very dark because we do need
darkness so this has to come off
that would obviously
well i two and of the wrong laser with an expert on the wrong that's
OK that's the second demonstration which i do is with a green laser this is
the one that i need
this is the red laser will come on very quickly
that is
if you could turn that off maybe that will help although everyone can see that
would help
so you see here very clearly
zero order is that the that right in the middle
this one's to is zero
and if they don't want my three and half degrees is also three and half
degrees this is the seven point one degrees and so on
so you see his whole
kind of
the fraction
for interference as a result of multiple
so it so this is a these groups
in a piece of plastics
notice how small the whole never they are compared with the double slit interference so
they don't have that
theoretical minimum with this one over and that the approach that
and the reason why they are not that narrow is because the divergence of the
laser beam itself is larger than that one argument that calculated
so you can never be that of course
we did this experiment was white with red lights
but keep in mind
if i take red light
here is the maximum zero order
here is the maximum
provided islam is islam therefore red
here's the maximum provided that the land for red
but if i white light
then of course i deal with other colors
and if i have blue lights in my white light it will also have the
maximum here
that's non-negotiable but has its first order maximum because the wavelength is shorter and the
second order maximum year
this will be the same distance
so when you do this was white light
you're going to see always zero order white light because all the columns of the
maximum at zero order but at first and second high orders
so actually
the it's school also
we like
and if you find the directions perpendicular
two hyper
and the
called by
well the value
that's how
well to be alive
two this line
so our problem so
so we can this that this function satisfies the point
the flying high
and we can also find the perpendicular from the height to
the five live you know
so they need it had this
we can actually also
we can apply to find this
this morning
from the hyperplane the support vectors of the positive examples
and also this
the support vectors of the negative examples
but let's look at
and the hypothesis
very well put it is that the wrong
so i thought i'd post the
the class is lot
thirty five creation w excitement he
i creator of cluster
o five
w x i this is more than
which we can combine in one quite
and here i have always
i can't find what i mean
classification model
but now to
to find out
this time
the last one
so this model
of high level
the hyperplane that defines one more
it is defined by
w x i b it's one
and we can also find the perpendicular distance from the the origin
one might
divided by p that
and similarly for how to find out more
the final w x y mind one and we have also the perpendicular distance from
the the origin minus minus one my behind by
so if you have
if we had
this type of data
i many you
to the origin and also the
this model to the ontology
we can
the distance
of the margin
which is
well defined by you that so actually wants to maximize
why do you
this is considered to be innovation we actually minimising the role of of dutch
subject to the
three the equality constraints
which is
this is going to compute
five of the nine to find the minimum value
and the
the dual representation
is obtained by introducing lagrange multipliers lambda
which is easy to solve
so we have to maximize which includes things like
the flyers
which are lot of the year
and when multiplied with the class labels
of the training examples and training examples such
now i think about how
come to this
two representations
i just want to show you
that's used in training
that you want to maximize
we've got what
so what examples and training examples
and you see in this country the inner product
so the
we take for each there examples this problem and this will come back later when
you look at the kernel method
so when we
maximize the real thing actually the decision function
the decision function is used to classify
OK as you can see i have changed the style of my slides that's rather
considers because there's some material that is joint work with julian gold and ralf herbrich
at microsoft research and so this is an application of reinforcement learning to a computer
and it turns out that carry some
extra difficulties because some of the notions of reinforcement learning are not as easily transferred
to computer games and there are also a lot of technical difficulties in
in implementing something into an existing computer games because the code can be quite messy
i give it a shot motivation and then explain how the algorithm works
and then i'll give you some results for some visual results and
then some numerical results and in particular address some implementation issues that arise if you
don't happen to have a beautiful
the simulated model about having messy code base of an existing computer game to work
let's just remember
this painful experience the right character there had when i was just using this gap
in the finite state machine that drives that and showed this very flexible behaviour
so that's something that's highly undesirable and of course we would hope that an adaptive
agent would be able to avoid such behavior
well i'm not saying that this work solves the problem but this work was an
attempt to solve the problem and we've learned a few lessons
we have discussed these problems that the policy of the policy of the non-playing characters
fixed development time it consists of a huge rule set
they call it the finite state machine that is really a bunch of if then
statements that are very messy and and therefore hard to expand or maintain
and of course it would be nice to have adaptive an emergent behavior which is
hardly shown by this kind of system
to put this in a very blunt way and in
traditionally i
used in in this kind of games the developer says exactly what it once the
non-player character to do
and the dream of using machine learning is really to give the tool to the
game designer
and that game designer would then
learning algorithm what he wants the non-playing character to achieve certain kinds of behavior and
then the learning algorithm will learn how to do that introduced the actions
now here's the set up that we have with an agent and the game and
reinforcement learning so we learning algorithm the game since the game state to the learning
algorithm and to the agent
the agent then takes an action which
gets goes into the game as well as the learning algorithm
and in this case now the game gives some kind of reward or punishment
two of the learning algorithm
and from that the learning algorithm generates the parameter update that then influences the policy
of the agent
so that's the theory but of course it's not so easy to represent the game
and in fact you can only present an abstracted version of the game state and
that's partly where the problems lie
which effectively makes this
this problem a partially observed
markov decision process rather than a fully observed one we have the state description and
we see it but it doesn't fully cold the actual state
we consider two look two different learning algorithms q learning and the learning algorithm sarsa
and the i don't know in how far dog has cover
either of these both of these
can anyone tell me with anyone at the lecture
he mentioned both the
so let's just take another look at these
so this is the update equation for both of them if you like so we
have that
this q table and we
take the old q value
and adds a small fraction times something new to it and this something new is
the reward
class gamma time some function of the subsequent
q value minus the old q value
and just to get the terminology right again
so q represents this state action value alpha is the learning rate here
a is the actual
hours the rewards
this is the current state here
as prime is the state is subsequent state and gamma is the discount factor for
future rewards
these two learning algorithms q learning and sarsa only differ in what this particular term
here is
and in q learning that is
the best is the is the state action value
in the subsequent state given the best action you could take in that state
and in end this doesn't depend on the policy of currently running and therefore it's
called an off policy method
now in countries such as
in science this quantity
is the q value
often the subsequent state again
also with the
actual next action that you're taking so you it's the best one
and here's the actual one take
that makes quite a difference
in this particular problem we use a source
because in q learning UCF to perform this maximization here and in order to do
that you would have to know which actions you had available at that point in
time now it so happens that in messy computer games it's not entirely clear which
action constitutes a legal action at a given point in time and
what happens in the code in this particular game was that you had to submit
action and the code would check if that action was actually you could actually be
used and thereby change its state
use it if it could and rejected if it couldn't so we couldn't explicitly perform
this thing so that's why we chose stars where we could just observe which next
actually were then eventually allowed to take and therefore could evaluate this quantity and therefore
do this update here
now it's
of matrices so this is something we want
we would
and that property would be true all right for this from the sky
because it
it's it's just we're just a matrix
stretching it along vector so it's so far frobenius it's the same as the triangle
inequality for this and squared length vector
we could look what i don't discovered that i was going to say about determinants
one just before i got want to kill off determinants
in this sense that the determinant of a plus b like we
it could be sort of almost anything
so OK so let me follow you thought
and now tell me more
how do i look at what he does to a vector
i get another vector
which has no that's right so we're going to create normal of the matrix
out of
that decision on
so how should we do if we take a vector
you know its length
and what do we do we
we multiply by a
and we know the line
so in link to this
and i know the length of the original
so what do i do
come up with the size of a service
five divided by this
what if i if i look at this
so that these are both factors so we know what links that are
so take any vector x
i have multiplied by and i looked to see OK to grow
and this ratio will be
growth rate you right
i could normalized to say well it take unit vectors
i wouldn't have to divide by the one but either way it doesn't matter how
often you see it one way or the other
OK but now what's up here
i've been to maximize i'm looking for the worst x right
some vectors x
my it
might in the null space and i go to zero
but that doesn't mean the matrix is the zero matrix
good norm is
r max
o all
non-zero vectors x so the max of this
and as i said i could take the max
i've taken over i could make the denominator one that i would just be looking
at the new
so the question is how much can the matrix blow up
how much can increase the size of
that's that's a good measure of the norm now does well OK
because we are to check
this property but it it's it's easy
this property will come right out of the vector properties
actually another property of come out for the matrix normal
that the norm of times b
is less than the norm of a times the normal b
i can sort of say it in words why that will be true
what's the norm of a b
five by my
by my idea here
i take vectors x
i see how much they are blown up
by a b
well first of all i could look at that in two steps i could say
OK take the vector x how much is blown up by b
and then how much is bx blown up by the
well why so why don't i have just equality there
i get two shots you get two shots on the right that the worst acts
the exit gets one of the most by b might not
producer bx at the
i was strongly
so so
in other words it just comes from here is the proof that the length of
a BX
so this article will be kept low
that's how much
they can blow it up by
and now i'm down here
that's just the way
and px
can be candle wax up by more than it's not
now i've learned this this ABX can blow up more than
so that's why this is a very sad this is like called the sometimes called
the operator norm
because i'm thinking of a an operators acting whereas this is more a ray normal
often but it's got uses
like self so those are two important norms i guess i should
i admit that we can measure the length of vectors other ways
and if we did this would give us another measure of a how else could
i measure the norm of
the vector x
the length of the vector
it's just that i to write down policies think of other ways that we can
measure the size of
you change some of absolute values
right just just i need to take absolute value because i don't want any any
the the but in
so it's actually
three of this side here
is that of their
the difference between the square of good this time the and the square of the
and the reason why this is true is because this
of users is large and then i agree
i have no idea
i mean no i i no idea
i don't think that
i mean i together under competitive pressure maybe we can we can
can they make it better invertebrate
if that if you think about what you can do anything
so in this work in
the really curious
i guess you might believe this one out
and the other one the proof is just lines
if you're in doubt
you you know you don't see how to this one
if one
none of the mentioned is correct
one this is correct
so let's see
the is is this so i'm looking at
OK this is looking at the main thing
so you see this you write c is the difference between the difference between a
we really need
OK then i created
so i scraped it is greater plasticity where miners who
ACA these vectors and this is where the
it a OK this i can say something about this i know this because i
the english up another because i think
what can being
once believe this one
now we done because we can
because we can say that
so what we have now
we have that
this created his loss
because now we have we have no relationship
it is
this created the hinge loss
although there was some
i guess some across all of these because
when it doesn't take place so they lost the run time
this LP
WP nine once we have them
this is most
there big and using this relationship now
and you you see that that one is that
if i sum that the inequality over the left and side
what happens if that's if that's the right inside the political
and i can drop
the last term of the right
all the way so i x
i have this max
x the square
and i some
all that being on
w human one minus two
great minds w
b-minus you
so no using this telescope in the i can
i can get the
right down here
i get the w zero
nine you
where the
and the quantity
which is the last term here
that your because they
minus bad
richard can probably because i mean the thing upper bound the mind of the positive
then i know that is that it would be wrong
because this is the man
like or not like any more
because i thought out from the director
so now i want to get for the whole expression is an upper bound in
the normal way
well finally
get this going to be here
about the ones where is upper bounded by some quantity as
the process here
which is marked
and then
OK so all
is the same as the perceptron
it's actually a bit
something something stronger than percent because
this is the last created this because the function
that expressed in terms of the margins again this is the
the margin
but this is the mistake indicator function
and in the perceptron convergence theorem i had escorted the upper bound the number
but the controls
is the squared hinge loss is the function
that goes like this
this is the wrong
zero to one and then goes up but
the problem
so is an upper bound because again a convex good upper bound on the mistake
indicator function
so i'm showing that the
so what
upper bounds larger quantity than the first
but this is what
and of course
i can say that
product of the determinant is only land every square that story of the order of
UGV squares
therefore this can only happen if you have one huge and one tiny eigen values
so that the product comes out
roughly if UGV and therefore this explains to you very naturally why these masses come
out to be of the order of ten to the minus two electoral votes which
is what one
it is actually
so these are the three reasons the main reasons which make supersymmetry grand unification looks
this is some nice to theorists it sort of seems to have the correct scales
before neutrinos for unification of gauge couplings does fit very nicely in the article content
of the standard model and it within the sense
be very minor issues if there was not rules
now that's the nice part of the that's what is the grand unified theories what
is the lesson i spotted is that many of the detailed predictions depend actually on
the the little known details of the symmetry breaking sector or of this careless
what scalar field representations should we have with what potential and what yukawa couplings
is up for grabs you know that's very much more than independent and of course
you can play the game of excluding models by for instance checking that you get
or don't get the correct must make this is for quarks leptons or even more
seriously one of the canonical problems is called the core doublet triplet the doublet triplet
splitting in particular this means that the higgs doublet has forced alignment even if it
in a grand unified marketplace
the simplest one four five is the five collect the vector of first five
this has both
they're usually electroweak doublet and the core of triplet which you don't want actually you
want to really sounded very far up because it does all sorts of things including
mediating very rapid proton decay through these channels here proton decay on this
antineutrinos and this so-called doublet triplet splitting
problem is in your system in the specific models and you have to find human
and devise ways to get rid of the triplet
so this is in this sense the unknown sector that's where you know a lot
of model building fort was spent
in the eighties and seventies and eighties
to be different besides this triangle anomaly cancellation which in cases like a simultaneous
totally automatic actually
there is really no theoretical principles that guide the search
that's the state of affairs
so this is the undesirable the feature the second undesirable feature is that there is
this huge hierarchy of scales between the electroweak and the grand unified scale
this is stable to quantum corrections because of supersymmetry but it is by no means
explained by in theoretical
these are calculation and finally of course gravity is not part of the story
supersymmetric guts as i said capture manually non-trivial feature so far lower energy world a
they have also nice implications for cosmology the predict dark matter biogenesis in particular the
for for these reasons theorists believe it
that that's our best current for physics beyond the standard model
how has string theory changed the story well here is in a sense this small
checked debris and i'll try to go through the quickly now
the big
of course success and that's what motivates theories is that gravity is now family part
of the game
now if you agnostic and this could have messed things up completely you know many
of these features could have not worked actually they do seem to still work pretty
you do get correct gauge groups for grand unification you do get correct
representations for arxiv leptons and even moreso also to you you do get the coupling
unification that follows really very nicely in place
at least in large class of models including unification gravity so this is by all
means you know the most successful part of the story
the main ones are
less successful from the point of view
a and b but not totally desperate try out as you will see
for a second this string theory will have modified as i will explain the nature
of the gauge hierarchy problem
it has modified it in the sense that it is clearly now
the question of stability and gravitational interactions
this is not yet solved but at least we understand that we cannot hope to
solve the problem without understanding better graphics
and you may say this is progress even though though the problem is with that
string theory did changed the model building orders
there are
for instance the extra dimensions you can use extra dimensions to do some of the
symmetry breaking this theory
with new mechanisms you may say which are not field theoretic
not any representations are allowed and we can use these brains and the fluxes that
discussed yesterday
to do some new things
the model building rules have been modified by string theory
this helps a little bit actually even for model building for instance it's much easier
to solve this little nuisances like the doublet triplet splitting string theory the grand unified
however again to be fair
it doesn't really narrow down the possibilities we still have so many choices and possibilities
and the guiding ourselves through them need some principle is missing
finally how about experimental consequences well at first sight
those are not
you know at low demand i mean there are lots of them supersymmetry is one
proton decay
modifications of gravity cosmic strings
kind energy states
and much more actions and much more
but again the question is when will these manifest themselves at what scale we see
that actually and of course that's the big question
and the second question is
are any of those smoking gun
predictions in the sense that we couldn't get some cheap away
that's where these questions are by and large open as you'll see unless we have
so like it but that's really extremely low probability scenario as to see listings
in the LHC
OK so let's not discuss a bit more these things in a slightly more detail
so when one thinks about string theory unification grand unified theories come from string there
are two large categories of theories one this discusses those are the only ones that
can give weak coupling there but really
feel it for grand unification
one is the so-called heterotic string which i haven't discussed last time that was discussed
now and the other is the type one which is a close relative of the
type two strings and discussed yesterday
this have very different properties including for the experiment and report potential experiment manifestation so
let me discuss them down
equivalently say you can see that there is an negative value if and only the
determinant of the matrix in mind is that the identity zero
which means that a minus on that the density is not invertible
you say that these actions he's i vector associated to the you can value if
if to be
they are matrices of four days in which missus obviously the
again values the diagonal elements and it's not true for triangular matrices right
you is can value if and only if a is not invertible
and would say that a is diagonalizable if there exists a basis of a given
vector which can be written as
if you put your your i can vectors are
as columns of the matrix p
then the products p times the things he one actually actually equal to it
four if you could if you
i have this be transferred there
you can see that if you think it
six exactly p times the
and so if you think of a column vector of of
b here intensities column vector is exactly the same column vector of this matrix there
and as the they along this means that it then this victory excited is the
is exactly it's clear that is the
they are the term that the same effect
these this rating there is nothing more than saying that he
is the matrix of column vectors are the good effectors
there's no
there's is a special thing that happens when
your matrix is symmetric
if that if your matrix is symmetric then you're guaranteed to find an orthonormal basis
of eigen vectors
not only are you guaranteed to
that the matrix is they they realizable but also that you can find an orthonormal
basis that that is the basis of a good thing
this can be written as is he
things need to be transposed where p is a unitary matrix
in addition
with say that this matrix made a symmetric matrix
is semi definite positive if the dot product between x and x is always positive
for any vector
then you can values of the matrix a of positive and that would be true
four sorry for any diagonal matrix for which the diagonal elements are
negative and for any matrix that can be written as the b for matrix
and the matrix is said to be definite positive if this care for x is
zero only if x is itself is zero
then it means that
that is
this implies that has
only strictly positive
i guess values again the diagonal matrix with positive entries along with you
then is different positive and if
if it can be read as opposed to be transposed b
and is invertible
then it's definitely positive
those images are important
first of all because you can there is diagonalized them on
orthonormal basis and if in addition there are different inputs and then you can verify
this form ax
here the dot product if you use the usual dot products on x
and if x then it's defining a new that products which i i was users
who is an index a and
this form here is new know the product it gives you a new norm on
and so
you can think of everything
as you're just
you can think of your vector space
it recently this new non there
thank you
now if you don't have same matrix and a symmetric matrix
it may not be diagonalizable
it may also be that you matrix is not even square
but using the
using for example so
so let's see bees and and by matrix using for example the transpose be all
these things be transposed which we've seen are symmetric semi the semidefinite matrices then you
can find an interesting decomposition of b which is the singular value decomposition
different ontologies you know if the document is a
two classes tend to annotate the same set of documents that the probably related to
these types of techniques had some success
so for the external sources their approaches for example that
try to use other ontologies on the web to create the corresponding to that of
course the lexicon and desire is always very rich source of information so you know
if one uses ontologies car other the users automobile and have lexicon that says that
those two are synonyms
that's all this very good three so these types of resources usually help in finding
the correspondences
and then sort of any other form of background knowledge and in fact i think
one of the
as is
you see
the look at the
approaches to ontology matching over the years these use external resources one of the things
that has really grown
quite a bit in the last few years
and now
during the
and six
OK all this techniques so what we call basic techniques OK because their daily acts
on a specific part of the ontology but not generally on the ontology that's all
any matching system which can seriously compete
you use several of these techniques OK and they can
do this in in the in the following way
the basic idea is that they will use one method for example name matching
and they were use in parallel another one
i don't know maybe they will match the properties based on their domain and then
will match again the classes being done based on their name on their domain OK
so it means that you can use this method independently
and then of course when you want to match the entities that you find in
an ontology you will have to aggregate the results of all of these techniques
and after the aggregation usually what you want to do is to filter in values
with the result that you have because there are some matching matches which are not
really likely OK so basically you apply some threshold on of or some functions in
order to select what is really important in the result that you have obtained and
and and then basically what you've got after filtering is rather similarity and assessment of
the commonality between the entities and then you will use the method for extracting the
alignment from this kind of similarity and of course i guess OK it's it's not
here but in fact what you can do once you've got this is to input
this again and OK we'll talk look very soon about the evaluation of matter that
we do and so this year there are several matcher that really do that is
that the output and the input it again in the pipe and they iterate until
was established to something which is satisfying
so if i if i can summarize
of course you will use several basic matters and you can use them
in sequence so you will compose them and pass the result of one match to
the as the input of another one expects from or you can use them in
and then you will have the problem of aggregating the results and you can aggregate
them because these are matcher that considering different things
OK so basically you will add the evidence of each match if a matter of
phone based on name that this things are the same then you will keep this
result and if another form that some other entities are the same based on the
structure of the ontology for example you would keep this as well and but you
also can create competing matcher so basically you will take the average of all the
mean of the average of the results that have been given by order the matter
so there are plenty of techniques for doing the aggregation and depending on the kind
of matching is this kind of not to know which one to use
this is
kind of the same thing for the filtering result usually people use threshold but it
is very difficult to
OK so i'm told that
in this sort of environment people don't have enough questions but again i'd encourage you
to anyway if you're feeling brave
there's going to be in a much longer break and another time
so the end of the
the first hour i left you with this question
there are many possible things we could do we could pick up all sorts of
algorithms and we can sit down and we came up with to try them out
i encourage you to do that
but we'd really like seven guiding principles that tell us what we're doing
there were
there are various levels so that the first of which is
but if you're writing an algorithm
it in many
in the broad variety of circumstances
it's a good idea to ask what is my algorithm trying to achieve and to
do that formerly it's often good to identify what's called an objective function so rather
than just running it something of that looks good is good if it can spit
out and number
saying what goodness is this had this output to goodness of six point three
so i like to say that you should be optimizing an objective by your when
you run an algorithm you're trying to improve some objective function
other people are much less
optimistic and they say i'm going to minimize the cost function in know exactly the
same thing is just a minus sign in front
and as soon as you do that my things happened saying
if you have an iterative algorithm like the perceptron algorithm i shady which is moving
the weight vector around
if you have an objective function you can ask the question
is my objective improving at every step of my algorithm
so if you can prove that an algorithm is monotonically improving an objective function
then you have already prove something about the convergence of the algorithm
so an algorithm that can make your objective works as well as better
could potentially form loops it could cycle through the same set of weight vectors circuits
say a
i'm going to let you like this now against the like this now i'm going
to play like this again and it could just oscillate back and forth
if you've identified an objective function and can show that your algorithm never make that
objective worse than immediately proved that that sort of loop can never happen so that's
a good thing to do
if you've got
and objective that you can attach a number two you could maybe ask the question
is one algorithm better fitting that objective than another maybe one is able to get
the same objective faster maybe one is able to get better value of the objective
but unless you've got some quantitative score
and you in mind then there's no way that you can compare different sorts alternative
before we do anything we should really be thinking about what this objective function might
be how we can come up with the real number that says how well we're
doing if we're
ten one of these little machine learning tasks
there's an one answer
but here it is
a very common
so the way forward
what we do is we identify what's called the loss function
and the loss function takes two arguments it takes
true output in the problem so this is
this item in my training set actually is an orange
and it takes another argument which is what you're learning algorithm to predict so this
i'm going to predict the suleman given
and then this loss function says how bad is it that you said it was
eleven when actually it was an orange like
how much is the person you're writing assistant going to charge you for making that
so maybe the loss would be zero if these two arguments matched and it would
some positive about from mismatch that's sort of the common thing you could do that
the different problems
this function will take on different values for maybe if for regression problem we want
to have the square of the difference between the two
the two items
the whole lot of things that you could put in here and we're going to
talk about that
more because it's an important issue
but once we come up with this loss function l
we can say well what our objective really what our objective is
is that when it comes to test time when we deploy system and it sees
new input to stop spitting out out for them
we don't want to suffer too much loss
so a
in the ideal case we would like to come up with our group test time
on going to do too badly
and it's very hard to prove about an algorithm
what is the value of that loss will be
because we don't know what's going to happen in the future after all we have
in our hands on training set of examples that we've been given and so may
be pragmatic thing to do this before we think of anything else is
that we do what's called minimizing the empirical loss so
we look at what
our learning algorithm we do on the training set that we've got at hand and
we say well what's the total loss that we
on the training set and that's now a score that we could use
the least squares algorithm
find the best possible
empirical loss it minimizes squared error on the training set and the learning algorithm with
one line of k but you could imagine iterative algorithms that sort of move weight
vectors around trying to improve squared error
they are never going to do better than this one line of code the hot
right to the best possible expected squared loss so that objective function we know what
the best algorithm is it's use the numerical library that does this particular thing for
but depending on the application we can have different loss functions so
the classification we might have what's called the zero one loss so that was one
where we don't experience any loss if we got the right answer we experience the
loss of one
if we get the wrong answer and that's
we are
that year
it was great
it is
and so
try to wrap up they
cross validation situation so this is this is expression that we have in the last
slide where we get and cross validated estimate of risk that's that's what this notation
means and and
that is a function of the regularisation parameter
and so
we also had this this slide this picture a few slides back where
the value of the relaxation parameter and the actual treaty
that is optimal for that particular about it
precision parameter
go to like that and so if
what you end up doing this is
o what you end up getting is getting a picture like this this by the
what you get in our if you use are part which is there our implementation
of CART
and so at the top you have the tree size and and this made of
risk and again
i tried to emphasise here how the three size which is
they indicator here for complexity go hand in hand with the value of the relaxation
parameter and not since since we're doing
this and the idea we can also compute
it's standard errors for that you know the cross validation and that that's what is
illustrated here with the with the vertical bars
and so on
you can either find a minimum
in this plot remember we're trying to find the have for that
generates three there has the smallest prediction
and sometimes what you do is is you're you follow what called a one is
he rule one is found that oral where you find the minimum of the plot
here then you go up one standard error in the dual f until you cross
the picture again and that is statistically you cannot differentiate between those two points so
you take the more conservative answer which would be the smaller of of those trees
they they
as i mentioned earlier when we're doing cross validation we're taking an average of measures
of fit and so the first idea generalisation is well can can we
fitted value as opposed to measures of and and can these in which is what
we doing and symbols and candice have average compensate for their for
overly optimistic trees
so i guess i'm suggesting that the seeds of n symbols where there early on
in cross validation and cost complexity pruning of trees
OK so now
continent get model selection but we switch to two regularizations
yes rank and specifically the lasso
and so
this situation here setting here is a linear motor
this is straightforward in water and in the standard linear regression coefficient estimate of estimation
problem is this data like this we are trying to find the values of the
coefficients is j
that minimizes the risk and the reason is estimated by by the addition of the
a couple of reasons why one is often not satisfied with the ordinary linear regression
one of his body and so off and that is high variance in the coefficient
estimates and the other one is interpretation when went to as the number of articles
we would like if possible to get a subset of the variables that capture the
stronger effect and so on
there are
generally two
types of techniques to
deal with
one is a subset regulation
which is a discrete pulses so it itself can have integrity
like the tree growing algorithm integrity discrete processes that often times you
a sample of the data and you get different subset
on the other side we have some linkage techniques
which we can think of them as a second ten years
process and they darius version of that is reach regulation and so like in trees
their waste linkage work is that it adds
a penalty term
two there cost function
exactly or very analogous to what we doing in trees now
this penalty term can take different forms if we are adding
this squares of the coefficients that's what is called reach regulations
when we are adding the absolute values of the coefficients it what called the lasso
and you can think of having here as in or so so if we have
this enormous just counting the number of coefficients that
and then it's identical to what we doing with three where the penalty term was
counted the number of the size of the tree so we have here this see
don't know it's similar to that now
they in
as as we mentioned in the case of trees so by the way this is
where the lasso name comes from
because the idea is that you have this
additional force that is trying to bring new coefficients stores area right so they don't
go y and
and so
as in the case of the trees the penalty term
pro i tell deterministic it doesn't depend on the data that's what i mean by
it deterministic value
so it's a counteracting force
i forgot whether it in the introduction we we mention what they
lasso is two to four
so it's least absolute and now we know it comes from the because we the
absolute and then the next to us is strain gauge and selection operator
and i want to emphasise the second a selection
we can elicit startled looks very much like star level at the start of a
forty years i really can't tell the difference when we're listening
it even lists the reflex which was the put back so we can stimulate the
cochlear neurons in the connection between the character neurons in this middle snaps
and let's assume that when the light comes on the compared with the shock but
in one way other modulates transmission in this middle snaps
if we were to elicit start electrically here or here that is after that are
upstream from that point of modulation then start always electrically should be potentiated
on the other hand if another animal we implant electrodes down here
that is beyond the point where i'm assuming the modulation occurs with illicit startled but
it wouldn't be affected by the light
so that was the logic in exactly that's exactly what we found when we elicited
startle electrically here or here we can get potentiation about the list electrically listeners are
acoustically elicited but when we listed here we get potentiation of acoustically but not electrically
so we conclude then that the light in one way or the other efforts compare
the shop eventually modulates transmission at that point the pathway and then at that time
there are these wonderful new traces was called horseradish peroxidase that just come by hand
skype or i think he was one of the first people to do that and
we thought well this is a really neat technique is what it does is it
feels axons that project to a particular part of the brain and then it's a
protein goes backwards through jackson to end up in cell bodies so you can say
so we're interested in this part of the brain we can ask the question what
are the parts of the brain project to this area of the brain so what
we did is we infused a this horseradish peroxidase
and what we found is that they were a nice group of cells
in the central nucleus of the amygdala so that was a really nice day in
the laboratory because bruce capital been doing some very important studies showing that the amygdala
was critical for fear conditioning his case heart-rate conditioning using rabbits in joel do is
just preserve beginning to do his work which were seeing the posters he had published
anything so that's one of those really exciting days because you say well the central
nucleus which we know is involved in fear has a direct projections to the part
of the start of pathway that we've figured out that the light ultimately alters transmission
and sure enough when we took out the amygdala with the lesion or we put
drugs in that inactivated it did the same thing it didn't do anything to the
startle reflex but selectively decrease the feet and hands component and over the years we've
worked out a great deal of the circuitry here this is the start of pathway
over here this is the direct pathway from the amygdala there's an indirect pathway that
was first implicated by ed moloney now at harvard and there's another pathway from another
part of the amygdala they all converge at this part of the pond in particular
formation and we how the visual information and the shock information get into the amygdala
they converge there and with this convergence in the nervous system there is opportunity for
and we show that a particular receptor the talk about no while the NMDA receptor
in the middle the goal was critical for fear learning so if you block the
receptor the animal didn't want the association between the light and the shock
and now many labs joel do my fans slower air kendell
a whole number of labs are now looking at the cellular events that turning and
different genes in the amygdala two
account for fear conditioning
well that's a very detailed look at the much larger an important conclusion and that
is outputs from the central nucleus of the amygdala go to variety of target areas
in the hypothalamus and brainstem
and those areas are involved in the specific signs and symptoms of fear and anxiety
so the outputs the lateral hypothalamus that's involved in sympathetic activation during the state fair
that's because when you get your blood pressure up you sweat because there's sympathetic activation
shaken marry anybody was acceptable
and then I look at the smaller
the remaining n minus 1 problem and what's happening there
now every set of those girls well among used up 1 boys
and I I said in this case that I had room to maneuver so it's
I'm OK they are with that that's the easy 1
then the harder cases when the sunset and given this proof without writing here those
right that case 1 which I just dealt with was of k less than that
the every
subset has
subset and so on
have more and more room to maneuver
an extra 1 or more is is OK and then we can make an assignment
get to a smaller problem where OK now there's a harder cases some
sense of
the girls
some for some k less than
likes only on board only exactly and boys OK idea without paying for
deal with that case
and and still also uh the appeared on doing so I'm assuming is true so
all said it is none of the tetragonal signals and all sets like enough
and some pretty subset likes just barely enough
OK with the claim is that those k girls I can't match them to those
keyboards which I better do
now why am I able to do that
that's the induction step
that this is a smaller than group
and it's
hypothesis is satisfied so
so it's a smaller problem and I'm assuming that I've sold all smaller problems now
coming in the case of n boys and girls
OK so so a match them off
this was a smaller problem so already present themselves and now I have to
what I have to do now I to get the rest the other n minus
k other and minus came out deal with it
well I guess
I want use that as a smaller problem to
but I then I would have to check that this condition
but came the boys are now used
so I have to check the other n minus k i have to check that
this condition cannot colonists halls condition was that a guy named Paul also conditions
I have to check check
all aligned there these remaining on these on the on the unmarried 1
it is
let's see story
so much
for these other guys
let's see the thing is we all we can't match them off with boys that
were used by the 1st k so we have to be done sure
that these remaining girls like little boys and yet they're the picture yes I mean
but do I know that how do I know
that those remaining girls
the case
can I can't continue but I have to check that I have that somehow from
the original from knowing the original big set a and if she went anywhere what
I have to worry about is paid maybe some of these remaining only like those
same k boys
the enemy something well here we use the null I haven't I haven't but but
I think if necessary I could but I didn't have the evidence of the yet
we're we're right in the middle exactly consisting of 5 years would have violated every
day is here you're in luck
the whole
that's right that's it that's it including this condition and can hold for sets of
girls which included these k and some of
and it's clear that becomes fun I won't like spoil everybody's gonna here it's says
beautiful that works so that that if I if I look at the center some