suppose we have a couple programs
we want to computer here like that
right and to run them to take up a certain amount of memory
so if we had this type of memory the amount of memory recall and
we can run programme one
but we can also write
now this that tell us we run them together
might be the most of
filamin completely and that the other one or that just have to wait
we don't want that
that's what we like
is that
he was that why would we like
well that tells us we have the memory twice
we have two lots of it
so this sort of conjunction is staying
the town to talk about
what we can do at the same time
concurrency that sort
but here we are talking about formulas as representing truths about the world they represent
information is different from other people talk about information as a resource
you can use it up in the same way
i know these chairs in the room blue values that particular thing i can still
retain information about way
if you pay
his example always paying a dollar per pack of cigarettes and or a cigarette is
a chain smoker that and so
other people which it changed into a dollar for a can of coca-cola so that
there is anything but if you buy coca give away the dollar
i give all its own
so there's a difference between resources that give away
and once you down and the nice thing about linear logic is you get to
make that distinction
what we have already
but are
and we have as much of it and we went around looking like an entropy
information or something like
we write it like that
i mentioned before
was put after because
and that
the other sort of infinite fusion
of these things we have as much as we want
we can collect
what's needed linear logic
well if you put bangs front of all of premises you end up and you're
allowed to do that the court
should point you put information what's very old premises end up with intuitionist logic
let's a whole that aside from in
you know
so we can we can use that as much as we want
that's what that tells us
is that we can do that as much as we want and that's quite nice
now what is that this that this logic doesn't
you know neither of those things you want to be sensitive to much ahead if
the it those using and if you have
it's a
and you need twice to give you a you can you have you can do
it just with one
if you can do it with one
it might not be that you want to be able to say
that you could do but with two
right memory sure
but there might be other things like with what the cells and things like that
you want to be very sensitive to how much of the stuff you have
right i mean if you think about this one
you want to be just very sensitive to the things of contraction and weakening are
just that
those things are just completely out
for that
one is is actually quite interesting in
the original formulations this logic
we not only have implications fusion but we still have
and or and
we can get out
so from one and seven and negation elimination we get
well what if we want to have a so we could use this
right that's why we use that we start off with this and we wanted to
prove what we really want to prove
is this that's LEM
we want to prove is that to get to
and so from this so that we get a
we're not a
so it one
and six
so one through seven
the negation elimination two
non into so that's not an intuitionistic arguments we used
that's right here
assume that
what we could prove
an intuition is is this
we don't have this but we do have it's double negation
now that's weird thing about intuitions logic
if a
is a theorem of classical logic
and not not a
is a theorem of intuitionist logic
and because it wishes logic is the subsystem of classical logic
the other direction holds as well
you can embed classical logic within intuitionistic logic by sticking double negations in front of
all the parents
that's just plain design
the rationale for intuitionist logic doesn't tell you that that's going to happen
and i have some proofs in the book if the proof of
the double negation of this is in your notes
that's very funny but that proved this fun
so you do use this at crucial point
and you could have just thought well i'll stop used instead of this negation introduction
to get that
OK so that's the relationship between classical logic intuitionistic logic they're very very close relationship
there was this debate actually by one philosopher here at the time richard sylvan and
with other people here on saying look into issues logic isn't a restriction of classical
logic is really an expansion of it because you capture all classical logic within
and you can write you can represent all quite yet
ninety two is not a rule systems are
well why do they reject this
it's because of this
we don't want this and why don't we want this to say if you can
that you cannot prove
if you prove can prove that you can prove something
then you've got it right then
if you can prove that you can prove that you can prove something that you
can have it and that means you you've gonna so
and that's not it we signals proves all those
if you put into intuitions logic but i mean s four dollars boxes see you
eat it
all user told the for class
i mean
that's really all you know it so
if you can prove
that's not the case
that you can prove that not a and a
it just isn't just a few you have to say that a million times yourself
it is a you have that same you can get that
this the same thing that be the other direction hold
for intuitionist centre for classical logicians so
these two are equivalent for intuitionist and that's exactly the reason they rejected the reductio
because they say well i
if i zoom is not the case
then i get into trouble
and it must be true
that assumes that either it's true it's not one that you think about excluded middle
why isn't excluded middle
why is that
OK intuitions to play
well you can prove something or you can prove that you can prove that
how do you know that
fermat's last theorem is gone we can prove that
maybe not intuitionistic labour improvement
but maybe
we can
could show that the ryman conjecture are called box conjecture whatever
one of these hard problems in mathematics maybe they're not
we can prove
that not provable
or least the negation is not provable
but that doesn't mean that provable cells might say
it's undecidable
i mean got inside problems if you're thinking about
mathematics as
what can be done with me implemented sometimes you just might not have you might
not be able to get it or its negation and so
the excluded middle you don't get
this you don't get and so on so that's that's where with the whole is
but you're right it does look off to classical minus it's very symmetrical
OK let's get any questions
OK now
so that's
intuitionistic logic
and with intuitionist logic we have two because you don't have these complete infinite is
so you have to revise mathematics very good a lot
calculus become something completely different
obviously right to talk about limits on what happens at the limit
i e gotta stop talking that way if an intuitionist
kind of you can use that one deltas and in in some
interesting way but
the construction the real numbers itself because we think of those infinite expansions of some
of the rationals infinite expansions
they have to be in some way
things that we can approximate
and that is something called free choice sequences which is often planet hard
i don't scare you away from that interested in doing it wishes analysis a lot
of people do work and that it is extremely interesting offline hard often means of
planet interesting as well
there are some funny bits of intuitionism as i mean classical mathematics that we have
to give up and one thing is this
we can talk about the quantifiers
it's one thing
suppose we have a function
at some point its values are below zero
at some point above zero
it is continuous
so therefore
and then i suppose
taking one attribute with the lead us to such a situation
entropy one here to visit weight in if we take another entropy attribute
this would lead us to
nine positive zero and negative seen one set zero positives five negatives in the other
obviously which was
this is more informative than this
this one
OK so and if we would go through the actual computation
we would see that for instance for each subject we basically computer the game
and we chose
there to to build with the maximum gain
has the highest entropy humidity
has slightly lower than the distal have even lower
attributes with the maximum gain would be selected and put into the root of the
then we split
the set of instances into subsets and then we repeat
we again shows the most informative attribute and then we stop when all the examples
in the leaf belong to the same class
so that's a pretty straightforward good
OK so you have more computations here
the formula
we had the computation of probability
the simplest way how to compute the probability is through relative frequencies
so we said what is the probability of class
we said well let us estimator it with the number of instances in the set
and then
we do
the relative frequencies of positive instances compared to the number of all instances in the
set for instance we had fourteen examples
the training set out of which there were nine positives
so this would be the
the root of the decision tree that
randomly drawn instance
from the center for the instances would be
the positive instance so that the simplest probability estimate the simple relative frequency and this
is described here
we could have more complicated
estimate of probability
one of them is the plus estimate which
assumes that the prior distribution of class plus and minus is uniform there is fifty
percent of examples of class plus and fifty of minus which would mean that if
we have no additional information
as it would be fifty fifty
why is this OK
and that would be for a binary classification problem the relative frequency estimator can be
modified to introduce estimate and for k
problem it is modified into this assuming the uniform distribution of k classes being uniformly
distributed and then there is more elaborate probability estimate which is called the name estimate
which takes into account the prior probability of the class
positive compared to the distribution of other classes so if i just try to intuitively
explain why these different estimates are
useful so the relative frequency is obviously the most intuitive and that that's what one
would straightforwardly use however it is unreliable with small samples suppose we have one positive
and there is just one example then we do our probability estimate would say well
the probability of class plus
is one hundred percent
so in order to
take into account the prior distribution of classes and if we know that it is
uniform we change this into the lab class estimate which means that if we have
whatever lands matrix of fine cells
to see if basically our strategy is our population of our best solutions sort of
beat around them quite
and LBC is basically long biased coin
basically we have with what we have
with that we're basically made one side of the coin heavy
the other side of the coin so it's acquired it's basically very likely to say
let's go along
as species short by coin which is like the other way around and what we
can see here
except for its wall except for stock of HSBC
for the other for invesco and glasses glaxo
well the twenty fifth quantile
the best solutions of sharpe ratio produced is actually better than
you know a random strategy
this basically based on the flip on flipper for quite
this is basically an example
a solution
four invesco
and it's basically what
as you can see it's
moving average of the past returns for for seventy seven periods
multiplied by the return at t minus thirty five and
some tricks
function that
i think what's most interesting about this is the one is basically the return of
ten by the latest which is like the best solution
and the red line is the buy-and-hold strategy
well what we see is that
the best solution is a solution to sort of learned
to get
to get to
it's not get but it's not
is land
basically get those ones right
maybe you have
you said that you will have to do
this is
one which is really really
so a
i don't know
well what we've done is we've
so to put maximum lengths which an individual can saying
so if with sort of put constraints on how large an individual can be
if you want to have this
so this is certainly something something that i think
we should look at
but it's
well similar to what sign saying you drive
get the ones that actually matter
decoding it's harder
and basically
who was doing the work on the spam has had on that for
over you got some positive results what does
complicated political process but that's
is it it's still kind of limited by
i have to say
you can go with all these things
only so far you still
at the end of the day after committee doing sequence models
you you translate phrases you don't three structures you don't have nice can generate is
you know pre-orders from the end to the second position that he would have an
so maybe
long range reordering
the argument this kind of thing works for many mid-range hillary has a long range
reordering you should really then do
past recent restructure
again being very motivated by german to english
because of the better handle morphology but
getting the first in the right place
we still only have crude hack parsing the source
having manual rules
having been able to learn this
his mission or the
yes i it's certainly true that not all answers and announcing on these things so
this also i mean once you get to the slow you this different ways and
it is things
two separate plural something like this
jennifer while the user part of speech tagger that included subject object tags
maybe you don't want to to have them included part of speech tags they went
somewhere else
this is
i mean that's all the propositions that english like five different text in which position
but then the frequent enough that we should actually use the surface of missions
i mean there's another
general sentiment about it the always sounds very plausible to say we should use syntax
that the next missions which syntax whose syntax which parse whose parts
you know phrase structure grammars dependency grammars
all kinds of people everybody has its own grammar
and and they all behave differently in there
it does have CSR we we have this trick of reordering before does have a
significant impact on this but just because of
it has all kinds of knock-off effective everything else so once you don't have to
work in the right place to you introduce structure it's all over the place
but there that's true
that's definitely true that you're not going to our pride is more important than getting
the of a
is small
four was
well i mean we always have the standard approach which is very narcissistic about everything
except you have to separate things up words which for something which is a big
i mean it's different i mean
i mean you want to do well
on on european languages who want to do well in spanish english which is a
relatively simple language care
one of the well on that so if the resources available we want to do
better than that
what if you don't know if you only have a couple of thousand sentences
parallel corpus that's the challenge
i mean develop different methods for different situations
we don't have to
make sure that bodybuild works for everything
this so a lot of work in low density languages and
this that the typical darker scenarios that there is a crisis in some foreign country
nobody ever heard of and you know
rumsfeld whatever it's called now comes and says i need energy system twenty four hours
we also papers so
so that's in our exists but
you know
in during the thing because scenarios
a company wants to translate the user manuals
well known languages
maybe has a lot of
so this is really looking at the robot really much more city member rather than
just a sort of device you're just interacting with on year-round really thinking about extending
into this larger larger of networks
so i'm going to show you could video this robot autom that we developed to
explore this question by
i'm ready to work with them to help you do your rules thanks for coming
i hope you had a good day so far
this here is the first robotic weightloss coach that we
building a set of these are going to go into people's homes around the boston
area so we can do a long-term study looking at two things one is looking
at various aspects of human robot interaction what happens when people actually have a robot
in their homes for a couple of months of the interacting with and also looking
to see if it is useful in this particular domain weight loss
it's also helpful for us if you tell me how much exercise you got today
what you do that now
the robot speaks to me while interacting with the various times asked me to input
information like how much i even today
and how much time
if you tell me at least one so the homoge exercise will be more likely
to get you to wonder what more schools
so you may notice a number of things about the way that this robot was
designed the first is that it has the physical embodiment and they can exhibit a
very simple non-verbal cues such as eye contact
and shared attention one hypothesis we had the simple cues are very important is listening
this sense of engagement with the human robot actually looks at you into your eyes
can feel much more connected and more motivated to interact with the the second thing
you might notice the nature of the dialogue so there's a lot of team building
dialogue and this was really motivated by looking at doctor-patient dialogues and how you build
a working alliance the robot is never pushy if never bosses never guilt-trip in new
but is trying to talk about if you did this is going to help us
achieve our goals as a lot of talk about the common goals and strategies for
achieving those goals
the relationship is the relational model of the robot goes through at the very beginning
of the interaction
the interaction tends to be the language of more formal rubber gives more explanation of
why that to do such things such as injury are waiting powers and so forth
as you interact with the robot longer the nature of the dalit becomes more informal
and explanations become short because there's an assumption of common ground and there's much more
reference things you've done in the past as well since are going to do in
the future and there's another state with the robot senses that the relationship is undergoing
disrepair if you know using as much engages in dialogue to try to re-establish relationship
is very interesting dialogue model and relational model that was built into this robot in
order to try to model patient-doctor sort of relationship so a fundamental question was
what about this robot with these nonverbal cues versus a putting the exact same dialog
and relational model just regular old computer
the same touch-screen interface is the actual robot make a difference and comparing it to
to traditional intervention which is basically people keeping track of the caloric intake and outtake
with pen and paper log
so we did a study design was a four-week mandatory interaction with an optional two-week
we built fourteen of these robots put them into people's homes in the boston area
we could have a lot of subjects from the boston medical weight loss clinic dr
carolyn province actually on cricket thesis committee which is very similar helping us recruit subjects
and so forth it just turned out that the age range happened between eighteen and
seventy two from the people we could agree to to the study i mean eighty
percent were female
the other conditions again with the computer and the people are
and the two core questions you wanted to know was
will people be more motivated to interact with the robot over the long term and
what is the state of the working alliance they feel they have a strong working
alliance with the because these are the most predictive of long-term success is important to
recognise that the weight loss itself is that the issue you can lose weight over
a number of different diets issues keeping it all so it's really the long-term engagement
we're trying to achieve measure in the study
we get a bunch data the robot of course would record all of the interactions
that very detailed look at how often you're interacting with those interactions were higher caloric
intake was going away management so forth we did not post any question
on the people on this subject after the study including administering working alliance symmetry which
is the standard psychological measure the doctors used to measure the working lives of patients
as well as just open and close study interviewed as the questions such as you
know the quality emotional interactions so for
and these are the kinds of questions you might look at and working life in
the choice of questions in terms of you feel that interact in the system you
could reflect more upon the process of losing weight do you feel that it was
accurate and how it helps you keep track of weight loss goals and monitor progress
did you feel that that you're able to understand the problem or yourself do you
feel also that the system had a working alliance with you
so if you look at the the results it was very interesting so it turns
out that if you look at just the length of interaction
alone it turns out that people chose to interact with the robot almost twice as
as the computer or the pen and paper interface and again and we were about
people were hoping for this result
but we were not expecting it to be the strong because again the information was
identical between the robot and the computer the only thing that different is the physical
embodiment of the computer
and if you look at
measure the working life symmetry again the robot outscored the computer and of course pending
paper log
if you look at some measures the working lives symmetry other participants reported that they
trusted the robot more
that the robot was more engaging
that was more reliable
make the network's see the kind the inputs that it would generate
itself during training so it knows to kind of go back to write
know the middle of the wrote the kinds of things that are
the human would do the teacher would do so
in other words the idea is that a instead of
of picking the ground truth as input
what we train with some probability we can pick the ground
truth and with some probably we can pick
the sample coming from the output of the model
and it turns out that it's actually wrong to do that from from
point from machine learning on view that
this procedure doesn't actually learn the right thing
but it's reasonable to believe i don't have any proof of that but
it seems reasonable that if we
if we make the probability of of choosing one of the other gradually
decrease to words zero that the sense that
ends up just listening to the ground-truth and
then you be ok and it would have some kind of exposure to the
kinds of things that kind of see equations that it would seem
to dries by itself
right so one interesting question
this something wrong in this you take some time to go
really understand that when we to think about it is
imagine that we we run the network in its training using ground
truth and then we let it run by itself for a few steps right so it's
what we open loop so just you know takes output and
as input and it might go in in a strange place
and in particular the place where it goes
might not the right answer for that as the state where it ends up
might not be the one that you have around to sequence so if you
go back to the driving example maybe the driver was is staying as
trade in the middle and if if the
the car decided to go bit right now the right action would be to
go back to the middle but maybe because the ground truth was thing
in the middle it says you know as you stay in the middle or even
go to derive because it was gone to the left so so these could
be inconsistent or targets that we're getting to this network
so so you know equation is really how should we trained as and
one idea i had when i wrote those slides
was that well we don't actually want to match the
the ground truth target a few steps later what we want to do
is to match the ground truth in distribution
so maybe something like gan which you will hear about and you've
heard a bit already about yesterday
might be a good way to deal with this problem
ok so let me talk more about some architecture variations
so up to now i haven't really looked in to how we structure the
architecture of the neural net but what you see
on the left here is sort of the the the architecture that
talking about we could we could think of
in several researchers papers have proposed different ways of making
this kind of architecture deeper for each timestep
and so you can do various ways so one the first ways was proposed
believe by alex graves is the one on the bottom left called stacking
where essentially we're going decompose the state into a different
levels so here we call one level the h is the other z but you
could imagine having many more levels
typically people have like ten levels like
normal deep nets so not that what happens is that
for a given input xt there will be a like a deep network feedforward
if you want recurrent net going up to all the state that the the
layers of the recurrent net but at each of these layers like ht for
example not only depends on the current input but of course and that
previous layer but also on the previous value of dots
levels state ok so that's the stacking version
another way that you could increased depth is to think about
making the transition from one state to the next state deeper instead
of having sing go find full by nonlinearity
for going from as t to s plus one you could
get in search like an mlp for example like the picture and middle
and similarly the mapping between states
and outputs could be deeper right so you could again search one
more hidden layers now there's a problem with this that
i should put the as i here doesn't for so we had a paper about
this as an issue when winning in search
when you insert an extra layer from t to t plus one
is that it it it somehow extra any more difficult because
the length of the sequences to be considered is not like doubled
and so we we inserted little skip connections here that goes directly
from my to t as well as the in addition to the extraordinary extra
layer in between
that's going to to the problem of long term dependencies which i'll
come to f if you minutes you can also
in my half lebanese mothers served in arabic lamb dish is the centerpiece every special occasion
so what would happen if i rejected the traditions that bonded me to my family
what i didn't realise back then was there
although change is always somewhat scary
and although changing ingrained behaviors is always somewhat challenging
the change would also be tremendously in power
i didn't realize that would be
healthy here today
forty five was and always half my age twenty two
and a half
i didn't realize that i will be able to cook and eat even more abundantly
and i didn't realize that the deepest bonds with others are forced not through unquestioningly following the dictates the tradition
could by becoming the kind of person who practices authenticity and integrity of the court
systems and dation have meaningful relationships
john f kennedy once said that belief in this allows the comfort opinion
without the discomfort a thought
james kay did not underestimate the power of minutes
anthony should we
because the mean me prevail despite overwhelming evidence to the contrary
and they prevailed largely because the system is so entrenched
when the system is entrenched that means that embraced and maintained by all major social
institutions from the family to the state that it's become
has expressed in this quote from a nineteenth century french political economist
can you see magazine
when plunder becomes a way of life for men and women living together in society
they create for themselves a course the time in the course of time a legal system that authorizes it
and a moral code
that glorifies the
and when we are born into an entrenched system such as carnism we inevitably absorbed systems logic around
in other words we internalize
carnism we were able to
look at the world through the lens of carnism
and criticism uses a set up defenses that distort our perceptions of meat and the
animals we eat so we can feel comfortable enough to consume them
for instance carnism teaches us to see animals objects
so that we refer to this turkey
rather than someone
are we call this little baby
and it's
thank you
rather than here she
criticism teaches us animal has abstractions as lacking in individuality and personality of their own
and then simply as abstract members of the general group about which we made
and generalized assumptions a pig is a pig
and all things are the same
like another victim
the violent ideologies we give them numbers rather than names
this is summed up by a meat cutter who i interviewed before my doctoral dissertation who said to me
i don't think of farmed animals individuals i wouldn't be able to do my job
if i got personal with them
when you say individuals union is unique person has unique thing with its own name its own characteristics you
yeah i'd really rather not know about
i'm sure it has
but i'd rather not it
end carnism and teaches us place animals in rigid categories in our minds that we
can harbour very different feelings and carry out very different behaviors toward different species
for example
a female meters were interviewed told me that she regularly consumes
pour me et cetera et cetera and when i asked her if she
feel she stopped
and she looked at me with an offended expression
and she answer well let's just say i came to your house and you told
me that i had just eaten real
i probably bombing
what i have to get out of my system
and when i asked her why she said
because deal comes from a baby
and i can intervene e
and when we look at the world through the lens and partners and we fail
to see the absurdities other systems so we see images like this or like this
someone mutilating their own body so that they can be
and we take no notice
rather than take offense
all we see images like this
more this and we
rather than cry
volterra was right
if we believe absurdities we shall commit
stopping is as our said it's like belly any cos you've got gotten
rid of to hyperparameters potentially three
if you were going to choose you know regulation constant
so yeah is more convenient compute nationally also
a right
and is not yet it is nine tally zero yeah
so those commun thing that perhaps there might be overfitting
on the validation set if it's too small
i think i haven't even address and i'm hoping to
yeah what is the choice for the training validation set split that's
i can give you some numbers but like the core on it
tends to be know like and this often it's ten thousand four validation
set and fifty thousand fortraining
but for a very small dataset it's early stopping is a little bit
annoying with respect to that
yeah yeah yeah
how many times you evaluate
yeah one last question yes yeah
well eventually so the question is whether these curves will continue
if you've you know if you reach zero error
you should have zero gradients so learning anymore
so then this curve should stop you know moving
so beyond that's as you reach you know as you get closer and closer
to perfect performance as you would tend to expect validation set
curve to increase i don't we frankly don't have like i got the
perfect intuition for what happens after you reach this point
because you tend to ignore all you care about his
evi gone beyond this point and after that
things happen don't with the care but
i would that joe expectation is that yes this would continue increasing
you can see that like that there's not a
like you know i wouldn't be concerns a i on experimented increase
the but it stayed somewhat flat that's you know not silly bug anything
like that all right so moving on
a few other things to know about when training neural nets
so i think that you should definitely do if you have a real
valued data so inputs x where the dimensions are continuous
use deafening normalize your data that is subtract
the training set mean for each dimensions computing the mean for
each dimension separately and subtracting
dividing each dimension by the training set standard deviation is
also a good thing and it's been shown to often speed up training
in terms of the number of epochs required for convergence for
reaching that over underfitting or fitting point
yes so what
yes you don't do that if you data binary yes that's for reeled
valued so non banner binary or multinomial data
the rest of
yes so so for for binary observations essentially this scale
is going to be i mean this scale like zero to one is just like
you know it's not a numerically stable scale
i guess is the best way could describe it
so that is imperfectly that's we can define
that's one thing the other thing is decaying learning rates
so far but i just that's the s gradient descent
have assumed i describe it as using a constant learning rate but
you can do better and this i'm sloops very
quickly mention a few ways of no more sophisticated optimization
and we're going to think of the
sort of dividing the
the probability of being misled among these functions with a distribution q
where we're sort of allowing
dividing the delta if you like among
these functions with each function f fn getting assigned q and fraction of delta
where we assume that the sum of the q ends is less than or equal
to one
and then we can do
what is known as the union bound
by applying that
previous results
for each
individually and bounding its probability is being less than qn delta
and therefore the if we just sum up the probabilities of all of these any
of these misleading as we get because the sum of the q and was one
we get delta
so in other words the likelihood that any of the mislead us
in other words there exists an offence for which it has zero training error but
it's error is bigger than the corresponding apps along
which is
what i computed as one n log one n qn delta
that was just the
this quantity here
with t
substituted for by qn delta
here so the
the probability that any of these
he e
it is
doesn't hold is less or equal to delta
so i mean if you're the union bound is a simple idea but
it's just basically
if you think of the space of
samples that you might generate
there's little region where
function one might
mislead us
there's another region where function to might mislead us and this has size q one
delta size two delta
they might of course overlap in q three delta might overlap
and so on
but if the sum of all of these assuming they don't overlap is less than
delta then certainly if they do overlap is going to be less
so that's just the basis of the union bound very simple idea
and so we get the
the result
so this doesn't take into account any connections between the functions this is assuming that
in some way no relationship between them at all
and clearly that's a weakness of this bound
but we can turn it around and we get our first theorem
so all of these say we when we do that the analysis you want to
think of it in bounding the probability of being misled but this doesn't really read
very well to a practitioner of machine learning so you have to sort of turn
it around and turn it into a statement about the generalisation performance so we do
that by just saying OK
that was the probability of being misled so with probability one minus that
content of that that we were misled so with probability at least one minus delta
over the random m samples the generalisation error of a function f and
there is this nice relation it has zero training error than its true error is
bounded by this quantity
now was we were misled by any functions so any function has zero training error
as this band
so this is a first learning theory has a very sort of standard formerly or
learning theory statistical learning theory bounds have something of that shape to them
typically one n
they typically have a log one delta buried in there somewhere
that's a nice feature because it means that the size of the sample you need
in order to sort of
up your confidence about the result is very benign in other words you know you
can sort of of delta or multiply delta by
one of the in you only have to add one extra example so you kind
in a very nice sort of
the nine situation as far as dependent on delta is concerned
now the depend the other term here log one on q and is something
you can think of is the complexity of the function fn that we're interested in
measured in some sort of
bits or even its or whatever
in the way that the distribution but we chose qn determined so we of going
to choose q and we can think of this in a bayesian senses the prior
over functions
the we're thinking that they're more likely functions were going to give higher IQ in
and going to suffer therefore better bound here
but the ones that are less likely QM will be larger and we may be
in the worst situation
as far as the spam but still log one on q and so again it's
quite a benign
entry so we can think about is the sort of complexity or description length of
the function fn
notice that we have to define a function qn before we see the data we
can't cheat
if we did have a distribution that we knew that was the distribution governing the
likelihood of different functions then the expected generalisation error will be best if we choose
q equal to p
that sort of the bayesian
and indeed this sort of is if you like the starting point of the PAC
bayes analysis of the relationship between
a bayesian prior
and so on
so mean you
i could
the mass of the sun
same idea
if you take
you should off
you make it
you make it dark
you dormitory
and in front of the mirror
the amazing experience
now we have to do it for you because but i told you i really
where cotton doesn't work was cotton so well
we really have to do this in ireland and when you take the nylon true
not only do you cracking
to actually see the glow of these teeny-weeny little sparks
you actually i like it like that is an experiment that you
i cannot miss
and i would suggest you try that
this weekend
do it was a friend that even more
we all perhaps remember when you just walk around
you normal things during the day
the roads in rooms and you
i want to leave the room when you touch the doorknob
you get a shock
this spark that flies over
the electricity
even when you touch to person
sometimes if few
this so
there you go
and your picture and read all these roles the then stuff
just doesn't want to come off because as you roelof
there friction and gets charged and often get scrambled up
it's very bad very difficult to handle
the whole experience that
boxes with chocolate the same thing happens as you take it off
your charges whether you like it or not
i know
i want to do an experiment
need volunteer and in school who actually is wearing
preferably not all cotton
i think simon you have a beautiful wonderful
parker so if you
willing to sacrifice a little bit for the sake of science
and come over here
and sit down here
just relax
make sure that your feet off the ground
so i'm going to do now simon going to be q was kept for
and that i dq is kaffir for
you get charged
since i don't want you to be the only person who suffers under these experiments
were also stand on an insulated stool
so if you become for instance positively charged so i don't know what it is
positive or negative i will get the amount of charge so we share
in the charge
and that i dq
you will charge up more and more
and i will charge of more and more
and then
we will have to convince the class
that that we are both charged
and we will do that
in a way that will be hopefully rather
and we just start beating you little bit
to make you feel at home we know each other right
OK now of course as i mentioned to you
these experiments were well when it is dry
if you have to wet it won't work
but let's see you sweat a little bit too much then it doesn't work too
we're ready
i have here in my
and a neon flash two
and although we don't know yet what voltages
because we learn about that in this course
to get good flesh out of these you need about a few thousand votes
so we'll see
will make it dark shortly
and i hold the flashlight the flesh
flight in one hand
the neon discharge tube and then simon will touch it
on the other side
and if we succeeded
you may see some light
simon look at the first don't touch it yet because we're going to make it
all the way dark
you know it's there
OK make it darker marcos that's it
but it
OK i tried again touch it again
OK thank you
we have some light
thank you very much
equal charges repel each other
i show that
the demonstration was the balloons
here we have an instrument this is called event graph
it's named after professor van der graaf who invented it was an MIT professor
and this instruments
which i will not discuss
in any detail about
but you will understand it later on in the course
i tell you all about it later
think this instrument as the super amber wrong
and although we don't know yet what
i mentioned already the twenty thousand fold between
in this installment you have to think in terms of several hundred thousand four
the history of the world has have
because you're population is the whole world
now you omit the information from the eight i can let you look at the
this are the sex column
i think this and you find out that they make from
there are a lot of men and women
and then maybe you will not just to predict and say OK i have a
little bit better off if i come along being among because it's more exceptional
if it so this is
pierre predictor in the
those you that said are you look at several of attributes
before making your
of course nobody would play the same
you want to see everything of the observation before making the prediction
so if you see all the values for all non class at
then you can conditions
history of the if it's separation of black hair and blue eyes and it turns
out that this subpopulation includes many of the women and very few of the men
all them i may switch my predictions
so what you are predicting the maximum a posteriori is predicting the value of the
that makes as high as possible
the conditional probability
indigenous to the observation that you have about
look at what values you have
check your ladyship you find that for people with this
over observations with centrifuge
classes are split in this way and the largest one
is the one that has
i would higher reliability or may be much higher depending on the number of members
this is due a predict the maximum a posteriori it is not necessarily the one
you choose maybe you would
sure some other machine or you know there are other options
but this is one
it is an excellent predictor
if you can use
but you will not be able to
assume that we have article should we have for our usage
this is
this is nothing really
not useful values this is nothing
still you count how many conditional probabilities and its
the the twenty
because the neighbor memory among
but it was part of it
you need to estimate all the probability
and with
how many of the original you need to estimate the parameters of fuel
and each observation only contributes to one
twenty two to twenty
items just to make sure that you have also been used one candidate
and we find candidate don't estimate the probability you have only a handful of them
i mean any sense if insufficient but at the end of definitely if you don't
have enough already
not going to argue you will never have so many
in the last thing that i will show you
maximum posterior is doing a
yesterday of course which
and i will ask you
where i am today what do we know that
naive bayes
assumes independence
it is one way
assume that
so first let's take this quantity the compost it this way my bayes is that
they are not you john
in the same game using a
and now you observe that for all values of c which are the different values
i said well
all time
you can
there are
to do this
if you know
they something
if you
because are in you
in one
that's so
not you
now i have
the problem
you get
now in the
also you
he it is now
if you not
he was also
a lot of c
so much for
so there not
world of particles
you are
you we need
it is
is a
i'm sorry
here's to
and we use
i mean
as you
and when
so year
well that's right
for very
it's a small
all right
thank you
it will
this is where
no o
all these that very
and on
one two
it's not
on the
he was
can use the structure
you know
but pressure
OK now
he sits on the board of
it is
all o
the goal
what's next
three or
i mean
world we really
all four
the pressure
you know
you read
so the
one of
let's use it
in fact you
the lego motor will lead will turn this
relative to the attachment
that's the robot kids
so you they wrote of robot will be able to do this
and the robot will have eyes these are photosensors photo resistors actually
so the idea is going to be that there is information available in those sensors
for figuring out where light is so that you could track at
your job will be
to build a circuit that's the thing
the connects via cables these red gables in yellow cables connected by a cable to
this head will give you the head
your job will be to make the circuit
that's converts
signal from the photo resistor which is in proportion to light
and figures out how to turn the motor
to get ahead
interface the light
and then shipped out information down to the robot to let the robot turn its wheels together body
so it's kinda like
the light comes on right over here the were looks at is yes reality
so that's the idea in the third module is to incorporate new sensing capabilities into the robot
the final module is on probability and planning
and the idea here
is to
one about how you make
there are robust to uncertainty
and they can
can implement complicated plans
that they are robust uncertainty
so there's a number of things that we will do including
creating maps of spaces that the robot doesn't understand
telling the figuring out telling the robot howto
localize itself how
how is it woke up suddenly in an environment could figure out where it is
how to make a plan
and as an example
i'll show you
the kind of system that we will construct
here the idea is that we have a robot the robot knows where it is
imagine that the jeeps and the reason but imagine there's a the robot knows where
it is and knows where it wants to go that's the star
but has no idea what kind of signals are in the way
so you know if you were a robotic driver in boston
you know
that you started out at home and you will end up in a mighty
but there's is annoying obstacle you know the old people
that's used should in principle these things that you know
data that's that's kinda the idea of
so he so
i know where i am on the robot i don't worry about nor were being summarized information here
where i am is purple
where i wanna be is golden
i have a plan
that's blue
my plan is very simple i don't know anything about anything other than i mean
i mean what famine i wanna go good cambridge
so you know blast
so i imagine that the best way to do there's a straight line
okay so now what i'm going to do
turn on the robot and the cart in the robot has now made one step
and i told you before about these sonar sensors
from the sonar sensors the robots learn now
but there seems to be something reflecting
and each of these black dots
he got a reflection from the black dots from me from these sonar sensors that
means it's probably a wall there are person or something that in principle i should
in the red dots represent
the obstacles so close i really can't get here
so i'm excluded from the red spots because i'm too big
the black box the black spots seem to be an obvious obstacle
the red spot seem to be where i can't get
i still wanna go from from where i am purple
two hour i wanna be golden so what i do is i compute a new play
okay then
i started taking a step along the plan and as i'm stopping along
okay so now i think that i can go from where i started over here
i have to go around this wall that i didn't know about initially
so not just are driving it looks like right i'm getting married
right and i know i go straight down here mean there's another ball game what i do now
so the robot goes around long
it didn't know when it started what kinds of obstacles that would encountered that has its driving it around
but i didn't work and start over
so the idea is
this robot
is executing any very complicated plan
the player and has in fact many some plans
and the sub-plan all involve uncertainty you didn't know where the walls were when it started
and when it's all done is going to have figured out where the walls work and provided us away
presumably find a way to negotiate the maze and get to be
to be a destination
so the idea then
if you would have if you were asked to write a conventional kind of program
for solving that's it might be kind of hard because the number of contingencies involved
what we will do is break down the problem and figure out simple and elegant ways
to deal not only with uncertainty but how do you make complex plans
so as i said
primary pedagogy is going to be like this
and so the ramolefi is
it how the course is organized
you can introduce herself and something about your background
sure thanks kevin lynch chief software architect adobe was chief software architect that media which
combines adobe about two years ago and and i've been writing software for about twenty
seven years now and
and i was early macintosh developer when the mackinnon eighty four hours writing software for
creating adventure games three d graphics package and publishing software and since i worked on
things like three maker frame actually also got acquired by the i did the macintosh
version from maker with two other the gas and that i was the general magic
for about five years old ten handheld communicators
before people really wanted to have them was around ninety two and then i went
to mecca media ninety six so seven there are now eleven years and just had
a great time there we have worked on
dreamweaver got to build the team built dreamweaver
which is a great honour and pleasure to do that is an excellent two and
the dreamweaver name by the way is the code name that i made up and
we working on the project would it mean to be the product name but then
we can think of a better name and so the shipping history river and then
flash was actually created by two guys jonathan gain robert roberts had to me and
and they built the runtime and the tools just the two of them and they
didn't have any q eighteen or
managers or anything like that so when required
that technology american media
so i started working on it and that was in ninety seven and so
since then i've been working with the flash team over the past decade to really
grow flash being and is usually just animation runtime that should cartoons to really
become an application runtime has a virtual machine and the scripting engine and is able
to run rich internet applications you know as well as you can still do not
animations in two and most recently
for the past five years i've been working on this project that's called air and
air is about to come out early next year and this is the time for
web applications to run on your desktop outside the browser so you you don't have
to have the constraints of browsers web that you can access local machines resources you
can raise notifications application can appear in the start menu or the dock was ten
hours and i can't latex
and your apps can run consistently across OS is this is really exciting projects it's
been kind of the holy grail the software industry to try to make one of
these runtimes that actually does work reliably across operating systems and people have tried to
do that before
java came closest to that i really couldn't get reliable runtime that were consistently and
so with air though i believe that we are on track to do it were
using technologies that already work across the web so
the flash player already is reliable across operating systems html of course is using the
webkit open source engine and then the PDF works across OS is and so we're
using formats already work words deploying them for new purpose now and
so that's been really exciting project for the past five years or so
that's what i've been up to almost three decades of soft
these two hack your memories first hacker approach yes i still program i may care
applications of which actually is really exciting so it's kind of brings back the energy
of the early days of computing when you could just as an individual available application
and do really quickly and your friends now you traditional application development it's pretty hard
to build applications that use these big tools takes a long time to develop the
application there's many thousands of is you've got no but with web development it's got
really exciting and now you can build these things really fast so the pace of
development increased again it's this revolution in software development web software so you i do
that my early work i was
my first computer was a digital PDP eleven
seven seventy and
and we was first allowed only to use the the line printer the terminal wrote
a paper and then i was able to use this year t while and
the first couple programs are actually were on hollerith cards realities and number two pencil
and color in the boxes and then you get the stack of cards and they
run it and you get results back so i got beyond having to just use
the cards by making friends with the math with the math teachers and they let
get the computer directly
but i was one of the things that we did we are all trying to
hack each other stuff basically and so we used to play this game called core
worse which was a very good thing to be doing but we basically try to
freeze everybody out of using the computer lab who could survive the longest using the
the the the machine you by reducing each other's quotas and things like that and
there's also the stack with the the line printer which actually printed entire lines that
once you know that you know see around anymore but it sort of kind of
painting the page with the head and actually had aligned with the page on one
life to published content it is called line printer and go plan plan plan the
page would be shooting up and so on
i wrote this program ones that i try to see if i can make the
paper hit the ceiling computer and just by sending line feeds really fast the printer
and sure enough you can you can do so
anyway we typed into we go that
past research
we had no results
we could also yahoo plus
and we got out of you who research so what is i don't standing as
far as research is concerned
as long as you mentioned your
almost dream team with jim that's a really good question so do has been very
focused on delivering software to people being very pragmatic about that in that committee before
something i really enjoying the about being w right now is that there is a
research team adobe their publishing very much right now and i think we should be
publishing more but we do have a team of researchers and are led by
a fellow named thomas bligh
and tom leads which called adobe technology labs and we do research primarily in the
area of graphics right now and recently there are some technology that we been working
on about splicing panning scenes together and you can place for example static photos together
this the same
you really don't
for you read you can
you you you
so far
on the other
you know what we use
you try your
the main hall
but it's particularly relevant for this sort of measure
one is reliability
there's not a measurement error
and one crude way to think about reliability is a test is reliable
if you test the same person
at different times and you get the same result
my bathroom scale reliable if whenever i stand on it gives me more or less
the same number it's not reliable if it's off by ten pounds
in the course of the day
if i give you a personality test now
and it says that you're anxious and defensive
wall and then give it to you tomorrow and associate common minded
it's not a reliable test
so while trust over time
validity is something different
validity is
is that your test measures what it's supposed to measure
so we really need to sort of a good test forget about how reliable it
is does it tap what you're interested in so for example suppose i determine your
by the date of your birth
i figured out what they are born and i have a theory that from that
predicts how smart you are
that's my and intelligence has to date of birth
maybe people born in january the dumbest people born in december smartness
is that
i was born on christmas eve is that
is that a reliable test yes
it's a wonderfully reliable tensile test you today architecture tomorrow at test next year tested
today you die
i get the same IQ score
is it a valid test it's the joke is apple not valid test it has
nothing to do with intelligence but you notice these are two different things
somebody can be reliable but not valid
on and something can be valid
and not reliable
there are no shortage of personality tests
you can get them all over the place
including on the web
so i took one recently
i took i took which superhero or
a series of questions
i determining what superhero you are
you could take this yourself if you want to
the same web page by the way offers you testing whether you're hot or not
most of us that later on when i did this
told me i was batman
good article of gadgets and about to help innocent not suffer the pain you have
now to be honest though
it is neither reliable nor valid when i first the test they came up as
the incredible hulk
i don't change my answers have been was wonder woman
and finally
finally out of frustration i carefully tailored my answer so i be batman but the
fact that i can do that
well raises questions about about but the reliability of this measure and its validity
here's an example of a real world example
this is in black and white format
version of the war shock
test there were shocked inkblot test how many people have heard
of the shock test
is there anybody here is actually in any sort of situation taken a rorschach test
some people scattered taken up it was originally used only for psychiatric cases but then
became extremely common
about eighty percent of clinical psychologists claim to use it
and most graduate programs
american psychological association
who are accredited teacher
catholic seminaries
he was it
for people who want to join the seminary
it was invented by a guy named hermann our rorschach shock
he devoted his entire life
the inkblot test his nickname when he was a teenager
i'm not kidding you was imply
and the idea is
by looking at the what's and and seeing what somebody says you a great insights
into the nature of their personality into on what they are
hundred and twenty degrees
this is my look number three
so each one of those
well given the math that has this shape but they are offset now
in phase five hundred twenty degrees
so sort all rotating in exactly the same way
like so
so the second one
i will give me enough
if five
right to estimate that roughly
something like this
this is the number two
later in time
number three
i will again be
look like this
number three
well we we call these three
face current
and a three-phase current
can produce a rotating magnetic field
we will make one for you
the first explain to you how it works
so if the period of number of only sixty words
and the period of number two was also sixty hertz number three is also six
but there's also that
in terms of
suppose you're looking down on a horizontal table this is horizontal table
and i have here
so no it
this is one and the same sort of nodes
when the current ones
clockwise you also want to run clockwise there
but is open you
we put something in there
we call this number one
but i have another one which is
physically rotating on the twenty degrees
it's here
and i'm going to feed current number two for those called later
those courses and number two
and never third one
i'm going to run
number three
the corals
so one sees current number one
two three car number two in three seasons current number three
at the moment
that the current through number one reaches a maximum
the current
in two and three
down by a factor of two you can check that form
during my lecture
i went a little bit too fast over the part that is coming up now
so i'm going to redo it a little slower to make it more clear
when the current through
reaches a maximum
let's say then that the magnetic field due to loop one
it's is in this direction
the current through this one
and the current through this loop
two times smaller
you may want to check that
but it just so happens that the vectorial some
of the magnetic field produced by
number two
and by look number three
also happened to be in this direction so the net magnetic field is in this
let's now look
third of the period later in time
the current in the loop number two reaches a maximum
so its magnetic field
is now
in this direction
you guessed it of course
it just so happens that the vectorial some
of the magnetic field produced by the other two loops
is now also in this direction
and if we now look again one third of period later
when the current through loop number three reaches a maximum
then the magnetic fields
will be in this direction
the victory of some of the magnetic field of the other two loops will also
be in this direction
and look now what has happened
in one
complete period
the magnetic field started out like this
one third of the period later it was like this
and one third of the period later it was like this
so what we have created is now rotating magnetic fields and it rotates
in one
all the way around three hundred sixty degrees
OK let's not go back to my original lecture
rotates once around
in the period
of your alternating current that is sixty hertz current
then it will rotate around
sixty or sixty times per second
so if we put a
magnet in here
these magnets rule
i want to go around when want to follow this
rotating magnetic field
and we call that
synchronous motor
so the rotor of such a synchronous motor itself will be a magnet
and it would rotate around
with the frequency of the alternating current which you need a three-phase current for that
so the magnetic field rotates
i can also place
in here
this is again a horizontal surface
going to do it right here
he was that
was crazy look with three-phase current
we can also put in here
conducting sphere or in my case i will use conducting ag
when the magnetic field rotates around
is a continuous
magnetic flux change
the surface of that
i feel eg
and so
going to run could any currents
seven any current going around the magnetic field
then the magnetic field in the every current will cause the talk on the current
similar way
when we discussed earlier the idea of a motor that you're going to build
linear regression on this new know that may be a linear function to the of
more less
that's a line which is not a very good fit to data
on you around there doesn't have to decide whether the features users maybe you want
to toss the quadratic function
but this is required right here so maybe you want to model this is new
x six square plus maybe some function of vector something that is around the features
on and off the wall you can probably come also features the model is OK
but open album that
you can use without needing to do that
now suppose you want to evaluate
hypothesis h at a certain point
thirteen creep points located at let's say
you want to know you want to know what the predictive value of y at
this at this position x
so for linear regression
what we were doing was one thing to minimize
summarize why i wanted to
and returned it has also OK so that was the new regression
in contrast locally weighted linear regression and things slightly different
going to look at this point x
and then i'm going to look at my data set and take into account
only the data points that are
so in all of the city of x
so we look at you know when i went to valley my hypothesis is going
to look only in the in the vicinity of
the point this point where one to evaluate the hypothesis
and then i'm going to take
this is just a few points
and i will on
apply linear regression
to further streamline just to the subset of the data
using this up term subset what was about
so i think there's this edit i think straight line you get a straight line
like that
and what do is that
validate this particular value straight line
that will be the value of it well it that this this would be the
predictive value
four around
this will be the value the my hypothesis OK
nokia way to regression
we can therefore no longer had form formalized
loki was regression because
on some of our i
to minimize that
where these terms study superstring i are called way
and there are many possible choice always adjust the right one down to e to
the minus the
so let's look at what these weights really are so notice that on suppose you
have a training example five
so there exi is very close to the small right
then on
maximizing the small civic zero then this is e to the minus zero
it is zero is this one
so excise close to x then w i will be close to one another was
the weight associated the i th training example because one
if x i x are closely
conversely if the timeline
it's like
an award of the ivy
the first zero right
this is
if excise very far from and this is e to the minus some large number
and needs to mine is a large number of course is here
so the picture is
at a certain point x showing the exact cost
and my data set
you see the that
then i'm going to give the points close to this large weights give the points
far away a small way
and so
for the points that are far away w i will be close to zero
so it as if the points are far away on
they were not contribute much all the summation things is some over i of one
times square drive in terms of course by points play zero times square always point
so the effect of using this weighting is that the way to the russian
it's the same attractor state paying much more attention to fitting the points close by
accuracy whereas for ignoring the contributions
so far away
c so it turns out there are many other weighting functions you can use on
it turns out that there are different in different communities of researchers tend to
choose different choices by all on there is there is a somewhat of literature on