the start with its profits
he is
in both
yes this universal
you are in
both extremes knowledge and
the opposite lane
morning today
problem in the sense that would be a massive
in order to come to both human and
the things going on here
we not only economic changes this simplification currently about
one of the
that means that we
human the one to of my face
i know
one experiment i know this is what you're not going to be
OK do what
the in connecting
you know
it's pretty low
he worked so that
the computer can cope
very well in the united states right up until
you you're on humans but what
you can't you don't even need to provide
think of of course
you can directly by
moving because you know you connect your computer computer
and like you know
i think it is something frightens you almost
five one
first of all
out of goal
in i
i don't so
i mean that the goal
united states
who in the greek letters
this is
but it is you're talking about you know about it
in now is now
but they actually you know we want to make
your brain images
electromagnetic which can be very complex
what we
we are
it's easy to reproduce those ways
we want you to use
you like the one
what we
you read about it and not to mention about these topics all of them
control manipulation
your properties that is changing general but general case
for the goal
so what are you
in the university
it's the connecting thing
keep your fuzzy so
three human capability into a remote control
you can make
in the leader
that that's
and the only icon guys in the can media you want to know
the fact that it of course you
but we want to be there
they get me this probably the
the question is the following
when you may be like control like
i don't hear you are
the guy
you and i don't know about you
the cars
how do i experience
it's like you know michael kind of compromise or we don't know
they claim that they did experiments showed
for this action
o thing going around freely but i i'm not know
it looks pretty so
what i'm saying we don't want to go one it's not i i have
the mother
what i'm saying is that featured ongoing now my which
in way the
she wanted to be human basic idea of human is based on the fact that
i think i hear of their
if you get four
we can use
and so on in which the band
we people avoid
both extremes of the mind
you get this notion of one four claims we have to be it just download
from one to another
on the other hand you this report that not in the remaining
now there are
we don't know
we all know that human nature is not the case and she
so we need more than ever now just coming from the here we need for
here we
here we need not
in what sense
it's fun
and to do that
today's societies
so size of
not much
knowledge matters to
it is that
i would say is
not that
we don't know enough you know about the
we have no
more and more in the sense that
depressingly well
but it's just a perceptron and it doesn't have multiple layers of representation. it has to
be the case for big complicated problems, multiple layers of representation are going to be a win
i'll try to convince you more of that later
what's wrong with back propagation? the reason it can't compete with support vector machines on many of the tasks
it was tried at, or doesn't do any better at least, is it requires labeled training data
and the big labeled sets is tough
the learning time doesn't scale well--it's slow in deep networks
and deep networks often gets stuck in poor local optima
they're much better than random, but we now know that: because we've got better ways of
training them of, deep networks can find much better optima than you find by just doing back propagation
from the labels
so the idea for overcoming those limitations
within the framework of neural nets in a very loose sense, is we're going to
try and keep the efficiency of doing learning by doing gradient descent some cost function
but it's going to be a different cost function, at least to begin with. instead of trying
to model the probability of the label given the image
just try to model the probability of an image
is going to build generative model of images
and once we've built this model, maybe it'll be able to say that's a likely image and this is an unlikely
the main purpose of building this generative model is going to be so we have
these features that we can use for something else later
but there are also other reasons you might want to build it like if you're monitoring a nuclear
power station you might like to just know that it's in some improbable state and then
you run
throughout the 1990's, starting the 80's, throughout the 1990's, people developed an area called
graphical models
i'm gonna use the term belief net
to mean essentially a directed
graphical model
which is acyclic
this term is not really very well defined
so here's an example of a graphical model. these are
variables that can have values
and these are the observed variables
and you assume that when you make an observation, it was generated by some model like this
so there's three problems
one is
and what's the structure of the model
i'll basically ignore that problem in this tutorial
a second
problem is
if you think you know the structure of the model, that is how many units
in each layer and how many layers, can you infer what state of these hidden variables probably
caused is visible effects
it's going to be a probabilistic model and therefore you're not going to be able
to infer these things for sure
indeed there may be many many different combinations of states you might have led to
the at least we would like to be able to pick some likely combination
or maybe pick some hidden configuration with a probability that's proportional to how likely it was to have cause
given the current model
that's the inference problem
and that's assuming that you know all the parameters that define how the states of
these two variables determine the state of this variable
what these arrows mean is that these guys determine the state of that guy
the learning problem is: can we now adjust all these parameters
so as to make this model more likely to generate the observed data?
so learning is going to consist, if you knew the structure, of setting these parameters to
make the model more likely to generate the observed data
and then perceptions is gonna consist of seeing some data and trying to figure out how
it was probably caused by this model and then saying the states of these guys are my
guess about the underlying causes
and then maybe if this one says
tiger and this one says running towards me then i do something
i'm going to use nets composed of stochastic binary variables for most of this tutorial
but i will talk about other kinds of variable later
so they're stochastic binary variables
bernoulli variables they get some input
which in the generative model come from above
it's the sum of the
states of the units in the layer above
times the weights on the connections plus some bias term
and they give some output
and the output is gonna be a 1 or a 0. they're gonna be stochastic units
the probability that it's a 1 is going to follow this logistic curve
so if the total input is 0, it's gotta,
it flips a coin essentially. if the total input is big and positive, it's nearly always on
and vice versa so this is just the standard logistic function that's also used in
some backpropagation networks
so now when we try and learn one of these nets
one thing that is easy to do with one of these nets is if i
tell you
the parameters on these connections the weights on all these connections
and i ask you show me the kinds of things the network believes in, the
kinds of examples it wants to generate
well, the parameters are gonna include biases for the top level units
so using the biases for the top level units i decide whether they should be
on or off
then knowing the states of these two units
i decide whether this one should be on or off, this one may also have bias
and in parallel i can decide whether these ones should be on or off
and then knowing the states of all these three, i can decide in parallel whether these ones should
be on or off so i can generate
a binary observed vector
and i can do it again and i'll typically get a different answer because it's stochastic
so it's very easy by doing what's called an ancestral pass just bandpass this
to produce samples of what the model believes in.
that's easy.
it's much harder to infer, given a sample that you assume is produced by the model,
how the model produced it
it's hard to even get
any good guess about that
that's because of a phenomenon called explaining away
so it's going to be very hard to learn deep nets like this because you can't even
to the do the inference, and to do the learning you need to be able to do
the inference
at least approximately
but for now let's suspend
disbelief and suppose that we could do the inference so suppose that
we could infer
some probable state of the hidden variables
we could
pick a state in proportion to the probability that that was the state that generated the
observed vector
then the learning is very easy in a sigmoid belief net
so let's suppose we want to learn the weights coming into this unit i
these are the units in the layer above
let's suppose this is some hidden unit
what we need to do
take a sample from the posterior which gives you a binary state for each of
these guys
and say: what we want to do is maximize
the probability
the observed binary state would have been produced by
the states that were observed up here
so the probability of producing the observed binary state
i'll call p i
that's the probability this is one given the states of these guys
which is just, ignoring biases, is the logistic of
the sum of these weights times these states
so that's the probability the units up here would have turned it on
p i
and we have some actual state for it, s i
and so
the maximum likelihood learning rule turns out to be: change the weight in proportion to
that's a learning rate
the difference between the state and the probability it's turned on, multiplied by the
i call this the presynaptic state the state of the unit that's driving it here
and the reason learning is going to happen is because the state of this guy when
you did inference
doesn't just depend on what these are up to, it depends on what's going on down here
so typically it won't be the same as the p i
and this will make the p i more like the s i
so the learning is nice and easy
it's the inference that's hard
and i want you to have an understanding for why inference is hard because it
turns out getting rid of that problem in the inference is the whole secret to making
these deep belief nets easier to learn.
the person next door you like a there's always the right where you thinking bottom-up
design you get uncomfortable calling methods that don't exist riots like but that doesn't exist
in like it's cool man right
and then we hold hands and sing kumbaya on everything good because of the and
carol going to know what to do so sometimes you just right methods and they
don't exist and it's fine because you're the one that's going to be writing them
so eventually they will exist right it's not like you're sitting there like the lighting
candles make some magic incantations hoping the go to show that not isabelle you know
it's not very
and you're right i have a friend one actually that would computer science i didn't
bother to tell them that that wasn't sure but if you think about it so
we can be pretty and i was kind of mean but that's all right he
does government now
we pick up to be present and guess what after we do that we've when
that's done we'll have picked up all the the first from that poll were standing
on and we would have put two next door for every people we picked up
so we're done with this while if we know that something is true is that
there's no more beekeepers on now pile because the first president is no longer true
so i have some pile next to me say on the next corner that has
twice as many people as on and so what i want to do i just
want to move the pile next door
and that's why function you like reckoning that sure why not so what we need
to right now well we need to know
you know how to put to be placed next or so let's go ahead and
write that provide private void
the person next door
right now i'm standing on a particular corner facing east what they want to put
to be put on the space in front of me and come back to where
i am still facing east some left in the same position i was when i
started how do i do that
i move
i need to put to be per so i could put a deeper part the
brain if you really wanted to you could put a formal appearance a you doing
something twice can i can i do for do before i called for in cycles
zero i less than two i plus plus probably for sure
but there is not always writing program is gonna put two but the first because
two lines the for loop put it into line still now what do i do
ah yeah rock on i move backward right which allows me to move back one
step and keep the same orientation so i end up my post condition is essentially
the same as my precondition except i've moved one b over to the output to
be present in the next spot and move backward you like a i already wrote
that so everything now in terms of instructions the carol understands at this point i
don't need to go any further so know output to represent store so the only
thing left to do in this program is to move the pile next or back
to where i am now
OK so what that means is how do i move that pile back to where
i am
so i'll call this for lack of well i know what the
function name is all oldest or the method name in order to steal it from
here can sometimes you just get tired of typing are right move the pile next
or back well
the place that i call this right i call this up here i'm not actually
on the pile next or what i call around my precondition is i am on
the avenue before the problem facing the pile but i'm not on the pile so
the first thing i need to do in terms of moving the pile next or
back is i need to move over to where the pile so now i'm standing
on a pile of twice as many beekeepers and i want to move all the
beeper back one so
what can i do
i could pick people but there's something i want to do multiple times
i need to have a while loop right and i'm going to do something what
condition i want to test right
in the first president right so as long as the first president there's still more
work for me to do because i there's still more be presented to move back
so what are the first president
what i move one beeper back move
one per back
all right again haven't yet that's fine but when this loop is done what i
know is i've exhausted all the people on this poll because every time i would
be prepared and i picked it up i moved it back one spot and hopefully
that method brought me back should bring me back to the place i'm standing right
now and i just keep doing this until transferred all the peepers so after transferred
all the people what do i need to do to satisfy my post condition which
i want to go back to the place i just transferred all the beavers
i need to move
backwards because all the beavers were transferred one avenue back so i just moved backward
to go back one now
i'm almost done i'm almost feeling good but not quite i need to do the
move one p per back at this point have gone to such a simple level
that maybe i could just do this stuff i'm standing on a pile of the
first facing east how do i move one back behind me
put it down and come back to the spot on that
well first let me take a deeper right because i need to actually move the
b breaker turnaround first that's perfectly fine as multiple ways i can do things from
and pick the beeper first and what i do
rather than turning around let me just use move backward i'll take me back one
then i
but the person
and i
move to move back to this spot that i
right now all in terms of things that what i refer to as primitives right
or instructions that previously defined and there's nothing more for me to define because every
time i find some new method hey i'm just going to call that i when
i wrote it and i just kept doing that over and over until written everything
i needed to do
on move pile next or back now because move one beeper back
i pick up b prime move backward i drop it off and i move forward
time on the pile that has all the beavers
and that's what i did up here right after i double papa then i move
backwards so it's a that's a good point which always want to remember what other
things are going to happen after you execute all that
OK so now the question comes up
that's a good question the only problem arguing that carol start with an infinite number
of the prisoners back right so if i pick up all five people the corner
that on that and then i take a step back to our i think about
five people and i want to put them all down and double them i don't
know that there are five anymore because africa cup for five look might be put
back in like manner i have infinitely many beekeepers infinity plus five and that looks
like infinity
that is a matter of fact if you takes cs one of three which encouraged
to do because i teach in the winter eventually we talk about infinity right calling
and it all comes back to carol not actually doesn't come back carol
but infinity plus any number is
within reason for number thirteen argue about that is still infinity
so that's why carol cannot account if we wifi at MTV per bag perl five
and look inside and then we can put down five but now we don't have
the minus say what you do
OK if you function doesn't look like that but instead in terms of symbols looks
like this you can still use the formula
or just a trivial change of variable means that you can write it as writer
instead now this is 1 place there's no way of writing the answer in terms
of capital letter that is 1 of those cases where this notation just no good
anymore I'm going to have to write it using the owner
all plus transform all of f of and wherever you see a team you choose
the right
the thing
basically this is the same formula that as that 1 will have to stand on
my head for 1 minute to try to convince you what I will do that
now what I'd like you just to take a look at the formula you should
know what it's called
there's a number of idiots who call this the exponential shift formula and beautiful ends
on the right side you multiply that exponential that corresponds to the function but fortunately
we pre-empted that a
we do when I could call this article Wikibook calls up the difficulty is there
is no universal designations for this formula important as it is however your book calls
this t axis translation formula
translation because I'm translating on the T access and it tells me what that's why
function essentially and this tells me what the
we will plus transform it
the other formula remember at the exponential shift formula the shift or the translation occurs
on the x-axis axis in other words the formula said that F of s minus
say you did the translation
In test variable corresponded to
multiplying this by
In other words the formulas for the dual to each other this guy translates on
the left side and multiplied by the exponential on the right
the formula that you know translates on the right and multiplied by the exponential on
the left again where we're gonna calculate what I'm trying to calculate so I'm trying
to prove this 1st formula the signal the easy and the easy consequence that I'm
going to calculate will plus transform that are
it's the integral from 0 to infinity all
either the minus st lines you will of t-minus say f of t-minus said the
a formula for but what I'm trying to express it in terms of the will
plus transform of f itself
now it's trying to be the will plus transform that the problem is that here
at T minus acres
which I don't like I would like that to be just t
OK now in order to not to confuse you and this is what can everybody
of will set t 1 equal to t-minus they'll change variables school changing the variable
and that integral
I change variable indefinite
integral well mostly the limits of e to the minus that's flying out t remember
you can change the variable for words direct substitution but now I have to use
the inverse substitution t
it's trivial but T is equal to T 1 + a so the change this
I'm a substitute backwards and make that 1
about the rest of the world this becomes you have T 1
this is therefore T 1 half change the dt too but that's no problem the
1 equals the because they constant so that the the 1 at the last step
is to put in the limits now when T is equal to 0
T 1 has a value negative
so this has to be negative and when t is infinity on infinity minus there
is also from
In other words this changes to that these 2 things whatever they are they have
the same value
all I've done is change the variables make a change of variables
but now of course I wanna make this look
and when you do that well
1st multiply out the exponential
and then you get a factor in the minus st 1 that's good that goes
so here we see that we have very small
so a very small number of
so a very high number of pages
the small degree
in degree so
if you generate the beijing you link it most likely this page new page will
stay stay in that in that shape
with very small degree and then you have very
a small number of pages with high indegree so this would be like this so
this would be pages like
google yahoo and so on so
so now if you
take all the pages the that
count in degree
draw a graph
and make a log log scale
you get to
straight line so this is the most characteristic footprint of the power law in the
so small number of pages
with the highest degree in very high number of pages with the
low integration so this is a a good example
the same would be four out degree but let's
keep this
and so the next very important concepts in social networks so whole small small world
small small world network is the concept where the
try to model the motion measure
what is
the linkage
how many steps do we need to go from one part of the network to
another part of the network
is called by the diameter of the of the ground
if we
maybe you are familiar with this concept c six degrees of separation so basically this
this tells people thought this was an experiment from the sixties or seventies
there somebody was testing one science social sciences was testing
people in the US are connected so how
one piece of information how true how many steps what you would need to go
so that it comes from one end to the country to the other end of
the country and on average came out that in six steps
any person is reachable from any other person in the US at the time so
that's why it's called six degrees of
separation now
on the that
but a few years ago to measure to what would be the
the degree of separation this would be
nineteen step so from in nineteen steps you can reach from any web page
two any
other web page on developing this main connected component course
actually this was shown by simulation but basically
later on i think it was confirmed by empirical studies
so here is one example of a small
one of the
in european project collaboration effort so this is the data which organelles from
our project is solid that so
we have here
eight thousand organisations which were collaborating in a roughly
three thousand four to to two hundred thousand seven hundred projects in FP five
so we have in this photograph
each node in the graph is one organisation in two organisations are connected if they
collaborate at least one right now the
the question is
the following how far apart are two
organisations such that
so the main connected part of this network so over everybody reaches everybody is roughly
ninety four
percent of all the nodes so
five percent of all
institutions in europe are connected somehow between each other so this is one of the
vision and the maximum distance within this network of almost three thousand almost eight thousand
organisations is basically
seven steps
on average
we you can reach any any organisation
in three point one step
basically this small network is much slower of course because don't not that many
and almost forty percent of all organisations have average distance three or less
now if visualize this
so here is the
link linkage graph for the most connected
the most connected organisation which was this fraunhofer institute in germany
it's pretty large institute
which so
this is musician shows the following so if put fraunhofer in the media
and draw
all the institutions which collaborates
directly from the whole for in the first step
and then all the institutions
so each line represents one institution which if
i didn't draw the name because then it would be to domestic so
we take the glass rods
and we have the silk
in order to show you know that if i approached this neutral below
there's no positive charge on it
when it sees the positive
rather it will come
to the class
that's direction
still no charge
that's induction
many of the keep them dry
you may know understand
by rubbing amber
which the greek already knew a long time ago
the tracks
right pieces
obviously that induction
and you may also understand that if you comb your hair
and the come get charged
that you can now also pick up small pieces of paper because that's induction
even though those pieces are neutral
this phenomenon
will make the paper
good call
and i want to demonstrate that
but given the fact
the humidity is very high in this room
i prefer to make sure that my hair is very dry
so to get the maximum amount of charge
on that card
so even though i washed my hair this morning without that would never have worked
they must wash you have to do any of these experiments first but
i also want to
dry my hair because
that is important
so let's do that
so far away i don't have to do that but it's family
let's hope that that is enough
i small pieces of paper here
going to put in here and you're going to see the
projected there was a small television camera
and then i will call my hair
and i'll show you
where i can make a track those small pieces
after that first
television on
let me check my notes
to make sure that we have the
proper lighting
all lights off
and sports
and for all
there you see the
i'm going to
call my hair
there we go
you see that
some of the confetti
comes to me
but now
there's something
very special
some of the confetti comes to the call
and immediately leaves
one thing that is
why do you think that happened so
they became
i'll show you again
the pieces of paper
would be repelled by the comb
if you go down again to the table some of them
why is that
come on don't be afraid in the worst case it's wrong
you mean well
when the paper touches the call
because negative remember we had already decided that earlier the pieces of paper takes on
the negative charge because they touch the column noted both negative and so they repel
each other
that's fine
now there is another problem some pieces of paper
stuck on the call
show that to you again
you see that
this talk
and i'll leave you
the question why is that
i always leave my students
was the problem that they have to digest at home
you can discuss it with your parents you can discuss it with friends why is
it that so
immediately rebelled
but others permanently
for a long time stay on the court
the process of course is induction
that's clear
why do some
i have
nice collection
of balloons
but already too
if i run these balloons
it shouldn't surprise you that the balloon
yes try we've seen examples of
that's induction why does it stay there
the same problem with the paper and the cold
the problem with undirected graphs and factor graphs is that
many useful independencies are not explicitly represented
so the two variables have to be merely connected because some other variable depends on
right so this is a classic example from u there pearl wrote an important book
on this topic
where you're thinking of you know the sort of life in california you have rain
occasionally you have sprinklers for watering your garden or lawn and both these things can
make the ground wet
whether it rains or not and whether you're sprinklers or not
maybe marginally independent if you're spline is on the time for example that it ignores
the weather
the ground being wet depends on both of these things so here we have a
nice directed graph that represents these dependencies
if we were representing these with the factor graph or an undirected graph we would
have to join up all three of these variables into a single factor or put
undirected edge between these two
OK what we have to put this undirected edge here
because if we didn't put this undirected edge what would it mean well the graph
would look like this that would mean observing the ground was wet
would make
the probability of it having reigned or the sprinkler being on independent
and that's not true if we observe the ground is wet
there are two
reasonable explanations either rain or the sprinklers on may be both
but certainly these two variables are not independent of each other conditionally independent given
it's a bit annoying in these undirected representations that you have to connect up lots
of things that are not a priority related just because something else depends on them
and this also sort of explains it it's the way of mentioning the whole idea
of explaining away
if you have multiple explanations for something
observing that this displaying sprinkler is on would explain away
the observation of the ground was wet making it less probable that it rained
OK so there's a complicated dependency between causes and effects that
that is well captured by
direct representations
OK so
let me now talk about directed graphical models
which go by several names we could call them directed basically graphical models
or bayesian networks of there's a footnote here because you can do
maximum likelihood or frequencies learning of bayesian networks
make use of
so the question is are the inference algorithm that they make use of this kind
of conditional independence yes so in fact the message passing belief propagation algorithms
are are really making try to make use of conditional independence
the form of the belief propagation algorithm is slightly different for directed graphs the factor
graphs it turns out not to make it big
not not make it practical
so is
well it's important if
it's important if you want to
however representation of conditional independence
in your graph i mean if you basically thrown away information by converting this into
but from the point of view the
messages they get passed around on the computer algorithm you can convert directed graph into
factor graph and you know
the algorithm will run correctly still
here is a directed graph we're bayesian network or sometimes called the belief network
and it corresponds to again to factorizations of joint probability distribution the joint distribution over
these variables
factors into a product of variables given their parents as chris already introduced so
the joint probability over x one to xn is a product over each variable
the probability of each variable given its parents so the parents
e are c and d
it was very easy to
independence in an undirected graph or factor graphs it's also not very hard to do
it is the notion of separation
in directed graphs are called this the separation
the dependency separation so the idea is
if i have the directed graph
i then x is independent of y given v
if the set b
d separates ex from y
so how do we determine whether
the d separates ex from y
these d separates ex from y
every undirected path
between x and y
is blocked by d
so we're basically i mean the way i like to think about this intuitively is
that we're trying to see what information
you can get to y and vice versa
without getting blocked by p
if the blocks all information they can get from x to y and vice versa
then x and y are independent given v
so we need to consider every undirected path right what's an undirected path well if
i have a graph like this i can consider pass on this graph
that can go either with the direction of the arrows are against the direction of
the arrows that would be like a
e d would be an undirected path right because i go sometimes again sometimes with
the direction of the
so i need to check whether it's blocked by v
and the way it's going to be blocked by the is
a path is blocked by the if there's is some node w on the path
such that either
one of these two conditions hold
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
a couple of announcements contest today
five o'clock in the email to my
wednesday will be
the test test one
i'll say a few words about that
coverage through the end of the electron
when c
so what i'm talking about today
i will not be testing you but maybe you might pay attention because
about a month from now
we will ask if you skill testing questions about it but it's always pedagogical things
if i test right up until the last thing i say
i don't think that gives you enough dwell time
the flipside is going to be couple lectures now we're not going to be on
the test so
i think you will deal with it
one day i will be
giving a seminar on engineering education
halifax so in my place will be professor balancer
well competently substitute
for me and
keep the ball rolling
but i'll be back tuesday
contact me if you have some
questions in connection with the
so first thing lots of all begin with comments about the test not wave
i for one have to worry about running out of time the and so the
test is wednesday
the twenty ninth
and i'll will be written during the normal class times
if you take the test eleven
come here
there's a plurality of rules because we want to have some vacancies here
right so if your last name begins a through OK
you'll come to this room if you are
last name begins kh through y a
if you go to fifty three forty that's the gymnasium on the third floor walker
the jam up on the third floor and will accommodate a couple hundred people there
and for those of you at the very end of the alphabet we have a
special room for u one dash one ninety somebody has
some elbow room please go to the assigned role
by all means if your schedule two
ten class eleven please take the
test eleven
don't all come crashing into one o'clock because we don't have
the room or the
for the number of exams
please go to
the assigned room
so here's what the mechanics are
you're going to just go to the room as you normally do come on and
sit down
so i got to do just sit down
what's the purpose of the test by the way
why do i give you a test
it's to give you a status report
status report i want to give some feedback to tell you how you doing
OK how you doing so
two messages i can give you either
keep up the good work or
you better change of strategy because you're not mastering the material that's all i'm trying
to do
i'm not trying to to cross-check on the admissions process as i told you i
believe that everybody
so in this room has the intellectual apparatus to pass this class
so there's no gamesmanship here if you've been investing in the time
investing the time that i i asked you to
you'll pass handling there's no tricks
if you look at all the exams you can look at your home works that's
the kind of
questions you can expect
nothing to broadside you
on the other hand if you haven't been keeping up i hope that you will
pass so i can tell you look you get to do things differently that's all
bring five things with you got five fingers five things
periodic table
table of constance and you're allowed in a cheap and a half parliament sheet of
paper you can write anything you want
you right on the front around the back you can write on the edge i
don't care
you can photocopy you can follow reduce you can take everything from the last
ten years of three and i wanted to make a micro dots i don't care
what everyone
so that's three periodic table table of constants h
something to calculate where there will be some computations
sunday calculate with i don't care program calculating the only thing is no wireless devices
this has wireless internet and here you are going to be sending e-mails during an
example no computers no wireless devices
lord help your cell phone goes off
and last thing something to write with
i believe it or not i have students walk in the first thing here goes
upstairs to
i can't believe
make sure you get batteries that are
good state charging calculator
we don't have four hundred fifty calculators for
and you're right i will give you
the question paper just fill in
on the paper and then you have to bring the paper
fifty five minutes will start to all five will stop you fifty five
stop when we ask you to stop out of courtesy to your classmates everybody might
like a little more time fifty five stars
we'll have people collect them either down here at the back and
it out here in orderly fashion
so that's the mechanics now
i want you to do well
i want you to be able to put your best foot forward i want to
get all
frustrated and and failed to show
what you know so here's a couple tips
the first thing read the test
it's all you should be careful
this is for any expansion of the macro on the left-hand side
should be f of n
there's an expansion of the marker on the right-hand side so that we get a
OK and what this allows you to do is if you have a chain of
the call sign relations the chain is is then the very first one is equal
to are bounded by the very last one so you can change call signs in
the we normally would you just kept them around
so that's a big o notation any questions
but that
crash fingers
so the goal is great for expressing upper bounds but we also want to talk
about lower bounds
for algorithms we usually care about upper bounds on the running time running times at
most m squared is at most n log n to figure but sometimes we need
to express functions that are at least some quantity
for example will show that sorting requires at least on log n time and some
so we need some other notation for that
and the notation is
big omega notation and it's pretty symmetric straight out the set definition here
and we're going to write f of ten is becoming a major event in f
of n is at least
some constant times g
of course sufficiently margin
so basically just reversing the inequality relation between f and g
nothing surprising
just to have it there
random example and i'll get a little bit more sophisticated grid and is big omega
log and you should read this that up to constant factors were then is it
least logan for sufficiently large n
so this so omega sort of corresponds to
i agree the article text me
he some analogies
we have big n
they have become again this is less than or equal to
this is greater than or equal to and i'm going to fill in some more
here at the moment
i mean it's nice to have
all the usual operators would have normally we have strict lessons degree than an equal
sign and we want those are analogues in the asymptotic world where we ignore constant
factors and ignore the lower terms
so we have for example data she then this is the capital theater
which means you right the
horizontal bar in the middle as opposed all the way through
and then greeks
the way is
theta means that you're less likely to endure greater than or equal to
up to constant factors
this is the intersection of these two sets big going big mega
so that's
sort of like equal sign but of course is very different so you have things
like and squared is big of two n square you ignore
constant factors but all of these other
relations OK and squared plus bigger than is going to be better than square
but this does not hold the data because square events really bigger asymptotically bigger than
log and
and some of the other examples we saw like sanskrit verses and cuba's are those
don't hold with data
we have some
districts notation
which are the little
and little make notation there's no little fame because there is no notion of strict
quality versus strict equality little o is going to correspond roughly to less than and
will make is going to correspond to a greater than
this is an additional just have to get used to
i'm not going to define precisely here because it's almost exactly the same the difference
is that instead of saying there exist constants c and not you have to say
for every constant c
there exists a constant and
the relationship between f and g this inequality
must hold for all
instead of just for one
and so on i can now depend on c
so you can assume that really n is sufficiently large but this gives you a
strict inequalities no matter what cos it you put here in front of g they
were doing little or no matter what the cost you put in front of g
f will be still less than c times g for sufficiently large
so we have some
random examples
and these are
these were again ignoring constants and squared is always less than and q for sufficiently
large n
and it's the principle here making could work out in order to do something like
this it will become intuitive
i k l make
certainly we were being very very happy to construct such filters
because that means that we can take any and you give me an input
and i and i take out all the high frequencies
and keep the good ones keep the good stuff
but what's the trouble with that filter
that i can
it takes a long time because right because there is no
i mean
that's gravel this i mean
all i need k all the way from minus infinity to infinity i want to
do that
right ideal filter
it will be i i are r
impulse response
so that i could stand for infinite and also for idea
these are
let's see what i'm
if i'm not sure what you're adding choose
so that's what this is what my
what this
we ask about this
filter OK
so it computes the average
now in the frequency domain if it wipes out of making pi
because that's the alternating guy
if if my input was the some of the that's a good question my input
was the sum of
d term and pure alternations
yeah but i was going to what what would be the input well what so
what input when i be talking about that
oppose i had
the inputs
for me was there are many who live is another good example so there's one
input with that give me
one two one two or zero to
there are two
right if i if i literally adamantly zero to zero to zero two
and what with the output b
o once it's beautiful
keeps averaging no zeros in two
and the average and the output would be o one
now that's a good example
so this is not a pure frequency
the some of
it's assigned to some of two frequencies right
right right right
so where do we get to we got to this idea of filter but we
what to do
this is certainly the most of the problem that everybody face
so they started
creating filters
we want this
but it's asking too much so what shall we do
well the natural way idea is
take these we could figure out these numbers right
because these are
this is the this is the fourier series of the function
what i have to say it again because i just love
there are no function and here's its fourier series
and we know the fourier coefficients of the square wave
they die off at what rate
this just linear linearly one or k
bad news
so if we truncate this
and then we have a thousand are still throwing away
pretty big stuff
and we have a tremendously long filter
and what it suppose i go from minus two thousand one thousand
and i i use the same numbers
well even when we don't have a problem
suppose i just truncated is that a good idea or not
in order to ensure should be somewhat ideal right
anyway way it's the optimal it's the it's it's the idealist filter we could create
in some sense
and what would the picture looks like this
what's the
so now i have another function
chapter one hundred
and what's what's the graph of the function of phi
it has the gibbs phenomenon
this is exactly what they get from the owners take the fourier series for
four true step
and shop
so if i graph this it would be really accurate here but it would get
worse and worse
worst of course right there that would do a good very good job drop down
and then it would
this would be a little envelope
of rebels
there are there
it would be
unpleasantly large
right at that frequency
all right so
feel the designers
that's this is actually the closest function
this ripley guy this polynomial so that's the polynomial time to read two hundred years
and the course it goes the other way too
it's going to be some
so that
now in what sense is
is that ripley
unpleasant looking or little sort of
no worrying because because this height
a fixed number
ah what sense i said it was really the best possible in a certain sense
and what is the sense in which
that's the closest function to the idea
and two
if i measure the error
the difference between those two functions
and integrate square
i've got a small i can get
because that's for it because this is an orthonormal
and if i take an orthonormal basis
in the l two norm everything it's obscure projection use the same numbers and this
set the other numbers to zero
that's all too so there you seem to
an advantage of l two it's so nice to compute with with and after all
we just did was truncated
the drawback is
o point wise it
that is really not is not perfect
OK suppose i wanted so now tell me what
one thing
but it turns that this definition is still wrong even when you make sense of
can be it's not it's not enough to be given y for free that's the
wrong notion
what you have to be given for free is
and elegant
an elegant self-limiting program for y
four y
and that's more than that given y directly you're given y indirectly the it
the best theory for elegant program calculates
and this is more than do you mean you from that you can get y
by running the program but you know more than y
you also know
the complexity of why because if you're given
the most concise program for y that's a y so you you know more
OK now why is this definition of this revised definition of relative complexity of
the right definition
well the reason the right definition is because you get the following fundamental result which
is true in shannon information theory
as an identity
but it
it's very it's an important result is not an identity in
algorithmic information theory
so what does this result say
it says what this means you know you're all mathematicians who i i know i
was impressed by all the
so you know everyone knows what order of unity is something that the difference between
the two sides is bound to write about the number of this this is the
size in bits of the smallest program that calculates from the calculates the pair of
objects x and y produces two
output this is the size of the smallest program just for x and this is
the size of the smallest program
suffering from the content why if you're given that x
for free but you're given
you're given
an elegant program for x
which is exactly the same as being given that the nature of x by the
so in when you do that then you get this resolved now this result without
the class sort of unity is an identity and shannon information theory
and when i got this result i said now i have the right definition of
problem size complexity
so it's not enough to make the programmes of limiting you also have to change
the definition of relative complexity
and then you get out of this beautiful result which is a very
major results
so that when i said i have the right theory
so this was
a paper that i published in nineteen seventy five in the journal of the ACM
and the title is an advertisement that was like a medieval title instead a theory
of program size from identical to
information theory that there was just one information theory was shannon information theory at this
point there
in my view to information theory is the shannon ensemble probabilistic information theory
from communications engineering and is the algorithm
information theory we to basically talking about the size in bits of computer program
so now there are two
but they
they have some similarities and this this result is is is is a similar
so i don't want to get into the technical i don't want to give you
a survey of the
of the of the theory
because there isn't enough time but this is one way to resolve this i was
talking to you about the
about the history of this field
but you see in my view the as i said the main application of all
of these ideas it's nice that you get these results because it shows you have
the right definitions
but but in my view the real reason for creating this theory is is to
look at is to try to find places in pure mathematics where there is no
structure where things are patterns
of where things have maximum possible information content
a maximum possible complexity
and and that areas of math with with with irreducible complexity will be interesting because
they'll be places where we can understand what's going on
the places where things look random essentially even though it's pure map
that was the reason
that was that was my motivation for doing all of this and
i think i'm the only person who really has been working on this
there have been other people working in this field but they tend to be more
interested or even technical
stuff or in an application stated time complexity
there is an industry which looks the program size
and tries to use ideas from program size to help
on questions involving time complexity
and those questions and interest me
so what i said
i think the really interesting question now that you have the general notion of structure
is to try to find some place with no structure and i told you that
the first example i gave you is one place which thing which had no structure
of the bits of any elegant program
you know that irreducible complexity but let me give you my best example
my best example
it is the halting probability omega
so this is a place
pure math probability
this is the place in pure mathematics
where you can define something you find something that has absolutely no structure
so let me tell you about this
what is this not so the idea is to show that this is to get
a worse incompleteness and the kind of ghetto in nineteen thirty one
and actually this
the whole the probability omega actually comes not from knows where
although the goal is to
look at incompleteness it comes actually more from turing nineteen thirty six work on the
halting problem
that's the famous paper in the proceedings of the london society
and doesn't talk about the halting problem you don't see that that
in the paper but it's really buried there it's in their the time of the
papers on computable numbers and about real numbers with an application to the shapes the
that was the nineteen thirty six famous paper by turning
so turning twenty shows in this paper and i just showed you in the previous
the women
shift the focus away from the husband on to
generation younger clearly that the water that's clearly a reflection of the fact that
peacock hit left people
clearly reflection the fact that grandchildren started coming so
the women are operating much more strategically into their placings there
their social capital and investing time
shifting away from
the thee
husband as it were
to the daughter and the grandchildren has these become
more important to the more demanding and you don't see anything like that happen in the males and it's also
if you look at the blue and
red lines are pretty much identical in there
lower left-hand peak and the peak is much lower than those the male and female children
look at the difference with
the women here
you have is very high strong peak for the children and the preference a very striking preference
the female the daughter over the sum
okay so just an indication really sometimes
how good these databases can be if you ask the right kinds questions if you like this is
the data with there
that is only because we started to ask these kinda questions that these can results so came out again
so this is a reflection of the fact that
creating relationships requires you to invest time the work it
and here is evidence that this is really true if you look at them in a cora five best friends
some of about half of them will be family of whom will be
true friends and biological sense
averages about five
but if few
also people who are in a relationship romantic relationship
how many best friends they've got
defined in the same way
on average you come up with a figure of about four
they have won a best and that's including the part where it won best friend
fewer people who aren't in a relationship
so this is evidence that falling in love
is expensive it costs you a friend
but it actually cost you to friends because remember if in forest you'll romantic partner
and you don't normally fall in love with somebody who's already in your in a circle a five
not least because to them probably family
what you the person who
u fall in love with this comes in from the outside i way out and
a hundred and fifty is origami
so to get a four
from five hand include sector person you've actually lost two friends from the in a circle you've sacrifice them
now there could be serious because if you sacrifice
well maybe if you sacrifice to
family it might not have such a big effect on their willingness to come to your aid
in future but can be or to friends
on the shoulders you need to cry later
and if you sacrifice both your friends you've got no shoulders
because family tend to be a little less sympathetic
so what
amazingly what people do is they sacrifice typically one family member one friend
so they still keep one friend one-shouldered crime
and then they rely on the fact that family
relationships will be less badly affected by
not interacting with them so much
a there will still come to help in the future so long very subtle behavior going on here
work kind interesting
the birds-of-a-feather story
i'm offaly which we've already heard about earlier this morning
we were interested in in
what is that determines friendships and the quality of friendships andrey had based on on the original birds-of-a-feather idea
the idea that
you could kinda drop profile friends on the rather like a personality profile
so we get a very large sample of people
a list of things that they might show twenty one things they might share
friends and family members of the network is a pig one
oh by the way
if we go back to this another big part of disease chronic disease
that's related to diet is the physical activity part of the equation is all discussed
in the class and most of you probably know this your body weight is a
function of how many calories you take and how many calories you burn off through
metabolic processes but also physical activity and it used to be a lot easier to
be physically active than it is today
and we'll discuss this later in the class but energy saving devices all over the
place you guys use computers i use the typewriter when i started college
so i was burning more calories creating a paper then you guys have two and
that would seem like a lot of calories but you add that up across
lecture grudge door openers and electric toothbrushes and
windows on your car that you no longer have to crank and of course you
don't have to get up and go across the room to change the channel on
the television any longer
these things contribute alot to a calorie deficit
that used to be of there's a calorie the there's the deficit and how many
calories people were burning compared to before and part of that is
our environment
and the way the environment structured a group of people in the united states and
elsewhere who study something called the built environment how the environment is built affects how
much physical activity we get so let's look back at this picture here
so let's just say
you have a child
will up here say in this cul-de-sac
and his friends with the child who lives over here
that's probably not very long distances the kind of distance work it could easily write
but of course no parents going to let the child right about from here to
here because you've got the superhighway in the middle
and the only way to get across it would be to go down here on
this very busy road figure out how to navigate over here even if there is
a walkway that one could write a
and then maneuver over here
and so the the introduction of the superhighway which divides these communities into really affects
physical activity a
you have another example of that that would
that would be
true is let's say you have a child who lives in this sort of
circular area here who lives
and his friends with the child who was here
then that's not very long distance probably easily walkable in a few minutes but that
child can be walking through everybody's yard
so how do you get there you gotta go here here and these could be
busy roads and so parents don't want to do it because of safety reasons so
you see how when the country used to be laid out in a grid
it's a new york city still is today than people walk to get places but
when you have things like this which is typical of suburban developments it affects the
physical activity lot
there have been some interesting surveys about people's relationship with food
and the pew foundation this survey that was published in april two thousand six
but as as people how much how to find out what percentage of people really
enjoy eating
and in the from nineteen eighty nine to two thousand six there was a pretty
significant decline
but even into the in nineteen eighty nine the numbers were very high
now there was probably a time when people enjoy eating more
they were eating all the time the meeting was confined to three meals a day
it was more likely to be a social event because the family was together
and the food had more
per head better personal relationship for
but why in the world over that period of time
people's relationships with food get even worse
well it has to do with our distance from food our psychological and physical distance
from food and the fact that we don't appreciate it as much as we do
because it's everywhere all the time
and we've been trained to eat outside of the normal mealtimes
how many of you have seen the talk about all
series of advertisments for the fourth meal
common one people see that now what that means is no longer three mills efficient
there has to be a four
people are eating late at night reading early in the morning they are basically in
all the time so this is not a very positive sign people are having a
bad relationship with what can be what can be done to turn around
in the same hole
people were asked if they were eating more junk food in asia and men and
women both set in pretty high numbers that they were eating more junk food and
they should
i hope that would be a small percentage of the population will be affected by
this but it's not turns out to be a very high number so we have
to ask why is this
why are people eating too much junk food will be are gases
what of the factors that have
so availability and cost become two key issues yes in somebody else there
say OK
OK marketing is a big factor yes
taste good
OK so it's not only available sort of out there all over the place but
it's easy
you can be it can be security easily it can be made easily in the
microwave or things like that that's all true any other ideas
so OK is part of the social system that we're in yes
OK it's
right it's easy because there's less cleaning less preparation and things right
OK that's a very interesting issue about the the response was that because the
other food might expire quickly
so that's true appearing in things like fruits and vegetables they only have a certain
amount of life before they go bad a lot of these processed foods have very
long shelf lives
and therefore can be stored for long periods of time they can be on store
shelves for a long period of time there has to do with economics of food
especially food available to the poor
which will discuss later OK these are you guys are all right everything that i
heard was the correct answer now the people in this poll were asked the same
and here's what they said to seventy three percent said that one reason is that
it's more convenient it's what people like to eat it's heavily advertised it's more affordable
people may not know which foods are healthy so those are all reasons
you guys mentioned now
what you might do about this let's say that we
that year the surgeon general or you're the top health official in some country
and you agree with this poor people are in too much johnson so we can
do about it
you've decided to probabilities choosing things and then you've got back can the then got
actually turned into an algorithm to how to choose things about probability because you want
to choose a finite populations so the standard ways roulette wheel sampling where you make
pockets of your
roulette equal to their fitness and then you just platelet p times to get new
members of the population
and the problem is that is you can fluctuations you could get all members of
the population ending up released for members of your
your new population you could be very unlucky and always the loser let's get released
a member of your population
or you could get always if affects members of the population minimizer those what you
you want to have something you want to maintain diversity
so there's another way of doing this called stochastic universal sampling she was proposed by
well you basically the
you choose one random number and then equal interview intervals around the wheel
you can place balls in a safe place
people's around at equal intervals around OK
this again also use select all members of the crew probabilities they give you many
less fluctuations severs many
let's ways
of getting right of
sampling happening
and the proportion of times so members selected is very close to the probability so
this is a better way of doing something that is in no way
but this is a better thing to do is actually faster to implement the normal
rule that was something do anything is personally i prefer that will sampling because it's
much easier to do the mathematics and something from this that the mathematics and this
turns out to be not something to actually
exactly compute how to do that that's a silly point defining is if you really
using e GA
he stochastic universal sampling there's no reason not to
it's not gonna make a huge difference for use against improved performance
so configuration is the genetic code operations are configuration is usually
represented as a string it doesn't have to be represented as a string in seventeen
genetic programming usually don't use strings use much more complicated
trees and things like that
and you can think of the working at two levels at the genetic level so
modify the string irrespective of the problem or the phenotypic level
the operators actually you think have a common problem irrespective of representation
so you can sort of thing of two kinds of operations of genetic operations which
is what i
more that's been talking about the city typical mutations of crossover and these are sort
general purpose operations you can work on all strings but they tend to be done
imitations you just mutate
things done
so the provinces of representation in order to get these changes work well you have
to have good representations the other thing you can do is phenotypic operates as you
can think of what they're doing on the phenotype of the problem
these after be special purpose because it depend on the problem
so this is two ways of thinking about
how to do GA you can think about your problem and think about what operators
you want to do good moves and problem or you can just think dumbly back
you've got string doing dumb things on the string
and the more you have to do saying how to represent my problem well on
that string representing to make that strings to may be dumb operations good
of the time
so so there is no
and since you certainly not doing on services and this is certainly not darwinian so
i'm scanners
so for instance OK so one of the things we will see later is as
good ways of doing crossover four
and for the colouring graph coloring problem very really means you know what
heart of
and now if I express that the
but but but but but but
as matrices
because you knew that was coming that's what I have
this is my goal
an orthogonal basis and the normally even bases in the row space
and an orthonormal basis in the columns space
so that I'm sort of diagonalize the nature of the matrix A is like getting
converted to a diagonal matrix thing
and you notice that usually I have to do I have to allow myself to
different places
but my my little comment about symmetric positive definite was the 1 case
it's a q equal q signal
where V and you the same q
but mostly
I you know undertaken a matrix like 0 let me take a matrix like for
minus 3 3
there's a 2 by 2 matrix
it's invertible so as
but it has rank to
so I'm gonna look for 2 vectors V 1 and V 2
and the in the row space
and you saw on the looked for
the 1 of the 2
in the row space
which of course is too
and I know look for you want you to do in the column space
which of course is also plotted
and I'm going to look for numbers signal 1
and sigma to
so that it all comes out right so these guys are thought awesome normal
these guys are orthonormal and these are the scaling factor so I'll do that example
assume as I
get the matrix picture straight
you see that this
expresses what I want can I just say
2 words about null space
if we have
if the null space
then we got what we want to move in a basis for for that so
here comes the basis for the null space the
all plus 1 down
so if if we only had an dimensional rose space and the other n minus
dimensions were in the null space OK it would take an orthogonal orthonormal bases there's
no problem
and then would just get 0
so actually would no zeros will come out from the from the head on the
diagonal matrix so what I'll complete that 2 of
the 2 of
orthonormal basis for the whole
I complete this to an orthonormal basis for the whole space and I complete that
was 0
null space
no problem here that is so it really
the true the true problem is in a matrix like that which is symmetric so
I can't use its eigenvectors they're not orthogonal
but somehow I have to get these
orthogonal in fact orthonormal
that make it work
I I have to find this these or normal guys these orthonormal guys and I
we want to be signal what you want and a unique to be signature muted
that's my goal
in the area of the
matrices they're gonna get me
now these are orthogonal matrices I can put that if I multiply on both both
sides by the inverse
I have a equals you
signal the inverse
and of course
you know the other way I can write the
this is 1 of those square error
orthogonal matrices
so it's the same as you
sigma the transfer
here's my problem
I got to
orthogonal matrices you
and I don't wanna find them both at once
so I want to cook up some expressions
that will make them
you disappear
I would like to make users apparently we only with the
and here's how to do it
it is it's the same combination that keeps showing up whenever we have a general
rectangular matrix then it's a transpose that's the great matrix
that's the great many
that's the matrix is symmetric
and in fact positive definite or at least positive semidefinite because of the matrix with
nice properties so let's see what will it
so if I took a transpose there
I would have A transpose A will be
what would I have I transpose that I have
segment transpose nu transpose that's that's the A transpose now the
and what guess
was like worse because it's got 6 things now together but it's going to
collapse into something what did you transpose you collapse into
the identity so that's the key point this is the identity and we don't have
you anymore
and sigma trend post time segment of the diagonal matrices
so the product is just going to have sigma squared on the diagonal so do
you see what we've got here this is the
times this easy matrix signal 1 squared sigma 2 squared times the transfer
this is the this is the A transpose that this is what we copy down
A transpose A is that
user out of the picture anomaly having to choose the bees and what are these
movies and what are the signals
you know what that these are
there are the eigenvectors the this is a perfect
eigen vector eigen value
Q land q transpose
for the matrix A transpose A
a itself is like nothing special
but A transpose
has the zero mean
so we can only be
expectation the expectation of conditional expectation given the
axes on g minus one
are then
these these up i is the function
this less than or equal to g minus one
so these supply is the function of the conditions here
so i can move all the
these are by
this is equal to the con expectation of these
but i can be
conditional expectation but the
because of the definition of the martingale difference the conditional expectation is there
so i you're there
yeah i i you know it almost
the conditional if given but i would like to what
these are all random variables
calculate this one
because the in the graph
with respect to the
conditional distribution of the
and given that it
well i have here that these are uncorrelated
i showed you that under fairly general conditions
the average the the media were
of the that the is square of the average goes zero
OK let's calculate
this one
but we being the color of the the average is one of our and were
that the expectation of all across product
but if i is not equal to j
this expectation is there
so only
those terms are non-zero for which i is equal to j
what were and were
times the farm
of the second moment of four
of the set
but you for example or
these sequences barmby
then the star and the involved sequence divided by and we're going to zero so
as soon as the fact that the the second moment that are bonded then
we had a weak law of large numbers
that the average goes to zero emus were that
i forgot to mention that on the wiki i have a survey paper
it so everything in detail
is written in the in the paper for
and also the slides are there
not harmful
use the martingale difference property for a general problem
hope to construct martingale difference
four a problem
i assume that you have that y sequence
which is a function of x i
and then in the use the
and my nose
the conditional expectation of y and given the media sector
it's a construction
i in any way i call it as the
and the claim is that the fuzzy and is a martingale difference sequence
putting a different sequence had the requirement one is that the only the function of
x one x two xn it's five because y is a function of x one
x two two x then you there is the conditional expectation is the function of
x one x two two x minus one so the first is of course
now we have to calculate the conditional expectation of the given the actually the previous
axis OK
definition of the
and calculate the conditional expectation for the first there
given the axes
and the second is given that which is the
it means that a
the difference is that in and the limit but it's obvious there
but in this
just looking at the next
very wide to the function of
actually it in this way we introduce artificially
martingale difference sequence is
and in this way
you can have a little large numbers
for these differences
because of the previous she OK
so we have to go back to the optimality
i repeat the definition
a be star
the local optimally
OK i have to prove that the
again this is a copy of the one of the views she i have to
to prove that all around
these average
cannot be better
the other average
growth rate
it is that the
not here to prove
look at the the restart the average growth rate of these have been very awful
you actually
it is an average of the logarithmic there
it's been my
y variable
from which
i derive
marking different
all to do this
i had
and for problem
the same
you see that here i i don't cheat
why i it
because believe in this case the
is an average of martingale difference
i took a random variable with the white
my nose is the conditional expectation of piecewise
given the user
the blue average goes zero
second application is in the field of dependence measures
so some of you
you might have heard of methods methods like ICA and kernel constrained covariance and the
hilbert schmidt independence criteria
and all of them treat this problem
of independence
so you have two random variables x and y drawn from some joint distribution
pf px y with these marginals and we want to know whether this is a
joint distribution factorizes
and the main idea in these methods work very well
it's very very similar to the idea that i showed you before but we are
rewriting distance as an optimisation problem over the unit sphere
the main idea is that
two random variables x and y are independent if and only if for all
continuous functions f g
the covariance of f of x into y vanishes so again this is like it's
a simple linear criterion but it's enforced over a large class of nonlinear functions you
turns out again we we can do this over the unit sphere of a reproducing
kernel hilbert space
and then get independence criteria that will work very well
but and now i want to
show on the shelf would tell you that we can recover
one of these arguments exactly using
the kind of argument that talked about the last ten minutes
and to do this we just have to map the joint distribution into a hilbert
space we have to map the product of the marginal into it was space
and then we use this quantity this difference vector or the norm of this difference
with is a measure of dependence
so we just take heart different all these two distributions
and if we then use the kernel no we need to come on x and
y for unicode user can that factorizes into two components
on x y
we can show that
in this case this quantity
square of this quantity is equal to the so called hilbert schmidt norm of the
covariance operator between the two rkhss it's generalization of forming is known and if we
look at the empirical estimate this quantity
we get this call this thing illustrates
which is exactly the same thing that has been studied before and called the hilbert
schmidt independence criterion
so we arrive at it from a somewhat different point of view
we can also look at the witness function of the equivalent optimisation problem but it
may not going to that now
just point out that
there's another talk ICML by shanghai so
on saturday before lunch uses the conditional cross covariance operator in the context of learning
causal structures for graphical models
so the application is in the field of covariate shift correction and local learning
in this case this problem of compared to correction
we assume we have the training set drawn from the distribution p
we have tested drawn from different distributions p prime but we assume that the conditional
distributions of y given x identical
so only the input shift and a number of approaches one of you what i
have suggested that in such a situation one should reweight with the training set to
some kind of importance sampling
this could kind of idea also maps well into our framework what we basically we
do is we
use the mean
one of the test points
test inputs is all reference and we tried to
reweight training points with this but i saw twenty points such that the
the re weighted mean of the training points becomes
similar as possible to the mean of the test points to remember
if the means are the same the statistically
these two distributions are not distinguishable
so we try to
well the training points to mimic the distribution of the test points
and this leads us to an optimisation program to to these constraints of course in
practice we regularize this problem and it turns out that this especially if the situation
is underspecified for the conduits are too large for the problem this can help a
in the special case where here
this set of test points only contains one test point
this actually
it's to a local sample weighting schemes as a method for local learning in that
last application
again related to the previous one but maybe a little bit more general
this is something that was only just started
looking at is in the field of measure estimation
and as a special case dataset squashing
there have been some related approaches are there and in this case the idea is
we try to minimize this discrepancy between the mean of the sample and the mean
of the distribution
when we consider an a priori specified class distributions
so we take this convex combination of distributions
and with these
constraints and we minimize this quantity and we can rewrite this as a convex quadratic
with this objective function
but this time is constant
it's interesting to look at these other quantities
so the difficult ones of these first two
these expectations of the columns with respect to these measures to be pre specified but
it's interesting to think about what kind of measures what kind of combinations of kernels
and measures to quantities that can be empirically analytically calculated
in one example is of course if both discussing and this is just an integral
over several gaussians which we can do
so they can be go sense of different with we could also use dirac measures
the distributions
in which case we can either try to approximate the training set by weighted subset
of the training set this problem as being called dataset squashing before or we can
try to
we can also recover the covariate shift correction algorithms we try to approximate the true
test set by
measures on the training points so that i can just talked about before we can
recover that as well
but if they are not
you're in very good company with people
who also there are
make any sense
so i don't have that prove to be certain it's not mathematically that you know
that's right it has it that's why it's still an open conjecture right and by
the way could show up this could not be so i mean if in fact
it turns out
that these are tech are theoretically not part the constant in front end up being
huge or whatever that would also block embarrassment
but it investment spread across a lot of people
OK that's because that's the topic will we'll come back to topic several times in
the class
OK so
when you save the methods to solve in general optimisation problem i mean they always
involve compromise so
if you
one is due to the two main categories of compromise are as follows the first
is is is not
back down
on the meaning of soul
solve min saw
it means find the point that is
has least objective and satisfies the constraints that's the definition of salt so you leave
that intact but you leave open the possibility that the computation time
in might involve let's take thousands of years or something like that OK so that's
generally people call it global optimisation off and it's a big field by the way
that it's been almost entirely it is based on convex optimization also will see a
little bit about that later in the class that so that's global optimization
now the other one which is the one most widely done by people who do
they do the following it's actually very very closely collaborate with the do
they go and some the first and have some of the little footnote like this
and then way down to the bottom here like this
the they write this
they they right and now i have to ask you to zoom in on that
task it is
there go
and there it is
OK so it is not really OK nineteen simbach back out OK so
what that means is that big a big story about this and they make it
they say well it's a local solution but when they don't
it gets tiresome to say
so locally local solution all they can place it doesn't look so as you drop
it after one
and then you say well i i solved that problem and i solve this problem
the the homework exercise i solve this negotiable give talks they said so i minimize
that the point is they didn't know what they did was they got a local
solution but we will talk more about that as well
OK now there are exceptions
well that now
actually if you're going to do that
i would maintain although this is not a
widely held actually you'll find it
many my opinions are not widely known but this is among my opinions are not
widely held this mean one if you're going to do that i would actually do
it via convex optimisation
and next four
which is to say actually since we're already like one quarter through around the spring
which probably be giving lectures
maybe even next week for them to do so i would recommend doing it for
convex optimisation but that's another story they doing it spain
what out now because we crossed the ground it's scheduled to be in the spring
who knows one of doing
i think it could be early february we don't know OK alright
OK so what exceptions there are cases where you can solve these problems no asterisk
nothing most famous one in the world by far the least squares norm
no asterisks there
it's not like
oh yeah well i transpose a inverse a transposed you know be aware that
that's a lot of work super well in practice that it's not the status of
that is that is the global solution
and there's a couple others that you might not know about you might though
and that would be things like linear programming problems will get to those quickly quite
quickly but those are ones where you you get the answer
you know
asters nothing
there are actually as in these but there are much in much smaller fine print
and i'll get to the later class don't worry i'll
we get when there is an admission that has to be made i will make
it will come clean
maybe quietly first but one that i will be quite OK
and in fact
the parents of these and a considerable generation is convex optimisation problem so this is
really sort of the exception
so a lot you know i mean this to a rough the rough idea to
put it all together something like this
that most opposition once you get so let's let's review what we've learned so far
we have really going to let review went so far a everything is an optimisation
problem OK well that's tautology OK
we can really you can't really solve most opposition all you really can't solve cases
so far
great that's the kind of depressing now the good news is actually here that there
are huge exceptions this entire classes about one of the exceptions
when you do convex optimization
there are no asterisks it's you you solve the problem in
there are no apologies nothing
it's the global solution
which is fine
is convex
his life convex i would have to say no it's not i hope it's not
more you know it's not said no no as well if we get later today
on the white
we don't really what i mean to czech convexity you really have to take two
instances and then form average weighted averages in between like for example the average of
two things
would you i would be the average of yours in your life look like i
don't know what the hell the thing that has happened is that life has to
be better than the average of the qualities of your lives
i don't
keep that is running topic will revisit periodic but for the most like this is
it's not a question there are exceptions besides convex optimisation nesterov
one right now
sure you're writing composition
that's that's one where
you can compute the singular as i could i can write as an optimisation problem
or something like that pretty easily write in for example a right in right this
work they find me the best rank two approximation matrix
non convex
and yet we can solve it and we get the exact global solution end of
story by singular values or by a principal components analysis depending on what future
so that's an example
that's pretty much about it now there are some others that there is that there's
no i mean there are some combinatorial problems
so taking things on combinatorial algorithms in computer science or something like that
they are common to all country problems
is that we say that given the class
then the each of the component if is independent of the other so that the
different measurement i see about nine
my input are independent
from each other
and so it's represented uganda presented namespace by this graph which
you have observed
the the
the different measure of your examples
and q you have the class
and so on
we see that
in going back to lower dispersion problem
is a is is the tate to tate
no note
and this
seeing it if i find the class
like if a conditioned on the class
any of the of the components are independent
which makes that we can
right this as the product
over the continent
the of of the probability of the component given the class
OK another example that you know
it is the first order
markov model
in which
we have
twenty which in fact it's a way of
writing the sequence short away
sequence from one to t
what is a random
michael's mothers our our
mothers to represent sequence of of states
and so it can be
written like that you have
the first
the first element in my sequence
and so on the table
t minus one elements and may may sequence and the
the last element sequence
and what is usually the first order markov assumption
is that
the probability of
one one element in the sequence is only dependent on the previous
the previous one and not on the the once before so that can do it
like that the probability of the state t
is given
the all the previous states inside equal to its equal to the probability of
the state t
given the
previous state
and you see that that was the model is the first
so the graphical model is is the first graph i show you with the which
any any not in here
apart from may be the first and the last hour head to tail
i had to
note so observing one conditioning one
we give
he some considered to tree consequent if states
and i observe one of the middle then the tools will be conditionally independent
and this can be generalised instead of having sequences i have liked
the two dimensional sequences
the like a map of
of states
this here is something more general
say that i have a joint distribution
represented by a directed graphical models
then if i take the conditional distribution of parts plant explaining my
may set of of random variables
so i am we consider that
conditional distrib distribution of
one particular not given all the remained in meaning
and so that can be written by a
bayes as the probe the joint probability
thank the marginalisation divided by the demand marginalization
and since
we know that this is represented by a directed graph so we know that we
can order the nodes in a way that
are any parent has lower degree
or lower numbering than any of his of his children
i can
decompose the joint probability as the product
of the probability of
it's not giving experience
and so here in the in the
a lot of of of
properties here
what will not depend on yx yx
thanks i and so they will go out of the the of the integral
and we'll council was it was the
top one
and so
this will only depend
on a few set of nodes