then you have to know what it means to just
talk about people
and you say my income is three db lower during
and that makes him very happy
OK so
that's all we need for this simple example we now want to go into
more complicated things
OK pulse amplitude modulation
this is one of the
major ways
of turning bits into signals and then turning the signals and the waveforms again
again i'm doing this first not because it's the most important schemes talk about
but because we want to understand these things one by one
and we understand p a and all talk about QAM and you'll understand that and
then we want to look at other other variations of these things
so the signals in PAAM are one-dimensional
OK the consolation
the only thing that can be sense one-dimensional
one real dimension
is the set of real numbers
so you're going to modulate
these are real numbers
now we're going to talk about later how do you find this function here we
are just going to take these real numbers which are coming in to the transmitter
one by one out of the digital encoder
you take these numbers you're gonna view them as being multiplied by the late impulses
and then passed through a filter
and the filter responses just
impulse responses p of ten
in other words what we're doing is saying we don't like the sinc function
therefore the simplest thing to do
this replaced the same function by something we do like
so we're going to replace the same function by some filter characteristic which we like
and that's the way to modify
the previous example
into something that makes better sense so we're doing two things here we're talking about
BAM one we're talking about generalizing this binary signal set
and two
we're talking about generalizing the same function
and to some arbitrary impulse response
OK so standard PIM signal set
users equally spaced signals symmetric around zero
and if you look at the picture makes it clear what this means
it's the same thing we were using all along we are talking about quantisation
if you're looking at one dimensional quantization
that's a very natural way
to choose the representation points
here we're doing everything in the opposite way so we're starting out with these points
well we're starting out with a symbols and turning them into a signals
and when you take a symbols and turn them into eight signals
perfectly natural thing to do
is to
make each of these signals
equally spaced from each other and centered on the origin
it was
now when the
this is not something we have to see later
i think you can see that that these symbols or are used with equal probability
and you're trying to
reduce the amount of energy
that the signals use
which will then go through and to reduce the amount of energy in the wave
forms that were transmitting
it's nice to have them centered around zero
because they have the means that mean is just going to contribute directly
to the expected
i mean square value of the signal you're using so so why not centred around
later on we'll see many reasons for that centring around zero but for now we're
not going to worry about any of those and we're going to senator round zero
OK and the other thing is why do you want them to be equally spaced
well i'll talk about the injustice
the signal energy
some high level knowledge here some hypothesis space of grammars this is what something was
called universal grammar or any in any computational linguistic tries to to grammar induction believes
in some form of universal grammar some hypothesis space of possible grammars and then in
this case learning the grammar is bayesian inference up at this level which requires working
up through multiple levels of not directly observable information in order to figure out what
these rules are so that's the idea of hierarchical bayesian inference here over multiple levels
with increasingly structured abstract representations as you move up in the hierarchy and the y
i don't know anybody in natural language processing tools implemented exactly all these levels of
various people implement various pieces of this hierarchy and as a whole this picture i
think captures you know resembles view of the state of the art of how we
think something like the integrated problem of passing and language acquisition might be able to
similar kinds of ideas are being explored in vision like this you again this sort
of a long history of thinking about visual scene interpretation as a kind of passing
and if you like the work but rather willsky and others that i should the
beginning it can be seen as a kind of scene passing but there's a complimentary
direction this the more sort of hierarchical structured probabilistic approach which is being developed by
people like sanctioned due in our new orleans two demon which is as more based
on the analogy to language when you talk about grammars for scenes in those grammars
give you priors over structural descriptions are parts of an image and this approach seems
to have a lot more promising these for representation for trying to describe how we
can see three d structure from two d image of course it's also a lock-up
computationally very difficult it's very hard to do efficient inference in some kind of a
scene grammar like this so one of the things we're interested in our group and
others are two is how do you combine these two kinds of approaches to try
to get the representational power of this approach the efficient inference of these capacities of
these bottom-up
object class detectors for example
so these are are all things like that
for the
you all in learning
and that's the key question those these sources
so here is
right so what's
right so so i would to talk more about this later on in the in
the summer school but there's many tradeoffs the world that we're all familiar with the
the more structured sophisticated your brain richer representations are the harder it is to do
efficient inference but also the harder it is to have two to learn everything i
have any idea what is the right hypothesis space for learning that could be effectively
searched and to learn this kind of knowledge and certainly some some ideas which have
evolved over the last few decades
our appreciation for well
what kinds of problems that seem intractable might be solved if you just wait long
enough either way long enough for your computer to cycle long enough for those clever
guys int'l two
to build a yet another order of magnitude faster computing power or for those clever
people into beginning and sheffield place to come up with clever mathematical formulations and i
think there are there's there's a lot of progress has been made to the point
that on both in terms of mass and
map of optimisation the and the the sort of hardware and software of
of computing power
that make problems that would seem completely ridiculous you know a couple of decades ago
standard and other ones which would seem so
ridiculous that you would never even have talked about them for fear being laughed off
the stage now this i can talk about them on the stage and i you
know i can't point to something which works and says oh yeah we can do
that efficiently
but it's this is a legitimate goal to work towards
and i do think that
you know when you actually get into it you can have legitimate debates in good
debates about what is likely to be learned or innate
what kind of how power how rich or unstructured representations are likely to be based
on thinking about what's computationally possible but just as
we don't really know very much about what's neurally plausible we also don't really know
what what are the kind of
i mean what's neurally plausible say in terms of representation we don't know what's neurally
plausible in terms of the limits of computation exactly and we want to say well
this is how the brain works
it's hard to it's hard to say well this is the conversation which which seems
intractable based on our current singing computer science and that's probably not likely to be
done in the brain
as far as we know the brain and i i tend to believe not only
the brain represents rich structures that is far more powerful computationally than we usually invoke
as a constraint in practical machine learning on what's algorithm willing to live
now these sets of these ideas have been i think fairly well well one not
fairly well worked out but at least there are being the starting to be explored
by number of groups in language and vision and in some of our work we
emphasise more kind of higher-level cognitive problems
but we're also interested in the vision ones like for example word learning so i
mentioned before and will show a little bit of this later on the class how
can you think about say learning the meaning of the word from a few examples
as also inference in this kind of a hierarchical bayesian model with various kinds of
structured representations or causal learning so again that's the problem which has a long history
in machine learning whether it's learning just associations are now learning the structure of graphical
models and we'll see how that can be described as a kind of bayesian inference
and also have more abstract calls knowledge the kind that allows a person to make
a causal inference from what seems like way too limited data can also be described
as something like a hierarchical bayesian computation
and lastly i will have too much time for this in this class with something
that we're very interested in them happy to talk about it with people here and
actually some of the students from MIT who who are attending the school
i have been quite interested in even worked on models of the sort of thing
so going to say
and so that's how you compute easy i transpose easy as you transpose and substituting
back into the formula
and you would then have your m step update
to the printer matrix longer
and also one the point on this derivation is that it turns out it's partly
because the name ian our expectation maximisation of one common mistake for the amount of
it is
in the e step on someone to
take expectation of the random variables e
and then the m step just the expected value everywhere you see it
so in particular one common mistake in deriving the factor analysis is to look at
this and say look as easy transfers
that's just for the expected value under the q distribution and you approach that
new qx i times musee arguments i transposed
into that expectation and this is this is incorrect there and been incorrect derivation of
because some
it's missing this all term frequency i think
so so one common misconception VEM is that in the east and just compute the
expected value of a random variable and the m step the expected value and it
turns out some our own that turns out to be the right thing to do
in the mixture of gaussians and mixtures naive bayes models that will actually be the
right answer
but in general the album is more complicated than just taking the expected values of
the random variables pretending that they were so observed that the expected value
OK so i'll go for this just illustrate that step as well
so just to summarise the we
the three key thing to keep in mind that that they came up with this
derivation were one for the east step we had a continuous scouting random variables so
compute e step
we actually compute the mean and covariance of the council of the distribution q i
the second thing that came up was on the m step
when you see these integrals
sometimes if expect the interpret as the expectation the rest of the map becomes much
and the final thing was
again in the m step on
you know
the album is derived by a certain maximisation problem that we thought is not necessarily
just the expected value of xei everywhere
the c
that is the kind of natural way too many equations on and and and even
doing this i was skipping many steps single selection analysis c
you know the all the that's all the derivations of the stethoscope like how you
actually take care to respect matrix slander on how to compute the updates to the
other parameters as well the new emphasizes
and so
that's the factor analysis out
in the step right or
the second is parameters in the first ten years of his life
but it seems to me that q is as low
as well
this is the right
this is questions raised to you
it doesn't q i have parameters and so on
so in the end however on QI is
that is is there any and all of them sometimes PSV i may have parameters
the URI of the i may never have any parameters on
in this was a case of factor analysis your eye doesn't parameters on in other
examples and mixture of gaussians model say
xiao was the multinomial random variable is an example of the i is you to
he was you i will never have any parameters
and in particular two i i was going to be
this is the scouts in distribution right is no doubt will be given by me
covariance you know singer
and so
it's true that mu and sigma made themselves have depended on the values of the
parameters i had in the previous generation
but on the way to think about you is going to take the parameters from
the previous iteration of the algorithm
and use that compute what QI is your i
that's that's that's the e seventy algorithm
and i myself computer what you lives years then this is a fixed distribution and
use these things values for mu and sigma
me deal with costs ten dollars to come from u to you
and these are the nodes and this is the network and now the minimum spanning
is the theory that connects all the nodes
but we start minimum weight the total number of is and you you see in
this one and this is very easy to implement if you the network in order
to find the minimum spanning tree the algorithm is very trivial you start to remove
the highest aggregate cost of the link for example here and from that is to
go to learn one layer one o one bits condition if you remove node you
don't remove this link i mean if you
remove the in the middle weeks
you don't remove have them can but you continue in this way you finally get
the three
which is called the minimum standards of the algorithm is very simple to get going
on but in this case there is the minimum tree
the is when it is it's a part of the network that is very important
for traffic for transportation
because of the goes and the minimum of the place for minimum course and this
is very widely used to optimize traffic flow design operation of communication network
so what do we know
for learning about that on this minimum minimum spanning tree
so first of all we know before they told you if you don't
eight the minimum distance without considering the weight
the minimum distance grows like log again if it's get free
if it's not scale free if it goes like looking
this is when you
i don't consider the now the question what has been you can see the debate
so one can solve using missiles form
statistical physics julie and find it you
use the weight and you want to find the optimal way you can see the
optimal bay
becomes much longer instead of going from a to b
to go to the links here and it cost fifty eight you go for me
to you and will cost much less because twenty nine only you see the sum
of these numbers and this
the past the minimum spanning trees that have been global and to become longer than
the land they begin to see but still they have relatively short it there will
flow again
however if you take lambda greater than three unable to show any and you make
the same analysis to minimize vanity and you find the links of the past that
you have to go on the minimum spanning tree which is important for for dynamics
of population
this becomes very large into to the one so instead of login so this slogan
platforms to once into the ones and possible to look at this you see also
be useful the importance was given the other important because they still can still small
world even if you
this all the time and you have a and you want to find a the
shortest path to the optimal path to find these
this is important but i want to use this
one can use it in the following the first of all let me show you
are would be taken big network NBC of the minimum spanning tree looks this is
the minimum spanning tree
and a because it is the minimum spanning tree inventory includes ultimately reaching everywhere in
the network
but if you if you have two in if you want to improve now the
network is a big the we have to use to import all the links you
but to be this is the order of n
again very big systems
we don't want to spend so much money in improving the system is not definitive
because we know something is you remember connects all the nodes
so what we do we use
concepts form percolation
and we instead of looking good manners when he would look on a subset of
them in spanning tree which we call which is called the infinite percolating cluster this
is xk subset of this cluster together minimum they infinite according cluster is also very
simple but now we know that in general and for
a kind of this form of systems c
it is one of the key zero
minus one because is the case the KL member carries the degree
and this is the average of the
because of the degree
you don't get
so we have to understand that they have to understand all of the social factors
play into predicting where we're going
these change the interesting demonstration against the
seven years ago
i would not have expected
there would be no money coming from the business world
small amounts of memory
these are the people who set a bit slow with another four gigs
but it turns out all sorts of different things to play this
firstly we have lot now shipping linux on embedded devices
a few years ago i was calling common
all of these embedded devices the memory constraint
these people are you still think the all megabytes is a lot of that
even more so for what's on the flash
so you coming from distributions which if you install everything
these they take two of three d points hard the
well you never the point that it's not just the methods of definition of the
door so usage you could never have to use all of the trials
is systems where
the test we can begin to fall megabyte flash
because there again the following words like the flash
might be the difference between the product being practical or profitable
so we have a better people are desperately trying to become small time which is
because that helps everybody else
the second reason people and now wanting small which is virtualization
because the historical model the desktop is
web servers getting a bit like will buy another computer
with virtualization the attitude is it's no longer
o my
and in any we'll use the only well-known authors use
CPA UIUC i did well to process who cares
basically every time something one virtual machine is wasting resources of every other virtual machine
that's very visible of things like three ninety nine
that is if you know the results
very fast world another
so the graph starting to realize that wasting the CPU is a bad idea
another big factor how would being driven by miles of better people
businesses while the latter
lot it's actually really really annoying when your battery goes flat trying to do something
so everybody was batteries last forever
how is a big factor for example the people trying to do really really big
data centers
o really worried about power
you know the the scale of one large company we switched over some of the
data set to more efficient PC hardware
start using virtualization power-saving is over a megawatt
the same in which they almost imagine how
the final thing plays into this is that the energy is getting more and more
got some more and more key
o things like carbon credits
the green always of relation
real time is another key part of our common future
large numbers of people in real time
used to be the for all
the typical its user base
interest in real time
does my MP three player skin
there are small number of people using it in a better world the majority of
the users was
i don't know maybe MP three to get one the one DVD smoothly one the
windows around
i don't think that receiving emails soundscape always felt this
today i believe that uses there are people asking questions like can i mean
timing requirements for mobile phones
people building
like piece machinery by someone who are interesting questions like that
if my machine guns that control will it stop before
after it goes through the wall
it turns out the big banks
are interested in this because one of the problems we have a moment
is that if you run several jobs on learning machine
you repeat few times
they don't tend to all finnish time
very efficient probably
do the job better
public can be quite there
so depending on how this
scheduling gets orders
pending on who happens to win the argument that fits in memory
you might start three jobs of the definitions same first step
one of the finishes way before the second so
and this caused problems some application
because there are lots of of solving applications
where we want to do
is right
a set of jobs
so therefore if you then go and compute well PH domain
y given x theta so basically trying to hidden markov models discriminatively
you get this serious part of it
well what's the upshot you can take it mark model implementation
he trained discriminatively you get this year you don't need to record everything from scratch
now to see whether we can make things a little bit more fancy
so far we've been looking at the change
basically where one variable
just depends on its neighbour which then independent on its neighbour and so on
now what i did wrong here is a tree
i mean you can pick it up in any
and hang out of there
it will be actually OK
now the question is can i repeat the same reasoning that they have so far
if my graphical models the tree
well the maximal cliques in the tree
i just the neighbours
we have seen with sort of junction trees before
never heard of junction trees before
who could explain to me what the junction trees
you can
OK so i will go through them reasonably smoothly
most of the time
so basically the idea
that allowed us
to treat
a chain
efficiently what to say well
every random variable
only influences the next one and therefore if i have to some or all the
random variables i can do this in
recursive manner
but just peeling off from the end
summing up everything had been
doing the same
i propagation backwards again
so that gives gamers the forward backward algorithm
if i have
this model here
and i have some function in
which couples these terms these two terms and these terms
then well if i had managed to sum over all these
all the values here already
and i only get an expression with this
is some function
of whatever value this right no takes
and do the same thing here
and i can eliminate this notice well from my reasoning by just taking the product
whatever comes in here whatever comes in from here times the potential function in there
and then seen this on to the next note
this would then allow me to perform the summation over all those variables here
first of all in nicely decentralised fashion
because i can do this part independently from that part
and i just
need to
seems rather simple messages along i don't actually need to know what's happening in here
just to perform this operation
all i need is just a message telling me well depending on
the right value
how this message in here will look like
so if this can only take two different values only need to send into numbers
from here
eight received two numbers from there regardless of how big this system is
and the former summation here
or something that couples this with
and pass on another two numbers
then here
i will have to pass on
OK he gets a bit tricky
because i can just say well i'm going to pass on the summation over these
past whatever the green state is over here and over there without thinking very much
what allowed us to do
the operations in the right now at war
but i had received all the messages but one
miss out on that link where hadn't received the message here
so how can i make progress at the green
forest received rates message
but i haven't and say i want to go down here
well what i will need is we the message from up there
so i do the same operations for police we know i get the message that
pass it on
here again
well if i want to move up there
need to get this message some adopt passes through
so now this gives us an algorithm to very simple one
it's called the message passing algorithm
he goes as follows
in order to send a message
it was two pi
divided by omega
fortunately for me very shortly afterwards i raise this from the black poured so you
won't see it for very long in any case this is what it should be
and therefore
i'm going to put in here
zero crossings to guide myself so that i don't make the mistake
would you often see
people think that this really is slowly getting shorter in time that is not true
it is the amplitude that decays away
and so if we know
try to
put in
he also nations
and this is what's going to happen
so you see that the oscillation dies away
in time
but the
a period t
is uniquely
and that depends on how much
friction there is
it is not uncommon to introduce
the quality factor
that is high
if there is little damping
and that is low
if there is
a lot of them
and that q which is dimensionless is omega zero divided by gamma
you see immediately if gamma is high
thank you is low
low quality also later
if you introduce that
you can go back to your omega query equation
and then omega becomes omega zero squared
times one minus one divided by four q script
is this any different from that
so is a different way of writing it because you introduce this
what it tells you is that if q
is about ten
and i bet you accuse are much higher for these pendulums
then you have you one divided by four hundred it is one quarter of a
but says omega is the square root of that
it's only one it's over percent so for q of ten
only guy
there is only one it's percent lower than omega zero
even if you make the clue as well as two
the frequencies only off by about three point two percent
so i wanted to appreciate that
most of the time but not always
is only got very close to omega zero
we can look at the case
in a different way
we cannot do that here
i'll do that he only sent aboard because we don't need that
any more
instead of saying i have to wait to overcome my seconds
forty amplitude to go down by a factor of e
i can ask myself
how many oscillations do i have to wait
forty amplitude to go down
how many oscillations
and also relations
i will take this long
to being the period
of one oscillation
but for reasonable values of q
TNT zero and the same like only going on because there are closely the same
so i can write for this
this is approximately and times to zero
that's approximately and times two buy
divided by omega zero
i can now substitute this time in this team
and only concentrate on the decay portion that early part
what i find then that a
after an oscillations
is a times e to the minus come over to t
to the miners come over two times this time after and also nations and
divided by two pi
divided by omega zero
you lose two
but only always zero divided by dumais q
so now
you have an informed
which is minus
times by
over q
is this any different from what we had before
here we say
i have to wait
to overcome my second forty amplitude to go down by a factor of e
we say
if n is killed divided by pi
then the amplitude goes down
by one of each so in one case i ask myself
how many seconds do i have to wait
in your other case i ask myself how many oscillations do i have to wait
and so if q
is ten
it tells you that you have to wait about three oscillations roughly
forty amplitude to go down
by a factor of e
and if q is one hundred
you have to wait more like thirty two
forty amplitude to go down
by a factor of e
eighteen minutes
now you can start taking notes again
i have here
and the pendulums have about the same length
and the objects
i have about the same radius
that means the
the b
which is this coefficient
in front of the
velocity is about the same
the gunman
it's not the same because if they have the same b
but if the mass
of the two object is very different this is styrofoam
and this is unbelievable
there's a huge difference in government
and since the period of the two pendulums is very closely the same they have
the same length
now is how can we specify a joint distribution over phi and theta because that if
we can specify this joint distribution then that's basically tells us we how we can
construct a G that's a draw from our Dirichlet process and there're kind of two ways
of doing this one  is called stick breaking construction and one's called the Poisson Dirichlet distribution the
stick breaking construction is yet another metaphor for the Dirichlet process and it goes
as follows so we have a stick of length one okay so that's black line here
and we're gonna iteratively take the stick and break it into two parts so in the
first step we're gonna take this stick and we're gonna it break into the blue part
and the red part okay and the red part here the length we're gonna call phi
star one we're gonna take the blue part and we're gonna take this
shortened stick and break into to halves again that and that part is gonna
call be called phi star two and then we're gonna be we're gonna take
this break off a piece phi star three phi star four and so forth and
because we started off with a stick of lenght  1 the total sum of the
phis has to be one and of course the the length of the sticks cannot
be negative so each of the phis are positive so the stick breaking construction is
given by this this iterative form here where at each point the breakpoint is gonna
be distributed according to a beta distribution with a parameter of one and alpha and that gives
us our sequence of phis for our sequence of theta we're simply gonna draw each
of them IID from our H distribution okay so that the thetas are gonna be drawn IID
from H the phis are gonna constructed gonna be constructed according to this stick breaking construction
and if we construct G as this infinite sum of the of of this atoms
then we can show that this G which we should be a random probability measure
will be drawn from the Dirichlet process okay notice here that the phis are actually decreasing
on average but not strictly decreasing so on average phi one will be larger than
phi two  which will be larger than phi three and so forth but is not necessary the case
that any particular instantiation phi one will be larger than phi two okay it's also
sometimes called the GEM distribution the Griffiths-Engen-McCloskey the other thing
which are described here previously the Poisson Dirichlet distribution this gives strictly
decreasing ordering of our sticks okay but unfortunately this is actually not a countr not a
computationally tractable distribution so people haven't really used it in practice ok it's kind of a way of
thinking about it but it's not really used in practice oaky so again we can also derive
a stick breaking construction using the finite mixture model so the reason why why we
take the K goes to infinity limit of this model that this model can in
a sense breaks down is because we basically assume a symmetric Dirichlet prior on our
mixing proportions right so that's that basically says that every makes every component
has a priori equal probability under that under our prior of being assigned a particular
data point okay so so that actually makes the so basically what we have
is a uniform distribution on one  to K as K goes to infinity and of
course that will break that doesn't actually approach any any  valid distribution on the
natural numbers as K goes to infinity there's no uniform distribution over the over the
natural numbers so the idea to get to the stick breaking construction is that we
can permute the mixture components under our finite mixture model such that the the first
clusters in our list of clusters will on average have higher probability of being assigned
data items okay so this kind of breaks the symmetry of the of the
symmetric Dirichlet and then we can take the limit as K goes to infinity and
this breaking of the symmetry is basically by reordering  the the mixing portions the the
clusters such that the mixing proportion are kind of either they are strictly decreasing okay or
the are kind of stochastically decreasing in the case of where we reorder them
such that they are of strictly decreasing order then we that gives us the Poisson
the chan the firing rates change with the with the variations in what in our
what the the stimulus were received. so this is well known in neuroscience.
it is also well known in neuroscience, and there are here I point here to some some references on
on the journal of the psychology of music and another on also in nature neuroscience
that music elicits feelings and emotions.
and the more expressive is the music, the stronger are these emotions and these feelings.
so we like expressive musics because we li we we like feeling emotions and feelings
because we feel alive
when we have emotions and we feel feelings, right. this is start very early, you know, even sometimes some
people say before we are born but what is sure is that
very soon after we are born, mothers they use this what is called motherese type
of language.
they sing and talk to infants using this cooing tone and have a higher pitch
so in a different way
than when
they talk to adults.
and this is and this is well known now is a paper about another paper
in nature that helps these prelinguistic infants children to regulate to regulate emotional states.
so for these reasons I think expressive  music is a extremely important subject and indeed
it has been approached not only from the neuroscience and the psychology point of view and
in music perception point of view but also from the point of view of AI.
and here I picked up a few
a few
a few early work on
on rendering expressive music.
the first one is maybe is the one of if it's not the first one
one of the very early ones by Margaret Johnson.
she used rules, a rule based system so a production system
an expert system to figure out to infer
the dar duration and the articulation of the notes playing
fugues from the well tempered clavier.
so let's have a let's listen libi a bit
to that also.
here is not bad
but still it's far from being being perfect. and one of the reasons is that
it is a midi rendering, is not is not sound file, is not wave, right. that
we'll see later the difference on that. that puts a lot of limitations for many years
people working on computer music and expressive performances
they were limited to to this midi type of rendering
that is is much much much too limit
too limited.
another work late later on is the director music just that they use rules but
neural networks to fine-tune
the rules also to even two to learn the rules
let's see that which is
a little bit better
well a a a
well i to do
with three expressive
created on set based on the
an article
i what is in the case of johnson was all was dealing only with the
duration of the knowledge articulation goes to this works by pressing the well that's a
third dimension
it's certainly much better
still it is maybe
the last one in one dimension and and i want you also to listen to
some some example is one which is going on since nineteen ninety nine leaves why
again had been more and his group
they are probably right now one of the
the top music technology music computer music look in the world there are impressive work
using data mining and other machine learning techniques
to discover the discovery rules instead of having rules
even is the system discovered rules by the trade being trained by way of tens
of thousands of notes being played by high quality performance unique global centre for grampian
control programme fiona which is centralized and they can capture very very subtle pull station
in the piano so it's very sophisticated to system
and they get extremely interesting results c
two songs
the solution to some of the
so here we are using
all right
but if you mention
city of usually also have no right
which is already quite
the system used
bit human in the loop
you want to suggest the most probable categories
and then
human selected between them that's why we call is more important than precision
and what is the we also have one or more just
one of the few results
OK so that was naive bayes classifiers
later after the work was published people found out that you know SVM performs well
for document categorisation so here is
some other work
which used writers two thousand datasets sample out of that
and the results i will show
the average over sixteen categories out of four hundred three categories
and the feature selection measures compared here
some of them are scruffy simple filtering scoring as the previous one and some of
them are those embedded they set
taking weights from normal
induced by the model
so here in the graph
this is the number of features
and there is an average f one
on the test data
we want to cause to maximize one
and this is the performance of different feature scoring measures the information gain this on
the previous
here it peaks at the beginning but then dropped drastically actually below
using all the features
speaking here again
they've bayesian classifier
by the two measures
that are proposed in this work
using this normal
way to in the normal SVM or weights in the perceptron
as feature scoring measure
and then based on that
the features for sorting the naive bayes classifier was wrong
so they do help
a bayesian classifier
much more
the other two measures that we saw previously
so and what if the perceptron is used as classifier
again the same for feature selection measures
and you can see here again the perceptron SVM
performed the best but actually
the overall performance of perceptron is not really improved
and if one is around zero points fifty five
and it was similar to the previous slide
so the previous slides we got improvement of naive bayes
but not more than what is achieved here using all the features
and if we use linear SVM
what i mentioned previously
and the performance is better than zero points having
the same data set the same setting
svm normal feature selection
have the most
but doesn't really help much the overall performance there is just a tiny gem here
we can't really say is significant
so based on this i would still say
using SVM
except for
by normal separation they don't have graphs here
but the publication was his vision of machine learning research two thousand three there was
a special issue actually of feature selection and dimensionality reduction
which i highly recommend it's really
a lot of very good papers in there
so my last slide
was my
so one one of the interesting thing is
one observation that was published
and feature subset selection
we select some features and discard the rest
but does discard features can help
in some situations
i'm john merriman and this is history two o two
and so on here every monday and wednesday ten thirty two eleven twenty and way
courses that that these are all really major themes and go over this little bit
on the talk about some of the themes are and i kind lecture on things
that i think the complements
what you're doing let me give an example
when i talk about imperialism the new imperialism why is that europe basically took over
the entire world between
of the eighteen eighties and in nineteen
fourteen i you can read the chapter in history modern europe which had fun writing
but i sure in the boy scouts
and i often say that a lecture the boy scouts because i was thrown out
of the boy scouts input them
portland oregon when i was a kid because i didn't manage to accumulate a single
badge and was totally useless after four seasons and
but that's not what i do it because to understand the new imperialism one has
took over essentially all of africa the places were totally uncharted suddenly became a highly
contested between british
french and german and italian concurs that one has to understand the cultural imperialism and
the order of the boy scouts
in britain
has a lot to do with that
why generations of british using their counterparts in germany in
and even australians you in other places
i began to think it was important people look at a map and a schoolhouse
that they had the color red for britain increasingly taking over the map of europe
and lots of other places i mean of of
asia and africa and lots of other places as well as or instead of at
the very beginning that lecture also looked at three things really ought to know about
the new imperialism why why they did this then i talk about the boy scouts
so that those two things will fit together when i talk about world war one
two lectures my friend and colleague j winners and one of them on the great
war and modern memory i instead of finding the entire war and i i think
quite sporty chapter on that in the book all talk about about trench warfare and
you see a film called has glorious and early a kubrick film about the mutinies
in nineteen
in nineteen seventeen and i'll talk about the news in nineteen seventeen people decide enough
is enough in other time for nothing we want to go over the top
so which is the say that it's important to come to lecture
and it's important the sections i cut back on the reading is to use about
four more books and i use now but it's better to concentrate on what you're
doing the books are a history of modern europe
which is basically second edition which i wrote for people like you
and then you read persian letters not all that that would be rather lengthy lengthy
they are still
you read excerpts in personal letters and wanted to know talks about in weight talks
about relations between west and east and it really phenomenal
moment in the history of the alignment
then you have a pause where you basically just reading me
for better for worse hope for better in so you get to a meal as
great novel jermyn out
which is which is the classic lower was the first naturalist
o naturalist novelist are at least in france
and when he wrote to me now
germantown means by adding the of trees but he means the putting of people being
aware of themselves as
as workers he went down the mines in the north of france in the as
in one of the heroes of the book is a woman called that spain who
was fifteen years old but is seen alive life being fifteen years old and was
allow rule wrote the larger now
he went down into the minds to look at fifteen year-old young woman barely older
than girls working in the mines twelve hours a day
so is the book that just resounds with reality and this really kind of an
amazing amazing amazing but anything like that i hope you will
and then home mister the butcher
hale is about accusations of ritual murder in germantown is about about the second german
reich and it's about antisemitism in a small place with bigger consequences george orwell i
went off to fight
the good fight in spain
during the spanish civil war
where was sort of a dry run
four even more horrible war and even more horrible fascist and it's about his engagement
in disillusionment in the spanish republican forces
the loyalist forces and about
tensions in the duplicity of
stones folks undercutting the trustees and undercutting the anarchists and is one of those classics
is a classic for very good reason it's really marvelous read and finally there's ordinary
i go to poland in the last couple years four five times for
for various reasons and i never enough and i went to auschwitz a year ago
and some you probably then there and it you're going through this the
horror that all
and if saying
you're seeing empty suitcases for people's names on them that people don't exist anymore interesting
baby shoes and things like that we think who could have done
who could have gone out
and simply in assembly line wakefield people or infielder on large which is was a
large industrial town still is in poland
simply gone out and one the brains out of mothers babies grandmothers anyway they found
who could have done
well the answer the chris brown has is ordinary man
and he had a quite brilliant idea of looking at a german
you know essentially policemen from hard work
the top the port town of harm called important hands before
and he follows them from the lives of ordinary people
in two
the killing fields there was nothing worse than that
and it's also short terminal along with these other ones are short and it's also
is gripping it's quite quite amazing so
those are the books i think the history money i hope it's fun to read
thank you and enjoy that and the lectures kind of see the themes speaker
for themselves sections to everybody liked wednesday night sessions
one of my colleagues has only once in eight sections are and we won increased
that because sometimes you don't find a large audience and even friday morning and thirty
slots abandon that cannot we're going to have to seven to eight and then third
one thirty
PM on thursday
at two thirty eight
and i don't know when we starting sections that sometimes we don't do it on
the second week it depends on what what is this wednesday so i don't know
maybe start next week maybe we want who knows but they will happen and and
there's also a short forty paper assignment
so what
will be
one hundred four
well i
he is the problem
this is not
is a
which is what
we also use it
it would be nice to
all right that
it is
exactly the
relations with
and you can use
the way
this is the
i was sure
it is the a
well said
we do
what really
we should
you see you want to use one
so we
it's a shame
it also shows
she what
then they
very attractive option
running it on five million data points may say we generated one thousand clusters and
then we tried to analysis to analysis clusters
OK so then you can already see those two reasons might be very different from
each other so you really want to achieve different things as those
those goals
but some of what is called clustering that's already part of the constitution
so yeah i just want to start off with some pictures before we
going to i was the this gene expression data and maybe many of you have
already seen it so you and so on the left side you see something like
so gene expression data is
is something for bioinformatics where you want to show you yes you measure the certain
genes are expressed in cell or not and you do this because you want to
find out i don't know which genetic reasons that might be the certain so there's
something or whatever another biologists c so the raw data get something actually already preprocessed
process that gets like matrix
which contains the genes in the in the
caught in the rules in different conditions the columns and all you might want to
figure out the certain types of so
there are certain genes which act active in the cells
this cluster the data ideally into
i believe that the best results something useful you get something like this where you
don't have all expressed genes on top and the expressed genes on the bottom
and then you can get this to a biologist and you can
i tell you whether this might have some meaning
so another area which i find quite fascinating is network analysis so
there are many datasets which
i'm not just numbers like gene expression in the end numbers vector but there many
datasets are in form of a cross directly so if you want to i don't
know you look at the internet into one to do
two tools
two data mining and some web pages they always have the structure of the graph
because if the links between the web pages
and maybe not you want to figure out which pages are related to each other
is this is an example for social network the you it's from
so company they collected who right similar to which other persons company and you just
make a graph of the didn't maybe you want to know i don't know which
are the
two groups of people who communicate with each other which books which would more communicate
with each other but actually they don't
you might want to find clusters in such a graph
OK an example which i many people of you're working on this image segmentation
but the goal is to beat
i mean what you want to do essentially is you are given an image and
you want to do a very rough segmentation which just don't segments background from foreground
something detect very very large structure in your data set and then you might go
in the DB
and the last example i want to show
this hierarchical clustering so the ones we shall show before it always
the dataset and then you say you want to find out of five clusters
here we have something where we
not only want to find like a certain number of justice but we want to
find a hierarchy of clusters
the example here still from some paper is
you want to
you want to classify mammals in different groups
and what do they get to such an evolutionary tree which may be so set
i don't know a rat and mouse are very much related to each other there
cluster there's much cluster
but then in a very high scale also related to primates
but so does the distance between the primates to the rats
this is pretty large so its or its
it's a hierarchy so so
all of the animals and then you can split them into different groups
that's call rocky clustering
so and that's the part i want to skip
because i just want to start with some
OK so the i want to start with now is called spectral clustering it's and
i was
which does not right just rings so you tell you to give me five clusters
and then hopefully gets to FA or it will give you five classes and whether
useful or not we will see
so i want to go into detail it is either them and
before we do this i want to give a rough overview you that in no
way in which step we are so
it's very
rough idea of spectral clustering is the following year OK we start this data points
and we assume that similarities
similarity means so that those as i j
so similarity means the similarity between two points is high objects very close to each
other if they were related to each other so the higher the value more
the more i believe those points in the same cluster
now what i do is i want to represent the state in in in in
form but i don't have caught it so i don't assume that those points on
our something like this it can be anything just any similarity function
and then an abstract way of representing data will be used to build some similarity
graph and you will see different ways of doing that
so what we do is we just to each vertex of of this graph represents
the data points
then we connect vertices which are similar to each other so we could say
and then you put an edge between between the two largest so you if i
don't know point one point two and they similar to each other so we put
an edge
additionally what do is we wait that's by the similarities of points are very similar
to each other you could like all this
but it's not use this shortage so that they related to each other that close
and it carries the weight as i j
here they and they may be for positive similarity but it's so human similarity zero
point nine and here we have point one suggests is a graphic way of showing
their similarity of the tools
and then
OK now we have this graph and goal of clustering is then
so this
to find the a cut in this graph such that
such that the resulting things are clusters and define how this can be done
so that's that's the basic schemes
just to give them back of your mind with
because now we need to start some notation
of the other
i don't know ten to fifteen
known now that we know all of the other if you think thirty or forty
thousand structures and the the base of increases is increasing so you have a huge
projects that aim at getting the three d structures
of all the proteins of an organism
and and so more and more so this is what you feel differences but this
is the the fitting we need to care about we start to have databases of
OK so we have the resources there's of thousands of researchers at the start to
be able to manipulate them to compare them to do the right thing to do
mission on them
so the fifty we input minutes for three d structures
on top of that we have network so i i showed you the iteration put
in the interaction network there are other ways that we have so these things are
input kids i think that are created by these technologies that were given kind of
them on the web and need to process them but we need to design first
problems and and reasons that should be able to process sequential structure courses throughout and
then you of course the time series of oppression it is many things but so
there is the there is still the on the data
that's for sure
one the expectations this is a very notable so why do we care about all
that in fact what the bigger targets of these industries so here the goal is
not only to have a good start enzyme for instance or to to make money
by amazing french series here the big expectations for first
in biology as a science thanks to this new that should be able to better
understand biology and there is a big industry towns and cities pressure images of course
so the idea of course we hope that things so all that would be able
to understand the structure of the functions of all the proteins et cetera that we're
able to to international recognition so how does it work to be
there are many things we don't know we in fact we we know almost nothing
about bot towards and sympathy with noise how to design a single organism
that does the function
here there is a very hard find this called synthetic biology
that a OK i want to design a small but we have to solve this
problem like the pollution problem or whatever and if i understand how
so how i can design about these
this involves of course understanding know-it-alls then this can have many applications
OK images and of course there are many applications that are the focus of
possession of this first things signature we hope to be able to understand many diseases
of the molecular level sold locally looking at the global thing i point out that
this is a start but now we can thanks to microarrays they face to match
between history we can look at the article details of how can serve rules how
they efficient over the virus takes place happens etcetera so the hope is that by
molecule are aspects of this we have better understanding and therefore better ideas on how
to solve that
there is probably something which is not so difficult i mean that some successes the
which is about early diagnosis and prognosis of diseases
so before you have you have some physical before you have some something called the
table from the table things at the macro level
of the face of it this is there are many changes at the molecular level
for instance when you have a concern that differ in their kids
things have started to change in your yourselves several years ago
OK so all
o thing because because we have the ability now this approach to process
so sort of information the molecular level we hope to be able to do early
diagnosis and early produces whole how would what be able to show this is thanks
to a biomarkers and things to do section of molecular aspects of it and this
also a lot of of
for instance when you want you can so one of the most difficult occasion of
and is in personal cancer is given different types of tumor u u
it is the moniker you obtain composition of its tomorrow by the effect of expression
of the genes and they need to design a classifier you
as you and whatever to predict whether when i give you my simple they can
pretty what type of commodities and therefore what is the best treatment for it can
of course there still some hope to design new drugs and to have some personalized
medicine that for the weight
OK so i will almost certainly this information but then you don't want to spend
too much time on it
if question is OK what do we do in bioinformatics if you got away from
this conference what types of paper written what other things it's very hard to have
a global teacher because you see that things are going very fast you have new
data every year and this new program every year
but i just want to summarize some aspects of the things that have received deserved
a lot of attention recently
and this is this is a ten years ago first you have to feel soul
obviously one of the the thirty first thing to be solved was you know that
we had this is
the blue component and ten percent of the
so i went to the inputs ten percent the blue component
so first of all pick one of the components with probability given by the mixing
coefficients and then you call your local
that function which generates from the corresponding guassian with its mean and its variance
so two stage process
that generates the data points
so the first time you might be the red components and then from the red
c and you have to sample the state point here
the next time you take the blue component and the happen to choose that data
points and so on
now we generated the data
in that way
we will actually be able to
colour in the data points so if i ran my when i run my
it's about like generate this data set
i can color in the data points according to which of the components
actually generated the data point
which component was chosen
in practice we want to solve the inverse problem the was given the data we
want to find the parameters of the mixture model
that will turn out that if we knew the colours of the data points is
you'll see in a moment
they're in
maximum likelihood would be trivial it would simply say
the corresponding guassian to the corresponding
in other words we fit
the red component to the right data the green and the green bay to the
blue components the blue data using the standard maximum likelihood solution for single galaxy and
it's pretty obvious but will prove that in a minute
the problem is that we don't know the colours the colours are latent variables the
things which are not available to us
in other words when i give you a data set and ask you to fit
a mixture of gaussians you don't see this what you see is this
so you see on college data point you don't have the colours so the colours
are hidden variables or latent variables
so we can formalise that mathematically
as follows
so these latent variables are are binary latent variables
for every
for every data point we have
is a set of binary variables one for every component so zk
k runs from one up to capitol k the number of components in the mixture
each element of z is either zero or one
and in fact all of them are set to zero except the particular one which
picks out the corresponding component
OK so he would be an example
this this would be any equals one to n equals five here's an example
of the latent variable matrix
four five data points
in which we have a mixture of three gaussians which might be the red green
and blue components
so what this says is that data point number one is coloured red data point
number two is blue
data point number three is green and so on
so you see that in every row of this matrix
all the entries is zero
except one of them which is set to one so that picks out
the component was generated the data point
so when i plot this when i put the corresponding matrix of data
i can colour the first component red in colour second component blue and so on
what i would say is this
so if i knew the latent variables i could draw this picture
obviously the latent so i can't
after all that picture instead
we can write down
a probabilistic model which is the joint probability distribution
for the
latent variables and the observed variables that crossed windsor this little piece of graph here
so for the moment just consider one data point
x one observation x
and z is the vector corresponding to one of those rows of the matrix so
this is
so z here my notation here is the z
is a little
it's just this little vectors zero zero one or whatever
and this is going to be a little graphical model
so the joint distribution
p of x and z
will be here said given its parents around today
here that's given its parents which is z
so i need to write down the marginal for z and the conditional for x
given z and then i've specified the joint distribution
was that is just a little indicator variables appear given z
if i know
which components generated the data points and is just the guassian with the corresponding and
and variance so p that's given z i can just write is the product of
all components of that guassian raised the powers zk k
because all of these numbers is zero
except one of them which is one
and that it's not the corresponding guassian
and similarly for the prior probability of the
of said remember when i generated this from matlab i picked the component with probability
pi k
OK component probability pi k so again z
i could just write is the product of pi to the powers that because all
the z zero except one of them say zj j
and that picks out the mixing coefficients pi j
so if i multiply this by this i get the joint distribution
these are both exponential family distributions life
i've expanded instead of just writing down
the distribution of x i've expanded my space by introducing latent variables and written down
joint distribution
over the observed and the hidden variables
that distribution is expressed by directed graph
in which the conditional distributions are from the exponential family
very simple example but we can apply the same idea much more complex models
now i can ask the following question i ask what the marginal of x one
p of x
what you get p of x
the math
o using huffman codes in this dumb way i could try and be a bit smarter you could say
let's encode blocks of characters together
and so you could take encounters time and say i can kill of this problem
one simple by itself being very probable by
having blocks say
six characters time or maybe sixteen characters time
and analysis all possible
blocks of sixteen characters
and ask the audience what the probability and all
fifty to the past sixteen
sequences of length sixteen is assuming alphabet size of size fifty
and then we can use the huffman algorithm to encode the blocks
well you could say
i think in terms of runs we could say how many runs and one other
and here we could ask the audience to predict how long do you think you'll
get ones fall before you get it wrong
and how can i ask you for bets on the number of how long the run is
and i give an integer that was
zero and it was five get a zero
five and then there was a around like three
and then there were three guesses and so forth
so we can encode into a different alphabet where we talk about run lengths
and then use the huffman algorithm and then if you if we can still use of
but maybe
we're finding is a little bit complicated
and maybe we'd like to move on and say that there's a better way than
simple codes and that's the message of this lecture
if you were to do what i just described the for example including blocks the
characters you'd have to compute lots more joint probability if we got up to this
i would've been saying q
okay i e e now tell me what you think that the next five characters
might be just the next five years ago i guess again and again and again
and i be implicitly running through a great long list of possibilities for the next
five characters
which you would have to actually compute
even though only one of those five character sequences actually don't happen so you'd have
to think about many more possibilities
so in summary
what we would like is any solution
data compression
where we can use
context dependent
probabilistic models
so we want to allow dependent want to allow for adaptation
andy we want
to be able to handle very concentrated probability distributions
so here's the summary
we want a methods that can handle
so we want
anne d
we want to get rid
all the symbol code gap between our land age
by handling strong certain distributions well
about tell you how to solve this problem but first let's just think it's something
we can do with this board before we wanted of
here's the game is to play
i'm gonna write down the green integers on a piece a paper
so how many guesses that did for the first character
five for the next five for the next three
one one one
one one one one and so on
well i could write down those entities on a piece of paper
and now
these integers
contain enough information to reconstruct the headline
sort of
imagine that's through this small here there's another lecture theatre identical to this one
identical in the sense that it's got a lecture in the front
here's my identical twin and all the view in the lecture theatre
are also there in the form of identical twins with exactly the same thoughts beliefs and predictions
and we post this
into another lecture theatre
and i come in and i said we just talk about symbol codes and now
we're gonna play a guessing game and i'm going to tell you a headline that
i've got written
thank you very much on this is a paper here
over the headlines and that it uses this alphabet and please start getting and now you make guesses
you say
and i say no
as a user may and i don't know is that this site and then when
we get the fifth guess cause has five on this with babies someone says them
and i said yeah that's what it says it is okay and we get them
and then we keep on going
stopping you whenever you get the right number and because we perfect identical twins
the next lecture
we would end up writing down exactly the same set of letters on the board
we go through the same reasoning process
and we would end up with a headline
so that's a fun idea
that we couldn't quite implement because we have all got identical twins
but it's the the whole it's the heart of all state-of-the-art compression algorithms that you're
range have identical twins the two ends and those identical twins run forest this context
dependent adaptive probabilistic modeling in software yes question
the question is are we assuming that it's a deterministic universe identical twins would exactly replicators yes
for the purposes of today the universe is actually deterministic and your identical twins would
behave exactly the same as you
that's the analogy and i'm assuming
four this to work in real life we need to ensure that we have to the deterministic computers so
be adaptive probabilistic model that i'm talking about will be a computer program that tries
to emulate an expert audience like you
hand we will have
one copy about program at our encoding
computer will have an exactly identical deterministic copy on another computer that will work in
exactly the same way so that we can replicate your guesses in your predictions
okay so how do we do about well first i'm going to introduce the encoding methods called arithmatic coding
introduce it to you
using several
toy examples
one of which will be the you the whole identical twin
that will start with slightly simpler
so let's give ourselves three tasks
these are tasks that are simpler than the general
desire that we have on the board over here
this implies that they have to be the essence
of the problems are grappling with
the first example is going to be bent coin
and we might have a bent coin with probabilities
they be
equal to i don't know point nine nine
o point zero one
so we already know that symbol codes struggle with this we have to do
something clunky with symbol codes to get any compression
for the bent coin
this is a database of
real objects now, as opposed to handwritten digits
they're toys bought in the USA
there's animals,
planes, trucks, and cars
there's five different objects each of which is seen from many different viewpoints under many
different lighting conditions
and then the test set is five more objects not the same objects so rigid
geometry is not gonna help you here
five more objects of the same class. so in particular
one of the test animals is a stegosaurus, so you have to gen--you have to realize that a stegosaurus is a lion,
not a plane
because the toys were bought in america,
every single person is holding a weapon
so the concept weapon would have done equally well.
in the data,
that is, in the norb database, there's two ninety six by ninety six images
so stereo pairs
with a centred object
the edges are mainly blank because it was designed for convolutional neural nets
and the background is uniform and bright
so i was in a hurry. i did this just before i left to come here,
in a few days,
so i simplified the data by: i first throw away one image
and then i only use the middle part of the image that was left and then i
downsampled it in the crudest way by averaging four pixels together
and then i looked at the histogram of the intensities
which looks like this, where this is the bright background
and i threw away all this stuff
and call all the background zero, and then just measure intensity this way
so now it fits the rectified linear nicely because got a lot of zeros
and then some fairly uniform values above zero
but limited
so that was the data i used
and i showed you lots of pictures of it. you can still tell what--what
the things are pretty well.
there's a few cases where
the bright pixels you throw are really important, and you can't tell any more what things are.
and here's the results i got
so this is now on images of real objects, as opposed to mnist digits.
if you take the full norb
database with
the full resolution images
and do logistic regression on the pixels, you get 20% error
if you train a gaussian svm,
or rather, leon bottou trains a gaussian svm, and he's pretty good at training them, you get
eleven point six percent
a convolutional neural net trained in le cun's group worked out really good, 6%, but this
thing has knowledge about geometry built into it. it knows which pixels inare near which other pixels
that's the best published results so far, although we've now got 5.3%
with another method that we haven't published yet.
on my little reduced norb,
if you do logistic regression on the raw pixels, you get 30% error
so looking at this and looking at this it's obvious you take all these numbers
and multiply by two-thirds, right? because that's what turns this into this. and that's obviously
what you lost by going down to this
so you should mentally multiply these by two-thirds.
if you do one hidden layer of a thousand units,
train greedily, and never fine-tuned, just greedy trained
and then you do a logistic regression,
you get fifteen percent.
if you do two hidden layers,
another hidden layer of a thousand units, you get down to 10%
i have to admit there were various different experiments went on and this was the best
but that's already better than a support vector machine on the full resolution data
now you might argue that, well, maybe i'm doing a lot of regularisation here
but that doesn't sort of fit with this very well
well, maybe it does, 'cause there aren't many parameters there.
this is just to demonstrate those kinds of units work nicely for
real valued data
and that greedy learning with no fine tuning
is already getting good features
if you were to back propagated, you'd now presumably do significantly better.
these are some of the features it learned
the first hidden layer of features
you can't see them very well here. there's little local sort of gabor-ish things
and there's some much bigger features like this guy that you might be able to
see, which is the sort of edge of a car
so with binary units, a feature--the most a feature can do is come
on and say hey
i'm i'm here
this feature
if you show the car that matches that
it won't just come on, it'll come on with a high level and say, hey hey i'm really really
so that's a bit like a template match or a partial template match
so you can have some units that are very informative
OK so that's one way of doing real values. here's a more standard way of doing real values
that's been used quite a lot
this is the value of a pixel, a real valued pixel let's say
and this is the
and what we're gonna do is have a parabolic containment function
so i have some bias for the pixel that says i'm minimum energy when i'm here
at this bias level
my energy goes up quadratically as i go away from there
and then the effect of the hidden units
the top down input that this pixel is receiving from the hidden units
is going to correspond to an energy gradient
because you have a term like this
take its derivative with respect to v i,
set this to one, take the derivative with respect to v i, and you get this product, right?
looks like this
so the minimum energy state for this pixel is where these two gradients balance
so as this term gets bigger it'll move out linearly, because the gradient of this thing increases
so essentially
you put this parabolic containment function on each pixel
and that guarantees things won't go crazy
and now you can write down an energy function. so this is the normal energy function
visible and hidden units
except that i scaled the visible activities by the standard deviation of this--
of the gaussian whose negative log is this parabola
because this is all in the log domain
and then
those terms to do with biases on the hiddens as usual
and there's this containment function which looks like that
so that's an energy function
and you can
run your markov chain just like before. you can activate the hidden--activating the hidden units is
just the same as before you just use real values times the weights.
then reconstructing
you use this picture. you get a top down input which is the sum of these
you can just set this to the energy minimum
and you can add some noise if you like
if you need--if you want to learn the variances, you factor out the noise. if
you just set all these to one
you can be deterministic when you reconstruct
and that works very nicely
it's slow. you need to use a learning rate that's like a hundred times slower
than for binary units which many people don't understand
so many people have published papers saying this doesn't work and we got lousy results and blah blah blah. actually you just
use much a more smaller learning rate
so here's a student of mine
who's very determined called alex krizhevsky
trained a hundred thousand
binary filters
so the idea was similar to reconstruct this organisation hierarchy from social network data
and so basically we were having we had communication records
at the time roughly seven hundred seventy just people and so probability that would be
roughly were able to reconstruct the organisational structure so what we did
so the whole approach was roughly five steps
first we started with the minister lotfi seven show
one example of this law applies lot lines from log files in the next slide
then b
clean this we got email transactions with section was written a sense person b so
we had just who sent email to whom and at what time does not know
out of this we construct the graph and this graph OK was transformed into sparse
matrix and then we we
they can assist institutional taxonomy ontology
now the data which we used so it should be used the data from email
spam filter software so somehow spam was already removed by the software itself and since
we using the log files directly from this suffering was
pretty easy and in doing so we we had information assets owned by sender and
receiver send this is an example of successful email section was about john davies
the correctly spelled
this time it was automatically generated to me at a certain point
maybe if you can there but you can check
we had
something like this up
the metadata for
from september fifteen two thousand three
march two thousand five roughly two
four four year in
initially we had just to give you a feeling for initially had on was thinking
about the data
after filtering out successful human sections it remained just five hundred sixty four megabytes and
these are often included two point seven successfully email section for further processing
so the whole dataset
references to forty five thousand email addresses
so this spammers of course joking and after cleaning
cleaning means that we removed all the email addresses which appeared less than ten times
so this was
good heuristic to remove all everything what was not really useful it remains seventeen thousand
email addresses of each seven hundred seventy million addresses were internal ones and so you
see this
almost eight hundred people communicated with roughly sixteen thousand other people so is
graphic communication records of our institution probably other institutions will have the same thing same
style of proportion
OK and so what got out of this so then we transform this graph into
the the for
some kind of analytic representation and we did clustering on top of it and what
it came out so
so this graph shows the set of clusters
hierarchical clusters and we can actually see that the structure of our institute so all
the email addresses related to
department of physics
would be kind of more closely connected then let's say connected to
maybe chemistry are two
electronic departments which would be one computer high-tech department
and within
well i think departments you would have obvious difference between different
systems controlled a i conferences communications and even AI we have a couple of department
store groups
we would see subgroup so basically this graph really
if we perform e simple not too complex
clustering on top of it then we
you can see
how this gets
split in into two
organizational structure of the institution
so another visualisation of the graph would be the following
so maybe you can see this this is this two d visualization there
a couple of mountains here we have three months this one this one and
this one and if the
number so each
i here would be one person in if we have more than area then we
would get
mountain and of higher mountain and we would nicely see
scientific sets of departments and administration in the middle which is connecting point connecting point
other people
this is one example which is a little bit related cool
x two and so on
the graph from the document
email logs from the middle so this means that
people from
chemistry would communicate with the administration of physical laws of physics would also think that
there is no content involved here
in this log file they were just set the recipient
i don't have any additional features
so i just a few more slides on this MSN
but is this would be
for relaxation at the end so this is just simulation which i won't go into
much into this
how complex clusters can come out and so this would be classed departments and clusters
and we can see that
basically a clustering was able to isolate very well
the existing departments
OK so the last topic is analysis of MSN messenger communication network services were done
by unesco it's last year when he was interned there
what kind of data that he get
for every conversation on MSN messenger
he had a list of users specific participated in the conversation and in principle there
could go somewhere people people on the conversation but
this is mostly they are just doing what preach conversation we have and for each
so if see all familiar
wz p
so we now instantiate w therapy for non rigid non rigid shape
it's just this main shapes s
a linear combination of these basis
well we're we pk
it is the thing i'm trying to solve
and i have the shape parameters here
now i artificially i can artificially insert
similarity is similarity transform here quite easily so at my talk and non rigid shape
but you can incorporate
so you can actually have
and i can think that's represent translation
in x and y
scale and rotation in
so that adds an extra four argument is that and that's what's quite simple to
so you can just to think of it as a linear
this is the linear model against the linear shape model
and so
so you so we have the construction of appearance model
and exactly what i'm showing that sort of god
the actual image on the source source image i will to the main shape so
rather than removing just the similarity although
richard what sorry i actually what this to the main shape surface s and that's
what i did PCA PCA on that appearance not on the non rigid shape
so but to shameless textures and then you can output that so
it's like an example of the
this is that it can become very well
this is a little bit of illumination change their
map opens kind of guy
coming out there
but essentially that's that's the variation in the shape
and and then again very very similar so actually the functional form of of the
shape and appearance models are exactly the same with PCA on appearance with PCA and
unable to develop my parents are all
and the template is that the mean appearance plus
variations in the shape
so it's exactly the same in microarray experiments only
so that's how i close the problem in concurrency from the previous the previous lots
of galaxies that have been going over
that it's quite simple then actually sold land and people
so this is the full idea of what's going on
we click on hollywood points thousands if not millions of points with process analysis so
that we know that we're really worrying about non rigid shape
we then PCA on the non rigid shape and
they're kind of more advanced techniques then the pedia now you can do things so
obviously cover
and we do this
a probabilistic PCA interpretation of this so kind can regularize for how much your face
can vary the things that so
let's say
i want to make sure that my face variations stays within possum minus three standard
deviations of original shape
and similarly by the PCA on my appearance models and again so this is the
linear shape model but the magic comes with
putting the two together and how do i fit
so when i have a
incoming power
so when i want to instantiate model so i've got the appearance here
and i know what my
so values so a lot of the first argued that the organ value of god
three thousand five hundred fifty nine three one to megaton fifty six
unable to put together the shape
the smallest and i determine our rate of convergence in the norm anyway OK
so one thing that happens in this case then this is we are looking at
so our matrix are semi definite
right positive semi definite definition simply says that for all x not equal to zero
august i don't need that here x transpose a x is greater than equal to
OK so i standard definition that makes all the analysis works here is that we're
interested in the support
of a by b
and this is just simply i want to minimize
i want the minimum lambda such that lambda b-minus positive definite
so what this means in terms of electrical circuits it says that i have two
electrical circuits one a and one b
and what i want to know is how many copies of the electrical circuit the
do i need in order to be able to carry as much current for all
experiments is a
good on the condition number here just the product of these things
so what ends up happening now is from electrical point of view what we're going
to do the viewer two
graph electrical circuits
and what we're going to want to know is how do we then
a might be that support b by a and that's going to determine our own
good and so how do you do that classic thing here is is using what
are called path embedding
so suppose we have two graphs
with vertices v gmbh
the path embedding is simply a map from the edges of g
to pass in one of them but passive h
such that the big the path begins at the end of the j
so let's just a small example here
so i suppose in this example now we have two graphs one is a complete
and the other graph is therefore cycle
so suppose we have our four cycle here
in a dream
and then the red graph here is actually a k four
so there's a natural path embedding namely this red ed will simply map mapped to
the screen in this red and will map to the screen edge this one here
to to here but this essentially here doesn't exist
in the original four cycle so why don't we just map that the path to
use this screen and then the screen
at the same time when we map
this redpath here to these two bring edges so the net effect now
so i guess
slide here so
so in the in this example then what happens
is the critical thing that makes all this analysis work then is the following
and that is
in this example
there's going to be congestion
have so the congestion in this case then it's going to be what
this enzyme is used by three pass straight namely the search
this engine genus right in the original k four
so the congestion here and that seems to be the worst right this has congestion two
and to so the top the worst congestion is three
the dilation here
in this case well
this red edges rap one and the same length so it's not dilated all right
this said here this red one is mapped a path of length two
so the dilation is two
so a natural thing then this is that the congestion time dilation in this case
is six
so what i want to claim then
and the set here in this slide
it's just check see
now let's go back
so if i go back so i guess that's missing here so any other slide
so this is the so so in this case here than a standard there and
then it it's is not hard to show is that the support then of k
by the cycle of size four than it is
o is bounded by
and so so therefore
and on the other hand clearly the support
c four
by k four sentences subgraph just to the path embedding is unit one is less
than or equal to one
so this says that the condition number
the class for k four
and the class c and c four
that is less than or equal to six
c is the cycle of length four
OK thank you
OK so so that says and is that in this particular case
that if we precondition k four with a four cycle
we expect to have to do about six iterations for better if we did the
naive method
and if we did conjugate gradient then we need to do
square root of six iterations but of course is the constants and the right
so this is the technology than that used to be able to analyse one quality
precondition to another
so i guess what i'd like to do actually is just talk about historically what's
happened in terms of solvers
for the
the plane or case still classic place for which
elisa theoreticians have cut their teeth
and so
if i go back to linear so to say well
prior to the fifties nothing was known as you could say that run time with