that four so if we want to learn trees we have hierarchical clustering if want
to learn flat cluster structure we have k means mixture models
if we want to learn some kind of dimensional structure we have both linear and
nonlinear manifold techniques but maybe what we want is to put it somewhat ambitiously is
something like this more universal framework replaces this this grab-bag toolbox of techniques with a
more principle in general purpose approach that's able to not just learn all of these
different forms of structured figure out which is the right one
so charles kemp did some really work when he was in my lab on this
project and this was published a year or two ago in PNAS and the basic
idea a couple of ideas about what is to come up with a universal
a language for representing all these different forms of structure in the same terms and
for that we're using graphs
the each of you know if you want to talk about dimensional structure manifold structure
trees either latent hierarchies are observable trees if you want to talk about flat clusters
those are all different forms of graphs and then we'll will define distributions on these
graphs to fit to the data but another team key idea is that each of
these different forms of structure can be generated by a simple process what you think
of as a graph grammar like a rule for taking a node in the graph
and its in and out links and replacing it with two nodes so growing a
little bit of structure and the appropriate in and out
a portion to those two new nodes and that's that that is a simple generative
model for these forms structures different graph grammars different rules are we to parameterize these
different structural forms
so now we can cast this learning problem in a hierarchical framework like this with
the lowest level is the observable data the typical matrix and then we have these
two latent levels that were interested in there is the level of what we call
the structure which is some graphs and it's a graph of particular form that generated
by some simple graph grammar at the higher level and by taking single productions or
cross products productions like say a cross product of two
two chain rules gives you a two dimensional grid i skipped over performance like for
example across down in the lower right across the chain ring gives us cylinder structure
and so what we want to do is basically do inference at both levels of
hierarchical model
as a way of learning the right structure and or the right form of structure
and the best structure that four or you could think of it as a kind
of fun structural grammar induction like by analogy to language or you want to learn
the grammar at the same time as you have to use the grammar to parse
sentences in order to even know how well it fits so i don't have time
to tell you about the details of our probabilistic model i just free to the
paper but the the basic idea
you should be again pretty much familiar to bayesian machine learning crowd there's
sort of the the
this kind of bayesian occam's razor in the probability of the of the graph structure
given form which tends to prefer simpler forms like for example the chain structure well
a flat cluster structure is the simplest change structure is is a little bit more
complex but some for the tree and so on
and then the the probability of the data given the structure for that we're using
some really neat ideas that together now to sort of classics in the NIPS community
on the idea that you can use a graph to parameterize the gaussianprocess just to
capture the notion of a smooth distribution of data by something like that you know
the covariance being be some kind of normalized inverse graph class in
and in the particular close to this is the work injuries you and lafferty and
ghahramani did but there's many probably equivalent approaches and what we're doing here is is
basically searching over this this these two levels to find the best grammar the best
graph that for
i can tell you details about later but just to show you a few results
of using this approach given a dataset of animals and their features and these are
you know genetic features these are the kind of things the child would see if
they walk around the zoo are real picture book like a walrus has flippers or
dolphin has a tail or dog barks that sort of thing the model is able
to is able to identify
plausible tree
the captured something of the hierarchical structure biological categories as the normal human child my
understand them but also to identify that should be a tree as opposed to some
other kind of structure so given say for example the data set of more political
domain supreme court
opinions these are all justices who served on the rehnquist court
then it identifies not auditory but more chain structure capturing the left right or liberal-conservative
spectrum if we if we give the model say for example on data that comes
from space of faces these are realistically rendered synthetic faces where we tweak interface synthesizer
two knobs corresponding to dimensions of basically masculinity and racial dimension so you can see
if you go sort of from top to bottom here what looks like a white
to black dimension and if you go from from left to right you can see
a sort of subtle mass masculinity variation the ones on the left is supposed to
be the more heavily masked faces it might help if you think that the ones
on the left are like the football team and the ones on the right are
more like the tennis team
and our models able to identify those two underlying dimensions but there's dimensional structure and
so obviously this is what we call fallacies of relevance or the paradoxes strict and
material implication
implication for us for relevant logicians should be a closer bind between the antecedent and
consequent then you get just with material implication material occasionally look set is this it
the truth values doesn't look at the content
now because of that a lot of people have said
what you want
is a logic where we have what's called variable sharing
i think this is all should be on you know some of the retina
variable sharing says that the antecedent and consequent of any theorem should share least one
non logical bit of information
what's that some
proposition letter columns in common
so you don't ever get off topic completely
that turns out to be OK variable sharing
not that because we don't have very much sharing so that you do
that you don't
that doesn't eliminate this one is this problem things summer school positive paradox well
what we really want
isn't just variable share a lot of logicians have said well what you just say
will take all classical logic but only those their rooms where we have variable sharing
that's called something called
relevance filter is one that was called turns out the logic is horrible
OK that you can actually ties many normal way because
because obviously there are versions of this and then this
that will have variable sharing but
it's still so how do you formulate how do how do you formalise it so
you get that and so on i mean those cases are too hard but the
OK so now
why is this the problem is what we really want isn't just this variable sharing
but vertebrate notion of implication
what does it say something and find something else this tells us that p is
true then
anything implies that's really the sets
and that really is
what's behind what's wrong with this
just because something is true even always true
doesn't mean everything entails that everything
anything fall it follows from anything
just because something is true doesn't mean something
implies that you've got to have
in saying
the moon is made of green is the moon is made of green cheese implies
i'm standing here lecturing right now
we know understanding and lecturing right now
that's not a real national implication that's the notion that if someone says
well there is that really implying this tuna in the outside a classroom and logic
you would say no
and that what you would you would say no because under any normal notion of
any pre theoretic notion implication at
anything you would think before you learn classical logic you would say no acumen class
quality so you have the second just to the truth table
but that's theory
replacing our normal concepts
but we want to represent and on the concept of implication we need something that
so much closer bind them
the finds much closer than classical
now the key
in my opinion to relevant logic
comes from this notion of the notion of a real use of premise
a derivation now
let's think about the derivation of this
what you'll do
if you are asked to derive that
in classical logic
it is in in the natural deduction system is you probably do something like that
in the same way
and give
some proof
OK so she gives some provably you're not be
he one use a
you would probably this
but still
in the proof again before from and b i wanna
i never mentioned in the whole thing
you can bring an end if you wanted but it wouldn't be relevant right could
bring it in for no good reason
in the brain and then throw it away again we know what to do that
OK so you do that that's your crew
you have an undischarged hypotheses which is the premise
and the conclusion
a is really irrelevant here
so let's do something to make sure you really use the premises
now back in the late fifties early sixties
alan anderson nobel
an idea about how to do this
people have formulated relevant on before but this is the first time it was done
in in know in the natural deduction systems
my them
when you introduce the hypothesis
you don't just introduce a hypothesis
well thank you very kind the goal
if you
active brain cells are very heavy we
i feel in many skulking in the corner where you can get but quickly with
very long stick quite fast
this is
and then the whole which gave the summer school two billion
if you happen all the unexpurgated they
my website
that is enough for you there's even the recall election
four four
we're we're going to do that if you want
in and around that time down to us
now we're going to get one
this process continues
the elevator pitch a lot
this is all about
second moment in which i think
has been particularly exciting last
seven or eight years really transformed
the way
all of that
i guess
he died because of the programme chunk of stuff on graphical models
and i don't know so you will have had
a whole stuff belief propagation
for nineteen
and what about
the belief propagation that come up
so you know belief propagation works that doesn't in
in tree
the graph has no cycles and once you start adding cycles in the graph
it's been doesn't work anymore but and so
and that was here
so the problem but they are more likely to say well i'm sorry i you
know i got involved in the graph have cycles in the nineteen some kind of
a solution to problems i get about and it's not just that they should be
and see what happens
the story
as the problem to talk about
problems of inferences of inference on ground
which are very much the kind of problem
you may that
when you have an obligation
here in the most of the time
the graph cycles in the back of the have very tight
five very tightly so
census rather bad case four
belief propagation
you know there is one school
but anyway on the graph and the consequence
what i'm going to talk about is is another way of doing it and graph
graph the kind of my thing
i think
given that in the past four
i'm not going to spend very much time
inference problems on graphs very well that
nobody present operating problem
but here the when i give belong to all these problems but i like go
through just express you know what the
for each of these problems and try to convince you that it does indeed boil
down doing inference on the ground
and once again one hundred and one of the three
which is
the problem in the
segmentation problem
all these kinds of problems have cropped i
the restoration for example one very wrong
put it back
that's we jump
in the audience
we start again
so image restoration is a problem is easy to understand you you have an image
which is an got messed up somehow maybe you could think of
this and let's say in the medical x-ray domain that there's a known x-ray your
chest and that somewhere
you know in the first is an ideal
x-ray your chest but you don't get the ideal x-ray you get a rather marked-up
version with with blur and noise and so on you could think of that might
version the real x-ray as being an ideal x-rayed has been corrupted and when you
want to recover something closer to the ideal x-ray
you need to think about two things first of all what is the corruption that
happened in transforming the ideal x-ray into this marked one
the second thing is
generally tell me about the prior properties of x-rays and how can you express this
prior properties and is expressing the prior properties of images where
graphs turn out to be so
effective and appropriate
now as i say i'm going to spend most of the time talking about problems
related to segmentation
so here we have a
common-or-garden and an enemy
but i think that's an enemy
and it is
because the starfish and they came so
sort of brightly coloured
it does say starfish dot j tag on the on the so you are probably
never mind about the biology the point is
can we get the outline of this object to anything like automatic i mean you
know what you really love to be able to do is just you know take
your magic wand and way the starfish and no not turn it into an enemy
just get out the outline without really saying anything more
i mean do you think it will be feasible
just to sort of
tell the inference system no more than that there is one object in this
in this scene and can you get
the object well you know for me that's still the holy grail i haven't given
up trying to do it but we haven't quite yet so something a little bit
more reasonable at the moment in the way problem setting would be
to get a an interactive graphics user to roll this try map
you know with a thick piece of lipstick
and the rules of the game are the lipstick is assumed to straddle the edge
of the object
so that's perfectly reasonable to give this is input to say the
the boundary of because somewhere in then now tell exactly where it is and the
inference system will tell you OK that's the object and in fact it can do
even a little bit more than that sometimes which is also to tell you a
little bit about transparency because the edges of objects when you look at them close
in images are not clear-cut and they can't be because they would have to follow
the pixel boundaries in pixel boundaries are weird staircase shape things of course don't occur
in nature so at least at that level there must be some sort of mixing
of colour and in fact there are other factors as well like the optics of
the camera which tend to it tends to blur the outline and so actually the
pixels near the outline are kind of mixture of foreground color background colour and believe
it or not you can actually recover under favourable circumstances that mixture but i'm not
going to think too much about that problem i'm going to think about
and if you do that basically services
standard statistical techniques then
you you you then have two steps the e step
what you do is you compute the posterior probability of causing the latent variable and
what that means in that particular case here is that
if you look at every word occurrence in particular document every
dw here for those
pairs that actually occurred for the other
so you have this big matrix you only have to do this for
you know those
entries that are nonzero
and you do that and that's basically the probability that the occurrence of a particular
term in document
can be explained if you like by
this concept and can see
very simple
of creation here and then in the end step
you just use these
completed statistics if you like you know the
the expectation of the sufficient statistics and use that as these
so what and what you get then this basically
over here
you know how often a particular term associated with a particular concept you just can't
that you add up the fractions
and over here how often a particular document associated with a a particular concept and
then you just normalize
so that these things really become
OK then of course what you do is you you reiterate and you do that
for a while until
you know you reach
you get close to convergence
or you have some stopping criterion maybe we stop the
OK i don't want to
talk a lot about
derivation you really one way to do this is to
we've seen is to introduce this variational distribution
apply jensen's inequality the only thing i want to say here is
that's what we've been doing actually
to be able to improve the generalisation performance of to avoid overfitting
is used this
of what we call tempered version of
where if if you if you look at this derivation with this variation q distribution
you artificially so you have
this term here which is the expected
complete data log likelihood
and you have this the entropy term here
is the artificially increases and term
so kind of year
you know you try to make
these distributions since this is just
the distribution over finite state space you just try to make it more uniform
i'm making the small
so this is there are better ways of doing that again probably brave and then
we'll talk more bayesian approaches
the inference for these types of models but this is something that in practice
it gives you a good compromise in terms of
the efficiency of the whole procedure stays the same
but you some examples here we see for instance you do and you do whatever
twentysomething iterations and if you don't stop there
by using some many the data set to do
the generalisation performance goes up again right and if you introduce this
the temperature parameter for different settings you can see that this is just
perplexity number here
log likelihood on test set
you know you can get much
one so
so what you see is that the objective function as the basis indians to just
optimizing basically the same function with
you know with these variation q functions but if you when you compute and is
that when you compute these these these these q
distributions they are no longer the posteriors
they become
bias towards being more uniform
this is also people do this influences in speech
recognition it's very often
you make certain independence assumptions right that are not true
and then
you're adding up evidence which means you know you're multiplying these probabilities that are not
really independent and then you get to be overconfident in your estimates for the posterior
probability and you know it's just very
i'm not saying that this is you know
something you should do but actually in practice often useful one way is just to
discount for that double counting of evidence is just to rescale
right and say
you know i don't have i don't know if you think about things like morning
naive bayes models or something like that right you know you have fifty observations and
you know your hundred percent sure it belongs to this class right
but you made independence assumption is wrong maybe aviation talk about you know fifty independent
observations may be the only effectively ten it's a right so you know if you
know that you could just
basically rescale
but then of course the writing to really do this is more bayesian approach where
you you introduce priors on europe
parameters say and then use that to avoid overfitting when i come back to
just briefly
so anyway so
you know looking at the BMI algorithm is really
really simple algorithm in the model is simply algorithms really simple
and he is known example of the types of things that you find in this
picture the draw
well i'm showing you basically these vectors
and what is that well
we have many of these vectors as we have concepts social three comes here
and then
it these vectors will be will contain
for each term probability which we
rescaled here
to make them look nicer and and then ordered the terms according to their probability
OK so
each concept with with each latent concept with associated these
the vector of what i call expression probability right and this is what you see
so for instance you if you look at this particular fuzzy concept number two here
we would see that it corresponds to something to certain context where words like ship
load tanker
set up the structure of the graph in which you're obligated to pass a message
to parents and receive a message from your parents we pass messages and then we're
ready to answer any arbitrary query one on the graph
when we take a break for about five minutes and then i will come back
and try and do a specific case of estrangement
moving forward and here
so i've of try to convince you that there are only
it is work is it is managed to compute these messages properly
because it's not entirely clear
it is clear that there are very many messages but it's not entirely clear what
should compute these messages to get the job done because in a single elimination rounds
it's very obvious how you compute the message you can only always sort of approach
the tail the message here when one way from the leaves up to it and
when you hit the tail you compute the message and pass it your parent that
but it's not clear how we do that so we're going to just go through
and then and then you have the full story
how we can compute all the messages so the idea here is that you ask
what conditions needed to be satisfied in a single round of eliminations before i could
send a message to my parents
and the answer was
i must have received a message from my children
so in a single round of eliminations university
the message from the children
you're ready to go
you have all the information that's ever going to be relevant for you to send
message to parents any time after that you could send the message to parent
and so i'm going to try to do is to design a club for computing
these messages so every message when we compute it it's true that no one has
received messages from all of its children and still you don't have to do in
this would work
and it turns out that there is a clever order that achieve that and there
are many orders and they have to just respect this message passing protocol so the
idea is that you remember to compute the messages so forget about the directed graph
just the undirected version of the graph
let's go back to the start symbol
here's the star example
and i've drawn undirected and the idea is
each edge is there's two messages we want to compute p
we need to be able to ensure when we compute that we have all the
information available so if we expect the following protocol
i know can only send a message to its neighbour
well received messages from all its other neighbours so
this no can only send a message to this guy
when received messages from the sky and the sky
and so on that's true for all of the if we expect that
every message we send will be correct
it will be sent under the same circumstances it would have been sent if it
were in the middle of a single round of elimination
and furthermore this protocol is actually realizable
that's the surprising thing there are schedules for computing the messages which which respect this
protocol and on the tree
impossible schedules and each one of them just consists of picking an arbitrarily is the
root and passing messages inward to the right and then back outward away from so
let's just drop in a different color here
so let's say arbitrarily designate this node has been
for the purposes of doing the computation of the messages right and that the schedule
is to pass messages inward to the root
that's the first pass messages that we would compute and then back
distribute back away
from the root
yes number the formula number one number two number three and four
now delta by plus one
is what
well there are two cases
it's delta i
the famous delta i in one of the cases
that i
together with gamma
together with
entails a contradiction
and it's delta i
together with
i i plus one otherwise
and also of course
it's going to be the union
the delta ice
we going along collecting a set of formulae
as we go
we walk along this list here
and as we come to each formula we either throw it in the delta or
we leave it out
we try what can
without going inconsistent
given gap
all right if putting it in would make things inconsistent then we leave it out
all right and the big delta that we
that we're going to end up with is all the form consists of all the
formula with fourteen
the like this
or that we need to observe
a lot of
about this construction
first of all
we observe that for every
delta i
is consistent
in fact
we can observe something stronger than that
delta i
together with gamma
does not entail that guy
union of delta i have ended up
the little set here
a way
union of that with gamma doesn't enter the
a contradiction
why is that
induction on i
it holds for the base case
because delta zero
union gamma is just again
and i'm going to buy
that's what we started with was the consistent
and if we suppose that delta i is consistent
then delta i was one
well outside the delta i in which case is consistent
all its delta i
together with one more formula
well don't i mean this is
with gamma rays
or is it is not known but in order to get one more formula
we have to be in this case
this is the case
is consistent
consistent with gamma
so by construction at every step
we study exist with gamma
that's that's that proof just induction on i
crucial step
in in the whole completeness
well let's
all right
just before the crucial step
the patient a subset of delta
how can it not be
take any formula in gamma it's all a
a i plus one for some time
right at some point we come like considering
all right
we consider delta i together with with
plus one
but i like was one gamma
all right
i mean that can't that can't be inconsistent inconsistent we just said that
right i mean the death
delta i together with gamma
is consistent
which would prove that
but if i i was wondering gamma then then we're in this case
therefore every formula in gamma gets added to delta
sooner or later
the observation
is the delta
is consistent
there is no derivation
of the bad guy
a contradiction from delta
how do we know that
but one of the things they would ask is the referees to guess who could
be the answer is if two of them gases then it is not going to
be accepted
so there is a danger as well so this kind of those things they have
done the first thing they found is that in two thousand six onwards
this axis rate of those established researchers dropped from sixty percent success rate two
one forty
so you can see that
you know when you do
a change to the model
you see the effect that you wanted to study these kinds of things
so you know that in the data mining conference every year
one of the
programme committee members would provide all these kinds of statistics you you know because we're
in data mining they got the data collecting all these years
they say you know they tell you if you have these words in the title
the likelihood of your paper accepted is much much
and similarly if your if your surname is one
you have a high probability now these are meaningless but just statistically you find on
these datasets and so you can generalize because samples which is very small in single
short but it's clear to see some of these kinds of contrast coming
so we may be interested in contrast in terms of spatial sense of for example
let's say
find the distinguishing features
location x in human DNA versus location x in mossley DNA so it could be
interesting from an evolutionary sense or you could also be interested in in the functional
sometimes we are interested in
you overfitting
within the class itself
are there any contest so for example find the difference between students versus science students
you know there may be different kinds of interest they might go to different parts
for example
you know all kinds of things you may be interested in knowing
so sometimes we are interested in knowing contrast between the class
so for example it says within the academic profession
there are few people older than eighty years old you know
maybe dementia
and other kinds of illnesses
probably want a lot of them
to be very productive
be uncertain age
and also you want the younger ones to be promoted to senior positions
and then we can academic profession there are no rich people for this is kind
of an absence of the of the concepts
or absence of certain patterns all within computer science most of the papers tend to
come from the US and europe which is not surprising
OK objects within it we may be interested in object positions in a ranking sense
so for example
find the difference between high and low income earners
you know these kinds of things we may be interested
so sometimes we want to combine all these kinds of aspects in studying the
this contrasts
there are lots of names to be in the literature sometimes you know people write
papers with different keywords for example they might use change
sometimes difference discriminator classification rules and all these things
the contest data mining is generally related to the topics
you know for example change detection
class based association rules
contrast sets
concept drift difference difference detection
discriminative patterns and similarities dissimilarities
emerging patterns high confidence patterns infrequent patterns top k patterns and so forth
what are the characteristics of data mining and generally applied to multivariate data which means
more than one dimension
generally very large dimensions
objects may be relational in the sense that the data you look at the have
a fixed number of features
each feature has a specific meaning
i mean you could be sequential
like DNA sequences that we made up in a finite set of of that
but the sequences could be
variable length
there could be graphs some kind of connected components
and they could be modeled so for example you might have
kinds of models in our people
propose real estate is for some observations
and you wanted to contrast these these theories and how do they differ radically inside
they they contradict each other so these are of interest to us
or it could be two different classifiers you you build them and you want to
contrast between these things these two express
or you might come in our you might have datasets
which might have all of these things you you know you might have
you know the section you can think of
heterogeneous systems
it has a relational
it's a very top level
and each feature could be sequential
are you could be a graph or you can start with the graph and then
you have each node could be relational age could be a sequence and all kinds
of these complications you can put them into the system
users may want to
to find multiple contrasts so in the sense that if you are given
datasets you try to find contact between them and you may be interested in finding
all of
it could be that could be exponential in number
or you're interested in top k
the moment you set top k
there is some kind of measure you given you know
you know in order to compare the top to you need some kind of ranking
so you have to introduce some kind of ranking to these these these patterns
again the moment user ranking know there could be arbitrarily infinite number of functions
one one could choose
one could choose for ranking purposes
you know that's why what happens is you know whenever you're not have you know
the universe is actually play this game in their rank them if you're in the
top rank nobody questions the ranking method your quite or even in the top five
you don't question
the moment you rank is low the first thing you do is the ranking function
is meaningless
and also in the such console in this election
the next round applications they have to do the ranking and the year i get
ground ranking is perfect
next i miss it
no the rankings terrible is meaningless
but they have course we always want to have a ranking ranking makes
like if an administrator very simple
to promote or this
and or to give an incomplete or not to give an incoming
so you need to have some kind of a scoring function so that we can
you know in an australian context if you don't know now this going to be
huge ranking
systems come for example
you know the number of papers he published in the year maybe one
one component
and what can often help is to try running a bigger model
which is a little bit like using more features in machine learning
or maybe even just running optimizer longer asking if it's converged
and finally if gap is large
you're doing great on your training data but you do horribly on your testing data
it could be that you need a lot more data you should think about things like reflecting images
adding distortions to get some more data
and this is a key trick
and those imagenet results showed you
you think about things like regular position or maybe even just using smaller model
so we lost about twenty minutes so i want to switch gears
to tell you a slightly different story
which is maybe when you already heard
of deep learning
which is
what i would say is unsupervised deep learning
many of you will say this is representation learning
and the idea here is that
in supervised learning we were trying to train
these different layers
of features
by essentially using some top-level objective so we have a bunch of labels that we want to fit
and we were backpropagating
are gradient through the network to try to fit all these parameters in the middle
define not only the best classifier
but also the best possible features to make a classification work well
but it's worth asking
you know the lines shares
and the lines share all parameters are system tend to be
in the lower layers
what if we don't have enough labels to actually train all these parameters
and for instance
as possible
to train representation actually train these features without using this supervised information
from our labelled data
and in particular can we learn good representations h or h times the higher-level representation
directly using only unlabeled data
so this is what we call representation learning
what we want to understand is
you know how how we accomplish this in general what is it that makes a good representation
other than just
making my supervised algorithm work much better
so there are few things that we want
and this is these three points kind of a nice summary from yoshua bengio
and some recent papers is
and the three points i think sort represent key things that we really want from a representation
are we want to be distributed
and what distributed means is that if we have k neurons k features coming out of our network
we don't just want to end up representing
k patterns
we can only represent k patterns like with clustering model things that are mutually exclusive
that we're going to need tons and tons of neurons and tons of parameters to do
anything interesting
so we really want our to representation to be distributed which means
if we have k neurons
we rather be able to represent something like to the k
different patterns we'd like to be able to make it much more express
we like representations to be invariant
we talked about invariance that in terms of pooling units you a neuron can turn on
and stayed turned on even when the pattern underneath changes when it's part of one concept
which is generally we think these kinds of features are really useful
and we want
our representations to get more abstract as we go higher levels
are so for example invariant feature we already know about things like pooled edge features so that when an
edge moves left right
we still have some feature that can detect it
and know that there's an edge they're even though it's not always the same place
and finally
we want a good representation to disentangle factors
we want to somehow takes separate concepts
like the color of a patch and whether there's an edge in a patch we want to put
them in separate features
so this makes our representation more understandable
because we don't have all these things tangled up
but it also turns out to make a performance benefit for example when you're using these locally connected
so those are the basic ideas high-level we'd like
but boiling these things down into an algorithm
so we can actually implement
is the tricky part
and so the field of unsupervised feature learning this technique is about
trying to find algorithms trying to find representation learning methods
that eq actually build representations with these kinds of properties
from data that when we don't have labels
the key idea
is to take all the tools we had for training neural networks take backprop
we take our neural network architectures with pooling in contrast normalization
take all the stuff that we just did
but to get rid of the supervised loss we had we had penalty function at the top
that depended on labelled data
and we're just going to remove that and replace it with an unsupervised training loss
and the place that we get these losses from the place we get these optimization criteria from
is usually based on generic priors about
characteristics that good features should have
and some this is born from experience sometimes they're theoretical
considerations neuroscience is sometimes inspiration
for the kinds of features we want to build
so we try to come up with loss functions that sort of us tell us what
kind of features we want to find
and then we're going to train these neural networks
to minimize the loss functions using all the tools we already talked about
and then once we've done our training
which hopefully tell us what to put for these weights w
we can
just use those features
in for example for example some off the shelf supervised classifier that just stick on top
and the sort of paradigm where
we train up our representation
from unlabeled data and then we use a small amount of
labelled data to train to classify the very end sometimes called self-taught learning
so the key idea for building these things is the greedy layer-wise strategy
and the basic idea is that we're going to start from the very bottom our
in some nontrivial cases like the one i discussed it's also it's necessary and sufficient
and then in other cases it's still useful as an more tractable
convex condition
that guarantees the the polynomial is nonnegative
and that's used in for non convex global optimisation of polynomial
as a relaxation is again
black station set
another exactly equivalents but
if you lower bounds and so on
so this was just once example maybe maybe i should skip two
it's more practical example to show that it is nonnegative polynomial constraints might appear this
is an example from single processing
here is a polynomial of course and polynomial
and it's the transfer function of some filters
and coefficients h will be the variables
we're interested in minimizing the maximum value in the stop band of this field so
minimizing the maximum value here above some
frequency omega as
so that's probably a could write like this seem in my city he will be
an upper bound on this value in the
subject to the constraint that h
this course in polynomial is less empty and greater minus the on the interval
so that's nonnegative constraint because this is really saying at t minus discourse in polynomial
is non negative on an interval
as a constraint on the coefficients h
and that's something you can express their sums of squares theorems for these constraints for
course in polynomials on intervals of
and they turn into a semidefinite constraints and so you could solve this problem
as an SDP
that makes sense
and it will be necessary and sufficient
so maybe the last example i can do quickly it's also a class of
applications of SDP
i think everyone's familiar with the standard chebyshev inequalities one-sided or two-sided
that give you bounds on the probability that
for example a two sided chebyshev inequality
that the absolute value of a random variable is less than one
if you know the mean and the variance
so if x is a random variable with zero mean variance sigma scary
then this is true for all
put this the lower bound on the probability that x is less than one in
absolute value
actually tied because there exist distributions that achieves this by
so that you can
think about extensions of this where the sets x could be a factor
instead of just the skater
and then instead of saying that values less than one year extended to some set
anyone lower bounds on the probability that x is in c given
some moments
the first and second moments of c
so we look at one case where actually turns exactly into an SDP and this
is where x is a random vector
with a given mean a given second moment as
and the set is described by a quadratic inequalities
so this set is a set or
it's described by m quadratic inequalities
check should be as strict inequality to be precise
and the the quadratic inequalities have to be convex so the ice could be indefinite
so that we can examine again compute lower bound on the probability that x is
in s
there is a lower bound over all possible distributions with these moments
it turns out that that's an SDP
it's quite complicated has variables p q r and scalar variables but that p
and the optimal value of this problem is actually this lower bounds that x is
in s
and as
product of solving this you also get the distribution of cheeses
so this is one example
set c will be defined by this group currently has three linear inequalities two
in non convex quadratic inequalities
that's the mean of the distribution the first moment
the dashed ellipses here gives an idea of the covariance so that's this ellipse
its centre and then made six years as is the covariance
let's give
so now given suppose we are given a the mean of the distribution given the
second moment
then this is the solution ready
dots give you the distribution achieve
that have these moments
and actually
minimize the probability that x is in c
so this
OK so based on that so you have decrease in one of which is good
on you can also basically
in focus on fully mature and some of other and then estimate which converts some
particularly towards basically the
computer interest
it's unbiased which is not something really chemical invasion but also
its ability to satisfy yourself or limit OK so that's good if you want to
play a lot of you are doing like learning balls all so if you want
to use finite bones basically you can also play with it on obtain some kind
of finite bounds for this type of a spin at i will go for that
so let's basically here is important illustration of the be my estimate
basically the function of so this is basically expected obviously as n goes to increase
to infinity is going accomplish is the basically the all
as n minus by former estimate if they is going to converge was zero as
n goes to infinity this is unsure about this ontology taught
so why do i show something like that actually is already an example
when you see this is a trivial problem with building trying to compute essentially the
dowry of the cell called basically using using some of the calorimeter the way you
can see that evaluation can be actually quite useful for basically low dimensional problems some
of the calorimeter is method of last resort
so what about basically so this is the convergence
this is all the while the realization to be aware the walls on we see
that you realisation we obviously as expected the valuation quite significant so
you all this property that had this fight so OK so i just say that
i would just basically discussing that for people who never heard of the calorimeter everything
i've been doing here
in the case where i think having the unit square
almost a so-called within square
can be generalised essentially to any domain any space so in particular you could have
have essentially
that instead of being say a square
on the two d plan you could have essentially hypercube basically of dimension n x
one and x could be about mentions say one part of
similarly you might be
interested in computing said the volume of the point belonging to the hyperbolic basically
in the space of dimension n x
OK on your mother carla everything i mean this is the same before that supply
also in this context never use whatsoever at any time any time in the process
argument the dimension of the original space OK so multicolour it will remain valid in
this case if i have that can of night rain in the hypercube uniformly distributed
on hypercube snx that can count the number of clubs which fall within the eye
ball on basically by divided by the total number of docs will have an estimate
of the planet of belonging to the i bought OK
so in particular
what is quite we want to calumet
is that the rate of convergence of the estimated to look at the violence is
to always going to be in one of the capital and whatever being the dimension
of the original space OK so this is essentially the main argument for using with
the calorimeters because you start with the government to begin its rate of convergence is
dependent on the rate of convergence to zero or the estimate is dependent of the
dimension of the original space on formal sophisticated methods on the regularity of the contour
of basically the our you're trying to compute the volume OK so that's really what
is really nice philharmonic our rate of convergence is independent of the dimension and this
is why i really
people are using multicolour methods
basically one should be also be careful about what's what we are doing
so if you look at the literature sometimes people claim that
monte carlo beat the curse of dimensionality because the rate of convergence
of your estimate is going to be one of the capital and then being in
the most important one being the dimension of the space this is not true because
you have to be very careful with that
OK so let's go back to the problem of essentially
looking at my problem where i mean hypercube OK
all i'm looking at basically
computing the probability of falling into the eye ball hypersphere of what use are called
one OK using the calorimeter OK so i know
in this case the analytically
divide by the volume of the hypersphere
all right this one
he has the function of the dimension the space is given by these expressions particular
it converges to zero as n goes the dimension of the space increases OK so
don't try to kind of like what happens in low dimensions often can be a
bit misleading financial mentioned so assume you're trying to compute
the probability using monte-carlo
falling within the atmosphere
given that you have an outpouring of solving the cube OK so was the violence
of the estimate in this case
well essentially
is equal to approximately
the probability
the original point i'm interested in of falling within the hypersphere
divided by the total number of samples so you could feel right because this is
very small this is a very small property but you should never forget
that actually what matters when you're doing with the callow is not the violence of
your estimate but typically what matters is the related violence of estimate OK
once more careful when you're doing with the comment that you want to compute the
if we
choose the decay factor lambda
in our geometric series here
appropriately then
graph kernel here converges to the following expression
e is the vector of all ones
both here and here
and this is multiplied to a matrix which is the inverse
of the identity matrix minus lambda times the adjacency matrix of the product graph
as you have seen in this simple example before
the product graph is typically of size
n square
if you to input graphs have n nodes each
so it is
adjacency matrix of the
product graph will be of size N square by N square
and in writing this expression this matrix
is then
cubic in the size
of this adjacency matrix system which means we've got an O of n to six
effort for computing the random walk kernel
the trick
by the Vishwanathan et al
was to recast the computation of these random walk kernels
in terms of sylvester equations
and these sylvester equations can be solved in cubic
run time rather than O of n to six
in order to understand this trick
we need two
first of them is the so-called Vec operator
which vectorize a given matrix
an N by N matrix A is turned into an N squared by one vector
well of length N squared
and what happens is
that this operators stacks two columns of the matrix on top of each other from
left to right
the first concept the second one is its concept of kronecker products
especially product of two
the matrices a and b
and it works by multiplying each element of a
the complete matrix b
and if a and b of size n by n each then your kronecker product
will be of size and N square by N square
so now
what are these
so the best equations that vishwanthan et al used to speed up graph kernel
computations these are equations of the form X = X S T plus X_0
S T and X_0
three N by N matrices
and we want to solve for X
in this equation
these as i mentioned before are solvable in cubic runtime
in the size of these matrices
and as i also mentioned before it's possible to turn Sylvester equations into graph kernels and
we'll do just that now
the first step
doing that is vectorizing the Sylvester equation so all these matrices
i just turned into a rect
and then
one exploits
a well
known fact
from matrix algebra
the Vec
the vectorized form of this matrix product here is identical to the kronecker product of
t transposed
times s
times the vectorized form of x
then we block this equality here
in here
so for its exterior first and then
for vec of x
the only thing that we do then as we multiply
both sides of this equation by vec of
x zero transposed
obtaining this expression
so just by plugging in this definition
and multiplying by
vec of x zero transposed we go from this equation to this equation
down here
now all you have to do is we substitute appropriately and that expression namely
x zero is a matrix of all ones
is the adjacency matrix of g
time city
transposed times to decaying factor lambda
and s is the adjacency matrix
of g prime
and we obtain
if we block that in
the term
it is the graph common value for the random walk on
so by solving an inverse a sort of st equation we can compute the graph
well value
obviously you in the end is to sum up the entries of the back of
x here that's why there's an additional
the vector of all ones here
one can use this idea here
four further speedups for sparse graphs
so we now assume that
the two matrices s and t to two adjacency matrices are sparse
and then we observe the the following facts which is
whenever we have to compute this term here the kronecker product of teachers post and
and they effects
we encounter and off into the four effort
quite apart contains into the four entries
however this is identical as we have seen before
two vectors of xt
which is
a product of three matrices which requires cubic runtime and then the vectorisation is a
quadratic effort so rather than
having and two to four effort for commuting this term
we could be evaluated
this term here which can be computed in
cubic granted
and you can rewrite
the formula for the
random walk across
both as a fixed point iteration
as a linear equation
and in solving both the fixed point iteration problem and this linear equations
you repeatedly have to evaluate this term here
and by plugging in
this term
which is faster to compute you can achieve an additional speedup
for computing
aircraft can that you
so what's the impact on
the cross kind of computation runtime of these different
these are four
graph datasets
having seventeen
up to
thirty five
notes on average
as you can see here
the y axis is the run time in seconds and the direct approach is much
slower than these
novel approaches by which one
the worst case it's even
more than ten two to five times slower
and questions on this
ok so we've done so far is get gradients with respect to activations
and pre-activation it's now we finally need grain as spectra are
parameters because those are the parameters that we will b updating
with gradient step so let's do that now
say i want to get the gradient or the start with the derivative
the partial derivative of my loss
with respect to the connection between the
i with a unit in layer k and j unit in the layer below
i can again use the chain rule so i can write it as
the derivative respect my loss of my loss sorry with respect to
the highest pre-activation at my layer k
times what is the derivative of this pre-activation at layer k for
the unit with respect to my weight
the weight between unit i layer k and unit j
at layer below layer k minus one and again because this
act pre-activation function is just a linear transformation
take computing that they're very simple so the bias does not
depend on the weight so this goes away
and then this whole some here here there's only the term involving
the unit j with respect to which i'm
computing the derivative that mathers
and in this case all you will get is so derivative of the weights
multiplied by the activation but just going to be
the activation itself and so this term here is just replaced by
what is the g if activation in my hidden layer came minus one
and so now if i wanted to take all these partial learns input them
into gradient format so get the full matrix
of all the partial derivatives so i can see that the elements at
row i and column j is essentially just well take the partial
derivative for the tf pre-activation or the
detective is a layer k district that
i with unit times the activation of the j unit at layer
k minus one so one thing to obtain this is just take
the gradient vector pre-activation layer k that's a
column vector and then do not product or essentially take the product
with the row vector of the activations at layer
ok minus one so that means that the entry at the row
i and column j is just going to be the highest element of this vector
times j element of that vector and that is
exactly the expression that i have here
the i have of element of that vector
and j of element of the activation of layer k minus one
so really getting gradient of my full weight matrix for the gift
layer just take my pre-activation gradient
and the other product with the activation
gradient sorry the actual the the activation of the gradient the
activation at the layer below
and next we can do the same thing with the bias
as we've seen we can interpret the bias i just weight vector on
a constant unit equals one so not surprisingly we actually get
the same formula as for the weights but instead of h here we
have one so we just have effectively
during which respectively pre-activation
so i hope i wanted to construct the full gradient
for my full bias vector it is essentially just the pre-activation
gradient respect my full loss ok just grayer of
ok so let's put this all together and to get
finally are algorithm the algorithm that will give us
for some given example x y what is the gradient of the loss function
with respect to all my parameters and
what we'll essentially do is go through all these different gradients
that we've seen in order such that i can always be used computation
i've done before to get my computations that i need next
and we would do this is we first compute what is the gradient
of my loss which respect to the we could do the activation will do
the pre-activation it's formalize simpler at the output layer
so a l plus one that's pre-activation the output layer and
we've seen that the gradient of the loss for this pre-activation
is just minus one vector minus the output
so after the softmax so compute this
and i'm going to go from the output layer towards the first hidden
layer so for k from l plus one down to one
and l one i'm at a given layer k well i've already so when i'm starting
this iteration i'm assuming that i've already computed the gradient
of the pre-activation for that layer
so in other words i have what is the gradient of my loss
just like my pre-activation so the first thing i'm going to do in
my iteration is get my gradient with respect to my parameters for
that layer for layer k well what is that just i take my
pre-activation gradient i do the other product
with the activation of the layer below
so here in this algorithm i assume that i've already performed
for propagation solid we went from x i'll to the output i've computed
all the activations all layer i've computed my output
so this simple operation now gives me gradient for the weights
and now i want to gradient for the bias that just have shown the
gradient of the loss which respect that pre-activation at the
layer k and the next i'm going to take the gradient on the activations
and push it down to the next layer k minus one
so that the next iteration i can perform again the same computation
to get gradients for the layers below
so i can go from the gradients of the loss with respect to my pre-activation
to get the gradient on the loss with respect to the activation at
the layer below as i said by jus just taking
the gradient of the pre-activation and multiplying that
by the transpose of the weight matrix
simple operation and next i take what i just compute gradient
on the activation is right here i do element-wise multiplication
with the derivative of the activation function
again other simple so computation and that gives me now
the gradient of the loss function with respect to the pre-activation
of the layer below and i continue my iteration so i k becomes
came and this one i continue like this until i reached
after no
that afternoon so
my my role here is try to
you've very introductory class on graphical model
the particles will be to the really the first exposure to graphical models although i
know that many of you have already
i am familiar with graphical models but
this is the summer school that is to give
the basics of graphical models from the very beginning
now to make it easier for me like to know
how many of you have heard of graphical model
how many of you
i understand a little bit or more about graphical models
and how many of you have worked with graphical models
and how many of you have published papers on graph
that's very useful because this is we can
calibrate the
for the presentation is
it is designed before the
these assessment so
i probably down calibrated here really going into the very basics
but this is probably not be a very typical
for the coarse and graphical models because
the main goal was to
the present graphical models
from a slightly different perspective that's usually presented so really focus on the basic
the idea is the basic concept and how we build
there is this whole is whole theory
and of course we'll talk about
especially our talk more about applications and and what you can actually do with graph
so the idea is that the goal for one hour and as usual
we stop for
two break breaks
go down
OK first before starting
would you prefer
like this or
so before i start let me just tell you what you can find out there
to learn about graphical models or to improve our existing knowledge of graphical models so
there are quite a few books on these
subject so
i would say
a very recent book which includes lots about graphical model
it's chris bishop's book pattern recognition machine learning that's really very nice book
there are some other classical works on graphical models
like work
laurie to work
which are very very good book
very good references well
in terms of unpublished material i should say that people have
i learned a lot from published material particularly from jordan's book
and also
more recently color fremantle
but this is not a publisher so
you need to find someone who has a high quality
i have a hard copy i for
commercial solution i mean you can you can have to have hard copy
and they're very good views on graphical models as well
in videolectures net you can see for example sam roweis videos
which are really very
extremely good
he doesn't graphical models
OK so after seeing some readers a thought well what should be talking about
i'll just try to give different
type of perspective
i mean
basically a graphical model
it consists of a bunch of tools that can be used to solve problems in
many different fields
i mean i've seen particularly applied to all sorts of problems in image processing speech
natural image processing looking for that by from
compute the canonical is sort of science i mean
and it's hard to believe mean there's is any area
of applied analysis
the graphical models have
if not
then you should be
thinking about
applying the
it's really a very generic type of
mathematical tools to model
real problems
so just a few examples here
and physics i would say that probably
much of what we know about graphical models started lot physics along time about a
hundred years ago
people started to try to understand
the marker structure of matter
basically murders from
the internal structure of matter
in particular how you have things like for example phase transitions
i mean
how does one other can so that
one hundred eighty degrees
i mean things like that i mean how can you explain these
strange phenomenon that you know
they are guided by local molecular behavior
they have a very
very clear macro
we were not
so four
finding clusters in the data
based on finding peak
nonparametric density estimation estimate
and that is
this function here
and one that does one have to do with level sets
now look at another matter instead of looking at the level that look at finding
and so to the gradient
after this
and before going further i would like to correct the typo the is
you so
if is expressed on page alone in the north that this is what the
so the
well to get
if you going to have a
to be
what in france some of k
x minus x i would change
and so if you have this function square inside
what you get used
actually maybe within a
but this is what does matter because
but the gradient of
so to get
you need to be a functional successful
so the idea of this kind of is to
find the peaks of the distributions are to the points where the gradient is
by the way the exact also called valley of the web
the most of the time
present to find all the high
the local maxima
and do you take the gradient which is this expression here right there
and some the region
gradient equal zero
by the way
it is not trivial to find a mix of kernel density estimation so you can
find these things in growth form
but what you can do what you can do is to take this right inside
equated to zero
and then you notice that there is this part some of k problem stems x
minus x i
and should take all the time
context x and put them on the left
and the the
this exercise the right
and this could be just on matter because the constant in this case doesn't
and then you can expression here which is multiplied with
the cell k primes
it equal to
the sum of excise weighted by the escape hatch
so the equation question for finding x peaks
or the next
but x is bordered on the left and on the right so you can solve
it follows four then the best you can do is to actually follow the gradient
which means move x to the point of which is the expression on the right
and if you keep taking x and replacing with you eventually going
they i think this is a little more prone actually locally increasing in the ocean
and so on
and this is expressed in the simple algorithm below
which says that
before i start data points
and the iterate
i iterate the mean shift equation so replace x with which she
until convergence
and because
i'm increasing the value of
at least it means that no matter
last that winter and the people
and now i can cluster is because i was going to say everybody on the
point x i who converge this peak will be put in the same class every
points over here which we call the probabilistic was reported in the middle east
so this is what everyone wants know
so have to be so
clusters with one point of possible like
it is clear what it does
OK now we also that by the way
there is proof that it does converge so this iteration will converge to max because
it's all it's fixed but that's what we would call the fixed point iteration
and it is started in this case to
we don't know much about the rate of course in this case
how to you understand how to do it you realize that very expensive
because these things involves all the elements
computing one mean shift volatility that was because some of k properties of
and of course you can
we can play
the three mentioned before which is not considered all the data points to consider only
the points which are in the neighborhood of x
that i'm looking at
which make it starts
but still i have to reiterate for every point in the data so maybe not
quadratic but it's still very very expensive
how deal with the idea and what
some people did was to make it faster
by eliminating most of the point
comment each and man the
there is nothing in the whole that doing the mean shift iteration for each point
in the
they select to and few
q four which
they say a common data
if you put serious around these cues selected points to cover all the range of
the data
this is really obvious in in one dimension because i just uploaded intervals and then
pick a point in the middle of each interval it's not as easy
in high dimensions because the exponential number of points to cover the whole data and
so another little question about
i how
how to find these initial set of points
however it however is algorithm is used and so people succeeded higher dimensions to do
to find by some
maybe heuristic methods
tools to find for company that was actually one of the ways of doing it
is to use them in order to cluster around that time and they discussed in
the first lecture which finds point as far as possible and so by
taking more and more sensors that algorithm
you control the distance the maximum distance between points
and when the maximum distance falls below a threshold then you can stop you've got
the question is how many points are used and
and how much computation
OK so you select a set of points at its diverse in
that we had
all physics
of the nineteenth century
and idea is called classical physics
examples are newtonian mechanics which we dealt with this whole term
electricity and magnetism
which you will
and counter the next term
the only part of this century
when we learn about the composition of
it became clear that classical physics
did not work on the very small scale
of the atoms the size of an atom
only ten to the minus ten meters
if you take two hundred fifty million of them
you line them up
that's only one it's
in nineteen eleven
the english
physicist rutherford
demonstrated that almost
all the mass of an atom is concentrated
in extreme small hole in the centre of the atom
recall that the nucleus is positively charged
and the electrons which are negatively charged
i orbit around the nucleus
and the typical distances from the nucleus to the electrons
it is about one hundred thousand times larger than the size
of the nucleus
as early as nineteen twenty four named the proton chadwick
discovered the neutron
in nineteen thirty two for which he received the nobel prize
now let's imagine that this lecture hall
it's another
and the size of an atom is defined by the orbits the outer orbits of
the electron
if i scale it properly now in this
ratio hundred thousand to one
and the size of the nucleus
will be even smaller
then the grain of sand
and it just so happens that yesterday
i went to plum island work for three hours on the beach
and i ended up with some sent in my pocket
i will donate to u one proton
actually hold on to it
what two protons that's too generous
to keep it there
one protein
and there would be an electron then also anywhere there
the other walls going around like mad in orbit
and that would then be
how hydrogen need to think about
one atom is an atom
is all
and i
all right
you think of yourself of being something
but we are nothing
you can ask yourself the question if you all vacuum
why is it then that i can move my hand
not other hand
like ghosts can walk through a wall
that's not so easy to answer
in fact
you can answer it was classical physics and i will not return to that but
you i all vacuum
according to maxwell
equations maxwell's laws of electricity and magnetism
an electron
because of the attractive force of the proton what's bile into the proton in a
minute fraction
of the second so adams could not exist
we know that's not true
we know that atoms do exist
so that created the problem
four physics and it was
danish physicist niels bohr
before in nineteen thirteen
that electrons move around the nucleus in well defined orbits
which i distinctly separated from each other
and that the spiraling of of the electrons into the nucleus does not occur for
two reasons
that an electron can not exist in between
allowed orbits conjunction
from one orbit to another
but it can not exist
of course suggestion
also shaking
because it would also implied the planet that goes around the sun
canada ordered to song just any distance
you could move it just a trifle
in or trifle far out it would also require
discrete orbits
it would also mean
if you had a tennis ball
and you would balance the tennis ball
up and down
the tennis ball
could not reach just any level
above the ground but it would only be discrete levels
that is very much against
our intuition we'd like to think that when you bounce a tennis ball
that it can reach
any level that you want to give it just a little bit more energy
and it will go
a little higher that according to quantum mechanics
would not be
now all this seems rather bizarre
as it goes against our daily experiences
but before we dismiss the idea of quantisation quantisation comes in when you talk about
discrete orbits
you have to
i realize that the
differences in the allowed heights of the tennis ball
and the differences between the allowed orbits of the planets around the sun
would be so infinitesimal this small
but we may never be able
to measure not always quantum mechanics we plays no role
in our macroscopic world
at very very small compared to tennis balls
and the quantisation effects
a much larger in the sub microscopic world of electrons
and adams then in our familiar world baseball's pots and pans
and plants
before we continue i would like to repeat to you one of the corner
stones of quantum mechanics
and it says that the electrons in atoms
can only exist
and well defined energy levels
i think of them as being orbits
around the nucleus and they can not exist in between
now when i e the substance
the electrons in the atoms can jump from in orbits two allowed out of words
and when they do so they can leave
a whole opening an empty space in the in orbit
but later on they can fall back
to fill the opening day can occupy
that place again
and when i keep this substance
there is some kind of musical chairs game going on
electrons will go to outer orbits they may spend some time
and then they may fall
lower orbits to in all its
you see here face
very precious face
and when i pick up this face
i have to do work
bring it further away from the center
of the earth
now is the energy lost in all
i could drop to face
and it will pick up kinetic energy i'll get that energy back gravitational potential energy
will be converted
two kinetic energy
it will crash to pieces
and it will generate some heat
effective breaking itself of this phase
will take
some energy
in a similar way
energy that you put into electrons when you bring into outer orbits is retrieved when
electrons fall back
that is apparent
dropping his face
getting the work back that i put it
i wouldn't be nice thing to do to this five hundred year-old face
but as far as i'm concerned perfectly reasonable to do with it so he ne
let that go
and the energy
we'll come out
in the form of heat and also in the form of perhaps noise
when electrons
four from an outer
it's just somebody
had a smart idea
in choosing the wavelet basis and inverting it
it has a nice inverse actually you can see why it has nice inverse
do you see any property of these eight basis vectors
well i'm only written five of them but if you
see that property for those five you'll see it for the three
remaining what if i give you those a vectors
and ask what nice property
well you'd say first they're all ones and minus ones and zeros
so every multiplication is very fast using just in binary
but what's the other great property those vectors in bayesian
so of course
when i think about basis one nice property i don't have to have it but
i'm happy if there is
there are five
if the basis vectors are orthogonal then
i mean good shape and these are you see that take the dot product that
you get four plus one thousand four minus one get zero
take the dot product that with that
you get two plus one to minus one
or the dot product that that two plus one in two minds
you can easily check that
orthogonal basis it's not
i could to fix it
i should divided by the way to make community was supposed to do that
so somewhere here i've got to account for the
in fact
this length square root of a that has links were to four
has links were the two
but that's just a constant factor that easy to
so suppose we've done that
tell me what's w inverse
that's what
chapter four
section four point four was about
if we have
the orthonormal columns what then the inverse is the same as
the transpose
so if we have a fast way to multiply by w which we do
the inverse is going to look just the same and will have a fast way
to do w inverse so
of the wavelet bases passes this requirement for facts
we can use it fast
but there's the second requirement is isn't any good
because the very fastest thing we could do would be not to change the basis
of all
right that's thing would be okay stay with the standard basis stay with eight pixel
but that was poor
from compression point of view right
those eight pixel values if i just took those eight numbers
i can throw some of those away
if i throw
away ninety percent
if i compress ten to one
throwaway ninety percent of my pixel values while my pictures just gone dark
the basis of was good the wavelet basis are the fourier basis if i throw
c five c six c seven c eight all i'm throwing away is a little
there are probably there in very small amounts
so the second property that we need is good compression
so first it has to be fast and secondly
has to be
a few basis vectors
come close to the sea
a few
if few is not
can i write it that way
a few basis vectors are enough to
the image
just exactly as on video of these eighteen o six lectures
i don't know what the compression rate as well as david who
who does the compression and by the way i trying to get
the lectures
that are relevant for the quiz out onto the web
so i'll send a message today
the point so he's using the fourier basis because the JPA so jerry pate two
which will be the next standard for image compression
it will include way
so i mean you're you're actually getting kind of up to date
picture of where this
the world of signal and image processing is
four a is what everybody knew
and what people automatically used and the new
the new one is wavelets
where this is the simplest set of wavelet
this is the one that the FBI uses by the way the FBI users are
more more smoother wavelet instead of jumping from one minus one it's smooth
cut off
that's what will be an injury-plagued two thousand
OK so that's the application now let me come
to my
the mass the linear algebra part of the lecture
well we've actually seen a change of basis
so let let me just review that
change of basis idea
and then the and then the transformation to a matrix OK so
so this
i i hope you see that these applications are really big
i have to
talk a little about change of basis
and a little bit about that the matrix
so change of basis
forget that
i have
i have i have my vector
in one basis
and i want to change to a different what actually use it for the wavelet
so i need that the main idea that the matrix w
the columns of w
the the
new basis vectors
then the change of basis involved just as the their w four
so we have the vector
say x
in the old basis
and we'll that converts to a vector space
no basis
you basically do
four things
before you even think about doing you should
try the nearest neighbour is set not continuous
probabilistic methods the
in my research
you should try naive bayes
you should try logistic regression
and then you should probably try overfitting
fisher discriminant or
is continuous on the other hand gaussian
so here's the interaction with rationalism always says the conditional probability of y
the class given the input x is
this log linear function this of mass
and i don't care about what the distribution of the
this is joint
we want to do
also say anything about the marginal distribution
it's not for us but that's OK train small
the previous suggestions
the training halls
that's why this isn't even though
full model to do so i think about that
we optimize called the conditional
so a new loss function now is the original one
the probability of class given him
this is the objective function use your training time and this is very different than
maximum likelihood penalized maximum one
so this is a very important point logistic regression and naive bayes
are actually identical models in terms
they specify exactly the same hypothesis class
but the difference is the naive bayes is estimated using maximum likelihood and logistic regression
estimation using conditional
so the difference is all in your loss
remember there were these three pieces representation of all
the hypothesis class and the loss function
here representations
we're assuming fixed by class between a and b bayesian is not just about exactly
the same but the loss function loss function is what conditional probability and in a
also was actually like
OK so but that we can take the same approach write down the small right
down the likelihood function and we take
the derivatives of the likelihood function with respect to each
so this is also streamline compilation but directed
they come here is very interesting for the challenge
this is this is the derivative of the loss function with respect to the i
so the parameters for how much weight on features i when we're designing
this is the feature
the gradient of
it's the difference between
the true
the true answer for the example
in our model's predictions
so the answer is
it has one in
it has one of the key position is class labels k is zero so this
true vector is zero or one in the correct position
and this is our model's prediction which is one of the world's one point
one point eight one point
so i think the difference between the correct vector which is zero everywhere except one
placed into predictive factor
some of you are somewhat yahoo
chief data officer
executive vice president of
research and strategic data solutions
topic of research while my general areas data mining i'm not
very active research these days although we're trying to do with your research and invented
new sciences underlying the internet
which is a much bigger topics and just data mining but we're doing what
in your talk you
distinction between
a possible distinction between researchers and
engineers in the data mining community so you research or in g or
a scientific businessman
scientific business and i like that term a lot to the first time i hear
i guess some definitely used to be a researcher i
started out as an engineer and
today i guess scientific businessman
probably spend more of my time on business and science these days but it's a
balance between the two
as we know yahoo has lots of data huge quantities
what is your opinion on privacy policy
privacy is very
important topic for yahoo
in fact if anything we are
traditionally more conservative than
most of those in this area we
i tried to balance
between the user experience and the monetization of the how much use the data to
do targeting
very carefully
and we often draw the line if anything to conservatively could make
ten times the revenue tomorrow
simply by
serving ten times more at
we choose not to do that because what we care about for the long term
is the value
of the long term which is basically represented primarily in the trust that users have
and in fact who is the safe place to be a place to respect your
privacy and your anonymity when you choose to
so as an example of that when
somebody has logged into your versus like that we treat them as two completely different
because they make the fundamental assumption that you're logged out reason
we also do not track any information
with the idea that can be tracked back to you
two personally identifiable information
and most recently we also know that policy for minimisation of search data
which actually we do it
the earliest and industry we minimize data after thirteen months others who are eighteen months
or longer
so there
maybe i could
because of the question
who is
that big
impose mustapha question what exactly it is you who what is it will be coming
on the largest scale
well i mean what you know is something that evolved over the years i mean
you started out as a directory of the web
from there it
added some services that we felt were essential to consumers like email
if the messenger
finance news and so forth and all of these properties attracted
millions hundreds of millions in some cases of users
it's basically a place to find
all the things that we think are applicable or are interesting to
people out there
including place to actually find your way on the internet through our yahoo search
academia and industry
do they go hand in hand
OK concerning academia and industry
what is it
it would be
i could imagine in this you to go hand-in-hand and how do you see
from the yahoo
consumer point of view the bridge between users in europe and america
that's industry and academia work more in america
or europe
so that's compounds and what do i know enough to answer the question
first of all let me say whether they go hand in hand i think in
some areas the connection is absolutely essential
so in some areas the academia is doing something that are highly interesting and
we ahead showing demand by consumers
so in an industry like the internet which is fast evolving
it's very important to home in on these very quickly and in that case we
actually worked very closely with the kids
so as an example here who actually does has a grant program has a fellowship
program we have a academic relations program where we
establish a presence we bring in a lot of interns somewhere
throughout the year
so at that level at which say they go hand in hand
on the other hand industry is much more focused on
working on projects you
results today
and addressing consumer needs today whereas academic typically is what much more about this theory
or you know investigation of norway is so
i think there is this energy
in some cases it is very nice and very tight in some cases they there
are very very far apart
typically in areas like machine learning data mining
information retrieval connection is very strong in areas like systems managing huge web forums
o managing big systems
the distance is pretty far
in terms of the us versus europe i really don't know the difference i
i would imagine that in the US just by the nature of things a bit
more vibrant connection
and i think in europe it's picking up no which more
which industry in the data mining field is the hottest at the moment
which industries in the data mining field is the hardest i think any of the
the data mining field that deal with mining unstructured data and text data
i don't particularly hard man now
any of the categories that deal with privacy preserving data mining
worrying about anonymity users and so forth is also in high demand
i want to give you the wrong impression because you know classical stuff like classification
clustering and so forth are still used every day and also in demand but they
seem to be the heart is simply because the mining unstructured data mining distributed data
and privacy preserving
i guess who's coming to to the end of
interviews so
vision and grand plan how see the future in doubt for the internet and maybe
you who and data mining to how you predict the next twenty to thirty forty
or is that too long
not zero
so you will be
this is presentation
true basically if you know value j
i think you know it
but in terms of liquid
so if i didn't
so far east we observed that it's
there is a sense
so the topic is going to cover is
sequential model part of
this also interesting because it's the
o model that i will talk about in this section course that has a large
number of unobserved latent variables
and we're going to see if we can train very similar
propagation to do
inference and learning
and so on
this small is a is very influential
computational biology is used to
o line
sequences is the core model in
speech recognition software
and it's used in
processing video or computer vision has a lot
is also
more basic all life so in
because text information for example although very small we have conditional
also our
but it's good enough to form the the
and if you have questions
it was also
it's something that you always comparing axes into two
so much all is really
markov chain just like the more yesterday
which we had some problems in the
so is each
more probabilistic functions of markov
we use the first order markov chain to generate hidden state sequence x
so this these variables x will be sees
generate according to just support or
so we have probability first c x y
and given x one to x two x two x three to more or less
but we don't get to
visited states
for each time t
we created output y g
which is a function of the state executed that
so this is a transition diagram many time t
we have to which is are not sufficient quantity we really to say
observations on the move tab
one two is
so you can
this year is
the only had
so your from
the response what
usually state
time one
you can source your initial condition
so the solution what does it tell you twelve
so you want to
well it's the not only had twelve is the transition or is the
twelve rows of the transition matrix as the transitions inherent state well
he was going to all this
so what i silicon transistor you don't know
so that's the markov process each day each time you and i will also very
the situation is generated by
the observation
so on the on the j these distribution
january observations to move around the status according to the traditions each time observation and
all we get to see is the observations we don't know
the markov models action
so this is going to make it is important for those of you who know
you can state sequences first
of the process is not more of any works
so there is no
the local markov models in order capture the
the distribution over sequences that came are of
so that's why i occasionally models in speech recognition language modeling simple information retrieval system
closed in this area
what's your models
so why like use
support from biology and
this is graphical model but you should be very nice so the first thing to
notice is is a tree
three voluntary so treat is going through rest business these things as you can see
some is why are observation and what this small town this man for your our
one factorized distribution be all on y is for you is this
right on the problem of s
given x minus one
what he did
the here
joint probability of a sequence of axes
instead of y factorizes as the conditional probability of x px
so this should be about
times the probability of y given x
so the data y one y two y three or not i d
there's certainly not independent press
the number plate notation there's no easy way to write this small weights
so that's why text and that
OK so
his just his solution to
so in a few
all right my either as a markov chain so is simple first order markov chain
the we're here by hiding in and giving stochastic operations to take this chain we
each time generator with you
observation which depends on the the value chain
you can see or you get mixture models
with the state coupled across
so this
for the last
depending about state
you generate
now what i from
one or two
for k
this is exactly what makes except that the choice of mixture component is called
outputs classifier or maybe best support vector machine
which gave the final output of the model
basically use gradient ascent or descent
it's dataset these because our it's a min-max problem
basically there's a big related multi rule multi-layer perceptrons
like the pastoral like perceptrons
and easy and they couldn't solve like to solve problems that means proper for show
having both ball those perceptrons
put together
we have the multi-layer perceptron
and you can each make the deep whatever you want
a support vector machine deep support vector machine base we do the same person each perceptron
is based support vector machine
so you can understand that
the real person face face much more space
food to get really big datasets
in the dual space
was sold also that all of professor bach
you have probably to
to do some kind sparse case like only kernels
which are necessary on input points
which fall away our partners
but there's
a lot yet the case here because we have problems
with at most like that thousand fifty examples
so that's fast enough
the architecture
uses follows
you have the inputs like given who
in this case we support vector machines
but in general we optimise them with some search algorithm
which is called particles solve myspace
and sometimes we get like even like how the support vector machine here
the psyche from
extracted each on one feature bigger support vector machine
can usually
and one feature
the same time
and promote other classes
we need to train all support vector machines
then this may support vector machine
and basically makes all feature and get the final output
so the work things of the system as follows
you want to get a few presentation just norm requesting
became get some kernel here we use radial basis function kernels
in both layers
so this is really basis function kernel and then we get on feature if you train
for each
support vector machine m one tool in this case for each one twenty three
we can like support vector machine support vector coefficients long term b
for while we get for each data example locals vector coefficients
and then we can compute features
for all data examples also called test examples
and then the main support vector machine
this is just the normal way but now it uses the kernel over the exact features
s inputs
so what we do to train the system
of first we had output function
which is usually like
the function is th
is now all the feature space first expected
for more objective function w is replaced by
a min-max problem but w want to minimise the features
monster marks five for all of patients
so this is still funny how this is going with the min-max optimization
because the same function open out
and also if you look at how learns
the world vector goes up and down all the time
yeah it's like something like cain theory way have opens
it's going up and
this known and into this
it could offer some seven point
but there are
some very often
the training procedure with the gradient ascent as follows
and we have like the main support vector machine
that from scratch simple because we are we've growth optimise the main support vector machine
so we add up all these alpha coefficients can create percent
this space this kernel year
so this is the function
that this is th the gradient ascent update step
both alpha and alpha stop
for the feature layer sensitive the more complicated but i feel like training multilayer set consists
source all back-prop case
so we have applied
the same way of use backpropagation
to get like datasets
for each feature extracting svm
so in this way we have really basis function
even here
then we have this is the
basically now to your letter to the features
then this can be written
as follows
because we know that kernel
we can compute
exactly like
how we won't who
what kind of features how this would be changed
instead of changing them immediately
basically mean we construct all dataset by
een did
to the previous feature
so we have a feature and subtract these becomes want to minimise it
best that dataset perspective
then we get for each point you get a new
feature vector which would be a pocket feature
and then be off getting this training dataset
we we can train each in payments indepen support vector machine
want to know who thinks
first of all you could do this with the multilayer perceptrons as well
by first training output
nolte and then giving errors all the other notes
would be a little bit similar i like best approach offers affect layers that phones
but in this way makes little sense
for the mob support vector machines initialized
we need some kind of symmetry bread ok
so otherwise would all expect the same features which is not what we want because
it turns out that the only
learn one feature source say
so what do we
we train support vector machines the first time
on like better outputs all that bach datasets
so that way it is already like an ensemble method a little bit