and the point is that
throughout this subject of optimisation
20 problem that uses the same input ABC and and what looks a completely different
and yet there to work closely related it's it's this is 1 of the more
subtle aspects of
linear programming and all of optimization is this presence of dual variables
well actually
that theme of variables x is unwise
has been fundamental in this whole
right from the start of these lectures
we are are you member in our network flow problems we had potential and currents
W and there was a certain duality between those
and in fact we had M O N and potential than M currents
and nodes and m edges so actually graphs there would nodes and edges were going
to be the central limit theorem
2nd lecture
so all we want not totally is not only news to us that there that
there's some
reverse problem which turns out to be a maximization also linear problems of course and
now it'll be the be transposed Y
so the the that within the constraint now popping into the cost
if I call this cost
or whatever income maybe
and what the constraints on this uh well not to everybody's surprise A transpose is
going show
and this vector
C is going to throw up on the right hand side of the age
transpose what
equals state
OK have I got that rated where want greater than equal and that I want
greater than equal
yeah if you're right that that
yeah at about it is checked do I want less or equal or greater equal
I want last
it's not surprising that
we have a greater than or equal than we in the primal problem well let's
report shows up here but the main point is a transpose shows up again
so we really uh I could
stretch our little framework
quite ways a little our framework of 3 steps to include linear programming shall I
do that uh men
it was make some comments about this and do that yeah yeah
well at the moment user to
independent problem
that I mean I I could hide the dual problem never tell never tell you
about it and just discussed the primal how solve
and revealing that there's a 2nd problem
that which if I had 5 lectures on program naturally probably wouldn't reveals so rarely
that there is a 2nd problem hiding around with the same inputs and also another
linear programming this is evidence that the linear programming problem to linear programming is linear
cost linear
equality and inequality constraints however that I can play you can massage 1 problem to
have sit another 1 I could do I could do that I could have a
x lesser rate will be there and play with it and and introduce some slack
2 unknowns to make up the equality sign and they would have to be nonnegative
and input impediment to the axes and all I want to say is that
1st this fits the general form but others that don't look like they're quite fit
as long as they have linear
costs and linear
and inequality is no no conditional on y yeah it's it's it's interesting
In a that's why you girlfriend correct I have to think every time OK it
is a condition that they let me tell you about duality so duality
some really jumping dear to the heart of the
of of the underlying says that the maximum work in the dual problem equals the
minimum in the prime
that the answer to this problem that the maximum whatever is the man is equal
to the minimum cost
so that
in a way this is a big help because it tells us when to stop
if we have a suppose we have an algorithm that gradually finds a better and
better exits
this is what you're really doing reality
you get an approximate X and you say that the best I can do you
look around it as calculus always does you say it up I can go off
I can change that x 2 is doing to reduce the cost
and so you go that way and then you don't know when the stop well
there are several ways to know when to stop what they have when you get
to a point x star let's say
serving galaxies in trying to trace
the rotation curve
and his conclusion
he's in her own words in spiral galaxy the ratio of dark to light market
is about a factor of ten
this probably have good number for the ratio of our ignorance to knowledge
OK so the master iteration for galaxies of all the
OK let's keep on going
so we know that galaxies
don't leave isolated
there are a lot of galaxy clusters out there and we've seen some picture of
them so for a group of objects that interact gravitational e there must always be
a balance between gravity and velocity gravity and kinetic energy to little velocity and then
gravity takes over and then the clusters should collapse too much velocity and the objects
should escape and the clusters should not just not explode and everything fly away and
evaporate the fact that clusters of there they are not operating
must be telling you something that we tell you know there is a balance between
potential energy and kinetic energy
so by measuring the doppler shift of galaxies in clusters you can measure the the
cluster gravity
and from that you can get that last month
and so to do that you write down the video DRM you say that the
kinetic energy is equal minus one half potential energy and these are four here it's
due to the fact that you don't really know exactly what the radius of a
cluster because the radius of a cluster is not aspect the sphere we are you
with the straight edge so depending on how you define the edge then these are
for parameter will take value may be slightly different from unity but here we're talking
orders of magnitude so let's not worry about this speed there's just yet so let's
consider the common class you can measure the dispersion velocity along the line of sight
and you know that the dispersion velocity is actually that is not just the one
along the line of sight it's three times
that of the line of sight this half-light radius of the cluster is about one
point five million pounds six black the number in
and you end up with some us that is two
time ten to fifteen solar masses
remember solar masses two times ten to the thirty kilograms
that amongst
and much more stuff there to meet the
four clusters must light ratio is from hundreds to three hundred
there is a lot more there that china
and so i couldn't resist of put in the picture of swiss astronomy and squeaky
because we can not is that in nineteen thirty three the galaxies in cluster move
much too fast for the amount of money that we see
so the cluster must contain a lot of unseen matter that provide sex
and more recently we have some other indication that come from the extreme case the
exterior is simply due to the fact that there is a lot of gas in
galaxy clusters that gets completed
and that's another way to actually measure the kinetic energy of the stuff that is
contained in the clusters and if you repeat the calculation by looking at this is
simply the kinetic energy to get from the temperature they come from lakes strays again
you get the same mass to light ratio that depending from cluster to cluster is
of the order of hundreds of your
another indication
i explained all this the mast bend space-time
and now i need to make a distinction here
global geometry is different from local geometry OK
so he may well be
that the universe on average in the very large scale c well described by a
flat geometry but if you're going to see the nearer block all arise the geometry
that is not going to be flat
and so
if you sit very close to
concentration of mass the local geometry is not going to be flat
but this general relativity describe as gravity warps the spacetime around a massive object the
stronger the gravity the more space times what
and we know
that light follows a geodesic
and i geodesic in space that is not blocked
it's not straight
and so you can imagine that a lot of strange thing can happen if
you have the light rays if you're sitting here and you have light rays going
to that
what is
and so this is what happens so imagine you have an intervening galaxy or a
galaxy cluster you're are hero serving this is the distortion of the space time and
you have a distant galaxy here the light from the galaxy come follow different kind
of part and then when you look at it from their your brain or your
telescope says well you know about the light rays should go straight and so what
you see
you see for example two different
position of the same background objects this is an extreme case if the geometry is
not that great to get two different position what you end up seeing is simply
a distortions so the same galaxy veins stretched and distorted
this kind of effect is called gravitational lensing
and it's an extremely powerful tool
two men should not just the mass of the intervening objects a galaxy of plaster
but is a powerful tool to measure the intervening mass on cosmological scales
that is the stuff that is even between clusters of galaxies that galaxies clusters of
so this is an animation of what will happen if you have background galaxies and
in for foreground over density of matter
and this is an in the foreground of the density of matter moves
this is gravitational lensing play
and this is an actual image
mutation you at the very beginning and i told you know these things are not
artifacts of the hubble thinking about picture this and background images that have been distorted
and then they replicated by the sheer amount of money that is in this clusters
of four
OK so very briefly the mathematical gravitational lensing in case you are interested
so the deflection angle which is
the object should be there but it appears he is related to gravity
the amount of mass that is in the intervening lens
the impact parameter is your geometry
and the
i'm going to see from here and then is also related to the geometry that
is the distance from you to the source and the distance from you to the
length and the distance from the lens to the source
basically if you write down the equation you end up with something like this this
angle you can measure and in this angle you have the mass of the intervening
what he every time
one of the u we want to
so all all in all the training and supply serious focused all
although he rule
and were here on the wings
tell us why is
all right
one is that the
what more
so that
here's one
four eight
the probability that all
in addition of the test
that's why
i'm sure
so those who may wish to refer to
what your
it's not for us
lo or loh
or a lot of
he also solutions
what and so forth should try using that you
this is your
the eurovision song expect
changes in the last season you right
heard those things you
so the problem is he has of
o is one
the only one
you seem to be on
it is possible that the
stanford it is that you know
so the question is
so this
the first one to hear a lot more
so should
and we
as an SP
this is nineteen thirteen pound in london
styling himself
isn t
after this renaissance artists and poets whom he would write about translate in this period
it could be in miniature war by a province all
damsel no
a little later pound after the war
in nineteen twenty three
member of the full flower of modernism still young man but got that came and
he's in paris
we're we're
he would
meet elliot and work on the wasteland with them
fast forward twenty years
this is pounds
pound accused of treason
pound accused of treason of his by his country
accused of treason as he tries to bend
the world to his
the vision of it
and he escapes trial
only by
the reason of insanity when he is brought from
under charges of
having made broadcast on fascist radio back to the united states after an or deal
in a cage in pisa
poses for this photo
it has an intake photo as he enters saint elizabeth's hospital
for the insane in washington
in this final photo
photo from nineteen seventy one back in italy in pollen
well here's pounds in presenting us with an image of something that would have seemed
impossible when he began which is an image of modernism grown old old and last
many sensors
contrast this this career encapsulated in those images
this one
who is this this is the author of proof rock in fact this is the
harvard student who wrote proprietary elliot wrote proof rock largely when still at harvard and
in the years immediately following
a little maybe
the whole slightly parted lips
windswept hair the
technology a crew that
now notice the handkerchief
here is the editor of gay editor of the publisher faber and faber
thirty years later or more surrounded by books the cultural arbiter of the english speaking
he only sixty
that here is now slicked down
their glasses between him and us
this is the young man has become a monument but really the customers the same
one right
pounds descent into infamy and sanity and dignity
and it's rise to the extraordinary cultural power and prestige
that he occupied that is represented by this and many other photos well these are
key stories in modern poetry in their interestingly interlocking just as there are two lives
another modern poet
this is
this is an old woman called mary and more
who became
a kind of civic icon who became a celebrity even as an eccentric new yorkers
who walked right corner hats and went to baseball games in the zoo
excess risk and excess fire
so what i mean by that well we don't look at the risk of function
and related to the fire risk we look at how much the risk exceeds the
bayes risk
right so how much worse f is than the optimum
in terms of the risk and in terms of the fire escape
so for any probability distribution in any f this function psi
gives us an upper bound on the relationship between the access virus can the excess
right we saw in this case
so i was just an increasing in quadratic was actually
sia theta was the squared
right so
you know we can invert that we get the in
in that case on the previous slide the excess risk is no more than the
square root of the access virus
right for that example
and that's that's true in general for
for any any phi we can we can come up with this corresponding function psi
and it gives this relationship between the excess risk and excess
virus turns out that the optimal
found that you can't do any better than that given some value of the argument
the excess risk
you can always find the probability distribution function so that the the probability distribution
and that function the excess risk is equal to
right so this inequality
is this inequality
right and there's a matching inequality on the other side
as close as you like to matching on the other side
right so so you can have
any better inequality you can have an inequality that any better than any
any value this one
if you want to hold uniformly over distributions in a function
OK so this is the right the right relating excess risk and excess fires
this fall
and thirdly
when we ask the question when the minimisation of phi risk correspond to minimisation of
right so
that's equivalent to saying well when does this
when is this upper bound
non vacuous
right when when does driving the right-hand side is zero
you imply that
the excess risk
goes to zero
right well we can we can precisely characterize
that kind of implication
OK it depends just on this
weakest possible condition the obviously necessary condition that the function phi is classification calibrated
OK so if this function
satisfies this condition that h minus is strictly worse than h
that's equivalent to
the value of sin go to zero implies that the argument goes to zero
is equivalent to the argument goes to zero
right but the case for interested in nontrivial cases the full implication here
right and that of course and that is equivalent to if we can find the
following implication if we can find
a sequence of functions for which the fire risk approaches the optimum
then for that sequence
the risk approaches the optimum right so this inequality is not vacuous in the sense
that when we when we need to send the right-hand side is zero
then the argument on left-hand side also goes to zero
OK so
so this is a fairly complete answer this question when minimisation of virus scanner the
right thing to do
right it's it's precisely when the when the function is classification calibrated
and as i said this theorem is true for arbitrary bounded from below
with the with the slide
change the definition of a sign
everything here is is true turns out in the in the case of convex phi
it's so there's there's also an easy conditions to assess whether our cost function is
classification calibrated and we'll see that animal
OK so
one other observation if we have this
classification calibrated
condition applying
right that is
sending this thing to zero implies that thing
the argument of psychosis that tells us because this function size convex
it's always connected to constant minus the concave function
right then
that means that psi
is strictly increasing and so it has an inverse
right and so we can rewrite that expression in terms of you know whatever the
functional in this is that the excess risk is no more than some function
the axis
prior risk
i which is some some strictly increasing bandwidth which is more natural form ideas right
this is the thing that our algorithms are working to to make small and this
is the thing that we'd like to
to to have small
OK this is the
the condition i mentioned
i alluded to earlier so in the case of the convex
the classification calibration condition is particularly easy to cheque
right turns at all that you that you care about
is what happens is zero
the function just needs to be differentiable zero
and having negative gradient
and that's equivalent to the classification calibration condition for convex functions
you know all those functions that we saw earlier
right satisfy that that condition
OK and zero all differentiable and decreasing
i have a negative gradient zero so the negative gradient is a very natural thing
right i mean it might seem strange to have things going up to the right
of zero but that's fine from the point of view of optimizing the
the fire risk leading to a leading to an optimal value of the risk
the differentiability
might seem a little strange at first but it's not too hard to see why
that's essential
OK if you think about the the case of the cost function that is not
differentiable at zero a convex cost function is not differentiable at zero
right then this some sort of point zero
OK so if you take a mixture
of the cost function with the point is zero
right and the cost function flipped
then you're going to and take fifty fifty mixture then the minimum is going to
occur zero but is going to have a point
and so
if you if you take something a little bit bigger than fifty percent
it should be classifying that's a plus one but it's still going to have a
point zero
right a little bit less than fifty percent should be classifiers minus one is still
going to have its minimum zero because not able to to correctly classify those cases
that have conditional probability nearer half
if you don't have different abilities zero
it turns out you know you can you can kind of exploit this in
in other situations so for instance if you're interested in
in coming up with
i minus p one c
i get this area
and instead of evaluating every time evaluating all those pixels all i need to do
is about compute the integral images of free look values and that's it
so instead of me having the sum is twenty four twenty four and every time
five pre compute the integral image
on the image beforehand but three lookup values
that's it that's all have to do
and there's some
thank you something attention
so essentially this is a list of experience
and so
so a three box filter takes only lookups
they evaluated
and and get very similar performance
two rally rally not work
in fact many instances they get better
the big thing to is that
with the linear classifier it actually would take five hundred seventy six lookups whereas as
we this despite that on the previous slide took eight lookups to do the same
so these examples of the defections and so i guess the big thing here i
just kind of wanted emphasise again is that special detection in vision
it's not just coming up with in the real temptation i think computer science to
sustain theory to say what i can make this work better to make this work
i mean in terms of better saying like in terms of my object detector detection
accuracy is really important i think especially in vision algorithms to think about the computational
complexity at the same time because really want success successful people to in the way
that measure success all over time isn't so much in the paper it's how ubiquitously
method is applied
this technique is kind of the the combination of what kind of well known machine
learning ideas but so applied extremely well
it's essentially changed a lot of what people doing because people don't know anything about
machine learning taking these tools now and applying the price and it's really changed the
landscape of the computer vision work
so this is kind of what i think apologize especially really good lesson four had
kind of two
good machine learning research that has a lot of practical value
and another thing that it too is i spoke open cv recently they basically
what wasn't them so another one one hundred he basically counted up
detector that was very similar to this input open sea essentially because it so ubiquitously
easy to use and it was applied to well known computer vision framework
everyone's using everyone can is has been around for years now and people still using
things and so there speedups
mister kind are
a colleague of mine in this tournament he came up with the way he can
again heuser all school of graphical models in machine learning things and so got the
idea of again taking this interval image idea
and basically box filters instead of calling boosting he can applied mutual information for techniques
step essentially getting histogram at each value
and trying to so she would not a naive bayes classifier c kind word this
who were which
box values were heavily correlated with each other in terms of mutual information and then
will and which ones were
and essentially if you can assume conditional independence between the more can essentially does we're
not these quite easy to learn histograms of the positive and negative classes and actually
got a lot better performance and is a couple reasons why
henry still have page and why that actually the case i think that's a boosting
essentially especially business that classifier to skip you single threshold whereas like kind of using
histogram can actually maybe about a much nicer or more advanced kind of decision boundary
and i think that all it's a lot more elegant to the mutual information strategy
they use but it's not paper and i encourage people to check it out as
in CVPR two thousand four
and is using mutual information and so and he actually launched a spin-off company called
that which is very enough based on pittsburgh both pattern recognition and so much
and so you so in his cuts packages are available online things and that's actually
a lot better than they are to be face detector but it's not really about
you have to pay some money for
so the can my whole thing on exhaustive local search
but as you can kind of see is that we kind of pushing because it
essentially is
and if you have a problem in terms of what we kind of what kind
of exhaustive research in these areas even though discreetly as the dimensionality my will expand
on i'm always going to be in trouble so made three or four
dimensional what a moron this is like i say
to face mesh here that's twenty twenty five dimensions and there's no way that i
can i can actually actually
so what happens if we want finer one
so there is an an alternative to be exhaustively search
and that's where i think how we go
another five minutes
twenty minutes i can source that on on the other the other stuff
so perhaps relationship and just to give you guys an trying to work
what do i do that
this guy going to give you guys an trying to
one of the talk about that essentially
we all know machine learning we can use regression to court to could use
is that is that perhaps some sort of learning i to play between what displacement
and appearances by its essentially if i have two images so i've got a source
image in my template image and the displaced in terms of image intensities
can i perhaps feed into some sort of regression
regressor or some sort of other kind of a linear relationship with the actual warp
displacement so it's kind of like is their relationship between
the motion field in the optical field between between between two patterns and it turns
out actually for natural images there is it so
that's what we're going to talk about next
to bring up
the next thing
this is the topic there are really like i really like because i think it's
really neat and elegant how well this works so CV
exhaustive search detectors worked really really well but still pretty much a pattern computational aspects
the pretty much this kind of high school in the kind of like OK we're
going to take a lot of good writing the gradient descent work that in the
talk about now
it's really
nice in the sense that the really talk about the pixel coherence
economists that they really do take that on board and they will happen we use
there should be a better way for us to kind the searching in this sort
of course looking everywhere
we skip ahead
as you said if you're in my person for machine learning exhaustive search is essentially
i discreetly search of the image and i
basically get these vectorize values of the of the object
and if been into classifier and say
you are not necessarily it's fundamentally con computationally expensive i can do lots of things
the kind of limit but it's fundamentally
so from that perspective
and another kind of problem with that is that this is the face detector run
across portion of the multiply face database
what i did was that i got i had the ground truth with the eyes
another distribution
which is not from the list
and then what to do
because the way of computing the mean of a gaussian which is the sum of
all the data
it's actually very sensitive to
one of us
and there are books written robust statistic
how to make another that is not
it's almost optimal when the data come from the core from the distribution but it
doesn't agree but doesn't agree badly when the data are corrupted
and one of the simplest ways of doing it is by the what's called the
trend in the three very
and that's the following basically your
so the the data in any dimension and then remove the highest
two percent and the lowest two percent the highest one percent the lowest one person
and of course that happen to come from the galaxy and then you are disturbing
the results
but you can show that in on average to there are introducing a small
and the potential of removing actually those outlets don't come from the data is is
is that the benefits greater when actually you have to rule it
and that's what remained because just to train the top and the bottom of of
the court
and similar model for the variance and so on
very intuitive
and that can be done at every step of reestimation nine years the year already
or in the game
however i mean is to me
there is another committee
which is that in fact is the to change the cost function
basically the but cost is more sensitive to outliers than the same cost without the
and so if i want to
and that is called the k medians algorithms because this is
because the minimizer of that cost is the median of the
let me make it to draw traditional
so if the data on this line
here is the
this is i mean
the median minimizes the cost
x minus mu
some of the text
and i believe this square and they want to minimize some or x of
i don't know
just x minus
the minimizer of this course is the media
which would be
one two three
move actually problem
OK and that's what i algorithm is called the k median
now the media the nice property with respect to outliers
the second thing is going to move it far away out of the room
the median will not change at all
the median is sensitive to the media that the
it's not make a change in the middle of the data the median change all
so much more robust to outliers
and therefore is this cost will automatically be robust
what i can say about this cost is that we don't know the minimum so
it can be hard as well
and in some way
licenses but there are some computer science algorithms that can give some very complicated but
i didn't include them in the the handouts actually give some guarantees these as for
example the i think a factor of four approximation
this means again
there are four approximation means that
the algorithm guarantees to get
at most four times the true cost
so will close to the true cost is small then that's not too bad
or is it really then it's not too bad if they are clustered but
not very compactly then it's also
another that are applied the two single linkage or
other algorithms that are really sensitive to outliers
i have to eliminate small clusters
yes so if have a cluster with two or three point
that's close to that
or one point which can come out in
in single linkage just eliminated enemy that point and counter clusters without that
before he quit the subject of let's let's think of the following
they they should be there and what outlier is some instances the philosophical problem or
it's a problem that
this fellow cannot solve you have to think what you really want
and one of the problems that the race is that if you have a bias
why don't we make a start
so last week
so unless we yesterday i didn't quite finish with our discussion
of the expectation value so this is still from the first set of lecture notes
but what we had gone through with this idea
but you have a probability density function that it's convenient to be able to summarize
it with some
numerical values that characterize its position in width and so forth and so that's why
we define this expectation value
expectation values can be used not only for probability density functions that are of function
of a single random variable but it can also be that the events that you're
observing are characterized by same more than one random variable so you have some joint
probability density function and in that case
it's useful to give a measure of the expectation value of
products of pairs of the random variables so suppose that we're observing i don't know
we're observing people
and each person is characterized by a certain height in a certain way
so you can measure those two quantities for each person
and you would like to know something about the expectation value of the product of
those two quantities now typically what you do is you take the expectation value of
the product and it is convenient to subtract off from that the product of the
two individual expectation values so here i have used the notation new setbacks to simply
the expectation value of x alone
and mu so y to mean the expectation station value of y alone
OK so
that combination expectation value of x y
minus the product of the two corresponding expectation values that's what we call the covariance
of two random variables x and y so usually written with some sort of notation
like that
if you if you multiply this out you can see the x the expression on
the right is is equivalent so it's the expectation value of the product of x
minus mu x times y minus mu y
OK so so that gives you information on how large on average the
the product of x and y are now if x and y have some sort
of units like axes in centimetres and y is in horsepower then
the covariance you can see i will have
the product of those two dimensions
but it is often
useful to provide a measure of the covariance which is dimensionless
so what we do is we take the covariance and divided by the product of
the two
corresponding standard deviations so remember that if a variable x has some units than the
standard deviation of x has the same units
so therefore this
combination here is is dimensionless and it is what's called the correlation coefficient
it is dimensionless and furthermore you can show that its value lies necessarily between minus
one n one
before i i'm going to show graph just on the next overhead to show how
to interpret that intuitively but let me just make first the following comment and that
is that if the two random variables
in question are independent
so recall from yesterday what we define that to mean
if two random variables are independent it means that the joint probability density for those
two variables factorizes into a function of one times the function of the other
and those two functions are in fact the marginal pdf for the corresponding variables
OK well if that's true then we can work out
the expectation value of the product is
OK what is that by definition that's just the integral over both of my variables
x times y
times the joint pdf for x and y
if this condition holds
that means that the variable will factorize into a very into an integral over x
times an integral over y
and what you get if you just stare at this for five seconds you realize
that that will simply be equal to the expectation value of x
times the expectation value of y
so if the two variables are independent the covariance
necessarily vanishes
so that's that's important fact to remember
the converse is not necessarily true you can have situations where you have variables that
it is absolutely critical
first of all because our customers
really want to have i think solutions which work
well on future data you know in all of the industrial projects i pursued so
far the the robustness of of the methods was a key ingredient the engineers asked
and that actually cuts down their their their their development time so if you have
a better understanding what it means i have a robust solution for image interpretation task
then i think we learn a lot about the generalisation in hindi context there are
a couple of approaches for clustering in particular and i will focus on the last
one because it comes
from my group its stability analysis of solutions
and who does someone have stable solutions
so they don't types you will find
clustering approaches for quite different data types of rectal data are probably used in more
than ninety percent of the applications if you are sure that you know in which
space you have to represent your objects then just below the vector space for these
objects and then start doing you grouping there another approach very successful and pursued by
tally tishby and his group in israel and also by my group is to use
the histogram data to find a good groups and
a third approach which i want to go into is the proximity the data approach
where you no longer represent individual objects either by vectors by histograms but you characterize
objects by their pairwise relations proximity data dissimilarity doesn't really matter if you keep track
of the sign obviously the the the
the last representation
the the proximity data representation here is is the harder problem because the structure now
is hidden in pairwise relations between the object to have a square matrix which might
actually have missing values and so on
there's a lot of
so all of
classification of the different clustering principles in the literature
i would like on the meta level sort of two
two point q two two some criteria which you could actually use to see if
sort of several methods basically do the same thing despite the fact that they are
written up in completely different ways so
compactness is one of the criteria which allows you to find groups of objects and
depending on how you represent your object in which underlying space to represent them you
might actually use a method called k means come to that about probably most of
you know that already if you represent your objects by histograms then you could use
a method called histogram clustering any does roughly the same as k means except in
a different space is the space of probability distributions see and here is the space
of vector
pairwise data clustering for for relational data for proximity data that she also a compact
this type of of grouping of your objects average association is a different name for
pairwise data clustering for cold and and people in my group has looked at a
connection between pairwise data clustering and k means and it's called the constant shift embedding
paradigm which really makes explicit how you go from relational data to vectorial data and
we'll be hearing people be drifting and thank you all for interrupting your skiing to
come so i just a quick show of hands how many people have heard either
jacob are myself talk about neighbourhood components analysis before
OK so maybe about half so i'll try and goal of the quickly through that
and then get to some of the newer work with with so feel free to
to interrupt me at any time
and ask questions or
make insulting comments or whatever starting argument
OK so as you all know the the sort of thing for today's distance metric
learning and the idea is that there's a lot of times in the course of
an algorithm when we need some kind of distance measure often we need to have
the properties of the metric but maybe not always which compares examples of scalar function
which eats two examples and tells you how different are similar they are
and unless the structure strongly specifies this metric or maybe some constraints on that metric
then it seems like the preferred approach is to learn the metric as part of
your problem
so in other words you have a lot of data often the data has labels
which implicitly tell you what the right metric is anyone who performed the learning along
with the rest of the parameters based on the training set so today i'm going
to focus on something very very simple semiparametric classifiers like k nearest neighbour augustine kernel
support vector machines and gaussian processes you know very local machines
and the idea is given labelset
so we have the training set of inputs so use extra inputs and labels your
why sometimes all use how should we learn a metric that will give good generalisation
when used in such a classifier OK so what's the idea of these classifiers they
just look locally in the neighborhood of the test example at nearby training examples and
they sort of average labels are there's
regression outputs or whatever and the idea is to make this measurement of what is
local mean good for whatever you're trying to do classification or prediction intuitively should think
that our goal is to make directions of the space which are relevant for classification
we want to shrink them
and directions of the space which are very informative we want to structure that lets
the that's the job of the metric
there's this sort of at this point in my talk usually
someone put up their hand and says
but you have a line of research is totally stupid because local if classifiers are
they need an exponential amount of training data to just memorize the space and they
don't generalize in any meaningful way
OK so that's actually a somewhat valid criticism but it's not a criticism i'm going
to get into a battle about today
i'm going to defer the criticism to this you know all paper by rob hold
which i think is still somewhat true today
which is that there a lot of situations in which very simple classifiers tend to
do surprisingly well
OK so you should think of this is the conditional talk if you're interested in
some kind of the local method like nearest neighbour gaussian kernel support vector machine or
whatever then i have something interesting to tell you about learning the distance if you're
not interested
there's a wireless connection in this room
and i'll be done in forty five minutes so OK
so just you know to remind you of the set for instance based on memory
based or non parametric classifiers the idea is that you just have the training set
and you take say the k nearest neighbors of the training set you take the
majority vote in that class labels so people to make fun of k nearest neighbour
but it's pretty interesting the decision surfaces are nonlinear
it's semi parametric and nonparametric so it has high capacity without having really to train
a lot of parameters
so what is this point i think this a very
the important point that underappreciated if you want your a classifier to do something complicated
it so in some sense it has to have a lot of bits inside its
it has to have some work has the reasonable capacity but we're not very good
at setting huge numbers of parameters
what we can do we're going to say well will make the training set itself
in some sense all those bits because we're pretty sure we didn't screw up those
bits and then we're only going to say you know one number k or one
bandwith parameter alpha
OK and the quality of the predictions of automatically improves with more data these results
about it being asymptotically close to optimal which you may or may not be interested
in because of the word asymptotic but some people think that this word is just
the gateway to lots of very interesting theoretical results and some people think that this
word means you should ignore everything that comes after
OK there's only a few parameters to tune usually you can do it by cross
validation or some kind of simple optimisation you know gradient on leave one out of
OK so what's the problem
the problem is what is nearest mean you need to specify some kind of distance
metric on the input
so that's one problem with these classifiers in the second problem is computational cost you
have to sort of story all training set and carried around in your suitcase with
you every time you want to do classification so
we'd like to sort of try and solve both of these problems
so today i'm going to talk mostly about the first problem how do you want
to distance metric
and also to show you how if you need to you can make this distance
metric low rank
we have to square pads coming to it
and we have two to the thirtieth pattern going away from it
so that's two to the thirty two paths going through it
so let's look at this past year we have to do the two patterns
i want show all of them
going from start to it
and to to the
thirty pounds going from it to the end
so let's label these patterns with names just to see what's going on this is
x y z and p q are
so we're interested in
well so one path that goes through the state is x times p
we can come in by actually by p
and another path is xq
another path is x are
another pattern is why p
why q
why are
zq q
xe are and for those of you who can see behind here it's exactly what
you'd expect
OK so can we factor this
this factoring trick is the whole idea here
so we've got nine had the well two square times to the thirtieth panzer
this is just going to be x plus y fuzzy
times p plus q plus are
there's always getting into another ways of getting out
well this is the this is the sum of two squares things up on the
shore three of them
and this is some two to thirtieth things but we computed right self
total number of ways of getting to the airport
to the thirtieth number ways of getting into her sorry total probability of paths getting
away from that airport if we multiply these we have the total probability will pass
through the airport so it's just tell the time spent school
so let's see how that comes out of the spreadsheet
so here we have the alpha color
the columns for the going through the cold state going through the heart state better
column similarly
and here's alpha times better so this is the total probability of all paths going
through the cold state day one two three four total probability of all paths going
through the hot state it is one two three four now if you look at
the alphas
these decrease tend to decrease as you go down the color right
if you look at the baiters these ten two
interesting well working backwards so it's not too surprising
they tend to decrease as you go up the
because the padgett as you go up the column the paths from day thirteen and
twelve eleven to the end get longer and longer
the story explaining more and more ice cream when we multiply alpha by that works
explaining all the groups
so now
this is
say all the paths
they go through
the cold stayed on day five to the thirty second pass
here's another two to the thirty second pass go through the heart stayed on day
five let's add those together one of the total probability all
two the thirty third perhaps
what's going on in this column
total probability vol two to thirty third has always the same right it's just a
question how we divide it up
so here
we can look at two to thirty third go through this state versus that state
or they go through the state versus that
different divisions of the past
so here
you know we've taken say pads a and b and c and d here it's
going to be a and c and b and
OK but are we divide it up into two
into two groups the total probability of all the paths will be the same
what do you think it means
that this number
is about one hundred times more likely than that number
a hundred times bigger than the numbers are all unlikely right actually what is this
sort of ten r nine times ten to the minus nineteen twenties this number would
the likelihood of that is retiring
the likelihood of that sequence of choices
what do you think it means
but that's about one hundred times more
then that
so i hard what it means is that there is a lot more probability on
has to go through the hot stayed on day three than on the cold and
three so all of all the to the thirty third ways to explain how a
those ice-creams the happen which is a hot day and a three
have much more total probability than half of which is cold and three
and that is how we got the graph
if you look at this is the probability that we're going to called state in
other words it was called a and that is
the ratio of this to the total
and over here
we have the ratio of that to the total
so these are these two numbers sum to one
because we're just asking about
of the
the total of these two numbers
here's the total what fraction of those to the called state what fraction goes to
the heart of it so it's about one percent versus ninety nine percent
and if we look at this picture we see that's what we get here
the three it's ninety nine percent
OK so this that's exactly where the graph came from
all right
so let me just ask a little question here it is we know now why
this state here
was tagged as
was was tagged as a hot day
despite having
and apparently uncertain two ice-creams it was because the data probability right
because the better probability allows it to look for if we decide to make this
high is more pleasant to explore so you know it's it's not more pleasant to
explain this to extremes here but it's more pleasant to predict the weather that would
explain the subsequent
however over here we've got tired eleven damon is the one i screamed and yet
we predicted that it would be high
so what are we predict that
why should one i screamed behind
i think it's probably right by the way
you not just so there are three extra days after there's three into icelandic before
i mean we have a lot of evidence that there's hard this before and after
so we we if we already believe based on information from the left this is
probably day and we already believe based on information from the right this is probably
a hot day what what what does it do for us if we predict the
cold here well mixed seven times more likely to seven times more likely to predict
the data that we actually observe so we're doing a better job if we made
the so-called they would be doing a better job
by a factor of seven
predicting a single ice
so what's the cost for it's terrible cost because
in order to given that this is probably hard and that's probably how what we
have to do we go from hot to cold back to hot
well because of factor eight
if we can
ha ha ha
this displaced water is about here
now we have the we enforce up
and now you see what's going to happen
i told to site
it will rotate even further this talk will drive it away
from the vertical
and that's very important therefore we ships
that you always build the ships such that the centre of mass of the ship
is as low as you can get it to give you the most stable
if you bring the centre of mass of ships very high
in the seventeenth century that is very massive cannons which were very high on the
the ship can capsize and has happened many times
the centre of mass which is too high
the centre of mass is somewhere here
very heavy this part
so now
if i is lower than the water notice it goes into the water to the
same depth
because the we enforce
of course the same so the amount of displaced
what is the same
in both cases
but now the centre of mass is high
and this is very unstable when i let go
centre of mass of the object was higher
the centre of mass
of the displaced fluid
so we ship you have to
a very careful about that
let's talk a little bit about balloons
available only
the situation is not too dissimilar
from having an object
in a liquid
but the balloon never mass
that is the mass of the gas in the balloon
all the rest
and what i mean by all the rest that is the material of the balloon
industry everything else that makes up the mess
it has a certain volume v
and so on a certain role of the gas inside
and there's role of air outside
and i want to evaluate what the criterion is for balloon to rise
well for it to rise to reinforce have to be larger energy
what is the buoyant force
that's the weight
of the displaced fluid the fluid in this case is air
so the weight of the displaced fluid is the volume
times the density of the air
that's the fluid in which it is now
times g
that's the way we enforce that's the weight of the displaced fluid
has to be larger
and ng
ng is the mass of the gas
which is the volume of the gas
the density of the gas
that's the mass
times g
you have to convert it to force
plus all the rest
i lose my g
and what you see
this of course
o is larger than zero
there's always some mass associated with the skin
and in this case was the string
but you see the only way that this
well and can rise
is that the
the density of the gas must be smaller than the density of air
density of the gas must be less than the density of the air
this is a necessary condition
for this to hold it is not a sufficient condition
because i can take a balloon
what little bit of in there
so the density of the gas is lower than the density of air but it
may not arise
and that's because of this term
but it is a necessary condition
but not
a sufficient condition
now i'm going to
make you see the demonstration which is extremely nonintuitive
and i will try step by step
to explain to you
why you see what you're see
we're going to see
very nonintuitive
try to follow closely
what i see what you will see
i feel pendulum
an apple
you blue
so this
i got this story and i cut the string gravity in this direction
we have over four
will rise
because in the opposite direction
the gravitational acceleration
if there were no gravity
this one would not arise
and you yet will not fall
i agree so far
without gravity
it would not fall
problem would not arise
now we go in outer space
in compartment
here's an apple
none of us great
no gravity
and here is a meeting field
of blue and there's an air inside
not spaces no gravity
has any weight
well floating
i'm going to accelerate
i rocket
two accelerated in this direction with acceleration a
we all perceive now
perceive gravity in this direction
i call it g
so apple will fall
i'm standing there i see example for i'm in this compartment close for ICT up
to go down a little later you will be here
i myself or little later and there
but i can put it bathroom scale even way myself on the bathroom scales
my way below and times his a and being my mass a being acceleration i
really think that is gravity in this direction
the air once to form
but the below
wants to go against gravity
will rise
and once to fall
so inside here
you create the differential pressure between the bottom
and the top of the air
two inside here
just like the atmosphere on earth
the atmosphere is pushing down on us
preciously higher than their
so we get p one
it's higher than p two
so you create yourself an atmosphere
and the building rise balloon goes in the opposite direction
if there were no air in there
then clearly all of us will fall four i would fall
and balloon form
the only reason why helium balloon rises
is because the air
because you build the differential pressure
now comes my question to you
instead of accelerating upwards
he had the absolute value of logo
it has to
so the value is the maximum of logan minus law
and then i can
have the maximum log minus the log
so i can move the log outside the maximum value
fact that the value
you can also
in addition to give this the right could he moved located outside
but the problem like this to minimize the maximum
of a cave that both he and one over it would be
objective about it
so i did actually compared to the previous problem is
move the log outside
thinking and that this
so it is now it's clear it's convex because we've seen that a maximum of
convex functions is convex
so the next few and one over you is convex for positive values of
so each of these functions h is a convex function in x two
convex function of it will be and then at the back
the convex
so this is actually the only important part here
this is a convex function
and then if you get that cpxm up to the code of practice what you
want to minimize the action so
matlab commands that the separate your code for modelling tool from
the rest of the mop up
and within the scope of the text again and again because the variable x
of land in europe asia terrible
he stated that get the function you want to minimize the risk minimized the maximum
and we write it in a lot of information age times sex
that's a factor but the value is a key for the
as a component
and this is the function in policies one over a x componentwise we at fact
and then you minimize the max of this
that's the same
the this objective
and they also and the three to expose the fact that one
and then you enter civics and and then called actually said of the problem of
it for you and the next
one thing you might wonder about why today define a function in both an open
up the page one over it or one of
mean not
the be doing here is defined componentwise com componentwise inverse effect
the reason why the standard model patient doesn't work one of x
is that wiki that section of the convex function of x
one over x is convex for positive x but not before i relax
one of over is the convex function your you and this
programme but you right one book slash x
cvx will complain about the conduct problem
because it's not intelligent enough to know that a x
it is always positive because the coefficients of a happen to be
positive and x is positive
eight positive actually equivalent to only considering the positive convex half of one of the
just say it that can establish convexity from
the the context of
this function is actually a different one and one of x one over x one
positive x
and it's not defined for negative
that's a convex function and then the problem
so this just to illustrate these modelling tools
the question
so there's two things still recognise this
you excessive variables
that that's a convex function of x
and then the second thing is it was set up in some standard for
and solve for
and so you don't have to know what sort
and the second one is to continue
this on part of different types of convex optimization problems
same thing for the sake back and forth between the two venues
it means a might cause as a means they could have a hidden common cause
the two headed arrow means as causes cell
i would fact learning that smoking causes lung cancer
and you can see what i was talking about at the beginning of the talk
to that there is value in having other variables because once
i'm able to directly search is this way
i can direct this one this way and i can that one smoking causes lung
cancer something i can never learned from data and these two variables alone
here is
a real study that actually affect the senator from from carnegie mellon
CMU but university pittsburgh which
it's not so interested in the this study done by some followers at CMU and
actually affected the way CMU
evaluate students afterwards
every university is worried about student retention rate
soon retention means of all the students who who
university what percentage graduate
and universities one
that to be high so they want to make changes to make student retention rate
is high as possible
drugs to we more
the study
and originally had more variables than others
based on data
thousands of university of trees
to see what
variables affected with
one we care about this one
this is that this is the variable which are about
they looked at
the fraction of the applicants were not offered admission
this that and then look at the average standardized test scores you're SAT's scores
if you look at the fraction of incoming students the top ten percent of the
high school class
fraction of students who accept the offer
the educational general expenses per student the student faculty ratio is all things you think
might be take a small student faculty ratio might help
certainly the professors were hoping this would be the important variable rates so they can
live for a
one when they find
this is a causal DAG they learned court that actually might cause causal graphs they
using my notation were
two hundred zero means cause an error like this means the hidden common cause
it was on one hand there are none here
there's no one hundred one idea would mean what i told the problem is
that's right
well i don't see it
that that's an rather than just due japan
and so what is alpha here
alpha is when you're on the right side we assume you know the conditional independencies
alpha is used to
determine the conditional independencies in determine whether to reject the conditional dependency
this is the significance level at which you rejected
so help is point
it means you reject conditional independency very readily all you need is to have an
and result
the point two range to reject alpha point zero one
if the conditional independences present very rare event
it's happened so you don't reject it
so for the smaller alpha in the more sparse graph is because
you're you're not rejecting conditional independencies is easily rejecting them very easily so there's lot
of edges here
with a lot you to reject them so there aren't as many edges to make
called what you learn is more reliable right because
i noticed when i was trying to learning what variables affect the size another break
with variables affected the
stock markets
they are i can learn a lot was making up really small is hard time
learning anything
anyway so at all levels of alpha
the only
variable that they found it had in the fact that graduation rate was test score
these are hidden common causes
you know it's
it's always the test score
in other words what this study indicate is that good in good out
you bring in students with high SAT's cause more gradually you bring students of lower
city schools they will gradually
it's about university wants here right they want to hear that you know they can
university better by
i think there will be more and the this seems to be about the study
indicates after that kind of don't change their this financial aid policy and they get
more financially based on
city square rather than need and in fact the graduation rate went up
after that
so i guess say can't be sure of causal influences but they
this is a reasonable results so it helps
people kind of mound believe that this
well in fact really important variable in this is the one they changed
now here's the study i talked about earlier with myself and more we're trying to
what variables said and the fact that
and racial racial harassment and we originally had more than five variables just like there
are more than eight but we know these
i mean say dominated by we know these five to be the important one
respondents races based on survey data of
about six thousand individuals in the military
respondents years of military service
whether respondent
he or she experienced a racial incident
whether the incident was reported to military
and whether the respondent held the military responsible for the incident
no i don't know i never heard
why should a
based on that indicate hidden common cause these two don't indicate anything at all
i showed this to the dean my own institution that you don't want to hear
that lawmakers should justify so why do we have teams in colleges i mean i
always felt that we can save money by not having justify their existence by looking
for solutions to these problems other than other than this one
here is
what we want
all right
we learn that the only variable that has a causal effect on race
this is only doubled
that's there was
whether respondent held the military responsible one was we learn this at all levels of
significance just like the green one
as i said before and it doesn't make sense to hold the military responsible can
change your right
now why did we learn the first try and has tried to how this could
happen and i just
i came up with the possible scenario for why it happened
the causal influence of
responsible on race would not be learned if there was a direct causal influence of
race and incident
which is why we were looking for right that's what you suspect in the domain
i was
find little that they
there are
or is
here all
it may in more
well you
rather than
as we well
we call this
well is is
and we
all the
you have express who
it is
and if you don't have
one hundred
i think we have
what you
all right
i mean it
all the
he is that you know
all right
one theory
when very well
but how of the whole
he will be
one of the
you want your
i more
you need to
distribution of building material
the over time
you end up with this kind of waif-like distribution which is supposed to correspond to
OK equally spaced pillars
and that's just through a one that's measuring the one dimensional space and the diffusion
of pheromone
termites and building material and another pheromone and how those the coupling of those partial
differential equations leads to this kind of equity-based colour building
here's a model in two dimensions the queen is sitting in the middle and she's
giving off a pheromone at some concentration that pheromone the termites like to build so
they're building a kind of roughly circular
wall around the queen
earlier this situation where that is happening on top of it you've got a stream
of termites crossing the world
in this direction and a stream of termites crossing the world in this dimension
and they're leaving they're laying down a trail pheromone which inhibits building activity
so now what this is supposed to indicate is too
two tunnels meeting at an intersection
because they're not explicitly modelling the third dimension they can't actually model the
the become cavity
we've got these models were were unsatisfactory in several respects
the the the fact that they didn't model the third dimension was was one of
the the main thing is the basic model model the physicality of the building material
so it's in this situation here although they've built a ring of building material termites
and pheromones are free to diffuse through it
OK it doesn't obstruct anything surely the the complication of the situation faced by the
termites as they
carry out the building activity
that's going to influence the flow of pheromone which is suppose to be guiding them
that's going to influence subsequent building activity which is gonna feed back on the flow
of pheromone that's where the
problem is right
it's relatively easy to show that a diffusing pheromone is going to result in a
circular structure if the if the building of the structure doesn't impede the pheromone
so in order to look at that and that's so that's what i mean by
logistics OK
what i mean is there are things that get in the way of this coming
from here to here
these individuals are over here and so they didn't get this message
etcetera etcetera local
so our model looked like this the simple three d lattice
just about rectangle rectangular lattice
a finite number of termites each modelled individually
pheromone diffusion
and termite movement were physically constrained modelled pheromone diffusion just using a standard sort of
fluid mechanics type model
and we also imposed a kind of crude physics that in which was supposed to
report prevent impossible structures so
termites were not allowed to build unsupported horizontal
structures for example
those who assumed this fall fall down
but we do that in any particularly sophisticated way so here in the middle of
the world is the queen
she gives off a pheromone which diffuses away from
and around that at some level of pheromone concentration but the termites
but they're compelled to build the probability building is increased at this particular intensity of
pheromone and you can see that the which started to build towers
pillars sort of characteristic distance from the queen and the shape
but i don't know
line these pillars it reflects the for the shape of the queen
so the reason that they build pillars is that when they deposit a piece of
building material they basically have chewed it up
and most and they spit out
and stick it to the floor
and the but they use gives off a pheromone
a building sort of building material pheromone which attracts termites
towards it
so as they start building they recruit termites to that building sites
and because the
that was a good reason to put a building block there in the first place
there's also a good reason to build on it and you find the termites compelled
to add two
existing building activity
and in fact the the
when you run this with larger grid sizes the relatively equal spacing of the pillars
you can see that you can sort of understand the pillars is competing for termites
but the bigger pillars give off more
building pheromone recruit more termites and the positive feedback there so any pillar that starts
sort of a small pillar which is it's impossible or
that inhibits other new pillars from starting close to existing pillars sort
so over time you see that the low wall form
and indeed eventually becomes the think enclosed concave dome
which had been demonstrated in the
in the math model
and the fact that had this is happening in the pheromone diffusion is being influenced
by the building activity doesn't prevent this from occurring
in the math model they also simulate situation where wind blows across the plain so
we did that too
let's assume
the posterior
is a multivariate gaussian so it takes at a specific functional for
you know its approximate
but it's the form that week it's an analytic form is one that we
you know we know how to handle it
and this is called the
the laplace approximation of the saddle point approximation
basically what we do
israel assume the
posterior this knowledge to posterior
actually takes an analytic form which is a multivariate gaussian
and a multivariate gaussian with the mean value
it is located at the maximum of the actual posterior
and the covariance matrix
there's not going to be proportional
to the curvature of the posterior
at the maximum point
so in other words
but will do
it is we find
the set of parameters w
that maximises the posterior
and we use
a covariance matrix as i said which is proportional to the curvature
of the posterior
or the curvature of the joint likelihood
now this should be familiar to you
from yesterday
so that's basically all that we have to do we need to do some sort
of search
one of the
this smart value
and once we have that we need to find an analytic four
for this covariance matrix here
and then we're done well we're not really done because we still have to make
predictions and we'll see this still doesn't solve the problem
but basically what we're doing is we're seeing our posterior
so we have this non gaussian likelihood goes in
and this no ngos in marginal likelihood which is non analytic it's all going to
be approximated by goes in
center the wmap
with the covariance c which we've previously defined
so how do we estimate the maximum of the
and also compute the curvature
of the posterior at that point
we need to find the maximum of the posterior
so to find the maximum of the posterior although we need to do is find
the maximum of the joint likelihood y
because the marginal distribution is independent of the parameters that we're interested in
so again if we take
joint distribution and take the log of that then we end up with this this
thing here OK
so here's the component from the likelihood he's the component from the
the prior
again those of you familiar with regularisation methods you see this is a loss function
and this is the the regularisation term
so we do simple optimisation because i'm running out of time
for those of you who are really into the the the the details
the to the first derivative of of the likelihood committed in this form here
so these are target values p is a vector of the probability
of the class label taking on the value one given of attributes
and this is just the matrix of the basis
and this is the residual from the
the prior
now of course we also need
the curvature so we also need the second the matrix of second derivatives
to define the covariance
if we just do some multivariate action because i'm running out of time
for those of you who are really into the the the details
the to the first derivative of the likelihood can be written in this form here
so these are target values p is a vector of the probability
of the class label taking on the value one given of attributes
and this is just the matrix of the
the basis
and this is the residual from the
the prior
now of course we also need
the curvature so we also need the second the matrix of second derivatives
to define the covariance
if we just do some multivariate differentiation we then find that our
matrix of second derivatives look something like this
for this matrix here is diagonal
and the diagonal components
basically the data in terms of the of the binomial
OK so is the product of PC because one times the product
the probability of sequels zero one minus people
of sequels one
and of course we have this
regularizing ten here so this residual component due to the
the prior
so we are done
on the other we need to do is used so so there is the covariance
of approximation
we started with don and again and again
so it
the MAP values well we need to use some sort of
optimisation methods
we all remember newton's root finding methods from school
the multivariate version
is basically
we want to find the roots of
the stationary points of
the score function here
and so
we just use
the second order
the message here
so we can plug in
the values of the gradient and the hessian
and again do some
some simple algebra and you end up
with far and iteration
so we don't have this is not in closed form
because w appears
and also
appears in the elements of p and it appears in the elements of e
so we basically have this
is which you can think of the compelled compatibility score
of a given observation and labels
so we're going to look at the compatibility score of the correct
correct observation labelled pairs
and we're going to look at the the labelled pair the deal label
that is not the correct one but this it is the maximum score with respect
to the
we suspect our current classifier so we define the margin to be the distance between
the case and n is that is before we're we're going to try to maximize
the minimum of these margins
so if we look at the graphical
representation of this problem what do we have let's look at one of the things
that x i
and for each x i we have many labels many possible label assignments
and here with the rank tells us that the are confident
our confidence on each pair
if x x i y i which is the correct pair
which is the correct label for example it is it a higher score
then all the other possible labels we have the correct classifications
and the the the margin is given by this and if this margin is larger
than what we have satisfied the margin constraints and if it is not the case
we have
satisfied the margin constraints
an alternative example is an alternative situation is when the correct label to do correct
label for for an observation
it is the lower confidence score than then some other
some other label assignments for the instance then we have the negative margin and we
have we need to do something about this
so we have the margin
the definition again and the confidence scores again the inner product between some feature representation
x y parents which they talked about in detail
and as before
are the this this problem can can be stated in terms of the quadratic programme
so and l two norms
we we try to minimize the l two norm of our hyperplane plus some slack
that allows us to
violate our constraints margin constraints which is given here
and this is exactly equivalent to here
so for each data instance we want the most compatible want to be larger than
one plus some slack
and if we want to look at this this problem or
and again in a graphical setting with the slack variables
the slack variables are going to be
just because of the definition of hard margin constraints
we're going to have a slack variable
four for a label that is that is that that is the most competitive to
the correct one so the one that achieves the maximum score
or that achieves the minimum of this distance
so let's see how
we can
visualize the
r compatibility score is an inner product of our feature representation in our hyperplane are
weight vectors
and the slides are slack variables can in fact be stated like this it is
it is either zero it is the max of
or one minus
our separation
here i'm showing
i have two examples here x i two training instances x i x j
so for example i am using green
the color coding for sixty red one
and for each observation
this is a structured observation obviously we can have many many possible labels that y
is the correct one of four
and we can have all these other incorrect labels so i'm going to use a
representation for the correct pairs in the circle for the incorrect one
i can think of this operation is the projection
after the feature representation and onto the onto my hyperplane and if
if the score is larger than all the correct once again
i have
i have no
correct classifications but this is not enough for me i want the most competitive the
difference between the most competitive want to be larger than one
right so in this case
these slack variables xj is this difference is larger than one
them also the slack variable is going to be zero if it's not larger than
one then i'll have to be penalized in my loss function
in i the situation is different because the correct one is ranked actually lower than
than the
then some other labels
but i'm going to be only analyse for the one
that use the max
of misery
well what you perceive is orange or yellow depends very much on context just as
what you see in the face depends on whether it's upside down and so it's
actually pretty hard to division system and i don't want to get so what i
did instead was i went to the supermarket also later oranges and lemons and i
measured them with the ruler so
i i did actually do this i sat down with the real and i measure
the width and height of a whole bunch of oranges and then we can we
can but now we turn it into numbers numbers is something i computer can deal
with say
in particular
i've got
the matrix text
one night in the street is going to have a height
and with the
and then i'll have to that one item for another one would have another
so i can have an
and then i'm going to have a bunch of columns for different features are measured
and i just happened to measure two features
OK and then as well as these input x and has the outputs y so
why is going to be a factor which will feel like and that will have
some labels that will be the first ones and minus one
saying whether it's an orange whether it's true so then once again the matrix and
vector that's something i can shove into a computer
and i can also
obviously draw plot so we can look at this and we can see that there's
obviously some structure in the data
not liking this example if it doesn't excite you a very similar example is saying
i've got an image from a
telescope and it's got stars and galaxies and and galaxies tend to be a bit
more elliptical than stars and you might plot similar plot for the height and weight
of those objects and ask whether the stars and galaxies
it's immensely problem so i'm going to back off back to my oranges and lemons
so the first thing i propose we going to do is build what's called a
linear classifier say
what we're going to try and get a computer to do
let down the picture down the middle of the black line is what's called the
decision boundary and to the right
if we were to see new item fruit
and it landed here
to the right of the line anything that we would machine with them say
that's an orange and similarly
to the other side of machine would say that so i goal is going to
be to come up with a computer program that can draw that line four
just as we needed to represent as free with numbers we're going to need to
represent the line with numbers as well and so
this is why your linear algebra needs to be pretty good to deal with the
los machine learning because
dealing with vectors and matrices comes up lot and understanding sort of the geometry that
associated with that can be very useful
if i want to represent a plane
the standard way to do it is to represent it with the vector which i'm
going to call w which lies perpendicular to that plane
if i wanted to classify
this side of the rain from the side of the room i could have affected
the points this way
and then the plane will be perpendicular to the
the vector and i will split you can
now that might seem a bit of a funny thing to do why am i
pointing down the middle i wanted to divide
the dividing line here why not just point that
and that
if i have got to two d picture like the oranges and lemons that's a
fair point but in machine learning we're interested in
things that are less trivial and what you can plot
in two d on this slide there were interested in
not just decision lines but decision planes and these planes could be of high dimension
so let's say i want to define a plane which isn't just here
but it's up to the ceiling as well so now
if i needed to point out down the middle of the room i don't have
to point up and say this is the plane i'm interested in
now we need two vectors to do that
and indeed dimensions i would need a d minus one planes vectors to say these
this is the plane i want all these vectors lie in the plane
there's only one factor that doesn't lie in the plane so much easier to specify
that one
all the others
OK so
if this sort of geometry isn't something you've seen before it's well worth drawings and
pictures trying to work out
how these planes work
the basic take-home message for the moment is that you can define a plane by
just saying
the inner product of the weight vector with the feature is greater than zero
we can think about that intuitive like maybe y is y values w
that vector is often called the weight vector
and the reason is that it
giving weight sort of importance to the features say
i'm going to define something is plus one or an orange if w transpose x
begins airing
OK so
let's imagine that
w won the first elements of this vector is positive
now in order to make this inequality holds in order to make the transfer effects
because than theory and if w one is positive we'd encourage that happen if x
one was also positive so
the meaning of that weight vector that is
i am saying with these features contribute positively or negatively to
the expected classes and thinking about so that sort of importance is attached to the
this in the bias here the necessary for general plane and i'm going to skip
the moment so i don't know if you can see down here
i'm just going to talk about planes to go through the origin and their weight
w transpose x begins airing
i didn't say at the beginning but i'm really keen for to interrupt me and
ask questions all the way through the afternoon in case any of this is unclear
a lot of if you've done any machine learning before this is basic introductory material
a lot of people haven't and it's
you know there's no point in marching through matter
i just wanted to mention in fight which is
that you if you don't already know one you really need to go away and
learn a numerical package like matlab or python numerical package or some piece of software
that lets you deal with matrices and vectors easily
and here the reason in one line
so i had a program this is given me one of these weight vector w
and i had now
a new bunch of examples that i wanted to classify say
i've got a matrix which contains a whole bunch of numbers associated with new apples
and oranges on new stars and galaxies here is the code to make prediction so
this one line says
combine the weights and the data
see whether the result is positive and negative and use that to make predictions spit
out the galaxy of laurent one line of code to make predictions
it might not be that much code to do this and see if you're just
going to sort of leap over these things and do this and it'll be a
lot harder to see what's going on
and we're going to move on to the things that are less
trivial and that's this sort of
six thinking this is really important
it's not just sort of need this will also be a lot more efficient than
any c program you go away and write because in the background this will be
solved by high optimize linear algebra routines are going to be better than any c
program you right
learn how to use these packages
once you've got away and learn how to use the package this is an implementation
of a complete program for
learning one of these weight vector vectors given some data
it's not important you follow all the details right now
two pieces but no segment which spanned both the object and the background so this
is so much in practice so here we go back from the big image to
a set of twenty six months
the will behind the conundrum about that
so here the goal is not to create a new way of image is this
a good idea because these people use that allow the vision of is in addition
the goal is to take this is the way people use images and put it
into the kind of work to get the most out of it and being able
to use the full can imagery
if it can be can only images things that technique for example then automatically you
can get out of four
image retrieval classification clustering and so on so here
if you can sort zone a potential
the problem for images you get a lot out of it
so you see how it works will be taken image that segments using night to
energy from economy important role
well you've been a gradient
and your computer what action
and with different number of segments that you can be considered
you see that is the same as to get your your tools is so this
is not the case
the case where
the semantic get out of it
but if you take the
then we started saying that get stuck with the job to make with the background
and there is no way you can really discover anything but if you go to
sixty four
higher number of segments
so you just stuck it into pieces produced to get something for the same segmentation
so what we do is go from one image to what they called the segmentation
which is just a graph where each one of vertex per region
and it is a labeled graph
we need to label the text with the set of the set of colors that
you have on your region and connect
regions which are spatial neighbors
this is a very common with condition and in vision
essentially what work on that
so it is difficult for many reasons and because it essentially
you have a planar graph that tree
and of course you wanted to inexact matching
i think we'll we'll but we did is simply to go back to bioinformatics so
quite interesting to see the exchanges between mathematics and vision of different OK don't look
at all the same problems
in terms of the
in many cases the same type of problems for example in biology
the mathematics put these got but it comes across a lot of work trying to
to to design a kernel for graphs and essentially what we did is extend this
block kernels that were used for about six in the vision
so what is it the principle is that you want to contact us about essentially
enumerating all the support
so if you go back to this high dimensional feature space there are other possible
subgraphs in like
by using recursivity factorisation can compute
don't part it in all possible substrings also lives in nineteen ninety nine it
so here
if you to the
and i should allow for details the principle is very
very important which is very large feature space here all possible some rocks and we
make sure that we can compute the product very efficiently
so this work so stickers people database of the one thousand natural images with fourteen
and see how it works
so it so that you get simply is what you call what you do when
you only consider one big segment of the image and compare
histogram of kernels
so have the images of i so you would get a lot out of the