three men and
the more
it's just
they all
we're not
this is a
so the right
that means but it
so much
in fact
twenty one
so much
no problem
let's talk
but the company and later
that's why i think they
is just the same
you want
so each
which like
so when
the above
but was
on the other hand
the model
if can
now that you know the one
the most
we can then
can you
just like
but this is the
so one are way or to way
my picture
the first of may one
so main
after the image of the last
and this morning
and i would
numbers we can use the
for the first time
somebody somewhere
one hundred and
hi because things
just like
so you are going to be talking about two many things
here in part three i'm going to be talking about
document retrieval so we're going to be trying to learn
hidden representations
of text
from the documents and from queries to try and capture the semantics
of these documents and queries to try and retrieve
good good documents given a query so
that's our goal we're going to try and use neural networks that and we can
compare it to
several baselines now
we can train
there is no networks
in learning to rank kind of setting so the supervised setting a lot of methods
have been published in nature about this many of them actually use
hand coded features like they take
features about the title and the body and the URL
and things like this and then they train like in SVM or perceptron but here
we just we just cannot take words and we're going to try and learn representations
words so in that sense it looks more like actually latent semantic indexing and other
approaches like that he said there typically unsupervised
although there are some
some of those approaches try and labels as well
so just going to look at some of the
simple baselines for retrieval first so we can use a bag of words representation
of the document so you just take the counts of of all the words in
the dictionary two vols vector
so length of the dictionary need to normalise it and then you can do something
really important just take the dot product of those vectors and take the cosine similarity
is a normalized in the right way
and and just take that
feel school so
so the query and the document
the dot product they should be large value and when
when that document should be retrieved by the query now this has the problem already
that doesn't deal with synonyms
so if
the to the query document have words
which are semantically similar but not the they're not actually the same words you might
even get a score of zero in this
dot product or low score actually any machine learning at all this
OK then you've got approaches
like LSI
and there's lots of other approaches like that as well and what they do
take this
bag of words vector and they learn a linear map typically
into a low dimensional latent concept space or you could you know concerning embedding space
you want to do that for the query and the document and then take the
dot product in that space
and and say that's how
how well matchmaker in document
and that can capture synonyms because two
was which is meant to be similar might trigger the same features in your in
your embeddings basically flat
but standard cyclist that's that's unsupervised learning which might not be useful for you go
so i'm going to look at some supervised models
also do
the that same kind of thing first and then we can see
what the problems are with them and how we turn them into neural networks to
try fix some of these problems
so we can look at
models like polynomial models
on on the original
the going to be polynomial features in the original bag of words so
we can have a linear model here
and as you can see is linear model takes the query and the document in
the joint feature space
and it's going to take a degree k
polynomial terms between the words from the query and document to in making new feature
space of these during the degree k terms and then learn a weight vector w
that this going to be
the degree of match between the query and document
so i'm going to look at two different kinds of models
the degree to kind of model here which is just going to take for the
i th word in every in the query
for every isolating the crew and every chase word in the document you've got a
weight w i j OK so it's going to take all pairs of words so
you can see how this is going to learn things about synonyms so for example
if i had a query here
kids in that's in NYC that's an abbreviation of new york city and i have
a document cap veterinarian new words new york so that any words shared between the
query and document here but with the model like the one i just described
so written in matrix form as q tw d
you can you can learn when
kitten and cat should trigger
high school for retrieval so in that case the part of the weight matrix w
i j where i is the index of kitten and j is the index of
cat should be some positive value
he has to learn that also going to look at degree three models where i'm
going to take
of words the case i'm going to take one word
in the query the i th word
and two words from the document the jason case
and i'm going to have
one parameter that i'm going to learn w i j k for every triple
OK plus i can add all the second order terms as well
now this thing
can capture even more
kinds of relationship between key query and document for example here is another example down
here at the bottom of the slide so it agreed to model could capture saint
even detect this upcoming season patterns from
the things that you measuring reliably
and whether you can implant these many problems with with some medication properly and chronically
there are some
some nerve cov electrodes so basically you have the nerve then this is the electrode
going around it that can squeeze so to say in
and so you could
basically also use detected in non invasive the detected signal to systematically squeeze such nose
in order to prevent an epileptic seizure
so this is a very interesting and very important
application and there's lots of epilepsy patients around
need our help
i'm saying that because the
it's it's good to be it became highly
complicated data analysis problems to define to predict upcoming seizures has been work for for
twenty or thirty years from from lots of people and i think a few people
have started to use the modern machine learning techniques that
so another thing which is maybe more obvious is that you take these implanted electrodes
and couple with some
and then you you just directly using a decoding algorithm two
control robot arm and you've seen that done by
in the video of any schwartz and also mechanically this is has done this and
the question is what how good this can be done for humans and how stable
this is
and can we make this very small devices how many electrodes that we actually need
how many degrees of freedom can we actually command
so these are many many questions and it takes a lot of research to actually
get there so this is future visions
see source about half now so just to wrap up the first
with an overview of of BCI
technology from
many different labs
i think it's it's fair to say
that that you that to say that
BCI is something very interdisciplinary
so in fact if you want to build peace have have little BCI lab in
home university i think it makes a lot of sense to two couple together the
medical department maybe
and the machine learning department signal processing department even it would be nice to have
to do something
sensor development
so but so what what is the
the task in this endeavour the first of all you have to think about some
neurophysiological paradigm
which reflects the brain function that you want to measure for example imagination of your
right hand will make you
left malta hemispheric motorcortex light up
then you have to think about acquisition
this could be e but it could be also henri or invasive or whatever
so this
this part you need a physiologist winner physiologist
then this is all part so we need to think about some robust preprocessing
about good robust classification techniques outlier detection
and we need to
i think about
the only thing that really requires
see that this integral exists
the integral over x may not even exist
it doesn't it doesn't have to make any sense
the key idea how we can actually performing inference in this
is well we avoid computing those for fixing was directly
but instead we only evaluate inner products
why this kernel function here
which defines everything in terms of inner products
and as long as we can write algorithms
in such a way
but we never need the FA x y directly
we can
quite immediately
get an algorithm which can work in arbitrary space blob tree twice
before the break somebody asked me
well in the binomial model
we have those
it's in one minus six terms
we had some far
and i got ask the question so well actually in those parameters to model is
unspecified because
i have a little bit of freedom if i have to normalization two
well play around with it
well that's true
if i just talk about in products
that initial degree of freedom goes away
that can just work in terms of inner products between fall fix
and for the next prime
which then just happens to be x x prime
k one one x
on one minus next prime
should be
two x
x one x prime one
and now this expression here doesn't suffer any more
from wherever this subspace came from
now not just as before we had the maximum posterior estimation problems
well densities
we now have one for conditional densities
the the difference is that now wherever we had forth ics before we now have
five x and y
the good thing is all the nice properties of the above problem
just carry through
the one below
it's strictly convex
and theta
what direct solution might be impossible if we cannot compute this directly
we can still solve it by just expanding state in terms of those for fixing
if this function g if they given x is nice
then the optimal solution will actually line the span of a finite number of terms
with the so-called representer theorem
this only holds
if the main y is finite
otherwise well you might get an infinite number of terms and then you need to
approximate anyway
the nice thing is well we can just put
linear combinations
formatting expansion of data
into this
functional below
and we optimize over those expansion coefficients
so what has happened is we've turned a optimisation problem that potentially infinite dimensional space
in the one that in the finite dimensional space we can now
optimize of individual coefficients
and then it all boils down to what this function g looks like what these
terms look like
i would just optimize away
so now what's happening is
if this trend feature map so we take x and y pass
we mapped to fall fixed and why
take the inner product with data
the mapping into our
the problem is we need to really evaluate it for all wise for the normalisation
but that's really the only
small technical issue
so the
the representer theorem is the following
four minimizes the objective function
so this is
let's just one man
the in the
in late
i think know
it's like no one
we need to do
and they do
he was
so this is the
the problem is
you know
now assume the
what need to know
the two
and in
you know it's true
the more
see this
we were
like this
six models
the main
the only thing
i think that
the problem these things only
so it is not
the models
in know
that is
it's not works
you know
this scene CA
so the whole
it was probably
is it
all o
it is
thank you
do you want to see
OK so this
o thing to be
o to one
that is what we do is
the reason
one the one variable
on the wall the probability of something happening
so we have to use small
of these about movies use
so this is something
that was the
actually that's one of the examples of common a few slides so that's called
chance constrained you want to put that in the limit on the probability that the
and constraints x is violated
and in general that can be very difficult except in
special cases depending on the density density
and concerns
those who actually see one practical examples very can be
so then so the next topic is called programming and continue this tomorrow
so called programming is a general
defined like this
it's the general format for convex optimisation has become very popular since
the early nineteen nineties
basically makes any
convex optimisation problem look like a linear programme so it just takes a linear objective
linear equality constraints inequalities
and the only difference is that replaces standard inequality between vectors
by generalized inequalities
and the generalized journalist inequality i mean that define concave convex concave
and this inequality means that h minus gx
lies in the concave
if i take for kedah
nonnegative orthant
then this is just another way of saying that the com the constraints hold componentwise
because componentwise h minus gx lies in the nonnegative orthant
but if you replace the nonnegative orthant by the convex conjugate interesting
convex optimisation problems that
extend your
so it's called called linear programming is popular the standard format because it makes the
general the problem look like an LP
and then it's important and also theory
we and algorithms because all
it turns out the duality theory for example is almost exactly the same as for
linear programming
and also the words for linear programming at least interior point methods are very similar
can be extended to this case
so it's convex sets
that's also called
so if you take an element in the car
and all nonnegative multiples
of the relevant article the entire half line
through the elements in common
so we see actually this is a very general form at the wheel
the interested in two specific cases or three if you include the nonnegative orthant
so the first one is the second order cone so this is a common that's
called the second order cone
so the second order cone is defined like this in general
so we have p
it's if it's a colonoscopy
then you look at the subject vector of the first the minus one entries
and then that vector y is in the icon of the euclidean norm of the
first p minus one and three is is less than the last three
so the second order cone in r three looks like this
so also the ice-cream cone
three of the vector three variable three vector y in the course if y three
is created than the euclidean norm of y one and i two
so for each y three
we have this
constraint defines a disk
of points this could reduce y three
and if you increase y three the radius of the disk increases that goes from
zero to infinity
so it's convex sets this example
it's easy to see it's convex it's also called because it includes the origin and
an older lines
so any point in court
the constraint function is not differentiable
that's the norm so this is also the graph of the norman white and r
so the norm is non differentiable at the origin
it's differentiable everywhere else but if the argument of the enormous zero then that's not
the french
so this is a second order cone programme and sort of the abstract of viewing
this as a program and say well o
look at linear inequalities with respect to this school
but the actual of means something that's very
state for the just means that
euclidean norm of a linear function of x
it's less than this clearly linear function of x
that's a second order cone constraints
so it means that
if you look at the geometrically that this
image of x and this linear mapping lies in the second article
at that appear in the different this time ensemble commonly found and we analyse the
degree of coverage and also the current european needs based on that we
we have selected the
standards that appear
but at the same time we need some kind of tributary taxonomies coming from the
different employment services so so in that case we have two
two two important tool for engineers some kind of taxonomies that were represented in oracle
databases or represented in HTML or represented in access
we integrated or
these taxonomies after building robinson after the
during the transformation from these
sources into into
our internet knowledge more than and one
we integrate the information from
the different sources some portions of the integrated model where specialized in other parts of
the model were extended and we also want those parts
that we didn't consider important for our final application so the what we did is
to generate the
the the ontology which reasoning because this is a the language
we we we need to
that in which we need to you the ontology for doing this the application
so for engineering
you can see that the wind
we started some kind of engineering we have
forty is that you can have some kind of XML information
like the ISO standard for
represented country called and you can also use for instance i despise that are facing
which the different values of spain are included so for that what we need to
do is to integrate and to create first ontology model
this is very very very simple so you we have the location we have country
and region which as of passive of location and we create a relation between country
and are you with the name of past so this allows us to transform all
the instances in the database into
RDF and instantiate all these instances are spain an of country and all this stuff
like instances of tree and that the and this is the RDF called genetic
so v
the next step is that you should go to analyse all the
ontology if other ontologies could be reused for your application i will not explain these
this process because we only ever use one time
one one ontology about of all time it is on the material you have you
have there
and i go to the concert twenty stations activity which is more important so this
from the
the use of non ontological resources we have all already selected and transformed some kind
of an ontological resources in a ball into ontologies we have also selected some
one ontology about time and on the the twenty station activity we should organise or
the sources that we plan that we should relate all this shows is that we
know the ontology is that we are going to use in our application
so in that case the representation ontology that we we are using these with me
we are also using in some kind of genius
or common ontologies like time geography
language ontologies
we are using domain ontologies like a of we need an ontology domain ontology like
economic activity occupation education as he is driving license compensation labour
competence so these ontologies has been built by means of the use of an ontological
the end what we have
or what we has been is the application
the in domain ontology just four percent did the job seeker and the you for
i want
in the same way
that we try to summarize the probability distributions which still we try to summarize the
samples so we might calculate the mean that's the average and the varience for example
and they will be that uses estimates of
what would happen if we going on forever so
so do that
we refer to these things parameters so we're trying to estimate the expectation and variance
some data
now when we were the summaries out
because what we're trying to do
we would like to know what the characteristics of the summaries so we did a
lot of trials
and we got a lot of numbers and work out an average what we want
to know is what the characters of the probabilistic characteristics of the average and in
particular we might ask the question if i take the sample of account its average
how fast going to be from the true value if i could have done
an infinite number of samples to any number of trials that would give me the
true long-run expectation that's what i try to find out about often
and what i would like to know is
well i can't do
an infinite number of trials going define number of trials so how far is the
mean from a finite number of trials from the mean for the infinite number of
and the way try to get that
is what's called the sampling distribution so
thank you all the observations the data is being individual random variables ifwe want to
make mean we have all the variables are defined by many random variables and got
and that will give us our approach so this is the function of various learning
components so it will have random behavior itself if we did the same thing again
in different simple we expect to get a different name where have is not exactly
the same meaning just a number very close to what
so so different samples will
it was different
i mean solar variation across different samples and that's
the variation across the different samples is called the sample distribution so that sort of
behavior why do want to know that will come back to that later
i've just included here because that's where is in in the book
so if open saying that what we try to to the statistician is so
data and work out things about the probabilistic model that's out there
this is called inference
and a more formal way of putting this down saying the probabilistic model depends on
various numbers
unknown parameters which in the frequencies will we would think of as constants so
that's what this thing here is
theta is just a vector of numbers is not variable is not the not random
we just don't know what they are so example of that might be
the long remained expectation
is not a random quantity is fixed by the book
we don't know what it is because in order to find out what is we
have to do an infinite number of trials and that we can't
we try to find out
about these numbers and these numbers relate to
properties of
the model that was thinking about and
we have two standard attacks on how do we find out what
how do we get an estimate of the quantity
because that's what i do but also want to estimate the parameters in the parameters
that back to
what we
i think about is this
we think of the probabilistic with probability model that we have also will if we
call f
and as these guys here t
if this was the a constituency what that means in terms of the probability of
getting the data that we actually saw so is some data and we might say
let's say we're playing about tossing a coin again
and i suppose we saw
with ten goals
and we saw six of those who had
so we get this we have knowledge of the world
there we are more
that is part of the
the query mine
so we have as part of our world
because they were able to audition world
make sense of the world
and operating intelligence
is that is that some of the crazy ideas said that after
well it may be
but interestingly too freely
developmental psychologists in last twenty years
i have been studying and something very similar to that
which is expectations about the real the world of words
apparently mis just
without ever having for example
object object
these are
goes on the edge of alleged faults
it appears that he
have expectations about the way the world a
even prior to any experience with the somehow that knowledge is built into the brain
is something very similar
so that
sorry which was presented
a couple of centuries
the question questions about this
all right
we began with this question
about ontology was really true in the world and what is the relationship between knowledge
and true
and what we've discovered
is that the relationship is problematic
that our knowledge of the world and what the world is really like
are not exactly the same
imagine that philosophers have been pursuing this question for a couple of thousand years
and they're not getting the answer
and it's been really frustrating
and about a hundred years ago
all this time he two that
were desperate to find an answer not
can you have certain knowledge
or is this
just chasing our tails is
this is a fool's errand
she tried to lock down
our knowledge that we can confident that our knowledge is what is true
and came to a head was
around nineteen twenty
we are the
school be known as logical positivism like all this
the loss these last ten
to gain certain knowledge
the group of philosophers first many of the inner circle and they were
they had this idea that
OK lot knowledge is uncertain but there are some things that we can say
for example
several propositions i
table hard
like right
tommy troops
they say you know as the
that we can and maybe a little bit like data we can build on those
and so on any to do this for a few years
the last was very poor
was that we didn't stop
who was from austria who was also a lecturer at
cambridge university so he was one of the original proponents logical positivism we can you
know certain things for sure
table hard
like bread
a few years went by
completely changed as well
and maybe it's hard to use different is
too hard
and like right
well take this very far
into the way human beings understand and talk about the world
two things
when we communicate when we think
we move into directions that are very far away
from those
tom treats
so there was a certain kind of
are sure was hard all this idea of talk that
it was not true
that was not
they really do reflect
the way that humans talk about knowledge and so
it wasn't long before the design
change his mind in and the idea
of logical positivism and said you know this
to understand
the world it has certain knowledge of the universe is actually hoax
that was that was sort of coming for a long time we have certain
instead he
he said you know what i mean
what we
i understand about world
is really what we know of language and language is sort of self into the
who's leads to reality you are
tenuous at best
and you said you see the transition
so here we are students per classroom
we're using words
we're communicating i deal with this this probable values
and yet
and he said
there are strong connections between the words that is
an underlying reality
and wittgenstein saying
that's pretty much
we are we or not
so after this long long long long pursuit of knowledge
it's more less speaking about a a hundred years ago smallest in the hand
what philosophers philosopher said there were turned their attention
so what matters rather than
finding the foundations certain knowledge
and this is sometimes called the system call
the linguistic turn lost their knowledge of the world that language
again trying to find a strong connection between
an underlying reality is
five problem
we will instead went to me
and maybe that's one reason that we need to see
make some changes
so don't be surprised if history is changed and so it means that then some
of the slides
on the internet we look little different from
but this may happen it later
in the second chapter we focus on symmetry because symmetry is very important topic in
and so what we're going to do
we're going to talk about
groups and subgroups
group actions
symmetry groups
then another very important topic is covered in grass this is where you get groups
and topology
come together
and symmetry in graphs
graphs are very
dollars structures
they have nice symmetry properties
and then the amount of symmetry introduce
maybe very important so that's this point five
it's is very very important and this is where
a lot of research
going on
right now
here in slovenia but also
in other parts of the world
i will briefly touched in the two metric spaces and then we'll talk about representations
of graphs and symmetry
chapter three
we get two maps
for surfaces
topological graph theory
drawing graphs on surfaces
again multiple motivation
and political complexes surfaces classification of surfaces
connected sum and fundamental polygon so the surfaces
torus in space maps like systems operations on maps
petrie dual
symmetry of maps
and and then
closed curves
on surfaces
again you see some of the topics
will just follow
some recent results
our mathematicians
so finally
any questions
no questions that
we go to the introduction
so what we're going to let's start with the
with this example
so what we have here
it is the so-called
final configuration
what final plane
have you seen this picture before
not everybody
should explain OK let me explain a little bit and indeed what we have here
so we have seven objects
i call them one
so they're all abstract object OK
and i call this objects points
but there are points like this you know
the number of points they're just points
quote unquote
then i have seven other objects
they call a
f and g
and i call these guys lines
the other thing i do
i tell
which point
it lies
on which like
for instance
o point
and four
the same line a and this is one
the line
like the same line of the drawing of course here
it is just schematic drawings there are no points here
just these three points
this is just to understand we're example for instance there is one
four curve
which choice two
six and seven
and if you look at
six and seven and then you get a line
OK so line f is this
so this
structures can be either either draw like this
and we know what we're are talking about or table like that can be
and then this the table that describe this combinatorial structure
this structure is called
that is the structure
so that's probably the most the simplest
algebraic structure that this is much simpler than the group's remember group or or or
it because it has one operation but this one
just one relation it has two sets of objects
he stands four points
and l
stands for blocks lines
and there is
relation by i here
which is called the incidence relation
which tells whether a point
these incidents with the line
so they can get testing examples from the same distribution so imagine that all what
doing whimsical imagine his learner and it's out the world exploring its learning all about
the environment and finally gets it and understand how the mind works and now it
spends the rest of its life can attract in its own body being forced to
act the way it did when it was still learning but knowing the right thing
to do and that's not be able to do it so so this is really
just not a good fit the fact that you really depend on this idea assumption
really makes it problematic to apply
learning algorithms are great in the PAC setting in this reinforcement learning setting with exploration
so that the gay people come up with other learning models the mistake bound model
is nice in that it assumes inputs are presented at the serial
right some
something out there is can produce any training example at any time
and now the models little bit different the model says that each time an example
comes in the learner has to provide the label and they can be wrong
and now covers parts red so
it gets it gets an instance it tries to predict the label it gets it
OK moves on it gets another instance maybe correct you get the correct answer green
bar the correct one it's another one and it's wrong it can continue to make
any arbitrary time but the total number of mistakes has to be bounded that's the
mistake bound
OK so here we've got this this is the learner that is is be given
any kind of examples from any kind of distribution but it can only make a
finite number of states about the number of mistakes for it to be a successful
mistake bound learning algorithm
now you can only really works if this is true as well you can only
really successfully make learning algorithms under restriction restrictive assumptions about what the hypothesis class is
what is the function that actually labeling these instances but unless there's a wide variety
of algorithms that are
sorry of a function class that are learnable interstate model
OK so
this is getting as much closer to something that we can use in reinforcement learning
settings the problem is from from the previous slide if it's making mistakes and it
doesn't know it's making mistakes it doesn't know when something's i guess it just guessing
and the try count against it it won't necessarily explore efficiently
so in particular if it's imagining all you know what's behind the screen i'm going
to assume that there's nothing
valuable behind the screen that might be mistaken the mistake bound model so that's OK
it's just a mistake but in the MDP setting in the reinforcement learning setting that
mistake could actually cause it to never get near optimal reward because maybe the optimal
thing is just go behind the screen
the following nothing there
to one side
so there's really nothing there is far so so this this mistake bound setting where
where it doesn't really know what could be making mistakes and not it can actually
achieve this PAC MDP time can found
so what we need is said well this the quick setting is going to do
things all differently now
but the learning algorithm if it's given an instance that can predict the label it
knows it can accurately predict the label cause there's multiple possibilities that could work it
has to say i don't know know
shrug shoulders k and so we can start adversarially selected input is coming into could
say i don't know and maybe another instance comes in cycle with this when i
get and gives us to give the right answer i don't know the right answer
right answer right answer i don't know like the mistake bound model it could continue
saying i don't know any arbitrary time in the future
but the total number of times it's going to say i don't know has to
be bounded by something small for going successful quickly learning out
this can be used in reinforcement learning settings and give us those those exploration PAC
MDP kinds of bounds because we can do is assume any transition that can predict
may lead to something
and we can predict predict accurately and therefore making mistakes on those
the combination of some kind of successful quick learner and this model based setting get
reinforcement learning algorithms with these nice guarantees
so that's the that's the basic story there
there's there's a nice proof that this works in general when combined with an algorithm
that is often referred to as max because it assumes that anything it's unknown is
that has maximum reward right reward max that the most training but anyway it does
work and
this this this class of algorithms has been used for learning and in these flat
mdps where there's and states in each state can be completely different from every other
state but it's still going to learn about them is going to decide what to
do in the states and there's a number of key ideas we know that the
optimal action for approximate model is near optimal in the real real model which means
if we know that the model is learned the environment may not be perfect but
it's epsilon close all transitions then taking the optimal actions with respect to that gas
about the environment this close guess is going to lead to near optimal reward in
the environment there's this weird discontinuity so if you just get one little thing a
little bit wrong your arbitrarily far away from from optimal
so that's the simulation lemma says we can simulate the environment with approximate model and
explore exploit lemma says basically this is a cute idea if there's part of the
of the state space that we can reach because it's it's very low probability to
be able to get to one of these states then even if they have high
reward we don't have to go there we can get near optimal reward just staying
among the states that we can get two with high probability
and that means that when we take actions within the non states if we can
reach any unknown state where either OK this is a better way to say either
the case that our algorithm can explore a can with high probability get some state
that hasn't seen yet and learn about it or if you can't do that it
must be able to exploit which means among the states it already understands well it
can achieve high reward for the real model
OK so these two pieces together give us these these nice efficient learning algorithms in
the in the in the flat case there's a number of papers that talked about
this but some people have looked at in last to call it on flat in
cases where there's there's generalizations that can be made between states
like for example if the dynamics are determined by dynamic bayes net some kind of
factor model or it's good a metric space is continuous there's a continuous state space
and the relationship between nearby states and the other states that are nearby
or in what we showed is in general any function class that they can be
quickly learned we get the same kind of nice
ideas that come into play and can get near optimal reward
and in particular what what we show with the
this is the only who's my cousin who's post-doc now and looking for good job
very bright man and so when he was able was show his thesis is that
is in any quick learner that we plug into this framework gives us the PAC
MDP bounds the time to learning environment depends on the time to learn the transition
function so if it's the kind of transition function that you can learn with very
few examples very effectively then learning to explore the state space is actually going to
be efficient as well
so i so you might ask i would hope if you're paying attention you would
ask okay but are things that we can quickly so he always should far if
you can click on function class action showing life stated use of our if you
can click on the function class then you can
behave well you can be behave efficiently in reinforcement learning sense in an environment where
the transitions have that function
but what are some things we can quickly well the easiest simplest actually the basis
of almost all the interesting stochastic algorithms is to learn the probability values so basically
coin flip if the weighted coin you don't know initially the probability that's going to
so basically restrictions of x onto those cliques
and corresponding functions on it and correspondingly the kind of x prime could be written
as the sum
well the maximal cliques
of kernels just defined on the maximal cliques
this was already a great improvement as it allowed us
the decompose any kernel that i might want to
use for a certain
graphical model
in two kernels which just basically
have terms interacting we're having edges within the graph
so this actually very simple intuition
but it allows us to do this
and show that this is actually an issue sufficient condition
so what we're going to do today is
we're going to look at specific graphical structures here
specific models of conditioning
and then derive specific months out of it and they have names and they exist
and people use them but we look at the general framework so
what you can do is
you can just draw whatever crap the model you want
and then derived from that quite automatically what economists would look like what inference procedure
should look like
well you think can actually go going solve it efficiently it's a completely different story
because it's very easy to design one that look really appealing in convincing but impossible
to solve
but OK that's
how they're touching upon that a little bit to towards this
set of slides
well there is actually a lot of research going on in this area right now
what i'm not even going to get into
so the fact that while i've been pretending to be a bit bayesian here
by saying well we've got the like we've got the prior we put all those
things together and perform parameter estimation but actually that's not
the true and proper bayesian procedure to do things is if you have a posterior
you don't actually need to sample from that you need to compute expectations you need
to integrate out of these
the trouble is that this is extremely hard even the simplest of all cases
things like expectation propagation of tom minka
for instance help in this context but they're not really perfect either there's a lot
well there is this entire family of markov chain monte carlo for various posterior part
of papers around and those things seem to be
slow and hard to implement and they don't work
significantly better in practice
so usually when you see a paper it works a little bit better but you
pay a huge price in terms of computation
and also it can be much nasty in terms of the ability to analyse the
so this is why
at least for this
set of slides i'm not even to go into this
also because there are people much better than me understand MCMC better than i do
and so for instance days
a guy called paul bear
they just like robert was written entirely very nice book
sampling methods
but what pages being very good book
he's also
got good slides from the summer school in there
so if you go to the there there
web page of the summer school you might be able to download the slides
about five hundred slide
so you go either through five the pages in the book of five hundred slide
but that would
give you pointers how to tackle this problem
this is not a solved problem
so if you come up with a clever way of
making headway there i mean you can probably have quite an impact
i don't know the name of the book but if you look for markov chain
monte carlo and while there
in google
i'm quite sure you'll find it
going on my bluetooth as disconnected
we have
what we do
look at conditional random fields
and discussed a little bit message passing my guess is thomas hofmann will be discussing
that to some extent on thursday and friday again
from a slightly different point of view so
guess if you see from several points of view look familiar you would probably know
some of this already from this morning when doug aberdeen was talking about dynamic programming
because what will be doing here is just the activation of the dynamic programming
i'll briefly mention this this is beautiful theory
unfortunately as we tried it out it's not terribly good for practical implementations
back to the hammersley clifford theorem
here's our graphical model
sorry nicely triangulated
and these are some of the maximal cliques and we know that things decompose that's
exactly expansion here
and that's our kernel
it decomposes along the maximal cliques
now what's the conditional random field
well conditional random field is a situation where
this is a graphical model
but the chain of lakes is
this could be text that could be a biological sequence could be anything
and i want to annotate sequence in some way
prince i might want to tag the named entities
like well
first name last name names of cities and so on
and well
you can clearly see that this is
not so obvious even if you just had like a list of features so well
some names like for instance smaller are quite likely
to be
proper names
things like well bush whether that means the probability is president is not quite so
you might need to exploit the context
a very simple model would be to say
every word depends on its neighbors
course any word will have a bearing on
how it's annotated
but probably also its neighbours
will have a certain influence on what annotation of the word
so if your friends have mister bush
o president bush
that separates two classes
so actually were
you want to find
and yet
that separates the positive examples here
it is like to have the negative examples
the set
classes for thinking about positive
and negative
but it could be told to other classes
that you want to describe lacks for
so you want to find the function which
the line
here is the diamond
she i mean higher dimensional
you have to
the your training data are linear
that's the budget
my point is to mention
in my mind
could that
we are of the
think examples
so i support vector machine in my
the height
that the
we might have more
with regard to this
the support vector
support vector vectors
nine more
so we look at a time when node d
five because
that means that
but also for
that you my love
they could be
that positive examples like the negative
the first
and they room
it's not
so kernel methods use specific
that's the idea can be generalized to examples that are not necessarily linearly separable
two examples that can be used by
but let's look at
so we have
and we have a feature vector
x one to x and so we have
and you can see it has
one of the two classes that
why why mines one plus one
so i x y feature vector is described as being
should be
plus one indicates that x y is negative or positive
so the
we again
the height the
that the
so the point that lies on the high
this these
that the phi of point x that lies on a high
that w
multiply by
because the
we can say that we are in the presence of stability and the summation
this is the basic idea
i tried to do this
and here we have the estimate for alpha
the value of alpha for the samples one point six to three
and i know that it's difficult to see because i was forced to to maintain
the table is more but i
i can assure you that are out of twenty cases just in one cases we
have an estimate of alpha which is not compatible with the one point six to
three were comfortable means that they the values comprised
inside these rockets
given by one plus one standard deviation you find one point six
so it's a this value is not statistically significant from one point three so from
this point of view
we are in the presence of a process which is almost stable information
but there was no problem
and this problem is that
this was rise by referee what about if we have a common shock
if we have a common shark it's one it's possible that we have factors distribution
simply because all sectors all the firms are affected by some show
so i had the problem of separating the common shock from all these amount of
that's standard econometrics which is called conformal factor model
but the common factor models based on this assumption will show it
for the errors
since i'm interested in the errors of the use of this
i e e i could not use
standard for common factor models
so i try to estimate the several across sections
regression by using an algorithm which is able to estimate
i linear regression and the assumption of the latest levy stable distributions
and these algorithm reports the value of the alpha
of the distribution for the arrows
so if
after we remove
common factor
from the data for a single year
for the wall sample
and we end up
with a narrow this is what remains after we remove the commercial which is still
low stable distribution i can maintain that's my results
our robots
and this is what happens
here you have the alpha
for all the cross cross-section regressions eliminating the common shock
and this is the alpha four
for the for the air for the distribution of the k
and a lot we have chaka
a and basically no cases
the arrows what remains after removal common shock is again leaves the city
so i don't think about it shocks are likely to be distributed as a stable
we have an infinite second moment what does it mean what what's the implications for
business cycle well implication is quite interesting because
suppose that we we we start and not going to try to fool the details
this is the vision but just a rough idea was going on here suppose that
we start from such productive functions
there's a paper by how shows that the growth rate of GDP
can be given by
the sum of shots
to the productivity of inference
OK this is same
and this is total GDP so these are normalized phase and this is interviewed look
the the the the
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
OK good morning are welcome to cystatin nine the machine learning class
so what i want to do today is discovered spend a long time going over
the logistics for the class and then
well start to talk a bit about machine learning
by way of introduction my name is actually LP instructor for this class and worker
machine learning that worked on it for about fifteen years now and i actually think
the machine learning is that you the most exciting field of all the computer science
of society always excited about teaching this class of
sometimes actually think that machine learning is not only the most exciting thing computer science
but the most exciting thing in all of human endeavor
maybe bias there
also to use the TA's for all practices seen research in related the machine learning
now it's machine learning on a public stock is on
works in machine learning and computer vision on KTH hang is actually neuroscientists who applies
machine learning algorithms to try to understand human brain tom those another phd student works
in computational biology and in so the basic fundamentals of your learning on zico kolter
is the haiti a
on seeing the thirty two years in a row now works the machine learning and
applies them to a bunch of robots and daniel ramage is of course not here
daniel applies learning algorithms the problems in natural language processing
so you get to know the tears in me much better from this quarter but
just from you know
the sorts of things that he is do i hope you know really tell the
machine learning is highly interdisciplinary of
topic in which we just that he is to find the any offers problems in
computer vision in biology and robots and language of and machine learning is one of
those things that has had and is having a large impact on many applications
so just in my own daily work i actually frequently and talking to people that
helicopter pilots the biologist the people in computer systems and databases to economics and this
sort of all
also you an unending stream of people from industry come to stand for interest imply
machine learning problems interest fly
machine learning methods to their own problems
and so on
this is done a couple of weeks ago students actually for there to be an
article on in computerworld about the twelve i t skills
that employees the employees can't say no about the you know so the totals desirable
skills and all the ITN all of information technology and topping the list was actually
machine learning so i think this is a good time to be learning this stuff
and learning algorithms are having a large impact on many segments of science and industry
amish curious about something
learning algorithms one of the things that touches many areas of science and industry is
a kind of curious how many people here computer science majors are in the computer
science department
half hunger from e e
OK develop honey biologists out here
well just a few not really surprise anyone for statistics
OK a if few
also where where they received from
i see a core
the and well
since this device is called
kenny call
there are still yes right
anyone else
pardon MST
goal so
and the ship was
in the
i think industry
people right
this is again tells from from from a cross section of the class think very
diverse audience in this room and that's one of the things that makes this past
fun to teach in front of be and i think
so in the class try to convey to you brought set of principles and tools
that will be useful for doing many many things on and
every summer teaches cause i can actually very confidently say that of after december no
matter what you're going to do after this december one when you have completed this
course of you find the thing to learn in this class very useful and these
things will be useful pretty much no matter what you end up doing late in
your life
more logistics go over later but let's say a few words about machine learning
if few machine learning grew out of early work in AI early work in artificial
intelligence and the loss alamos a lost fifteen of the last ten years or so
it's been view as
during new capability
thought computers on
then we are guaranteed that this point will be correctly classified solution
because the only way for a point not to become support vector is if the
point is somewhere either over here over here so point this easy classified correctly when
we leave it point which doesn't end up being support vector
we would play classified correctly and that's where this part comes from the that's just
a little little side remark so it's good to have few support vectors
second sight remark is about the interpretation of the solution namely to show you before
these constraints of this
qualities is that we get from taking the derivatives with respect to the primal variables
those with these two inequalities interestingly these two inequalities imply
some kind of mechanical stability
you can make the following model assume that each support vector exerts a force
perpendicular to the hyperplane parallel to the w vectors of size alpha and direction y
you assume that your hyperplane is the solid plane sheet
the support vectors
pushing on the hyperplane
then the solution is
in terms of being mechanically stable in the sense that
this one constraint that the forces sum to zero
because these are forces and these other the directions of forces
in our second constraint which implies that the torques sum to zero
to see that you have to write down the
the definition of the talks
so the talks act on this point x i and then you have to take
the cross product which product with the forces forces have size five direction why i
times the unit vector
and on the back of the hyperplane and i use the by linearity of this
which product so you can move over the y i phi into the first arguement
if you move is over then you see get another w so you have w
this unit vector
and if you take the wedge product or cross product of two vectors that are
parallel you get zero
so that's nice we have mechanically stable solution anyway now finally getting to the dual
problem to remember we had these constraints
which we can use to eliminate the primal variables so if you plot these into
the black watch function here and again i would recommend to do that then you
can believe me now but you wouldn't believe me in a different way if you've
done it yourself and it will not take it too much time so i always
recommend to try out these things you will understand much better
so if you plot these in
after a few lines of algebra
so you should not take more than half the page let's say for this calculation
if you plug it in you get
following problem you get the problem of maximizing this function of far so a function
of two variables
subject to certain constraints
this is the constraint that you heard from here
and the second one of the flies and the negative
by definition of this method of life force multipliers
so these are the constraints
and one of the nice things about this
the solution is that again the
patterns x i x j only appear in the product so we know how to
so both the decision function is actually before and the function to be maximized expressed
in terms of the product so we can now say wherever we had this boldface
x i x j what you really meant was
five exi five xt so we were always talking about points in some feature space
some high dimensional feature space and we're going to do the actual computation by
substituting kernel of these points for this dot product so we just put in the
kernel here and we put in general
and then everything is done in terms of kernel
even though
in principle within the computation in this high dimensional feature space
so what you end up with is a solution
which once you've done this training
number the solution which is a linear combination of kernel functions centred on a subset
of the training points in the training points that have a non-zero lack of multiply
and you can interpret this thing is a neural network if you like we have
some inputs that compared to the support vectors by a kernel function then
the outputs
linearly combined using the weights which i essentially the or
and then summed you get to a decision
OK maybe i mean just show you a little demo again
it will look very similar to
so this is still something treatises so
get exactly the same solution under certain conditions
strong convexity which are
not o is he said i suppose the genes in the work
but roughly speaking if have a convex optimisation problem which is what we had done
nothing wrong
so in the street when
in two
very detail so it depends on
the aspect of optimisation theory but
so if all this is a list of the machines we can assume that is
to do
the same
o thing
yes and shows that people always say
support vector machines are easy to to train because it is a quadratic optimisation problem
it's true it's to quadratic convex optimisation problems
every quadratic optimisation problem has to be convex and matrix
part is positive step
fortunately for data to support vector machines
so the
let's take two classes training points
and train
the solution
look similar to what i showed you two days ago
the decision boundary are this is boundary well
depends on the
i was told that i would
let me take a very large value
this doesn't have lasting months almost
again the solution separating hyperplane is the lines of plus minus one lines with the
support vector machines support vector points come to the solution depends on these three points
in this case
they are on the the bits
so this is still
successful using this very simple
so what happens now
so a few points
correct side but we change seen in
and so on
now you can see it's obvious that class together because they
could use something like newton quasi newton if you use newton if you can if
you can
if you can use the direct method that's it looks excellent choice again you would
we don't catch the factorizations but you what you do cash is the permutation
for the sparse matrix factorizations that's cashed across everything if you a very good choice
to be something like limited memory BFGS
scale to extremely large problems and i should add something here even things that would
wouldn't work well
with l BFGS will not work very well because you admit you've augmented with a
and for methods that
depend on smoothness and things like this adding that rover two
quadratic term is just like it's perfect right you just it's just what they want
to to make them work extremely well i'm including things like lbfgs
right now we're looking so we're going to assemble the parts and cannot have everything
just put them together and you'll see
what's weird is although nothing i've said so far has been
i mean it's all very basic so now we just start assembling so we'll start
just was convex general convex optimization i mean generic problem minimize f over convex sets
or reformulated reformulate radium in this way
and i mean if someone comes up and says i'm going to rewrite this problem
this way i mean this is just like completely stupid it doesn't look like in
fact if you think about you know about how linear programming solvers work the first
thing they do is they dupree solve
priests of scans the problem and looks for
looks for constraints this stupid right this constraints is like x one equals the one
so that's exactly what we solve an LP solver does look look for constraints that
are idiotically stupid it makes no the one x one replaces it here and the
has all symbol table later this says oh by the way at the end please
write fas e one one x one is never seen and saying here so i
mean this doesn't look promising right and then i written it this way g is
the following it's zero if you're in c plus infinity outside and so this does
not look at it just looks too simple too that any good can come of
it right OK but the algorithm is very simple so here you do this is
approx tap on f
in proc step
with g is simple g is the indicator function an approximate the projection onto c
and so you can see and i have a method that will minimize f over
c but it's different for something like projected gradient although for rho extremely high it
is projected gradient
exactly the same and have smooth this does not require f smooth this works for
african itself can contain constraints it could be something horrible but it doesn't make any
difference is works just works period that and so you can see what we have
is a method for minimizing f of x in c
and the only method you have to implement is approx method for f
that's this
and you have to be able to project onto c
right and you can also see here i think it's not that hard to see
the row gets really large this is projected gradient method
right the because this is the gradient step
and this is then you make a projection and so on
all right
so let's
let's look at animals looking less so
i mean why not ten ten thousand algorithms for solving this and this probably another
one developed last week or something like that with a new acronym two so
OK so let let's try it so here
you have a least squares term which is the standard regression terms
and then you have no one sparsifying regularizer
and you know spirit is very simple i mean spirit is
quadratic you we have a very good way to solve those just you girls wrote
a book in latin from round eighteen hundred about least squares so yes we know
how to do that but we have a lot actually we have a lot behind
stuff like this right a lot of
what a lot of integrated knowledge over the years about how to solve problems like
that with this one in there it's harder but in fact we know how to
handle approximate that so it's all going to work to right this when again as
you can see the splitting is like embarrassing
that what really doing is taking single variable and you're replicating it calling it xin
zhi and adding constraint that there is consensus that they agree with each other it
sounds dumb but that's it
and you end up to write this down and you get this thing you do
you do you can if you want you can do factorisation caching here there's a
soft thresholding and there's the dual update
so there's just turn the crank
just to see that it kind of works is an example of this with the
dance a like fifteen had about five thousand
and so if you do this is all by the way something like an eight
line implementation in matlab or something station believe that we should trust in the numbers
and the real implementation would be similar to but smaller numbers right so
the factors asian oh by the way which is the ridge regression so it's a
right that's one point three seconds
and then after that you get a discount it should have been more with thirty
millisecond and you can see by the way when you first iteration this is the
second and subsequently this should have been something like ten millisecond right you can see
that now getting all bent out of shape over how many steps it takes is
completely idiotic doing that position cash right so
let's all takes pride in a couple of seconds by the way you can then
do the full regularisation path because you can share
if you change lambda it doesn't change in any way the fact you just keep
the same factorizations
right so
just a quick example is not that this is like six line matlab script you're
actually close to competitive here i'm sorry you're in urine in the range right so
you write something real quick and it's it it's right there
until end type i mean
nothing was tuned or anything like that so
so this is just to show that knowing about these methods is good it just
means you can actually put bits and pieces together and you can get something very
quickly that is in the ballpark
i do one more this quickly and then we'll get to distributed stuff
with their questions
so for sparse inverse covariance selection here
you have samples from a zero mean gaussians with sigma inverse sparse
and you want to estimate
you want to estimate sigma right so
you're right down will estimate sigma inverse which is called x here
and this would be the negative these two that these two terms are the negative
log likelihood
you know to some constant or something actually that of course animals like the constant
that the negative log likelihood and of course if you just max maximise this you
get lexical sigma
and this was ninety four
by a younger couple phd student of mine he
he developed a very simple trick
we synthesize the polymer network which was not completely crosslinked applied mechanical stress that is
sufficient to get these over all
chain conformations
that is sufficient to get the complete orientation of the liquid crystals and then under
these conditions he performed the second crosslink process and end up with the robot
which is in the nematic state which is completely ordered uniformly order which behaves like
a single crystalline material comp is that in comparison the same sample which was not
mechanically stretched during the in
so this is all which does not contain such
i have a clear we introduced anisotropy of the chain confirmation by sentences
of course such material is much more interesting
in the polycrystalline material single crystal organic or inorganic it's much more interesting than polycrystalline
material and of course the question
is what are the exception the properties of these networks
here again summary
of some basic properties
we measure
four such a single crystal the state of order the order the nematic order parameter
as function of temperature skate all the pace transformation liquid crystal and isotropic i will
not go into the details of this has been nicely investigated in detail here annually
on that we get enormous more or less normally say order parameter function of nematic
phase as
and on the order parameter
behaviour of the nematic phase as function of temperature
interestingly when we look at the length of the sample
the length of the sample of this
microscopically ordered sister behaves very similarly
in other words at high temperature the isotropic state
our rubber has an expansion
which is given by some expansion coefficient of such a rather and this is typically
the expansion corpse efficient
in which has order of magnitude of conventional liquid
but when we approach
the isotropic to nematic phase transformation we can identify spontaneous elongation
of the network in the direction of the optical axis or in the direction of
the preferred orientation
of the molecule and interestingly both graphs can can be combined and if we look
at the correlation of the order parameter as function of the lengths we get a
linear relationship which
can this nicely
described in the frame of the notation
the really and
the slope of this line
gives the
so called coupling coefficients between state of all of these systems and the microscopic dimensions
in other words
if we know this relationship from the length of the network
we cannot directly determine the state of order of the liquid crystalline phase
OK we see
here we see
that we have a spontaneous elongation at the pace transformation of about forty percent and
this of course is highly interesting
i think there's no material that changes
that spontaneous lists the changes
its shape by forty percent within the narrow temperature range
and therefore to jenin
ninety seven on the basis of these first results on the such implements
i made a rough calculation with the system might be used as artificial muscles
it's interesting because here the thermal mechanical effect simply limited with respect to its velocity
to the transportation
compared to other
effects for artificial muscles which are mainly to be determined by diffusion processes
and according to the spot calculation
there was
a clear
answer yes these highly interesting is highly interested gnarly interesting material for artificial moths and
of course being a chemist the next question is when we have such an spontaneous
elongation of forty percent of the system can we improve this
coupling coefficients can we improve the
mechanical behavior of the system
and of course this is straightforward
here we consider the so-called liquid crystal affection elastomers where the liquid crystal and it
it shows side groups to the polymer backbone
and if we
two these liquid crystalline polymers directly within the polymer backbone then we should expect
more pronounced behavior these are some
recent results
we have these these what like moiety is with in the polymer backbone the so-called
liquid crystal made champ almost crosslink
and here one example for a nice system where the pace transformation temperature from isotropic
to liquid crystalline said about sixty degrees
i mean temperatures
as a function of temperature here we are in the isotropic state
one approaching now zero
there is a huge part
that means energy
that's crazy
there shouldn't be in
so some of you must have had sleepless nights
not being able to explain this
some of some of you actually wrote email
you don't have nice i can tell that
so what's going on
there is only one possibility
and that is
there must be free charge
on the glass
how to get there
corona discharge
that's the only way you can get there
keep in mind
that the
electric field
in air
can be no larger
and three times ten two six volt meter
it gets larger you get corona discharge
in glass by the way
it's a bit higher
ten two seven both
i will now make some calculations
based on certain assumptions
and those assumptions may not be exactly accurate because i don't know the exact dimensions
of this
but the exact dimensions don't matter
what matters is the idea behind
it does such a crazy thing
so first of all i will assume that this
just two
parallel planes
this simplifying situation because it has the shape of the bottle
i will assume that the grammar
produces about thirty cuneiform
i know it's approximately right maybe twenty five
maybe thirty five
i would assume that the air gap
between the outer conductor
and the glasses one millimeter both one millimeter
and i would assume that the glass
three millimeters
and i j capriati qualified for the class
well that is the basis of my calculations
so now i have here
the conductor on the outside
this is the class
this is the conductor and inside
so this is one millimeter thick
this is three millimeters thick
and this is one millimeter thick
and the potential difference over the whole thing
it's going to be thirty carnivals
but i know
that the potential difference
is always times the
that holds for this gap
the local a kind of is the local kind of is the and the local
kind that the
i also know
that glass
is the same as in the air
divided by the cap which is five
and i know that the total potential difference between you and here
but thirty thousand
so this allows me now to calculate
in a very straightforward way
the electric field here in the air
the electric field in the air
and the electric field in the in the last because they get
simple equation with one another
and that's the following
i first go over this gap
so i get in the air
times that distance
which is one millimeter
but of course later on
i have to go through this gap again
so i multiplied by two no
and i have to add
the electric field in the glass
which is the same as and divided by five
find it
distance which is three
that must now be
thirty thousand because that's the potential difference between here and there this one equation was
one and
i can calculate the electric field in
the air gap
and the electric field in the air gap
turns out to be
eleven point five
i'm ten to six
both the media
here the same of course eleven point five
ten six and here
it is five times smaller so i find your
o point three
i'm fantasic
to show you that i did my homework correctly
the potential difference
is now eleven point five intervals
but if you can afford
potential difference here
is now about seven kilo
and the potential difference here is the same eleven point five careful
and if you add them up
you get very
look at this
for this matrix c i j
now if i need to look at its compatibility
don't get into the four but into the eighteen trees
that's something i can still kind of before
a decent computer
OK now let's assume
i don't want to match to graphs of size one hundred but maybe size one
thousand i get into the twelve entries
bad news at that time this algorithm will for
so even if i had an efficient algorithm it just storing the problem can review
computing this objective function can also be tissue
well i have treated the bit because quite often this PCA sparse
so we don't really need
that many entries but still
i think you get the idea
basically what you do is you would set up this problem
we CIJ just described the vertex features
as the match
thank you i j u v
described the agreement between the potential age
if well vertex i and you match to jane b
and then you just check well if there is an edge here
you've got to have an edge there is one
so define it this way
and you can see that if i have twice the same graph
then well this function here
it will be
if i find exact match
and once you're if it's larger than that so you can clearly see that this
will give you an exact match if you wanted to
travis is an NP hard problem to solve
so what to do
and people have used lots of
algorithms for that so for instance one of the more famous ones
is the credit assignment algorithm of
gold and rangarajan
so this is really famous in computer vision at least
it basically relies on the sinkhorn
methods in the middle
what it does is actually something that he would say well
cheating but i mean
this is an area where will people really desperate
people are really desperate you see it for from the fact that actually genetic algorithm
and taboo search
are some of the basic methods to solve quadratic assignment
but they have a particular versions against them but this is usually indication that people
are really hopeless
or and colony system or anything else that's really desperately heuristic
people use those things for quadratic assignment
so in other words by saying well hey i reduce the problem to credit assignment
problem that's not really gain anything i just said well hey this problem is so
even if i get enough statistics and so on i will probably not be able
to get a fairly good solution
it is the sum and well it works the same chimney sweep things under the
you just perform a first order taylor approximation of the credit assignment problem
they take derivative of the quadratic term with respect to the permutation
and then use all
la the
the first order approximations such as the immunization
they take a small step in that direction
nicky penetrating
actually the
credit assignment as a few other hacky things on the way but that's basically what
it does
you can find semidefinite relaxations
he said you get big problem because you see it order of four
in terms of storage
and what's worse
order of six in terms of computation
so again semidefinite programs
usually people
and let's exactly called boyd and vandenberghe don't really solve problems of size larger than
most people
we'll stop at anything between one hundred and maybe five hundred
just because it's very hard
and if you want to go beyond that you need to do serious extr
so in practice
if you use credit assignment you can only really solve problems of size may be
less than one hundred nodes
some of the better benchmark collections i think they have like thirty forty nodes and
that's where people are able to solve things are optimally
so it's a serious problem
in other words
quadratic assignment would be really nice if it were solvable but since it isn't
we probably don't want to go there
what went wrong
well what went wrong is that we actually spent a lot of time now discussing
how are we going to solve a given problem
but not much time on
how they actually got to the problem