now my pleasure to introduce you miller from carnegie mellon
thanks very much for a
thank you
thank you for inviting me to give the talk
so hopefully this will be understandable so again please ask questions this workshop
so today what i'd like to talk about is this area which is called
now spectral graph theory right is the idea that you think about graph is the
matrix and looking outside investors into using matrix of the graph
and graph theory to the matrix OK and particular going to look at questions about
how do you quickly solve linear systems
and again that's going to reduce to graph graph questions and we also show applications
where we used spectral graph theory to solve some of these questions
so far the simplest of all constraints systems that has been around for hundreds of
years is the notion of a linear system and this is very fundamental in all
the workers everyone every talk have seen so far under the hood somewhere solving linear
systems so it's critical to be able to solve these these systems quickly
so it's obvious thing to do is write is the matrix i guess it's interesting
point i believe that gauss did not understand this notation so that's one of the
reasons i have never been able to read a lot of his original work that
he didn't know about matrices with much later discovered but very
the beautiful way to think of the world rise matrices
so what's interesting is that is theoretically anyway if you want to solve dense matrices
you can do that and q time stress then showed how to do that and
the two point eight and then time and improved most of the centre course way
too large for the kind of system we'd like to solve today
and so it's still a very big number right
so what's interesting is that is not if it's just general sparse system we don't
have a better theory worst case analysis to say much better bounds
so there are easy cases for the simplest of all these cases the upper triangular
lower triangular we can do back substitution and when we do this then we get
to solve the number of nonzero right so the goal one goal then would be
to find a bunch of other
linear systems all of which we can then solve as fast as we can solve
an upper triangular system
offensive that's our goal
so the first obvious constraint people put on that symmetric so throughout the rest of
this talk them with some matrix system that is symmetric
army corps is the graph that means our graph is undirected
it be nice to get rid of this constraint i don't how
tonight but anyway so i'll use that
so another assumption throughout this talk is going to be the start with positive definite
right namely that all the eigen values values are
it strictly positive or that
the rayleigh quotient is always positive
so the first approach that people started doing i guess i just decided to do
a history of some of the standard computer science literature and solving systems that selected
direct methods gauss elimination this is still a matter to be uniform if you only
have a few thousand variables so that's where we're going to start because in fact
what happens in all modern systems is what you're going to do that is to
reduce the problem to smaller size in this in this fall size goes below a
certain level you're going to go to whatever the method that best for that size
in particular
let's look at the direct OK so in the seventies
graph theoretic interpretation gauss elimination was popularized probably was known before that but that's what
you do is the view every nonzero off diagonal edge
value is undirected edge
you view pivoting as a graph operation OK
so in particular what is pivoting for
from the graph theoretic point of view is you have some brass free original matrix
and you have a vertex and you'd like to pivot on the vertex so what
you end up doing is you make a clique out of the neighborhood of that
you then remove the that vertex and its edges from the graph and you repeat
until you have eliminated the graph
come up heads or tails that's the thing you have to learn
but given m trials
and we observe x successes x times the coin came up heads we can estimate
the probability is x and there's very nice found very standard testing downstream of found
things that say
how many times you have to flip a coin before this estimate this empirical estimate
is really close with high probability to the true value
so this is this you can you can think of this as a quick learning
algorithm in that somebody gives you coin you have to predict what's the probability comes
up heads and you have to be right
there were said no but only no smaller times
so we can quickly is probably by just saying i don't know
up until we've flipped it enough times that this bound kicks in and we can
be epsilon accurate with high probability
so quickly learning the point is no big deal people know how to do this
this is the standard building block
but the things in addition to the coin probability that we can quickly and so
we anything that we can quickly learn we can learn
the hypothesis class that says that the output is
the output of some quick learners
so so what to well in this in particular case you can think of it
as being that the dice learning problem so imagine that we're going to try to
estimate that instead of always calling we've already died then we're gonna roll it it
comes up one two three four five or six with unknown probabilities well we can
treat them that as being six separate points
and what we're doing is on each trial predicting the output of each of those
points simultaneously so
so we can quickly to the queen probabilities and what this is saying is that
if we have a vector of something that we can quickly learn then we can
quickly that hold back to
so we could do dice learning is actually better ways of doing it and thinking
of it is bunch of coins but that's one concrete example here another one is
a forum for learning a map from some input space to some output space
and the input is partitioned into regions where each of those is kwik learnable
then we can quickly in the whole space and that's a really easy result as
well it just says that we run a separate quick learner for each of the
partitions of the input
and then when it comes in we just as the corresponding one for the answer
so that's
this seems sort of two
simple to be worth mentioning but combined this and that the coin probability and you
can learn a standard transition function in an MDP because what is the transition function
it's mapping the state the choice to stay in the choice of action that bus
of the input space into into n times k separate problems to learn in each
of those you have to learn the vector of probabilities which are the state transition
probabilities to each possible next each of those values itself is just bernoulli trials
by combining these three levels which can actually quickly learn entire transition function and therefore
quick we can we can solve report learning problems efficiently in this in this
flat setting where each state action pair is considered to be a separate problem so
the hand
now when you see cardinality
it's like the partitions of the input space that was partitions here
we don't have the numbers state
this was
i see i see
and we want to bound grows with unknown number of states say yes these these
algorithms do that as well they
ten not actually need to know necessarily the number of states
but they behave well with respect to what the number of states actually is the
the other question is what are you talking about known input partition what if it's
unknown what if i want to state act act like each other but we don't
know which ones we have to discover which one is correct which i will get
to that
but this is kind of the the lowest level basic is just a regular MDP
the way bellman talked about them we can now efficiently learn in that setting how
to behave with unknown initially unknown transition and reward functions
i think
so if it were
OK so so if if we have a deterministic system where you can actually choose
you know when you take an action always goes to the same next state exploring
that graph getting the same kind of bounds is easy you just get his basically
like that for sir thomas you just go to any any transition have visited yet
you try which the reason that this isn't just completely trivial
is in the MDP setting there's probabilities involved it may be hard to get yourself
to state to learn about it
so you can't really just reason about saying OK we'll just i can quickly visit
all the states and learn about all the states because you can't force yourself to
a can put itself in interstate necessarily
so you need you need more
flexible notion of what optimality means they can account for the case where
maybe the state you can get two or maybe can only get away with really
low probability
you don't count that against the learner
that that's the question about his
where it is
this is
it is the
what i
so so the question is what happens if you say there are parts of the
state space that are very very difficult to learn it's not the right sort of
rapidly mixing markov chain kind of situation and that's OK these these results will still
apply they tell us that the stuff that we do get too often enough we're
get a we're getting high reward if things are very hard to get to there
may be very high we were there but it can have a big impact on
our expected value
because it's very hard to get there
so the reward those are the sorts of issues that make the analysis tricky but
think the top of story things are actually sort of nice and clean as long
as we can quickly learn the transition function how horrible the state space is we
get higher would with high probability with only a polynomial number mistakes
OK so idea that these particular mention is quite notable classes because it gets up
to transition probabilities there are the sort of things the union of two kwik learnable
classes kwik learnable
now mentioned a couple others as we go
all right so just in case
there were too many of songs and dances from it here's here's video of robot
again this is not the robot in our lab is trapped in a four sided
box but there's a door one side has to escape through the door to door
over here you can see it
and it's got there's that or it's got forward backward left right slide last slide
right next step without turning left and right which have to be important not get
stuck with your shoulder on the door it's if we describe discretize the state space
into four thousand fifty states and the number of positions and orientations and then give
one of these models base learners this armax words quick learning the transition probabilities
to the system to learn it can actually learn this fairly effectively and the dog
can escape from the box all is well in this case the dog is being
tracked you can see it's got a little green
the raspberry beret here in green park and those are being tracked from above mounted
camera so that's how it knows where it is
so you know they can make it work
but i think it's a natural thing to say this point as well
it's growing with the size of the state space if you have to learn about
all the states in the environment most problems that we're thinking about the we care
about have a very large number of states
if we really view each of the states completely independent this transition knowledge doesn't transfer
learning is going to be really slow
these algorithms can actually even the really smart ones can do really stupid things under
then you can again write that as an integral representation form
so you can see what these what the underlying theme here is the underlying theme is that we
if we want to do
bayesian modeling and we want to
we need a conditional independence like this to justify
this assumption that we have
that we have an independent random this part and some form of common information joint information that we can extract
by statistical inference right
and we need some kind of
so and the way we can get that is
by looking at some form of invariance in this case and the permutations
and then finding a representation like this
i can tell you it's not easy to find these representations but fortunately probabilities are
doing all the work for us now so we don't actually have to do it
there's a whole bunch of these
these theorems already around that we can use four different types of data and so if we have
based sequences of points and we have definitive theorem
if we have
if we have sequences in the sense of time series
which in some sense evolve over time
that's the
here by diaconis and freedman which says that
such sequences under certain invariance condition on mixtures of markov chains right
here we have mixtures of eighty sequences and mixtures
change because here we have a markov chains
the case of partitions we have here making and which says we have
this a copy books partition that is working and call them but it's basically sampling from these cluster weights
if we um
if you want to look at graphs are
and then then there is also a theorem this is actually more generally applicable to
erase and the idea was racist
you think of you can think of a graph as a matrix right has the adjacency matrix
and now you can think of making this matrix
which is a two way array you can make that a three way array and so on yeah
okay end
and just to
to close up this topic there's the there's kind of like
the underlying
mathematical theory which is the theory of regarding decompositions and this is
really one of the most in my opinion one of the most
stunningly beautiful topics in probability
and what it basically gives you is
you have those are the basic the basic common theme is
you have a probability measure
and it has invariance property that was what we saw was exchangeability you different forms
of exchangeability of partitions on graphs and so on
it can be expressed as exchangeability by saying is invariant under permutations
permutations are group
in mathematical terms
and there's a lot of groups
and what these groups what groups press expressed in mathematics of different forms of symmetry
so we have a permutation invariance which is a form of symmetry you can have
rotation invariance which is spatial symmetry and so on and so forth
thee the basic theme is you have a probability distribution
end it is invariant under some form of symmetry
which is formalized by a group and that gives you an integral decomposition
it's truly awesome okay
so much for their
so this is like
basically if we want to construct new bayesian models on new types of data
four for a given type of data we first have to
solve some
fundamental questions before we can really start modelling was designing specific models
but we don't have to do this over and over again for each model we want to design right
just have to do this once more this time after graphs of all permutations
four four partitions and so on
okay after
after all this applied topics let me get a something more theoretical
all right so
well i've talked about so far
different forms of modeling right modeling end a little bit yesterday about applications
and there are some
there's a different line of work
that that's happening in in mathematical statistics
great don't ask the question
how can we build new models but rather ask if before the models that we already have
how they behave
and and what statisticians always want to know is if i if i see more and more samples
that's a model how quickly doesn't converge to the right parameter values right how how
quickly can i how much data do i need to estimate my parameters in order
to get a good
good posterior
about the last ten years some
very good mathematical statisticians have started to applying this idea that are rather ask this question about bayesian nonparametric models
using logistic units
but with this gaussian model of the pixels
on small colour images
and you can't see a thing unless we turn the lights turned can we just
turn the lights off for this one thing?
OK what you can see is
when we train on a million color images
each of which is three 32 by 32, just the RGB
we take those weights, so we've got three sets of 32 by 32 weights,
and we display them by treating those three sets of weights from a binary hidden unit
as the RGB channels
and what you notice is that almost all of them
are completely uncoloured, which means they have exactly balanced weights to the r g and
b channels
in other words they deliberately learned not to be color-tuned,
and they tried very hard not to be color-tuned
and they're all the high frequency ones
and then there's complete separation, almost complete
and there's a few non color-tuned
low frequency ones
but basically it's high-frequency non color-tuned
and then low-frequency color tuned,
and they're
they're basically two colours
they're sort of purple green just because of the funny
colour balance here. they're purple green
and red blue
actually, no, they're
that's, that's an odd one. that's is the other color you get. you get purple green and you get
sort of yellow
and these are low frequency
so that's really weird because the human visual system's like that. you've got low frequency
things and high-frequency black-and-white things
and it's an efficient way to do business
jpeg in fact uses ideas like this to do compression. but this isn't to do
with jpeg artifacts.
but it's there in the data, right? what this is saying is in the data
from the visual world
there's lots of evidence for
high frequency edges that don't have any colour contrast
and i think that's internal edges in an object
like sort of folds in my cheek. the colour of the surface is the same
both sides
because illumination hasn't changed and the material hasn't changed
of course, in an occluding image,
there's different colors on either side
but there's something about the data that says this is a really good idea
and the colour you would handle in a low frequency channel
but the main thing is to show this learns nice filters.
now i want to go on to
can you remember which ones to do?
was it?
now i want to talk about
these deep belief net ideas
with ideas about
gaussian processes
that's a sort of kernel method for doing regression
deep belief nets do
really well when most of data's unlabelled, because they can learn these layers of
features without needing labels
they can learn appropriate features that are going to be good for discrimination
because they've learned how to get the stuff, and then all we have to do is get from
the stuff to the labels,
uses fine tuning.
if you take gaussian processes and you're
naive about them because you don't really believe in them, then
they don't scale very well
but they're very good if you don't have much data, much labelled data
and they're very good at not seeing--not seeing structure where there's noise
so you can combine the two
what we do is we learn deep belief nets
using no labels
then we take
the top level of features
and we apply a gaussian process to it, try and predict the labels
and that already does much better than
just applying the gaussian process to the raw data
'cause we made use of all this unlabelled data, we get nice features
but then
even though gaussian processes are slow, if we don't have much labelled data, we can back propagate derivatives through
the deep belief net
so what you're doing is now learning a much better kernel for the gaussian process.
that involves a lot of iterations of the gaussian process, but if you don't have
much labelled data that's fine
so this is really good for the regime of lots of unlabeled data and very
little labelled data and doing regression
so here's the example that rus did
you take a patch of a face that might--and you're trying to figure out what orientation it's
you learn
gaussian units here
binary units here, learn an RBM
take this as data for learning the next RBM, take this as data for the next
RBM, so we've learned one two three layers of a thousand features
then stick it all together
and apply GP on top that's trying to predict the orientation of the face
OK, rus tried various things. i--fairly sure it's just--it's the
negative squared exponential
just so as not to be confusing
the exponential of minus x squared.
so here's what
training data looks like
here's the orientations of these face patches
unlabeled test data
no, here's unlabeled training cases, and then here's the test data
and he tries three different under numbers of labelled cases. when you get to about a
thousand, the gaussian process is labouring
because you have to do it many times
because you want a derivative from it
and here's the results
if you apply a gaussian process to the raw pixels
you get 22% error--22% mean squared error because it's regression--with hundred labels,
and sixteen percent with a thousand labels
with only a hundred labels i can beat this
over here
you apply the GP
on top of this deep network
and you also back propagate derivatives from the GP to fine-tune the kernel
and so you get something with a hundred labels that's better than what you got here
with a thousand labels
alternatively you can get something which has
much less than half the error
mean squared error
was that people got
confused even even skilled programmers
we're confused when they had to
so class
things to in order to use the software the logic programming
this is something that people are familiar with
but it's
it's still not completely obvious it's still it's still of kernel
the users of software would prefer not to have to
to go over just said
some software music this was the least my experience
in the in the
early nineties
i think that's still the case of this something to them
i left school and worked excite for three years
running the writing software there was originally written by another fellow not taken over early
it was the indexing here was actually performed pretty well was based purely on on
merging of indexes you may make indexes in memory writing to disk
and then you when you start the process of hierarchically merging indexes into larger indexes
looks like we we have four levels of merging with fixed that process
you can skip a lot of this
we got to be a fairly large collection for the day
and for a while we were the largest search engine on the web at the
at the picnic site had two hundred fifty million pages indexed
and was i i think around and i forget exactly
what the traffic volume ones
and it was always one of these
secrets not supposed to talk about
so i don't have anything written down anywhere about
traffic but it was around a thousand miles per second at peak of the data
so things i learned here was that
merging indexes
it's something that
scales very well
i also learned that
writing software that runs on the server is is a very nice
way to develop software as opposed to writing software that
people then installed on their on their
the computers and you have to maintain installations in the field in lots of different
environments if you can control the environment that is delivered on and even in solid
yourself in the
i mean it's much easier to do new releases daily or weekly
as often as you like
and you can also have
a good sense of what the what's hardware platform is going to be on and
therefore guaranteed certain performance properties
and so that was that was really nice is first someone worked on server side
and most preferred that lovely me to focus on things i was interested in c
plus plus
really fragile we have a lot of problems a lot of reliability problems when we're
doing rapid development using c plus plus
and i actually started while i was still working excite working job and that that
say there's a lot of thought has also worked work very well as a replacement
the last lesson that i learned excite was that
when the company went bankrupt
in figure around two thousand one out business all the software that was written there
and there was a lot was in early
fairly large company that live for
six or so years
it's gone
was it's
owned by some someone is the result of some bankruptcy-court proceedings but legally no one
but i know i can access the software it's disappeared effectively from from the face
of the earth which is
so i mean we
now if you think of software has written knowledge we this sort of stuff that
we keep it
libraries universities history may may not be great literature but
it is something that we would typically
i don't like the throwaway stuff like that the people who worked hard to create
and yet
in this context
proprietary software can simply disappear
and not everything that was worked on their effectively harnessed
i'm going to digress
before i come back to
the seen
i mentioned several times this issue of
index merging
and i one i want to go into this little more detail it's sort of
basic computer science
but it's it's a confusion a lot of people
seem to seem to make the trees are the
building block of
relational databases primarily
that's that's that's so the
well as far as i know every major relational database at its core is is
using the trees for four indexes on the table
it's a it's a very useful data structure
it in general case
requires login
six or access for either read or write
but in general you can optimize things so you only have to do one seek
to right
it and
if you
take advantage of axes and new for them and sort then you can actually
go optimizing things somewhat more
so the only access each page once per update so the two works as this
top level index is a simplified version of it to little bit rate
it tells you that everything
the before g
is over here
between GNO is here
between o and use over here
so the the top level things so you divide things up and
works because we see how blocks of data we do you see the disk your
block of data
but the problem is that you can actually build the tree
and then sorted accesses and go through and by access in sequential order but over
time you have to end up serving as as work is getting started inserting another
page between here
and you'll end up setting another one in here
and a new chapel things around i'm going to go into too much detail but
that's like
and the most popular
actually the most popular features
texture features used
also have a special way
special kind of
we can make it possible to be like mother like and we can think about
he was
one of the ways
and like can
that year
five which is not right
the presentation
we so
you see that
there is no
he was the
while the full scale so
as before
when we change the parameters have differing functions
which is actually composed of bank
so for every value
this problem one see one for in this particular case we have
we don't
which it was
he that
and the way
somewhere in just of before
that's the way sections
actually the same idea from
and you want changes very
independent component internet so this also
a kind of the competition but instead of looking at the data
that way we do could
big problem
which i think the real images
by one
depend on one another
we know a lot of pages of some images
and we try to understand what the
the same way that this image is it
so tried to
i really like
article which is
so we
try to find the most independent
this debate we have
you waited
this training
when we have the
bank of that they can do exactly the same so we
two pages
we can it
and was
well a picture no single energy but he
of the responses so that for example and
so the result in histogram
and and we know where you ever there
it's a
which is one of the image of the particle
using all but
division actually to measure
the five
this between two images you simply like just south
o barkley individual
all right
the application
so does
the result
development which
i don't have to be able to measure
the the
so i
so you can see why
independent of
so there is no such as like that
this one
to the book to describes
in the right direction
which is to try to class high
that particular direction
and i think for just
when wiring
a straight line like horizontal and vertical
i this was very
on the
for this one
you want to test that this is why it often a better strategies
to use random search so random search instead of specifying a finite
number of values for each hyperparameter
you specify some distribution over some range
for the hyperparameters maybe the number
of hidden layer could be just a uniform distribution over one two
and three but for the learning rate maybe
i would have some log uniform distribution
over some range and then i specify a in advance instead of obtaining
from these choices a number expense any to run i can also separately
determine how many experiments of i'm going to run how many configurations
hyperparameter i'm going to use run a grid in this and with these
choices and then ultimately compare between experiments
and to get a configuration you just sample independently
from each distribution for each parameter run that experiment
and then report the number of validation and store that for all
my experiments so what's really nice about this is that there's no
relationship between the distribution you choose for the potential
values hyperparameters and the number of experiments you have to
do to sort of completely explore the space sufficiently explore
the space one in to like one particularly back case for grid search
is that if for one and that's often typical of the learning rate
for one choice of the value of say the learning rate
you for some reason get very bad results so
that is quite typical the learning rate if it's too high a
the training might divergen give you a very bad results
no matter what other choices of values with the other parameters
you've made so that means you've wasted a whole lot of experiments
because you have a big chunk of experiments that are
committing to this one choice of the parameter for the learning
rate whereas in this case all hyperparameter are chosen independent
the across all experiments so less likely to be
a victim of this that situation and there are
us smarter ways of also doing exploration hyperparameters
there's a whole field on vision of the zation or sequential model-based
optimization where which are trying to do here is
actually have a model whose job is to learn a relationship between
values of your hyperparameters and some prediction on what would
be the performance on the validation set
so if you doing experiments iteratively
you can imagine i can use previous experiments to orient what
kind of values on try out for my x experiments
in fact as people doing research this is exactly where we
do we often even in the random search case you do a bunch of experiments
will be noticed that it seems like maybe you know the maximum value
was allowing for some hyperparameter was too small i'm
going to increase it there's still some iterative procedure area
in this model explore version-space
and vision optimization or sequential base optimization
is trying to automate this and make this you know
machine learnable i'm going to tell you do this but that you should
be aware that this is another approach that can be better
ok so yeah yes yes
yes so so i guess the question is you know if you have a model making
predictions s to try to model the relationship between hyperparameters
selection choices and the prediction well doesn't that models
have hyperparameters for which you need to select hyperparameters
and that you know yet stack overflow essentially
so in this case it it actually is a really good motivation for the
asian approach of machine learning because in this case you
can try to integrate your uncertainty over the hyperparameters
of this model making predictions of what could be good
choices hyperparameters and this is partly why yes some a lot
of literature is actually using gaussian processes
for which you can actually put priors on
the hyperparameters of that gaussian process and try to integrate
that uncertainty and there has been problems gaussian processes
that are not superscalar also if you do a lot of experiments you're
going to have a large training set of
validation set hyperparameters and performance and then beige neural
nets can be then like an alternative again to be visions or
integrate over some of the uncertainty in your
choices hyperparameters there's another reason why the beijing cases
convenient here is that typically you don't just want a prediction
of what you think the expected performance is going to be but you
want to notion of uncertainty over what's your i guess
confidence interval over the range of values you would expect
so just the expectation is not as useful as also getting a full
distribution on that conditional distribution
because if you you think the expectation is fairly
bad but there's a lot of variance might still be worth exploring
so that's another motivation for using a gaussian or
the patient approach here but you do have to be careful you could
imagine maybe training a a model that performs hyperparameters
selection and over multiple problems and there's
work on using multitask vision optimization which tries to justice
so there are solutions but it's true you have to be careful about
that yeah yes
yeah it's so this is something people do quite a bit in practice
so the question is should do what makes sense to start by just
tuning the learning rate keeping everything else fixed
and what you did that maybe move on other hyperparameters and
that is indeed like strategy people use quite a bit
in practice because indeed it tends to be one of the most
influential hyperparameter within all
hyperparameters that's definitely a good
thing to do in practice yeah and are actually
i'm going to cover a partial some of them are algorithms that
are fairly rule more more robust to the choices of the learning
rate because they have effectively adaptive learning rate
that might be other solution to rely such optimizers instead
other questions
a think might be were not superfine earlier with that literature
the one of the one of the things that makes genetic algorithms
to be less interesting is that typically here you don't want to
run like thousands and thousands of experiments
and one nice property of things like vision optimization sequential
model-based optimization is that
there are usually considered as approaches that's
require fewer guesses to eventually find a good solution to
your problem whereas depending on you set up your genetic algorithm
it might make a lot more while guesses
in terms of which hyperparameters to try out
so that would be my you know warning about using such an approach
in setting but there might be good i'm that first into
these algorithms so there that could be
interesting approach in certain yeah situation
i mean yeah this requires a pheromone of like you know you need
to implement that's so that's pretty good like vision optimization
for the first experiments you're going to do
is not going to do much better than random search
and so it might be for certain problems are of fairmount of hyperparameters
are good enough but this is a good direction to explore if you
so let me remind you of the program which and I believe these look at
the slides are on the web if people checked and they're not there please let me know
first day I talked about up a little bit about observations of the universe yesterday
I talked about inflation today in the third room of the lecture I will
talk about dark matter and tomorrow we hear also alright so two days in a  row
in the same room I don't know how that is going to work so
this is the cosmic pizza that you've seen every day and I'm finish for a
while talking about the things we see and  now I`ll talk about the things we don't see
about dark matter the I believe the simplest evidence for dark matter comes from looking
at rotation curves of spiral galaxies this is a procedure is a technique that
was pioneered in the late sixties and up through the middle seventies by Vera Rubin
who is also continues to be involved in this subject and I think that a
one day she will be remembered as the person who really brought dark matter into the
public consciousness at least the consciousness of physics physicists really the evidence that it exist
so what she did in in the early seventies is start on a program
of measuring the rotation curves of galaxies so this is an example of her data
she`s looks at a nearby galaxy m thirty-three so a couple of megaparsec away and
by combinations of various techniques she can measure the rotation curves either of stars the rotational
velocity of some objects about the center of the galaxy either stars or in the outer
parts of the galaxy where there's hydrogen you can measure the redshift or blueshift
of twenty of the twenty-one centimetre emission and so she plots the rotation curve here in
given in kilometers per second as a function of distance from the center of the galaxy
and to orient to about sizes of a galaxy we are in the Milky Way
about eight point five kiloparsec from the center of the galaxy
a parsec in the secret language of astronomy is three point two six light years
so sort of this size is a visible parts of galaxies or
the size of a galaxy is a little bit arbitrary to define but eight ten or so
kiloparsec is a good picture so this is the observations of the rotation
curve as a function of radius and you can try to model the rotation curve
as a function of radius that you would expect just on the basis of the
stars that you see of the light that you see with the idea that there`s where
there is more light there's more mass and this is what's expected when you go
out to the out of regions of the galaxy where there is not very much mass
interior to this circu interior to the orbit you would expect the rotational
velocity decreases radius as Kepler's third law right this isn`t rocket science it's Kepler's third law
so this is what would be expected on the basis of what is seen
in terms of the stars and this is absurd and the observations of the
rotation curves generally at large distance or flat they do not decrease as you would
expect on the basis of Kepler's laws it's not just our galaxy or m thirty-one
or m thirty-three or andromeda when we look at many many many spiral galaxies we see
the same type of behavior that most of the rotation curves increased reach a maximum
bounce around here but out here the rotation becomes flat and this is evidence that
most of the mass is not in the form of stars this is a remarkable
result in again we need other conferring observations before we really believe this remarkable
result and one confirming observation comes from gravitational lensing a gravitational lensing is based upon
the idea in Einstein's theory of gravity the light path is modified by the
existence of a massive object and back in the nineteen-twenties and nineteen-thirties Einstein
and    worked out the distortion to an image that would be caused by a massive
object known as a gravitational lens so this is an example of having a source
a of distance source and having a gravitational lens in this case along the
exactly the optical axis so if we imagine we're in the lucky situation where we
have an observer here in Geneva looking at a source and exactly on the optical
axis is a gravitational lens and if you do a simple calculation assuming point like
source point light lenss exactly on the optical axis what you discover is that the
image you would see would not be deployed like source but would be a ring
of actually of infinite surface brightness and by measuring the this is known
as the Einstein ring and by measuring the radius of the Einstein ring you can deduce
the mass of the lensing object so in real life we do not have
exactly point like lenses we do not have exactly point light sources and we
never find something exactly on the optical axis but we do observe gravity lensing
we do observe Einstein's ring in strong lensing so this is an image taken by
the Hubble Space Telescope of a cluster of galaxies Abel twenty-two eighteen it was fifty years ago
that George Abel put together his cluster excuse me his catalog of
galaxy clusters this is a two thousand two hundred and eighty entry in that catalog and
this is you can see the cluster of galaxies and what you can make
out with the exquisite resolution of the space telescope is the objects that are distorted so
these objects or images that are behind the cluster of galaxies and it's not perfectly
on the optical axis as you can see the lens is not a perfect point
source so it's not a perfect ring but it forms art and by
deducing the properties of the ox or the radius of the Einstein ring you can deduce
the mass of the cluster of galaxies and again you come to the conclusion that
there is a much more mass associated with galaxies and clusters of galaxies then you
how does the space of all possible choices that you could get look
let me just she tried to figure out what i'm going to say
right so
what's true about this set is
in the case of trees wire trees easy
trees are easy because this is the deep fact i'm not going to be able
to go into it but it turns out for trees if you just impose the
obvious constraints if you just impose the marginalisation constraints that they should collapse down to
and also the normalisation constraints that that somebody else mentioned so those are very local
and obvious constraints so easy to enforce
that's enough that's all that you need so you only need to do local consistency
operations on the tree
and if you do local consistency you'll get global consistency
this is sort of the essence of something known as the junction tree theorem which
i'm not going to go into but it's it's a general technique for understanding how
trees behave
right so
what's nice about trees is that the obvious thing to do is the correct thing
to do
that's not always the case in life right off the obvious thing you do this
sort of greedy algorithm or the dumb algorithm
not the best thing to do but somehow trees life is good
easy thing local thing is the correct thing
i'm not going to derive this but sort of giving you the intuitions what you
can show is that you have a constraint here and for this direction of the
edges you have a constraint for every value that acts of s can take
so what you do when you derive max product is an algorithm for solving the
LP is you put all the grounds multiplayer
one of them let's call lambda as of access one of them for every constraint
and so have
a vector of multipliers that sort of flow from node t to note as
and that vector multipliers is exactly like the log of the messages
so if you work through the derivation and you have to use some duality see
here theory here things that live and probably would have mentioned if you work through
the the details but you'll find our work to it later for the sum product
algorithm you find that the lagrange multipliers exactly enforcing this constraint the messages are lagrange
right so this gives us another view it gives us to view the
what the max product algorithm is doing on a tree or on a chain or
what the viterbi algorithm is doing its solving a linear programme and it's a very
efficient way of solving a linear programme
OK so the reason that i went into this i mean what we've learned
essentially we just learned a rather different perspective on why trees are easy
trees are easy because
these marginal distributions are easy to characterize that's that's what we've learned
but this gives us a way of understanding what is max product doing when we
apply to graphs with cycles
well will see max product is not actually doing what we'd like it to do
but we'll see how we can modify it to do good thing
and this leads to what are known as convexified forms of max product these are
algorithms that are actually solving linear programming relaxation so they have some exact guarantees the
max product does not have on general graphs with cycles
during the
so here
OK so
this is the probability distribution and for a discrete probability distribution by definition of expectation
if i sort of
take whatever function
i weighted by the probabilities and i sum over everything
that's the the definition of an expectation for discrete thing so i'm just using either
q is a shorthand for saying i'm just taking expectations under that distribution
oh sorry i see this yes OK that was your question yes sorry the squiggly
brackets everything in here is the china expectations including the some yes
sure so
the sums it came back
initially had some over the vertices and the sum over the edges
right that was my cost function my or loss function my l
so it decomposed across the grass so it sums over vertices and edges
i introduced an additional sum over x when i did my expectations
the l
so i bl includes everything here l my entire cost function so this l includes
that some and that some so when i come down here and i break l
out again i get back the two sums that i had four vertices and three
OK so you can read the proof of this in in the book with mike
jordan or
proof sketch perhaps
the junction tree theorem is covered in the introductory lectures
what i'd like to sort of do duties to continue building intuition is we sort
of said that these are exact for tree
they must not be exact for graphs with cycles because we know somehow that you
know graphs with cycles are hard
if we think about the problem that we're trying to solve but down over three
variables so it is easy whatever you do
but in general if you have an variables
and you don't have the tree this is conclusive very broad class of problems includes
many problems that are known to be NP complete things like the max cut problem
on the graph
many kinds of satisfiability problems case at three SAT maxsat all of these are a
special case is not exactly of this but of
graphical models so there's no way we can expect that we're going to get a
sort of generic solution on any any graph with cycles
so we sort of have to understand from this perspective whereas the complexity
the complexity lies exactly in in this step the trees it turned out there was
enough just to do this constraint but if you're the many you have even a
single cycle
then this is not sufficient anymore so let's let's try and explore that why is
it that cycles make our life difficult
OK so we're going to do is we're gonna play a little game
and you can sort of tell me whether you think
the this is valid what i'm doing
number of pieces of paper some from somebody just
one minus y
now i and replacing them with this expression here i have
it is the form of my solution
and then OK and then have x
so this is how
but this
OK now
let me get this right
i have all the
one minus
these guys here like by this
which is something we all
and there never remaining thing which is
but in this
and this
so the go away
in i get out of the
x is created
my my my nose
but is rare that x being spread it
i just think that this one and wrote way
so now
i know this is single
but critics at x
lots of and now i can write this
again because i'm making up the only one a lot of negative
i can write this as the hinge loss
o seventeen one
this is the wall around function or the
but still i have i have my
what's called friend
know if i e
so all i can now also for
and they get solution which is
but if it well
it's obvious
the effectiveness of people there are
get out of it was
l w
w b
minus one
by the by
x squared
now i to take into account also the addition
but can't get the a
i can write the update like like this
they can also that account so
WP one started that
but that you might not want blast it but
thing where it but
it but the minimal
if see
something like this
and that
that's the main one that
OK so
this is the
the four here
one one
this is a very simple so is just like modification on the on the solution
i mean i can just of musician
functions they can get an analytical solution
it depends again on the loss of the previous
OK now
and this is something and how do how can we go about line
the performance of
number this is something similar the because one but this using this different form of
one possibility is to exploit the quality
in the following way
so i start
so i go back to the
to the SVM functional
a given string of examples
so i have
in fact in the bit background
and then look at the
and then look at the full SVM function
what do i
do the same idea for the k case so i compute the URL
will look and function i'm not doing it so that the one show my ignorance
again but the just right
hoping i copied correctly
it is not
i mean i can write the the
now i one
so this is the one for and we can write it will you
for completeness
this is going to be equal to minus
my heart
the square of the sum of
x being read the
some over
under the constraint
box constant
i know
from what i think
i know that
optimal by the value of a descendant of the out that maximizes the likelihood function
equals the value of the primal objective
that could be a possible
much better do this morning but as you can see these two charts for property
for two different
so influential blog post and both of them have very different
comment reaction one has very spiky comments reaction
intuition you can always
i think that's very spiky comments reaction
could be
two of very influential blog post but on other NBC flat comments reaction to an
influential blog post as well
so this is not exactly very good differentiating between conventional and go
in this study you can see the different temporal patterns of influential bloggers
in the rows
or you can see
the of
by the months starting from february two thousand four january two thousand seven
and on the columns who have different influential bloggers who have been influential it's important
and the kind of media and shows the influence level
the darker the colour is the higher
the more influential so in this chart can observe long there are
different kinds of influential bloggers somewhere along all influential bloggers
like this
who has been quite influential belong to the same and some of them are
very short on order the average influential bloggers who have been influential for number of
the transient influential bloggers who have been selected for very small and then burgeoning influentials
i just started to become influential so depending on different different modelling applications you can
use these bloggers for different
OK so far we have
the addressed questions like all these
so influential bloggers are different from active bloggers on
what are the different types of bloggers but we haven't
that is the question how you can read this
this morning
the influential bloggers should we propose i created in french and art and specially when
you have no ground truth how we can find out these things
one obvious solution is to
use human so it again
as the people do
rank for audio findings and one the thing
but it involves a lot of cost effort and resources and beyond that it's not
always guaranteed to the
a evaluation
we need to think of something
very differently
it has to be are different alternate reference point for the ground truth in this
case we use another
the one website which is today
because all of these part content
everything is submitted and voted on by the digg community share discover bookmark and also
that part you visit big is a huge user base
we have a lot of collective is people for what they see and if
an article is really important problem keeps on acquiring another big score and it keeps
on getting problem
so the higher the digg score for a blog post is the more it is
blog post is not on the data that means that it's not like odd
it was not about symmetry
so you have this wonderful website digg as a reference point two
two modifications
the center for this experiment is
big record stop hundred blog posts
we have to find mention as well as five active bloggers
which we used to construct four categories
forty two of these four categories of bloggers
we collect top twenty blog posts from our model and compare them
but at the top the
so as you can see in this first stable
there are four categories of these bloggers influential active influential inactive non-intervention
active and so on
one influential and active bloggers the cell is one
you can see there are
seventeen o seventeen locals that overlapping between the top twenty blog post office
influential active as ants compared to the hundreds the blog posts
seven of the top twenty influential blog posts from influential and active bloggers fall on
the top and of the
similarly in this three you can see
only three of
the block top twenty blog posts some interactive bloggers
appearing in the opening of
if you compare this to an s three you can
make of that
being influential is more important than if you want more information
then you have
more likely to appear on they are more likely to be popular with the people
as compared to
being active
in the next two
charts me
give the
distribution for
one hundred
blog posts and big and the five thirty five blog posts collected from the unofficial
apple logo
so in this case if you compare this to stand here and it's too here
you can see around the
forty percent of
there are blog posts
on big big as compared to just six percent of
these dollars
this is quite significant and sticks
next we study the
that importance
what's the importance of these parameters in the morning
used up and the influential blog posts from our model and top twenty
blog was that appeared on their and then we tried to do and all that
house and try to compute the overlap between these two
not going to list
four six different months starting from january two thousand two
june two thousand seven
so again the sea use those five configurations
for all in no links no comments no planes and no blog post length
as you can see for all and then you have all the parameters in the
model that that's when you get the maximum water level
and when you remove all in links from the model that's when you get the
minimum overlap
and this is a bound on the amount of information we've lost
and we can bound in terms of
the some of the eigen values from k plus one up to all the
training samples so these are the
i can demands on the training set
their average size divided by one whatever and
some of the last k
and plus this
OK so the term here that is
really just related to the
the radius of the ball containing the data and has won over and
turns out that should be quite controllable the log one delta
and this term here
which has the rademacher flavour to it and it involves the square root of the
divided by the square root of n
plus this
sort of normal rademacher term which is roughly as well as well
because he got some of basically terms the bounded by r squared divided by and
this is roughly
sorry roughly square
OK so
what this is telling us is yes if we've got igon values that fall off
quite sharply
and we don't have to use too many dimensions
we are going to get a good representation of the data
so this is the kind of results were able to get
using this rademacher complexity what i wanted to do is try and show you how
we arrive at this result i wanted to motivate first results show you what we're
trying to achieve
it's slightly unusual to use statistical analysis for
analyzing essentially as unsupervised learning techniques it's slightly strange-looking but hopefully
i've given you a picture of what's going on the stage
so we can sort of think of it is in the sense learning the subspace
how well it would space is one way of doing it
so it does tell us i mean this is telling us i think stuff we
didn't know i mean we know from practice people applied kernel PCA we've seen it
work but it is telling us that actually there is
you know statistical reasons to believe why that's the sensible thing to do
provided that the
mention the production is significantly lower than the sample size
and the the igon values on the sample fall off reasonably sharply
here's an outline of the proof and
hopefully this
you know will will
you know make
i think this is nice tricks i think in here so
imagine what we can do with the data matrix x is now the data matrix
if we perform the singular value decomposition of the matrix
then the columns of u
are the eigen vectors in the feature space
of the correlation matrix
i want to verify that this
a lot of fairly straightforward show
and me
columns of the
the eigen vectors of the the kernel matrix of this
decomposition singular value decomposition actually size together
the kernel the i can that is the correlation matrix which is where we're projecting
and the i can by values of the
kernel matrix which gives the dual
what we can see is that when we project into the space of the that's
what we're actually doing
is taking five x and applying the matrix UK
that's the new is the matrix with the columns equal to the
i think that is UK is just taking the
matrix where we throw away
all but the first k columns of the matrix which is projected onto those
so that is computing the inner product and therefore the projection onto that
value and this is
reducing the
taking the norm of that we just take that times itself transpose
so this gives us the norm squared of that projection
that's how much data how much norm is captured by that
now we can write that
in the following way
because of the way the
let me just go back to the previous slide
because of the way this is written you can see that essentially
each element of this matrix UK UK primed
it corresponds to multiplication of five x i five jason take the i j entry
of this matrix
it is multiplied from the side by five excited by the side by five xj
so we can think of this as the sum
weights w i j
o five x i five x j
where the weight w i j is just the
i j th entry of the matrix new prime
UK UK prime
and the nice thing about this is we can this is actually the feature space
the features
corresponding to the
polynomial kernel of degree
where we take all pairs of features
of the base kernel
i'm going to call at phi that i have that i j if i
is the projection
into a feature space f
and w i j is indicated was the i j entry
and and so we can write this now as a linear function
in this
extended speak feature space
and this tells us that that is actually the feature space we're looking at
if i had of x y z in this feature space at
is given by the kernel
OK which is just the base kernel
and that's just basically this is just a rewrite of the standard polynomial kernel of
degree two construction
so essentially
very long standing issue in physics
and i will show you
i think the next week maybe after the exam
o young eighteen o one
conclusively demonstrated
that light
a way
so it looks like organs we're going to be the winner
on the other hand i showed you last lecture
light can behave
like particles
radiation pressure
that's particles
the whole thing
the whole ball of wax and so
maybe newton was right maybe they are particles
they both right
there are times that you can actually
interpret what you see best by assuming their ways
and that there are times that is much better to assume that they are particles
with mass like in the case of
the radiation pressure
but of course the key question now is was right in terms of the speed
of light
is the light going faster in water then
norton was right is the light
going slower in water
an organ was right needless to say that the dutchman was right
the speed of light in water is lower
then the speed of light
in air
when we arrived the
the speed of light
in vacuum
we use maxwell's equations
and they allowed us to
conclude that the speed of light
much to everyone's surprise
depends on that film zero and you zero
in a very simple way
i will call it for no v
that was one over
the square roots
of actually non-zero
zero and we call that c
if you had used maxwell's equations as they
valentin material
in dielectrics and also in materials that have magnetic properties
then it would be exactly the same derivation which you would have seen the cap
here the dielectric constant and you will see here
the magnetic permeability
car five
if you don't care
in glass and water
o is larger than one so you see from the view that the speed of
light and water is lower
than the speed of light in air
this can also be written as e divided by
the square root of kappa
divided by caplan and we will nowadays simply right c divided by and so the
index of refraction
it is really the square root
of the product of the dielectric constant
and the
magnetic permeability
no cap on
and cat out of a very strong functions of frequency
and that's not so surprising
because at very high frequency
the intrinsic electric enigmatic dipoles
which being aligned by the alternating external fields
i cannot follow quickly enough
if you want to drive them in this direction and wants to drive them back
and forth and back and there's just not enough time to do that
and so you expect that high frequencies
the values for kappa lower than at low frequencies which is exactly what you see
in the case of kappa and that's only important when you do with ferromagnetic materials
because is paramagnetic
and diamagnetic materials kappa
it is always one anyhow are very close to one
i have chosen
one as an example
to show you the dependence
kappa on the frequency
this on the web so you can download it and make yourself a copy
so if you look here is for water
you see there the
at low frequencies it's zero even at radio frequencies
at a hundred
a hundred megahertz this is radio
radio waves
notice that the dielectric constant in one is about eighty
at visible light the set frequencies of visible light it's way or
we just discussed that
the oscillations go too fast electric dipoles can follow it
and so the
the index of refraction then
radio waves hundreds
roughly nine and so to speak
of those ways in water is nine times lower than the
the speed of light in
call it speed of light but the speed of course of the radio waves and
and in the case of visible light
you see that visible light in water
this speed is only one point three times slower
then what it would be in air
or of course in vacuum
frequency effect
is very noticeable
if you take a red lights
and blue light they have different frequencies
and therefore the index of refraction is different
four red light
and blue light if i take water
numbers i'm going to give you
f of water
in that's of refraction for red light in water
is one point
three three one
but the index of refraction
four blue light
in water is one point three four three
we're going to use these numbers shortly
this is an asked to select
x days select the correct splitting
so that
collect sufficient statistics from a small set of examples
this debate many
it at
and i used often involved
two one and the best attribute is really
so the basic color
given the
the game
like to follow
one example
they statistics
next example and so on
thanks to barry
even with many of the test
thank you get caught to him
select the best two work through
and the phi
to get the difference and engage with both satisfies the offenbach
is expressed
so this means that
but they have used to to compute
featured the piece
it is
so if you use large enough
in favour two
this split that
so i can fix
so later on the cells inventory
we expand is
take into account the views
o point
the album create an example propagate through the three deal the example below it
they sufficient statistic
and and when
so that it's really
we the kind of a small dataset
yes statistics from a small
this is in part
these fine
in standard
the two classifier test examples
the example
that's the
from the field
and it is classified using the majority class
of the examples of the
so this means that
you are only using
it's not for me
probability of
in the FPT
we have a
the leaf
the thoughts much more information
they start information required by the splitting criteria
and the information required by splitting correctly
is most of the times of this form
of of setting class given
he was born
we have
lists we have also that information
so you can use
much more
if you strategies to classify
best example
that information
it's is exactly
the one that is required by the naive bayes classifier
that is
no need to model computation we have that information
we can classify example
and i five classifier it
only two
this is illustrative
using four
this is the four different number of examples
we are going to
millions and off
after million
and we compare
the standard approach classify majority class
in peru is using and i five classifier leave
and yellow
is c four point
c four five
standard that's classifier what kind of
is that you might find classifier
using ninety five forty five of ten
almost equivalent
two c four point five
much less disorder
that is before
live on characteristics of fifty years of
the first one
while standard decision to the last that season will
that is based on greedy decision
i have a lot of
two i variance
the FPT like health and
i could have low variance model
and most independent from the author of the examples
we don't have fitting in this type of all
basically we basically overfitting is
too much room for example
and this is due to
it's several pass over the training set
and in that case we process it examples
only one
but also
it's possible that mean prove proved that
the FDP
let's talk confirm
two to see season three that will be used in the late
using all
the information
here but i will explain it there
the black dots means that that is what is called a week density
the dn denotes the empty circles mean that is the only the strong station
so that means that the
d in the second but
creates attention that is immediately after it is it is resolved access when it comes
the second day of the the this CD right
in the second
it is called weak because it dissolve immediately
and this will strong
DS when it is of much later so depending on how how much time it
take to resolve is called strong or weak as w so all these that i
was finding u
is it is automatically inferred analyse by the system and is incorporated into the into
the case space associated to each of the nodes of the
one of the examples
so you can see here is a little bit of everything down here is the
score when they have this is the different notes which is the next which is
the underlying underlying caught any medical strength is is this is love mental has value
that has been with the GTTM theory
and belongs to a hundred and fifty so has been the parts of the using
the IRMA implicated anonymous system or theory we can we can deduce all this information
so all these is there in the case base and is ready to be taken
into account in order to figure out whether or not to
so phrases
the motives of music are similar
and obviously because we have is is the case which is the president we also
have the performance information so as you can see for each one of the five
expressive dimensions you have
the level of the value high and low high
very low density and in fact i understand explosive
so this a sequence of events are related to each which note to each node
there is a that is related
this is the overall picture no of how complex is the structure of the case
in this system of the complexity of the of this presentation is is one
what obliges us to to think of
new ways of new retrieval audience of the existing retrieval algorithms in in CBIR that
that the time
i couldn't deal with cities such a complicated situation
you cannot you don't have lead approximate values what you can compute some sort of
the euclidean distance or something like this some very simple distance he unit what is
what we call knowledge intensive retrieval and we see what a little bit about is
so what is knowledge adventure people
but before we provide some indexes in the system
and the index is provided by default in this case you can see in this
case is
not more part
so the first thing
two that the system those when you look for similar similar interpretation similar performances in
that case memory is to look for
now more patterns nodes that belong to the same monomer more as the node that
has to be decided how has to be this is also say how to play
OK so they would know the input problem
right this is an example if you have ideas on the left you can see
these motifs this race and the system has to decide has to four
how to play the this version of the b
seems by the followers system looks for
nodes that belong to people turns it leaves what you have here in the middle
it is all this budget information because it forms indeed note
that is the first note of the pattern
so this is the first step that the retrieval algorithm those
the system allows the user interface that the user can decide that instead of paying
attention first to fall two
the similarity between the the patterns could say no medical strength or ten of another
tends to ensure normalisation of the note or any other any other
aspect of the two theories of of music that we are dealing with
so but will be always provided by the full what we
what is our personal opinion believe it is it is more reasonable to do
but you know this is not enough because
OK then this first not is is the first to be but if by default
la what is important is is to look for nodes that belong to be patterns
in may find more than one if it finds one that's that's we have one
that's perfect obviously general it well it will find a bunch of them because there
are there are a huge number of
note in our memory right in the case memory
these are very simplified a simplified example of usually assume that it found only two
and what it came down to was
the top that
and combined the more general view
these kinds of large margin methods for structured prediction
combined with applications that i'm going to introduce
this talk is going to be about supervised learning
in a very
additional i mean
in the normal setting that everybody knows
so we have
data comes from the distribution of x y
given the sample
and here
just regular training example
when learning function that maps x to y so that some
with this loss function delta gets many
so from that perspective it's very standard
and we have a lot of methods for
no classification regression
to the supervised learning
what's going to be different in this talk was
not standard part is
considering these problems where
the prediction y
it is not just like a binary label multiclass label
but some structured and complex out
so both x and y will typically be some discrete object like a graph
what other types of problems that i'm thinking of so
for example
natural language parts right
that's the problem where
the prediction
is the tree
so the
given a sentence
like a sequence of words
we want to predict what the correct posture
and if you think about this it's not easy to break the problem down into
that's a multiple binary classification problem right
it's kind of hard to say
you know
the first words have you know phrase
because everything is connected everything depends first and eventually the whole thing up for grabs
so it's not clear how we could actually break down to binary classification problem
so here the prediction why is the tree
here's another problem
sequence alignment one of the kind of people techniques in bioinformatics i given two sequences
s and t
we want to predict is what's the correct alignment these two c
and here
well the prediction again is on the line and that depends on the output gap
here in align these two here then there are certain other
that are eliminated five
here's another one information retrieval
you want to predict the ranking
and so there are two reasons for why i think it's beneficial to think about
the structured prediction problem one is
typically in information retrieval we think about loss functions that are
and function of the ranking
for example average precision
is a typical loss function that people use performance measure the people use make people
really you can
every transition is not defined on kind of binary labels but in the final ranking
thirty one to
optimise performance measure we actually have to think about the problem of ranking
the second one is that
i would actually like to model the dependency between the results
in particular
we wouldn't want only present results that are
table SPM software here
it's only a very kind of narrow interpretation of re as the
so we actually want to among model dependencies and then becomes structured prediction problem or
i think the problem of noun phrase coreference resolution there
the problem is
given a set of noun phrases
predict equivalence classes of noun phrases that belong to that refer to the same entity
in the world
so essentially were predicting equivalence relationship here
so all of these problems where
we given
more less discrete or structured input but in particular were predicting structured output ranking an
equivalence relation three
and there are many many other problems as sequence labeling
collective classification multilabel classification
any kind of opposition non
linear performance measures
and also
like planning for inverse reinforcement all problems that fall into this category
what i want do in this talk is the following
on the
give an overview of
essentially an SVM style algorithm
four tackling all of these problems that i mentioned
and what this case this is kind of a general way of formulating these learning
this leads to
an optimisation problem
and i'm going to talk a little bit about training algorithms
guarantees for these algorithms
and then
outline how these
method for this framework can be applied to these applications that particular sequence alignment for
after prediction
the first application of retrieval results in the ranking
and to supervise
so predicting improvement
all right
why do i think this is an
important interesting line of research well
for these from any of these problems that mentioned for example the information which is
the problem i don't think we currently have
that solves the problem
this gives us a way of
learning problem
but some of the problems that have mentioned
methods already exist for example the noun phrase coreference resolution problem
people often do first pairwise classification
and then do of clustering
to come clean things up
and get an equivalence relation but that
can for complicated process right you have to get the classification right and then the
two things that clustering works well
much easier to just do that all of that one that
optimized things directly
we get other problems like the natural language parsing problem we already have enough to
this kind of one step
but in many cases they are generally
the hope is that
this kind of methods like the support vector machine or conditions like
will allow us to get better predictive performance for example
my experience from text classification
we went from naive bayes
well first i would like to thank the organisers
for this opportunity to actually to present some of my work on this very beautiful
framework of information geometry are has been pioneered by professor mary what i
going to do is
to start out from
bregman divergence i think this community is has a lot about and dan
trying to give a generalization
of bregman divergence which hopefully will give a deeper understanding about vision how it arises
and its connection to complex analysis in general
and that these two are kind of geometry
we call sort of hessian geometry which contains two flat space but has very nice
properties and then they're going to go into the infinite dimensional function space
trying to
work on the exact same kind of structure
that's present in international space
and finally i will give the fishing the metric the fisher metric and connection in
this information about space assuming topology now i think the high point of this
analysis is want clarify two kinds of
in information geometry one is a call kind of article called referential duality that is
to say
when you are doing comparison when you see captain the divergence
the point
or the function you use as the basis for comparison and the point of the
function you use as the comparing point the asymmetric but there's tool
relationship between the two so this is called the reference should work and it is
the representational duality basically you can present some convex functions are as and subject to
freedom of monotone transformation and the embedding would be a class of that kind of
me so
these two duality actually are quite different kind of two entities
but in the classic framework
the two two entities so mixed together
and without so so that's why you see a lots of labour nice results but
we really want to have a deep understanding about
whether it is related to a refreshing twenty or embedding twenty
and i hope this framework what i'm going to present is going to very much
give you a clarification of that
so let's start with the bregman divergence
we have a strictly convex function
define on the subset of
i and and what i want to point out that
this property
so quadrilateral relation it's an extension of the triangular relation that everybody here probably wouldn't
know that easy for any four points actually twenty four point
they don't want to be the three three to four
you have this
this very nice relation so that
the right hand side basically the difference between these two and so here's the period
of the two space so the triangulation is
in degenerate case
OK where you take say theta one equals that two
many of the two
o point will be the same so that we generate two triangulation but eugen in
general have quadrilateral relational what does it imply i'm still thinking about the implication of
i think it contains very significant
the information here in terms of this kind of space that we are dealing with
the second thing i want to point out is this is this
reference representation by twenty in the
bregman divergence in the following sense if you look at the bregman divergence between theta
one and theta two
by the way this is the particular notation i use a particular definition of the
problem that which could be reversed OK but some books but in this case i
just used this so
if we look at the convex conjugate function
this five
and then
you can exchange the theta one theta two
after the embedding after you a transformation of this and lines see the variables so
the so
see that one is true is chosen as the reference point the the two is
accompanied by comparing the divergence of the two with respect to the one
one is the base for but then it's equivalent of comparing
the divergence
we using the phi as the inducing convex function
and treating theta to what is essentially the two transmission of the two as the
base point so just reference representation by twenty it's easy to verify by the formulas
of the intelligence and these are the things i just want to point out which
may not be so well known well recognised i think it's important properties forty eight
bregman divergence and we shall see
with the rise in my following
so no
it's about the money has pointed out and averages is intimately related to the so
called the canonical divergence canonical divergence what can i do that i would just is
is that not only have the two points that i wanted to
you can see the divergence
if i
get effective transformation on the second thing to say
OK so now in this case i call it's easy to all it time that's
basically a one point transformation of the second compelling point and then define the divergence
in this case it has this very nice form
which will hear star is there is a continuous function you have this kind of
tool is symmetric
kind of expression for this bregman divergence functions
and that's the bregman divergence canonical form because
between theta
here is that it's easy to see in the same form is used it i
think we would defeat uses if you stop
as you change
the comparison reference point change that what at the end if you the same to
also change the
convex in using functions from theta on this
really is a reiteration of the state and really of the this referenced
the representation by twenty which is deeply significant and the individual's
i think that once you write in this case what it's obvious that the
actually it's related to the french
and that the basic guarantees the nonnegativity
of this canonical divergence
eventually quality stands and that guarantees a basically is subtracted the right hand side from
the left hand side
so from this perspective
immediately that leads to the following intuition
this kind of divergence
computational this kind that which is geometry junction general by that which somehow related to
this particular complex inequality
because the equality when you move the right hand side telephony minus and you get
the divergence functions so
what in the most general case
so let's see
in general
for a strictly convex function fy
we have this
quality which basically the definition of kind of a strictly convex function so the inequality
for all theta one theta two
it end the equality holds if and only if beta one is equal to that
so that's the definition of a strictly convex function
OK so this is if i hope people can recognise here is restricted between minus
one positive one
this the definition of ft
as a strictly convex function not
if we know
move the right hand side to the left
so this becomes the things in the curly bracket
then we expand the the square the square of there
and we just observe because wt made mistakes on the example then this must be
negative this is the model
and because it was mistake madness to be negative
so we can drop this get an upper bound
we've seen these guys are all the more we get this relationship you so again
we have an occurrence we can work out the recurrence and then we get this
well again these things sum up to the number of mistakes
and so we can be combined using because she shorts inequality
to recover
two relate to this
with the
quantity that we used to prove the the other part
we can just solve the for this
which we happen to have been both sign in both inequalities this one in the
previous ones
so we can solve for it
and we can get this which is you can think of it as a generalized
perceptron convergence theorem says this does number of mistakes made by the perceptron on any
arbitrary string is bounded by the
the best trade the infimum of the hinge loss of the fixed linear classifier u
plus this could normal blasts across to that involves both for both things
so this is what you see this is
as interesting properties it's an oracle inequality because it basically
without knowing anything about this you is able you're able to compare the number of
mistakes with the best
trade between hinge loss and more
OK so for those of who know some of you who support vector machine is
you know that if we should drop this part here
this is actually the function which is minimized by
the support vector machine solution
sure there is some kind of relationship even though
if you have information across to here
and now you can get of course the special case of a separable streams so
if you cycle
the the perceptron the linearly separable streams
then that you have that
i will
then this term disappear
this is here because the hinge loss of the best guide
you want to linearly separable three is going to be the right
and then you're left with b
mean for you
the infimum of the new unknown new square
where you square is
separator achieving zillions losses in particular you can take the
support vector machines solution which is the shortest linear separator achieving zero loss
so basically
shows that
the number of mistakes made the perceptron on elizabeth stream as
bounded by the squared norm of the support vector machine solution for the same stream
and another consequence is there
you know if you have a separable sitting always exists
a linear separator expressible as a linear combination of at most these many support
this is because
the the update rule of the perceptron
you can view it
as anything support
which is mistaken example every time a mistake is made
so you see you added is going to some
so after and mistakes
this guy here will be a linear combination of m mistaken instances
which you can view as supports
so that's why you can see is the
you make economic and most this many mistakes gonna make you don't have that most
of these many supporting yourself in your solution
so i
so there's a number of interesting properties of this is a very basic example of
online mistake bound for the simplest
binary classification i agree
OK so
let me move on
two special cases of separable saying i want to say something more about here
and the first thing is
one thing that you could you can be asking now is OK
we saw the perceptron doesn't doesn't have the correcting up update
so the the margin after every up the margin increases by a constant additive term
which is the square the number of distance so now
what you might want to do is that you might want to modify the presenter
also that sought to enforce a large margin so you want to come up with
the corrective update
and now we can wonder whether corrective update might be
might work better than the perceptron update
so in particularly what you can you might find corrective update
as follows
as an update that enforces a zero hinge loss
zero hinge loss its weight
after the update
OK so
we want to be
we want to modify the participants also to make it more aggressive in responding to
the two mistakes and see what happens in terms of the solution
so now
again you admit you made
you made a now you're looking at the hinge loss of the
of the online so whenever they are learning curves something to loss then you make
an update so that the the updated weight the will have no no hinge loss
of missing some example
so this is a
a different and more aggressive update so so we now can try to analyse the
properties of this is a different topic here and
and this
this thing this this
what does say in the moment is strongly related to another in proposed by his
hildreth in convex optimisation in the fifties
that has
i mean you can do this is very special case of the general in general
algorithm by hundreds
i'm not going to tell more about this relationships that to start to see in
in learning and convex optimization
so now
let's get this
that the solution
all of this is the solution of the weight will have this form which is
just the perceptron update with the learning rate which are going to determine
now we want to
choose it that is such that the updated with margin big enough so we can
just to solve and find the solution here
since his roommate made an update
this is this is a positive and so we can just the right
hinge loss
this is actually equivalent to the hinge loss against the positive part of this thesis
we made enough
this is we making up whenever this is positive
the probability that the couple's
the value of the of the couple falls into this rectangle
again it is symmetric and
if a integrate
over the two domains
it's equal to one
i have like to previously
all the same rules and so the distance d some rules and not for the
properties mission that for the probability density function
so again if a sum over the
the domain of one of the variable they have the margin of the other variables
trying to everything and can be decomposed into
probability density
of the conditional tense the marginal
the bayes rules applies and
two random to continuous random variable it to be independent
if there
china probability density
can be
decompose into the product of the
two probability densities
and the definition of the expectation of
the function x
this time
is the sum of the domain of
continuous from a random variable of the function
always it again weighted by
the probability density
some classical distributions continuous
the version of maybe
let's classical i didn't know them
before my phd
remember the
binomial distribution so how many
and if i toss my kind if i keep my kind several times
what's what's the number of times i have have a head
so the prior distribution on the parameter u which was that the number of
of the probability of t
so it's it's very off in the in the minimum distribution
is usually
you take a better distribution
was store which has two parameters a and b
and as you see
we find here that this product that we had before in the in the binomial
and OK got my these strange function that's for four normalize this scene
but what was
what is interesting is that some giving
the density to the
to the
the parameters to this the to the probability of having a head
but they and what you see here is that these two values a and b
which are made to parameters in fact something like that
the effective
number of times i see
days or hit
so it's my prior on i'm pretty sure that for example
these two are another good example
i'm pretty sure that i'm going to see
water is than hits
so i'd say i put eight two eight
and beta four
and what they have is that my the prior on my
on my
coefficient on my parameter
is it
closer to one down to zero
it's a little bit the maldives
the other side of
i have
the other way round if i put i have a prior that maybe and see
i had done is
and so i have put eight two one two three and the
prior is
in this way
and if i have no idea
i said that it would have looked prior on bus
d a and b
and what they will have is that
any chance
you will give me one zero and the other is zero
and i understand my is it or you know it's it's completely
the reaction
OK this
it's a candidate it's also generalize to the case of the multinomial distribution
the classical prior for the
parameter u which is the vector
a multinomial is taken as
as being do the outlet distribution
with parameters
being the vector
and with this kind of
of probability
density functions
if i take for me to nominate of capello's favour days with
true face
it's not possible
so the
so you have lots of things like you know the ball and
are a and you know and
and then you have always because it's it's about the model you have these all
these different word probability distributions
and then you also have another sort of large state for organizations
and what sort of conceptual transitions from every state here to every state in here
they all these transitions share the same set of parameters
so you didn't so basically did sort of completely
exacerbate the premier estimation problem
i mean this is this is actually a pretty reasonably common technique think it's called
like parameter tying
and there are other cases of this parameter tying things in the research literature
the other really interesting thing that they did
and what really gets the core of why humans are
not completely satisfactory for information extraction
is that they wanted to use various types of capitalization
and features about this
format of numbers
but if you remember one thing that should in the early on the talk with
this list the features
they had nothing to do with actually the identity of the word itself
it included in any of the world but basically had like
fifty other types of features based on form adding capitalization
i mean other sorts of things that are not being used here by hidden markov
models right sort of no hidden markov models just looking at
the identity of the world so you know it's really sad about hidden markov models
is that they
by using this rich source of information
so let's try to hack around it including
this small set of perhaps a dozen features
in each word was really not a word
distribution but it was paired with one of these features so for example
most of these are various flavours of trying to recognise digits and money at the
and then always wanted the bottom are various types of capitals asian
sort of features and so the word abraham would actually be a pair of the
world abraham and
initial caps
the cell
and so this
one of the factors that this really expands the parameter space right fully by creating
ten different things
you almost never quite be really always increase the number of parameters by an order
of magnitude
so quite true because the word abrahams never going to be a two-digit number but
it could be any kind of a ranking of any kind of this capitalization
right so that's there's definitely tension there are you can really
creating that many premier should be
somewhat scary
good OK so
eight interns works pretty well in practice but why should we not be completely satisfied
in markov models and actually have identities
and this sort of don't allow for these features to be handled so so nicely
i mean the other thing that
we should be said about is it
it turns out that the core generative technique writer there
what actually written down mathematically is the way that we believe that the document was
ramsay approximation is sort depending on this fact and we know that to sort of
be blatantly not true
right and in particular the number of actually spending quite a bit of parameter estimation
trying to figure out how it is that people
what the words and things like that
well you really wish is that they
the technique wouldn't actually is
spend that time and we really focus in on
what we really care about right which is what's the label of the word right
to the land was given to us and so
we have to worry about generating was already given to us we would have no
choice we really want the model to account for
and really pay attention to is trying to do a great job
predicting that label
and there's nothing in this generative model that tells that yes what we're really interested
in is predicting the model
so this brings us to
yes question
most problem
what you see is that when people
o and know that are some
so for example when you actually
so what you want these things how exactly
inside the building
so i wouldn't say that hidden markov models are particularly
understandable models
like it's not very easy to look at of HMM in
see what's going on under the hood
i don't think i have any strong suggestions for how to in no
when your models good
i think there's a lot of room for domain expertise to play a role in
crafting the
state structure
and i highly recommend that but i don't have any
guidelines other than just be clever
conditional random fields but the heart what the model is the probability distribution of y
which are the output labels given x which are the words are actually occurring
and sort of
give you some sense for the mathematics of conditional random fields
i wanted to show you the hidden markov models are special cases of conditional random
fields i think this will help your understanding of what's really going on in canada
and conditional random fields
so i'm going to sort of
take you from this initial formal
formulation of hidden markov models and sort of wacky through
to show that
she took arrive at this sort of functional form of the conditional random field
one thing to keep in mind that the conditional and feel how the enterpri amateurs
and need to be estimated
if we set the parameters in some strange way will
and that's exactly as had hidden markov model
well the training for real concern feel actually end up with quite different parameters and
we'll talk about that in a minute
so here we have this generative distribution
over first generating a next state and then generate a word for that state
i'm going to basically
do this EXP exponentiation and long hair
so in that will convert this product into some
it allows get pushed n
and to separate out the addition of these two log probabilities
then i want to try to make this a conditional right so i want to
derive its sort of probability y given x and for some this joint y
this is just a little
that's probably why next if you sort of divided by all the other all possibilities
of x y pairs there is so i've done the same thing here
which is basically just introduce this ze which is the some
the normalizer that depends only on x so x is the only thing that matters
here because y is taking care about the
and don't worry too much about that but but busy barley for now