right so that's where
this is the possibility score
this the the
confidence of facts for centuries
thomas for the first for the
as each other in a different way
it's more like this out
so we we actually go back to the
he was born
the reason why i think it's
just because possible was ranked number one more
OK if you can be part of the merger okay
one hundred random books
from these solitons of also the so
OK in the bookstore he also
one chance of course
this time it was later revealed religion whether it's right or wrong
go get the
one of the best of both
the book's authors or not so popular
OK so what find if i see this about to fire
response no
and i don't know
five hundred sixty four
missing data
for every day and she will be part of
the reason is that we we use by the part of sentence well with all
the stories of things we come up with some power
in the interesting way network reason why
can be box
so we have not only
boston with many bookstores
we have this one first
to our surprise
that's people
so we know that
there are there are you can see
they almost in every
but by the act
a six five the
well known
you want to demonstrate
but the point six five
because the
it's more on their books
so of course is problem
the world is
the figure in nineteen
two thousand seven
so this is a
this model was
on his website there are ten i
by the time and
yes this is very far actually in this paper is said we discussed later on
the topic at that
this is copied the samples are they going to do what they want to work
on more than that you can that's that's quite possible
in some way
so now we can use
google news has more complex than that
of course news agencies
you can send their children to go to the page
he so they need some copy saying but some of the carbon in one way
something like
so in the summer
also for this kind of environment
all the provinces or is it just using
i think to change is of course that's so there are a lot of the
carbon that that we studied some it's just what you call gets
actually after we have very nicely
in general
lost to solve the problem that they were lost during the really big companies
in the research she published two papers
in the year the conference
for she finer ones actually that
this is the car
this is a problem
people like you said is important
how to get rid of
the interesting thing is that
that show
only at the world cup in the united if everybody scaffold
you can discuss
then in
the interesting thing is similarity search
which i did this
in the network you want to search
this is different from us
search for example
you've got little
you have something
you want to find
sometimes you want for example companies really one
some of these problems and i want you
scenes of surgeons
you can think
four kinds of search
one search
this structure so
you isomorphic to this one this one this one company some some
four always comes out there
one this one this
search you
look across the US
this semantic similarity search for example this is what is most american christmas policies
this is all crystal palace's two brothers one sister
once you business process was not as well as follows
it's really
produce one papers published papers
on the party
some of those
this one
for some some kind
OK so
we also have a similar because they are similar to what is working on problems
using this
i was working on something
some profits in user
for his father was active in our data mining
there is
how can we
the similarity is based on for
this is
the first few
what substructures
the reason that
you want to construct
you gave graph those
this is really going there are twenty one structure this
his website is
with this kind stuff
i don't want to have fun
not only he was
michigan wisconsin or
CMU structure
that's reinforced structures which list is
this one is is a paper was published in february two thousand and six
one of the structure search
eight can
school day one
you know so was formula a two
there's conditions group data
and so on
everything maintain soundness and completeness that's
this theorem
is the one that gives us
that diagram on the previous page
and then of course given the collection itself is one the logic is complete
that's just follows from the other two
so for a long time
people thought great
we've got this notion of sulcus formula and look you can have a calculus you
can have cookie
frame with an eye condition and its first order definable
so now i what i want to do is show the limits
of this
i'm sorry
the conditional
these conditions
right i've just said condition here i'm a condition on the reachability relation so
you know the shape box find classifier corresponds to
that for all w wrw
sorry shape of by implied by corresponds to a for all w
and the are condition is the
that every points is it right
exactly all of these axioms so quest on that
on that
page which is gone
given an arbitrary formula five
it doesn't work that's why self-interest theorem is so important
OK so
it's undecidable you give me an arbitrary shape
and ask me what's
first order correspondent
it's an undecidable problem
OK so
we know that
southwest outside cells which were on shaky ground
right it may make you may be able to find one
but you won't be able to give the general algorithm which says
given the fight it out the first of course
what about conditions on r which are not
captured by any shape we saw that there were conditions on r which corresponded exactly
to shape
these three conditions are examples of one that can't be changed
i reflexivity said every point sees itself
you reflexivity says
no points is itself
the symmetry set
if you have
i just want to use the same variables u and v
so if you
see the
and this is you
and actually they have to be the same
so you can't have two distinct points to see each other
and the third one is a symmetry
which says that
if you can go from here to here
then you can't come back
OK it might seem as if
the second and third of this is the same but they're not cages
work your way through that
how do you prove that you can look at that in the book by blackburn
can very much you define transformation frames
by which you can
joined two friends together to get bigger frame
or cedar point and just look at all the children but you can reach which
is called the generated of frame
and another notion which is called the p m offic image i don't want to
go into the details and what you can do is you can show that
first order properties are preserved by taking these transformations and so you can cook up
frame so that
you prove that provide contradiction that now friend class can
capture reflexivity say
what about
another question is it the case
all shapes
if they correspond correspond to first order
conditions so we know that some shapes
i don't have any correspondence
but if they do they always correspond to first order
well the answer is no
so here are two logics
and the condition
making your statement not
the and dependent on the given future that you choose
so what does that mean
remember had structures where you had
and transitions of going to state
so here is about
choosing one execution in this structure
so it means you first choose an infinite
and then
properties about
so state
branching time
the view of branching time logic is to see the future as branching of g
so it doesn't mean it means that instead of choosing a particular
you just interested in in which point you the structure and you can tell about
all possible passes
you can tell about the set of
that's start
from this state
so what you do
is that
you allow yourself to use quantification
over the set of possible passes
that starts from the current state in
so she can start simply says
you would think here
something where you have simply and with the negation you would have the universal quantification
as well
you simply say here
so this is going to be interpreted
game along the path
when i tell you that
along the given sequence
i currently have the existence
o passed satisfying some formula
so this is your standard models are very familiar with
so that's my purse i thought
OK i mean starting position i but this is not a big issue
think of just
and if in in this that i tell you that
there exist the best
which satisfies
the site now is formula in this mountain logic
but think of site
just that formula
it tells me only that from here
there exists a path which may not be this one
it may be another one
in the structure
so it does you that from here i mean where i am currently in this
i'm currently on the execution but in this execution here
there may exist another future
and this branching
it is very important when you think of programs where
the programs in is an open system
i have some use which is going to enter value
like the menu
what you want to do you want to play
the first game second game for game
please type
and you try and depending on what you type the program execution would be very
from many another way would have to OK
so given the program when you're in a given state considering
possible futures so the sum
of these equations is is worse than
it makes sense
so in this logic
you can say there exist away
there exists a possible execution which may be
o one which which forks
from the one you currently looking at
so that blah blah blah so the blah blah blah is LTL formulas
but now that you have this ability to
to use the
quantification wherever you want
well you may of course
here say that there exist to pass well at some point
satisfying site and this site if you if you go down side at some point
you're missing site contains also for example a proposition p is true
vision q
for that
something it's
so here we have p all along the and the new HQ
and from now on
wherever you go
say trying hold
in their own right
here in order to understand how to use evolutionary simulations it would be nice to
know about how their component parts worked
unfortunate that poorly understood
when this work was done there was little explosion of interest in neutrality in search
so that's search spaces where points that are adjacent with respect to genetic operators share
the same fitness so those genetic operators don't bring about any change in fitness
populations can drift across neutral networks in in search spaces
so here's the picture
these plateau here are neutral
with respect to evolution
and this white line that you can't really see shows the progress of the population
as it climbs sort of jumps up onto neutral networks eventually manages to make it
all the way to the top
or maybe it's error minimisation this kind of what i don't know
so what we were interested in
was whether
drifting across neutral networks was going to retire an evolutionary process for certain classes of
of problem or whether as some people have claimed neutral networks were beneficial because they
open up
transitions to a wide wide variety of locations in search spaces and prevent you from
getting stuck
and local optima
and for the for the particular class of landscape that we were looking at which
were this sort of idealised RNA
secondary structure RNA folding landscape we could demonstrate although there was neutrality there
it was structured such populations didn't spend a lot of time
neutral refuges refuse you like called
so some there was some sense in which
if you're
imagine that the this is error minimisation this landscape right so so you start out
so i would say error minimisation
imagine it's hill climbing
imagine that the population has reached this plateau here
it could be the majority of transitions off the plateau are negative right
and what you find is that regular GA
if there are points which are close to apply then parents which find themselves on
the edge of that cliff will have offspring and say half of their offspring will
be over the cliff with low fitness and that means that you don't expect those
you expect the population to persist very long with parents like that parents who are
deep inside this neutral landscape who consistently generate offspring with the same fitness is there
are going to outcompete lineages that involve those parents are going to outcompete lineages that
parents of these these dangerous cliff edges
but it's the edges of the neutral network where the transitions are so if you
if your population is being forced into the middle of neutral networks then maybe it's
gonna that's gonna retard the rate at which is discovers evolutionary innovations but
the structure of the neutrality within the space was such that that didn't happen so
the point for this lecture is not to explain
much more about neutrality but show that if we want to understand
how we want to understand the implications of our models one include components that
we have yet to have mature theories on then maybe we should be spending part
of our time
exploring how how those systems work and not just consign that some some kind of
engineering activity
OK so is another reason model that i'm going to try to explain in a
bit more detail than the neutrality one
so i've already mentioned termite construction i've already shown you fascinating DVD of the man
pumping a termite mound full of plaster of paris
so the
the the things the termite builds are impressive
OK you end up with fungus farms and climate control and tunnels and air-conditioning and
what have you but it's largely unexplained how they achieve all of this complexity but
we know how it starts stops with pillars that have joined together to form low
walls and those walls grow and enclose spaces to form domes and in particular the
first thing is built is called the queen chamber which don't like structure built around
a huge
termite we i think of them on the radio today the queen termite and around
so you can see these little depositions
which are
increased space
pillars which are being
extended vertically and eventually they will start to merge together to form wall
and then that wall grows and encircles the queen
the previous models of this
had been constructed with partial differential equations that were one of those equations described the
distribution of termites across some space one of the one of them described the distribution
of building material that have been deposited across that space and one of them described
the distribution of the pheromone that the termites give off
one facts i think maybe even two pheromones
so very the graph that the mathematics models produced looked like this
so this is a graph this axis time
on this axis is space
what you should be saying is that at the beginning of time you've got a
very rough
plus the norm of the transpose x three if you look at the supremum
o like that
and then we see that this is a second order cone
a linear function of x and then the euclidean norm of some things that make
and the problem makes a lot of sense because what this means is that for
example by zero means no uncertainty
just a i just a single point and it reduces the LP which just mean
of a i
then if the by is large large matrix and at some slack in the constraints
to make sure that x is feasible for all possible values of a i
how you could have exact this
in this problem is
clever because you add up all the slack
and then the amount of slack have always also depends on the on how the
product of the next
could be that like here apart from the actions and or another direction
depending on
singular values of the i
that's an example of robust convex optimisation problems
to take an LP
with uncertainty that turns into an association SOCP
another example is the squares suppose take least squares problem x minus p minimize two
but now is uncertain and i assume that a
it's actually
so in this model like this is then
normal choice it's zero
press firms that depend on the unknown parameter u
and this unknown parameter you is
bounded norm peterson
and then
so now that makes our matrix a certain
and in this robust worst case approach to minimize the worst-case values that minimize the
of this nuclear norm
over all possible choices you ask the first is that this
and this turns out to again writers and it is the set of an SDP
that's exactly this problem
we have access variable and you two
except for one
and by solving this is the problem
and so this gives you an idea of what happened was i think in this
case two
very well known parameters
for some a and b
and here i come look at the distribution of the residuals in the least squares
problems for three possible choices of x
if i assume that the uncertainty happen in your view that defined like this to
i assume that u is an
uniformly distributed over the this two and there's you know there's one suppose that because
certain x
and then take for you and the choices in the universe
and then for different choices of actually get the different distribution of the residuals
so the first one the problem here is that east coast solution because i just
an audience
this problem i just added additional thirty
and optimized for a zero nominal case
then if i use that solution x
and in the actual model that uncertainty than i this distribution model
we see that
the best solution is quite a bit better than the other solutions but it's also
the actual
these girls objective
could actually be much worse than what you ask
that's not robust non robust solution
residual depends very much on
the second choice here x
OK this is the kind of solution
so that's another the classical way of making x more about respect the choices a
is added the organization
the penalty term or a constant multiple of of the norm of x
that's the kind of solution
it's used to make it more robust that actually makes it does make it more
about the distribution of residuals
three is more narrow and these
this solution is more robust against errors a
the first one
you pay a price for the best case solution also
the script
and this
distribution is the solution of this robust spacecraft solution
he really minimizing the worst case solution actually actually minimizing the
but at the end of the distribution
minimize the worst case solution pushing this
the left as far as it can
and that results in a more narrow distribution is more sensitive
and the price to pay is called the best solution is
as high as
that's sort of the goal of robust optimization tried to make
the ocean more of
respect to the uncertainty
without actually decorating the normal solution
the solution for the normal system too much
so that's robust optimization second very active area is
seven programming
using polynomial optimisation
and the idea is the following
suppose you have polynomial extensible
two x is vector of coefficients
and is the vector of basis functions
for example when
he is an independent variable could be just to scare could be multidimensional
so i will come to the whole
thanks for
think we speak to you in front of you today
that was quite an important he made bit at the last minute
because initially as in cinemas this summer and
one anyway i'm here so
that's a work which was presented during idea and then i made an extension of
the two
that's why and and to a bit more about the topic to the talk even
last week two idea
first my quote also for the history of the popes addresses from port again
with whom i initiated this is this work about two years ago professor cook
from ztx leiden university he's my supervisor in holland
but but three can from the ICT group of TU delft the technical university of
delft holland
and myself so above
the second is by the
the set out of his the guy will remain most the kids with whom i
have collaborated most is easier to make this paper in this contribution
i started working text classification two years ago when i was
in bottou go my my sisters this possible brazil supervised this is this
so it was six months is
and then the data in french was propositional command assume
classification to king
i can text classification study so the goal was to give suggestion to study practically
pragmatically if we want to use
classification agreed
OK well what's happening
so i kept this work when i got involved in business studies in holland i
kept working this party but time so now i am in ztx leiden institute of
advanced computer science in in leiden university and the distribution of both so-called que and
the funding comes from and big the netherlands bioinformatics centre
two main projects i will
present in one or two slide my project in
in bioinformatics
but then we spend most of the time we are discussing about text classification study
so one would about and they can just well that's a big initiative in india
in holland it's a foundation that coordinates research education and support activities
in bioinformatic and citizens
that's quite a big project with twenty one million euro and and then about semantic
position new position created just forces bioinformatic initiative in in the sentence
so many
many different entities collaborate to universities companies and then also hospitals
university leiden university
that's is oldest universities and is and fifteen seventy five it was created as a
gift from william of orange to this from my supervisor because
obviously i don't know anything about my university yet
so here it is
a gift from william of orange to the citizens of flight in
we had was to the long siege the spaniards
so is the oldest university in holland
now those are about ninety co-workers in the lab and then number the floor we
the mathematicians
and so on brain and in his lab and there few surviving clusters focused ago
in computer systems
the foundation of software technology and imaging
and the bioinformatic cluster is spread over a cliff and images
well i don't university is really a nice space to be because obviously that she
will visit us next winter for a couple of months so that's even more interesting
so one of two states about just bioinformatics to know i'm not just
text classification guy but also
i do we set with bioinformatics we analyse data about osteoarthritis so that's when you
join skate
that's it
complex we analyse the complex phenotype of course outright is so it's a disease which
is spreading over your body
the joint location
and we have to do with sibling pairs suppose and sisters recorded an integrated to
and then we recorded at multiple join size which means
under hands
under spines civically and alone by the hips and knees we recorded with roger graph
is a disease severity of
it's always severity under different during location
and this involves many techniques
the mining visualisation statistical testing something techniques as well as by computing so quite
a large amount of techniques to study it is
and then the workflow is the following morning so you might be used to
this kind of focal for the workflow
data transformation model based clustering
because we want
to see down groups of individuals sharing the same phenotype so we try to clusters
in by by phenotype
so this is people have what they keep stuff like this is one so we
can start discussing
visualisation which is
very important in when we work in collaboration with biologist is the key point
and then of course when you we do we say clusters we have to assess
the validity
and in addition to computers and specific datasets
we need
to assess
two to see them more sisters
in one studies and what we expect
so that's
what what we have to do when work was biologist
two visualisation among the three that i was using
this one we not use it yet at the moment we use it for y
but then
when forces visualization so one is bayes and pull out coordinates and one is part
of the coordinates
we also use heat maps quite heavily
and in that case we can
reflect as good as possible
the phenotype of the individuals who favour here so because he is a robust source
and then we have
different clusters
and then we can observe increasing severity here
of of sand
the disease for this clusters
so i cannot show more results because data confidentiality by biology so we much
protecting the datasets
so let's go on we
with text classification in the behavior off is him in text classification
so i'm not really anisian gave more
i try to
so let's suppose we have a very simple belief net. so this is a binary belief
net. these are the binary things; i've given them names
this happened to me in california. i was lying in bed in the house jumped
and i just assumed a truck had hit the house because i'm english. actually it was an earthquake
but let's suppose that it could have been either
houses don't just jump
so by putting a bias of minus twenty there, you say the probability the house just jumps is
about e to the minus twenty
the probability of a truck hitting the house is much more likely than the house just jumping. let's make
that e to the minus ten about
the earthquake about the same
let's suppose these are independent causes
that is, we ignore the fact that trucks steer funny in earthquakes
so let's make these independent causes
the most likely
state here in your sort of prior distribution is that neither of these will happen
it's very unlikely that both of them will happen
and there's a small chance of e to the minus ten of one happening and
the other not happening.
but because of these big weights here if a truck did hit the house,
then there's an even chance the house will jump because now the total input is 0
similarly in an earthquake, there's an even chance the house will jump
but you'd be very silly to explain the house jumping by saying there's an earthquake *and* a truck hit the
you're appealing to two very unlikely things to try and explain this extremely unlikely thing.
the product of these unlikely things just as unlikely as this extremely unlikely thing, so you don't win
by doing that
so the posterior distribution over these hidden causes look something like this
possibly with more nines
the probability they both happened is very unlikely
this is given that you see the house jumps
the probability that neither happened is very unlikely because the house after all did jump
this might have happened
or this might have happened
and those each have probability of about point five
all the probability is here so these two things are highly anti correlated.
they were independent in the prior--they were assumed to be independent events--
but once you've seen that the house jumped
then if you believe this you almost certainly don't believe that, and vice versa
that's explaining away
pearl was the first person to make a big deal of this
and it's what makes inference
difficult in these networks
and we're gonna
get rid of it
there's two ways to get rid of it
you just pretend it's not there -- that's called variational methods
or there's a more honest way to do it, which is what we're gonna do
the reason it's hard to learn some deep belief net that has these layers of
hidden variables
driving the layers below until you eventually get to observe the data
let's think about learning these weights here, just these weights here. you go from the bottom layer of
hidden variables to the observed data
in order to learn these,
we need to sample from the posterior here
the posterior here
depends on two things
the posterior distribution of these
vectors here
it depends on
the data
i'll call that dependency the likelihood term
and it also depends on the prior
OK if the stuff up here said this unit never turns on,
then that's that. it can't turn on even if the data would like it to
and you have to take the product of two distributions then you normalize. a distribution comes
from here which is the prior distribution over the possible vectors there
and a distribution comes from here
which i'll call the likelihood distribution
and you multiply them together then normalize and that gives you the posterior here
so it looks like to learn these weights
you need the posterior
and to know the posterior, you need to know all these weights here
therefore, you're gonna have to learn all the weights at the same time
trying to find out where the two distributions are the same
based on
the doctor that we've drawn from those distributions
we've done one two and three
and now what i'm going to convince you that actually
this mean in feature space
and we've been playing with that now for the past three lectures
these are very very powerful quantity
in fact
if you
pick feature map in the right way
this uniquely identify the distribution
this is great because it means that rather than
playing with distribution
you can play with the point in hilbert space
so at least i find is sometimes a bit daunting computing kullback leibler divergences in
similar things
but playing with means
in the feature space they can compute distances although this is really easy
that's what i really used to doing
so maybe i just find it easier because i've been doing it for a long
but it turns out to get very very simple algorithms
and you can use it for quite a few things
and after the break
will cover this
the first thing you need to discuss in this context
is the two sample problem
the two sample problem is
and given two sets of observations from two different distributions
or at least four
two different to this mission i don't know
and i want to and so one very simple question given those two sets of
other drawn from the same distribution or not
well it will be very hard to give
such an answer with certainty
i can give such an answer with high probability
sounds very dry very abstract and a bit boring
as the efficiency love answering such questions
it turns out you can do a lot of useful things with it
and the applications are really fun
so namely
what you can do is
you can do things like start integration
three into attribute matching
or you can actually do things like sample bias correction so in other words they've
got the training set drawn from one distribution
the test set drawn from another
you just given the training and the test set
obviously tested unlabelled
you told you based on that test it
and it turns out you can actually prove that and
fairly reasonable assumptions
you can do
basic as well as if you knew
how the test distribution differs from the training institution
the first part now is
fairly heavy-duty statistics
and then will do lots of applications
so it will be a bit
OK so
let's look at the city
given some data x
and why so
not to be confused in this case the water not labels
i'm just give some
diversity and another one there
i want to test whether
people's q
distribution p distribution q
well what can i use this word
let's say i'm working
with various micro
array flaps
and while they all do some measurements for some big cancer study that i would
like to do something with it
and you know they all have their own protocols and all that
i would like to know
whether there really measuring the same thing
so you could look at each feature separately and look at the means and well
might give me something but what i want to do is just you know i
should be some dots and you tell me other drawn from the same distribution
or let's say
after companies which merged
that customer databases
and obviously because they were all outsourcing and everything that followed the person who's written
the database schema
you want to be able to
rediscover fairly easily
what that schema looked like
for instance you might want to know
what are names or
and the other
terms such as you can really merge database
you get the sample boss correction problem
well the training and test sets different
well that can occur fairly frequently
for instance
how you might represent images you might just decide on an arbitrary ordering trying use
this very big stick here
an arbitrary ordering of the pixel so you might scan out the pixels in a
row by row
and then you might miss the value of each pixel is the number here say
between zero and two fifty five so if this is a hundred by one hundred
image hundred pixels by hundred pixels and you have all the pixel values as numbers
between zero and two fifty five then what you have is a ten thousand long
OK so your representation of the images the ten thousand long vectors and furthermore
how many
possible images are there
right two hundred fifty five raised to the ten thousand which suffice it to say
is an unimaginably large number and so
the following strategy
is not going to work
every time you see an image that's labeled as stanmore
the she or alex or someone that you know
put it on the side and little scratchpad these are people that i know every
time you get a new image compared to see if it's the same as one
of the people that you know if so
give me the name and if not so i don't know
OK that's not going to work because there are so many images of as the
images you will never see the same image again even if you put a camera
in front of me right now take a picture of me and take another picture
second later it's not going to be the same
not in the actual details of the images that were taken so
we definitely have to be careful about how we manipulate this representation
what we're going to do is going to take away
numerically representing everything but then we have to live rely on probability and statistics in
order to do
whatever calculation need to do matching images to people or detecting whether something is spam
or not spam and so on
and so in in particular we're going to do is we're going to
use something called the random variable a random variable is like the variable in a
computer program
but represents a quantity
whose value changes depending on exactly which data the programs looking so you might say
for example
the pixel here in this position
that's a random variable which i might call x three hundred eighty four this is
three hundred eighty four pixel k
and that is the variable which changes depending on which image we're looking at and
if we had some probability distribution over images that would induce a probability distribution over
that pixel and that's why it's considered a sort of random variable changes depending on
what the image represents
and the value of these variables is often sort of uncertainty and that's why we're
going to employ the theory of probability
OK so
random variables can either be continuous random variables in which case they just take on
real values usually between negative infinity infinity or maybe you know that there are positive
or something or can be what's called discrete are categorical
so these discrete categorical their values take on just say zero one that's a binary
variable or a set of fixed set of values like in if you're doing so
simple weather prediction and generally what we do is we have repeated measurements of various
quantities and so this is the convention here i'm going to use the indices i
and j
to denote the components of the different
values in our representation and can indices like an and to represent the data cases
are records multiple measurements so x
and is the i th value i th input or the i th representation
of the end the case here and usually use extra inputs and y for outputs
but that's not going to be hard rule
and again we can just think of this whole thing is a vector the end
data cases of vector so chinese boldface which may be shows better on printed notes
on the screen
so i
i i just want to cover some of these these basic topics that i listed
here on the left to try and set the stage for
not only my lectures but for some things that other people be talking about
so we
given the inputs and outputs that we are represented we often want to compute something
about them so for example given an input image represented now is the vector i
give you that vector and i want to ask is this picture of my face
for example
so our computer program you can think of now is a mathematical function x which
probably should be bold here is the representation of the input
and f is the function which are computer program is going to actually implement and
z is the answer
so maybe we think of that is a binary function which just says is the
picture of salmon be very simple machine learning task
when you start thinking about this function
you start to realize that
there's a lot of these functions here right
if there's two hundred fifty five to the ten thousand possible inputs and there's two
possible outputs then this is sort of zero one cross two hundred fifty five to
ten thousand that's the space of possible functions again that space functions as a huge
number members and
the key
two in designing a machine learning algorithm is to think about the task that you
want to do in the real world
represent that task as a function approximation problem and then passed of all possible functions
that i could consider what subset do i want to restrict myself to considering
and the reason you want to restrict yourself to considering a subset is because if
i show you a finite amount of data
that's a finite amount of data can only help you choose between a certain number
of functions as those of you would like to think in information theory terms imagine
that i show you some data and that data has a certain number of bits
of information in it
the most you could ever hope to do is choose between two to the
number of bits in your training data possible functions so if i show you a
hundred images and you think those hundred images have you know a few thousand bits
and then the most you could possibly hope to use the function space has cardinality
to to a few thousand just a big number but not nearly as big as
all possible functions right
so the set of functions that you're willing to consider is called your hypothesis space
so we don't just make up functions randomly choose them from a very carefully
restricted set and that set is called our hypothesis space and that hypothesis spaces generally
indexed by a set of parameters which generically call status and you can think of
those as no we can turn to
choose different functions in the sense so the hypothesis space h is a sort of
map from these not stated into functions from the input to the output
and the hardest part of doing machine learning especially the probabilistic approach is deciding how
to represent the inputs and the outputs and how to select the hypothesis space for
those of you who does little bit of work in this field you may be
we don't know
there's a pretty good indirect evidence that i mention later that is indeed the case
but experiment to discover one more tomorrow we have to revise the textbooks but that
is where it is
now i
i need to be careful
because i said that
in beta decay
if you omit an electron here
and the neutrino goes long way it hits something downstream it turns back into an
that is true in all experiments done in a laboratory
you know in a small
but if you know those neutrinos travel far enough
it turns out that there's a very small chance that the first they go
they will somehow sort have lose the memory
how they were born and change from one variety into another so
if you've got a process which produced electron type neutrino for example
in the heart of the some
where hydrogen is turning into helium and emitting positrons and electrons type neutrinos
by the time the electron type neutrinos have traveled one hundred fifty million kilometres
it turns out that is long enough for a strange thing to happen called neutrino
oscillations that the first go
the greater the chance that they have lost the election time memory and start beginning
to think that they become sort of a bipolar in fact can try
but they think on the me one time neutrino all maybe i tau tau neutrino
and by the time they get there pretty much
one third chance each
the detectors here on earth forty years deep underground detecting the solar neutrinos were only
able to detect neutrinos of the electron time
very sensible because that's all they thought they were looking for
and they found about one-third as many arriving at the theory says should be arriving
and it took forty years to sort that out
before the discovery
that a there are three varieties of neutrino and b
but if neutrinos have
a little bit of mass
this phenomenon of changing the variety can happen if they absolutely massless as people had
for many years that could not happen
but if they have a little bit of mass
the wonders of quantum mechanics enable the neutrinos to change from one form to another
and that we now know is the reason why
after one hundred fifty million kilometres only one-third were remaining as the electron type
that was why the only detecting one-third as many theorists suggested that li ray davis
who started program
back in the late nineteen fifties to sixty
so long it is notable prizes nobel prize i think it eighty eight
so it's a long time in the neutrino business before things get sorted out this
phenomenon of neutrino oscillations
it is now
what now the state of the art is trying to
qualitatively measure
see precisely
how it happens
and from its hopefully be able to determine what the different masses of these neutrino
varieties are
state of the art of the moment is that we know that
not the three neutrino varieties can massless otherwise this phenomenon would happen
but then masses i said are exceedingly small
very near to each other
and precisely what they are and why they are what we are is one of
the big questions is being chased the moment and you'll hear much more about that
in following lectures but the set of experiments that have been done it started off
a bit like
particle physics using natural things produced in the cosmos namely neutrinos from the sun
neutrinos are also produced in cosmic ray collisions in the upper atmosphere
they tend to be more of the muon neutrino variety for technical reasons
and it was about ten to fifteen years ago
when they started discovering that when they detected those what we call cosmic neutrinos underground
the they also
seem to be changing from one form to another and it was at that moment
for half is to many problems in the solar neutrinos problems with the cosmic neutrinos
may be the common story here
and now experiments have been done in laboratories by using
neutrino beams
there are produced in labs in particular here it's for example you can produce beams
so you want to neutrinos and five them through the earth towards rome there's the
laboratory under the grounds sasso wrote the detector
you have to fight through the
the curvature of the earth of course means that rome is not she said been
here when in space time around the beamline is pointing downward direction
road you can then measure
number of
neutrinos of this variety arrived in rome compared with the number set out from here
and from that see how many have changed disappears and the similar experiment happening in
japan and so it's amazing which a major research programs trying to understand neutrinos and
that i think is one of the major things that will hear about
and what's exciting things in the future that come out of all of this
is the ability
to detect neutrinos i haven't told you how this conundrum was solved
it is made into a whole new science the idea
by detecting neutrinos from outer space
we can
i have new means of
doing astronomy without the use of the electromagnetic spectrum
the project we've detected neutrinos in the heart of the sun for example on one
occasion detected from supernova nineteen eighty seven
and people hopefully waiting for the super to happen
but a remarkable things have been discovered neutrinos is already
so i'll just make a couple of people here is a nice picture to
show half of the conundrum it is true that an individual neutrino can travel
statistically through light years have led to have been detected but it's a bit like
the national lottery anybody here ever won the major prize the national lottery
nobody able to handle this point is into the case but somebody always does never
any of us
if enough people into somebody wins if enough neutrinos set out
by chance one of them will bump into something
so detecting neutrinos requires
two things and as i said i mentioned in the first
the of them set out
a very big detector
to try to capture those combined
and the third thing is actually it turns out that
the high energy neutrino has the bigger the chance to bump into something so neutrinos
clustering algorithms usually the way they show the algorithm is better than all the previous
algorithms is by showing the pictures
look at the picture on two constraints that my clustering is the right one but
this is
limited scientific value and it can only work in dimension two but we are clustering
that in in
in hundreds of dimensions
so we really want to answer the question what is a good clustering
and we really want to be able to say
can carry out clustering efficiently how much running time doing it you don't know what
a good clustering you can't answer the question how much money time you need and
how much space
can we distinguish clusterable from structures that if i give you some data and
and i tell you
here is my my patients for medical there
repository and they have their i want us to do those patients naturally cluster into
groups so we will treat each group separately
although all just one big
can we define the notion of class that
these are very important questions and we don't have answers to these kind of questions
i will start by
axiomatic approach was initiated by jon kleinberg and then
we'll see what can we take from them so i don't have what i think
was in two thousand two he tries to give some
to allow the definition of the clustering in general way so it restricts the set
of clusterings of looking at but it's still pretty general so the idea is that
our our domain is going to be a finite set of points and on top
of it
we can cluster points and we don't have the notion of which points as most
similar to each other and which bones are not similar so input is the pen
which is
a set of the main points and a distance function which i call dissimilarity function
on pairs of points so
we have this notion of our input is just to find a set of points
and the notion of how similar they are to each other and so we require
this dissimilarity function
is a symmetric the distance between x and y is the same as y
x and the distance zero only two of the point itself
and then we define a clustering function is a function that takes as input which
is the pattern
of domain and distance
so a clustering function takes such an input and output
partition of the domain
that's basically what clustering functions do
and what we wish to be able to define is to find some properties that
distinguish clustering functions from functions which
not clustering functions not every function to take that
as input and outputs the partition of the that would be considered a clustering function
right if i if you have a function that takes the real numbers as input
and outputs the partition into rational numbers and irrational numbers
you are not likely to call it a clustering
how do we distinguish between functions that we call clustering in front of the court
a plan offered
three axioms
so don't sound pretty natural so the first one is scale invariant
so what do we mean by scale invariance if i take my dissimilarity distance matrix
and i have multiplied by a constant
so i didn't change the relative distances just
two call the distances and say
if the similarity between
i mean john was too
before now i have multiplied by ten to will be twenty news similarity between your
seventy but not seventy magical everything right
what we expect is a good clustering function will not be sensitive to this scale
scaling if we scale the distances we should get the same clustering so that the
scale invariance requirement f is the clustering function
that's the in there
a distance metric
and if we inputs lambda times the distance the we should get the same in
the same partition as was input to the
because you know how to write these down
is independent of b
given seed means what he
of a given c
is equal to p of a given c
he of b
so what we need to show is that these
when would what to check is whether these problems is equal to this problem
well not not with physical what what these from implies is from
so i just assume that these well
then what we have
well p of a b
given scene
is equal to p of ABC divided what you seem
by our assumption
p of ABC can be factorized in this way
but p of a p of the given a is equal to p of c
p of a given scene by bayes rule
so this first problem here is equal to the force approach
so immediately you can
fact here
then you get p of a given c
p of the given c
it's exactly what you
we need to understand exactly what is the relation
i mean what is an efficient means
is that a factorisation
of the bayesian networks
the conditional independence statements
given by the notion of
separation between
this to y
in other words
it's a very simple notion of separation we we're just
noting that these two vials are separated by this guy
so these conditional independence statements
precisely when the whole thing is
we are here trying to figure out which conditional independence statements hold for every graph
these one holds for
now we keep on going
we need to check the other way around
will condition dependence imply factorizations
to see if these two things are equal for this graph
so now we are going to assume these facts here
we went to check whether the factorisation of these graphs will emerge
from these assumption
that's exactly what happened
you just need to work through
just assume that this is true
in other words it is happening
now you open the joint distribution according to this way
and now
a b given c you can factorize
because you have these expressions here for factorizations conditional independence
and you obtain this by bayes rule
you know these property
is equal to or
the of a
the of c given a is equal to p of c
the given c
it's the first and third
i call to this effect is here
and they will you get the factorisation of this thing
so i mean you should
you should pay a lot of attention what's going on here
there are two parallel fields one of the few of graph theory that's been telling
this is the conditional independence statements that
would make sense to observe in the graph
it's just
the conditional if conditional independence statements
is given by
the notion of separation
and you make it precise
one of the supernova separation
that's exactly reflects the conditions the factorisation
factorisation conditional independence are synonyms for these graphs
one implies there
building by the one
now let's look at these graphs
who works for all graphs of three nodes
what is too much with detailed knowledge
want to relax but
remember that we have three no
how many
how many bayesian networks we have three no
technically we have five right because we have the line here which is be
we have these one year
which is the fully connected bayesian network
we have these one here
and it's just right away
we just
so let's not that is too because
this is the three d o is the entire set of conditional independence statements
this is
there are no conditional independence they try of these two graphs dangerous
so we studied these graph here
OK just
now we are going to study the graph
so we have one child and one parent and one grandparent
we have got two children and one
what the other options
we have two parents and one child
let's look at each one of them
we saw that for these
we saw that for these particular
when we observe
this thing here
this becomes
independent so in these graphs
a b
and c
these graph represents a condition that the
you can see
and the
the factorisation for the graph implies
these conditional independence and vice versa
let's look for these guys
first let's let's ask them all simple question is a and b
with these models because the product based model not mixture based model
again and again if you look at you know trying to do recognition or trying
to do in this case information retrieval
you can do much better than the traditional topic mixture based models
if you're looking at speech the same story holds
you know you can
this was done by group at stanford wear
and if you look at the first basis or discovering
you know
that's kind structure
and the remarkable thing is that what what turns out is that if you're if
few apply this model then it essentially discovers phonemes at the first level
right so that you know
this is sort of has a corresponds to a particular phoneme or even
this is has a correspondence between particular know so here what i'm showing you this
is what the the actual phonemes
and this is what the model is learning
so by basically applying
pretty much the same model
the model can basically discover phonemes which we know is a useful thing for the speech recognition right
and it sort of doesn't on its own
you can see that there is a correspondence that was discovered and i think that in
you know
this is not a speech
community but if you go to the speech
conferences use
you know you'll see a lot of these models declining kind models basically making a huge impact
just because you basically learning what are the right representations
to extract from noisy signals
and noisy speech signals
and maybe i can just point ah again the difference between the two models is
that's you know you've probably seen nearest neighbors clustering or sort of local density estimators
and the idea behind these models that use essentially partitioning the space
clustering based models and mixture based models
you partition the space to finding these local regions
a new finding parameters for each local region
so number regions is linear with the number of parameters
but if you look at sort of
distributed type of models like restricted boltzmann machines factor model species coding models
they all sort of do
something slightly different
and that is the following right imagine i have a two dimensional data
the first hidden
able can partition the data into two
so the two points right see zero see one
if i introduced another hidden variable
i can partition the place again in two
you know
see to once it easier right notice
two things i have four partitions
if i introduce another hidden variable
i can partition the plane as well
right so the interesting thing about these models
is that each parameter
each hidden variable effects many regions not just local regions
and the number of regions grows roughly speaking exponential in number of parameters
so so so this is where you know
these model shine because they to some extent able to do a little bit better with the curse of dimensionality
something that local models cannot deal so the difference between
between the two models
so if you look at you know a lot of different domains like natural images
text collaborative filtering you know we do applications motion capture and i'm gonna show you
some of the more speech perception
the beauty of these models and what makes it exciting is about yet the same
learning algorithm we have multiple domains
multiple input domains
right it that's fine interesting structure in every single domain
but obviously there are limitations right
and there are limitations to the types of structures that can be extracted by just
basically single layer of these our
nonlinear features
right and then as we've seen you sort of able to extract things like low wages
right or if you're looking at words you can extract correlations between words
always speech you can extract all four little parts of speech signal
right and obviously there is a need to go beyond right so people knew about this
you before but
up until five years ago we didn't really have good learning algorithms for for being
able to learn multiple levels of representation so focus has been focusing on just building
these a single layer models
so now let me
introduce you to the deep belief networks
and then we're gonna take it
i have an outbreak
i'm just
to use weather
whether we're gonna run out of coffee and not eh
anyways let me let me just speak for another fifteen
twenty minutes and then and then we're gonna take a break
okay so this is the exciting part deep belief networks
right so these probabilistic generative models
u have multiple layers of linear representations
and the beauty of these models is that there's a fast greedy layer-wise pre-training out
and pre-training algorithm was discovered back in two thousand six and basically opened up
the space of of of deep learning
the interesting thing about this algorithm is that's
inferring the distribution of the latent variables for
is easy in these models
and there was a breakthrough
right because all of a sudden show union image i can quickly tell you what
a high level representations that make up this image and you can do very quickly
be today what's died
first cutting DNA how do you have DNA
restriction enzymes
it turns out that the way you could cut DNA at particular places is as
follows from take piece of DNA
here's the double stranded piece of DNA
will go a g c t a g
a c g t c t t a c c
hydroxyl there three prime and let's go back to the other strand what we have
GG t
a c t
c t
HEC c
i dropped so there
prior my double stranded DNA
it turns out that there exists an enzyme
that recognizes that exact sequence
g a c
the enzymes
goes by the name
this prompted this enzyme looks scanned along the DNA
and it finds the sequence GATTACA
actually it's understand what about on the other strings it's a
what's reverse happens symmetric
that's very good and that in turn out most restriction enzymes do that OK so
what it does when it finds that
with the benefit of colored chalk is just showing up here is
it cleaves the DNA fragment
like that
and what it gives you the
a broken
double strand
with an over half
as you can see
five prime and three prime three prime
five prime
this has a hydroxyl here this has the phosphate there and this other fragments here's
a TTC
c c c c
but stops there
so what happens is
and this has a chance five prime
three prime
three prime five times
i get to
fragments of DNA
that have been broken there and heaven over
the overhang is complementary to two
those two sequences match match each other there's what's called the five prime overhang
and they are complementary so we have complementary
that is matching
five primary
this is called
he go or one
because it's purified this particular enzyme
from e i
strain are
and it's the number one such enzyme that was purified from
that is very simple and country
now here's a question
why bacteria
in enzyme like this
there are some people feel that the reason is that this enzyme is here precisely
to allow molecular biologists to cut and paste in this represents oppression on the part
of the solution
there are others who think that's less likely
find this stuff
shaggy dog story i have to tell you the following shaggy dog story so this
is a fun shaggy dog story and it's an MIT shaggy dog story because it
comes from work of salvatore loria who was very famous biologist who worked here at
so the gloria was studying bacteriophage lambda bacteriophage of the viruses
that infect bacteria
so he was studying bacteriophage and he took his bacteriophage and used to infect
a strain of bacteria strain
and he also used the to infect a strain of bacteria
strain b
so what that
what you do is you played long of bacterial cells
you kind of have us motion bacterial cells that you played here with virus mixed
in and where the virus
the virus
growth virus grows replicates and either kills or slows down the growth the cells so
the bacterial cells grow everywhere else but we're viral particle landed there is an absence
of bacterial cells and that whole
in the long run this whole thing is called a along of bacteria and the
holes in the one are called plaques
so we did this
he found that we needed to australia he got a bunch of plax
and when he did it on strain b
he didn't
no blocks
so what you suppose they measures
string these different styles resistant to the virus on the virus has come in into
much more efficient and perhaps more effective and so
this is one example clearly
young right people can think of many others
but today
i'm i'm i'm racing i was going to give another example of this kind of
thing but i don't really have time
light it up a little bit
so this is the so the last part and it better be only eleven minutes
because that's all we've got
you have plains to catch and places to be cars to drive
i thought i might sort of give very light sort of discussion of the some
of the tools that people in the
in articulatory phonetics use
to study some of these principles if i have time
talk about some speech corpora exist in other resources that in terms of workshops and
things like that
one of the most common measuring apparatus you you here referred to is the
and used in
acoustic like acoustic articulography
and actually that technology has recently gone through something of a revolution
is that now we see this core character can you see here is that too
this is organised
can you see
we i probably in the interview that you can see
but you can see he's got this is why are sort of
in his mouth
they been attached to a long standing in and lower lip in various places and
he's got a smile on his face now but wait half an hour
of uttering nonsense syllables and see how it is flying but the in this this
new technology actually will obtain a sort of three dimensional trajectories of of articulatory articulatory
motion and it's actually much easier to use the old system you had like a
helmet and would just in you had you had a very
careful placement of these coils
and the article and the article is for you to get the the measurements such
is that you thought you're getting over on the right is a young
we have one of these and we have a guy
vince clarke was came from the haskins at mcgill who who
does these kinds of experiments the
and the right here is the plots based two-dimensional plot exposition
position here for any x and y axis and each one of these colors corresponds
to the trajectory of the different articulators and you can see here
probably on your paper not here but there's a ton tip the image position back
position that corresponds to different placements of the of the of the coils
and so
what people have actually done with these is actually tried to do articulatory to acoustic
mapping because general you will have a parallel corpus of the
article these articulatory
measurements and then also the acoustics
is an electro
which is something you will like come off guard in
and you can european
football they wear mouth guards
now working
american football with that
more violent that this is not about this is this is an array of sensors
so expensive device shouldn't spit it out when you don't know but it does not
interfere with speech a little bit and so the speaker has to be trained as
to get used to it but what are the sensors to is a sort of
measure the percentage of contact between ten and the palate and it's it's it's sort
of and you can see here there is the the red
the dots here
correspond to the
the points at which
you know the tongue actually contacts the the palate and you see basically the point
here was to show that it's different depending on different different sort of acoustic prosodic
so there's also the electric got electrocorticographic which measures airflow through the glottis alex mention
the EMG that he's actually were suggesting is going to use it for real time
language translation actually
excites here
it's quite exciting that you would speak in same would force you to say the
now he's he admitted that was one of his more speculative ideas which is that
so many ideas
the the the other interesting measurement things are are used for you part partial direct
measurements and mentioned before
audio visual ASR are everywhere
basically you will in general you'll you'll go through a process of sort of synchronizing
your your video with the the
with the face and then sort of locating the mouth and so on doing feature
these days my understanding is that the features are not highly parameterised but in
back in the day they would use to form deformable templates and very highly parametric
representation there's lots of that now
and you
well you
one eight
so that nu
one more
so far
i seen
you need to be
this line will be
very good work the
bring he
based on these
what you're saying
one of the problems where we are
if are
right off the
and what
our goal
it is often very
as you can
or one
these are you
and t that means you can not find any smaller sequence
that satisfies one two
the support constraint what i didn't talk about with these
you can also see what is the maximum gap
that means if the elements appear too far away probably they don't make any sense
but sometimes in in in the DNA and the proteins
the physical position in the sequence is not as important as their
geometry composition because
you know they have this holding in
and the sequence there might look very far away once the therefore they might come
very close so sometimes you might look at their
the physical attraction rather than
the sequence position in a sequence
so there are various algorithms again if anybody interested the courts can be downloaded
so this is a way of showing how we can mind these things
so it's it's it's a set a credit to kielder them i don't want to
go through so there's some performance results
so i'll go to the next moral
graph model model mining
as i said these are details that you know genuinely interested in you really
spend time to become the concept
but i give you a general feel for what sequence mining is
so when you're looking in graphs what you're trying to do that you want to
find the
the subgraphs president once
one group and not
representing the other group so you can see in this case
this is a kind of annotated graphs
so what you're trying to show is that this structure is appears here
but not in this
and similarly this structure
it appears
in this but not in the and the reason is
you have
and you know if you look at this thing that right
there are necessary so this is set
so if you look at here
the zero is present there and edges all match and you don't have that much
so in the next one
so even though
this this edges common
and have done is i've removed is that means once you post this vertices
this is still a congress party
but if you say connected component then of course this is not
and three seats itself the congress because you don't have any that we see
so typically could be a chemical compound and then you're you're interested in these things
so in chemistry people were saying that you know you sometimes
somebody finds the molecules
and they wanted to know is that any molecule that already known that has a
lot of structure
chemical structure same as the one you want to know
so it's very very difficult so they not some gifted individuals
you seem to know it is there are you this chemical looks like similar to
support chemical
they really wanted to that can help and these guys have done this stuff
and they were able to
build a structure and i'll show you second
so what have done is
these are the list let's assume these are chemical structures
there are the chemical compounds and what they done is they've built some features using
these kinds of structures so for example
later they have chosen these features and how you choose these things again it's a
kind of contrast mining you can do
so what happens is that
you can map each of these graphs into in terms of these features
so the next thing is when equity comes what you do is you create is
mapped into one of these structures
what are the present in your query and and straightaway you look into this thing
and this made the
OK this like
phenomenally is
you can deal with matching
that are
somehow structurally similar and then you can find them much more
so this is a big impact in terms of chemistry and of the other
so that that's one one application of the contrast mining
and you can also do edit distances and all kinds of this
you know what to come to these measurements you know there a limited as i
said before i find so you can come up all kinds of measuring techniques
OK so
so when you are given two models general models and you want to compare them
how they differ or not
OK this measurements out all scoring functions can be given
they could be
euclidean distance or jakarta distance lots of things you can do
i'm sorry and rushing through
but i give you
good examples here and there
so that leaves it makes sense to you
so there are various measures between given for support it says somebody is given a
data set
i do one model clustering and you do have kind of clustering and and somebody
might ask how
different these clusterings of the big difference between them so you can do using
either rand index or card index and i'll how we could do
or we can do some kind of mutual information
or clustering error
OK so
equally but we would like it to be moved along our minds
we can more about what happens along the manifold
and what happens
in this somehow
outer space
and for that for for that purpose where adding this extra term this intrinsic movement
and this is going to be basically i want
the gradient
of this function
along the manifold itself along the probability distribution more generally so really what you want
you want to consider manifold with probability distribution on it
and i want that quantity
tools somehow baseball i want to control i want to have control over
how much it changes along my
you can shows theorem about this
basically there is some version of the representer theorem for the continuous case
so if you most so you can just imagine this being granted
there is a lot less
and then basically there some version of represent first one
let's keep this point
manifold for
so now what what is the norm the norm is really this is this gradient
and this is what we want to control
and this of course is controlled by the what lies and we said before however
there are various other things we can do we can for example take the differential
operators on the manifold for example one can try taking passionate maybe this would be
related cool fashion i can maps by donoho grimes
one can
i tried to do
one can do or exponential of the placenta
this is related to the work which actually
will be presented i think today
and there are
other things one can also the wall
this is to say that if we actually knew the manifold cover perfect solution would
we know exactly what optimise and we can do very well but the manifold is
not known
and we already if we already know how what to do with it because we
can estimate the laplace operator from the data
so instead of trying to actually
do this differential operator integrates gradient what we do we estimate the plus in from
the data and use this laplacian as the penalty for most and this love plus
and of course is just
it's just the matrix associated to the point
so it's an by n matrix where ice to help plus you so l is
the number of labelled points you is the number of unlabeled points so the the
slope plus and is the
helpless human
so on each data point with labelled and unlabelled you have
you have some sort of
when we put this here
you get the best now just becomes to evaluate this function
and few labeled and unlabeled points
and you
take f principles l
so now when you write a function that you labeled and unlabeled point you get
help us well
you multi you take from schools
times l
times f
so that's matrix
roll times the matrix times column so you get the number of this number you
the intrinsic penalty associated to you function
and you want to minimize
in the upper rhine across from modulation which is the dominant crop which they developed
in the same direction o in all across which is most sensical to integrate them
what comes out of that if you do that is
and he component of many EEG components that has looked like in one has the
difference between standard target cities differently if you look like
processing negativity into BP three and that's saying it's mismatch just saying it's processing negativity
that has mismatch in it to all the
here p
the first people here it the central topography which makes sense with with this type
of component and then correlates with
this map with the across trial modulation of this map which is bilaterally in the
temporal lobes but here in the frontal lobe and inverse
blob here the
the reason of the critical information
altogether if you look at after i literature EEG literature
makes sense with respect to the locus of generation of n one
of the auditory onset response will be looking at is some kind of joint representation
the auditory onset response and its modulation across trials the interesting part with this response
doesn't show the learning curve that we want to that we were so what did
we would think it should show but rather a transient
two the onset of random or the occurrence of random target after caesar regular once
was just responding to the incremental surprise it doesn't by itself could modulate with the
decrement of surprise
so that's that
i didn't
i have a good feeling of how robust this analysis would be
i mean you do a lot of things in their lot of
steps in this analysis which look
city or look tacky
so i took a look at the different set from a colleague of our stuff
and they've been published simultaneously with us
basically engineering science
they looked at the year end which is narrowly negativity which occurs only when subjects
making error in some kind of task
can be complex or simple test test with time constraints accuracy constraints they do that
they get this post response negativity at about fifty to eighty million seconds after after
response on so
it's a pretty specific component two errors
has this topography and correlates on a single trial basis with this region in the
anterior cingulate
which makes sense with respect to
these and data for example or to source estimates
which is nice so what we ask if this is what happens when people make
an error
how would we
go about and extract the brain signal that would predict that people are going to
make an error
is there anything that we can see in the from my data in the data
that will allow us to make a prediction that on the next trial you've so
so many chapters so present of it tends to make an error
we do the same thing
group ICA model
which just consists of this taking part
reduction part concatenation estimation of the components that protection of the components that we have
the step where we may component selection
which is
difficult to solve
we have some some map based criteria so we do the ICA like like suggested
the previous talk multiple times on non identical subsets of the data as to subsample
big data set into
neighboring voxels
it should be calling it should result in the same
components if its physiological importance because of the spatial correlation and whatever is not seen
across these red repetitions of the analysis is not taken into
consideration further then we look at these components in sec whether their physiological not
with respect to cortical generation so there's many components that we need to see is
components that relate to
blood flow
which tend to be many components because there's flow signal this dynamic signal into india
from my and then we have an additional step we check the population relevance of
these components is there on the average or on the FDR statistic
and activation of this component
gift of the group in
group ICA is
detect components in the population when they consistent about ten percent in the subjects so
you do see components that some subjects have some components of the subjects have
there are not significant
it's not that all subjects have to have all components
to start with
because that makes the text difficult
and then when when we when we when we check those
the components that have an additional event response that
has some some some role in the
in the stimulus paradigm we take further
and do some deconvolution here
when we when we do that with a stimulus timing
and then
multiply the pseudo inverse of convolution metric of the system's timing with the with the
time course to get an estimated rest
and with the graph we can get back to the parametric modulation
so we take out the human dynamic lag
of the data
and when we do that
we get
this kind of map
in the inferior frontal gyrus
for example many of superior frontal gyrus
with this editor have the starts being the individual observations
and this type of modulation
this trial here being the error trial
and before the error occurs this
reduces activation over thirty seconds
so we thought that five
we got another component which is in a precarious
an event related the activation
that gradually
increases its activation
before never occurs
these two systems here interact
in an antagonistic fashion if you will and
if it looks like
if tries look like this here so this would be
bigger than zero and this would be smaller than zero probability of making error on
the next trial increases by fifty percent
if it's the other way around it decreased by forty percent
the point is we wouldn't be able to see this with the standard model
currently we did the group ICA of the data and got this type of component
which is the stimulus like you're p with this
negative deflection poster early
makes it into visual and two
we also have gradient before error shows a slightly different modulation after or during the
error but then again there's great here here here which makes this a coherent system
conclusion of this
that a makes EEG fmri together not just for artifact rejection
improve the detection of correspondences in concurrent data
we did that in this case with the one i meant
we we cover something that is known that we don't mess with the previous
this is a
and they have some parameters which could be for example in the case of multivariate
gaussian distribution the mean vector and covariance matrix
after this
see i'm sorry see means conditional independence
motivated distributions extracted according to conditional independence this is the subject of the second hour
of of course
essentially the structure of the these
of these
mortified when the distributional study
is essentially
given by
pattern that call pattern conditional independence
and so for me
maybe some of these
but if you sure take over the world some
so their bodies
you may want to answer this questions for example if you have this probabilistic model
you may be interested in computing what's the probability of a particular
realisation of these right
love value
think of these spirals from x one to xn for example
pixels in an image OK
if you think of them as pixels in the image
we can
assume you have a model for
the noise images
and then the question is
what's the probability of a given the just some so
we want to compute the probability of particle element of all the image space
to be very difficult
we'll see
because you have many variables and they interact with each other it's not like the
the interact exactly precisely according to these
i conditional independence structures
for him
and the other question is they are approximation for what's the most likely image
most likely corrected the image from the
appropriate model for
for the lies
i think that
it's possible to say
it doesn't mean however that
a particular case of a noisy image processing it doesn't mean that you can have
an estimator for the more so
you can estimate the noise if you know how
images behave
natural images
you can
two compute how that
the images from
what it should be made
maybe you should have across the image created for performing inference
we need to have knowledge
i want you
so again the next four years
OK let's assume you want to try to
and so
the following question
we want to compute
the probability
we have
what if i distribution with anybody
and let's assume that every one of these viruses the discrete fire
for example
this described by with that takes only two
possible then
good example could be
i don't know
the weather the weather can be made ward of
it also required to be in the hands of tail
for each one of these viruses from x one to xn can attain two values
just making a simple example
we can ask the question if i have this model is multivariate model that combines
all the five
i mean interested in the outcome of one particular driver
for example if you have a model of of the word in australia may be
interested in the question what's the probability it's going to rain today and dark
i don't have a model for diary only i have a model for the entire
in australia
so the question is not interesting whether it's
training camp not training camp really silly when operating in sydney