hard work
now really
what they
i think
if get
you can use
and it's not
the or
it meant
we have
so what
you know one
many of know
they a
you know about
and that
then of course the end you make predictions and decisions
you know
obviously a lot of what i'm going to talk about is in this
modelling framework here but there are other parts of it the make me uncomfortable
john get to the more depressed part of my talk
two the
sort of a nice this is very nice find modelling a particular problem
i want to really solve it
i tried put some understanding into that etcetera
what about the second part of this question what is an operations let's talk about
parametric versus non parametric model so we're all the same page
parametric models assume some finite set of parameters data
in the parameters
are independent of the observed data in the sense you know that's that's that's captured
by this equation here
you know if you're if you're frequencies this is fine you just open conditioning bar
but essentially the idea is that you you capture
everything there is to know about the data
through your parameters theta
this is what peter orbanz was describing in his first tour was talking about the
pattern and the noise
i think that captures the pattern
but now
we have a parametric model a finite set of parameters is the man
obviously after a good breakfast a like-minded was russia
the complexity of the model is bounded
even if the amount of data is unbounded
so there is if you like information theory and of course i do as well
the parameters are information channel between
your training data in your future predictions on that channel has bottleneck as like traffic
jams through that channel because it is of finite which
non parametric models assume that the data distribution can be defined in terms of such
a finite set of parameters
but they can also be defined by summing some dimensional parameter theta
so you add more lanes to your
information highway so that you don't get traffic jams
and now we can think of our parameter data as a function
the nice thing about that is the amount of information that they can capture about
the data the
it can grow as the amount of data grows
so again
data has been this
efforts to some five precision
and you want capture some bits to make predictions and this makes them more flexible
so that part of the point of doing nonparametric modeling
now why nonparametrics i think actually that transcends the bayesian thing
actually if you look around in machine learning
a lot of successful methods
are essentially nonparametric
i like the whole kernel revolution with ESPN's and things like that and the related
gas processes these are nonparametric models in our view that's one of the reasons why
they were so successful
of course kernel method is replaced the neural networks is a big paradigm machine learning
and people came back afterwards and said i'll make bigger neural networks
or bigger and deeper neural networks
and these are not nonparametric into formal mathematical sense
but there has been a lot of parametric OK
you know one of geoff hinton or young raccoons the networks
well million parameters which is like more than my nonparametric model ever expresses a sense
that i have on my computer so
no no no i say move
the was sixty minutes
we show you what it does
nobody does you know we're six units
so these are also successful because they are very flexible
even methods like to pooh-pooh like k nearest neighbors are pretty damn good
and they are pretty flexible and there
so nonparametric but there are very nonparametric
so what
no here
which is exactly the machinery are essentially nonparametric
and then if you can read down there
or highly scalable OK so there are also you know that you know i don't
know how to measure success in machine learning i just look at you know
two things that people are excited about and are excited about these very fancy
possible evidence or they excited that they can run logistic regression on a hundred billion
data points in
twenty thousand million dimensions and because you know some methods you can make a very
very scalable and you're google or microsoft or yahoo you care about the law
those are successful as well i don't want to put that in fact if i
was working in industry government i would probably be
you know
less interested in the school mathematical flexible things and wanting to figure out how to
do it is the progression of cloud of ten thousand computers
nonparametrics is successful thing isn't restricted to bayesian
but they are already argued bayesian methods are very nice it's the one thing the
two together
so another way to approach this
is to start out with like a wish list
OK i want do machine learning or or statistics
what are the desirable properties of my methods
when we write down analysts this is
my list from late last night so i apologize if i do i any of
your favorable favorite desirable properties
so here you go
good predictive performance
sort of goes hand in hand with good predictive performance
robust to overfitting depends you know the
all this industry of figuring out regularizers and things like that
model based i think is this sort of
you know if you're doing it there are some advantages to this is not absolutely
necessary good predictive performance in your flexible and robust
it doesn't have to be that whatever you're doing corresponds to particular model
but you know if you have a model based
approach you can make it you can make it modular and filled with other things
what i'm about to show you now
is that have come back by the way and revisit this again when i do
which corresponds sampling algorithm and eligibility traces what they should be thinking about to anticipate
legibility traces that marcato is very good
in that is independent state space are also comes with a cost that cost and
a high variance cost so just to anticipate eligibility traces
is the answer
in reinforcement learning to the question of how do we get the advantage of monte
that is independent of ci the state space
and reduce the variance of the same time i'll come to really traces and talk
about that
OK i want to show you just
popular ontologies and applications just two
break the monotony of just talking here is a a video
from peter stone slabs
are using direct reinforcement learning to learn to improve
the gate of walking robots so he has the backing just visit in three weeks
ago and it's really funny to see this is got this
pretty big sized
soccer field because they play soccer these robots what he has is he has you
see because of the OECD's little
poles with these bars of pink and white and so on and what is what
you want to doing is are continuously walking back and forth
back and forth
and they know where they are because they see these bars at the end and
they can make their stopping point where the bar becomes big enough
in the visual field now what they're trying to do is improve off at the
so they're walking gait parameters
you know they have like i think seven rate parameters it to determine how they
and the idea is to make the learned to make
learn to make it walk faster because walking faster would he be an advantage while
playing soccer because you get to the ball
right so just keep walking back and forth
and a learning
using a direct reinforcement learning methods for
tuning these for updating parameters the action choices on the parameter choices the sensors are
for proper reception they know in the past around you know
how far they are from the from the
the the target points on that things like this so i want to show you
so before training this is how to walk before training
looks pretty clumsy to me
but if the walker knees because when the play soccer ball
and the ball needs to be captured between the legs of the working these because
the ball gets captured between the legs and this is after training
you see the work much better much much smaller
so it's an application
it's really faces was walking the walk for days on end to try and improve
here's another one on where somebody using indirect methods and so the helicopter control problem
so so
started can really tell it has done so it's helicopter control problem and a few
hundred causing helicopter but it's about twice the length of the stable that big
that's from
the nose to the end tail
and its body itself is about as big as the stable the the front part
and so let me just give you a little
how house was housework was done we simply moving on
school again
the video
let's see this policy or this one
so this works started because they want to believe helicopter they could take part in
these competitions in this competition where people play with helicopters and the required maneuvers to
them and what i think you're seeing emmanuel where
its nose it's its nose to create a serql so it has to move in
this circle
it's very hard for people who very very few people can do it
big lots lots of time
with these
with these helicopters two black you get these people to get people to do it
and how to do it is that if they had a
the bilinear let model
of state action the next day
so they used about half an hour training with whom you pilot came in and
flew his helicopter
and they collected at state action next mapping
they train neural nets
with that mapping
not a model
and they use that model
two do interact training
so for the optimal control policy
four that helicopter
these are specific interact algorithm that i'm not talked about but you can imagine using
any sort of indirect methods that learn eleven model and all the good videos he
got and doings website policy lots of videos very recently they actually made the helicopter
flying upside down
which is very very hard parity there are only a handful of people in the
country can actually make these very hard these
big size helicopters actually fly upside down
it's very hard to get but they apparently
almost effortlessly manages to make
in direct reinforcement learning work on helicopter is quite amazing
quite amazing to master
you sort of more or less no
having this what i just talked about
how to do this court except you lack the magic touch than doing seems to
have one making very large things work on these matters that so
this to illustrate two different applications of direct and indirect reinforced
question for acme question if you can you're asking more about this application i can
tell you about that
or i can one
you know land right so it
they learn
in those they had been
i the higher because really
you have to be
do this so
it was the system must be able
raise your right
so i can very that you see a helicopter flying
well only tell
it's like this one looks like it might be
normal normal way and then the camera pans back they see three
according the top line
well done
i would like to thank you because you
very briefly one algorithm for sparse sampling out from you before i do that i
mean let me ask you this question
i told you about the algorithm
monte carlo
for solving the policy evaluation from which says if you want to find the value
real valued parameters so it is in one parameter models
but if you look at it you see that for
distribution in the second order in the first order models
the two parameters there is one
and element of the one parameter model which is close to it at least in
euclidean distance
so you would expect that this model
is a lot more like the
one of the two parameters
this model
so both of one parameter
but this one resembles the two parameters a lot more and can fit random data
a lot better
so indeed this normalized maximum likelihood term will be much larger for this model
and that will
translated of this term being larger
so now let's compare this to bayesian model selection
so base so-called bayes factor model selection
if you ignore the priors the models which usually can
you simply
because the model which maximizes
the marginal likelihood of the data so you have
this is this effort you've seen before the integral now over the probability of the
data according to theta
integrated by the prior density of theta
you can look at that for each model and then you pick
the model for which this
integrated probabilities larger so minus log integrate probability smallest that's what bayesian model selection bias
so you can also approximate this by the plus approximation so it's basically taylor expansion
and if you do that it turns out that again on the conditions of the
model this turns out to be equal to this
so you see it's almost the same as this base there's something very similar for
minimum description tools
normalized makes like the minimum description length
in particular you see that these terms
they do not depend on the sample size
so for large
base will do the same
as you
if the number of miles you compare
is a finite
so how does this term relate to this term that well
you see that in base what happens depends on your prior
of course basis depends on the prior
basically what you see here this is the prior
of to evaluated at the maximum likelihood
basically if you're lucky
the maximum likelihood turns out to be the region of parameter space to which gave
a high prior probabilities so your prior assumptions were kind of
then this term will be small because the prior density of the maximum likelihood parameter
will be large
you will give large probability to the data if however you were unlucky and you
get small prior to what turns out to be the probability maximizing theta
then this will be
the probability will be smart smaller mines log probability will be larger so this depends
on your priors
course some bayesian so-called objective bayesians have proposed priors
but you can use
if you don't have any clear prior knowledge
and the most famous of these is the so-called jeffreys prior
which is defined
by the square root of the determinant of the fisher information matrix
usually if you that if you integrate over all theta doesn't become one but
something larger so you have to normalize to make the probability
so this is what sometimes objective bayesians
that's OK to use the model selection and if you plot this in here
you see that you get minus log
of the square root
of the fisher information and they here plus lack of this grid of the fisher
information only council and what remains is plus log of the denominators yet plus lack
of this so then you see that they actually become the same
up to some order of one
so if use jeffreys prior
then asymptotically base and MDL based on the normalized maximum likelihood become actually the same
so interesting is jeffreys prior was proposed in nineteen thirty nine as a kind of
uniform priors on on the space of parameters but on the space of distributions so
the space of parameters depends on your parametrisation is essentially arbitrary
the space of distributions can be be defining the more generic matter
manner and if you put a uniform prior on that a user base
you get
essentially the same as and you at least in the simple setting we're talking about
here in more general settings
it turns out you don't always get the same
because for example if you have nonparametric if used in nonparametric settings then with some
priors you will actually
not compressor data so there are some instances of bayes which can be thought of
as MDL
because they don't lead to compression of the data
given the time i'll skip these less well just talk about these two
there's a certain very important interpretation of what we've been doing which is the so-called
predictive or prequential interpretation
if you codes you can only
you can also look at what happens outcome by outcome
and then you can think of the minus log probability assigned to an outcome as
a loss function
so you can just think of probability says prediction strategies
and and then
one reasonable way to measure how good they are
on the particular outcome but looking at the minus log of the probability assigned to
the outcome
if you assign probability one to the outcome minus log one zero so you loss
is zero if you assign probability zero
you're also be infinite but you can also think of this is
if you use the distribution
as the cold then it's the number of bits you need to encode that particular
so if your goal is compressed the data as much as possible this is logical
loss function
it turns out that it's
if you use
to sequentially predict data
it turns out
then you get you can look at the community of los so that's the some
of these individual or classes
and it turns out that is the same
the code length you need if you could base the whole data so what does
it mean
well this is what we've seen before you get the basic universal code
so is the basic mixture distribution you can turn it into a cold and this
is the code length get for each particular outcome
now you can also use basic when surely to predict outcomes so you have to
predict the first outcome using the bayes predictive distribution for that then you observe the
first outcome you predict the second outcome using the conditional distribution
given the first outcome
and you have a certain level class then you predict the third outcome
using the conditional distribution based on the first two outcomes to predict the fourth outcome
using the conditional distribution based on the first three outcomes et cetera you at all
the losses
so this is what you do you at some of these losses
we always predict using
based condition on the previous outcomes
of course by the definition of the word implies this is equal to this
now because the sum of the logarithms the log of the product
and this
factors in this distribution
you're performing some asians
and that sort of shrinking things down it's making new factors and shrinking them and
there's a very nice graph theoretic correspondence that you're watching this residual graph sort of
and shrink down for instance to the target point here i was interested in x
one so the nice correspondence between the factorisation in the summation and the graph theoretic
properties here
and so what we're going to see is that some kinds of graphs are actually
nice graphs in that they have good elimination orderings and some graphs are not nice
graphs they don't have good elimination orderings and so essentially the elimination algorithm it's useful
because it gives you an algorithmic way to understand why this graph structure affect how
complex it is to for instance some and perform marginalization
it sort of tells you that the way in which the graph is connected controls
how the elimination behaves and that determines in the end how much computational complexity pay
so any questions on that
before i move on i want to move on with that kind of intuition i'd
like to move on to talking about trees which is one of the simplest case
of graphs that have very nice elimination ordering
well i don't know
right so
here i was giving you one example and i had some two cliques on a
three clique
so in general you have to start with whatever model you're given whatever used are
right if you give me a graph that to start with had let's say
clique sizes of alpha and or something it wouldn't be actually very useful model because
you know to store things you'd have to pay complexity to the alpha and for
binary variables
yes so that that's the key point that
elimination can only make things worse for you
and the issue is how much worse doesn't make it for you
this example actually i mean it made new three clique it that there's edge
but i already had three clique so it didn't really make things any worse it
all for me things were sort of
there was no additional sort of jump complexity
what will see is the trees
the simplest case of no jumping complexity but other graphs there is a huge jump
in complexity between this graph and in the residual graph what you get after eliminating
so any other questions about elimination
again i encourage you to display with this example it's it's a simple example but
it actually has all the basic ingredients that you need just to get intuition of
how this works this is not what you implement but it's useful to to play
with because it sort of gives you a feeling for what's going on why why
graph structure actually matters here
OK so
let's move on to the the sum product algorithm
let me first talk about it on trees and then i'm going to talk about
on a more general class of graphs that are called junction trees
and so the first part is talking about ordinary trees recapping what sam did yesterday
but again i'm follow the elimination perspective so it's it's from a somewhat different point
of view
so again remember that tree
is this simply an undirected graph here that has no cycles
you can always
i choose a particular node in the tree to the root
we think about this being the root and then you sort of move
words and you hit the nodes
on the edge and these are called leaves for the obvious reasons
so you want to think about this is again put appointed SMA yesterday's elimination is
but i remember elimination i sort of presupposes that you know i was sitting at
node one and i cared about note one
and that's all i care about in this case
but it could be the case that i care about note one and note seven
or back about all nodes simultaneously that's quite possible
if i give you a noisy image from the telescope
you might care about for instance removing the noise is called de noising you don't
care about just one node you care about all the pixels who'd like to actually
do things simultaneously over all the nodes at once
so if you think about this but if you think about running elimination you see
right away that being very stupid
it's sort of violating the basic principle of of algorithms you're not recycling computations you
doing the same computations again and again and again you only need to do them
so really the sum product algorithm is just a clever way to run elimination simultaneously
for every node of the tree that's all it's doing it's it's cleverly running elimination
for every node
but it's doing in a way that you don't waste computationally only the computation the
minimum number of times needed
now as well by the way notice that if ten is zero
that's going to take care of a constant term two
in other words the reason is the constant term from because that corresponds to the
cosine of zero t which is one
suppose i input instead a and
cosine entity
all you do is multiply the answer by a
the same year multiply the input by b and you multiply the response that's because
equations of linear equations
and now i am i gonna do
i'm going to have the mop
if i add them up for the different ends
and take account also the n equals zero corresponding to the first
constant term
the sum of all these according to my fourier formula is going to be f
what's the summer of
this is the response
the corresponding response as well
it's going to be some asian a and
plus b and y and
the response to the side
that'll be the sum from one to infinity and there will be a constant some
sort of constant term here was just c one
so in other words if this input produces that response
and these are things which we can calculate will lead by this formula for is
the response to things which otherwise we wouldn't have been able to calculate namely any
periodic function of period two pi
will have as is the procedure will be
got periodic function with period two pi
find its fourier series and i'll show you how to do that today
find its fourier series
and then the response to that for a general effort he will be
infinite series of functions
we're the why these things are things you already know how to calculate the responses
to sines and cosines and you just form the some
with those coefficients now
why it is that were it works by the superposition principle
so this is true
the reason i can do the adding and multiplying by a constant i'm using the
superposition principle
this input produces that responds the sum of a bunch of inputs produces the sum
of the corresponding responses and why is that why can i use the superposition principle
because the old and the e
it's OK
since the old is linear
that's what makes all this work
so what we're going to do today is also how to calculate those fourier series
i will not be able to use it to actually solve the differential differential equation
that will take us
pretty much all period two
show how to calculate the fourier series
OK so i solve differential equations on monday wrong
probably won't even get to it then because
the calculation of the fourier series is sufficient amount of work that you really want
to know all the possible tricks and shortcuts there are a forcefully they're not
very clever tricks they just obvious things but it'll take me a period to point
out the obvious things
obviously my sense it's not yours
and finally the third day will be we will solve differential equations are actually carry
out the program but the main thing we're going to get out of it is
another approach to residents
because the things that we're going to be interested in
picking out
which of these terms may possibly produce residents
therefore very crazy
your training data it will get
a score of zero
which means that
the probability that class is going to be zero the probability the complement class will
also be easier to just never seen that word
a very common thing to do
is to put a little bit of smoothing in here so we put on a
waiting an extra value here on the top and bottom
and typical examples and might be one he might be one here what's
so this is the this is the
one you already used for estimating the probability of the word
here in the class
this is called the multinomial distribution
so it's a fancy term for very simple idea
and this particular use of m and p is called the dirichlet prior
again a fancy name for very simple things
if we use these counts of plus one plus point five which means basically the
probabilities go to you know one half never seen
r work before
OK so that basically means that the school for particular class given list of words
is going to be
essentially if one work in log space which is
probabilistic models like this almost always more convenient
because the actual values could very close to zero very quickly
we can and we end up with this by scoring everything by this particular formula
right which you could see is very simple very easy to implement and the only
things you really need to keep track of this the number of times each word
appears in the number of words that are in category
so this is a very very simple algorithm
and it turns out to work quite well
we've got a little
dirichlet prior here OK
now we only need to the nice thing about this is what i was going
to particular document but looking at the score for class
we or non we
i only need to look at the accounts of the words that actually appear in
the document
all right so
i'm accumulating counts for many many different words are right i'm looking at a large
collection say twenty thousand news articles all have counts for thousands of words but each
these counts are going to be
stored in various
pathway right so we only need to worry about counts for the words that actually
occur in the classes they actually occurring
the total number of words for each class so i can actually do this quite
efficiently even if there
a lot of classes there are lot of words
so this is a pretty common technique
it's quite likely that one of you
it's quite likely to each of you have actually use one of these things if
ever used any
learning system that has an adaptive spam filter you know all male reader where you
can sort of classify things as delicate remembers that
most of these work using some variation of nineties is naive bayes
so on the first paper that was published on this was like in the late
nineties nineteen ninety eight and i was at microsoft
and there were some other papers just around the same time the talked about using
naive bayes for spam filtering
and it works fairly well
or at least it it works fairly well until people started getting the idea of
words that were in the message
by using variants look a little bit different so you know instead saying
you know free they might say four
you know three three or something like that
that was in nineteen ninety eight so five years later there was basically a huge
email filters that you could download a lot of these are based on naive bayes
you can sort of tell sometimes from the names
so people were playing with these things
this is
one thing which was in the sourceforge repository was the one of the top downloaded
things for quite awhile
so this is kind of cool so we've got to machine learning program based on
research ideas for a few years ago that is already sorted in wide use
naive bayes has got some really nice things is very fast it's very easy to
it's very well understood formally in the sense that there is this nice probabilistic model
which you used to justify the algorithm
OK and people have been using for a long long time and so
it's well understood experimentally
the bad things about naive bayes is it usually
if you think about are
the problem or if you look at alternative albums you can often find other of
that work will be better so you paying for a little bit a little bit
for their simplicity and ease of implementation
another problem is what would really like these probabilities to be good estimates so if
someone is if they if they so cial probability that's really is point seven
you'd really like to be able to
i believe that probability so you could pass it along to use it in some
other systems
in the later stages of processing but in fact those don't tend to be accurate
just because the assumptions made about the model shows simple
o thing in practice the probability tend to get very very close to zero ones
are not not very useful
that's the first step that's the warm up now we're going to talk about some
learning methods
like naive bayes are relatively fast simple to implement and and and fairly practical for
for text classification methods
so let me go back to this question how we represent text all right
so i talked about a couple things like removing stop words and
seven words
another very common thing you're going to do
to collapse the multiple occurrences of words into a a into something single figure
all right
so this to motivate the recall in the naive bayes algorithm we looked at list
of words
and this what was generated independently
which basically meant the contribution to the score
i was
was insensitive to the position
you get the same contribution to you get the same score you took the words
and reversed were shuffled and randomly
so what does it matter made we don't need to store state the orders rather
than saving is of words in the west we can just say if you know
words of the stems that appear the document and the number of times they appear
so that's basically all the information in this document
r modulo the fact that you know here there's an order of the words here
there's no
right so this is somewhat simpler way of representing the document and
if you look at this particular
picture of the document were essentially we done is i've
i've put in bold made a little bit larger the words that are most frequent
what we're saying here is one function
of a
plus b
which is equal to the same sort of function of a times the same for
a sort of function of b in other words
when we multiply these functions we get
a function of the some of those arguments
what functional form does that
so in other words
the the a class b
equals the to the eight times each day
right so it suggest
that there's an exponential
i suggest
there's also some physical insight that we can apply to the problem
first of all
we expect that states with higher energy in general be less probable than state of
lower energy
you know if it's
it's called not much thermal energy around the how much energy to the particle in
equilibrium collection of particles
i have
at thermal equilibrium
well you know that there's not much the letters around you don't expect it to
be very likely the particle is a huge amount of energy that one individual particle
as it could happen
from some random collisions that just happened
the bulk of the energy that one particle
but on balance is not going to be very probable
lower energy will be more probable
the other thing is you know even thinking about something like that
temperature comes in immediately
if you raised the temperature lot surely we have to expect many more molecules will
start to to become energized more energy
lower probability for higher energy
but the probability violation go up if the temperature goes up
in other words the the ratio of energy the temperature
should be involved here
i should go
as you know i was
should depend
i over t
we can start with this
functional form
you know by the way there's no reason we can't have in general we have
some constant here right we haven't changed anything to do that
and now
let's just use the
a little bit of physical intuition
there were
thinking about here to
refine this just a little bit let's right
we expect the p
the eyes some
exponential to the miners
i over t four c
some constant greater than zero so
this will have the property then the as
energy goes up the probability goes down but it scaled by temperature by raising the
temperature that makes the higher energy states
yet more and more likely
this is
functional form for probability
of the molecule being in state
with energy by i and the only difference between this and what's written conventionally
is the
re the constant is labeled so really what we have is he i
of the i
is proportional to
e to the minus ERI
so you're just kt
we're k
it's called the boltzmann
constant and it's just equal to far
overall the god number the
gas constant per molecule rather than per mole
one way to
try to rationalize this is is
you've probably seen you'll see arrhenius kinetics right
arrhenius rate laws
if you remember what that looks like
you get this rate constants
arrhenius rate constant
some constant they times e to the minus p a all were or
t relax
seen that before
so what's happening here e a is what is an activation
the idea
is a graph
products and there's some barrier you've got to get over the activation energy before you
have reactions to the rate
depends on surrounding that activation barrier
this is really coming from the same
the idea is this which is
the probability
one of the molecules having this much energy
depends on the minus
energy over this is promotional this from all
the exact same relation
so the idea in the context of kinetics
is that the rate depends on
how many molecules can get up here
what the probability is over
getting enough energy to go over the barriers
and that energy that probability is given by these expressions
so in this form you've seen this kind of dependence before and very explicitly
OK let me just
take it one
a small but important step father
which is
that proportionality constant
series untapped one coefficients and plug them into formula
this combination
we take the direct product of two
representations two
fourier transfer matrices conjugate them by the appropriate that for matrices are multiplied by the
appropriate some of
three matrices and the other side of this is the natural generalization of the by
spectrum to noncommutative groups
people are aware of this but it's not widely known especially not widely known in
applied communities
it's also interesting to note that
that this
does become quite large objects re c even in the original classical
the case
what we had was that the original of fourier transform was obviously of the same
size as the original signals but if the original signal was still numbers there ten
minus one is like an n dimensional vector but the by spectrum was and squared
dimensional objects
so it's larger have completeness but the price to pay
by spectrum
there is also larger but the individual components of very large as well because here
taking representation matrices are taking the kronecker product so individual
not only do we need some twice over the set of integral do so representations
we also
four rather large matrices that will contain these invariants
the interesting thing
and by no means trivial
thing is that the completeness property survives in this case for all compact groups and
even some
exceptional noncompact groups
so this was a major result that was approved by caroline his thesis in the
mid nineties
and then
it can i think it kind of sort of remained on the
the fringes of mathematics because applied communities were not necessarily
noncommutative harmonic analysis literature mathematicians did not necessarily see the
how this links up with the math problems in pure mathematics and not very many
people use this thing
but i think this is a really powerful
and deep results
what is the difference the generalisation of the by spectrum to noncommutative and is the
straightforward so as i just tried to explain to you it sort of does follow
the general logic of how you do things when you go from ordinary harmonic analysis
to noncommutative harmonic analysis proving this theory
this theorem is actually not trivial it goes quite deep into representation theory and exploits
the kind of duality between groups and the set of any country usable representations
i also have to say
that there is one condition on the
r in the theorem which at first sight is innocuous and has a direct analogue
in the classical case and that is that the theorem the complete this part of
the theory only works if the original spectrum is nonsingular so each matrix in the
four original fourier transform has to be invertible
so in that sort of
a set of functions of measure zero where one of those
matrices disappears becomes singular
and the
i invariance property still holds because just depends on the on the straightforward and went
the uniqueness thing fails
so it's important to bear in mind when we try and apply this result in
real problems
in particular it's important when we try and apply it to problems
when the original function is not really the group but something that the group is
acting on
so these are called homogeneous spaces this is this is where we put the
stuff too
were right
so what is the kind of context in which
in which
this is noncommutative by spectral calculus results are going to be useful in practical problems
well the sort of
things that i have in mind are things like functions on the sphere and thinking
about what happens to them when we rotate the sphere
so can to consider the two sphere which is just ordinary unit sphere
three three-dimensional space
and consider that we have a function
this complex valued functions
on on the sphere
now if you look at it
so three so the group of three-dimensional rotations
that acts naturally on the sphere rotating the sphere and rotating the function
with it
what's interesting is too
developer sequence of invariance for such functions
which are going to be invariant to this action so the action of
the rotation group on the sphere
now it's clear that the sphere in the rotation group some related but they're not
the same thing
so here the function is not on the rotation group it's on the sphere
and that is an important distinction what's happening here
in mathematical terms is that we have a function of the group but one what
is called a homogeneous space of of group by homogeneous spaces
basically any space
on which group acts
so clearly
if you have a point on the sphere then the rotation group sticks it somewhere
in the sphere
and also
the other requirement is that the entire space has to be swept out by the
action of the group which is again trivially
satisfied in the case of the sphere and this is a three-year-old so you have
the sphere a point on it so you start with the north pole
this is your x o and then you consider have rotation matrices rotation matrices acting
on as point x o then you then
you get all the points on the sphere and this weekend so be about the
entire sphere so you can get anywhere in the sphere just by rotating any
single point you start out with so this is what homogeneous spaces it turns out
that this whole business of fourier transformations naturally generalizes to this round because
when you take the
all you have to do is to choose a single
sort of initial elements such as the north pole in this case and you can
here you have somehow
look like you'd involves all the all the layers interacting in a complicated way you
still have this funny thing that
it's hard to train these things
because of the death
but if you
find a way to initialize this deep structure by
training each level in an unsupervised way
we really get better results
actually he's getting the best
results on mnist which doesn't use convolutional structures
OK so now i'm going to
i spend a bit of time
tell you about
evidence to try to understand why these
these things work
so i've already talked about
why deep architectures such
it might be interesting but why
we get so big difference in performance when we consider training
this unsupervised layer wise
versus training everything together with respect to some single objective
this bill here
right what one first observation is that you can as i said earlier you can
replace rbms by other
the first
things that have been tried or auto encoders and variations of autoencoders particular
in any other constructive been working on sparse autoencoders
but you can also do things like kernel PCA
we've been exploring various autoencoders called denoising autoencoders
i will say a few words about
and then there are some other methods which is very different
the idea is really going to learn
two two two
to use an unsupervised training criterion
at each level or maybe at some intermediate level
tries to learn an embedding of the input
so we already know a lot of learning algorithms for
a supervised learning of embedding otherwise transforming the input into some space in the way
that capture variations well that's exactly what we want in this setting i've been talking
and so
various embedding algorithms have been
blood into this framework and combined with this revised criterion
these these experiments showed you can you can get
really really better results than if you train
everything from scratch
globally with a surprise criteria
one of the interesting variants of this that we're investigating recently
and so there's an ICML paper
what have you know
which is the group but any c
and and my group that the next steps
is about using slow feature so-called slow features for this embedding
one simple idea is that if you have sequential data like video
the features
many features that would be interesting would be abstract features that don't change very quickly
over time so if you consider a sequence of images very likely
the identity of the objects in
the sequence would stay the same from one frame to the next frame
and many other such features i also
the constant or change slowly
so you can take advantage of that
in order to
features to do something
it has to that
property and also you want them to do the same thing so there
details there but
but it's completely unsupervised and can be used to initialize
was the networks or can be combined
so you can have an unsupervised criterion unanimous frustrating and combine them
and train with respect to the some of them
one type of
level local
the model is the autoencoder
let come back
OK so
what is not one quarter
don't clutter
it is
simply something that predicts its input
going through some intermediate code
the simplest autoencoder is just
one linear transformation one fixed nonlinear
transformation like the hyperbolic tangent of sigmoids
and then another linear transformation
and this
tries to predict the input
so you optimize all the parameters to get
the output look like the input using some
so once you've done that training this
which might as well why would be useful
you could stack
these autoencoders sold
the representation you get here
can be used as input for training as second with one
so why would these be useful well actually
if the whole thing was linear you would get
something like
like an unfair comparison here i'm sort of making sort of the treatment of the
maximum likelihood estimator something that little bit of theory
and no
nobody in their right mind would we like to compare
this is the probability with which with other properties and in this is true that
people don't actually
choose the model based on this exactly for that reason why so if you use
dataset two two two to fit your promise to optimize your problem then you know
this not a good estimate of the actual
of the actual predictive abilities of that model but they have to do something else
an unfortunate thing is that doesn't really seem to be an ice and so within
the framework
as to to what you should do instead
so the core problem is that you're reusing the data to do two things once
you try to estimate the problem
and the other thing you want to do is you want to
figure out
how good is the model actually
the one way of resolving the problem is to use cross validation conservation you
yes you a two
sets or into into multiple that and then you train on some subset of the
data and then you try to evaluate on the on the other set and then
that remove this problem
but instead you get different problem you get different problem that you need to fit
multiple models and you need to you to fit these models using only a subset
of the data
say if you split the data into in the new train one half and you
still have to value things then the problem that you're now only using half the
and in real applications this might be a problem i might be much harder to
find the relationship and that you only have happened many fish
they also ways around that so you try to use
you know
anyway cost the nation where you see the thing we only hold out
you know very small part of an effort
trying to model
OK so
the the
initially thought the mysterious thing we had here was that the more the model that
doesn't really
it doesn't seem to officially
the that that to model data well one actually got no votes for this model
from from a hundred people the
prior probability must have been in these smaller than one over a hundred
but this model the base in the form of a treatment with a that the
model as well
ever so slightly more likely actually of that small equally likely
it turns out
six the numbers in the higher
how can that be y whereas whereas the mechanism coming from that ensuring that this
is happening
he is one of my
there were pictures of try to explain how this comes that you might have seen
this picture before i think it
it's a picture which is not so easy to understand will worthwhile
each trying to think hard about what's going on the
what i find one i want here
finding the value of the marginal likelihood
for notation
don't want to talk about is the different here this should be
data given the model
where the
probably much like
following the the the the
you might like a function
of a data set out the the the the the the the x axis here
is is is
it's an abstract representation of data
that's the way it's supposed to represent all possible data datasets that they are because
you can think about these ten point one example was actually only a finite number
of different outcome if have to think about these things being ordered sequences and there
are two to the ten
different possible outcomes for each experiment two possible outcomes we can think about
you know you know lining of the data
in some cases would be infinite but that using the best models
abstract thing
but the interesting thing is that we
the marginal likelihood is the probability distribution
i think the probability of the data given the model
the probability distribution of the data
and in probability distributions
have to normalize
the other thing that integrate to one of them to one
and i have drawn a bunch of different models
i call this one
the green one here
OK if you changes flat heads and tails
randomness should not change and that the property of symmetry
it's also got this property of additivity
and this is a very useful thing
because so have two independent random variables that the entropy of the taken together is
the sum of the individual his
and that's why this is the case
OK so
i had these two things that are independent
and i want to look at the joint entropy the some of them taken together
well that's the sum over all possible outcomes x and y
just plug into the definition p of x log one of one of the of
x y
but in this case because the independent of x y is next time span of
and so
and because it's a lot i can split this into its two pieces
lot one of the p of x plus log one of the of
so i get these two individuals summations
and i can now some of the y and in this case i consider x
OK so i get the the individual entropy effects was individual and the y
so this is another person of the properties we wanted
what the variables are not independent
in that case we wanted to be the case that the entropy of the joint
distribution is at most
is that is at most the sum of the individual entropy
because we want to do so
and that's called sub additivity because if they are independent
the the entropy of the joint is just the sum of the individual entropy is
if the dependent then it's going to be less than that
and that's another that's another good property that got
we normalised so that a fair coin has entropy one you could just buy an
arbitrary constant
a reasonable normalisation is just to say fair coins entropy one
and finally we want to be the case
as as the bias of the queen goes to zero the entropy also goes to
because as it becomes more deterministic everything goes to zero and it also has that
so it's got six properties
that we think you know the intuitively should be true of any measure of randomness
but now it turns out that entropy is the only measure that satisfies these
OK so
proceed an axiomatic way
if you say look i want to
i want to come up with a measure of randomness and now let me put
down a few properties that any measure of randomness should have
all very reasonable sounding properties
OK well with extensibility
that's totally reasonable if you add on fake news some you don't the new outcome
that never occurs
sure that should not change the entropy symmetry additivity
so that activity of normalisation
these are very you know these are these are things that you know we would
think of course this should be true of the measure of randomness
but entropy is the only one that satisfies all of them look into this justifies
why we fight we use something with that we functional form of the law one
of the it seems a little crazy at first but this is why we are
stuck with it
this is why we have to deal with the thing
so let's look at some other let's look at some of the properties of this
first of all it is closely related to the KL divergence
so some of you might already know this distance measure
it's a very commonly used distance measure between probability distributions
suppose i have two probability distributions p and q
and i want to measure the distance between them
many ways one could do it one could look one could for instance draw the
curves to p and q and look at the area between the curves that's very
intuitive way to do it and that's one distance
one could look at the o two distance between them
all one could for some reason
plug it into this formula that looks a lot more weird than any of those
other two
and it turns out that this is something that is very widely used in statistics
so what are the features of this what are the properties of this
well first of all
it has many many unpleasant aspects to it
OK so first of all it's not symmetric
the distance from p to q is not the same as the distance from q
to p
not at all the desirable thing
this thing could easily be infinite
if that's the case he was zero at the point where he is nonzero then
this whole thing becomes infinite
OK so
it's already the the many reasons not to like it but at least the case
it's always positive
and zero only if p and q are equal
so so distance this distribution be
very useful in many contexts like entropy
when you're dealing with the product distribution
these are the product in here
the log on the product interact very nicely
so when you're dealing with product distribution system that to be very convenient functional form
in the same way as we saw the additivity property interest
and also this is closely related to maximum likelihood
if you have a bunch of data
and you have some some
parameterized model and you want to take the maximum likelihood model
making the maximum likelihood model is the same as making the model
it has the smallest scale divergence to the empirical distribution
that's the distribution where you just take the data points and assign them all the
same way
so this is so how is this related to entropy
to do that we look at the two to see how the here
is related to the entropy of
the distribution p
so that a random variable x has distribution of the KL divergence from p to
the uniform distribution
OK so that's just looking into the form of the KL divergence
that's the log over the uniform distribution
uniform is just one over everywhere
so there are
this possible outcome
again the log decomposes nicely and we get a lot of people as long as
and they never that and modelled and modelled and modelled and modelled
but in the end they figured out it's just not possible to model everything and
also you have a large blob of ontology which is not very efficient if you
ask queries and draw inferences and things like that so
the community shifted a little bit to the point of view that what you need
is not a whole monolithic large ontology covering everything but rather snow more handy modular
domain an application ontology is that are specific for certain domains for certain applications and
it is actually what is going on right now
but we also try is the standardisation so for example
hopefully upcoming in the next framework from the european commission there will be a thematic
network called knowledge that and one idea is to have some kind of standardisation bodies
also for ontology is that ensures certain quality insurers a certain syntactical correctness and stuff
like that so the the world is really ongoing
OK let's
communication what is it about and is quite nice picture
from the last century from one and richards which is the so-called meaning triangle maybe
you've heard about that which is pretty good shows what the problem in communication actually
so first of all you start
in the real world let's say with the form and we take jaguar
so if you read jaguar immediately in your mind you have some pictures of some
some ideas jaguar is you think about a certain thing so this form evokes the
concept in your head which refers to a so-called referent which would be a real
object in the world
so let's think about what is an jaguar for you but for some people course
it's the animal jaguar that you're thinking about but for some other people many from
the car industry thinking about the car jaguar
and then you see the problem if you if we are communicating i said jaguar
you think of something but i mean the other one so what they have a
problem so you have to this ambiguity which is one of the large problems also
from machine learning
and this morning it really shows the basic situation that you have to solve also
for computers so you when your agents communicate with each others you have some pre-defined
concepts into your ontology and you have to define the meaning for the concept do
you mean the animal or do you mean the car
and if you look at the current
state ontology if you have a lot of different views on ontology is and one
of the key purposes of my presentation
in the following will be to clarify a little bit what is actually meant by
the different views i would distinguish between friend and and back-end solutions but this is
a rather personal view
so if you look now for example you have things like topic maps is very
taxonomy is semantic networks extended ER models and predicate logic also on the one hand
for example the topic maps
quite established also an ISO standard quite nice applications this would be a rather front-end
solution because it can
you can navigate through and knowledge base you can still click-through
a topic hierarchies and find some documents on the other hand you have things like
extended ER models or predicate logic our preferred solution which is now in the back-end
side because you can draw inferences for example you have really precisely defined semantics which
helps there
so what typical
applications were on the front and of course you would like to provide navigational structures
you would like to support information retrieval for example query expansion with taxonomy is already
in the end you want to share their knowledge on the back and you have
the reason have consistency checking mediation enterprise application integration so these are the typical pass
if you talk about that
and would have a little bit into
the deep of that different topics and show you how relate taxonomy is very topic
maps and our view of ontology
let's start with a simple taxonomy well typically what it gives you
the segmentation of the classification and ordering of elements into the classification system according to
the relationships between each other so let's take a simple example here we start with
but generic object for us important use personal public document you know that students and
researchers isolated the person you know that there exists also doctoral students and phd students
an interesting topic for us would be semantics and you wouldn't maybe that logic frame
logic is our preferred representation language for ontology is and you know that ontology somehow
relates to the semantic so that's basically a taxonomy
what concepts
next step would be a thesaurus
so what you what is actually different is that it's typically for a specific domain
so define terminology for a certain domain
if you look a little bit closer the to graph with two primitives and you
have so-called two fixed relationships on the one hand you could say that a doctoral
student is synonym to a phd student on the other hand you could for example
say that athletic similar to ontology so these the two fixed relationships and originally the
this comes from the bibliography so that was the main
the original features
next step a little bit would be the so-called topic maps
reduce the amount of time to explain these terms
probably in all of these terms
last few blogsites blogger's blog posts reversal equal
chronologically ordered entries blagrove
number links and trackbacks
all of these so
this is the case this is the point everyone can publish
but not everyone will be heard
only very few people
and in these few
they can make a lot of money
all they have interests they can exert to their interests
so then many interesting questions to address
how to build traffic
how to find a niche online
and how to increase influence
there are many how to use
we can do
i was i think anything at all me
there's even though there's is a site to the world
the try to based on the blog posts right to tell you it's a female
female blogger on milk is you just need to find
this kind of application then you can
establish a company
to make money
you use
you don't know that's why they do it they don't know based on because it's
an anonymous right usually but so then how can you tell a blog post is
written by a male or female
or computer it's possible
spam is spam we want to tell us spam blogs
but basically i hope i have convinced you
it's a fertile research domain
because fullprofessor we will or interesting researcher
OK this is basically
an example
this blog site
we have a blog post this blogger
types of blocks
in the early days
blogs blogs basically we note spire is one person just serve
his or her
opinions experiences or things but things change
after people can comment on
we have like individual versus community
nowadays you can see individual blog sites and community blog sites
these are the different
so you have like a single of other people can only comment
when we will see how monte of
and what you can do is like many people can
start a new thread and to discuss
a lot of things to get your comments it it's not necessary only the only
single off can control
so the we also
you can see the regulated versus anonymous
blog sites
so how about individual blog sites and the community blog sites there are different
many ways
so now blogsphere
we will talk about like this it's basically it's complex social networks
OK why because we have these about
in degree and out degree have links have links
you can cite other people
and you can also link
two you can cite other people's right people can cite to so then having degrees
and degrees you consider but this is you have to
so these are
the rules you have those here so that means the directional
so we have also the friendship networks versus blogosphere
friendship networks versus france that
not exactly the same
these are the
i won't go through one by one but they are
these are the differences between them
here so you see there's overlap you will give you some examples
and if you have done the research in social networks and computer science
it's very likely that you use the citation networks koko offer should networks
so this is also different from blogsphere
we listed these like
citation links
thank you for DBLP that's one of the dataset you can use to do research
so you have strict notion of links
the people cite to what they refer to
blogs links are
and often missing
and then for social networks
on the other
you know
that's not what i would call this a with
i think we
if at all
by two
all these things that make you of you noise
it means that there you know
he my mind
by that we use
two weeks
this is one one
the like
he said we have on
and they use see
what happened
one of us
you get more and more
what comes
you know one
sure sure
he asked what i
more less
by that i mean that we
it is not
how do you
what is doing
i believe that
so you know
you can see
he was
would that be
you can see by
the other thing is the
what is all
this happens
we need a little
he e
can you
he really
he she
what find
and i
i think the
it is so we can see
what you all
on line that you know where you have
why i
equals one one
what would this feature function be useful for
you will learn that this feature function is going to be a negative weight
and what that means is that you don't have to hide the road
but much
you won't be able to learn any patterns about about three hyphens on on hyphens
in world
so the part of speech labeling it would be it would it would be quite
useful to have a low level feature functions like
proper noun proper nouns proper nouns
that's unfortunately not allowed by this framework
it's not alone is not allowed by standards
it is not allowed by standard linear chain crfs
and the reason is not allowed is because they don't exist algorithms for that case
it's it's allowed theoretically it allows mathematically
but then decided our will break down
so if if you really wanted to much
if it was really important to you to have patterns like for like
proper noun proper nouns proper nouns
you could
you could try developing your own algorithms
you could try
creating some sort of multiscale model
so that much
so that you could group words into groups and then have a CRF that refer
to just pairs of group as of consecutive groups of words
or and
actually both of those have been both of those have been tried their papers in
the literature about both those approaches you you can relax this assumption of two neighbouring
one and in fact actually the arms of tomorrow i'm going to be presenting a
paper at the conference
which is about
an extension of conditional random fields
and we actually have a comparison in the two method
that was actually published by zoubin ghahramani whose
professor at cambridge university where they have
they have an extension of linear chain conditional random field to allow for more triples
and on this particular application it's the best performing method because it really is a
lot of information in the triples
but the
the algorithms for that case
much less tractable
a significant
and i think that would be an additional conducting going triples the portables i think
essentially the
the algorithm is exponential in the number of adjacent
labels they allow
so actually linear if you don't pay attention if you don't
pairs of labels and quadratic the labels cubic if you allow triples of labels
that's what i was just wondering as i was just saying that i'm not sure
if if there's a paper in the letter explicitly gives the generalized algorithm for any
fixed number of adjacent one because the
this is the this this work that i'm thinking of by zoubin ghahramani
it may be it's more general than just linear chain crfs
because it also applies to non-linear crfs
and so i think maybe a gap in the literature that somebody should write a
paper that
that gives the algorithms that are just for linear chain crfs but for any number
of adjacent labels i think that might be
what we're doing
i think
so the standard algorithms require adjacency
i think there might be non-standard algorithms that actually have the same time complexity they
don't require adjacency
but the standard that would require adjacency
i guess that's what should
i get to the next month
and as you know we have another break coming up doing
and informant yes so
and let me
move on to more talking about what are the two central problems that i'm going
to provide algorithms for solving
so the probability of life given x and w
it is
xe of expert w
on the numerator
exponent exponential of some of the j
wj j
x y
to make a predictions
why that is the argmax
over y
of some of the j
wj fj
x y
if we want to use one of these models to predict y
then we're going to plug in the x and look for the y has highest
and the y has highest over years the y has the biggest value for the
the denominator is constant for all y so when we went away when we want
to find the argmax the probability we just need to know the
argmax the numerator and in fact is one more simplification that i can make on
this argmax
what can i simplify i don't actually need to find the argmax of this i
can find a argmaxa something a little bit simpler
i don't need the exponent because it's a monotonic function so
i need to make it prediction need to find the argmax over y
function that the
this is the prior is too strong
and if you're interested
in making probabilistic
prediction then you're interested in how your error bars behave then you should use models
like that i should be using models that are and here we are going to
be nonparametric limit right we're saying well you know that they lots of things could
could be happening potentially right
and this sort of a miracle
that the amount of computation we need to do is is actually the same as
if only treating these these weekly basis functions
but as we saw in the slide from yesterday we get this nice error bars
that increase when we move away from the dataset precisely because this interpretation that with
these bumps that are living in the feature space and out here then not constrained
by the data
the the question about here
well so the joke so the question is you know doesn't really make a difference
whether using zero with with with high confidence of their with very low confidence i
think it makes in many cases makes a huge difference right let's say you're say
you're using the model to two
to predict what you should be making some financial from transactions on like that in
one case it was saying i'm absolutely sure what's going to happen
so that would give you
that will give you confidence that
that's what the model is predicting is actually also going to happen in the other
case it could say
well i i'm i'm neutral well actually you know anything could happen right that seems
to be a very different very different situation
so typically
people focus a lot on the mean predictive distribution but i think actually be
the answer is typically
more realistically the whole distribution and you should worry about if
different put things are possible
then you know this is this is usually an interesting interesting thing to know about
yes it does mean we
and user should read
with binary functions because
most countries of the
that's correct
so always use infinite dimensional models
OK in this in this case for free flight
because the same
the competition to compute with these things as it does
to compete with the with the bad counterpart
OK so so so some people actually asked about this site
well the
o but here to to solve this problem i only need to store nine numbers
actually if i recognise that my matrix is symmetric i only need half of nine
but irony i only need to solve a three by three system here
there's no need to represent all this stuff
like the gaussianprocess formulation will be telling me
anything i could possibly want to know about the distribution
OK so so there so so
so so long to models that are currently being used in lots of different fields
are actually special cases of gas and process
so so very large neural networks are exactly the reason why i got to think
about casting process in the first place so radford neal who was in the lower
where was doing my phd he did his phd on doing inference using monte carlo
techniques on very large neural networks and had a sentence somewhere in his in his
in his thesis saying when the
when the networks become infinitely large this actually tends to process and it might be
easier to do inference if you think about it as the gaussianprocess process so actually
chris williams myself look at that sentence and try to figure out what what that
what i got what i got imposes was we actually came to gaston processes sort
of backwards it turns out that it's very easy to show how big neural networks
tend to go process so but a lots of all the models that have been
used a lot so one in this is spinal also just go through this very
quickly if you don't know what's finals is then it doesn't matter
so spineless are our models where you're trying to look at it trying to find
the the
they functioned the function to fit data again to find finer function that minimizes this
loss functions so square difference between what the what the function is is predicting and
the and the observation and then as the regularisation term here which is some regularisation
constant lambda times the integral of the second squared second derivative of the function quite
so it's penalizing the function before curving a lot
it turns out that the solution to to this optimisation problem let's not get too
mathematical about about in some some class of functions you can you can solve this
very variational and the solution is it's called cubic smoothing spine so so there is
a piecewise
cubic polynomial and the pieces are
are from between the data points here in in in one case
and in one dimensional actually have is not that lie between zero and one and
you have a piecewise polynomials cubic polynomial inside each of the difference between the two
points and these models have been used a lot
it turns out that this is actually also gaussianprocess so i can construct the process
in this way here so it looks a lot like what we did before so
the functions are now alpha plus beta x so this is just a linear contribution
and then we have then we have again
a bunch of functions looking at the limit as we take more and more these
functions this function this bracket with the pos means means the positive part so
you have zero inside the bracket if the if the if the bracket has a
negative number of you just get the number which is inside the brackets so we
are adding together the basis functions that are little ramps i zero until some point
i iowa and and then they start ramping up
OK and we just give gas in independent components to those and some of the
whole thing up
and normalized so that will have a reasonable limit when n goes to infinity
and then the interesting part
we already know is to compute the covariance function and you have to do so
first we get the covariance function of a linear function we already computed that and
then we get the the
the there some of these products again we only get the these these these terms
you don't get across terms again because the the the the gas and random variables
when independent for the different contributions and you can you can solve this cylindrical and
you get something which is here gamma is just like a constant here you get
something which is the which is a cubic polynomial
OK it's a cubic polynomial but it involves something like the minimum of x and
ten x ten x prime
so you can sort of see
if this is the covariance function and remember the predictions you get from a gaussianprocess
the mean prediction
it's just an example
common x one is the training cases times k nearest times the observations y
right and that's the mean prediction
you mean prediction so the mean prediction look like this so the mean prediction you
so you give a matrix of distances i can recover the matrix of inner products
if this distance matrix of rules from
a set of vectors in a euclidean space
and once make a matrix of inner products how do i find the vectors
simply by looking at
dikin vectors of this matrix
so you do the next step of embedding
essentially noticing that the matrix of inner product is going to be
technically going be positive semi definite so to be a little careful you have to
actually do you could do the spectral factorisation carefully
keep the orthogonal spaces in those spaces
cricket this is done over all non-zero igon values as follows
and i and so this is
a map
that will take you from
for any x from one in one through n
you get a map CX
like this
as written the
and you can check
the this map
well actually satisfy the inner product and satisfy
the distance matrix
so the way the multidimensional scaling works is that you start with set of distances
the distance matrix you go from there that to candidate set of inner products
and you go from the candidate set of inner products was set of vectors is
consistent with that inner product matrix
so what people did they applied this algorithm
a lot of data
OK so here are many pictures
and this is the picture
i guess the hand
where the wrist is rotating
the finger is also extended scientific and see this very well but each of these
pictures is a picture of the hand and the pictures differ from each other along
two dimensions
since some of those pictures the fingers are extended
and in some of those pictures the wrist is rotated
so there are two degrees of freedom in the natural degrees of freedom in the
data pictures corresponding to rotate addressed in pictures corresponding to extended finger
and basically you collect a lot of these pictures lot of images
you apply the size of isomap technique
and you can now embed this data every picture into two-dimensional space
by asking for
two dimensional embedding
once you embedded every such picture in two dimensions space you can look at
every point in this two-dimensional space in every point in this two-dimensional space corresponds to
a picture
and this is what those
pictures look like you see that you actually recover
the wrist rotation and the finger extension
suppose all the data lived actually on manifold in this manifold was flat
here is the statement that is actually true
flat so it
falls flat manifold which is isometric to a convex domain in rn
there's another algorithm called his united methodist talk about
call local tangent space alignment didn't talk about and all of them are trying to
do the same circle of things OK
what data living on the manifold can you actually on rules
this manifold can you actually we embed the data into a low dimensional space and
then you can ask whether this really embedding is correct are isometric
in some sense and some of these statements may be true
for some of these other things
here is another algorithm which people use color locos
locally linear embedding
so how does this algorithm looks so
you could also say that that truck is also class and you could say that
truck is the of metal you call that's the second example you could say that
the measure he could
as the domain is registered to a person which would be the range
and you could say that for example something is owned by a person or something
else and this would be the property of registered to these
i mean the syntactical details sure but just to give you a short glimpse of
some conclusions
why is it so important that except that RDF is serialised in XML first of
all when it gives you the flexibility
to embed your metadata into XML documents and if you have an RDF aware agent
he can make a little bit more with the document so that's the principle idea
behind it but still it's the next step up from so-called plain XML because you
have from our perspective small ontological commitment to the modelling primitives and i introduced the
basic ones and it's and it is possible to define further vocabulary that you would
need for that
but what is still missing you no precisely described meaning that is still missing in
RDF and RDF scheming schema and you have no inference model and this is one
of the key aspects if you have more complex problems which you would like to
solve then typically you have a large set of actions and this is still not
included in RDF and RDF schema so the next step from RDF and RDF schema
is really more ontology vocabulary then you would for example
i define an inference model and this is also ongoing work actually
meant to give you an impression what is already existing and where people working on
so you think you you're you not the request commendation the XML is already a
standard RDF and RDF schema is also a standard ontology vocabulary is not standard called
but this is a short tutorial so why not introduce the before standard you but
if you are interested of course you will find a lot of presentations and stuff
the web but this is really the next step on top of RDF and RDF
schema and work in progress the so-called allegedly so there you want to add more
capabilities so in the ontology vocabulary you only have a simple inference model and allegedly
would like to add even more inference capabilities and if you're familiar with description logics
and frame logic then you have a clear picture of what is needed there and
on top of that but this is still
a bit more in the future i would say is the so-called proven trust layer
but especially for business applications of course this will be one of the crucial layers
but beginning from the bottom
the semantic layer is now really becoming reality by standards and also by tools that
support these standards
and last but not least that further activities mainly driven by the w three c
the world wide web consortium which is for example the semantic web service committee but
again this is just a short tutorial but i would like to give you that
important pointer because the combination of web services and semantic web technologies is seen as
one of the great potentials and of course something like query languages and so on
OK so what what what open up until now what is actually an ontology we
talked a little bit about ontological vocabulary i've shown you some little examples but now
i would like to give you some
more detailed views on it when first of all let's start with the purpose and
that's actually a citation from the knowledge management community davenport is quite well-known writer that
people can't share knowledge if they do not speak a common language
and this can be done in the last two agents can conjure knowledge if they
don't speak a common language so what we want to achieve with ontology is it
exactly that common language so we want to support the knowledge sharing
another definition by which was one of the key players in the early nineties and
started that whole ontology community an ontology is an explicit specification of conceptual innovation
well that sounds a bit strange what does it give you
first of all we have the better communication between humans and machines which is given
to you
erm and then explicit specification you basically get former construct and this is what agents
need to communicate to each other and you have you have the explicit specification of
concept innovation which means that you only cover a certain part of your world which
you would like to model so maybe you've heard of the site project which was
one of the very famous projects also in the i think it's in the in
the eighties there were the first roots and they try to make the whole world
so it was really quite ambitious
not only that actually it's not too hard so what happened then it is that
in two thousand five
also another spanning tree was proposed called the low stretch spanning trees which get around
this problem going to the definition here but there's another definition spanning tree which then
remove this
this is this problem of having lightweight edges perturbing the spanning tree
and the advantage with these is that they have a much better condition number
one problem is that we don't know how to find them in linear time for
the super linear to find
another problem is that there still not really very good if you take even though
simple square mesh
as the underlying system you want to solve that there is no good spanning tree
right so when that that's one of the results from two thousand four
grandmom and iron ninety four proposed that what we really should do is take a
steiner tree
so the idea here is is instead of
taking this graph and requiring ourselves to pick
a subgraph what we just start a lower self have steiner and
so in particular what we did here is is these nodes are the original variables
and we just introduce new variables to form a tree
so so in fact the square mesh this goes dramatically better condition number and you
can solve them much faster
and also experimentally this works quite well substantially better than any of the other spanning
unfortunately we never really figured out how to find a good way to compute these
trees in general minutes and i a hard problem
so we we haven't made any headway there in two thousand seven
good estimates of proposed using steiner forest
so the idea now is already going to do is is we're going to take
this underlying graph
and we're going to find highly connected pieces in this graph
i think in this case it probably doesn't actually exist that way but the idea
now is is what we're going to do now is just a small pieces of
this graph and we're going to make assigning steiner tree for each one of those
pieces and
use that are preconditions
well actually more precisely
so the advantage of this is that it's very easy to find these things they
work well
with recursive solvers so we haven't got to that so the next thing to do
is is is shown how to recursively use these ideas
and also to give good experimental results will show that can unfortunately at this point
we still have only been able to analyse these for the players system so for
those we can show
could run time linear time OK
so the second idea to invite you had is that what you should do
but we're now applying this to llo are steiner system so the idea now is
again these original variables these are steiner variables and these are the edge weights in
this new graph
so the idea now that the vieja propose he said well find your preconditions
and i suppose it's not just a spanning tree but actually has a few more
edges like i think this has one extra edge in this case right remove this
says then we get this right a tree
but suppose in general we may have a lot more other edges let's just remove
those edges which are easy using direct methods so in this case will remove all
the original variables
and then we'll end up with a much smaller system
and then we'll do now
is take this system here which is now reduced
and instead of trying to solve that directly what we we're cursed will just now
as for recursive solver to solve the simple this newer system and hopefully this nervous
system is much smaller than the old system so
it will get a geometric increase decrease in problem size which will give us a
good solver
so when we worry about this so
so maybe i should just
talk about congestion dilation right so hopefully you will know this stuff i'm not sure
why this should be here but if you have a simple recurrence relation of this
right like in the case we started with anyone analyse how fast these things converge
a standard result says that if you let the air
b simply your guess minus the actual answer to the problem
but in fact the gas then the airtime i
is simply the original air times the genes power of your matrix OK
so all you need to then shows is that this matrix here goes to zero
as i goes to infinity right
so so that gives us and
so this list let's remember are defined before but if we have a system of
equations of the form x equals lambda b then first recall lambda and i can
value and exciting vector
in our case here all aragon values there are that are
greater than or equal to zero so
that's all the posse and actually the zero one and there's a bunch of other
right so i suppose we sort these
so the condition number is simply defined to be of this matrix the largest eigen
value divided by the smallest i can
so the standard results says that the convergence rate for the basic iterative method is
one over the condition number
so this ends up being very poor
if you then go to conjugate gradient standard result says that you get to take
the square root of the condition number
so what is roughly says for simple examples is that the rate of convergence in
other words if you want one bit of accuracy the number of iterations has to
be something like the diameter of the graph right
so if in other words you take the square root of n by spirit of
anchorage and you can't gradient then you need square event iterations to get one bit
of accuracy
so this is the classic analysis
what we want to do now is bound the condition number of b inverse a
because that's what we're generating on instead of simply right
while another way to write that is is simply if we're interested in the i
can values of this system is that equivalent to the generalized values of the form
x equals lambda b can
so the land is called the generalized tagging OK
so in general than what we're interested in is the condition number again so we're
interested in the i can values of the system here so the largest divided by