independent random variables are column x one through x n
and we have a function that maps from
from some domain x
for many maps from from
the space that these
the baseline to to the real
this is not true there should be a bounded interval in fact
we know that this is true so that's that's the real and then we have
that whenever we take any value of x one through x n
and and any
and any other x are any all i NEXI prime
OK so maximizing overall the arguments of the function
if we look at how a function g changes when we change x i to
XII prime
the biggest change that we can get is COI i
if we have this condition satisfied this is the
the bounded differences condition
is another name for this inequality the wonderful many of bounded differences inequality
then with high probability
the deviation between a random variable in its expectation is is small
you know on on the order of the two norm of this vector of these
maximal deviations
OK so when we apply that in our case that g takes
has as fluctuations that are of order one over
OK so we get some of
of n terms
of of one hundred square and we get our square that's in
turn down here
all right so that's that's taking it a step in the right direction we've got
away from
you know i remember we're trying to prove
we're trying to show that
that expectations are not much bigger than sample averages
we start uniformly across the club across the class we trying to show that the
that the supremum for over functions of
functions g class differences here is not too big and and
what we first shown is that random variable
is not much bigger than its expectation
there's no conditions saying that g has to be bounded we have
so g is bounded here implicit so so the point is we are always looking
at differences
right and and
for any change of the
of these variables were getting is small
a small change so g
g is necessarily bounded
because we were getting no more than the sum of these changes to
right it is not necessarily that if we subtract some some
the value of g at some fixed value of x one through x xn
right then
then so sent just entering around zero so for some value of x one to
x and this thing is zero then g is bounded by the sum of the
sea ice
right in the way that we use the boundedness of g
i guess what's confusing here is that there are two different genes floating around g
means two different things on this light and on this line
OK so here we are
the class of bounded functions the fact that they are bounded
right means that
the sample average
can't change by much when we change one of the arguments
OK the random variable we're considering
to apply the demons inequality is the supreme over g of the expectation must sample
average so on this slide in stating the dems inequality i have used g
there should be some other and some others
symbol for the random variable right so the random variable we're talking about here
in our case this thing
so sorry for that was an unfortunate choice
of notation
so i want to say a little bit about why
about me damage inequality
and why it's true
and some of the ingredients of the proof he will will pop up later when
we consider the
the VC dimension
OK so
we're looking here at deviations between
the function g of these in random
and the expectation of g
so i want to express that
as a sum of a martingale difference sequence so i mean we not using any
properties of modern nongaussian so you don't have to know what
so we we if we define the initial sequence x one through x i and
worry about how
the conditional expectation expectation changes as we see the i th random variable
right so this is the function g
and we consider
the how the expectation has
increased so the eyes the increasing expectation conditioned on c x one through x i
over what the conditional expectation was then we'd seen x one through x i slide
the condition on just the first one is one of these guys
all right then
the random variable g
minus its expectation is just the sum of these things right is the telescoping some
the first one the expectation of g given nothing
well that's this
in the last one the expectation of g given x one through x and well
that's this
right so we can write it as the some of these things and now it's
some of those guys
that we want to bound the deviations of of this thing
say with high probability the summer's
is small
OK so
you know i want to get the true steps but the
the expectations of these things given the past are all zeros
OK so
you know this allows us to apply
ideas of
of of hosting going back to her
and i'm going to
to go through
the argument here because
it's something that we will see we'll see later on
OK so we can write the deviation between a random variable
and its expectation
as the sum of these
differences between conditional expectations
and now he is attracted pops up again and again
the probability that this thing is bigger than anything
well let's take some monotone transformation of those are the two sides
OK in particular with the monotone transformation take is the exponential function
with some
positive constant s
OK so this is bigger than that precisely when eta this is bigger than e
to the that
well u s times this
this is the this is
something that we can bound using markov inequality
OK so
he does anybody know that that inequality
if you do nobody is admitted
was just saying the the the expectation of some nonnegative random variable
it is at least as big as the probability that is bigger than something divided
by that some time that something
right so
so we can get upper bound on the probability in terms of an expectation of
this thing times
in the months st
OK this is called the chernoff
you get very little revenue and this becomes a very big business problems
you according user experience and the
you have still never let you do this so what we need is some sort
of a
which can converge much more quickly
and the only way to do this is by using some additional structure that might
be available
and as the above mentioned
one possible structure is that of the taxonomy
which is already
in existence this is sort of stuff that
the yahoo states people use
as with the marketing departments of big companies and so on so these are are
these are already existing taxonomies the main thing
and they are actually used for the purposes of selecting
as and my segmenting the at market
so for instance we have classifier that can be in any page at any at
map one particular note in this taxonomy
and and since these taxonomies are being used for marketing purposes it's reasonable to believe
that there is some information in this taxonomy which if
we could use nicely then we could probably come up with better than that
which converges somewhat fast
the question is how we do
so what present next is one possible solution
which is a multi bandit policy which uses this taxonomy and i show briefly that
this does fairly well
but this is not a course the end of the
the question
we the content that makes matrix where we the
if ax and each row corresponds to one big band where we want to figure
out the best ad for this particular
but now we have taxonomies of what's
let's consider just this basic taxonomy
let's say that our world consists of acts which belonged at computers and travel
and these ads have been shown only on the pages that come from
apple computer center
this sort of this segmentation
but except matrix into seven chunks blocks so for instance the central block will correspond
all of all assets belonging to computers being shown on pages belonging to computers again
so since the at all similar pages are ultimately we can sort of expect the
CBS are going to be
broadly similar or homogeneous as compared to
CBS all of the matrix so there is some
structured but this matrix
in the city of matrix that we should be able to use
you know bandit policy
the key idea here is that the same applies to be more homogeneous than on
how can we use this in our banning policy
and then see how we could use it in both the allocation stage
and the estimated chen stadium the one
so in that location
let's say that we have to use
who came to have their say same
came page and this web page was classified into one particular note in the taxonomy
it's a
somewhere inside computers
so this specifies my one
big figure out one at the peak
so from this particular rule
and should be used
now the traditional bandit policy would just not
abandoned on this and that in fact possibly a million pounds and it would be
very slow to converge
what we can do instead
it stood on the bandit on the top level classes so i just under bandit
figaro should show at from happening on different computers or from
so dependencies or lecture natural capital
this reduces the space the fact that i now have to search from
so i go down and say
it on another planet
among children of africa in the taxonomy and they keep doing this one after another
and the late each one the sun and this leaf node corresponds to one had
which i should put the use
so essentially instead of running one bandit
and in the bandit on each level of that exon
OK but why would this
ever work
the reason why is because the higher level bandits some aggregating information from all the
lower levels of the taxonomy so
the high level bandits have very few arms instead of having to deal with millions
of fans
here the level bandit has to deal with only three
so it's much faster convergence
and what this does
is that our full model delivered policy essentially quickly converges on the back
portions of the space
it takes time to figure out what is the best actor at the show
but it figures are very quickly that happened is the good
the best at show is probably somewhere inside so it reduces the space the fact
that we have to search for
that is how
the taxonomy could be used in the allocation stage to figure out which acts to
show next
it can also be used in the estimation
so here's the problem is that i suppose i should add
in response to a certain page and get some feedback maybe the user clicks on
something like that now this feedback can be used to optimize CTR estimates CTR for
this particular
but we also now know that this particular act belongs to a blog
and all the cds in the bloggers fall machines are close to each
so in some sense should be able to use this feedback
four cds for everyone inside the block
how can we model this depends
and this is well
the whole literature and shrinkage models comes
so one very simple changes more go something like this
if i knew the CTR
of particular cell
then i could say that the number of clicks to get in the some of
the number of successes in this it is just a binomial variables
which depends on the number of impressions in the cell
and the city of the
but the city itself i don't know so what i can say is that they
want to see the end of the cell
as something that draws from the block
so in some sense all the cells in a block
i have the CD drawn from the same distribution
and so if this distribution is tight then all the cells will have similar ctrs
as compared to the average
and what's your answer them at all this does is that your estimated CTR becomes
the sum of two terms
so the first one of the densest of services
how often have i seen success
for this particular given
the number of impressions of this
but the second is something like a block quite see what it means for the
entire plot
so what happens is that initially
when you very data
and the block CTR so dominates and this brings you very quickly up to the
mean level
and later on as you collect more and more
the estimated CTR moves more and more was observed the towards
maximum likelihood estimation so what this does is initially
the matrix is too shoot and you have very little
the block CTR sort of brings you up to the average levels
well if you take all the DNA you have the number of a which is
which can be between four hundred thousand million four here for the human genome on
for those of you have seen the answers
so it's not a very small but still going only be on your computer
something that is very low
the examples of the other examples is here if you would like to use to
fly to human you have the impression that the complexity of the organism is increasing
you when you compare human two
the eastern would say well you can do more than and you know that you
size increases say well the goal
number more than but this is not true so there are many
the main exceptions here so in general administration but you really need to show that
if you take plants
there are much bigger than humans
so it's not clear to that is more than but there's just there's no single
there is no single link between number of chromosomes
the size of men
see the complexity of the organism
but just to give you some idea of the of the sizes of these countries
six hundred to describe the
the human genome
so let's that's
how it was so i said that DNA was supposed to contain information to make
human how does it work well what could be more this few because we so
we don't know much
thank about how it works but what we know there's something we know it with
ninety four which is called has nice also called the amount of money by biology
so it's the it's OK just natural science over the last one of the reasons
why it is useful is the american there is the called
to make money because called proteins
and what the following remember that in cell you fields
could you go into a single company
and at some points your yourselves so depending on the we require some some problems
of this approach is looking for the producer of macromolecules which are functions of for
instance head of is protein that using the blood to carry oxygen when you need
live in the there is no specific so that means there is reason somewhere in
your DNA code to make protein so what we need to be in the same
we read in a product that contains a call from king hamad bin and then
it we far into another article called RNA
it is very similar to a
single stranded that are and will lead to the US
and then another missionary
we really are in a region which are just local optima
OK that contains the
the this
specific plans for ordering him to be and then the machinery with real information in
our a to make another molecules
and this would be the protein
because of the central so that you you need to compete with unit two and
a you know this is what you see this is the first when you are
in a little bit of theory when you live in the local
for with computing are in a is called transcription
and the information they will be ready to make the final output is useful
these are here simply means that DNA itself is called the when you need a
source of someone wants to separate into two daughter cells and also when you bristol
when when you want images
this is the control flow of information what's important is constantly reverting there are and
what is going to be many numbers you may have to make many on these
so this specific are in here is is called foreign aid is messenger RNA it
turns out that there are many other functions for and which are not cover so
are they are in republic see because it is the chemical composition of the molecule
one be used for the main use of is to to the world in terms
of mediation between DNA protein but it turns out that the sun
that's what i was looking the same single strand of RNA can have different functions
to do this but also there are transfer RNA there are
a small are in four generations to right so i think the name
he right and RNA a
because they are in not here to write is messenger RNA
there are there are names which have different functions
so i said that the
in this in the central to the image of l
this is called the commission to make proteins
so it could be what proteins are one thing because you are not going to
so putting the chemistry once again is the output variable is an assembly of basic
building blocks
but the attachments are also in your building blocks which are called losses in this
and what you assemble like you think protein
so i wrote this like a sequence of amino acids and find these these things
when you when you put in the solution will take some specific three-dimensional structure like
the one we have here is that this is the
and this is the traditional for protein is is that of relying cities but because
of the composition the weights male
based on specific through social interactions with have function
OK so to begin with take model based on the life and then some configuration
in three d and the final three d
structure and the
chemical properties of this process will allow it to to sequence one
so far as what important that the sequence of events and in fact there are
so i said they are for the intermediate for building blocks in case of proteins
there are twenty amino acids
so for each protein sequence over the alphabet of size twenty
i will not the twenty one
but the data
so the
o thing
thank you for having me here this
to open this conferences workshops
i'm going to talk today about
search technology that's what i primarily work on
two most of here
but with an emphasis on
one hand technically projects that i've worked on it also on the open source
methodology and and sort of how that works
i'm sure it's something
all you're somewhat familiar with
and maybe even participated in some
but there are some
the more important the more i learned about some subtle piece of what really makes
open source work and liked
talk a bit about that in the process
so the first one of my time
not really an academic i suspect that many of you
are academics and researchers
i used to be one of those
some years ago
our to xerox research centre in palo alto
five years and
papers and
that all that good stuff
and i'm not a commercial software developer i haven't worked on
proprietary commercial software
in a few years anyway but i used to do that flows well so that
the the the title on the card is the space is open source guy
and i to the site was on the cards so that's what i call
and so on in that with had i mean i'm a developer software developer and
architect to some degree doing research
so the manager of other people
and to some degree and i'm an evangelist trying to
to each other people about the
how open source works i'm not all i don't think it's the only way to
do things i don't think this
lots of lots of other
you a valid way to develop software so
why then what happens
to distinguish from
the other way
so this
different things like you
might think distinguish
the first one to go visit the licence you you you might think that just
putting software under an OSI approved
license releasing it that way
makes are technically
that's all that's really required i mean that's that's probably the most precise definition of
open source
he to me that there's a little more to it than that
and that is implied
other ways to compare
open source to doing research on and around reading commercial proprietary software easily to caricature
so please don't
take this too literally and these really are
either orthogonal models
there are many ways in which they can be combined the this just
to be clustered i don't want to offend anyone
so you know researcher can you can really things under various licenses in the same
commercial companies
really things under various licenses under the license alone does uniquely identify what i'm talking
about open source
software development
this is the artifacts producing you know in research the primary artifact factors is arguably
the publication
that's something people
are we are really after an
the software is is a means of publication i would argue in most research communities
and and same in
the racial barriers products patterns that those things that you're trying to build and the
source code itself is
it means where is an open source you really focusing on the code so that
and i'm going to discourage this
so instead of just
fitting how well i separate out my original training data how well i fit regression
surface in
my original training data i'm going to have a trade-off between that
and how we can my surfaces
so that i think finally brings the
this final slide the first time
that trade-off we fitted an objective which was something called which was the
the objective that says how well we fit the training data and then i had
something like
slammed the sum of
a bunch of white
this the free parameter here that said
how do you
how do you decide where to set the trade-off between fitting data well and coming
up with sort of simpler explanations
and one way to do that was to just try a whole bunch of different
hold out some data at the beginning
which your fitting procedure doesn't see and then see which is the best lambda which
lambda generalizes to new data that hasn't been seen yet the best and then you
go with that and that something simple you can do
that's not the only thing you can do
so that's what we're going to resume
other any questions
i promise i was going to a broad overview of machine learning
it's not really possible for me to do that because unfortunately i don't have a
deep knowledge of everything and
one of the
large important areas of machine learning that i'm not really an expert in a
statistical learning theory say
there's a lot of statistical learning theory in the major machine learning conferences but it
also has a conference it's a cult
one of the big questions in this area
concerned with is computing bounds on
generalisation error
donal this stuff
and i picked w's and lambda is in some way
and i run some kate
given some training data
but what i really care about is when i play the system
how well is it going to work on future data
it's impossible to now
that because in
you know the world could spit anything after that
but what they can do is give probabilistic guarantees they can say well
with this probability you're going to do no worse than
and this threshold and
that's very nice thing to have it's very nice to be able to give your
the person your consulting for some guarantee that this machine your handing them will do
something useful
one of the simplest ways i sort of understand how to do is to construct
that sort of guarantee you think the validation set so
you held out some data
nothing you did sawa
at all
so i held at some data i put it on
another directory of my hard disk i didn't peak it it even for a moment
in my whole fitting procedure
and then right at the end for my system that i'm about to deploy
i run that on my held out data
and see how well it did it's possible to construct bounds on that performance so
here is
a sample of how well the machine will be one future data that i haven't
seen it all
that gives you an estimate of how well it will perform in confidence bounds on
that fairly easily so that sort of the
easier space of learning theory
it's important
it's in some ways the least interesting
i described k fold cross validation to which is something where you have multiple validation
sets do peak at a bit while you're running much harder to analyse those overlay
there are papers on that area
well learning theory gets excited is
when they
try to compute bounds based not on held out validation set which is philosophically
not very satisfying because your sort of not using all of your data while you're
there are also found you can construct based purely on test on training set performance
i e
optimize some
regularized objectives and because of the regularizer i won't get perfect performance will be some
which are on the wrong side of my decision line
and so
the training error
the wind b
zero and a lot of sense regularizers
summary of learning tree will do without take place training errors and health
up quite this and say well that's related to the error you're going to get
at test time you'll probably do that west test time because some data have two
and they can tell you how much worse
as it bounces along bounds on generalisation error
that's sort of i philosophically pleasing that's a nice thing to do than having to
hold out validation sets which is a bit dirty it's kind of interesting because
it then tells you what sort of possible to learn because you bounds on whether
it's possible to generalize
in the given problem
the difficulty for practical purposes often found very loose sense
and the reason is that they start are
one of the huffman code
yes you within plus one
he has this
less than n plus one and that plus one dominates
so you're miles off from the actual entropy for many distributions such huffman start because
the symbol code and symbol code such in that case
so it's bad for
extreme distributions
and if you're doing a good job of your machine learning and making strong predictions
i as i know the next sentence of jane austen's emma because i figured out
the plot
you get extreme distributions
OK so have been such
in addition
the probability distribution changes
and the changes for two reasons
it changes with the context
just got context dependent predictions and it changes because we are learning as we go
so if i told you i have been calling here and i want you to
compress the outcome from the bent coin but i don't know what the bias is
and i start talking heads tails
you want to learn on the fly what bias the coin is to make an
optimal compressor and you could do something really ugly like listen to the whole file
work out some optimal code some complicated sort then you have the header and things
like that but maybe there's a better way
a final complaint about symbol code is if the alphabet is
zero one
then the optimal symbol code is zero one you don't get any compression so binary
files you've got to do something else anyway
what we want is we want a compression method that solves all of these complaints
we just made here we want to method that worked absolutely fine for extreme distributions
we method that works fine even if the probability distribution changes the context naturally fits
into that way of doing things we want to method is perfectly compatible with learning
because we believe data compression is machine learning and we should be doing probabilistic modeling
for anyone who denies that
if you have a compressor if you've written a compression algorithm you have define probabilities
whether you like it or not because if your compressor encodes
a file
and encode things of x which is a string of bits you have implicitly defined
the probability distribution p of this thing has a length l of x define the
problem is due to minus lx whether you like it or not your compressor is
defining probabilities so you better get used to the idea of data compression is probabilistic
modeling because
that's the interpretation
and it makes the whole thing makes sense
so here is what good is going to assume that we've got an oracle our
let's go back to this game just one moment
here's how arithmetic coding is going to work is going to work on the basis
of this guessing game
plus an extra assumption please assume that through well over there
there's another audience
full of all your identical twins
and my identical twins
an identical twin
comes in
so we're gonna play guessing game
and what actually happened just before all you
identical twins an identical twin
just before
these numbers seventeen one two one three one one one two one one one seven
two two two one two one one nine one two one have been written in
this book and pass through the whole here and i come in the identical thing
comes in and you're identical to say
i have got here before me the headline generating book
please guess the first letter the headline and written in front of me is the
number seventeen
and guess i say no to you know do you know that people saying no
discounting one sixteen seventeen p and all i need to know is the number
and i can put up p
and then
use you read one and someone says i say yes that's right because you're all
perfectly died identical twins and i'm following this rule here
we end up without me knowing anything about what's going on is all thanks to
your expertise
so that we end up with this headline
so identical twins give away
o think compression and compression
now that science fiction
but one thing is that computers are science fiction you can make one computer that
builds the probability model does machine learning it makes predictions and you can have an
identical twin computer runs exactly the same algorithm and make predictions at the other end
and that's the principle after encoding uses we assume that the encoder and the decoder
will both have exactly the same identical twin probabilistic model which you can ask for
any given context what's the probability
the next character being a b c d and you know little probability distribution out
of your expert
so what we do
we ask the expert please tell me the probability the first character being a to
and we get the probabilities and i hope you can see this is a b
c d e f g is the back can you read letters
it right
OK and we take the probability of a the oracle has provided the oracle is
this friendly audience inside the box the reliably you tell us the context so the
context is nothing we haven't got the fact that was the first country give me
the probability of can we take this probabilities and we represent them vertically and order
them like arithmetic interval also the height of this green boxes one and the height
of a little blue box within a written in is the probability of a according
to the article
and we can also take exactly the same info from zero to one we can
subdivide it using binary
with zero top in one second so one neuron so can keep subdividing
and any one of these little strings here say one one
zero one
one which is what this box corresponds to here
defines an interval of the line so you can interpret the binary string as defining
an interval for example the box called one
is the interval from harm
to one if we call the top of the box there in the bottom one
and similarly every letter over here has got an interval associated with it
and we can recursively subdividing can say
let's imagine we're trying to
the drug so we're going to compress
there are the tide has meant
and a group of other people added faulty
so eighteen t has this
or had better but still present has this business called natural voices
which is very realistic sounding text-to-speech engine
so you give the text and outputs
realistic sounding speech
so what eighteen he wanted to do
it is to come up with like storefronts or help desk where people could call
up and have a fairly natural dialogue
this system so the car could call up and ask for demo and pricing information
technical support and so on
and one of the color to be able to have an interactive dialogue with the
system so i can
play one of these dialogues they can see what sounds like
so you can hear it i'm supposed to take my microphones in this
so here's here's what one of those dialogue sounds like so you'll hear a human
voice which is the male voice and the synthesized voice which is the woman's voice
to name is crystal
how can i help you
we like demonstration
sure happy with
i don't know what the english going on or challenge
or i can give you an idea of what can been going down like
which would you prefer
o point for you
one of our going on
called which has the power to
here it is
the mariners finished the first half of the season with the rest of the paper
i'd like to customer voice
the red
which is what we are going on
of which has the power to appoint down here finish the first half of the
people with the rest of the paper
we vanished
OK all the very
it's not on the market right now it will be the
language we get out
female voice
from nineteen ninety seven i got that you don't to go the people
we need custom again
all of the boys
OK so you get the idea
how one of these dialogues go
can hear me
OK so
can you hear me OK
yes stop when you cannot
OK so how does the system like this work
that is a dialogue system like this work
well you've got the human over here and the human says something
and that utterance that speech signal gets passed through an automatic speech recognizer
which converted to text
very noisy text
then that text passed two was called the natural language understanding unit
and the job of the NLU is to try to extract meaning from what was
to the extent
whatever was said can be placed into one of the set of categories and the
categories are things like once the here demo wants because sales representative and so on
predicted category gets as the dialogue manager of the dialogue managers job is to keep
track of the state of the dialog for instance what question was recently asked
and the dialogue manager takes as input that predicted category
and converts it and formulate a text response of some kind
that text response gets converted into computer speech which gives way to the human
and the whole thing has to happen in
real time
the part that we're we're using boosting is for this natural language understanding unit
where we basically are just taking
text which comes out of this speech recogniser and trying to categorise
so it seems on the surface to be
just standard text categorisation problem
and to a large extent that's true
but there are some things that made it a particular
particularly interesting problem
in this case
so in this case
one of the goals of the project was not just to get the system to
but to get a system that works as quickly and cheaply as possible
so in order to do that
it's very difficult
i'm sorry so
in order to train
architects categorizer
we need to have a lot of data
and in order to get a lot of data it takes time
get all of that data so because you need a lot of data
that makes
goal of cheap rapid deployment very difficult
so it's kind of a chicken and egg problem because
we need in order to train our text categorizer
we need to have a lot of labeled data
so that we can train and deploy the system
but on the other hand to get that labelled data we have to have the
system already deployed so that we can be collecting data
so it's kind of a chicken and egg problem
so what we did was to
try to use human knowledge to compensate for insufficient data
so for these kinds of problems a human can pretty well guess a lot of
these prediction rules right a lot of these weak classifiers human can say
well if the person says demo then they probably wanted them out as a sales
representative they probably want to speak to a sales representative
and so on so a human can come up with the whole lot
of these rough rules of
and then the challenge is how to take this prior knowledge which has been built
by humans
and combine it
with the the training data which is available
so as to
take advantage of both sources of data both the training data
and they human crafted rules
so to do that what we did was we took the loss function
which is being minimized by adaboost
and we modified that loss function
so that rather than just trying to fit
the training data that we have
we kind of wanted to
balance the the that training data against fit to the prior model which has built
and built by the human
so this
it seems to work really nicely so for instance this is on
another text categorisation dataset called the EP titled dataset
so this green curve shows how well you the human crafted rules work for this
and the blue curve is selling
how well boosting works when we're using only the training data which is available
as a function of the amount of training data that we have
at our disposal
and the red curve is showing what happens when we combine both of these together
and what you see is that
are fairly small
amount of training examples like a few hundred train up to a few hundred training
you getting big improvement by incorporating this prior knowledge
OK we also applied to this help desk data
the first one is the data term
experts suppose x which is the usual
term which measures
the coherency of the clusters
and then we have regularisation to
this one
this is a
interesting because
this is a concave function over standard simplex
it is maximized the virus and
so just to get into the picture
what happens
when alpha is big enough
large and when alpha is low
then this
will dominate history
so in one sense
we do expect that the objective function becomes concave
this is
picture i think it what happens when a lot of two terms one is very
large with respect to dominate
actually what you doing approximately just maximizing this
this becomes negligible
but then you are maximizing
concave function thing
this is man
i didn't magic so a minus
you are saying
if i understand what you're saying that we are adding the same content of all
the terms the
an offer is only on the right
that's right
actually we can be even more formal than that because then this is related to
given them
one of the most
so i should
probably and the one of the next slide
let's make an observation for what happens actually when i have this of on the
main diagonal
it can be seen this is equivalent
adding of to all the off diagonal elements this is a very simple actually
because OK here
the vector e
it's just that we ones
the prime it's just metrics with old ones
it's a simple trick to denote the metric
don't one
a man of i lost count you is just
the automatic
a month of high lost count so we are adding this constant kappa to all
the elements in the magic
now what happens to the objective function
x transpose the minds of i lost this cap can be written this way
and your ex-prime
a mind of i x lovers
here we show them
count a prime x but x is the vector of the standard simplex so a
prime x is one
and again we have ex-prime e which is the sum of all exactly at one
so this is kind
so for all vectors in the simplex
and in the diagonal on the main this myself is equivalent in terms of finding
solution of the objective function
constant over the over
often over the entire element of
so if kappa is equal to one particular when kappa is equal to all
this means that the diagonal becomes zero
so technically speaking
and in this minds of all the main diagonal
is equivalent in terms of finding the optimizers
two having
for two all the off diagonal elements
in terms of the similarities and whatever what's going on we are saying that we
are adding a constant to all the similarities
so when alpha is very large so dominates the i j
actually what we are doing all the pairwise distances become more or less equal
so i will get a very large cluster
so intuitively what we get is that when alpha is very large
and after the final very large
we get a very large class because all the pairwise distances become more or less
equal to
we can neglect AIG
now we we can see exactly
large means
the first let's see what is the effect of this whole
by the
you know we have
this is the original the we have just clouds on
clearly we have three clusters if of flies large enough in this case for example
the other fifty
we are adding a large number of the entire
semantics of similarity and then we get a unique large clusters
so dominant sets actually is this one
we are changing the scale
twelve ways actually scale
in the world
and the topic of this lecture building index
we remember from the first lectures that
what we are doing creating
toy search engine
and now we
come to
when we need to create index and index is the structure that
our search and so
you don't have this slide in in my presentation in in your book because i
simply copied this slide from my first lecture to remind you
we have decided that it will be inverted index
and it it is a special structures that
i can see
from two plaques
for first are on the left on this slide it's
dictionary where we have all of our because
i assume that during church going from our document
covering a set of rules and getting a set of documents there is
and on the right it was released
it's forcing its ideas of of documents in this work
and also i told that information retrieval is very old and library science
thousands years ago already invented the structure and this is
again the fourth of
of index
mechanical implementation of the same of the same data structure
and because it's seem
building this index is
very the piece of wire
it is very very simple
we create some index then we are going to iterating through the whole collection
get every document
from the document to get more put it into index
and or
if it is already in the
up and till is that this
connected to this work
ideal followed document that processing right now though this is
so what are called in places like length
close to pi semantic that implements the story
and it you it is very simple
four lines of course
we don't have any problem with this
what i really question is going to discuss this lecture
first of all we need to decide how should iterate of documents and extract
and all of the features that we discussed in the first lecture
and i promise you that
i want to talk a lot about it i think that it's pretty simple topic
and the current
second what to do if we are going to index because lecture
what is what should be our approach to election huge
and then again from the second lecture you know that something that usually compress structures
can be not only small but fast
so the question is
compress index and
we're going to discuss situations usually in their lives we don't have a stable complex
we always have some change
if they are indexing internet
we always have news sites and updates on the site
if you are in the same
some documents from the company we always have new documents in new versions of these
documents so we always have some updates
therefore we need to talk about how to update its index what are possible strategies
and the and the and
again from the second lecture i promise you that we always talk about pluralisation and
how we can implement blessing not talking about not not unsupervised classification but class how
to implement this very in
a cluster of computers
in parallel
this is called slide from the first lecture
what to extract features from document
we're doing mineralisation so
great some more general suppose that that created on the first lecture
that can
analyse for much of this document
and can extract all words
from this document
so what you getting the editing
four and we are getting some idea of this document
how we can assign this idea
it can be some external IDE can be for internet that can be or this
document its address
another collection can be the unique he
for the document
so starting from this point for our toy project we assume that we always in
i d of the document is simply not
as intentional
even if this is not an integer let's assume that we can simply create some
table with this he
and man
this is simply to simple intention
and another assumption that we are doing right now the the beginning
that when we get documents to our index
this interchange
always increase so we are adding documents and
this unique identification of these documents is simply increasing intention so fails document is one
second to its
it can be done
it's not like percent rule sometimes needs additional tables and the additional weight
what we have seen that we can do this
it's it's some simplification that
simplify all all our processing of the data
so now we are ready to build index and
as also i talked about it
on my first lecture
i things in the same series of building in texas
definitely implemented in ancient egypt by librarians of this type so of
how this goes
can work
i'm taking a book
i'm taking work from his book for example these bogus
well designed for example these movies book was eighty one so i'm taking first work
from this book
i take this work
i put on some
a piece of paper
number of this document i opened this dryer this war
on this dryer
four days
piece of way for his car into these dry clothes then take next door
and i do this step by step
this is this rigorous so from linearisation
they're getting worse the idea of documents
using our dictionary
we find was please for this
i d
and the port new to command the and
this puzzle is very very simple
and so
now you
all right
long weekend ahead of us one more like to the go
if i have an object
mass and gravitational field
gravitational forces in this direction
this is my increasing value of y
this force
vectorial and written equals minus
and g
why rules
since this is the one dimensional problem
we will often simply right f
equals minus
and g
this minus sign is important because that's the increasing value
of y
if this
level here
it is y equals zero
and i could call this
gravitational potential energy is zero
and this is why
then the gravitational potential energy here
because plus
mg y
this is you
so if i make a plot
of the gravitational potential energy
as a function of y
i would get a straight line
this is zero
so this equals you
equals and g
a plus sign
if i'm here point eight
and i move that object to point b
walter lewin move it
i have to do positive work notice
that the gravitational potential energy increases if i do positive work to gravity is doing
negative work
if i go from a to some other point call it b prime
i do negative work notice
the gravitational pull of potential energy goes down if i do negative work
gravity is doing positive work
i could have chosen my zero point
of potential energy
anyway i please
i could have chosen it
right you
and nothing
i will change other than that
i offset
the zero point of my potential energy but again if i go from
a to b
the gravitational potential energy increases by exactly the same amount i have to do exactly
the same
works so you are free to choose when you're near earth
where you choose your
now we take the situation
we are not so close to the earth
here is the earth itself
which you can also replaced by the sun if you want to
and this is increasing value of are
the distance between here and is object
equals are
i now know that there is a
gravitational force
on this object
newton's universal
law of gravity
and that gravitational force
divided by these are scrapped
our rules this is a vectorial notation
since it is really one-dimensional
reward just like we did there
we would delete the
arrow and we will really unit vector in the positive direction and so we would
simply write it
this way
gravitational potential energy
we derive last time
equals minus
divided by are notice here is are here is are squared
and if you
i that
the plant grows sort of like this
this is are
is increasing
potential energy all these values here negative
and you get curve which is sort of like this
this is proportional
one of four
now of course if the earth
at the radius
which is this big
then of course this curve
does not exist
it stops
right here
if i move from point a to point b
with the mass and in my hand
that the gravitational potential energy increases
i have to do positive work is no difference
if i go from a to another point
b prime which is closer to the earth
notice that the gravitational potential energy decreases
i do negative work
if i do positive work gravity is doing negative work
if i do negative work gravity
is doing positive work
right here in the earth
where this
one of our curve
it's the earth
that is of course
exactly that line
that dependence
on y is exactly the same as the dependence of on are and then
you can simplify matters when you knew earth when the gravitational acceleration doesn't change
you get a linear relation that
only in exceptional cases
when you don't
very far
the gravitational force
it is in the direction
the increasing
potential energy
that when i'm here
the gravitational force
is in this direction
increase in potential energy
is this way
the force
is in this way
when i'm here
gravitational potential energy increases in this way
the gravitational force
using this direction
when i'm here
the gravitational potential energy increases in this direction
the gravitational force
is in this direction when here gravitational potential energy increases in this direction
the gravitational force is in the direction of the force
is always in the opposite direction
then the increasing value of the potential energy
if i release an object zero speed
it therefore will always
move towards the lower
potential energy
because the force
i will drive it
two lower potential
and that's it
i changed from gravity
two spring
i have a spring which is
relaxed length l
i call this actually equals zero
and i extended
over the distance x
there's a mass and the and
and there will be a spring force
and that spring force
equals minus
kx is one-dimensional situation so i can write it without having
to worry about the
the arrows
there is no friction here
it's clear that if i hold it in my hand
the force
consider all of the possible resulting partitionings i'm covering my space of potential by clustering
in such a way
they're guaranteed that
one of them is epsilon close to the true cost
it's a different type of use of the statistics here and it works for each
of them
of the of the cost functions that i is defined
so that's all i mean these are very i mean these are results from from
from this summer
so we haven't had time yet to try them and we'll that so in this
sense it's very theoretical we don't know how it works and that what we do
these are
as far as i can tell you the first step
performance guarantees for biclustering algorithms
tell you that if you follow this way on time algorithm and you get guarantee
that you are
within excellently optimum solution
OK so that's as far as the complexity goes there's only one more issue that
they wanted to
and this is the learnability of bi clustering so
if you consider the netflix problem
then there
the problem of writing predicting their right the ranking of movies that it's a slightly
different problem because the main issue is that the metric is not full have lots
of missing entries
so assume that
i want to predict in which groups assume already the biclustering of my matrix of
and movies
and now there's a new movie coming
i want to predict which group is this new movie going to belong to
or maybe new users
is joining my
pool of their customers
i want to predict
which group this user is going to be long
so that that's a very natural question to ask so
i call it learnability of bi clustering is a way to predict the cluster membership
of a previously unseen
on moving
so it turns out that it is
what the case in learning in order do prediction we have to restrict the family
of potential solutions that we are considering is like a classification if you want to
be able to to get any guarantees of equality the occasion to restrict yourself to
some for this class otherwise you have these no free lunch phenomena
we propose
so the question is
how do i restrict the family of all possible partitions of my
of of all possible clusterings of matrix and i want to do it by taking
into account side information so assume that now i will allow to take into account
information they have about users so when someone joins the member
i'm a asking to give me is date of birth and his address and whatever
the parameters and of course i have several properties about the movie i know well
what was the year
the movie was you know the
the movie was produced which country it was with the director and so on
so i want to use the side information
so i want to use the features of the the rows and the columns to
restrict the family of potential clusterings
one natural way of doing it is to restrict our attention to the family of
all clusterings which are in the feature space is of the road
and in the feature space is of the columns have only diagram
so now
are known from the column architecture also in the early visual cortex for example you
find patchy long range connections in prefrontal cortex that are typical for example if you
want to hear connect cells that have the similar orientation preference what you do is
you need a long range connections to to bridge between all the between all the
intermediate me the meaning intermingled cells that have a different orientation preferences long-range projections and
you find similar anatomical substrates also in prefrontal cortex which might suggest that you have
such an architectural also in the prefrontal cortex and other parts of the brain
now the problem is that the the voxels here are far too big to resolve
this cortical columns at
so the column pattern has as the resolution of say half a millimetre to bit
smaller depends on the species as well as some species apparently don't have any columns
for example here dogs apparently don't have columns but never heard that validated anywhere so
the key is that the problem is you can zoom in with the for my
resolution to these individual cortical columns
so you can't get this fine grained information and that's why content selective processing has
only rarely been studied with for my
unless use very artificial cases for example where people funny faces and houses because they
use the face area and the house areas attacked for content selective processing
a couple of years ago
we and others have looked at the this in more detail
and this graph here shows quite nicely that you can possibly expect to still gets
at some kind of information stored at the column level
with your pretty large voxels
and what you can see here on the left is simulated that's kind of pretty
colin architecture that encodes different orientations and the yellow
great is the voxel grid views
and i could say obviously the grid is far too big to to resolve these
individual regions of orientation selectivity but now you can display a very simple game and
you can go into one of these voxels and count how many cells there are
of each different type of orientation preference
and then you get a self reference count you can see that here in the
right for each works
and what you find is that in some voxels you see a surplus of one
type of cells and some voxels you see a surplus of the different types of
just due to the random fluctuations in the math you see surpluses sometimes you get
a few more one cell type sometimes you get a few more of another cell
and now
what you predict is that if you stimulate with two different orientations what should happen
is that you get a patter subtle patterning of the signal is not very strong
would be expected to be weak because obviously the majority of the response can be
determined by some kind of common factor that is kind of the same in each
of these different orientations here but you would expect some subtle patterning of the author
my response due to these biased sampling effect here
and in fact the shows for example something from the first study that relate to
this value can be tiny in front of you see the sampling bias patterns and
you can also for example measure them i can show you another slightly see more
so this is the sampling bias pattern
this is the sampling bias patron in v one
four different orientations
this is something buys pageant for color
in early visual cortex so this is the one here the two is power boarding
and then v three and you can also see it for the OP for the
eye of origin even in subcortical structures such as the LGN
and i could say well this is just some happening who can tell if this
really is in any way reproducible reliable or whatever
well the simple way to test that is just measure the pattern again and see
if it correlates and in fact you get a very high correlation between these patterns
when you made the measure ones in the new measure them against the very highly
correlated so that the distribution of preferences in each voxel some voxels have a very
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
so that we can doesn't begin until at least after the 309 1 lecture
than play couple of announcements next Tuesday quiz to based on the subject matter of
homework to
the periodic table on Thursday and it's gonna be not before too long
have time for monthly tests the 1st monthly test
the mnemonics contest deadline is a week from today plots sent to me by e-mail
if you wanna when they're hottie that hot stars and it's come to my attention
that people are moving freely about recitations without arranging through my office in some of
the recitation sections are are
uncomfortably large which defeats the purpose of the recitations or in part and we want
you to have access to the instructor and we've got 30 students there instead of
20 that dilutes your access so are we insist that you
to the section that assigned to and if you must change because you have a
you've got some other activities so please do it through my office so that we
can now
make the learning experience good for
the majority and not just for the diffuse and
so there's something else think
yes I just just learned yesterday that somewhat disappointment you know my favorite transuranic element
is 111 because it goes as plutonium but does it has been isolated by the
team Darmstadt in Germany and they have proposed a name name-brand again and again after
a villain rank and who was the discoverer of x-rays and that's now before the
International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry so maybe before the followers of will have
to change our each showed you that this is not done steady and so we're
going to have a whole bunch of would like to invite Miriam so that we
have a bunch of German names along here
busy over Berkeley what are they doing they're going on video divorce leaving
OK so let let's get to the lesson last day
last day we study the boar model from 1 electron atoms and other models showed
us that through the quantum condition all of these quantities uh were quantized they were
functions of the quantum number n and later in the lecture we began to look
for reconciliation between the boar model and bombers analysis of angstroms
spectral lines study of atomic hydrogen and so we looked at the prism spectrograph gas
discharge tube but I showed you the energetics of what goes on in there
and towards the end of the lecture we started talking about the actual energetics of
collision I wanna return to that so let's put up that sketch again where we're
looking at
the incident electron and this is the electrons that is
accelerating off the cathode rays electrons all over I wanna make sure we're not confusing
1 electron for another set of this electron I'm talking about here is this 1
that is moving off the cathode and towards the end node and on route is
going to collide with some atomic hydrogen so this is the incident electron and it
has it has kinetic energy it has kinetic energy of the denoted the incident one
half mv squared it's not bound is moving along and let's subset stress this is
well incident velocity incident velocity electron rest mass incident energy and it's gonna collide with
a hydrogen atom at some point I would draw the hydrogen atom schematically like this
with protons in the nucleus and alone electrons in some orbit here
if the energy is the energy of the incident electron is greater than the energy
for some transitions with
the hydrogen then it's possible that this electron will capture some of the energy from
the incident electron and be excited to some other states so let's put that on
what's called this some initial state and let's call this some final state and that's
only going occurred when this incident energy is greater than the energy of transition so
we've got 2 electrons here here's a moving electrons free electron this 1 is bound
so this is in the target
or can be specimen which in this case is atomic hydrogen
let's look at what happens here the excitation occurs
and we can get the energy required for this
transition by using the boar model the boar model gives this value gives the value
and the funeral of the of the postulates that delta E of transition is equals
minus k
I'm putting up generally z squared to
allow for a higher z level of 1 electron atoms and it's 1 over the
quantum number squared minus 1 over initial quantum number squared so that gives you the
amount of energy and that energy is going to be taken away from the kinetic
energy of the incident electron which then will make its merry way off after the
collision and purposely making that vector shorter to indicate that this electron has been slow
and we call this electron be scattered electrons
scattered by the collision with the target hydrogen it has kinetic energy the sub scattered
as one half m v squared scatter the mass of the electron doesn't change but
found out well actually we doing the same and if you remember the story behind
the scenes then that actually adapted for the for the adapted for the US market
because they had nothing available so they adopted the but due to the fact that
it was american funding they had to
so the the same and ask them to please
and then then they found out that there are still some some things to say
is are some issues to solve and there has to be some standardisation effort because
this was product driven so the work was performed within projects then the
so we said OK we take some the standardisation process the people that worked previously
in the project and that project then worked jointly together the web and group and
not find
standard it hasn't translated by way
that's the current standards is basically the democrats standard with modifications and extensions but this
could method that no converter who does automatic translation but also doesn't exist too much
to develop energy so effort of transforming them
well maybe not too big and so that's who says that there is that the
introduce so you have some top you have left on top you have not and
this well is for example to see that has with the schema
after that is serialised in XML so it's
agent comes he's able to process the XML information if i have agent comes he's
able to process the RDF information and the agent comes he's able to to process
this information so that we have the
architecture that some unsolved problems with that layering what happens if the information given in
the RDF layer contradicts the one which is given the level for example so you
can make statements in which
which correspond to the things that are not there for that some problems that have
to be served that's how can you go into the den cycles in it and
stuff like that so the process the implementation side a little bit but what i
see is that we have a standardisation body
w three c that has a very good reputation that is working on this from
the blue one standard which is then supported by a lot of tools
that would be
so these are the
then the business people to look
such too much because know that established standards in some first applications and proof of
concept this
but you can do that said that
we have to distinguish herself the scientific revolution because they're of
scientific projects would and it has been working commission and some major funding going on
the web and exists some companies in the
something like a spin-off enterprises comparable to system of quentin returns and
that's not true
to give bed bread and butter for twenty people so there is market that that's
the difficult market because people not understand couldn't the the benefits of the technology so
it's very much a consulting job so that that company for example and so we
can solve some of the problems mobility and this because what's interesting the product but
they didn't understand what technology so it's not just which use it but specific that
technology which we have to adapt to the problem
and then we can do to solve the problem and they have different requirements and
stuff like that so it's that difficult market which will become easier as soon as
the standards are well-established as soon as the standard products for ontology modelling
i mean there are a lot of ontology editors just this simple example that you
have parents and whatever editor of cement of twins but there no standard product in
a way to some extent true that but i wouldn't claim that these are the
standard products for the community and this is an important step toward notes
the commercial market i would so that potential there already some revenues but it's still
a large potential
we're going to use all of its should
are you going
and that's the computer quote face-to-face meetings this as a basic ontology language so we
can define the ships between the concepts and what you do is you know could
unfortunately representative those folks example that you can define
relationships as opposed
so it's not relationship is inverse to another one you could say that one relationship
is symmetric you could say that a certain
certain relationship is transitive for example for the are to say that such a big
of a deal with at the soccerplex see which is the topic of these events
is also some topic of any of the plants that you have that object identity
so you can say that two
entities it not the same which is quite important for certain applications and you have
some other ontology modelling stuff so RDF and RDF schema is really very basic first
but not necessary to draw inferences for example like the rules so if you want
to process of such rules you need more modelling primitives which i introduced in all
what about
we are going to to be so
so there
it seems to be what
OK and that is why we can't shake the semantic web that is also very
large networks that spanned you will large wide area networks was ever developed in each
of these little square nodes here is the
is a machine that song so there are four machines only opened in nineteen sixty
nine and there were these
routers that were being used
this is nineteen seventy one so by nineteen seventy one
there still is a cluster of these machines in california
but you know the illinois carnegie mellon and boston have suddenly appeared on this map
MIT's here lincoln labs here harvard here BBN which is another large company that does
a lot of networking research in this area is here
the network is started to evolve and in particular you notice that there are now
these are two clusters these two regions one on the west coast and one on
the east coast have a number of nodes
so it just keeps growing and growing and by nineteen eighty is see the network
has gotten substantially larger and one of the interesting things about this is you starting
to see a diversity of links so noticed that hawaii is now connected into california
by way of a satellite connection as his london so we now have not just
not only just these wires run but in fact we have wireless links were still
on top of this the at the same time this is happening all the particles
we've been talking about being developed in one of the whole goals of this would
be able to support these multiple different kinds of links on top of a standard
networking protocols
so by nineteen eighty seven this thing is really become turned into a number of
decentralised networks as this large network of the urban that there's something smaller called backbone
and a number of other networks there's military networks and so on these are all
connected together and all being in this debate by nineteen seven there were all running
TCP IP protocol that was being used to exchange information between all these things
around about a few years after this right the internet the this world wide web
suddenly happened and it became this huge commercial interest in
the internet and that has really caused part to this explosion of nodes and made
the network just huge incredibly fast so it's hard to see this but the middle
of this you notice that there is little orange note here
this is this bar on the left side showing the out degree of nodes in
the network so this is this numbers two nine seven seven is that means there's
no to the centre of the internet has two thousand nine hundred seventy seven links
to other nodes
so this is like this is a really incredibly large network and you notice that
all of these twenty or thirty bright pink red nodes here have hundreds to thousands
of outgoing connections on each one so there is this core of the internet is
very highly connected to a very large part of the network now down to out
around the edges of these much smaller networks that have much lower conductivity
and these are things like service providers for example that consumers might pay some money
to get a connection from so this is the sort core of the internet these
are the people who are not so much the end users on the internet but
the service providers are providing activity for the end users each one of these little
nodes represents one of the service providers this was as of two thousand three
OK so
what i want to do now is to start as i said we're going to
start off with a baby version of the network particular going to look at how
four reading or how routing might work in this very simple network that shown here
let's see what happens to see what happens to renew the particle that we call
path vector routing
the idea behind routing is that we're going to build up the paths from
that is the sequence of nodes that we should we should forward messages through
in order to reach a particular destination
and the way that this work is to reduce stay there have two steps
here so
routing is going to consist of two
two steps
advertising phase
advertised steps
and integrations that
the idea is that during the advertisment step each node is going to advertise what
other nodes it knows how to reach
and then during integration steps each node is going to take
all of the advertisment her during the previous
advertising stuff and integrate them into a new set of rules that identifies the new
set of nodes of this node can reach
this will be very very clear when i showed example so let's just look at
the case of all the nodes figuring out how they can reach node c so
it's going to happen is that first node is going to send out an advertisment
it says that nobody knows how to reach node right which it obviously does and
the way reaches node is simply by forwarding a message up to and where
so it is to reach node e come this way and sends it out over
the two links that has to node c and d
so nodes c and d here this advertisment during the integration step what they're going
to do is to add this information about this connection with to node b
and they're going to store which link it is based on that message out over
it was they they should they should send messages out over in order to reach
i e e
one of the rule
is the
or or
o machine your
it is
so the rest of the questions
how many people
so that's she
in some sense
this is
all of of this is that
falls right
very very
we're seeing here
one four
no more
that is just a special case
you need to use
but before she has to learn a
all songs
rain forests
we know
he that
because there's whole
this is
c three
one hundred per cent
on is true
he was
all right so
are possible y
three are
for example
the reason we use
maybe mention is all
vaccine preventable disease
we're going to draw the this list in nineteen fifty
polio been on top
so some things have really changed
now what i'd like to do is to briefly explore
some of the factors that
i think i have contributed
has c
the first is the decline in vaccine preventable diseases
these of much less diphtheria
we are not
of our cultural experience as a society today
i think also that we're has been brought recognition
particularly since about the sixties
about the limits of medicine and technology
as the nation emerged from the second world war
we had a view that that modern technology could pretty much anything
it was the
the primacy of the engineer
and i think little by little we have learned that many of the major concerns
of life
are not easily solved
medicine and technology
and this is i think in part explains some of the resurgence of complementary and
alternative medicine is people look for other ways to solve
the problems that they faced
there's been abroad growth of consumerism which fact
which have aspects
our entire society
and then there are major failures of US health care system and here i was
pointing specifically to our failure to deal with mental health disorders
autism being among them
concomitant with that has been growing
growth of the vaccine injury compensation fund
which was of funding created
roughly in the mid nineteen eighties to compensate people who have been injured by
was thought to have been injured by a vaccine appropriately manufactured ministers
and that's funded by a tax on every does vaccine
well that's fine which cannot be used for anything but compensating for injury is now
over three billion dollars and it's no surprise that individuals who was family members have
conditions that are not taken care of by our health care system might look to
that one as a way of getting some resources
but there's more because the origins are complex clearly there has been today i distortion
of scientific process of proposing hypothesis testing
accepting or rejecting it then refining today
hypotheses are regularly then first in the media
and then they are validated by by
and when you look for the enemy of the enemy is us because i think
every major medical journal today
releases its findings first press
and then those of us who work in clinical medicine often hear about it first
on the today show or
for myself on NPR
he's going in the wrong direction
then the issue of causality
the criteria for establishing causality
differs in the world of science and medicine
in the legal world and in the world of public opinion and the quickest and
simplest example of that is breast implants
do breast implants cause chronic disease
there is no
credible scientific evidence that they do
however the manufacturers were found liable court of law
and clearly they were found guilty
you are responsible in the court of public opinion
risk communication is a very complicated are
and case reports are enormously powerful
no matter what the study shows
when you see a pair parent
with the child
who's suffering from a disease or a bad conditions and whose parents believe that that
was related to the things that is very
very powerful and often much easier to understand than for example an institute of medicine
and today
the media
he is interested in contacts privacy
and that's what cells
the media's concept of balance
is to present both sides of the story
i was like this little piece from scientific american
good journalism values balance above all else
we are to our readers to present everybody's ideas equally
if politicians or special interest groups say things that are untrue or misleading our journal
duties journalists is to quote them without comment or contradiction
to do otherwise would be elitist and
you might notice that day
the that appeared in the scientific american
april first two thousand ten
that was that was a joke
but to make the point the media or do regard
balance as evidence of
journalistic integrity
they tend to equate one expert with another
and again there focuses mostly on controversy rather than necessarily the search for truth
now not all these names on this slide may be familiar to you
but i would submit that those on the right are highly qualified experts or website
that is a tries to present strictly science-based information
where some of the photos on the left have particular viewpoints and are very effective
and today
communication tends to promote science
and in part that's because not because in general parents do not have a clear
idea how to evaluate the credibility
the source of information about immunizations it's not something that they are knowledgeable about and
they really don't know
how to go about figuring out who
who to believe
now i'm going to shift in talk now a bit about the history of compulsion
for immunization
in both massachusetts and in england laws were passed right at the beginning of the
the nineteenth century requiring populations to be vaccinated
so the question was what maybe all the people from the other here but again
i repeat there is an assumption here
the class of functions
i will be a
you know
he said the function as to be a bounded set in the matrix
yes i mean the fact that you can cooperate with by many balls implies that
within the with respect to all
yes but you can have the fact that is bounded and enclose the positive impact
in finite dimensions but you can have an infinite dimensional space but you
i have this well is it's called
we come back they get in this case when you can cover with finite many
yes there is this
restriction i mean if you want to apply this things
and you have lot of
because this
the notion of being able to cover your space by many
but which can happen even in infinite dimension
this is just too
come back to
in the IID assumption which
as i told you is like the only one that i'm allowing myself is to
assume that the data comes in IIT fashion and i just want to say that
this is
so our mind
assumption in the sense that
OK we can argue whether
in our data indeed indeed comes from and i i d
and of course we never can verify that this is the case
so maybe we can argue about it but on the other hand it turns out
this is a convenient setting for studying the problem and you can have all sorts
things that are kind of more realistic but still give the same result so it's
fine to work in the ITV framework because you get this the right intuitions
and if you're not happy with IID because you don't want to to assume this
and work in these
two other framework i mean one of them that i mentioned already this online primary
duty see that's
in the next lecture that actually
you can get the exact same type of bounds
in this framework without making any assumption about how the data is generated but from
i like the way he writes things is a bit different but in the end
the same
you know the same phenomenon occurs
and the other cases
i want articles
if setting where actually you consider that the data is fixed so you have you
big said that
extracted from the UCI library for example and you know you have a finite set
of data and you never we get to see any of the data points you
just based on what you do typically is used these they think well parts use
one portraying the other one for testing
you know and you hope that your algorithm is doing a good job
and in this case you can you know
consider that what is random is not the data about the we use these data
and you can actually make sure that the way these data is uniform in the
sense that you have you know
an equal probability of generating any kind of fit of the data that we can
actually implement that scheme of
random speaking
and this is typically what
we do an experiment and we write when we write papers and we report experimental
results we have exactly done that and in that same thing you can
basically derive the same bounds
for this case where you have a fixed set of data and run the risk
of these events part
so this is just to say
don't be upset that me five
use the IID assumption
even though i think i i should not make too many assumptions this is
perfectly fine in that respect
at least i it shows you the right information
OK so now i want to go back to the bounds that i mentioned yesterday
try to understand
what do they mean what can i you know infer from that conclude from obtaining
such bounds
the first thing i want to mention is that
when you look at the bounds of this one so when we compare the loss
of our algorithm with the empirical loss of our algorithm and we get an upper
bound you know we've been and some confidence that that's what this
o with high probability
this is an interesting fact of bounds
it only tells you OK
these two quantities are close so which means that if you want to estimate the
true error rather than from the empirical error this algorithm it's fine you can do
but it does not guarantee you that your algorithm is performing well does not guarantee
that this is small
i mean this may be small only if indeed
the empirical error is small we can only
be sure on the given set of data that this is the case but
you know it's not the statement that will tell you all your have wisdom is
good in general in
and in particular if you look at the value of the bonds you know you
we could say well i ever smaller bound for my algorithm that someone else will
for ease algorithm so
my algorithm has to be there were
actually it's not the case because
you can have i mean the small band that you can have here is when
your algorithm is just picking always the same function so
a trivial algorithm that always in order have the same functional model where the data
plus the sum of all i said y equals zero
by david j
log probability of zero
same as before
changing my alma notation a little bit
somehow i equals one
so i
far such that like not changing the summations
so while was one
david david j
log p
just going to call this
and this is
one minus p
because the probability that y equals zero is one minus the probability that y equals
the by david j
log of one minus p
really see how i got here
i'm going to
star work going to evaluate
by deviated j
log p
and this is
one of the p
by debated j
it is a derivative of the log function this is the natural like functions of
under the log
is the
one of the function
divide j of log of one minus p
is one of the one minus p
and then minus one
i be debated j of p
so much so
both cases
now what i need to do
so what
drop the
open try out
let me introduce some notation
so he
the exponential of my linear function
minus some from j equals zero the d
from data j
and then
one of one class e
so this is my arm logistic regression function and one minus p
it is of one class e and one plus e minus one is he over
one class
use that notation
the by
the beta j p
so that's something i need to work out here
it's and this is the definition of p
my so it's
minus one
one plus e to the minus two
ninety religion e
minus one one person e to the minus two
and then the this is he is an exponential function so the derivative of an
exponential is the exponential
thank you
and then
debi debated j
and now i'm taking the derivative
inside the exponential which is a linear function
i just really pick out the term here that involves peter j
and that is
so i've
i looked out the window
now comes the
the elegant rewriting parts
so i can
these minor says
and then what i get is one of one class e
and then he over one plus
because i had one plus to minus two here
my times
which is
OK so let's think about this a little bit more
how can we use this space to visualize the performance of these trees is the
way i like to think about it
if i had treatment for leaves
think about possible ways that label tree for these two possible classes so after four
sixteen possible it and all of these can be actually visualized as points in this
space so for instance the labelling
plus minus minus minus which corresponds to this point here
the label minus plus plus
doesn't matter and all of this is something that needs to be really good morning
class class
all correctly that one negative
and two
six five days cells
so mind
one of class were
and actually
one you
the figure out that they symmetrically opposite so it's point through centre of gravity of
the space of one from the
the midpoint in that so you can do
it is the space but the and the reason why
it is that some
all possible represent classifiers structure from this tree has to somehow go
some of these sixteen points there are no more points
in in in
what is this is what discrete ricci
on this
on this dataset tracks
and the actual
by using here of regular i use some of the points fact the point which
which is the convex hull of this
the point is that it's not a coincidence
now let's use this idea to to think about how history being built so
decision tree building is nice because the process so what we do we find the
best the world because the tree by the
so far we can actually visualize very nicely in ROC space so because just think
about it if nothing else then basically we have since that year
and if we use this to rank with the
go from this point the left the sixth of this form
about four
six so i think history is visualized
by this
and what we can do about growing tree in the lab
strong tree and let me know if you need to find
who here
so the next get something like this
and then finally in the that's that we grow right to get something like this
OK now is
i can see some of the questions that some new which is
it doesn't quite look like the raw the show before
so what answer is about what the show you
here is not the right thing or it's just the waters
tree is being built
we therefore trace the decision trees don't always ordered
from left to right
so we have an additional step this is sure
social thing
we take a stronger
and then
using posterior also realize those leaves
and we get something like this
on that by very first animation and
that means that you
so this is the key
decision trees have some kind of syntactic structure
but that does not modify the ranking order we don't have stay here or to
believe that we find that the water so we have the those vectors
but we put them in different order and maybe you can quite easily proven to
for some time
on the training set you will always get the context right
so i think the decision trees you get is the best friend
as is already such a link between the classification
OK that's what i was
it may not be immediately obvious naive bayes is tricky
certainly if you have this free use it is a a tree like structure one
now page needs to
estimate probability for each possible combination of attribute values and that's what we do with
this country
is it true that
of course is always complete decision trees so there's no pruning you need
all the possible combinations
also of course there are many different ways in which to draw complete decision trees
and here is just i just use three short years before so what is happening
one basic probability estimate
the joint probability that use marginal probabilities to estimate the joint probability
you can understand follow the
prior of here which is uniform so that can do anything
then i have
the model for a
but i will zero
the market of b are all in
six of this form that the model for the long before this expected
one now