I guess in the next two slides
actually in
not in the next two slides
a little bit further down I'll be telling you what are measures before I can
tell you what are
distributions over measures okay
and Dirichlet process being kind of this very
basically a canonical example of a nonparametric model it that's kind of like di different ways in which we
could derive it
and it's kind of a special case of lots of different
processes okay
and we'll be looking at we'll be deriving the Dirichlet process actually in three different ways
the as the infinit limit of Gibbs sampler for finite mixture model and using the Chinese
restaurant process and using the stick breaking construction
okay so let's start off with this infinite limit of finite mixture models okay so this is I guess the
simplest recall that we have this
model this model for model based clustering which is typically called a finite mixture model
and it's finite in the sense that there's a finite number of
of mixture components or clusters
and it's a mixture model in that you assume that the data that you observe
is a mixture of of different basically heterogenous populations
right and so just to recall for you the the generative model is that we
have some indicated variables that i which tells us which cluster
x i belongs to and it can take on one of k values k goes to one to big k
the mixing proportion is pi with a prior given by a Dirichlet okay
and again we have for each cluster k we have a parameter theta
star k
and we have a prior over theta star k given by h
are pe have people here
who has seen a Dirichlet distribution before
who has not seen Dirichlet distributions
quite a lot okay so
I'll spend a few slides on them
by h what I mean is a prior over the parameters of that cluster so
f is gonna be your
your cluster distribution
and h is your prior so in the case of a mixture of Gaussians okay f
would be a Gaussian parameterized by a mean and a variance
and that theta will be
vector of lenght too is will be the mean and the variance and h is gonna
be a prior over your mean and your variance so you might think that maybe
the mean
I expect it to be lying close to zero okay and the variance will be approximately one okay
so those are counter priors on your mean and your varinace
so Dirichlet distribution is basically a
distribution on the
k dimensional probability simplex so this is basically the set of all vectors
pi such that
each entry of the vector is nonnegative and it sums to one okay
typically you can think of this as a
maybe I should draw this
if you
have a three dimensional space
okay so this is your
pi one
pi two
pi three okay
and this is the space which basically corresponds to something like this basically it's
this plain which passes through
one zero zero
zero one zero
and zero zero one
okay so it's a plain in that
every point of this probability simplex is gonna be a vector of lenght three
each of which is each entry is positive or is nonnegative and they have to sum to
one okay
so it spans by these three vectors basically it's all convex combinations of these three vectors okay
and a Dirichlet distribution is a distribution on this space it has a density given
by this thing okay so this here is gonna be the basically is the normalization
constant for the density and over here is the part of the density which does
depend on pi okay
and is basically a products over k goes to one to big k of
pi k raise to the
some exponents minus one okay
so these exponents are the parameters of the Dirichlet distribution okay
useful when evaluation of each
individual it takes a lot of time so this can be distributed
o specific topic here is
genetic algorithms have been subject to
evaluation of solutions
so far we we assumed we have some measure that can be
calculated that can be checked on a computer so this is the most traditional way
of problem solving with computers now
in this case
i subjective evaluation means interact way of using the genetic algorithms there of course some
problems with the solutions cannot be measured using some numeric
function like a way to minimum cost or the minimum error or whatever
imagine for example
some designs for example where one needs to decide about how these colors are nice
how come how to evaluate this subjectively in this sense or maybe to evaluate taste
or whatever so
this is a way of doing it again in a sort of
evolutionary experimentation computer
or the algorithm offers a solution
and the human expert tell us how good it is
and then this is used as a measure
to perform or to guide the search further
there's also a very popular topic now
the multi object to g is when there is
more than one object you
to be optimized within a certain problem this also requires extensions of these techniques
OK this is already the next technique before going to that i would like to
an example again of a which would be
the support that explanation of GA's
OK can you see these simplest colors in the back rows
OK this is really a simple example but i must say that students use really
like it because it illustrates in the way how the the genetic algorithm works
first of all about the problem
the task is
ten digit number
so to get the right ten digit number and the the information you get for
that for every number you offer you suggest is the number of digits that are
for example here is one solution seven six eight and so on
and the blue
background here indicates that this value is the correct one
all the others are not
actually you can say the fitness or the quality of the solution is one because
only one digit is the correct one
how this can be this computer program operates first it generates a sequence of ten
digits it keeps it aside and then the solutions in this search is evaluated according
to that solution of course according to that ten digit number
so here we see a population of ten
such solutions generated randomly and we see that actually
there's different number of
right digits varying from zero to five so
more or less blood
let's say we to solve this problem or try to solve it by genetic algorithms
this is the population of ten individuals and this is what happens after that come
the variation phase
two strings these we first and the second one
produced these two
offspring by recombination
so we can see
seven six eight zero nineteen sixty five
and then
here is six eight
but heuristics eight in the second so this was the crossing site and these two
substrings were exchanged OK
it's actually performing in the same way as on the binary string we use to
parents and this defined crossing site and exchange the second part
now this grey zone here are mutated values
mutation is something that happens with low probability so
these zero here you can see originally we had
eight here OK
so now after mutation this great period indicates the mutation this became zero
so again this goes on according to the principles of variation and selection so we
can run these
it's a full one population for one generation so this continues in steps so we
have some statistics here generation eight mean fitness average fitness and maximum fitness
and best solutions from a solution found so far so we can run this
not too wait for step and what you can see here is that
OK ten digits correct here
and this was found after one hundred and and eighty seven generations
we can run it again
this time we were lucky only thirty two generations
as do it again
it takes us to be more
seven hundred and something
maybe once again
OK now
four hundred and four
so this is to illustrate the stochastic nature of this group
you can see that
in different rounds
depending on of course the random values that are used and the seed is
said differently in every round and the idea is
with stochastic algorithms and this will be and a message from this demo
a single run is just a single run if you want to
evaluate the performance of the stochastic algorithm this should be done
sequence of france
with some statistical evaluation why this is important
somebody may be interested
what is let's say the average number of iterations one needs to run in order
to obtain the solution
if you're on the with once this is
not not really informative you know what you need to provide some information you can
only get after doing statistics or the number of rounds
and so on
this is a very good
right this is this is just the next point i wanted to illustrate yes
the role of the operators
in particular mutation here y mutation is important
we said this is a random changes of certain bits of certain genes
two distributions p and q
and is an epsilon p
this is a little neighborhood of the distribution
so while
think of
these y one through y n
all right that's just the realization of say and i i d random variables and
what you could do is take the empirical distribution
of these vector of random variables you take these empirical distribution
the true distribution is key
that's why i have these bq here
right so
we know from the law of large numbers that
eventually these empirical distribution
is going to converge to q
so now this is telling us
what is going to be the probability
then this empirical distribution is going to be in the little neighborhood of p
it's going to be visiting a little neighborhood of p
after and samples
so if n is very small three or four
well maybe there is a chance that u will be impersonating p
by the sequence but it is going to be very unlikely that you are going
to be in the neighborhood of p
n is large because you should really be close to q
the the relative entropy is actually gauging dot
that the probability that road is going to be exponentially decreasing in n
and the exponent is really the relative entropy
so that's the difficulty
of impersonating p by q
now imagine that hue
imagine that there are some
some letters in this alphabet
that have zero probability according to q
and positive probability airport according to p
well there's no way that you can impersonate a distribution
the doing in in
in person p with q
because no matter what you do that the empirical distribution of y one through y
and will never have positive probability in those letters so you will never be able
to impersonate people you'll never be able to to be close to be and that's
relative entropy in that case is infinity
you cannot do it was the other way around around you may very well be
able to do it maybe may very well be that if the true distribution is
then after a while you're still a very very close to q
in that case
is is a finite number
OK so this result is in our paper chernoff
in fact it's interesting because
he attributes the result
and it turns out there
the story is that then they are cysteine about this and he said i have
no clue if never seen these results and so was called this time this times
and so on but but then it turned out that what happened was the chairman
of submitted the paper
and then one of the reviewers said all you know i've seen this results in
an unpublished paper by this time
so then chairman of just reference this this thing it without even looking at it
because it had not been published and so it's back like stein's lemma three
the to turn off and is that the turn of in this paper
usually people
and reference to the wrong paper might of
in order to reference this results
now this one is the law of large numbers type of
all of relative entropy
this is kind of like invasion
the type of
analysis say after you have
several observations
in the observations come from p one is the reliability of rejecting q when p
is true
what you're going to do is we're going to find the posterior probability of both
and then decide
according to which one is larger
so if you were to take
that number
there there
the ratio of the two of posterior probabilities they belong them and then divide by
and then that actually is going to
to convert to the relative entropy of p and q
so in fact this is the kind of based results
then on patients can live with because
it actually does not depend on the priority probability of the hypothesis even though
unless there is that
a priori probability you cannot define the quantities here
at the end of the day it washes out
OK so if this is large then you would expect that is going to be
a likely
that you're going to decide the all hypotheses
you're going to the two
be able to reject q when p is true with high reliability
now in information theory
when we do lossless data compression for example we do i huffman coding we ever
huffman called then selects valuable
length representations for different elements in the source
and that
code is designed to minimize the average length
so it was designed for some distribution
but then i suppose that the true distribution is
these people
well then you have to pay a penalty
and that penalty is
dpq the relative entropy of
p with respect to q
note is that what i said
actually is not quite what i have in the slide in the slide i say
the asymptotic ex is right
because to be precise that result is not true
is not true for any length
it's only two asymptotically so the fact that this is the that the penalty
for the mismatch in data compression is
is true in the limit as n goes to infinity
for kirk
the first speaker is the chairman the head of the department of brain and cognitive
sciences maracas who has
been a fantastic leader in this department for the last five years six years
and he's going to lead off the other speakers for today are
l in and i once in
i think it's been in the news lately because he wrote
the smallest book
was the bible was the bible bible
on the smallest piece of metal known to man has been a new york times
and there's
the things but there's no reason
anyway regardless are
a our leader in brain and cognitive sciences
they're not going to be any exams
i've been promised
drawing on
that is
but have
it is
three you
the reason
the range
he want to bring
there are a few
you read the article
three three
two hundred people
the only way
can do this
this is one of the batteries
we have that it ourselves
one reason why
can better computers
has to do with it
the way they are why
the way that brain cells while themselves into networks and can create nonlinear output from
simple inputs and therefore emergent out parts that are not simply predicted by the courts
there's another reason and you'll have to wait till the end of my talk
the figure out why that has to do with the deep structure of the brain
and cognition so you to stay away
the brain is made up of cells
and there are two ways by which brain cells differ from any other cell in
our body
and one of those ways has to do with the fact that brain cell has
what is called an excitable membrane
a brain cells firing impulses
and electrical spikes impulses are
the language of the brain all information in the brain
it is conveyed the
the interval between spikes there is no information in the height of the spikes but
all information is contained in there
the time interval between spikes with the formal
all scored modulation and the reason brain cells can fire spikes is because they have
what is called a semi permeable membrane that keeps sodium out and keep potassium in
r and and and a brain cell five despite when sodium rushes then
and then put us in russia
and the nobel prize was given for this discovery
hodgkin and huxley in
in the early nineteen sixties for the discovery in the fifteenth of the mechanism for
generating action potentials
the second way by which brain cells differ from any other cell in the body
it has to do with how they connect to each other
and brain cells connect to other cells at specialized junctions called synapses and the sign
up is not of physical contact that still makes it with another cell but it
contact with the gas
and so the brain cells
makes between one thousand ten thousand sign-ups is
with hundreds of others
so if you add it all up
ten to the ten or ten to the eleventh cells hundred billion cells each with
ten to the four sign-ups is
a hundred trillion two thousand trillion synapses
these numbers are the essence of complexity in the brain is because have such large
numbers of the maps and such large numbers of brain cells
you can do things that you cannot predict from a trillion times one hundred trillion
OK so what i was saying by the way is is that was in the
part of the talk that was about the contextual annotation so in that case it
was negative but i like your idea that can amplify
it's an intensive fire
that's nice
OK lexicon development
what who could do it humans do it and that's valuable right
have someone sit down so we can get a lot of knowledge out so o
and what what i mean by mexican i mean the lexicons of words and phrases
in constructions and senses now
that of things that can be used for subjectivity and of course you can refine
that by positive negative sentiment arguing whatever
OK and
especially when maybe not the document level
i analysis because that's more in text categorisation but when you're at the lower level
most groups use some kind of lexicon
so it's an important part of this area
so humans can do it you can have semi-automatic methods and you can have fully
automatic methods
so we want to find relevant words phrases patterns that can be used to express
its activity
we want to determine the polarity of subjective expressions as well as people want to
do that
when i'm not going to get to it all is an interesting other sub area
which is determining domain dependent expressions
was on domain dependent expressions right that hot nightclub is a good thing but i
have concerns about things like just will get to that
i think that kind of moving forward in this work
our kind of the clearest case we and others have found they usually the least
ambiguous the clearest part of speech in english
for subjectivity
so we can have positive adjectives honest important feature large patient
yes it says these i wonder if it is overturned
and then of course negative harmful hypocritical inefficient insecure and chris we want to point
out that you can have subjectivity that's not positive and negative sentiments you can have
things that are serious are likely or probable
that does it you know there's not pull polar by their nature so too as
his probable successor the two speeches species are likely to flower at different times
but people have worked to another part of speech as well and again this is
to sampling there so you can have verbs like positive praise love
the negative blame criticize
something that subjective but neither positive and negative is predict the same thing for nouns
these these two
do phrases containing adjectives and adverbs in that they do others as well but i
was pointing out that that's something that people is that it's really useful thing to
do in english is to look at the faces containing entities another set english but
this is actually about japanese so something like in japanese was was useful as well
so high intelligence low-cost little variation many troubles and that's kind of getting to the
point i was just talking about which is that
you you can build up
collocations or phrases that seems like a promising thing to do
so i mentioning my because i know myself better and i could speak about easier
but there's other people that were kind and lexico syntactic phrases to so
we use extraction patterns representation and these are these are patterns that were developed for
the purpose of information extraction
and then just mixtures of words select scenes and used in particular syntactic ways so
the way with and three NP
you would never put away by itself subjectivity that second because so many instances of
the word way
our objective so it's too ambiguous it just make your system
over predict subjectivity
but if you have a way with NP a lot of those are going to
be subjective everybody signed his first to have its way with
i should tell you the corpus we use is
seven hundred eighty seven different news sources there are english translations of articles from the
world press i don't mean to be taking in china led to really good juicy
examples from the chinese press
but there are very good for us because the US whether the US issues human
the second question was only converges to a local optimum voice
and know we we start here we get here is there any we here or
so in general there is no way to find the global optimum
you can prove that this is computationally hard some sense
that let's to say you can always create a data set for which is huge
amount to find the optimal parameter as much work essentially
parameter space
there are some things you can do so
there's one set of things which is the way to go from this local optima
two very different parts the parameter space that we expect will have like
these are also emerged so essentially what you do is you take two models that
representing sacrifices herself into one and you one
and split
so the total number
the number of clusters but wildly nonlocal movement parameter space and because the intuition these
clusters of you know what to do if split cluster into two
nearby blocks emerge junior by two
the expected value of the parameter space
one the things you can do you can intentionally
construct a model that has a convex lens
and then you can reach a maximum just because it's convex
and sometimes even though that might be less flexible it's work because you know that
you have to worry about
so again trade
but in a more like this there's no way to to resolve loss
in any reasonable amount of time
other than that the
OK i want to move on and talk about continuously variable so
the example i gave you mixture models had a discrete latent variables there was just
so for example the
the rest of the talk today
conditional likelihood
the rest is a convex function as
so there we have to worry about a lot when you're just in time
the rest we knew for data that we transform our labels for that data
the the likelihood function which is convex if just descended
and just like when you get to the that's all
stable up to point in that so
in general
you know
it depends on how you start
in general don't want to model the variables are are convex but there are also
meant that
that's the kind of accent
the model which we can talk about which has
many many many things
there's also a non convex by
a lot
that's easier to do with symmetry don't care so on the next
case two
clusters slot
different parts of the space
it's really
so the likelihood function as these weird signature moves
parameters here with some shape and has an identically she part of parameters based on
the clusters so this better things all the and so
when you analyse mathematically of course there a lot because is to me you here
between symmetries which you end up
so the fact that
there are multiple stable is in itself a cause for concern we really
so the answer experimentally
problems abound to
during the day
right so
simulated annealing
simulated annealing is this unfortunate result from optimisation
on the basis that looks very promising it says
if you do random exploration
and you reduce the amount of randomness gradually over time that with high probability theory
and in
in a lot of work
just as about that
results that
the speed with which need to
use the search is so slow
there you might as well just read the entire universe in search
the french
four so it's kind of like you
the result is interesting
again but it is basically useless
so really there is no serious
then you're much better off with you know with aggressive inference techniques to do approximate
inference and
and you see that the parameter space
it's good
here is a gradient descent
roughly speaking e
t and potentially take a very large space
guaranteeing each time
one so that it seems like we to bring great methods in order to guarantee
you things to take into
and by the you can sometimes
from initial
parameters which is not in the business
you can skip over all is convex
you know the better
however in practice you can be much slower than an impressive green so the intuition
here is this in
a reasonable parameters
you have very little uncertainty variables
in fact
is given to the parameters you still have a huge amount of uncertainty about the
variables that you will be
so in this case for example
what is in this case we expect you to be very fast
because you know the parameters
variables are completely different
however if you have a situation where it was very ambiguous where very hard to
two friends and then you expect him to be very well because it has to
be very conservative about semantic difference was conjugate doesn't care that really doesn't have to
that can only take steps to live search
so there is over there is a relation between the two hundred and ripple height
i mean that
you can get now
you can get involved so so somehow
the there is a relation between this like all this degree and
the the relation between and
number of professions i'm allowing
may get as minor something p
we're trying to do this and
and the delta
this student mine
and that down i think more
closely it was known people did
matlab experiments
to get a graph of this relationship
but the theory is possible here
i just mentioned that of oppenheim sitting here
he would say
he would wait
he would sit with allowances here is that he would not want smaller ripples
in the stopband than in the past
so he would introduce away so so
i will
w oppenheim
four for for weight
that the weights that allows you to unequally
have unequal height ripples in the
as and stuff
but let's take
mean that's that's set up nineteen one
so what was my point
that that these equal ripple filters are the best
optimal error sense
and also that we have to
we have to go to matlab to
so just
so what will matlab output if we if we give matlab that what we want
the coefficients except
that level of
and it'll plot the graph
and it was it was like that
like this
and we we know relation between these so that if we know what
as stop and has been we want we know how the
what do we we have to take to get certain
error reduction
OK that's the a discussion of
filter design
now it's not a final discussion filter
i mean this often oftentimes course could could could ask other things you might like
the UK is so we've got to two choices here l two least squares
and max
but that's not the only two choices we could
we could average between those we could introduce other
error measures all sorts of possibilities
maybe at some point two
go to high pass
let's look at the other extreme
what would be a high pass filter what its graph look like
let's give me an example of a high pass filter let me give me an
example of a high pass filter that kills
zero frequency
so let's let's do a high pass filter and dotted lines
i guess i'm going to look for a filter that
it's of omega
it is probably sign
of all male over two
what what what are or what would be an natural how can i fix this
change one of the side right
in computer vision
literature there are several ways of just breaking down
text pictures and the simplest you can think of is to break it down into
regular grid just like this believer not this this technique is an even more powerful
than some of the fancier ones so we we can break the images down to
great or we can take the fancier technique of so-called interest point detectors where were
we have tools to find the interesting spots
interesting is defined by some kind of metric but in any case interesting spots of
same it so we can break it down into smaller pieces
OK now
let's take one interesting regions or one grid region it doesn't really matter how do
we put the take this image and take this path to break represented as numbers
because eventually we have to tell the computer that with the what what this patch
being so normally people we we tend to do is take this patch normalized probably
according to the intensity or saw and then
and describe it using some kind of space in computer vision we have we have
a very powerful descriptive concept sometimes people just also
use score
wavelets are sometimes people use just pixel intensity value it doesn't matter in any case
all these all these regions are expressed as vectors of numbers so you get thousands
of them
and now
the issue is
OK we we got thousands of these points but we want to have a building
block that that this can be used universally used for all the images so
the simplest way to do it is
to cluster them and then we have very
oh sorry
what you are talking about very the second thing is very top-down attention what if
you look at the human visual pathway we start basically from the primary visual cortex
v one and v one receptors are very similar to bars oriented bars and edges
and then images
comes into our human visual system is sets of these oriented bars and edges
and then starting building on top of the the one we have layers clean these
bars and edges and making more complex
receptive field so this level what what computer vision is doing
by detecting these
busier or interesting textual patches we can also approximated to to the v four or
inferior temporal cortex of the human visual system which is about two or three layers
up from the ones so that in terms of seconding
that's all already be on feature is
it's guided by m
it's a
i mean it's not in this domain already it's more data by saliency and other
some context on the bottom up saliency
so that's a whole different lecture and
OK so we got thousands of these
that is
patches and we want to make it dictionary out of it so that we have
a building block and
vector quantization or
some kind of clustering algorithm would do it here we're just showing many papers so
far just using k means clustering with some kind of smart pruning and so on
so so what we end up with this as an example is pulling together
tens of thousands of millions of patches and ending up with let's say three hundred
and and so here is how the scheme works very roughly i'm going to
just look at this in a very high level
you start with a bunch of data points and then you build the neighborhood graph
on them so you have a node for each data point
and then you put an edge between points that are close together
OK so for instance within some radius
or points that are k nearest neighbors of each other or sometimes just put an
edge between every two points and you wait the edges according to distance there are
there are several ways to do this
OK but you do this you build neighborhood it build neighborhood graph
and the new query some points eleventh in this case let's just say we have
a binary problem
it's very some important thing we query these two points that turns out to be
zero this one over here turns out to be one
you propagate labels
you look at the data you have so far i propagated to the rest of
the graph and it turns out that there are some really nice ways to do
this basically by solving an i can value problem and one way to think about
it is to think about the semantics of this number is suppose you started this
node i needed a random walk
what fraction of time which you first have to one what fraction of time which
first it is zero OK so you can think of the semantics of these numbers
in that form roughly
once you have these you can use this as the basis for deciding which point
to query and so for instance one thing you might want to do is to
query the most uncertain point which
which would be this point five but then this seems like to point that a
little bit of an outlier is kind of sticking out from the graph
so it might be better to
to query this because
it's likely
two lead to the biggest reduction in overall uncertainty and one can put in nice
probabilistic semantics on top of these kinds of graphs in which all these all these
analyses are very meaningful and you can actually quantify the amount of residual uncertainty after
finding a label can superior point and then you go back
so why is this in a sense cluster based active learning
if you have a clearly defined clusters in the data
you might have the clusters might be something like these three and the remaining points
basically when the clearly defined clusters and the corresponding nodes will have cut between them
through which which don't have too many edges and through which influence can propagate only
OK so this is an example of
very beautiful scheme for doing active learning that that seems to be motivated in part
by a cluster learning but i sort of a cluster model
and so
i'm not i'm not clear on what the what the consistency
status of this is you know what one can say about statistical consistency
but i can tell you that but but but i'll tell you briefly about some
work that basically uses this is motivation to come up with a different scheme in
which you can actually prove things about consistency and that give some idea of the
kind of analysis that need to be done
OK so here's
here's another cluster based
which attempts to use some of the same intuitions from the previous one
while while achieving consistency and so the idea is to look at the data
you find a bunch of clusters you sample a few points in each cluster
and then you assign each cluster its majority label
and you use that label set to build a classifier
so that
kind of a high level of what's going to be done but let's look at
the reality
OK to start with some unlabelled data
you find clusters
you also some labelled
o point in this cluster is looking pretty good because they feel
it's relatively pure you have
six points you've chosen six random points and that in this cluster that gives you
a certain confidence interval on on how pure this cluster is
and because it's a random sample you can use you can come up with this
sort of confidence intervals so feeling good about this one
this one is looking like trouble
OK so what you do that
is that you
then we find the clustering
so the the overall overall a nice way to do this is to just use
a hierarchical clustering
indicator variables between zero and minus one in each case no matter how the interest
comes out exactly one of them will be one all the others will be zero
so now we can
divide out the running time
of this algorithm based in which case where
that sort of unified this
intuition that we did
and get all the cases and then we can look at the expectation
so to
in if we just let out by cases
we have
upper bound
like this
so if we have a zero ten minus one split the worst is we have
n minus one we have to recursion problem size n minus one
in fact pretty hard recursion from the size zero
if we have one to n minus two split then we take the mass of
the two sides that's the
certainly going to give us an upper bound
and so on
at the bottom and minus one to zero
so this is now sort of conditioning on various events but we have run an
indicator random variables to tell us when these events happened so we can just multiply
each of these
values by the indicator random variable and will come and zero if that's not the
case come out one and you give us the value of that happens to be
split so if we add up all those
will get the same thing
this is equal to
the sum over all k of indicator variable times
the cost in that case which is max OK
and the other side dishes and minus k minus one
plus there
OK so this is our
recurrence in some sense for the random variable representing running time that depends on
i mean the value will depend in which case
we come into
we know the probability of each of these events happening is the same
because we're choosing
the partition element uniformly random
but we can simplify much beyond this
until we take expectations
we know this random variable could be as big as n squares
hopefully it's usually linear
will take expectations of both sides
and get
what we want
so let's look at
the expectation of this random variable
which is the expectation of copy of
summation we have here
so i can work on this board
so i want to compute the expectation of the summation
property and expectations should i use
linearity good
so we can bring the summation outside
so now i have some of expectations so let's look at each expectation individually it's
the product of two
random variables
this is an indicator random variable
and this is
some more complicated function
more complicated random variable
the set representing some running time
which depends on what random choices are made in the recursive call
now which should i do
expectation of the product of two random variables
independence exactly
if i find that these two random variables are independent then i know that the
expectation the product is the product of the expectations
now we have to cheque are they independent
i hope so
because otherwise there's much else i can there
so why are they in
because we stated that they are because of
this assumption
the reason that all the random numbers are chosen independently
we need to sort interpolate that here
these xk is
all the xk is x zero up to x and minus one all the ones
appearing in the summation are dependent on a single random choice
of this particular call to random partition
evans that or for which the intersection is empty then
the probability of the union of these and even is to discern the sum of
the probabilities can
and the
you can also see that
the probability of the
union press the probability of the intersection is the sum of the two probabilities
and we'll to to measure and study these random events will be able to be
able to see them or to measure them through random variables so
for your kindness and then you define the random variable x
goes from meager two
for example two zero one
and we say that x is equal x of media
is equal to zero for example when
and the result of the time because it is it is that he is
and acts of is equal to one and the result is as
the proof the the reason we use a random variable is to transport the probability
from your space of random you can still me again
something that is measurable for example think of
capital being our
for example so random variables on omega two r
we transport measurable sets seen in two measurable set in rd
that's what
basically what's written there
image of your random events so
actually extra random variable may take values in different kind of said
i said for example
x maybe maybe taking values in rd
are you know already said that would be difficult i there may have so it
may have one or several viable but it could also take values in in in
finite set such says you one then that would be
the discrete
random valuable
it may take
here so we basically making the distinction between
the discrete and the continuous firewall so these three firewalls discrete random variables
take values in the discrete set one continuous random variables may take values in rd
for example
eurandom firewall is actually several coordinates would call that the random vector
so i used
it is the notation px
when i look at events that are in the measure in the measure
we which are measurable quantity of observable quantities and and p is the probability in
initial random set of media
again if you consider again the the
a coin toss
we the media with x that goes from all media you one
we write
a small p as the probability of x being ads
are being one
and the random variable that you obtain here from observing single going to this is
called a bernoulli variables
with the parameter p
and it's it's
the law of the random variables with the way it either axes only
is defined only by p
if you have several
and independent going to tosses if you if you observe an independent going to
let's say that y is the random variable you observe why is this sum the
then the probability of life being k exactly this one
where this is the binomial coefficient for kitchens and
and so this will decent useful
random viable is said to have a binomial distribution with parameters n and p
so if you want to
OK now if you have a measurable random variable the new me
i wonder what is the mean it's me its expectation
it is defined as above on the set omega of random events
and so if x is discrete takes values in into to a discrete set x
one to x and then the expectation is the sum of the x IPI where
p a is the probability of x being excited intermediary can define the which is
the deviation of the random variable
two from its mean
so it's the expectation of x minus its eggs
i'm sorry the expectation switch from this similar to
this implies that is it is it is it is exactly exactly the same thing
the variance is the expectation of x minus think is its expectation square then you
can show
actually that is equivalent to this definition here which may be more easy to use
in any case if x is that is a discrete random variable you find that
the valiant is has this form there
modern or you can defend the expectation of any function of your
OK maybe i just have to try to try to address draw this by hand
it's not completely impossible
because well it would take a long time to try to get the new version
of this in another version of these slides i'm afraid
OK so the point here is that
we have two independent components with uniform distributions
inside certain intervals so let's say
from here to here
the mean is zero so it has to be something like that and because the
independent the independent from each other then the scatterplot is simply that kind of square
so this is the edges of the square simple but so we will have like
points inside that square everything quite uniform
so this is the distribution of s s one
and it's two
so this is this is the latent variables that we don't observe what we is
x one
and x two
o scatterplot is now
some kind of really distorted vision of this thing something like for example like this
with a uniform distribution inside
geometric form
so the point is
well first of all from this kind of the distributions what you can see
is you can see that
you could possibly estimates that kind of a distribution as the one who could possibly
estimate the independent components because obviously
but the directions of these edges here of this distribution have something to do
with the coefficients in the mixing matrix
actually the directions of these edges will be something like the
will be almost the same thing as being the columns of the mixing matrix shows
so now what happens is that when we do i see what the story when
we do what
so let's
how do know what i did i don't seem to be not widening anyway so
let's say xt lies previous
so when we do the right thing what you see is that we get the
same kind of square as in the beginning
it will not it will be
in some direction i don't know to do this the right way but in any
case you will be rotated somehow
so we will not have a uniform distribution inside this kind of this way
this illustrates just the fact that
after whitening the mixing matrices is also going
what was going on with an orthogonal transformation is basically is a rotation in space
in the case of two dimensions well there is only you know one way or
rotating a square that is you know rotating by this centre axis so we will
know that after we had done whitening we basically have only one parameter left so
in the beginning we had four parameters left because we have two times two mixing
matrix but after whitening we actually only one parameter left which is the rotation angle
in this direction
so we can see that we see that whitening order correlation is quite a useful
thing to do
but certainly doesn't solve the problem because this we with this orientation here will be
completely arbitrary and it will not be
what these
basic orientation that we wanted to have in the first place
so this should be compared with with a cake in the case of of gaussian
so i got some
so as i wrote previously was the PDF was
PDF was basically
proportional to the exponential of
well it's a
well it's xtrans posts
inverse space x so now
if we have in the data then c will be identity and c minus the
inverse will be identity so what this will be is simply a function of the
norm of x
so the contour plots
for this
distribution will be simply spherical so
you can call it spherically symmetric
this kind of distribution if you like so from this distribution you would say that
well there is basically no way of determining what is what is the right orientation
for training data
in this case
if we want really the preimage problem if we look at the
his next mission
you have to make some new version we see here as is this function we
see that we are not going to sicily
so this is just a reminder to to tell you that also the competition
can be done
OK six using the canon creek as usual
that's in the space
and there was this problem of prem of squeamish program so i'm just doing just
to what about it because in fact you know problem of network completion
we are not using the preimage
we are still working on the future space and we are going to make this
inner product of output
so so
and known moments will be you really need to make a free image problem but
they just give you the answer because it can be useful
so in fact what we want to do
we have dozens of work in the future not s
and we deal with the outputs as they chose this feature map
but always using canada
can value
and now you want for instance for one
that actual
o point blue here
we want to
guest predict
in the output space always in a good place the first
open space
we propose a very simple and general methods that can be in fact improve these
if you can is well adapted but this is what is the most general solution
that we can have
we are going to say well
we are looking for we are going to look
and the set
of training to the set of output and the the way to solve the preimage
is is to find out
so why you apply
which is the closest to the true solution to this one motion so it is
the feature map
and the idea is to find the best ones so said quite how the other
day you usually why is huge
can i can do computations so what we're going to do is we're going just
to use the
how the training data which is of course
the construction and we are going to say well i'm going to set
to find the y
prime such that
it is the closest in terms of of can then
OK so in terms
five of why prime using the euclidean distance in in this space
i'm going to see
which white from either close this
was my help
OK remember the output of the regression trees
it just as which
the output falling leaf
OK so as i have
why if we were to say mass
all this competition again can be done we can
what you can see it at this stage it surrounds approximation
it seems to to be too rough
but in fact i think that the tree will be used in some combination
it's possible to make sense
and then we have the better
bit accuracy because the responses would be combined with those instances
so this is strictly a single tree the output kernel trees
and so we could this
OK three
by regions of the one of the first
treaty proposed by queen anne
eighty six which is called the index decision tree
and now
i'm going to tell you short world
about ensemble methods so
i have let's say fifteen minutes again you
so four b we
we began at a quarter past nine
so they tell me that it was possible
OK so
OK so women
it's that we want to be in this function
the output can entry is one way to be such a function
OK it's quite simple way
it's quite
let's say
of course as as we wish and trees in the classic classic space it's a
rough approximation of the function that
that's the first solution
OK we're going to try to improve this function
by using ensemble methods
which is essentially a thinner tails than the target
what happens if you have things when you look at this is simulated sampled across
iteration number so this is like basically the possible market change so what happened is
that you see
at some stage basically when the absolute value
of the state is quite high
basically there's a lot of rejection
so the markov chain they quite long time OK so this is a as well
so basically market share reject reject make many proposals rejected quite a few times on
it was back and so it's coming from his behavior
well simply coming from basically if you look at the metropolis acceptance ratio
OK you get these guys
so assume basically
that the current value
you have the value of x the absolute value of x is actually quite large
it is that essentially the ratio gamma over q is very large OK that is
then the acceptance probability of image processing is going to be very small so essentially
the condition when you have a demo that x is not bounded on that essentially
the racial gamma x can take arbitrary values then essentially you can be it's you
going to be in scenarios where sometimes essentially your algorithms can be stacked essentially in
the tails some OK the distribution so that's why you have this actually kind of
pretty bad behaviour
if you look at least one zero of the simulated so important you would like
to look like an ocean distribution pretty bad because essentially because of rejection that once
you basically you to change in the tales basically then it does a lot of
time it takes a long time to escape then basically you got like quite a
few samples in details you that compensate for
for the for the fact that he agrees that support oppose doesn't explore the support
of distribution popular OK as that's about
simon says there's no magic
if rejection sampling
essentially it is
not applicable then you can use metropolis testing egories but it's been exhibited bad behavior
well actually particle in means that you can show that actually this algorithm can be
geometrically ergodic this is famous paperback between on mendelson publishing that
OK so now if you consider case where essentially q
is actually has seen as figure tails than the target distribution you be able to
hold on essentially the same policy like this would this thing that you have a
huge amount of rejection at some given in some given part of the space on
you can basically do is to go on simulated sample merchandising approximation of the oceans
the gaussian distribution of interest OK
if you do that also also that system that for the time being without much
like benefits so if you also in i mention so assume basically
you're trying to solve important from target distribution which is dominated by the notion
in dimension of dimension nx so this is zero mean and unit identity covariance matrix
or that you use the
similarly basically proposal
distribution which is normal which is a little bit shifted OK we've mean that is
the mean vector which has epsilon well basically component on the same covariance structure
if you look at at one small basically
basically the ratio
essentially private q which is in component of the metal processing factories and you can
see that this race to actually exhibit a lot of violation of lot of viability
as an an effect increases so maybe that essentially if you try to use the
similarly this independent metropolis hastings and i mentioned is similar to what's happening fall
basically rejection basic is not going to mix very well so in this case if
you this kind of proposal distribution in ten dimensional news that we image processing area
is that acceptance rate is like o point three percent is like ridiculously bad
OK so that's basically independent metropolis hastings uris until c is not really
actually good algorithm is low it says it's in the more flexible than the accept
project because you can use it when the tailwind this race was approach is not
of bonded that's the kind of deceiving because then the MCMC algorithm doesn't work well
in this case
so i could you what's the benefits of using this kind of independent proposals
OK for the reassessed things he basically it's as bad as the rejection sampling
what is the advantage of basically
mcmc of rejection sampling is in MCMC you get is this idea that you can
essentially the initial something problem into some kind of subproblems so instead basically of trying
to update using metropolis testing all the components at the same time you could try
to and they don't like the gibbs sampler one at the time OK so is
the same thing you can have the same features of the s four gibbssampling don't
have the right to date everything simultaneously the six and essentially trying to do something
a little bit toward so what you do
it would be
that wave could go straight through the slot
there would be no problem at all
you be that's what
in this way
three through
because it moves up and down in the
now imagine
that i have lights
there also made in this direction spring
oscillating in this direction so now
also it's like this
i'm trying to make you see the three-dimensional way it comes here
now it is
this narrow and it can go through
get stuck
so you see that was this morning
you can easily see
why this light which is polarized in this direction
goes through
but light which is polarized in that direction cannot be true because the
this what is to know
and in that sense you can perhaps now imagine
why unpolarized light can be changed
it to linearly
polarized light i'm just mentioning this so that you have some idea of on what
may be going on
in that
plate even though that idea is not
absolutely perfect
there is something that i have to teach some of you
although many of you may know this what comes but i'm going to need this
for the rest of my lectures
that's the idea
of an angle
what is an angle
and how do we express anger
if i have here circle
and i draw the line
i draw the the line
then we call this an angle
and how do we measure an angle
in mathematics
we have
adopted that's the definition there's nothing that you can understand about it it's just the
name things
we call an angle
it goes all the way around
so it is what we call a form rotation
so this like going all the way around this angle then
three hundred sixty degree
is it logic
no i would prefer on on the degrees but we call it three sixty can
that's the way it's called it's called three hundred sixty degree
you think of it
there are sixty minutes in an hour
equally absurd line of the hundred final ten
equally absurd is that there are sixty seconds in a minute
makes no sense
the very absurd twelve inches in a foot final ten
i don't know all the things are historical
and we have to live with it
so once you define this angle three hundred sixty three
you know that one quarter of rotation
it's going to be ninety degrees
so i'm going to make their picture
of ninety degrees
since we're going to need that
very badly doing this lecture
so if i rotate this flag
over one quarter of the rotation
then it will be like this
and this now
ninety degrees
it's one quarter of the rotation
and this ninety degrees
we have another word for that matter recall at right angles
it's like when officer once in a bunch of soldiers on a parade ground to
stand on the rectangles he could give every soldier is GPS coordinates down to within
a few inches
and that will be kind of hard work
or you could tell roughly where to stand and then tell each soldier what distances
should be from his name
that's a much better thing to do
so we're going to try and make a more powerful module for doing this deep
and this more powerful module
we'd like the units in one layer
to modify to modulate the interactions in the layer below
so in the level or something like markov random field and we will be in
a similar but to specify the weights in the markov random field
some previous work in a few years ago assignments in there
i had a fixed markov random field with units in the lower low-budget specifying the
buses and that's already with
but after something more ambitious to actually modulated markov random field
to do that we need higher order boltzmann machines
so a higher order boltzmann machines
and asking first thought about these in nineteen eighty six i think or thereabouts
interaction terms that are more than quadratic
so the second equation that is for three way one that's all we're going use
and if you think about this the state of you can see that SK second
when that's all of
the the that doesn't apply
when is all one has got state award now you got pairwise interaction between i
and j so the state of sk
is gating pairwise interactions between i and j
and each unit can be viewed like skating pairwise interactions between the other guys
so one thing we could use higher order boltzmann machine for is modelling image transformations
i could give you pairs of images
the simple cases when there's a global transformation to more interesting cases when there's more
local transformations and several transformations going once in the same image and we can cope
with just fine so i give you pairs of images
and the hidden units
and i'm going to get interactions between pixels
so when there is little triangle cymbals i will have a three-way weight
gives you an energy is a function of the states of the two pixels in
the state of the union
and red unit
likes the to the two transformations of pixels this is because they consistently correspond to
consistent translation
so if you have the image at time t in the image at time t
plus one
both those parents will provide evidence that he knew unit should be on
so tend to say that a consistent transformation
if you have the image at time t and you turn on in unit it
will tell you whether pixels should translate to an image time t plus one
one of the most savage and i had a paper that uses this and has
a huge number weights because you see this triangle cymbals have three indices they connect
three different units
and so this cubicle in many
so the sort of central trick to this talk is going to take that to
be many
and we just use factorizations because we don't actually believe that we want hidden units
be able to cause arbitrary permutations of the pixels we believe this regular structure so
we don't really need that many parameters
so we can
take the
three way weight w i j
and we can factor it as a product
of the three weights WIF wjfk w h f
per factor we're gonna have a bunch of factors
so it looks like we've got four indices that's true but notice we haven't got
anything that has more than two indices so basically turned the cube into
three pairwise things
so we
we only get many many parameters per factor
and we have about as many factors as hidden units are visible units so we
basically turns on this cube wilkinson's replicate quadratic
here's a picture of what we're doing
each factor
corresponds to
tensor one it's
much what is a typical fraction of hyphens in word
one one high out of seven is probably below average and if this and having
a hyphen after every second letter is probably above average
and there's some intermediate
density of hyphens which would give
this is the y string the highest probability
for linear chain crfs
there is a restriction on which feature functions i'm allowed
this is that
the feature function j
for any j
it's a function of x exploring wipe
and now i'm going to use the pontification to mean sequences
it's going to be the
so i
ranges over
the sequence
so from i was one to the length of the sequence
little fj j
why i minus one y i
exp are high
of feature functions so feature function eighteen little feature function eighteen
five b
one of
why i minus one y i
might be
i equals
and why i minus one
and y equals one
x one x two
they have
so forget this for a minute and just think about this is an example another
example of feature function
march so
paying attention to the position i corps two
so then why i minus one will be y one y i would be y
so i pay attention to the first two labels in the string
first first two tags
those first two tags are zero and one according to this feature function
OK let me make that p
one and zero
then move
and paying attention
so the first two letters in the word in those first two letters and
and more so
we have the first two letters a and
one zero is that plausible tags for the first of those living and
well you think of words that begin with a there is a moral
you probably can hyphenate like this
and then there's some
but you immediately get high and then there one which i can think of where
you wouldn't have a hyphen think amateurism word means to do with love
depending so sometimes are allowed to hyphen after the a and sometimes you're not allowed
hyphen after the a
and but probably mostly
you are allowed
hyphen after the a
with this feature function
then you learn
wait for that was positive
and what that positive weight would be meaning would be that you know any
any tag sequence y
that it starts out one zero
everything else being equal
has a high probability
so every x y pair
where x starts out and y starts out
hi for no hyphen
is a higher probability
x y pair
this is
the user is exactly right and the the idea of feature function is an awful
idea for machine learning and is an idea that it can be hard to get
your head around the first of month because we're so used to thinking of features
as being properties of the input x
but when we have a very large output space y
i really can't we really need to talk about properties of the out space y
output space y also and rather than thinking of the mapping from x to y
we should think of
x y pairs
and then
map and then working out whether the XY pair is good pair
or bad
let me
try to sketch yet another example and this will be an example of a log
linear model that is not a conditional random field
consider the problem of
multi label
supervised learning
who knows what multilabel
for multilabel problem is it's different from the multiclass problems
the multiclass problems when you have an input x
you want to predict the label y
and the y comes from a set that is bigger than the binary set
if you want
classify somebody is
freshman sophomore junior senior
multi class
but multi label is when you want to
classify all tax
as having
zero or more
so each tax
has zero or more
and it so
for each document
you want to map it onto my
of course
so you you have some
you have some classic document categorisation problem
so this is kind of an exploration exploitation kind of problem you pick something it
did pretty well is there something else better i don't know try and see you
need an algorithm that can kind of mixed these exploring exploiting stuff
it turns out this kind of thing you can do in a reasonably natural way
the bounds of being works but the ideas are fairly straightforward when you want to
do here or this one thing you can do
you realize that all the algorithms need to work is an estimate of the cost
to the sum of all day one day two hundred eighty minus one that's something
that's the only thing you're using and even if you get a pretty close that's
good enough because you're going to be noise to anyone c and noise it's pretty
close to the right answers
the same thing is i is the right answer
that might help you get
OK you see an estimate of the
some of the
cost factors and today's the day one day two day
so you see that estimate how do you do that well what you can do
is you pick some sort of basis which would in this case look like the
fixed collection of routers that together
every other row can be written as a linear combination of those
and everyone said well your sample something random
and you do you stop products with your basis vectors to reconstruct an estimate of
the final that year so everyone so i take some basis vector input the dot
product of you
and you can
use that to reconstruct an estimate of what the actual cost
the healthier basis to be is orthogonal is possible
whether you can do that depends on the kind of problem if you have a
problem like this figure what's of passes it that is orthogonal possible in this in
this space
and you can show that even if the world's adaptive knows that you know how
to get you if it's still campfires to estimate how much he was right
so that that's on this say about the band
but if not once you have the other thing it's not too hard to be
extended to this case we do a little bit x exploration in your merge
so let me and this part of this is the end of stuff one before
we go game theory part with just one natural generalisation of this problem to something
that makes sense for
problems like dealing with text and other sort of learning problem
let me start by thinking this from the point of view drive so
we were just trying to be nearly as well as the best fixed route
that's fine but a more ambitious goal might be to say that but we also
want to rainy days we do nearly as well as the best route for a
so maybe in general this is the best way to go but rainy days or
some other better
and we would like a strategy that has the property that not only does it
overall time do as well
nearly as well as the best round time rainy days
it really is one of the best referee days
on mondays does nearly as well as best monday's traffic
about it so traffic where i live is a lot less on mondays
even if ten percent of people who is not gonna work the boy that's that
pay them to knock OK
so more generally what if you have an
prediction rules
your prediction rules could be things like on monday use happy
all simultaneously for each of these rules that we want to guarantee do nearly as
well as that rule does in the time steps from which several fires
OK and
because the for all rules i expected cost of our algorithm on time steps in
which we live wires should be not too much more than expected and the cost
of the rule i
on the time which fires classes
it turns out you can get this
OK and what's nice about this is that many places in machine learning we would
like to combine
if then rules
in fact in the data mining lectures we saw that there you no
there are these strategies for pulling out this the high specificity rules don't quite often
but when they apply they can be very good so imagine though the someone's hand
you a whole bunch of rules some of them may be very good some of
them may not be very good if you don't know in advance which one you
want to combine
so think of the document classification so
a rule like a four x appears in document predict label wiser has football sports
that's probably a good
if football then classifies economics prior that give be lots of rules in advance you
don't know which are good and which are bad
we would like to have the property that if it really care out the ninety
percent of documents with the word football really are about support and you should do
nearly as well as the word for all those under so football is there ten
percent and then you should have only a little bit more than ten percent
but that that kind of an goal corresponds
and this is called the special problem sleeping experts problem so this rule like an
expert but sleep it only wakes up and the doctor has football football football i
know about sports there goes back to
i know people like that
when i was in italy
during the world cup the whole country was sort of like that it's likely that
they are so once the game was on everything shut down this is what you
can walk into someone's house is an account what
he went even though
it's great actually really great anyway
OK this has been studied theoretically and also experimentally in a number of papers
well i just give a feel of how some of the other things talked about
could be extended to this case i will go through the
the arguments not hard i will go through it just we've done after
i want to go into the game
everything analysis part but here's here's the so just like before we start everybody with
weight one
and just like before
every time step now some of the rules fire
some of
will do is will pick one with probability proportional to its weight just like we
doing before
the with the first we had all the guys with the weights and we cut
the waste and we picked on the probably proportional to its weight so do the
exact same
but now we can update the weights differently so before we penalize things for getting
it wrong
now we don't want to just
now we mean the problem is if you do that kind of penalizing rules for
writing and one highest weight ones never is and you want to penalize raising anyone
also reward them to
the user and do
if they didn't fire would be the way loss
if they did fire
OK listen some to ignore them matter second
so if they did fire we're gonna raise their way or lower their way
depending on how well they do compared to the weighted average of the rules of
in particular what turns out to be something that you can still proves thing about
in practice you may not need some of the hedging but
it proved to work to do
is it the rule
raise its makes the predictions and it doesn't exactly as well as the weighted average
of the rules of fire by weighted average weighted by the
but rule fires
if someone is exactly as well
as the weighted average of the rules of fire
you penalizes a little bit
if it does better
and there can the point will be that 1 of these corners is the winner
that that if I don't know if to think why
but but let me emphasize that point the winner is at a corner
the winner is
at corner
so anything with so what that mean ordinary words
that means that the winter of
the only 1 of these
at the optimal X stock
it is not
is working is not 0
it is and I only need like 1 to just because I only have 1
so so at the corners of the sources say what a corner
but the
corner is have em
nonzero Texas and that and that gives me enough to solve the M equations x
and the n minus
the house
because I'm adequate so that in that it's from it we can visualize this thing
in this 3 the picture
the visualization gets quite
uh harder
in a so that in M and then dimensions in so my point was that
the winner X star
it is a corner
some courses
this thing is so you might think OK just try all the corners
evaluate the cost every corner once you know the winner a corner
but the thing is
there are too many corners the number of corners is
N choose them or something which is a very big number
it's 3 here
so the 3 corners and we can check a
but generally you have to imagine sorry imagining n-dimensional space
like this where n was 3
and then
what is the constraints give us
think of n-dimensional space X 1 to X N
and then we have equations
the any equations 1 of the idea of
in this space
well every equation is linear so it's a
Soviet on planes
and forget the optimum because octant
positive direction in an n-dimensional space of and website because I can't utilize here
but acceptance conservative important to realize
that the feasible set is
a polyhedron it's the setting curve boundaries
that everything is is there they based planes which dropout here
coming from x greater equal 0 chop up the positive part or the constraint planes
coming from the constraints that cut through in some way so you get somehow region
that's created out of N plus planes
it's it's
but it can be quite complicated
and less is pretty big number you're just in areas they we have all mean
this would be big 20 equations 10 constraint so we're in 20 dimensional space got
30 planes all things through and you can see that
the feasible set could be empty for example how often I look how can I
change this prior I create a problem where the where there were no feasible X
it's not out of this example
well I could make for a minus
if I may therefore minus 4 then there wouldn't be any non-negative axes that would
solve minus 4 but of course that
problem with with minus 4 our 0 marks to do
well often have no homework but I've never signed number of homework problem so anyway
OK which is the winner
which is the best point well in this case I could just check the cost
of every
at every corner
at all and I have to say why is the winner adequate
the fact that the winners of the corner is is a big help
and it somehow depends on linear narrative forever linear functions you know you
if it's increasing it continues to increase until you bump up against
or continues to decrease over time to make something decreases
like like suppose you said well maybe that's the winner in the middle
all 3 working away well
but if I discovered that the move from around from there
in some direction is better
than more is better more better more and better until finally maybe I just make
edge at that point
it can't
it's not legal to go further because Annex would get negative so at that point
what again
OK but now
my point is that we only have to consider corners
and why is that
that's right the drive to a corner that's just that's the fundamental reason you what
1 way to see it is
is now just think of these cost if we got the answer is a good
way to see not only that it's corner but but what what picks out that
corner so the cost suppose I'm trying to do this job for a total cost
of a million dollars it's not costly million dollars for the area personal workers and
only forward problem but suppose I look at the equation 5 Examples 3 extemporization
0 I don't even know if I could spend a million dollars
yes I could
I don't well at an even know but anyway suppose I look at the axis
that's all that give me a cost a million dollars
yeah I don't think I could spend up there not feasible right is that this
we have is that the top the slide off two a one we want to
show their faces
i came up with the covalent here here's island
to change the examples so far there is a great deal of corporate and government
surveillance of people
all they want to get be example of
we want to do what we do what's going on cities experiences to want be
within the
there's a lot of those in some ways part that you villages where you start
at two in the morning to have fair
they used friend of
it might be pretty visible involvement was
this is a different individual the family the
he is the american examples that apologize for the
that was the type the
radio and and television shows
and when the images were there
every school
my later learned to read
master home two kids play
and one of more things that of the many TV shows like this has been
shown on one user
this is changing
but this is
what your children and so on
and by the the show itself
is it
that's is not possible
the reason that describe
because he was playing very easy to do
so when we it was not going to be
kids what it's
those long all nodes in the PC
i wish know where where you are told by accident
examples that you
call and say we're doing now you know he's going to get from background noise
with the
his parents were
and we know that this is a paper based on a few days before the
network also
that's also chapter six per
call network
families of which is a lot of communication and this is why or how can
this work addresses the president's policies related to each other
you can see that are related to each other all the time using a mobile
phone call is the way forward so you know that's a whole
as far is for is still alive
there has been
the networks
at the same time so this is a very good
has changed in is a that few households with children the american association words from
parents he has to say that are
we had to that
parameters and therefore is the only american data
on the
two things maybe not all the samples will pertain to europe
perhaps in parts of the
we know how to use the wiki
all let's find together
they keep separate works of the conductor mobile
and the more interesting and i are just published a book about two sets of
there are many kinds of doing work at home the first of all the people
who say it all the time
two were based on these three to four days we were
they really really small