so we have to be really careful but in this case it doesn't matter
any questions about the substitution method that was the same example three times in the
end it turned out we got the right answer
but we still need to know the answer in order to find out which is
a bit of a pain
so it would be nicer to just
figure out the answer by some procedure and that will be
the next two techniques we talk about
how would you improve lower bound i haven't tried it for this
recurrence but you should be able to do exactly the same form
i have argued that human is greater than equal to
c one times t m squared minus two times and
i didn't check whether that particular form work but i think it does
so try it
these other methods will give you in some sense upper and lower bounds
a little bit careful
but to really check things you pretty much have to do the substitution method
and you'll get some practice with that usually we only care about upper bounds so
big i mean for like this is what will focus on but occasionally we lower
so it's nice to know that you have the right answer by giving a matching
lower bound
so the next method we'll will talk about
the recursion tree method
and it's a particular way of of adding up recurrence
and it's the it's my favorite way it's particularly
it is usually just works that's the great thing about it provides intuition for free
it tells you what the answer is pretty much
it's slightly non rigorous this is a bit of a pain so you have to
be really careful when you apply otherwise you might get the wrong answer
because it involves dot dot dots are favourite
three characters have but that that so is a little bit
rigorous so
be careful
technically what you should do is to find out what the answer is with recursion
tree method and prove that it's actually write with the substitution
usually that's not necessary but you should at least have in your mind that
is required to rigorously
and probably the first you requested yourself you should do it that way when you
really understand the recursion tree method you can be a little bit more
sloppy you really sure you have the right answer so
do an example we saw recursion tree is very briefly
last time with our sort as the intuition y with n log n
and the sixth i mean if you took an example like the one we just
do with the recursion tree method is dead simple
so let's just to make her life harder
let's do more complicated recursion so here we imagine we have some algorithm starts the
problem size and it recursively solve the problem of size n over four then recursively
solve the problem size and over two dozen square work on the side
with without non and non recursive work
so what is that i mean that's a bit less obvious i would say
so what we're going to do is
drop picture
i've had which is going to expand the recursion
in tree form
and then just and everything out
so we want the general picture
and the general principle in
recursion tree method is we just draw this is the picture we say well to
you then
the sum of n square TNN over four
and over two
so i mean this is we're we're writing a someone to write it that way
OK this is going to be a tree
and it's going to be retrieved by expand by recursively expanding each of these two
lee so i start by rick expanded to this i keep expanding expanding expanding everything
so let's go one more step
we have this square here over four
you an over two weeks spent one more time this is going to be in
is actually good
the basic on the basis of this proposition independence most you're looking at the two
hundred and its
and because of optically if the URI then through it in looking at things and
this transform from two set of posts in something
and when i look at the real digit or something you dream of digital to
another letter or arabic letters whatever they follow the same transformation
and in the first place you have and
they're going to be on the same
and is still going to describe the domain
the thing the the examples you dreamed a lot more
the examples you actually of from the facts
the fact that you can use exemplars you dream
is quite amusing
so we called them unicorns because nothing you dream this for
helping children understand what the truth is
how important it is
the funny thing is nothing really bad happens but
if you know
the points you have
actually examples of the two classes the opposite you like to do
you would like to put them squarely into one class or the although not in
if you have a few of them is not going to bother you with all
if you only have that you could be in trouble again
we almost always
we don't know so much
we we had this concept met some experiments showed that
well the concept that the quite powerful
we understand that just do repositories tradition spaces
and we understand this relation with the motion of bodies priori and that's about it
for now
the amazing thing is that this is
quite innovative provocative ideas so
now i would say
if you have a semi supervised the
you have an additional set of examples of the liabilities
you know there are five or eight
the examples of the class
the class is seeking the point is
but you don't know the label
and that means that intuitively what you want to do with this example
is not to place them in the middle of your separation
but place them squarely into the red side of the inside
the a level exam the quite close to the test examples here
see the green one
there is some relations between transitions and since the right
what this tries to do is try to find a good separation between the
i love the example you want to
classifiers for us
green right
so you will have to them nicely
it's the opposite way
so you could consider you have a full set of examples
from training examples of one class
training examples of the other class
the training examples all of them
the best patterns which are the one that you're going to test this one
the one for which she won answers
the unlabelled examples of the classes
the class of interest
another five hundred states
and the universe some examples of how should belong to the class
but help you define the geometry
of the problem in the high dimensional space
and in fact that it is the way we implemented if we try to play
with these
it behaves pretty much the way i tell you just don't have the numbers here
i'm going to go to another idea letting it called as the employees for purely
local reasons
the wonder
explain the learning algorithm for maximum number of contradiction that some approximations
because counting
born that contradiction no
so what we said is that we took as the cost
transitivity in because we trust them
that the norm of the w square
but that is the
the soft margin down
that is the transitive them physically was saying that we would like
testing but tends to be far away
from the hyperplane
we basically the testing about things we want them to be squarely
in one class of the order
and we added another ten cost function which say the universe poland should be
as much as possible
it in the kind of highway between the two
close to the separating hyperplane
for each of these terms
as of course politicians so hyperparameters
and then we may cross validation experiments to find the right way to do it
and optimize optimisation is just
i is
he is
the most difficult part is not the universal which is convex
it's the semi supervised because it makes nonconvexity
the thing is that if i go to explain this in the there's going mad
then to be long
it's been applied to all the elements i just don't have the mind images and
it is here
it was the talking
apply to all of them and place some speech recognition problem some fixed classifications with
the same kind of results
so you can dream up official text mining syntax together
they belong to the class because the not complete nonsense
but still this nonsense text that you
i understand
meaningful text
you can do the same thing from some speech recognition problem
this is not the did you think it this is known to work in many
yes there is
i think you should
if you go to
do you can show you now
maybe i should tell you to likely to the key this
there is a cyclical universe university
that has been written by fabian scenes including and he was end
the two years ago
but when binds to apply to serve surface it does so
with carbon down
the oxygen and and there's a really good reason for why that is the case
then we'll talk about that when we talk about molecular orbitals
what you see here is really just the top
of the CEO molecules using the oxygen and of the CEO
all right well
this image here
it was taken by something called a scanning tunneling microscope
i'm sorry to say
but this is actually invented just before you were born
and it was invented was actually work done by who's got affected by the again
and they are the nobel prize for their work
and the way the technique works is the following
let me the
four life here so there
i'm going to do some more work
what you do to to do this is that you take a tungsten wires
and you do a little chemistry with the tungsten wire down to is finite set
as you can
so you want
but it in some potassium hydroxide and current with the will can
and what you find is a predefined
at the end of this tungsten wires
but what you do
if you take that tungsten wire
and you can actually
two a ph so electric crystal
so i piezoelectric crystal and let me
put it this way here
is some material
if you put of voltage across that it expands a little bit
a little bit means
and twenty years from
and so on now
you would have done some wire to the material you have some
control on the angstrom scales
that's what happens
in order to move the active around
what you do
if you take this test
and you bring it say within five angstroms of the top of the socio
i plan for this year
my carbon here and here's my oxygen
well i'm going to do
it is i'm going to bring this this
say within five storms here
oxygen and
of the CEO molecules
OK and that
i'm going to put it
a negative voltage and this constant here
and i'm going to take the city of molecule in the attic flat surface and
ground it
now in this country
there are course of electrons instances of that all the metal has the characteristic were
some of those electrons strongly bound to the nucleus
are actually
they actually run around the solid
this is a high energy state
in that electrons are negatively charged and their environment the negative potential that's rather high
energy state
for those electrons
if i were to draw
energy level by william here
this is energy
and i'm going to represent those electrons and the tungsten
going to be at some
energy level
this is the electrons in the tungsten
however there are also some electrons down here in are at ground potential so these
electrons that are more energy
so i'm going to
draw energy level representing that the electrons and the planet right so this score years
distance right this is the distance this of the electrons at the time spent over
here the electrons and the planned
these electrons and the constant
i would like to to do
it is to be here on the planet is that the lower energy state
but the problem is
there's a gap right here there's no material
between the tip and the oxygen and the CEO molecule
there's if you do it in a few areas of the accu here there's vacuum
few here
so for the electrons to go from here to here
well there's a very large areas
this is a very high energy state of an electron in between this guy here
so i'm going to represent
the energy change
as electrons flow from the tungsten tip to the tongues to the land surface and
is the area like this
right very large periods
now you've seen these kinds of i call the reaction coordinates in chemistry in high
that is you SC
situations where we might here we're doing energy level diagram
this is the energy
of the reactants out here this the energy of the product
right and in between
is the activation energy barrier that we call
in other words
you have to put energy into the system
in order to get the reaction to go put energy into the system
before you get any energy out
right that's what happens in a chemical reaction point energy stop before we make the
and the speed to
as with the beginning of the last talk i was
i noted that
the masters to make the talk accessible to a broad audience yet when i get here i find that fourteen
experts very mathematically technically skilled
who probably know more about this field and i did so
what i'm gonna do
is given my broad general talk that do it very very quickly
and hopefully that will sort of engaging
i got materials so perhaps if you could stop me about ten minutes before the
end will just stop there and then sort
deal with questions i
big right hand
what i'm going to do
today is then taken through
an approach to try and understand biological systems and in particular the brain my perspective
comes from neuroscience and using
statistical and information theoretic approaches to understand the structure and function of the brain
i should also say that you're not going to learn anything from listening to me
so you don't really have to remember very much in the sense that
the idea of the ambition
it's a develop a general framework that
provides a number of contacts for many things which are only understood both in terms
of neural computations andin terms in machine learning so i repeat the idea here is
really it to try contextualize
hand unify at a lot of existing work
the approach take
borrows heavily from the notion that be helmholtz machine from geoffrey hinton peter diane and
appeals time and time again today
the writings helmholtz here
in essence what i'm gonna be talking about is
a perspective on brain function
that the
the brain has making inferences about the causes of its sensory inputs and this is my articulated by helmholtz
in this class of objects are always imagined as being present in the field of vision
doesn't have to be there
in order to produce the same impression on the nervous system
i'm going
uses these advances
brought the table by people like jeff and d from statistical physics which refinement formalize notion
in terms of a variational bayes and the minimization of variational free energy
and just provide u with a few examples depending on how much time
so we have to show the sorts of things that we are all that can
be simulated on the this general approach
i normally start of this talk for a general audience by asking them
to think about
in particular question which underlies the motivation
for this this approach
and the question is what's the difference between a biological self organizing system and non-biological
self organizing system and in particular
let's hear about what's the difference between
a snowflake
and the bird in the sense that they're both
thermodynamic systems that both shallots cells in the structure
they are characteristically different in one aspect
and i normally ask the audience just to try and think about what is a
crucial difference between a biological system and a biological system that we have any answers
for me there is you
yeah am
i'm assuming that there is a strong agent shot boundary
because the answer is is actually on on the slightly amsterdam's great before anyway so it's somewhat arbitrary question at
having thought about it
there one only ends up with with thee
conclusion that the only thing that distinguishes a biological from a non biological system
is that the biological system can physically move
two ri
configure its relationship to the environment or to change the samples of the outcomes from the environment
and they could be
yeah well phototropic behavior i think would be a nice example of physically moving to resample
those aspects to be violent
and is like
or even a single cell organisms so showing showing chemotaxis
so yes so
changing one's configuration over very slow time are very very quickly
in a way
that is a function of the system in all the cells selective sampling importance
you know of symmetry example would be that would deploy its
leaves in order to get a sample
light from the sun for example
yeah i will be very particular to each sort of integrity sort biological system absolutely yeah but
she you so
yes so there wouldn't be would be an example a non biological systems so what's
the quite essential difference the water doesn't actually
move uphill
maintain it sort of a
the states that could occupy
so the idea here is that the biological systems will try to avoid
crossing phase boundaries or more particularly the try to retain
the physical
physiological or any sort of state you can imagine within particular bounds so put another way in so doing
they will avoid particular boundaries in particular phase transitions so that i don't die auditory doesn't desiccate
although the water doesn't drip into the drainage system
so the idea is that they simply move
in order to keep the physical states within particular bounds
also put expressed mathematically in terms the shannon entropy that will try to minimize
the shannon entropy
all minimize dispersion states that they could occupy
that's basically what i'm going to be using to motivate the survey
the minimization of free
so support very simply always saying is that biological systems physically move
particular there may be a face
then there is also the work here by civilian collaborators in which they try to
model the object of relationships justin segmentations of the take an image this segment this
image from this is segment they try to the create set of possible object labels
that may exist there have been some object appearance models of the on examples of
now there
possible labels that my account for the different features of cells in each segment
and then they will have a kind of a CNF on of it in order
to decide what are the final labels
and the way they do it here is the one that they try to model
the full joint high so what they're going to do is to model
the joint just separate of all possible pairwise comparisons at all possible locations
so that's just an upper approximation
but if they show that also improves performance is in this case
they are going to have this prior you they all the labels all the segments
and they are just modelling by dino all possible pairwise comparisons all the possible level
this is another piece of work in which
another thing that is very interesting is that most of the time in images what
is important in order to learn consistent of relationships is not a relationship between this
object is the fact that you have a monitor chair but the relationship between staff
and objects stuff is what makes most of the scene led the ground grass sky
buildings walls
does this stuff is more or less what it buys more like ninety percent of
the image and the discrete objects that appear from time to time
so in this piece of what they try to do is to model stuff
and stuff in order to give context information for which of disrespect to be on
the image
so what is interesting is that they don't use labels in order to train
but this stuff is so they dont have training data for so you know this
is sky or graphs and so on what they do is they
segmentation of the image they like a bunch of segments with a computer features from
the segments and they they apply k means for instance to do you get a
bunch of cluster centers for
and then they
they use each cluster centre as one label and they
analyse what context of relationships between objects and those clusters into labels
so here for instance they learn the relationship between buildings and cars but there is
not an explicit representation the something some building is just when you have looks like
then cars generally appear on top of it and when you have actually look like
this then cast nearby by but not on top
there are all the things that you can do with scenes
not just trying to model the
consist of relationships in order to improve the detection of objects
you can also try to answer all the questions like
what is happening on the image who is doing what
so in this case in this image so this is work by william fyfe
in which a what they try to do is given an image they try to
give you information about the five there are no people here on a boat and
after this in the background but also that is an event going on these people
is role the scene
that is the lake so that all these three themes here that interact with each
the goal is not anymore to just labelled obvious personal image but after provide you
some additional information about what is going on the picture
this elephant
so this is different examples of different events that they have in the database like
polo players so here again the objects that our
participate in this event and then the scene description of the what of this event
is taking place
and the same thing here
then there is an old family of models that i'm not going to talk about
which grammars these are very important class of models and it's almost a shame only
going to vote with lies to them is to be almost an entire tutorial by
itself and and these models started very long time ago from the seventies and they
have been there family awards trying to develop grammars for vision
and basically the idea is that
again you are going to the composer seem to have this hierarchy of different interpretations
of an image but they are just not grammars so not only do are going
to have a rules like and and or this is present then this should be
compose instead of elements and so on and so on
here are some works by some senses group in which they use grammars to represent
not just scenes but also objects that you can use this for almost anything
it's a very rich set of models and i'm not going to talk about them
here but they basically pursue the same goals what have been discriminative
OK so all that was about
object recognition but all the things that you can do with scenes in particular decomposition
of the three d structure and the something very important that people are starting to
do very recently seriously and so one of the first observations that humans we have
really wired for three d
you know here i have two eyes
they are in front of my face i could have one i in front and
the my back in this way you will see the entire we still feel i
will see everything around me but now i decided to give up half of my
visual feel and i put my my eyes here nearby
you seem exactly the same thing so that i can see
so that means that it is really important for for many many animals and they
are willing to give up half the was of feel and you know you don't
know what's going to become in front or back
but you get to see into the
so that means that he has been a really really important for us
and in fact the is again something that we get to use all the time
we can not shut down
so here is an example of one of the solution
in which there are these two lines both mention as early the same length
and yet you see there must be in different is really hard to believe that
they are actually the same length
but this is because when to see this picture to reasoning through the about it
and you can shut down the fact that this is a three d picture
of course is that the picture larger projected on the screen and these lines happen
to measure the same thing but you can't shut down during processing
so it's very very powerful this is another example by a little bit and ridership
in which
these two table tops are identical
they are one
just the rotation of the and i did this just by adjusting for the show
so this stub is nothing from his original driving just the figure and i rotated
for the shop and put it on top so is identical is the very same
one although who knows what windows does with objects not but that
but the truth is that
you you can of really all i through the perception here
i you can see these two you can actually build them all and you can
be the object you know is the same object you know exactly what you have
done you could have better priors about what this shape should be and yet you
could see differently
so here all you general bayesian enlisted just fall apart
during the this is not the kind of prior that you are you are built
to encode
and also the something that people have been doing for some time
so here is an example of
you seem very simple city it can also already be very powerful
and so in this work this is war by in scotland and ireland u
the only thing they try to do is to identify with the right online of
possible sets that we can assign volume two
now it's simply taking the powerset doesn't work
because it's complicated and so we have to figure out which sets we would like
to we would like to
to be able to stand volume two
and in that case so
the original way that
this is spread sigma algebra was defined on the real line was people started
by taking all the half open intervals
and said OK that's certainly something and tell us something that we certainly want to
be able to assign one two
otherwise our theory would make might make much sense because basically just take the length
of the interval and that's all
OK and then then you say
it defines the signature of the smaller sigma which contains all these half open sets
of these have open into about
and on that you define and measure so every set in that interval is mapped
a number
we still have to figure out how to find measure that would be like the
original historic examples here
i want to do
exactly so usually if we if we work in this way
then then we don't have a problem basically it's more problem that you have in
improves when you have such maneuver claim OK akayev's is this sigma algebra comes out
somewhere and i have to prove the smallest one containing all these sets
they can be really really difficult
sigma of
well because
what does this
it does not include all subsets well what if we want to greater one of
the sets were OK so the question is what does not measure was set in
this sigma algebra look like on the real line
basically the the the sets that that are not measurable
in this in this for a sigma algebra on the real line r ridiculously complicated
actually for those of you who are
who are familiar with the axiom of choice
if you want
a set four is set to be non measurable
it is basically constructing an unmeasurable set in the signature requires the axiom of choice
are actually in
that's not corrupted but
so is that is not measurable in the technology but if it has if there
is no model of set theory in which it does not require the axiom of
choice to construct
does it help
it's great have no OK basically basically and he said
just as
and he said that we ever will encounter that we can
meaningfully integrate or want to integrate or any application within be the signal that is
why it has emerged as as the standard sigma algebra everybody uses
so in the beginning i don't think that that was clear just took some time
to figure out first of all that all the
the different assumptions that we can make about what sigma what sigma would be reasonable
seem to lead to the same signal or do lead to the same technology
and that really
turns out to be a meaningful series
that gives you all the power in the twenty
but you can see they are still there still in a signature like this right
for example if you want to construct half open
the open the open interval would be in their own right
and since
individual points are closed sets
the close
the two endpoints are also in the individual individually and they can just take the
of the interval one of the points and you can do the same for more
complicated sets
as long as you only need a countable number of those operations
and that's why the sets become so complicated if you if you don't want them
to be in there then you have to invent some
some algorithm which does uncountably many steps to construct them from sets that we usually
any more questions
good so
now after
i've been speaking for forty five minutes i can finally tell you what to measure
so if we
if sigma algebras given so that's the domain of our right we want to measure
to be a function that maps
the sigmod but to the real line r positive like this
we know that the definition so that the
any any such function which does that which maps the sigmod approaches to the to
the real line
with these properties here
is called to measure the properties of first of all the empty set always has
measure zero
that integrating over an empty set
and then we need this this property here of additivity or pairwise disjoint sets so
if the sets here are pairwise disjoint
the measure of the union is the sum of the measures
and you you were
you will notice that these are not all the properties we looked at four measures
but if if you have not already seen all of this and if you think
it's interesting then you can quickly check at home that this is that this is
implies all the other properties
OK so this is the measure in general with these two properties here
and then if
four for the measure to be a probability measure we just the only additional requirement
we make is that it's not like so
the probability of the whole space
here is one
the probability that if we take a random draw that it is somewhere in our
sample space that's one
it's always
OK and the two
the two most important examples of measure
that we
we use in in everyday math
are the lib back measure which i already mentioned that this measure which assigns
the d dimensional volume two set
and integration with this measure basically is a generalisation of the semantic
all of them is one of the things that have been
seems to be the same so so so so
so question of how do you test the convergence rate and the different ways of
testing for convergence one is you can look at two different iterations to see if
he has changed a lot and if it hasn't changed much winter operations you say
is more this converged of something that's done maybe slightly more often is look at
the value j of theatre and j theatre
so the opposite a is the quantity you're trying to minimize is not changing much
anymore than you might
being kind to believe it converges so these are sort of heuristics standard rules of
thumb that are often used to decide if it into service composition
you know it's true
one one
twenty two
so what we do
this see that there are some questions
you know how going send looking pre sixty around changes in the direction of steepest
so it actually turns out not the second part of it turns out that if
you are
if you stand on the hell and if you are
turns out that we compute the gradient of the function we compute the derivative of
a function then it just turns out that that is indeed the direction of steepest
ascent on but it is point that you would never want to go in the
opposite direction because the opposite direction would actually be the direction of steepest ascent right
so so it turns out
new hope made it seem to me that he talk more about this on on
the intersection of those entries on to so we take the derivative of the function
and the derivative of a function
so it turns out to just give you the direction of steepest descent on
and so you don't explicitly you know look of the agency's degrees around users just
compute the derivative that turns out to be the direction of steepest descent
i mean it is this is us that using talk more about this i
let go ahead and give this algorithm on a specific names so this album here
is actually called
on back street to
and the term batches and greater term the term that refers to the fact that
on every step again this and you're going to look at the entire training set
is going to your performer some over your or m training examples of
so so so back to understand afterwards very well so i i use it very
often on and it turns the sometimes if you have a really really large training
sets so imagine that it's having forty seven holes is from portland oregon training said
he had to the US census database of with US census size devices can often
have hundreds of thousands of millions of examples
so if m is
you know a few million
if you run in batch gradient descent then this means that to perform every step
appeared in descent
you need to perform some from j equals one two million which is that's that's
sort a lot of training examples for your computer programs have to look at before
you can even take you know one step down hole in the function j theta
it turns out that when you when you have very large training sets on she
is she right down an alternative
that's whole stochastic gradient descent
sometimes also called incremental gradient descent
but you have to follow
you will repeat until convergence
and what the rate for g equals one to m
and will perform one of these is the gradient descent updates
using just the j th training example
and as usual this is really you perform the update all the parameters theta as
you performed as a natural
meaning before i indexes and the parameter vector c just before the study of all
the parameters simultaneously
on the advantage of this algorithm is that
in order to pull in order to to to start learning in order to start
modifying the parameters on
you only need to look at your first training examples is looking for first training
and perform an update using the derivative of the error with respect to just the
first example and then you look is sickening training example perform another
he said that he perhaps much much more quickly
without needing to
t scan over your entire US census data point started out this
the c
for large datasets of stochastic gradient descent is often much faster
and so on
what happens to stochastic gradient descent is that it was actually converge to the global
minimum exactly
but on
these are the continuity of function
then as you run stochastic gradient descent is you sort of tend to wander around
you may actually end up going up occasionally
parameters also the
of them on the web would be happy to talk to you if you if
you need it
and we are blessed with three
who took this causes freshmen
who act as what are called peer tutors no run session sunday evening from eight
to ten PM is the current plan will announce the rooms for these things on
the website probably by email to you as well
so let me introduce to you know how
OK and recline
and justin kemp
so there will be a big help to do so there's plenty of
plenty of personal help so use it
these are the dates we're going to have exams at ten lectures that exam nine
lectures exam nine lectures example actually if you check you'll find the the and also
you get fifty points for participation in the wiki
and the total of six hundred fifty points that's what your grammar exams based on
actually this doesn't cover nine lectures that are covered on the example of the previous
wednesday part of the lecture is going to be a guest lecturers it's going to
be here just that day
so we're putting exam offered lonely cover the previous material not that that's a big
OK this master grade
is biased that is based on this your total score here how six hundred fifty
points but if you're nearer cut off and you are very good about turning in
your problem sets and so on then we boosted up here we don't great problem
but if it's worthwhile to do them
right and they might make a difference
where are we going to this one of the goals of our fresh and organic
chemistry in fact if you click that your powerpoint you get taken to that site
but it's right on the website you'll see it anyhow
first of all is to learn the crucial facts
and vocabulary of organic chemistry products what we think we're here for
and to develop the theoretical intuition
about how bonding works
this is the goal for the primary goal of the first half of the fall
semester is to learn how funding works really
and that relates that the molecular structure
and also how bonding changes
and that of course is reactivity
but under the line there are a lot of other things that you we do
in freshman organic chemistry that arguably just important just as important
like to make the scientific transition from school to university
in school they try to teach you what people know in the university you try
to develop new knowledge
so you need a different mindset for that and we hope this course helps you
develop that
so learned from organic chemistry which is really in my view of marble science
how to be creative scientist so here's here's the creative scientist by anybody's major louis
and in the eighteen eighties he said this in french but in english it says
going to be astonished by something
is the mines first step toward discovery
another way of putting that is
the characteristic comment
on making a real discovery is not eureka
that's funny
so that's what you really have to learn you learn enough about how chemistry works
in form this picture in your mind
that when
something happens that doesn't fit you know to be astonished so that you can discover
that's exactly what pastor did and we'll talk about that in the course
and even perhaps more important to develop good taste
so that you can distinguish sense from nonsense
there's certainly more non-sense floating around themselves
and being able to tell the difference for the way you do it is to
develop good taste by looking at a lot of good examples
and then you're aware of how crummy the bad examples are so we're going to
try to emphasise the examples
and have fun
so in a as we go along if you have questions break in you know
this much more as we go along no
the class really is mostly about theory
although we describe the basis for the theory and spend a lot of time trying
to make it real
but we require chemistry one twenty six l the lab this is the only chemistry
course that requires you to take a lab simultaneously so i hope you're all rolling
in that because there will be a certain
they that you want to be able to take it it's just one afternoon a
three hours or whatever it is
but if you want to get your first choice of line soon
well you'll be accommodated but it's just more convenient if you get
given range earlier but why
because lab answers the really big questions
let's define the
partitioning based r
portfolio election
we have two integer
one is here
the length of the nearby which is taken in holland
and the other one is that in here
we should really be indexed
if a sequence of partitions
for example the partition and you can imagine that the that
e g
cycle and go the miners
for example
and we
each such partition we
i have a partition or a quantizer of the
the return vector
the imaginary back
let g be the
one quantizer a bit
corresponds to the partition pn
and then just because there and and like a sequence of one thousand value
just use it using these short vision
OK i imagine that we we are
n minus one
and we would like to construct a portfolio that or
in order to make the ricci v and
so we
park read the segment of nearby
look at what if he
but until then we look at the vector today and yesterday
and make the quantization
and the search for similarities is in the box
similarity in
at the time you i'm i'm one means
that quantifies the
that's one of these goodman is equal to the quantized version of the fact that
if we find but i minus one
then OK then we are happy
and expect that
the very next return that are
the time for
they i
if behaviour will be
that is the goal is similar to the behaviour of the two more recent
so what
chevy do
we are here
this is an minus one
go back in the past
search for i mean i'm i'm one that the segment is similar to the that
five bond matching similarity
then becomes the very next to the
and and then again in similar
and we get a stop sequence of return back
this is an obvious way of thinking that
if i don't do anything but i have a history
possibly said then more for the actual current situation
i look for similarities in the past
because of the very next the return vector or the after the similar
it is the the set of mass makes here
i minus one and become the very next the in
what is it here
this is the song
maybe i can divide it by the size of g and
and it would be
an estimated or
all of the regression function
but it is better to explain it as the as i did before
so i look for similarities
both the very next week there learn
and for the three vector for these
stop sequence of the return vector or
these are dynamic portfolio that or
which performed best along the
and this seems to be the definition of the portfolio vector
depending on the eye
and depending on who are parameter k and l
i have two
because of the choice of the and
if accidentally
if you sorry
this g and
is that
just to the uniform portfolio
so for each feature for a pair of integers k and l
i introduced the portfolio vector for
sadly i minus one
the point
we don't have any conditions on it
the other
this is the
i mean at university it's a good question maybe a i i did the two
because he mentioned
concept of universality
are all these nonparametric in problem
classification regression estimation
one month is going to
one month the second one
and the reading of the rules
rather than
the that you can read them semantically
if the numerator if all of the formula in here k satisfiable
in one of these guys is k satisfiable
case class of kripke frames
what is k satisfiable mean it means there is some
with that contains the world makes the truth
some models
it contains the world makes it true it's double existential notion
there exists some model there exists the world
the same is true
at well what does it mean for us it to be true at the world
means every formula in the same is true
in the multiset sorry
OK so what's a k tableau
it's an inverted tree
with the root note so k tableau for set y you give me some say
and the first thing i do is i work with the internet of y
they are preserved logical equivalence this is slightly bigger just means i can use three
rules rather than
ten or whatever it is
the root note is nnf y
the children are all obtained from their parent node by instantiating a rule of inference
so what you do is you pattern match this guy
with these rules the numerator these rules and say is any one of them
a pattern match and if it is then you extend the tableau
by the bottom line of given example in a minute
and take a k tableau is close so you're going to get some sort of
three years
it's closed if all of the things across the board
i'm not with across
in other words the last rule in every branch is that it's true
on there
here's an example
so he is an instance of k
it's been negated
i showed you on the previous slide that when you push the negation in you
get something like this
so this is we're going to begin this is the end y
and now i look for rule is applicable
is that all applicable
what am i looking for
i'm looking for some atom and its negation and some other stuff
uh well now i've just got one big formula here
but is one formula sitting here
there are no free atoms
so that is not applicable
that one is because i've got a conjunction
and x is empty
just to the conjunction into a semicolon
now i've got two
formulating the multiset
it's still not
atomic contradiction
is now
got there is a conjunction because this thing is a conjunction right parentheses can be
so i just turned that into a same
there is still no atomic contradiction
there are no conjunctions left
there are no disjunctions because this disjunction is protected by the box
so i've got an instance
of this
so what's the diamond formula it's this guy
so if i is equal to not p
what the boxes in x it's these guys
and what's state is indeed
what do i do
i removed the boxes from all of these guys so i copied this there
i copied this them that box
i removed the diamonds and copy subformula down
have i got a contradiction well known as the p norm but that's the p
one they differ so it's got an instance of that because that's is that have
to be the same
you have two of them
it looks like a little plastic plates
this is that plate
and it is cut in such a way
i will take this off because we don't need this
and this plate is cut in such a way you can come in many cases
by this large sheets
cut in such a way
that if light
unpolarized light
goes through plate
that is hundred percent right what comes out
in this direction
and i believe that all these plates have been cut that way
but i cannot be a hundred percent certain
i can find that it's possible that some of them like this but i don't
think so
i think all of them will be like this
so that means if light comes from the back
and reaches you
after it has gone through this play
all the light
going to come to you this
that's one way we can make linearly polarized light and that's the first thing
we're going to look at that there is another way that we can make a
linearly polarized light which have also
discuss and demonstrate
and that is by reflecting light
of glass of water
and there's a third way
more difficult
that is if we have a fine dust particles
and we shine the light to these fine dust particles the light will be thrown
in all directions it's not nice reflection like you have mirror recall that scattering
i'll show it to you
that's also away
and you can make
polarized light
but that's first now turned to these
polarizes which were invented by
edwin land who
founded the
polaroid company
although the idea that you can make polarized light out of unpolarized light
it was already known
in the seventeenth century
but they didn't have these fancy mice
edwin land plates
if this plate
we are what we call an ideal polarizer
i you right
then it would mean that if you shine unpolarized light on it
that fifty percent comes through
so the light
is we do
in half
but everything that comes through
this is the uniform
so certain light intensity goes in
half of that comes out but it's all in your
that's what we call an do for in reality
you never get fifty percent you can always something less
think of it as being an ideal polarizing
get picture of what these plates
will do
so what i wanted to do now
this take one of these plates close one eye and halted play from the one
and hold it like this
all the light that you will see now
is linearly polarized in this direction
this is an exciting experiment no because you can see it
i can not see linear polarized radiation
animals can some animals can all be scanned
you can see the linearly polarized light
they can only which direction
but at least i want you to look through it
imagine if you had everything is now polarized on percent in this direction
and then i want you to put the
played like so
now all the light that comes through is no polarized in this direction
and i want you to
played like this
and all the light that he sees polarized now in that direction
in fact some people can see
but i've actually afforestation that's the difference
takes a tremendous amount of training
most of you can not
how can it be
that this polarized light
going through this piece of plastic
everything comes out like this that is boggling
to imagine what's going to happen and i agree with you that it's not easy
that's why most physicists will say
we don't understand light all that well but we can predict what will happen
if i go back
two my
when the spring was oscillating like this
that has a spring
what i was shaking is up and down
and new wave went like this
imagine that i would make stuff like this
this award
was essentially the reason so belief propagation passes the entire distribution is the message
rise expectation propagation will only pass onto the distribution certain expectations distribution allows you to
a very compact messages
you get to work
there's hardly any i mean there's some for belief propagation which would be a special
case but for the general case of all expectation propagation organs there's hardly any results
on so
what i did was i i took the exact mean of the posterior distribution
so the mean of the the green colour of the blue curve
and then i used
the mean of the gas in the came out to measure the absolute difference
and the same for the
o thing in both cases
so even if if you use
good zero
that's right
so you know cases OK right so this so using this metric is somehow cheating
because it's measuring something that goes in capture
and yes i agree
the have
this is the first position
the woman exactly that's right
so measuring air
that's correct
i mean will very cases where the posterior mean is actually the answer to the
problems of example if i want to predict for a test point where would appear
what is what is the expected location of a new point
and the posterior mean x would be the answer to that question
so so
earlier this morning increases talk someone asked about censoring
so i thought why we do something
so person here
we can we can write down a censoring problem which is very similar to the
court problem so here i've written down simple centering problem or
i have
the next that i want to estimate from y
x again has discussed in prior
and i a bunch of wise which are discussed in observations with his axe
but some of the wiser sensors and the scenting process that i picked
is one where you just know that the magnitude of y is bigger than some
threshold seen otherwise has magnitude ten
or more for example censoring process my my whatever device i'm using can measure beyond
some threshold just says all international that's it
but that sort of sensing problem we can solve using EP as well
what's the first thing we do when you want to solve the problem
right on the fact that right so
thank you for this problem will be
a bunch of wise and suppose we have a special centred y
we are writers
y four parente
this special censored observations
OK so
these factors
will be ordinary gasoline factors connected to x
OK and for the centered observation of this
special factor
who's formula
over here
so this factor says
this is just the probability of observing
a y
which is between minus infinity
here is the probability of observing y whose magnitude bigger than t
so here get zero minus t
the probability of getting observation
some disintegrating the the likelihood
because you like that over the region
now will be the exact posterior for for acts in this problem
as if i have a bunch of these censored observations will get similar things will
happen before i have a bunch of these features the centre observations because some
and if i'm multiplying together all have to the these terms showing each of the
terms in this sum by the way is very simple because this term for example
is just a cumulative garcia
so this term b
the problem is that you have to solve two to this kind of gaussians
so if we want to estimate approximate the posterior for acts in this problem we
can run expectation propagation essentially what happens
when we visit each of these
calcium factors
you will find their approximations themselves
because there already and so when you want to formalise this find should yourself as
the approximation and the only thing that we need to wear something interesting happens
it is on these censored observations
where we're is going to get
the following problem we're going to have this observation
we're going to have this
context term
you know i x
in this case it will be easier to be the product of all the other
graphs in terms
my context for one censored observations and then only all i need to do is
to the project that
divide that by q not iax
and that will be my
approximation for that censored factor
this is the moment of this product
our our can be worked out
so basically you have discussed TV of time the grass in the work of
and i'll show later on a strict for working on moments of this type which
arise quite a lot in t
so all that
that shows how you might use this censoring this
this framework
so let's move on to some other problems
now illustrate how you can apply
those problems as well alright so
here's the problem that arises a lot in machine learning
you want to use the tracking problem right you have
if an object which is moving around i observe the object at certain spots
at certain times
and my measurements noisy so the object is moving around central location
which is given by x
and as an instance in time
i observe a noisy estimate its position so the y one which is noisy version
of x one y two is noisy version of x two and so on
so what is the factor graph that sort of problem well we have supposed that
object is undergoing some simple markov chains around the market very common assumptions
so for example this equation for the dynamics which turns into that
familiar linear chain photograph
and our observation just we have got noise tracks so we have this thing off
and the
estimation problem is that we want to estimate where the object you want to estimate
x given twice
OK so
what i'm going to do
so first of all
you might recognise this is familiar problems you might see on this is the common
for problem you know with your signal processing book and star rating calling filtering equations
but i would suggest don't do that
because we are going to give you is much more general so you can apply
not only to
you got some problems but nonlinear problems well i'll show you how you can write
on nonlinear problem so put away your signal processing book for while i just think
in terms of graphical models and so we just have a graphical model when applied
general purpose graph modeling techniques this problem
now we assume that it is orthogonal to all expansion
and also that this function is strictly monotonic therefore if we plug our general functions
so we set our function can be
decomposed into their
part in the span of the training points in the from part
we can rewrite this
just using pythagoras
this quantity
but now we since we know that there is only a strictly monotonic and also
the square root is strictly monotonic
then we know that if we throw away this part
we actually might get smaller but we're not going to get bigger
so we can if anything we can we can save something in terms of the
by throwing away his of part
so that means the objective function two parts the first part of the first part
it didn't matter whether we have enough problems part or not
the second part we actually have to pay more if we also know that is
nonzero the minimizer of term must have must be zero
so therefore the minimizer so before we started with this fall
we started with this general form of functions we showed that actually this part should
be zero for the minimizer therefore the minimizer has this kind of expansion which is
exactly what we wanted to prove
and there are two different applications of this theorem one is support vector classifier but
i'm not going to talk about this now because i alex small i will tell
you in detail another example
are maximally both posteriori so you only estimates
in a bayesian setting or kernel PCA
which i also don't have time to talk about all these things can be viewed
as special cases of the representer theorem
which brings me to the conclusion of my three lecture so far
so it was all about kernels and i hope that i managed to well i
started with the informal notion of thinking of the kernel as a similarity measure for
the data
so we started then
on the blackboard reconstructed
a hilbert space such that the dot product in that space is equal to the
kernel we constructed a representation of the data in the table space such that the
kernel is equal to the dot product in that space so therefore in a sense
we have constructed a
a linear representation of the data
so the kernel also corresponds to a representation of the data in finally due to
the representer theorem representer theorem i told you that you have a fairly general optimisation
then the solution of the optimisation of the function is an expansion in terms of
the kernel so in that sense the kernel also parameterizes the
the function space that we use for learning hypothesis space is sometimes called so i
mentioned before i answering some questions that
in machine learning is always crucial not only to have training data but also to
make hypothesis about what solutions we will admit
so in this case
due to the representer theorem you can see the set of possible solutions is actually
is a set of expansions of kernel sitting on centered on training points so the
kernel some whole represents a way of dealing with all these three issues at the
same time unified way
so that's that's quite nice from a mathematical point of view maybe that's why is
also very popular field to work in an interview different problems in
and from a practical point of view of course and i could show you that
but from a practical point of view the reason why people wouldn't girls is that
they can they can
people we did a lot of different geometric algorithms and
construct interesting non-linear
methods for data analysis and i only show you a few examples one was the
thousand windows-based classifier
i briefly mentioned the possibility of doing two sample tests with kernels of also mention
support vector machines you will see them some something about them tomorrow i mentioned kernel
PCA and i think we don't even have time to
talk about kernel PCA but i guess you can imagine how it's going to work
now that you know the country
so there's a lot of different algorithms so comes are
not only from a theoretical point of view but also from a practical point of
view and probably going to see some some examples in different pictures also references i
i don't
shortly say ten to the ten
bits memory
um that's if you've got one gig memory because they have more
but i don't want to be unnecessarily unfair because what they just sitting there being completely unused
what about in the city itself
maybe is another million or so devices in a single
ceepee u
so you could say i yeah the pigeon is being the greatest got more devices
but the pigeons devices are slow so we taking into account the clock rate
i'd say
the clock rate is something like a thousand megahertz
which means that's
we're in the ballpark of
ten fifteen
or ten from nineteen
the second
i just checked what the latest news on supercomputers is in
that's a super computers with lots and lots of superiors in terms of memory
and they can do
ten to sixteen
floating point
per second
so this is two different ways the avg quantifying how much you've got a grey
services in terms of the hardware
how many hardware device operations you've got a second and this is in terms of the output what an entire
this isn't
a single
craig anymore
this is
today's top soup supercomputer
and crank sixteen floating point operations per second
what about the pigeon
well clock rate corresponds to attend millisecond
i'd say roughly because a single neuron can fire a hundred times a second if you push it
you could argue that some bits of the hardware maybe have a faster clock time
maybe you know an advocate the idea synergies can do some very rapid interesting things
let's just run with this number anyway
that's means you've got ten to thirteen operations
per second
if you take the neurons has ure
operating devices
ten to the sixteenth
operations per second
if you view elementary transistor like
as being sorry these sign-ups is
so in terms of operations per second
device operations per second the craig got more
going it
they pigeon actual output floating operations per second
if you take the signups is doing floating point operations
the same level as a supercomputer in a single page brain so
amazing computational ability in a pigeon brain
but it's not actually bigger
in terms of these numbers than a crate yes
okay the question is what's the size of the words so you're saying for these floating point operations
he is a floating point operation craig so
probably that's some sort of operation along the lines of the thirty two bit
in getting multiplied by another thirty two
the interior or something like that
it and doing it absolutely perfectly
if you're lucky is probably doing
and maybe two of orbits
per operation
i guess i'd be surprised if on on a timescale just ten millisecond
really getting anything more than two of bit because it's all dominated by class on
noise weather channels are open or not you've only got small integer numbers of channels
so yes the word sizes all
the precision of these operations is bigger for the craig
i'm all for today supercomputer
then for the patient there in the same ballpark
and that's not the case that the pigeon has far more resources at its disposal
maybe the pigeon is far better this image recognizing task because it organizes hardware
are essentially just a standard serial computers wired up slightly
different way
they have a sleepy u
all also to be used
if you want to store new memory
without losing interview old memories in a standard computer you have to have some new virgin hardware
so there is no connection at all between all memories and numerically just put them
in another place and you need to know
well they are
meanwhile pigeon brains have um
they have high conductivity
the typical neuron is probably connected to about a thousand
other neurons
whereas the typical transistor
and craig
is probably connected
roughly three or ten
other transistors
the computation however is being done
not we understand it
is definitely distributed
pigeon learn some new memory
restaurant process and then the guy wisely chooses his own table
the real point is used to meeting and make sure
as a density is your evolving over time just as the number of pixels so
can change and particle methods can be used to approximate this type of evolving
this it is
to do nonparametric inference
tom griffiths also did some work on nonparametric inference i forgot to include
let's come to static models
and those are the most we tend to actually use a lot
things like both machines for example
now in the static model the state space is not growing over time it's not
changing over time you state space is fixed
there's no index and the state space is defined
just on
kspace x
the space
it's not like what we had before
which was the state space there was growing
over time
however we might want to have the distribution is changing over time
even though the state spaces
thanks to get better samples from it
so one example is if you have a boltzmann machine
so two hierarchical levels
if you really like deep belief networks i believe this and tutorial on the topic
next door might be more related nonetheless
this improves the actually to apply to these architectures and people like you and me
marry and ruslan have actually applied
so we started
the way we do this we start with the simpler distribution
and in this case it's a tree
and in the simplest region it's possible to draw samples of this guy
exactly the same the forward backward algorithm so we can get exact samples we don't
get approximate samples and now if we had a way
of migrating those samples to become samples of this
and i remind you that in an undirected graphical model
every time we have an age what we're doing is we're adding constraint
by adding the age forcing x two to agree with tax-free three
and in fact that's why these problems are hard because each h either requires agreement
took our disagreement and this obviously needs to a lot of contradictions and these systems
known as frustrated systems
but if you have the constraints one at the time moving the samples the way
we heard in the samples as we are adding constraints were able to move the
samples to these regions
we we might end up with some of the the right target distribution
that's the sort of intuition for it
after is in blue that's in green
the only difference thing now is the distribution of static the sequences artificial
what sequence to construct its arbitrary
you can construct a sequence by hand different sequences of possible could have any of
the edges or i could add edges
and in fact because we can construct a sequence you can actually take a look
ahead and if you don't like what you got
if you go back and all sorts of games start appearing for the station
so one example of this is just sequential bayesian estimation when you have a posterior
and you keep getting more data you start with some data in the data keeps
so in this case is just a graphical model again we are adding more potential
it's very similar to what we had before
another examples annealing where we might have a distribution
and we have some sort of power the power goes up this thing gets more
and more concentrated sort of samples concentrate on the peaks of the distribution
well we might want to do tempering where we start with an easy
to sample distribution mu
and we start with a schedule that makes mu beta one
let's active so we said it initially to one
and then we decrease eta and so the samples
but we had from you which was the easy to some distribution becomes samples of
in the limit
we can do rare event simulation which is a big problem especially in high dimensions
because in high dimensions a lot of sense becomes really
exponentially small
so if we have to estimate the probability of an event and this problem is
very small like tail probability
so the target distribution and the
subject is
the final for this very tiny set
we can again construct a sequence that first we sample from from the whole state
space and then we just
we're we sampling from until eventually we
and our sampling from the right
target distribution so if you have a system where you're adding more and more and
more constraints
and you're trying to sample events are very rare
like rewards in for reinforcement learning for example if there were if there's very
logprob motivating that reward
you might want to construct a sequence u
zoom in
in important areas
and this is true of many other problems in computer science
in science you might find some constraints always work like this you are closest one
at the time
so you have think constraints you could stochastic version of these methods for sat
and it's been used in other problems were
a study by computer science theories
OK so
the derivation of the moral and are not that many people work on this problem
was the really hard problem two to considered as one good solution
one very reasonable solution to come up with the following
even though we care about the topic distribution that static
we can do is we can create a joint distribution by expanding
the state space
so we create a much larger distribution
there's always to do that but
they tend not to be as efficient as this
now for various reasons
but we construct is extended distribution so when i take the
one marginalize
and actually this should be over x one to n minus one college at the
when i marginalized from one to n minus one i still get the right target
distribution of what
again the derivation is the same as the one that i just scribble before
the importance weights are
the unnormalized function divided by the proposal
and in these methods the proposal will typically be an MCMC kernel so we're going
to propose by just doing one step of gets the one step of metropolis source
in one go your favourite samples
so i'm going to use k
instead of q
it's the same thing
and again the same derivation
and importance weights we end up with now have this extra matrix the matrix
that's exactly what we had before
except that there is this extra l matrix
and so the algorithm
this again is and the same type of sequential monte carlo we had before
well for the boltzmann machine we would have had all the samples drawn from the
tree at the first step
and then we would have moved to those samples by applying one gibbs iterations through
is the probability of the intersection of a and b
divided by the probability of b
that's just the definition
and a and b are of course just labels i can turn this around and
right for the probability of b
given a
is the probability of the intersection of being a divided by the probability
but then if you think about the way what does it mean a intersect to
be that that intersection of subsets a intersects b
is the same as b intersect a we denote the same subset
so therefore the probability of those two things also must be equal
so if i simply solve each of these two equations for the probability of a
intersect b here the probability b intersect a and i said them equal
then you get an equation
which i can then be right in this form
it gives them the probability of a given b
is equal to the probability of b given a
times the probability of a divided by the probability of b that is based there
which is very important theorem
in comes up all the time in the analysis
it was published in
actually a couple years after bayes died in nineteen sixty three
and i'm sure you can google for this and find it on online and reprinted
many places it's interesting actually to take a look at this to see how much
the english language has changed in two hundred fifty years it's absolutely unreadable see if
you read it and you can even realise he's talking about probability theory i think
that's that's a challenge
but it's certainly very important there
now certainly go back to this
the probability of b that appears in the denominator very often
it's useful to rewrite that
in a slightly different form
and so that's what i want to talk about now is is a way of
rewriting that
probability of the of the smaller subset which is going to go
for the condition of the conditional probability
i have two ways of explaining one with a picture one the some formulas
so let me start just with the picture suppose the
rectangle represents the sample space
and then the red curve represents b
so i'm i'm trying to find the probability of a given b so i'm going
to suppose that that i'm going to impose the condition b on the sample space
in certain circumstances it can be possible to
the initial sample space s in two
disjoint pieces
so is that suppose i've done that and and i will label those pieces a
sub ISO a with an index
and so these are the different a one a two a three and so forth
and then in the places where those
pieces which are all disjoint
where they intersect with b
i would say a b
intersect a that's what the yellow guy represents
now so there would have to be
intersect AIP intersect at j and so forth
remember what the third kolmogorov axioms sense it says that if subsets are disjoint
then the probability is simply add
the statement of the law that i'm trying to derive the following it says that
the probability of b
is simply the sum of the probabilities of these individual pieces
b intersect AIP intersect
what that on there
and so forth if you simply sum the probabilities correspond to those
pieces you get the probability of b
that's the graphical
derivation of
the theorem of the formula that i'm going to write down
now in formulas here it is again you simply say that b is the union
of all these small chunks be
intersect a i
and so therefore the probability of b is equal to the sum of the corresponding
probabilities because they're all disjoint
and if you think back to the definition of conditional probability you see
the probability of b intersect AI
that's simply what appears in the numerator of the
definition of conditional probability that simply equal by definition to the probability of b
given a i times the probability of a i
right so there is that is that my formula for the probability of b
that's called the law of total probability and if i put that then in the
of bayes theorem were before i had p
that gives me the
the form of bayes theorem that is actually useful right so that the
the version of the of bayes theorem which we actually apply
OK so let's do an example
with that and by by tradition the first example that always gets shown with bayes
theorem has to do with the medical test this tradition
so i suppose you have some
some disease i guess to be topical this year i could have chosen swine flu
or something i suppose you have some
the disease and that in some group of people
suppose the probability to have the disease is one in a thousand
o point o o one and so therefore
the probability not to have the disease has to be o point nine nine nine
some of those two numbers has to be equal to one
right now suppose you have a test which can test whether a person is a
carrier of the disease but this test isn't perfect
it is simply a plus
of positive or negative results
but the test isn't perfect suppose the probability
to get a positive result given that you have the disease
is ninety eight percent
and so then passed the probability of getting a negative result
even though given you have the disease
is two percent
some of those two numbers has to be equal to one by construction
if you go to your doctor and you say well how reliable is this test
hearts ninety percent reliable
well then already know your doctors in very good doctor because that
that alone is insufficient to characterize the reliability of the test
you can't simply say
what is the probability say together
incorrect negative result you also have to specify
what is the probability to get a positive result
if the person didn't have the disease that's that's separate number that's not derivable from
those so suppose in this case that happened to be three percent
right then
the probability to get negative result
given the person doesn't have the disease is ninety seven percent those two numbers have
to add up to one
OK so in any case it looks like it's fairly reliable
test you know maybe the doctor is a ninety percent ninety seven percent and it
looks like a pretty good test
so suppose you take this test and you come back with positive results
how worried should you be
do you have the disease
OK so if you look at the numbers you realize that what is the number
that you really want
you want to know the probability to have the disease
given that you have a positive test result
that's not the same as any other numbers up there
but we can get that using based there
so what we want
is the probability to have the disease given the positive test results
that is equal to the probability to have a positive test result
given that you have the disease
the probability overall what's called the prior probability
they have the disease that's before you took any test
and then in the denominator here we have basically what was coming in through
the law of total probability this is the probability of a positive test result rewritten
using the law of total probability that's the part probability of class given the disease
times the probability of the disease plus the probability of a positive test result
given that you don't have the disease
times the prior probability
not to have the disease
OK so we can simply plug in the numbers
from the previous
and work it out
then it has to simulations of the ranking civil twelve policies and you have to
simulate that as well and we have used in the same amount of space as
the comparative law
so i just want to point out injured
the simplest algorithm will be when the well
so they really have discovered by the current best policy would best means lowest number
of hits in the window of say three hundred
this works well
including a little bit
it's hard to the window size and it takes a lot of additional space
so what we did is we use
four online learning
we have one where one weight per expert policy
we're WIC estimate earned
relative performance of policy i believe that the current policy it's best if the numbers
closed is point nine it's a pretty good policy if it's point zero one it's
about policy
with respect to the recent data set
we need to do
updates of these weights
one is going to be the last updated twenty e to the minus loss with
all this stuff i did this in the first lecture
and then a new classifier is called the share updates which are very crucial to
prevent the curse of the multiplicative updates
it's quite interesting this of these two groups so you to fix them
the first update is one of those updates e to the minus loss update you
can also write it is always tend to be been miss it's a number between
zero one the majority of the world's simplest version of the the second of july
OK that by itself
it's very dangerous data is
very dangerous because if one policy
isabelle bad or
it has a lot of missus it's which goes down to zero
so when the same policy gets good later on
you can recover
so the multiplicative update is a very dangerous thing because is very fast it's too
so what you need to do is you need to do what's called share update
we were from california we share so
so you
take a little bit of the weight
so you take your weight vector to be
the weight vector you just got but you also take a little of
the weight given to the past average weight and this has an amazing effects that
i will elaborate on now in the moment it put it lets the algorithms recover
into all kinds of things and i
we can theoretically motivated this actually even though
the catching applications much richer
and full of clue jason the theory doesn't apply but in the clean context we
can what it is
these are the probabilities
and you can see that it really does shifting these are the probability of one
of the runs of the algorithms on one of the datasets you can see that
some of the weights very low some algorithms but some weights the good ones actually
if you go back and look at the slides
showed the current best response to look at these colours that are often used here
a lot of purple
and the way and these out cities online algorithms the kind of
shift between you know he is the herbalist weight is pretty high the right one
does the right thing
it's kind of like cool
to watch
so now i'm going to give you a little bit more
information online out shifting expert on them
OK remember with the expert framework
they want to predict the weather
prediction true label loss
we had updates
this was summarizing the predictions of the experts
this was the the
first of all
good prediction to make predictions labels incur loss
no still no statistical assumptions on the
on the data and you want to do as well as the best expert
this is the total number of the total
x that is the kind of about one
i don't really the loss the best expert
they update was simple weighted average prediction and it was
e to the minus loss
weighted majority was an example generalized but you all
i talked about all this
good but now what happens is i mean the shifting setting i have expert seven
might be good for a while and then the data shifts
exp at twenty is good for one
then the policy for is good then policy fifty one is going missing
so if i use these kind of multiplicative updates at this point
the weight of the two
exp at twenty might be zero why because expert twenty might have
stream amount missus you've lost in this area
so i need to do something to help it recover
and that's what share does so we want to do this
well as the best compartment expert what's the loss of this commodity for total loss
in each of these segments
lots of data two well it does not recover fast enough
he has to fix
due to its that
right so that's what explain
two of these the first there is this multiplicative updates either minus loss
that homes in very fast it's i call it the short-term memory it homes in
very fast to the best policy
if policy is good
its weight
is going to be not multiply by these factors and all the other ones are
multiplied by these bad fact by these factors and wiped out and it's going to
be brought the good way is going to be brought extremely fast lots
the second thing you want to do is you want to take
the current weight vector
this is
and makes it
they can make sure the previously factor
and the simplest way to do it would be to take
imagine one percent
ninety percent
you take the weight that just got
is isn't and using the even minus last update
and one
say you take a uniform distribution
well in
so that means
no wait goes down to zero because you always one percent is always
you know
mixed back to the uniform
fancy one will be
it is ninety nine percent times the current weight vector
one percent
you take past average weight vector
or some kind of king of the past
so the thing
so all the old ones come back in
so this is a particular simple
where you
nine you take this update and then you take ninety nine percent
the weight vector is ninety nine percent time this displays plus one percent times to
pass average
everybody understand what i'm doing
so you want to mix in the past all the vectors and there an extremely
interesting thing is it was
so we did some additional expenses joint work with the scheme
so my had had fourteen thousand trials
i had twenty thousand expected huge amounts of experts
and i did six shifts
in this segment
the first expert was the best then the second was the best person with the
best second best third person person express second was the best
so let me show you
it's the total loss
this is the total loss of an arbitrary expert over time
great goes up like this you square loss
this is the total loss of best expert
if you would know what the best expert is
there's some or noise rate
the idea is quite similar but the difference here is now that can not k
nearest neighbors so risking his neighbours are
used for the reference but at some neighborhoods
OK so again
points that have distance less than epsilon
to that
point of interest
and the idea of
this local outlier correlation because also to test multiple resolutions multiple
well values for epsilon
which are here called granularities
and this is
especially important to get rid of any input
so the model is based on that sunday one point and then the local density
of points just the number of objects
in this have some neighbor which is very similar to this distance based approach with
epsilon p
but now it computes the average density of of neighborhoods here
if you take a closer look
it's very complex here but it's not really so this is the density the average
density of the point p
so absent is there is the radius of the neighborhood
and i find is parameter which is smaller than one two zero and one
and what
the according the local correlation because actually does is
we examine the
o point p itself
of with radius absolute
and and for the neighbours
decrease the radius of the of the neighborhood which we which we can't buy
this factor
OK so maybe we could do this
picture here so take point p year which is on an inspection and well
we this is that the have some neighborhoods
of p
we count the number of points in the steps and they which is the density
around p
and this is compared to all neighbors in this neighbourhood the density of all neighbours
in this neighbourhood but for the the density of the neighbours
consider a smaller range
i five times this power should be absolute sorry
other times that's case so the density around the neighborhood the neighbours
this is a
reference it is smaller
OK this is the
most important
o point here
OK so and came back here based on this on this density we can derive
a so-called multi granularity deviation factor which is
and an outlier score
which is basically here
one minus the cardinality of
the neighbours
we've hired by sorry divided by the density
of name
for this muddy deviations
we can compute the normalized standard deviation of all densities of all points
which is
denoted here by
and the half and
it's very interesting because this is the kind of
relationship to the statistical based approaches statistical based approaches where we have these tests with
the gaussian distributions a very common test is points that are three times the standard
deviation apart from the from the mean
are considered outliers and we can apply these three sigma rule also here
so all points
that have a multi granularity deviation factor of more than three times the standard deviation
can be considered
points that have ndf zero equals zero are definitely within
so this is
nice feature and there's another features of the parameters epsilon alpha are determined automatically
to use don't has a doesn't to specify this in fact all possible values for
one test
all of possible
and the output
is a very nice display for each point
for each point you get
visualisation like this just
plots the cardinality of the that neighborhood
of each point on the density around these each point with varying epsilon varying radius
and for example for for the point here but this is the micro cluster point
is this
this red point here
you see that
his that this so it this
distance special eps along
happen something
what happens well
the distance gets large enough in order to make this point an outlier
here for cluster point in this in this direction here
over large spectrum of epsilon nothing happens that means
over all the spectrum
this point remains in layer no outlier
and for this point over here
you see that several
at some threshold
so you have these bombs in this in this course
which indicates that
well use this point all over all these these values point is it's not
so there's a nice feature that you get for each point kind of graphical
is it and also not
and which
shortly a sketch of the algorithm so the exact solutions rather expensive because you have
to compute all these values for all possible absence values of course
not very nice so
the office came up with the
all draw something from the distribution
so this is interesting and now calling self distribution
and remember this will be different for each stock
it will return me some random value from either the gaussians or
the normal distribution
with different volatility for the stocks because that was also selected randomly
plus some market by us
saying well the market on average will go up a little bit or go down
a little bit
and then
all set
the new price if you will self that price to sell stock price
times one plus the base move
so notice with this says the base movie is
then the price doesn't change so that makes sense
interesting question
do you think
i said
self-doubt prices times one plus the base move
rather than just adding the base moved to the stock price of the stock
again the first time i coded this i
i had in addition there instead of multiplication
what would the ramification of in addition there b
that would say how much the stock changed
is independent of its current price
and when i ran that
it just i got we're results
because we know that google
price to take three hundred
is much more likely to move by ten points in today
then the stock priced at
fifty cents
so in fact it is the case if you look at data
and by the way that's the way i ended up setting a lot of these
parameters and playing with it was comparing what my simulation said to historical stock data
and indeed it is the case that the price of the stock ten the move
the amount of move tends to be proportional to the price of the stock
expensive stocks move more
interestingly enough the percentage moves are not much difference between cheap stocks inexpensive stocks
and that's why
i ten ended up using
a multiplicative factor rather than additive factor
this is again a general lessons
as you build these kinds of simulations or anything like this
you need to think through
whether things should be multiplicative or additive because you get very different results typically
is what you want to do with the amount of change is proportional to the
current size
whether it's
price or anything else an additive
if the change is
of the current value typically
this is i think the general way to think about it
you'll see this other kind of
the chilean thing
so i now set the price
and then i've got this test here
if mo
most stands for momentum
i now
exploring the question
of whether or not
stock prices are indeed memoryless
or stock changes
and they fancy word for that is possible
people often
model things as possible processes
which is to say
processes in which past behavior
has no
impact on future behavior
it's memoryless
and in fact that's what
the efficient market hypothesis
reports to say
it says that
since all the information is in the current price
you don't have to worry about whether went up or down yesterday
to decide what it's going to do today
there are people who don't believe that
and instead argue that there is this notion called momentum
these are called momentum investors
they said
what's most likely to happen today is what happened yesterday
or more likely
if the stock went up yesterday it's more likely to go up today
and if it didn't go up yesterday
so i wasn't sure which
religion i was willing to believe in
if either
so i added a parameter called if you believe momentum
then you should change the price
and here i just did something taking gaussians times the last change
and in fact have
so if it went up yesterday it will more likely go up today example throwing
positive number
otherwise the negative numbers
notice that this is additive
because it's dealing with
yesterday's price
change with the change
so that's why we're dealing with that
now here's where i should have
put in this test that i had up here
get help from there
because what i wanna do it says itself that price is less than zero point
zero one
i'm going to set it to zero
just keep it there that doesn't solve the problem we to have before the right
then i'm going to
keep the last change for future use
OK people understand what's going on here
and then show history is just going
producer plot we've seen that a million times before
any questions about this
well my i have a question
it doesn't make any sense is going to work at all
so now let's test
i now have
this unit test program
called unit test stock
i originally did not make it to function i had in line
i realize that was really stupid
because i want to do a lot of times
it's got an internal procedure internal function
local to the unit test
that runs the simulation
in in a in the linear model
where we have infinitely many basis functions on the basis functions a little gaussians that
are centered on every possible point in the input space
OK so think we get the same answer as if we did a bayesian inference
on a linear model
where the feature space
contain these contain these galson points galson bonds and their as important distributed everywhere in
the in the input space
she n
he was
so it's just in this case is just that it's just it is the sum
of these of these things that are all that all galson in the variables that
matter it doesn't actually really matter what they what the basis functions because that doesn't
include the variable
which has the gauss distribution which is gamma in this case
OK so this is the only u
what about the way
these people we have this is that
you will be
so the covariance matrix is fixed well
my prior to that he was born with
in vision
there's always generated by the
one thing
that's a good question question simply you know if if i come up with the
covariance function then you know is there a proper gaussianprocess
interpretation of that and it is the class of functions where and that's exactly correspondence
there there some criteria not all functions are covariance functions right so the critical command
functions of functions are positive definite functions right so it has to be
but if i evaluate the
the covariance function for any choices of x and x prime then the matrix i
get out of that has to be positive definite because otherwise there isn't that gas
in gauss interpretation of so any any covariance function would give rise to you know
properly define problem of course you want to go the other way right we wanted
we wanted to be the case that you give me a data set and i'll
tell you you know what is it good characterization of the dataset that's what's going
to be learning in these casting process so that's what we're going to get to
in a few minutes
OK so this this from this maybe remind you about a very similar model which
is a radial basis function model so there is a no model where you have
coefficients on the lookout in bonds the bumps centered on your training points like this
is a little bit different because you gets in everywhere
why not just on the training points
so but is a new real
the difference between those two models i mean in the end i'm just going to
use and dimensional in anyway
so let's let's look a little bit that you know how does this thing behave
when you do inference
over the model
and to illustrate that yes
just because were
with the kernel
your own
that's correct to trying to that
it's funny
it's fun you can do you can do all sorts of things like you define
things that are always symmetric functions and you look at the covariance function you say
you know how could know where this is going to be symmetric right
it's nice
i tried
OK so so here's here's the cartoon example which will illustrate why there's a big
difference between using a radial basis function network and gaussianprocess although computationally is going to
be the same i do still have to you still have to just solve the
system system of n
the night creations what just and by n matrix inversion involved so let's pretend that
we have three data points to three points in green here
and we are fitting it with the model that has three gas thousand bombs and
the problems are centered on the on the training points but so if you are
bayesian model of this thing and we have to put priors on the weights
and then once we see the data and then we'll have a posterior over the
weights in the you can think about the the since jiggling around they can move
around a little bit back and forth but they all they always have to some
of them always have to sort of more or less describing the data
up to the noise level
OK so you can think of the posterior as being these gaussians are wobbling around
describing always being put close to the data points
OK now i want to make a prediction
OK i want to make a prediction here
OK so what is the posterior distribution look like out there
zero yes
because the calcium pumps there they're moving around under the posterior distribution right but they
have they always have value zero over here it doesn't matter what the weights
so the predictive distribution for model like that is zero
with very high confidence
that was the wrong answer right
the answer is that OK the mean might be zero but we certainly not confident
about what function is doing here
like something went wrong and what is it that went wrong
for all we know
that's right there's something wrong with the model right to model is already saying apriori
it's impossible that the function does something up here is that your prior surprise as
a function can do stuff here but it can do some stuff over here then
once you've seen the data you still think it can do things that you
so there's something wrong with the model and actually the thing that's wrong with the
model is that it's finite dimensional model
you've already before you see the data you said there's only a finite number of
things that can happen right
and and things that that that are close to this can happen
OK so that's a very strong statement about usually you don't really want to make
a statement like that
so instead in the in the gaussianprocess formulation you have galson bumps everywhere right so
what would the posterior look like in that case
so we have bumps everywhere and then the data comes also so under the prior
to the bomb just bumping around right and then the data comes in
and the data says well the pumps that are jiggling around over here they actually
constrained by the data
but the bumps over here they're not constrained by the data
so the answer in that case is well maybe the mean is going to be
zero but more importantly it's going to say well i don't know what the function
is doing over here you could do lots of different things
and that's the right answer right along with the wrong answer by the radial basis