and as you have
the special unitary groups because
it's central to how we deal with angular momentum in quantum mechanics you might think
you can do the same sort of thing for the group's it's true you can
do it but it's much more difficult has been like last weekend to computing a
couple of these serious for the case of the symmetric group it takes hours and
hours even for relatively simple finite groups like the symmetric group and many for many
groups this problem is in fact unsolved so even as the of first non trivial
question representation theory and really get you get something which you know is the solution
but it surprisingly difficult
this is the kind of reasons the representation theory is occupied mathematicians
the reason that
i think are important representation theory it is important to the way that we handle
symmetries in machine learning is because
representation theory is what you need to generalized harmonic analysis into this noncommutative and harmonic
analysis is one of those areas of the map which spans across basically the whole
of the spectrum from across geometry and analysis and algebra it's really one of those
unifying concepts
so the generalization of the fourier transform
two group
really very simple
if you think about the fourier transform
on in the classical case is a on the real line
well this just the weighted sum
take a function that takes its fourier transform at a particular
frequency k
it's going to be something like the integral over the real line
of the exponential factor i x times six
to generalize this to groups you do something very similar
start out with the function
group so f is a function defined on the group general complex valued function
some over the group so it's sort of an integral hybrid things in the discrete
language for the sake of simplicity so you imagine you find group just some and
then you wait by something but instead of the exponential factors you wait by the
representation matrices
that's not such a crazy thing to do
representation matrices obey
by definition this multiplicative identity in world x times wrote my because of x y
that's exactly
what these exponential factors the behaviour of a over the
thank you
so this is saying that fourier transformation is kind of this weighted sum by something
which obeys the representation property
in particular
these exponential factors
from the algebraic point of view justified in the case of the
classical fourier transforms because they are themselves representations of the translation group
just that they happen to be one dimensional representations of people don't normally think of
them in terms of matrices but
and in this case because we're in commutative group it turns out that all representations
of one-dimensional and that's just what is taking them so this exponential thing is in
fact a representation is just a special case of this more definition of fourier transformation
on groups
and much of the machinery
from classical fourier analysis does carry through
so for example you have an inverse transform
given by the formula
and all the classical
properties that were used to
so it is of course linearity
you need to parity with respect to the appropriate norms
and the translation and the convolution theorem fall out naturally
but one thing that is different and this is important to bear in mind
is that
the symmetry between the space that you start out from in the space in which
the fourier transform lives is broken
this is something that is the direct result of non commutativity so if you look
at the formula in the on the previous page
i'm taking of OK we'll let alone
now you have the full slide that so
what i was saying is
my take on how to actually make use of semantic web OWL two employed to
exploit to combine all this data is by building applications
is by beating
not application but cool
smart nice and semantic web based applications
just not application that takes an RDF triple store
but it the back and and do something with it but applications that goes on
the web find his data everywhere
put it together and there's something called
what i want to show
is very quickly i mean i want show and a big overview we need to
us three days to tell everything you can do with the semantic web but just
show very quick to develop cost-effective something about
what if you want to be an application what we use what could you currently
with the semantic web
some of you may know this website called programmableweb
that face to be talking about
marsh API and the web as platform so basically
what i think is emerging now
is a programmable about semantic web something that talks about semantic mashups semantic API and
the semantic web as platform something where you can just take bits and pieces of
data bits and pieces of haiti is anywhere and an application in two or three
days that do smart new things and potentially useful things and if you're lucky things
that you get your money so i did was just this is
the domain name and you want to do it for free but
what they will
quickly talk about and end his introduction
is what
there is currently what exists as web API
two balls
for application developers to integrate semantics in their web applications
and i will also show
examples of applications of the example of what can be done today quickly and easily
and maybe
we could discuss about what more can be done in the very near future
so what
i would recover
it is
web API is that they semantic applications semantic data but give you semantic data without
you having to create it without having to collect it without you having to manage
all star they give it to you for free
there are no API that produce semantic information
from input you give you given to like
open calais semantic proxy and API
the collect on the web so is the existing RDF information to the existing RDF
data and allows you to exploit it to make use of
there are many of them and we only talk about the one ball
in particular
so far
this category is talk about sunday watson that are two semantic web search engines i
put watson a bit bigger
because i'm developing it so i think it's better
and we take can be
more time to talk about it
what i will not talk about it and i agree with everybody would think that
it is a pity
it is also kind of API
you could use to integrate semantics into applications semantic search API that i can i
is that you can just simply
using a web API without having in any need for infrastructure being you on semantic
search engine
which is quite cool
so i won't talk about online platforms like the platform to store manipulate and process
semantic information
and i mean not talk about
API is engines two
act on the presentation and browsing of few RDF information
but to make things simple and everything in we show
it was see
based on the very simple model which is the rest service kind of mother which
means that everything is accessed two http
all the API is used simple URL
but our parametrizes you through the URL was http called and return XML JSON or
two simply integrate in any language in any browser all you need
application what they produce
let's finally stop talking about
the topic of the thing and the first category of things i want to talk
about his
so the API that produce
semantic information there are a lot of them let's use name entity recognition natural language
processing of latent semantic analysis
where you can just give them the texts we can give them web documents i
can give them that basis and what they give you for your
it is
five hundred categories thing your text is about that
which is pretty simple but useful or it can recognise elements in your text
of actually extract anything from your database the first one
is the simplest probably is called textwise semantic hacker
these are very very simple API
you give it a web document text and it tells you
to each category
in which category of demos are demos you our it falls into
if you get a very simple example
i tried it with
the web page is one of this tutorial
so if you go there there you put that into your into your rules i
want work see why that
this is more the idea you get
the basic rate of the API
give it to talk and that is the number to give you an overview registered
to use the API
you give it
the URL of the documents so here is the website of
this tutorial
so in the sort complex to code up but it works quite well
so each stage you got a relatively simple a simple
to the analytical solution to your problem
very few numerical operations and i went the data choosing pairs as i go along
for the next can best candidate pair
always pushing my l
my da sorry maximise my w so this will be able to handle any subs
any classification regression
all other non detection tasks
well i've got a lot of the data so i would recommend smile that's what
i really say about it is its stream chunking the two samples only one time
if you get this problem of the data
it's too large
so it's a for the algorithms directly approach training from an optimisation create new ones
could i think might jump over the
right so no issue because i introduced the kernel earlier on like against incoming how
to actually find the kernel parameter
the sigma in the second of all the degree
and the polynomial kernel and indeed the whole issue maybe
what kernel do i use because i said these are different kernels but
i present you some data
i going to do with the linear kernel like the data is separable would just
do a linear kernel but it was not separable
should be using this gas kernel all modified RBF kernel
or something else
one point actually choose the kernel itself you may want to talk to know locally
had a criterion kernel alignment for doing this issue was you can probably describe invented
it but
one issue i want to deal with this
not the choice of kernel having having chosen the kernel
what do you do about the kernel parameter
if this parameter is poorly chosen then the hypothesis is over simple complex leading to
poor generalisation just remind you that this is it actually
this is the data set is actually a toy dataset it's a think symmetry problem
was about that but i'm very much sigma
and the bicycle is too small
i get this poor performance here
in the first was the other and they get
poor performance as well
and just very my
sigma magasin kernel i guess some sort of minimum when my performance is optimized OK
so it does make it difference what that sigma is
actually if in real life you can make such problem i would be inclined forgot
sufficient data
just to do this
cross validation study
to find the best value sigma OK
just keep some data site and event
the question of the paper but
i would say that if i got lots of data around and actually
i don't student projects we've done cross validation versus the criteria is i'm just about
to give you to find me
kernel parameter
and it's actually cross validation in in africa data which wins out but cross validation
simply can't is wasteful of data
and the context in which i can't sometimes do it when i did my will
tumours optimise
my lectures often had twenty nine patients OK i had to do training twenty eight
test and what i just can't do
and sort of
which is why
so i'm just going to say the foundation is is the choice but weights the
data simply can't do in some context were going to just show
the number of schemes have been proposed bayesian otherwise
i wish to give you need to find the kernel parameter without recourse to validation
data OK i'll illustrate one of these
this scheme i give you
it is due to toast and you can use and was in ICML several years
and i suppose i had like that will tumour samples
and perhaps i'm just trying to say something about the leave one out error
that would be this beta here
is an upper bound on the current now if we actually chose against income
the largest value that can become i could have simply one
when we speak my normal distribution OK that's greater than zero
so actually
choice garrison kernel give me a one here
in here so choose against simply everyone here
let me also do for hard margin case
simply set aside variable to zero just to make it simple to the simplest possible
so i guess in kernel
and no
soft margin
what the hell is going to work
let me increase by sigma value OK sourced start the small sigma i train my
finally first i find many instances due to alpha
greater than one this is represents the cardinality perhaps five fifty letters of the alphabet
after hundred i get this criterion violated divided by the total number of patterns i
have which is perhaps one hundred so perhaps is point five my christmas sigma
re-evaluate my album phi nu alpha
find what this number is the number of times throughout for greater than we could
actually has an explicit form
right this is the cost function that we're after
and so if we sort of plug the pieces in
what it says is that are
cumulant generating our log normalisation constant is optimizing over that constraints set that i define
you have a linear term
you have some of entropy is that the nodes
and then you have to subtract out mutual information is for edges
so it's an explicit problem has distilling linear number of constraints it's
something you could plug into any convex optimization solver
what makes this the most interesting is the belief propagation actually comes out of this
and belief propagation comes out of it by
doing a lagrangian formulation of it
so the high-level message here is the belief propagation is just an iterative algorithm
for solving this optimisation problem that's all it's doing
quite surprising i think
because it's not at all clear when you first see belief propagation
why should have anything to do with optimisation you can
sort specified without any cost function no constraint sets
you know it just looks like a local iterative basically dynamic programming
but this is basically that the messages are lagrange multipliers and they are lagrange multipliers
for this problem
so let's let's work through that i won't go into all the details but also
to give you the sketch
and if you're interested it's not too hard to fill in the details here
so what you do is remember this constraint set
the constraints set consists of some nonnegativity constraints let's not worry too much about those
normalisation constraints
and you have marginalisation constraints
so what's the matter to us is it's really the marginalisation constraints that are going
to matter those are going to correspond to the messages going along edges
i guess i don't have time to go into the full theory lagrang multiplier statistically
the high-level intuition
the way to think about them is
but the most police officers
so what you end up doing new form the lagrangian which has your cost function
that's the part in green here
it's right there
and then you take your constraints the ones i'm interested in all these guys
and you sort of assign a police officer each one of them
so the police officers were measuring your speed it seemed to satisfy the constraint or
not and if you violate the police officers gonna is going to find new is
going to penalize you
so what goes on in the lagrangian algorithm is that you sort of end up
adjusting the police officers to a point where
you are all forced to obey the constraints
see sort of think about the policeman continues to find new and fine you find
you up until the point that you first start to say well i'm not going
to speedy anymore i will be your constraint
so that's what's going on you've got the cost function
plus lagrang multiplier
time constraints
and what the theory tells you to do is is actually just to complete treat
this is an unconstrained problem in you this say
you take the gradient of this and you set to zero to try and find
stationary point
so let's let's go and do that
if we take derivatives this is just a bit of algebra
what you find is these equations pop that you have two equations two sets of
equations one for the singletons
and one for the
joint marginals
and what the theory says she set these to zero
and if i do that then i get this kind of form here
so what this is doing is it's it's telling me what the solution this is
what i'm optimizing over
it says there should be a function of the problem data
these are the potentials on your graphical model
and these guys right here are the graves multipliers
and so what it says is the optimal solution should look like this this is
the form that should take
now what's magical here is that if you remember we have a constraint we have
a constraint that if you some over this guy
that should marginalise down to this
right that was our constraint our polytope
that's just to recap that this constraint i have right here something over that should
give me back that so if you know of course that constraint what it does
is it gives a set of equations for the multipliers or equivalently you can define
messages these are exactly the same messages we had before and
what you get is this update rule you should somehow
and you have a product of incoming messages
so that's exactly the sum product algorithm so it says that the sum product algorithm
is just the lagrangian method for solving the simple optimisation problem tree
if you're going to see the goals and some more
it's possible to
have an algorithm to decide whether annexed the formula is an axiom of school recursively
enumerable set of axioms you can recognise whether something is XML
because he continued in the water straight away
so if it's got recursively enumerable set of axioms
it's consistent
so the theory set of axioms
this basic arithmetic inside it
you can tell whether the formulas because it is actually an is an axiom
and it's not inconsistent
there's is the a formula
it can't be
decided know which you can prove it compromise the form the negation
and this
completely destroyed program
because the program
research programme was to have mathematics put on a purely computational basis there will be
an algorithm to decide the truth and falsehood you want to to know
and girls result shows
this is not possible
such series includes the they arithmetic
and this is consistent then it's recursively enumerable set of axioms is completely natural thing
that would be what you would work with
so his
potential theory in mathematics and then this form is you can prove
so it destroyed building
the second problem died with the answer now
so this is a very famous there OK so went back to the point
lucas argument is this destroys i i
and i i system
it is the formal system in the subject to go completely
there will be things that could improve
that was essentially
his his i
so as i say the time it created enormous
now the control
i don't particularly i mean become i could spend the whole summer
well the implication was that humans went from systems
what humans do have inconsistencies
but these arguments against asians
well exactly was
that the agent was the former system and therefore subject to girls incompleteness there
but humans but humans were not subject to this
but the germans were not subject to this limitation
because we much money i don't so not defending the coast
well well roughly speaking that humans had some other mechanism that they didn't have this
limitation we get
so i'm not going to particularly defended because as i say
i guess since nineteen sixty girls incompleteness in mozambique
what i this thirty is also
was took part of being used to create
OK so basically there's this mathematical result from and used against us
another philosopher time
series of books and there along the lines of
computers can do this
and presuming that all the
and then the light and other ones what computers still can't do so this is
the god of the gaps argument
if you know the god of the gaps argument
OK so this is
evolution something you don't understand regarded
so is analogous to that
so the
whatever we do
that's fine but you cannot do this therefore cos
one of them to do that
it isn't really very convincing i mean you got
one of the proof that so finding gaps in what i can do
doesn't actually prove anything this means that they get to be solved
so i don't have much time for one either
his argument was basically the
this two books on this
and i very famous physicist
the emperor's new mind
i was actually amazing
there was one reference paper and i
the entire reference this one paper guess what what
wasn't burns eliza
that was really funny and fill in the hidden field a study what i was
going to prove it was possible
so roughly speaking the argument is that that and this is very common
the that items are true machines into machines kind of intelligence
and as well as that
i mean is
he's done some very strong working
in cosmology
reputation and so on
as well as that there was
i guess stated belief that there was some quantum effect was going on inside the
was somewhere inside our bodies
in this quantum effect was explaining the fact that the intelligence making intelligence possible
two machine
and then do that
and sells chinese room
as a kind of thought experiment
this is pretty famous
what is well the philosopher and skeptic
with a human side
and two slits
web pages coming papers go
and some work
pencils worksheets
and the book of instructions
and human
you can read english
the instruction books written in english
and you imagine a bit of paper coming in through
this led the slide here
with an indecipherable symbols
for human takes the pipe with indecipherable symbols
that's really instruction book
and it follows all the instructions
and produces the paper to add more indecipherable symbols input from others slightly side and
disappears and in this process is repeated
human system simply saying that
following instructions in this book
taking input producing outputs
OK on the outside
there's a bunch of chinese
and they actually have conversation
with this machine
because they're putting in questions in chinese
and sensible answers in chinese coming out the other end
so the chinese on the outside
having a conversation telephone conversation
this change
on the inside him and just looking at the rule book
OK so the moral of this
experiment is the following that
it nineteen look from the outside
as if machines intelligent
clearly in this case it could possibly be intelligent
we look on the inside
the human doesn't understand china
nothing else in in
and inside the understands chinese and yet there is the appearance of this kind country
sensible conversation taking place
so that was cells
chinese room and provides
a lot of controversy so people now argue back-and-forth about whether this reasonable
learning and it's great part of the
of the algorithm we
plain fact
with this
the formulation of this optimisation problem
because you can you can
the main objective
function here
with the constraints is that you can exchange is you know that's not a musician
we can play with very different kind of of optimisation formulation and you
after keep in mind that we have to maximize the journey to magic
and we have
to keep
this margin
so high
because let's focus
so in fact what we do not usually do not transition problems
we are right support them as a minimisation problem
and what we want to do we want to maximize something which is one
but one over w w
and we are going to write seats without changing as sense of meaning of the
optimisation is minimized
is normal
w square
w and as the following constraint
OK so there is a small mistake here because i just keep some days so
so we have no more
and the sorry i've just forgotten to
so we have some function so when you want to optimize some problem
you're going to use language and formulation OK so if this is
what you're going to do is going to take your objective function
and you know you're going to the
you're all constraints
by adding them
we some some here and some
that evolution coefficient OK sorry for science
if you look at this we have this objective function and we have these constraints
what is should
usually the do doing optimisation you take these constraints you and then in the fall
falling from
he you take this one you put minus one
and you
you are going to work
to work
with the new formulation
this formulation is with w
so far as far as i wasn't coefficients so the exciting
if you
the goal is a legend coefficient is an interesting fact is to formulate the dual
and solves the optimisation problem
not guaranteed to permit w that according to permit
and then of course you will be able to come back to the formulation of
parliament w and
so in fact
this quantity
as to be minimized with respect to
w and b
and maximize with respect to the lagrangian coefficient
so what you can do if you want to just two
to get rid of the inquisition
w and b
you can start differentiating
this quantity
put in its equals to zero so often you'll get ready
and writing this equation is well by writing equation you will have
links between w one and five
and you can rewrite
for this formulation
on reason language and coefficient OK
so here
we have i
you have also some constraints and these constraints come from this differentiation of the gradient
and fine sense for the user value b
you can you can use the country condition also to get the value of
but just
look now it's problem
so maximisation problem
what you are here
you have your training data that appear on the
as a dot product
so this is a good find
in this problem of
map genetic matching
musicians will have
the formulation of the optimisation problems on in terms of
scalar products
this means that
when we use we want to use can edit it would be possible
so in fact if we use fuzzy equations set gives you the form of w
you will you we get the following
in fact the solution of this
the problem of optimisation problem of
musician credited mission is the function differing function
you will take this time
take this to be on
these conditions
so we get a lot of you do this in an awful areas
where were people
you know it's difficult to say hey
the cause
what we talk about what will be out at the moment
because see that good services new
it's actually only working with one where every works within
but that will you know about the model support as it gets bigger
splitting down into these groups within your
you have the biomedical community and high energy physics two big ones it's difficult to
judge numbers because the physics community are working as individuals
was about making will and have a portal
for example the support it being set up in glasgow
is common and
project in glasgow
has because they users don't want to have to handle certificates
i have
one certificate shared by different authentication that was negotiated negotiated so we can only see
one user working
yes it's very difficult to know was certainly i nothing on an individual basis will
come go physics is the dominant community
more communities like yourselves you the fact of the talking here recognizing
that could provide a great resource for
the money is going into communities are waking up to it physics has led it
but in physics as i say is no longer a science wing to the research
does that sort of answer
it's difficult to actually
put numbers on i can give you more
be on
that i have and then
well the NGS is
for jobs i mean obviously the
chemistry people are very keen on it for their protein folding stuff and
at the moment there are jobs show running on the national grid service works for
other people and sixty four hundred twenty eight no jobs and they could easily be
i wouldn't be surprised in fact if you just was more orientated that way anyway
because of people who because in injustice news
a lot of physics communities working cells in the old stuff as well
and access to resources
one of the the you can measure who's doing what
there is a monitoring occupancies within
e g
when the NGS and the moment they have taken much more simplistic viewpoint
they've said that
we don't have to worry yet
they have imposed the same tools so that they can start putting constraints on
if it becomes necessary in the future
but at the moment
it to provide the source
it uses more more the queueing system so
it's first-come first-served
and though it does a few good job is not to run for short time
it will run much you'll get to the topic you quicker
and within each is going to allow for
they have different cues we access
we may have different sources in different part in behind them
so you say well my job will take up to two hours
if it's over two hours it will be automatically killed goes inactive
was is twelve our human is a infinite q and that's how they resolve
that's so it's not a case of trading between organisations on that level
used by
the point is
if you notice that what it has when it's one of the k the communities
tend to be orientated but applications
so then so long as it every ten working on the same source software using
the same sort of resources i think
that is
the old based task two somebody's only using it
that is where we have this concept of the management and and it's their responsibility
to handle that
i think there is an interesting talk actually give them
a couple weeks ago chap from oxford working on project with
coming up with the ability to trade screensaver time between the departments in
the city
so you can actually look up credits and then he says you can have the
derivatives market in screensaver time
so you can buy your computing resources by allowing other people to use your resources
and that would actually very directly answer your
question he started to be such that we should i think be quite entertaining
for this is this is
because it
three as are
called the shrinkage estimator shrinking my browser little bit towards that particular solution
you can
not quite sure but
it at least this is the estimator that you will be getting
what you can also show is that this is exactly the regularized risk estimate if
you impose good penalty under normal on the natural parameters
so the idea is really strange things towards the origin
that works better
so it may be that the proof that james stein gave worked for two or
three dimensions so it's quite possible
but this is the basic idea
all the support vectors and gaussianprocess estimators actually do exactly this
but OK the optimisation problem looks all the more fancy so this is why
you would immediately recognise it
is an interesting connection between fisher scores
and exponential families
so if i have a member of the exponential family in the fisher score
it's just fall fix one st theta g theta
so in other words is the same to the version of for fix
and furthermore the fisher information
it just happens to be the second derivative of g if data
this gives rise to
well quite some work on information geometry
is now this
all implies the metric and all that
but the nice thing is that the efficiency of the estimator can be obtained directly
from will take the second derivative of the log partition function
and if you can get this
true covariance matrix explicitly
don't know the privatisation all that you can actually go for the outer product matrix
and will you have to sing to anyway
so what you get is kernel PCA
as a way of obtaining
an empirical estimate of the fisher information matrix
well which is another nice application of kernel PCA
and this is actually very it's a bit more interesting name priors and we so
far this is all really like
thirties forties textbook statistics
well maybe not the kind of peace and so on but in a way it's
really quite standing
problem with maximum likelihood estimation is that if we don't have enough doctor well parameter
estimates will be bad
remember the example of the dice even if i had to talk to the hundred
times i might not get very good list
so well what can we do as well we just use our prior knowledge
quite often we know where the solution should be
well one
way of setting this and that's just for computational convenience for instance is we set
the prior on theta we just assume that theta is somehow small that may be
much smarter ways of doing this through conjugate priors and so on but this is
one way of setting
well in this case
well what's the posterior distribution
well by bayes rule
we know
p of data
given x
it is
p of x given theta one
p of states
divided by
p of x
p x doesn't really occur anywhere in the most important thing
we can just drop this maker proportional
and then if i do that
i can just write up here if they given x
this this expression here
and then i could several knowledge to maximize
the posterior probability
rather than the likelihood
let's see what happens
the same data before
and i probably applied only very very weak prior because of what you can see
so the blue ones for reference all the maximum likelihood estimate
the red one so the maximum posterior systems
what you can see is that even though i didn't see a single four
actually why
max aposteriori
estimate of singapore is pushed up from zero to something like point of
o five
and those really extremes are reduced
just because it's not like in the same pose prior which assumes that all the
coefficients are pretty much
the same
i get more data
you can see that
well the posterior looks more like the maximum likelihood estimate
it just means that as i get more data
my estimate starts believing in the doctor more and more
and discount the prior
which is what it should
after all the prior is there to help in situations we don't have
but it it also shows you
is that well have probably chose my prior prior way to weekly
this after all is advice
and you should see pretty much a uniform distribution
the deviations so that have been looking at are actually
whatever your random number generator would do so there's no reason for me to assume
that this was truly biased
so here's an example of a prior
but actually products too weak
usually people worry about the opposite but maybe should always
now the top prize are conjugate priors
might be something that
you can read a lot about in statistics textbooks
and it's always a little bit of a mystery how people get there
so if you actually
the a big to the bottom of it so it's a very very simple concept
so the problem with the nobel prize in the posterior doesn't look
like the likelihood
that's bad for two reasons first of all you don't know the normalisation anymore
of gene expression
so gene expression its concentration of messenger RNA and it's tricky find since it's quite
simple for
forty four
plans for so for some
for some plants like you had and now for some very simple organisms but for
instance four miles that's all for your mind you it's really difficult to get the
formation and to make the
the technology works
in to get
time point time series in very short with a very short time interval
so in this case
you just take data which are static
and you
you taken organisms you give you
give it an input signal and you you went
and you look at at some instantaneous response at some point that is think it
is really to see the point
so sometimes could from but it's also possible point of interest is the case usage
data and there are a lot of paper
in fact the first paper about this subject
which are from two teams teams of the
daphne koller and the team of the everyman
and what they do
they learn parameter and structure of bayesian networks for this unit rock as a bayesian
tree so of course in this case you can't have looked
the new network
at least you can infer something
and give the first picture
of the network
but i'm going to to talk
is is about
inference of biological networks so it's not exactly so we're not going deep into deep
modelling of the system
we just want to get the structure
so why unsupervised way to do this is to say that is to say well
images that i have example
the input is a couple of genes for instance and the output
is zero or one
and i'm going to say that there is
and interaction between g one and g two
if this function is there is a response one
so it's kind of classification problem is that you can solve with any supervised methods
but of course you need to deal with a couple
of the
so as we may gene for support vector machines to be good at that but
also as it seems like you're not rational learning
and this was part of
recent work on the subject
so is another way to
to look at this problem
so you're going to say is that in fact you have
the partial known
network of interaction
and you want to complete it
so it's again supervised
you can see the problem as the problem of
metrics completion you have you have imagine symmetric such represents across and you want to
this is the work of sudan colleagues and you can see this is a supervised
inference of biological networks as the problem of supervised metric learning
this is what is done by their germination and colleagues in two thousand five and
it's a really nice way to deal with this data again it's really different from
city is a city in fact its unsupervised
you don't know
examples of our rules is insisting we make we assume that we have some examples
of our rules in the internet
and i'm going to talk about answer
which is which can be related to the this to once which is what which
slows us with this one that's quite big began and also point-of-view
the idea is we're going to solve the problem directly
i'm going to solve the problem
by doing first
prediction regression
in in out in an output space which is on the some cannot
of course can then be closely related to the network which is known
in fact that is the
so can then we are going to to use it space is the diffusion can
and it's again and which is able to describe the similarity between nodes in a
and we're going to do
be able to make a prediction
formal description
of some
forty five cents and we are going to
go into an output space on the efficient can
once we will be able to do that we're going to use this function
and we're going to use this function for a couple of the x x y
and z
user scalar product in this open space and make predictions
of the camera so in fact we are going to do
can learning in order
to predict the rules it's the ph is
so the edges will be predicted
once the value of the
i cannot predict it will be high
the ball high is that since that then some fresh
OK so i'm going to work
to explain this in day
so it turns out that this marginal probabilities
it's very hard to compute for
almost all models of interest
i'm not sure that you talked about
whether this
to compute this
probably has have been doing so
forced to do model selection i reaching we'll always need to compute this thing
and the idea is that the full model stations to prevent overfitting underfitting by finding
a model of right complexity class
two exploded and because his
because there's not marginal probabilities hard to compute
is expensive to compute
we we don't really want to do this too often
so so that's one inside there was
not about a few people including callousness and zoubin most recently i think not that
recently like it's about people before that collective high and revenue
is that
because we're integrating all of all parameters where we do this computation or when we
are being bayesian
we're not going to overfit anyway three because we integrated out of parameters
there's nothing to fit to all data so that we can really overfit
and if we can't really overfit then what
is that what is to prevent us from using a really large model
because we if we if we start with a really large model
then we want and the fit to data
and we want to overfit either because we're being bayesian myself
so that's kind of the the basic
the idea of why we might want to do
bayesian nonparametrics from this perspective
so what is nonparametric model
nonparametric models basically a
parametric model that's really liked so when the number of parameters
is it the infinite or increases with the data that we see
we can also think of it as
a model over and some some infinite dimensional function on measure space
so you've seen an example of this in the case of the girls process right
so sokol
place a prior distribution over all possible functions is given by a gaussian process
this is an infinite dimensional space infinite countably infinite an uncountably infinite
dimensional space race we needed to have a latent variable
for every input
after function
another way of thinking about what is an appropriate to model this is the family
of distributions
that is that in some large space so
that's in the sense that if you give me any
any other if you give me any distribution i can find a distribution in this
family that's as close as you want
two your distribution
j and
and so the idea is that with the parametric family when parameterizing it with a
finite number of parameters so we can think of
family of distributions as very low dimensional manifold in our
in in this large space of possible distributions and if you have a small that
if you have a low dimensional manifold you're not going to be able to
approximate any distribution to arbitrary accuracy accuracy
so with not from tree models we're dealing with a family of distributions there so
large that it can approximate any distribution to any arbitrary
so why move
we want to deal with non parametric models in bayesian theory of learning
so a
it's a really nice way of sidestepping model selection and averaging
is we can also think of it as
i have a broad class of priors that
it doesn't restrict
the model to a promontory
family so it can
in this sense allows the data the data to speak for itself right so if
you have lots of data then you get very close to the
distribution that
the underlying the data
i personally find
but if you want to
extract because you have to put a very big quantity of energy
the problems with the liquid drop is related to the fission fragment distributions
so as i told you
we could what was first developed two
the distribution
it's true
for the feature it's OK
but in fact there are many problems and for example as i told you knew
can only
produces symmetric fragments of the same fragment
seven different nations amongst members of number of protons and neutrons
an experiment that is not true at all
this is a very famous experiment results from people from geo site
in darmstadt in germany
you have the a fission fragment distributions from different actin uranium relevant i'm acting
and these are sufficient for distributions
so when you have here when people it means that the most probable from opposition
here correspond to two identical fragments
so symmetry fragment
but can be described the liquid drop
it you uses that for many many nuclei you have these two hand
distributions so and this most fragments correspond to a small fragments and everyone one
so this is what we call asymmetric fission
so from many nuclei and especially all the ones that are interesting for example for
four runs
they do have these asymmetric fission which cannot be reproduced
by these liquid drop model
so conclusions
the nucleus is not a liquid drop you have
structure effects that are
but appears and that can be important
so what
as i told you there are magic numbers so the magic nuclei
which magic
you can imagine proton neutron
and you have very stable nuclei which are doubly magic like led to eight
ten one hundred etcetera
so that's why there's a need for microscopic approaches you have to replace
the technique was drop by
something like this
where you have the nuclear
which are is quite nucleons and the interaction between the
so this is the way
microscopic approaches to do so they consider anything else in strong interactions
then you have two problems to major problems
the first one is quite general problem in the many body problem
whatever it is when you have and
which interactions
it's impossible to solve that problem
and particularly for large systems
so the same for us if we have to calculate the interaction
you see how many combination there are for example if there is only
two twenty four so we have to change
one by one and three but with three people forwards and then we have to
to symmetrize everything so it it's impossible to solve these equations of corporate set of
short linear equations
so from medical applications when the port
different magnetic field something like that it's the same problem so it's something really junior
so that means that you have to make some approximations
the approximation that we using nuclear physics some common two
all the different physics case
some are specified to make our
nuclear physics
second problem which is that case specific to nuclear physics in the nucleon nucleon interaction
we don't know precisely
and then you can only nucleon interactions
in need so it's not a free interaction you're in many cases you have the
medium and then we don't know how to derive that completely
from the first principal of QCD
so that is specific because you not only physics when you're dealing with electrons you
know the coulomb repulsion
even if it's difficult to treat
but you know the expression nuclear physics you don't know
so these two problems which seems to be the copyright are in fact that cooperate
to be sign theta this path length will be
such that
constructive interference will occur in phase radiation will be reflected as such
and this
is called regular
this is bragg's law it's the condition for constructive interference
condition for constructive interference in the crystal
and three o nine one in three online one we're going to do
three nine one we're going to neglect higher order
reflections on three nine when we neglect higher reflections so let's just put
the equals one so i should be and equals one so bragg three online one
will simply
lambda equal to the
sin theta
that's the bragg condition
suppose i have new
the system
and i find that i have
now adams here
let's say i go from a simple cubic
two body centered cubic
well in body centered cubic there atoms here
another in a different place relative to the board relative to
the horizontal there's a plane of atoms at this location so let's see what happens
in this case
in this case if i have a third comes in let's call rate three
and re three also is in phase with re one hundred two
this is the reflected ray three
i can define the additional path length of re three as
he f
and what we see is that
it turns out that the
do you
plus f
for n equals one this is going to be one half a wavelength
if a b plays b c is one wavelength this is one-half wavelength
and what that means is that the reflected
reflected three is perfectly out of things
perfectly out of phase
raise one and two
with one and two
so that means we're get destructive interference
we're gonna get destructive interference
and that means if we put in detector
if we parker detector right here we'll measure zero intensity
so we measure
intensity at that angle
now what i want to do so want want to generalize what we have observed
here want to generalize this analysis and if i generalize this analysis what i get
is that if i take the interference criterion
if i take the interference criterion
and i combine it with the crystal structure
i combine it with the crystal structure
what's that give me
it gives me the set of expected
the set of expected
in essence this is a fingerprint of the crystal structure
fingerprint of the crystal structure
it's not a fingerprint of the chemical identity
it doesn't say anything about identity
but any crystal structure
of this
description will give the reflections that the same set of angles
any crystal structure of this description will give no reflections
at the same set of angles
this for example will show you
what would happen in the case of
zero zero one
zero zero one we saw reflects zero zero one we saw reflects
in simple cubic
the given angle theta
o one
it does not reflect
does not reflect
body centered cubic
thing to
o or one because in
body centered cubic there are atoms in o o two
and adams n o o two
will be totally out of phase with
the reflection it's coming off of all one so we will see no reflection
at all one
and likewise with FCC FCC also has atoms at the midpoint on each face
it does not reflect in BCC
FCC both of them
so now i can start to distinguish
i can distinguish which are
which are now let's take a look at
some opportunity to
make sense of this
so here's here's just figure that i took from
one of the text is showing what i've drawn on the board
zoom through this
OK so now this is on the handout
this is the selection rules for reflection in cubic crystals
what has happened here is is that the geometric analysis
along these lines has been performed
taking into account the atom positions
and what we see
we see the simple cubic we get reflections at every
every index
body centered cubic
is not reflecting the one all
because we've shown already that the
reflection from two all at that angle is perfectly out of phase so the
computations have been done likewise FCC so this is indicating that you won't see
i want all reflection in
face centered cubic or
the chernoff bound
right this is an idea
that's used in in chernoff bounds and and district
appears in a lot of places all this thing this is an expectation of e
to the east times some some
OK that's the moment generating function
we have a random variable here my considering the expectation of e to the is
times random variable
OK who's
is not met
moment generating functions before
if you
of the birds this is this is
modular sometimes changes all plus transform so for the
other electrical engineers
among its in essentially the same the same as well plus transport
so what we're concerned with now i mean we can pull it either minus st
out we're concerned just with controlling the moment generating function of of this random variable
can we can express that as an expectation of this product have the eyes are
not independent
you know the the whole things inequality relies on independence of these things
we have something close to independence because of their
we have enough properties to to make things work by by conditioning appropriately like the
details of that but you know the whole game from now on is controlling
the moment generating function
of these other of this random variable
OK and it turns out
OK i condition on something appropriate
all right so if we have a mean zero random variable lies in our a
bounded range right this is her things inequality
OK think first prove something of this form may be with the
what i think you got a different constant
and that was
now actually editing and improving the concert so
you can show the moment generating function of bounded random variable is is bounded in
terms of
this either a square
kind of quantity
OK and
it's the bounded the differences property
lets us
but let's argue that know the appropriate random variables here abound
OK so so now we get available on now
moment generating function in terms of the
the variable x squared and in terms of the sum of the differences square
and we just play with the variable as to to come up with to come
up with the bound on the probability that we get the deviations and that's that's
the that's make demands inequality right that the probability the deviation between g expectation being
larger is bounded by
decreasing exponentially in two script
right so we get some sort of something that looks like a gas entail
right provided that the
the random variable g has this is bounded differences property
OK so that's
that's where make demons inequality comes from
this idea of
the moment generating function
the other
bounded random variable is something that that we'll meet again
OK so we're only
so that's my demons inequality
just remind you a headed for
for this
this result
alright tells us that
expectations are not much bigger than sample averages
so far we've got that the supremum
the class of the deviations is close to the expectation of that thing
right you know a little bit extra
because of this
the arises from victims inequality so now we just want to control the expectation of
this thing
all right so
and this is where the rademacher averages pop up in a very natural way
right so these
these things
very close to the
rademacher averages
right song writer
a string of inequalities and this is really nothing nothing hard you
was in a big problem
of the other corner
a whole bunch of edges
a whole bunch of possible entering variables all bunch of X is that willing to
work and
simplex act and some of those will mean higher costs so we will grow those
and some will be lower costs so I will pick out
which 1 which way to go which Newell X should enter
and then have to go along the edge until
come to that corner
for the next corner and then I do it again so that's the that's the
repeatedly your a corner
you test directions
you travel along the direction where the like steepest descent the cost goes down fastest
step along the edge and then you get to the next corner and you do
it again
that the picture of
how do you know that did not just a local minimum very good question it's
it's because of this linearity it's uh it's picked from these linear equations and linear
constraints you can't
can't get in
but to and similarly if I had this quadratic 1 and was positive definite I
could get track but absolutely local minima and so on
you know a big challenge and then minimization problems in general you give me a
function of cost function so you most cost functions are linear
you give me a cost function f
hundred variables so that you love me to play with and how long have you
minimize function of a hundred variables boy that's the that's the resolution of the question
if that function
then know so if a function is shaped like this maybe with wiggles but still
convex then you know there is only 1 minimum
and problem much easier if the function is quite general it have looked like a
golf course it's graph is some surface with ups and downs of ups and downs
then when you find a local minimum
you can just look around in a local minimum
because everything
works upward
at some other point
there's a whether is thing much further down and and a whole lot of ideas
are going to this
subject and I guess there are a lot more to come
you somehow have 2 jobs that
that possible local minimum you know enough to get out of the little well and
on with the job
but to
how much do you
and you don't want to spend all your time worrying about this you won't find
that local minimum in the 1st place it's best
OK 1 comment here and I not
wasn't planning and and don't have time to develop interior point methods but just so
you could guess what that means that means that we we travel in the interior
we find a point so Interior Interior interior of the feasible set
find someplace that solve the equation
don't worry about the number of zeros and non-zeros this this had to do with
finer points
find direction is better traveling
decide when to stop
and probably stopped short of the boundary
then you're still inside calculus still operates so to speak
look around and find another point travel for a while playing point and eventually
infinitely many steps
reach the way I mean because you're always stopping short but getting closer and closer
that of course in reality we
are happy together with internal minus
something of the winter and and that's OK too
so that's that's iterative and this is
a finite number
can't take well we know it's fine of dying thing has only a finite number
of corners
when the number of edges in nanokernel backwards on an edge because as we saw
forward if we went forward on unintelligible was because it improve the cost
reduce the cost and will never traveled backward on that so it's going be finite
but the number of edges is exponentially large parameter and so there's a big amid
the big the theory of the simplex method is
doesn't actually take exponentially long
as mn increases or
be done in polynomial time
this is the 1 of the the most important problem problem where it was quite
unclear even the experts whether
it whether it can be done in polynomial time
media power of eminent
or whether they're not whether it grows like the number of corners which is
M choose them and grows exponentially
well peers the incident quick report on that
the simplex method can
really worked up cases
take exponentially long
so if I described this implies that the clear straightforward simplex method also it's average
cost that is used all the time so of course it doesn't take exponentially long
hours we would use it but
it's worse in in in extreme example could be exponential
we we could travel along an exponential number of edges before we finally settled on
the web
and you see because traveling on edges the court that the cost the computing causes
is the same however along the edge
so anyway
but that but average costs are polynomial so a lot of people and the guy
at MIT is looking at this problem again and found another way of describing an
average costs and the
showing that that's polynomial and then there is a polynomial
so this may a huge range of things you can do and that's that
the nice thing about machine learning and it's also nice that you're not alone like
you're even if you you in the next or in the case of the practice
we can also talk about london
if you still have something like according to
so is
so it's so a single reason to to research in machine learning is really fun
but some like it also can be very hard and i think it's something which
might be
what people already said like the pressure to publish papers and thank you for that
you have like two years contract for the next ten years of life for the
and there's something which
i mean you need to know that before i mean if you want to go
research in machine learning about this future
you need to be prepared to
to be able to
just very often to to
well under pressure
that's nonsense
there were times when it was something like
and what you saying that
very different here
think that we're talking all
what would be the frontier between
machine learning and engineering
it's a question i don't know exactly where to put it
is it
you're doing machine learning
finding application with is visiting it's also machine learning that it's going
what's more that analyses which is the engineer john
what is the the limit between being a researcher and being in charge
these questions and then it's interesting
this is what you meant
you know
so what you need
i might have so
i mean that's exciting thing of machine learning that the people for a few you
were only there
implementing or making happen i get something about how
things were not so
we have
you know people have titles as in
or you see
that's why
one of the one of the sort of
tags can
how on your teacher is
research software development engineer
or are st
so our is the is an engineers are mentioning and he works together with researchers
but it he or she doesn't really developed
new algorithms all that much more sort tries to understand the behaviour of the family
about was very thing that is the person that's really really good at coding
and it has enough understanding of machine learning
just enough to be able to talk to machine learning research to just implement the
although we have these guys going around the useful
i really think that as someone who works in machine learning you must be able
to some to some degree you must be able to do a bit of engineering
there might be exceptions might people who were very much as well it was saying
on the more mathematical form there is sort of the of border of of
of machine learning there almost that's pure mathematics everything that
in the way a machine learning is something of a patchwork of
although of different things and some people might have more engineering science and much more
definitely bit
there exist
something about the work
because of the because it's interesting it's there are some similar work
i wish to point where i decided that i never called
my customers
because i'm not a programmer
in my skills program
the next morning solve the problems
and so i consider myself very much you
but not sovereignty
when it comes to new problem because because
with experimental design because they everything i before
you know
if you have a choice between hiring a couple of experts collecting data states going
to cost two
four thousand dollars thousand euros per year for machine learning because they say
and it's hard to describe the money that much money
you could probably
connect home data
go from the data
more than ten years
but this incorrect and should know
how to quickly update
i can use of interest
design not that expert experiment design because the statistics is covered with two experimental design
extensive however if you find a statistic books from
the only
two of these n experiments in practice
in practice so many constraints
that the usual experimental plants that you
don't apply
so there's a lot of engineering that goes into this
not all of these
actually most of know
it helps to have a map
you have to draw the map you need to know where you are
typically the way we have a model that is used to represent this
is something that
and i'm going to assume that the maps then map such
but often that's not complicates things
you might have
the map in this case is the variable try to to learn and there's different
parameterizations from the grid
could be based on landmarks
you know
you remember that
three of the cell phone
kangaroo corner and so on and
so i think the features you learn to navigate
there is also the location
your location which is a in x
three d there
and from that you get some observations
and then the next time step
my changes location changes
and you get another rash
and these guys
you location depends on where you are in the math
the observation that you get depends
on your location and the map
and so on
so you get this type of system where you have to bear
and we're going to look at the efficient ways of solving these
first i'm going to give you a demo work
what happens in practice
these things
so here is an example
what i'm showing you here
a robot guy over there
the green so the map is this thing this room with dark indicates the worldwide
is empty space
the green indicates observations so this guy sort has
so said to be get people back knows with the wall is
with respect to itself
and this observation usually noisy
the blue
indicates the probability of where
these two things
he is right now
in particular
when we start
it has no easily taking a few measurements
he believes it could be in any of these cells
OK so the map is
now this type of distribution
i mean the main point here being that if you have the samples
by having the samples you can truly account for multimodality
and four
all these problems that arise in practice
mainly due to symmetry
but when you get here
it's already got a pretty good estimate of twenty years
but unfortunately because there's this symmetry this daughters looks like this the or
you could be here or here
because of the nature of the world
the distribution of the u i truly by model
and some of the comments like one these sort of things happen when you have
but the model distributions and obviously just using gauss and would not be at the
he doesn't know that he started off in the left corner doesn't always start
but he doesn't know that
i think about it
that in this case
the guy has really not in this market doesn't always start
everything is relative
in this case actually in this case it does not the maps sorry no you're
right action
in the general case it doesn't matter that that would be the case
as things progress
while i
the learned
and this is of course projects of my students that's why
robertson looked like it had to do this with a week
here's another one that basically no learning the
as the navigates
and then there is the real robot assists
the first stuff
and make it look a bit more impressive than with my students
this is courtesy of the passenger and stanford
actually that's how much of this problem as opposed to just showing some
i mean the observations
she should the demonstration of articles and so
but in those are the kind of capabilities that is going to happen place
when they actually do
so we started with this yesterday
we have samples x
these locations and i'm doing the one d case
in all
of service
we then are going to propagate the samples that i'm ecosystem
we start with the sample
x y
i produce
one thousand
you will be blocked
but it wasn't until i
a lot because we that
and by
which includes
if i have some more in addition to that because there is no violence
it would grow
for a given t
all right because she
simply because she but just to show you another effect of the infinite divine i
told you that you can
simulate cushy using and all
but i accept reject we can pretend to do it by importance sampling again you
so from a normal zero one
and use the weight
off because she did you take their it shows the distribution of the cushy of
decision normal
and the weight will be the same shape that an exponential
although one suspects square
OK and because of the exponential
the expectation of the square
weight is infinite
and if you have infinite violence is tumor
and i run another experiment
for estimating the expectation of the exponential sex
because she
ten thousand
to ten thousand normal simulations zero one and you can see
o five application days
not at all
this nice central limit theorems
decrees of the range but you go along iterations
no more
OK this is a very large weights so the range
he just exploded
i got a very large weight of about forty four thousand eight hundred iterations
and and this is where it is so huge that it just doesn't diminish the
range of to
and this kind of totally
we have your
it typical
of infinite violence
this two meters
the connection with the project which is that if you don't
four which have g
is bounded
they may be problems and if you use it for enough
functions h then there will be problems
now let's see what the point of using it was something when you could do
instead accept project and get real simulations not
simulation from the function one the point that
you may have f of g which is bounded
but the bound may be so
that in terms of simulation
it's not a practical because if if m
is ten thousand it means that you have to run ten thousand iterations simulations to
produce one
o point for your target distribution
so in terms of of recycling of simulations images bounded may not imply
that exit project is the right choice
now is the best choice of dual there is
optimality theory which is the following one that you can find the best possible chance
of g
in principle
it is actually
the function g stuff that is proportional to absolute value of h
times have any pages positive this gives you a zero balance this tumor
so just use one simulations
you get the right i no violence
of course the
fall because simulating from this function
is usually to totally
in fact because
remark that if h is positive to see from this function and use it in
the in the importance weight you need to know
the integral you're trying to approximate
OK so it's like a vicious circle
issues useless
you can try to make this result to produce better results than do that
to choose the right j
you should be close to age the particularly one example
of application of this is is that if h is zero
do you think should be zero so if you are trying to approximate integral over
this region is useless less to simulate outside this region
like if you want to approximate interval between two and three
if you knew the distribution which have the support larger than the interval
two three
one one one you've saying that there is another thing that again
we facing the problem of the normalizing constant
we're missing the right
constant either
in an orangey for trained to mimic the optimal choice of g
but we can get out of that very quickly but
approximating the
the numerator and the denominator integral
well there's is the senior professors and they behave one way and junior professors are
and the graduate students or something like that and that choice of where you do
that is important
OK so
the next thing we want to talk about his inference imperial arms and inference in
one thing you can do is
just like with the rule base case
instantiate the business and then
the reasoning over it so
this is an example i'm going to use
i have
simple skeleton where one of their two papers for reviewers and i'm interested in whether
or not
a one is a good writer given that i find out that two other papers
have been accepted
i get this big business and i do inference and such
hopefully we can do something a little bit better than that
what we want to do is we want to
make use of the object structure hopefully that's going to help be helpful is not
guaranteed to be helpful but
ideally it will be and
use that to reason about encapsulation
the probabilistic dependencies and then do some sort of caching so that you can we
use computations wherever possible
and that's the idea behind
obviously first work on structured variable elimination gonna go through kind of an example of
first of
we're going to be defined for any
object the set of variables for ten to the
the object so if i look at for example reviewer two
OK there's
the attributes of
that object itself but then will also
i worry about that
things that it depends on
it depends on
good writer attributed author one and
the interface
two and j is going to be
the set
attributes those are attributes
the stuff in that object depends on and exported attributes the stuff that other things
depend on so for any object can go through and define OK these are the
subset of those attributes that are either imported or exported
and we're going to use this to
keep track
what is encapsulated
with and
and object so
if i look
interface for
p one
this is
the interface
objects are encapsulated in p one
if there is no
kind outside
except through this interface
in a lot of ways
you know if you're used to cutset conditioning and bayes nets it's a form of
finding useful cuts in the bayes net that kind of
can be used to factor in the bayes net during inference
we're going to
use encapsulation together with three use to do inference efficiently
the idea here
we started off
and we know
we're interested in a one
being a good writer
right now we have these two
objects that are encapsulated
a one
to do inference all have two
focus on one of these and
i'll go ahead and look now
paper one
i'm trying to
get out
distribution over the cuts
and so still all the blue stuff i have
i figured out yet so i'll go and and
compute say
the information i need for inference for review two
so reviewer two
this again is interface
at this point
everything's groundouts
i can
perform inference two
get a distribution over
good writer
so i do that
and now i come back to the place i was
i have my distribution over the interface here
and now i need to go here
and do that
in fact
when i go
do the appropriate marginalization this here
now i can go here
now at this point it turns out the review one
looks exactly the same as
future did
i need to compute exactly
the same
distribution so
i don't have to actually do inference here i can just take the cash result
that i have here
and inserted here
at this point
i go through and do inference i have to add in
the fact that i have the evidence
that p
one was accepted
i can get
distribution of the interface for
paper one
and i inserted back into the bigger
friends that i was dealing
at this point
i can go to
paper p two
the same structure as paper p one had
has the same evidence so
i can just reuse that computations
and then finally compute
distribution over a one being a good writer
so that's the idea that i first stuff
reason about what
interfaces between sets of objects then i have a good way of cashing in looking
at any time i need to compute the distribution over the that interface i look
and see
there are a computer that and i don't have to do it again and this
the same
a lot of work in doing inference and partly it's because
and all the
he played
and he
you know
are the whole
and you can
can improve results
he might be
all of information
right well i should know
we want to the
thank you
so all
the station is one
well i
you know why
the people
and if
you should
he was
it is
unification based on
in this case
instead of money using
almost all of
the next year or
the proof
o c
it was part of the
OK so
thank you
and none
may be
i mean i think
the result of the
you can't and i use every day
and this how we make lots of money in his picture might of my because
on so my friends he said he said well this great graphic in machine learning
so is actually useful so still was you know you know is that which is
the pressure was that the
the PCA was the bayesian networks what the level so helpful and since it was
then that that
for those of you that i don't know matlab i hope to do that it
is not hard on and what actually have a short matlab tutorial in one of
the discussion sections on for those who don't know
the very last piece of logistical thing is the discussion sections so discussion sections will
be taught by the TAS and attends the discussion sections is optional although that there
also be recorded and televised
and we use the discussion section is mainly the two things on for the next
two or three weeks we use the discussion section sick over the prerequisites on today's
castle some we haven't seen the probability or statistics for a while then the algebra
o look over those in the discussion sections as a refresher for those who don't
want one of the ten this quarter also use the discussion section has to go
over extensions to the material that i'm teaching the main lectures so machine learning is
a huge field under a few extensions that we really want to teach but didn't
have time in the mean that just for on so they did this quarter we
use the discussion section to talk about things like convex optimization on to talk about
the about hidden markov models which is a type of machine learning algorithm for modelling
time series in the field of things of extensions the materials that i'll be covering
in the main lectures on and attendance at that discussion sections option
that was all i had on
from the just states on
the final move on to start talking about about machine learning let me check what
questions you
so also has been that you welcome to use are but on i would strongly
advise against the mean because in the last problems which is apply some code that
will run in matlab octave but that would be somewhat difficult three to translate that
there will be some people who transition to our yourself
so for any assignment awesomest solution are that's fine but i i think that was
actually tell you what learning i i i actually i know are matlab and i
personally and using matlab
quite a bit more of the variance
so the the temperature you welcome to do to smaller groups of three you're welcome
to do it by itself or in groups of two of grading is the same
regardless of the group size so for large you
sorry i i recommend trying to form a team was actually certified to do the
smaller group if you want
c programming in this class other than any that you choose to do yourself in
your project on so that all the whole works can be done in matlab octave
and on
c and against the current prerequisites is more the ability to understand big o notation
and this and knowledge of what data structure like the link research you were our
values on most knowledge your job specifically
and in
but what exactly the testing of the methodology
the problem is that later led me on in a couple of weeks actually give
other hand out with some of guidelines for the problem
but for now i was thinking the goal as being to do on a cool
piece of machine learning where they will that you experience the joys of machine learning
first-hand on and we can try to think about in a published book is work
on so many cities we try to build a cool machine learning applications this for
the most common project on substance to try to develop we try to improve state
of the art machine learning something to some of those projects are also very successful
so hard to do and there's also a smaller minority is still sometimes try to
prove the developed the theory of machine learning for that try to prove theorems about
machine learning
so there there are usually great project all those types of web applications in machine
learning being the most common
if not
the court
that was the logistics on
let's talk about
the album
so can i have the laptop display
actually could you know the big screen