two maybe there's something in one can you know go to the next one you
know do something then come back
and also of course
we need machine learning algorithms that are efficient because you know it's pretty clear this
is that the way you can actually of the state and be able to handle
it has to go through
machine learning approach
in essence what i'm going to do here is to propose an example of this
and the example is this language called markov logic
here's the one slide summary of what markov logic is right so if you fall
asleep after this you still haven't you noticed that the main idea of the talk
markov logic is a language that unifies first order logic
and probabilistic graphical models
which i believe is is a good way to try to achieve these goals because
first of the logic handles structured information right knowledge bases that first order logic and
things like that log
really special cases of first order logic probability handles unstructured information
the noise the uncertainty inherent in text and you know semi structured sources and it
doesn't just them together it really truly i hope i will say that markov logic
really does unified the two
there is no separation between the logic and the probability and the structure unstructured and
in my
logic anymore because so
if you get to this from of mine that you don't have to worry about
you know well the structured here and there is an structure over there any more
than just think think of it all in a in a uniform way
it does of course a lot on previous work ongoing and not really going to
lock in the interests of time but i would just like to mention that here
it builds on ideas that go as far back as the early nineties and something
called knowledge based model construction where he was taken knowledge base and it's you know
extract vision was from things like probabilistic relational models and so forth but compared to
the previous work i think there's an important difference which is markov logic really is
the first practical language as opposed to just a theoretical proposal
that actually comes with real efficient learning and inference algorithms and the complete open source
implementation of them they can actually use today
so as far as i know
at this point marco was is really the only language that does this but you
know i expect that the more will appear in the future
OK so
he is the one slide summary of markov logic and what i'm going to talk
about today
the syntax of markov logic
right so what is this language markov logic syntax is very very simple syntax is
formulas in first order logic no difference from before one addition we going have to
wait for the formula
the semantics as all see is that we're going to interpret these formulas as templates
for constructing graphical models
in particular for the features of my networks
so markov logic sets up to be probabilistic graphical model markov you know knowledge base
markov logic and then we're gonna system inference algorithms which not surprisingly combine ideas from
logic and probability
including things like satisfiability testing markov chain monte carlo knowledge base model construction and so
and similarly learning is going to combine ideas from the logic and from the statistical
things like the perceptron pseudo likelihood inductive logic programming programming and so on
and as i said this is all available in the alchemy software package that's what
it's called an output up your own opinion
and it's been used already for a wide array of information and knowledge management applications
like information extraction web mining social networks ontology refinement personal systems et cetera the best
paper award that's you can last year was for that apply markov logic to do
ontology learning
so you know we will see more interesting examples of successes of markov logic
so let me in the interests of fairness now walk over to the side of
let's start with a little bit of background and you know most of you are
probably familiar with at least some of this background but just to get us on
the same page and it's going to be very briefly covers two things
markov networks and first order logic
many of you are probably at least passing familiar with bayesian networks markov networks might
be slightly less ability still images briefly introduced and here a markov network is an
undirected graphical models
so it models the joint distribution of the set of variables
so for example here's four billion barrels smoking cancer asthma and cough
and the markov network has two parts one is the graph and the other one
is the parameters again like vision network except that its undirected and not between two
variables means that they are directly dependent on each other
and conversely if i take out the arcs that are adjacent to an art
that makes it independent of the rest of the network can
so the structure of the network gives you the conditional independencies between variables
now the parameters are defined as follows for every clique in the graph and here
there's cliques smoking cancer and cancer asthma cough
we're going to define the potential function
and the potential function is just a real valued function
of the state
so for example
real valued nonnegative function of the state so for example for smoking cancer click there's
obviously four states in his about the potential function for each one of them
and the way compute the probability of the state is just going to each clique
you see what's the same you get the corresponding value of the potential function and
you multiply them all
and then of course you have to normalized by the sum of the several states
to make sure that it's illegal probability
now this is all very nice but there's actually a problem here which is this
only works
in terms of scalability if cliques are small
but if you have a large clique i have to do a large number states
and things fall apart fortunately there something else that we can do
which is something that is very popular with statisticians which is to represent the markov
network in the form of what's called the log linear models
a linear model
is just the normalized exponentiated is over teachers
and you can convert from one to the other because the product of potential if
you take lot becomes the sum of things
so in the simplest case i can just have one feature for every possible state
of every click
and the way it is the logo of the corresponding potential right so i can
convert from potential function
four to log linear form very easily
but of course the the the the thing that we gain here is that
i don't have to have one feature for every possible state
i could have a very very large clique relating many things
so what we can say is that if c is a maximal clique
then for all
outside scene
the the number of edges
scholars this with the number of edges
between shame
and an arbitrary line
where i is a member of c
must be less than three months less than or equal can start less
otherwise cannot be max
it strictly maximal clique
this i mean
the number of edges start from any outside external graphics incident two
the the vertices inside
must be
strictly less than the cardinality of c minor
the reason for having strictly maximal cliques is that
maximal cliques in one sense are unstable
in the sense that
if i i for example
take this click here
and i dropped the vertex and they had this verdict than this
it's not the maximum degree
it's unstable or the reported in the sense that they can just take one vertex
in the maximum clique throw it away
at the external and then they get the new mexico
while strictly maximal clique more stable since no external vendors
so external that
is a sufficient number of edges incident to the
internal vertices
so can just take one of these
so we would have one
so it's in one sense and more stable this is a distinction which reflected
the structure of
local optima we have we have an optimisation problem continuous optimisation problems for example
you might have
strict local optima and local optima which are not strict
and we shall see later on the actually there is a one-to-one correspondence between
the notion of a strictly maximum weight and the notion of the max
now it's clear that when
we are just have binary similarities
the notion of the maximum clique is exactly the notion we're looking for
the notion of a cluster coincide with no inside the notion of the maximum clique
is satisfied
both internal and external
so now the question is how can we generalize the notion of the maximal clique
two edge weighted graphs and this is where the concept count
it each
yeah so you might might have several so the maximum
OK so
now our objective is
to generalize the notion of a maximal clique which
OK let's wait let let's take
an edge weighted graphs let's take a set of what is this as
let's take a vertex that belongs to us all
this situation
set s
of is vertex i
we we picture
OK so in this set there are other viruses probably
just some of the similarities between i and all the bodies inside
and get what we call the average weighted degree
all i with respect to s
so that's something
which is the sum over all age a
which it belongs to us is just sort of average similarity
average wages similarity between i and the other objects
in c in in s
now we derive a notion of relative similarity between two objects i and j
i remember that
AIJ elements of the metrics similarity metrics
AJ represents an absolute similarity between two
now we
we introduce the notion of the relative similarity
we are in this situation is here to
OK let's in this way
we have
set s
we have a vertex change
and the vertex inside as she outside US
so the number to derive here is the the absolute similarity between i and j
o introduced by as i j
is just the difference between
the actual similarity between i and j
and the average similarity between i and all the objects in
so this is very simple notion i just comparing the similarity
by and j with respect to
i similar to the other objects and j of course
this phi can be negative or positive is positive when the absolute similarity between i
and j
is greater than the relative itself and this negative
now comes the main definition which allows us to to
define the notion of common sense
it's actually looks quite complicated but it's quite simple
it's a recursive definition
let's consider a subset of this as
let's take verdicts i belong to us
OK so the recursive definition is actually allows us to assign to each vertex
this allows us to assign to each vertex in s a weight remember that we
have an edge weighted graphs in this way we are
we're signing
weight the vertices but with respect to s
so we have a set as we have vertex i and then if the set
s is a singleton then my definition WSI i
it's one might think
otherwise if i have more than one object in the in the set
what i do was just the following and just summing all the relative similarities these
between i and all the remaining in s
but this is not just plain so i'm just waiting this is the weighted average
action i'm waiting it's
these are relative similarities with the weight assigned to j
training data putting in to your solution vectors some parts
of the some component which is orthogonal to the space spend
by the training data would appear a very you know it would play no role because it would have a zero in a product
with all of the training data so this extra component
that will be orthogonal to the span of the training data
would have no effect and since we have that regularization
term which is trying to minimize the norm you would
immediately throw that component away and get a lower
optimisation of your your objective here because throwing that component away would have no effect on
this because it would have no effect on these inner
products the component is orthogonal to the span of the training data
so would have no effect on this but it would reduce this
because you've actually projected the data the the weight vector down into a into a
smaller vector in this space spend by the training data so it's clear you know if you think about it that way that the the weight vector will be in the span of the
of the training data therefore it will be expressible in this form that
I've put here and indeed this just verifies that fact but also
explicitly computes the form of that alpha would
actually be of this form all okay so this is the so-called dual
representation now it's a slightly at odds with the
optimisation theory where you have primal and dual sometimes they coincide sometimes they don't exactly in
support vector machines there's a very nice coincidence between
the primal and dual of representation that I've referred to here and the primal and dual in
optimisation theory but I think if we are being honest we need
to just say this is our terminology that we use in
kernel methods and it's loosely borrowed from optimisation
theory but doesn't always exactly accord with optimisation theory so think of it as just a way of representing your your solution vector in terms of the training data and
now what we want to do is not try and learn the W but try and
learn alpha so we've got a re sort of jigging at the
problem we now rather than try and learn W we try and learn alpha so
sort of implicitly learning W through learning its dual representation okay well let's try and do that in this case here's
our alpha here is an equation for it but unfortunately it involves
W so we're not gonna get alpha out of this equation
because it's sort of a recursive but what we can do is just substitute for this W what we know it can be expressed as in terms of
alpha so we're just gonna substitute X primed alpha in
here and we'll now have an equation involving only alpha so
that's what we do here and this is the equation that you get lambda alpha
equals Y minus X primed X X primed alfa okay so that's just multiplied by this lambda
Y minus X X primed alpha so it just subsitute that in there okay so now
rearranging terms we've now got the following equation
it looks very similar to what we had for the primal
solution but actually in some respects it's even simpler because now
on the right hand side we just Y whereas before we had X
prime Y on the right hand side here and this term
here was X primed X plus lambda rhi in the equation for alpha is X X prime so the order of
these two has swapped and we've got rid of this X primed on the right
hand side in in this equation here right so it's X X
primed plus lambda rhi of course the dimension now is
different the X primed X had dimension equal to the
feature space dimension because of course the
weight vector had has dimension equal to the feature space dimension
and so the identity matrix also have the same dimension
that we had it but in this case alpha has dimension equal
to the number of training points remember there was one alpha
i have a huge investment into any offspring
i'm not investment in the sense of hard work and effort but there is that
investment in the sense that when you're when your
and just when you have e
when you're pregnant with one offspring you can have another
what this does is it has ramifications percolate upwards
in the to different psychologies
males as single market for several females forcing some males to the main list and
giving rise
the competition
to see who can the most females
for females
however females can always find mates
so sheer numbers don't count
this competition to may with the right males
those is offering has the best chance
of surviving
the competition
now explain suppose we started with it explains why males are typically larger
and often why males have evolved special weapons
the special weapons of all fighting other males for reproductive access
it also explain something else
females biologically are choosy
so males have to compete not merely of other males two
two two to get reproductive access but also to woo females
so often males have all special displays
like this
which existed only
to be beautiful
only to be attractive and to attract mates this called evolutionary logic was captured in
this cartoon
really does sum up a hundred years of mate selection research
the logic
it goes like this then
the difference in the size of sex cells leads to differences in typical parental investment
leading the differences in the sort of psychological and physiological mechanisms that of all OK
that's a good story
what sort of evidence is there for it
well it turns out this could explain some otherwise surprising things
for instance
there should be there are some cases where the parental investment to switch
in some cases where it turns out when males and with more investment than the
and the and the theory predicts
that in these cases you should get an asymmetry
in cases like fish for instance the male takes the eggs
in two appel
and plug them into his bloodstream
the females should they have less investment in the males
in this case
you would predict as is true
the females should be larger
the females by
other females more than males but males and the females try to compete for the
attention of the males
the movie march of the penguins
we saw a clip from it
and this was in the context of discussing the emotions that have evolved towards their
offspring but remember the story and how both the male and female have to go
to tremendous lengths
to protect the eggs
and if one of them fails they dies and neither one has
you should then not even have to remember
whether male females are much bigger
and female penguins
you should realize they should not be in fact they are
they're about the same size
because the parental investment is equal
you should be able to predict the size differences in aggression differences based on differing
parental investment
so for instance
elephant seals
are four times the males are enormous there four times bigger than the females
and this is in large part because elephant seals compete for herons the females
is the winner-take-all
given names are about the same size
this is because gibbons are pretty monogamous to raise children together
this illustrates something which is is not always the case
that male parental investment
there are some species including gibbons
where is in the male's reproductive advantage to care for offspring imagine a situation for
instance where an offspring would die
if both parents didn't want to for many years
and where
devoted offspring had to be exclusive if you focus on another family or went away
offering with died in that case you have equal investment
it wouldn't matter equally to male and female to invest in offspring and the cost
would be the same
there's no species is hard to the species that had that
much of an ecosystem but some primates are close to it
and this raises the question then
what about humans what about us
what do we know
about the differences between males and females
are relatively polygamous species
most cultures most human cultures are are polygamous
american culture is what they call serial monogamy
so we're not like some species of birds we domain for life we do a
series of pair bonding
for some period of time it could be for life but it need not be
in usually isn't
males are bigger in females
human males the size estimates vary so much but the average human males fifteen percent
larger on average human female this suggests that there are some may has been in
our evolutionary history some male male competition
for access to females
which suggests in turn that parental investment is not quite equal
males have smaller testicles for their body size
then chimpanzees but larger testicles
gorillas and gibbons
and this suggested there was some intermediate amount of competition
the capacity to create space
and this is relevant for different sort of competition with regards impregnation of females multiple
and this suggests that over evolutionary history women were not wantonly promiscuous but we're not
entirely monogamous either so much so that the pavement evolutionary point of view
you do all males throughout the capacity to to produce more sperm than other males
as i said the idea is to work with something
much more rich than the dictionary what you would like a is to put in
your dictionary any features that may be useful to do your classification and potentially the
dictionary they become you wish so as a result you get very large and redundant
dictionary of of and then the question you mask is of course the same
how can i approximates f by picking the best elements from detection
and very quickly of course you realize that this is an NP complete problem it's
very closely related for example by the three set covering problem so you need to
approximate is NP complete problem with some computational leave feasible solution
one approach which is the simplest which is classical when you have an NP complete
problem is to
use greedy approach so that's the idea of the matching pursuit algorithms the basic idea
is instead of picking globally the vectors you pick them one by one and which
will be the best vector you pick the one that absorbs the maximum amount of
energy from the signal you take it out to get the residue what's the next
second vector the one that will absorb the maximum energy from the residue you pick
it out and so on and you iterate and it does indeed converge but potentially
extremely slow
now there is a second approach
that was introduced by and chan is this idea to say well what you are
optimizing in some sense the number of elements the number of elements of decomposition vector
this is the else zero norm let's replies
this l zero norm which is non convex by the closest lp norm which is
convex and you get the l one norm
and you end up with this
minimisation which is weighted by the l one norm and you can indeed out of
that extracts a sparse representation if such a representation does exist
OK so let me now
go to
inverse problems
so in an inverse problem what you have is your data u
and what you'd like to recover is the signal that has been degraded by an
operator you
which is typically not invertible
plus some noise and your data d let's say belongs to
a space of dimension q so you have to data
and if you're doing resolution what you'd like is not only to estimate if but
you'd like to estimate f at a higher resolution than the input resolution in other
words would like to estimate f in a space of dimension n
which is the larger of dimension mentioned in the space of the which is larger
has the dimension sorry larger than the dimension of the input data so basically you'd
like to increase the resolution
this is a very fundamental problem in many application domains so for example satellite satellite
data are blurred often because the satellites moves because also the imperfection of the optics
so you'd like of course is the convolution and potentially increase the resolution this are
major industrial issues the second example i'm going on the right are cystic sparse spike
deconvolution so insisting data you have to inverts the wave equation and you'd like to
get very sparse representation providing you the geophysical layers that are the most meaningful elements
for the analysis by the geophysicist of the data
OK now i would like also to speak so these two problems we worked on
them as i said initially when we began to do start up and then we
realized that we were not going to survive by working on this kind of professional
data so we decided to go for
consumer product much larger market and the idea was sent only to realize while the
high-definition television around i don't know if you've ever boat high-definition television
but when you buy in the store you have
amazing beautiful images you take the television you go back home
and images completely crap
now why is that
well the reason is that when you buy it in the store the guy
puts a high-definition television DVD so the image is beautiful you come back home and
what you get into your TV standard definition images and UTV nowhere another has to
take small images in larger to fit your screen OK so that he has to
interpolate and the result is pretty bad
so what is the TV doing first of all it has to be interlaced image
one nine out of two has disappeared it has to be recreated
it has also to increase the size of this is typically superresolution and now issue
by new screen you've sixty image per second input and in fact it's displaying one
hundred twenty image per second so it has to recreate an image and if you
have for example a tennis ball well if you just do an interpolation you'll get
two tennis ball in the middle image like in this example we have a moving
words so that doesn't work so you need to indeed interpolates but followed the geometrical
properties in space time
OK so
that's the type of problem and just to give you an idea so you have
your small size image basically have to multiply by twenty the amount of data
to get to fits the high-definition screen
and if you count the amount of data you have per second it is about
seventy get by per second
and you have to do super resolution out of seventy get by second now the
reason why mentioning that is that
suddenly you have an issue of scalability on your can you have an algorithm which
treats seventy get by per second on the chip which is supposed to be less
in on training samples and some corrupt the training samples can be mapped back to
a training sample because that's exactly what we want so that will show the energy
surface in the right way but just limiting the information content in the code and
we have to push up on the energy of anything
OK so that's kind of indirect way solving the partition function problem by not having
to push push did you know of anything but just restrict information content of the
you can show this on sort of
so you can actually interpret pretty much any unsupervised learning algorithm in those terms in
terms of how the shape the energy surface PCA is an encoder decoder models both
are linear
you could near the corners near the transpose of each other and the way PC
and limit the information content of the code is that it just makes the dimension
of the good small
so does
the sense of sparse coding it's what i just described i can means is an
interesting thing could kick k means you can also as a special case of
the encoder decoder architecture
it except doesn't have an article really has decoder so k means doesn't have this
it doesn't have that it imposes user one of n code
and the reconstruction is linear
and the error function is quadratic OK so basically replaced so you find the values
e which is which is closest which is going to minimize reconstruction error OK
inference process which means what it means is sort of a simplified version of this
if you want to get sparse coding deal size and scale models sparse coding is
similar you also don't have an encoder and you have to do for the
he could near
this is quadratic and there was requisitioned term here which is kind of an l
one penalty or something that i know in color so i think about having an
is that inferences is quick
should don't have an encoder
and you have one of those terms here if i give you an x you
have to run an optimisation algorithm to find the of wolsey that minimizes the reconstruction
right so inference is complicated because you have to do this sort of minimisation process
whereas if you have an encoder encoder is going to improve the prediction with the
solution the minimizes the energy that you have to get rid of the decoder altogether
OK that's why this why i was not
so this particular implementation of this called predictive sparse decomposition that we've been pretty fond
of the last year or two
and the energy function that is
it's very simple so it's the
also since model with an encoder
and so if the encoder decoder here
so the decoder is a linear decoder where the columns of the matrix are normalised
to the one
and the the distance function is just a quadratic distance function there is a specific
constraints here which could be an l one penalty on the on the could that
something that will
OK and the
the anchor the is the sort of non-linear regressor or if you want OK so
in know case is going to be very simple
sort of
you know one or two layer neural net some kind could be anything you want
to come machine whatever any parameterized function they can differentiate respect the parameters it's fine
for any function you can train to regression
and so the way you trying to thing is you play you plug your plugin
observation input
you find the value of the code that minimizes the sum of the three are
the three energy terms
OK so something that's going to
reconstruct the input properly there is not too far from where this guy predicted and
this is at the same time is sparse
and once you have use this as desired output for this regressors transistor russir two
cannot predict that value and you train this guy to predict that value by me
to minimize OK
very simple
just a very simple you can do everything by gradient descent or smart method if
you want
and the and once we have trained the model
if you want to use it as feature extractor
basically get rid of this part
you just next run the encoder
forget about this just use that value
and actually running through the first past fire and you can use this as features
can use it features
as will see little bit later
which the
where the weights
in which
that's right so like recognition with the reconstruction weight
and i don't know if it's kind of like weeks limit
is an inference process and then you can train the both
with the same time which is
you can't
what was the
OK so the the way you use right is that you go
you know trained as you go from one stage of this
in the second using the output of
of those
use as input to another stage trend that stage three multiple stage like this and
what it gives you a good starting point for supervised learning
we should
this is a
and sparsity OK so that's really important so sparse it is good not just because
it solves the partition function problem but also because it produces features that are high
dimensional and sparse and those are good for
recognition right these revisions were
this is what
OK this is not sparse PCA is very compact so think of this like an
expert on the kernel right so if you have a kernel
first you do that with the kernel layer does that expands the input on to
sort of high dimensional space is very sparse
that's why it works because now you have one independent component
the parameter for every training sample particularly OK so this is kind of same thing
because of the sparse the sparsity here you can create a high dimensional feature vector
is very sparse and a high dimensional feature a feature space things are more easily
this criminal case
and he is the fact that you get the high dimensional representation to now there
are several criteria you can use to make it
efficient one of them is sparsity other people use you know
other the criteria but sparsity is it is an easy one two three four five
where is
six that
all problems
on one hand and all
one that in it is our universe
actually what's the formal way of solving i mean
you can think of k two events are independent i want to think about the
second just compute the probability of the first
in detail the way you should do it is to compute the probability of every
one of the four possible events
hands and heads tails and tails heads and tails tails heads
you know that there is a uniform distribution on
so what you should do is to some
it holding instances where the
first thought
they one of us
and that will be point twenty five was point two five two point five
so i mean
this is marginalization
but in many cases the virus are not independent like she is example just came
in some cases
the marginalisation
everything almost everything that you
do in terms of what we would call inference in graphical models
basically computing is marginalizations OK
computing this marginalization is just there are efficient algorithms for cases where
you have a probabilistic model which is structured according to
conditional independence assumption
now what i mean this is just the beginning of the the
of the r
i mean
it's probably a good
please stop anyway because
will start getting into
more technical detail
why don't stop now
and we come back in ten minutes then
i propose that we restart now
so let's
let's try to
to restart from where we were so basically
i want to tell you that we have
these two basic rule
which will
navigating with you wherever you go
in the autumn of the model basically you have conditionally
which is
which is failure the
probability of x a given x you will be given by these
and modernization
so now
let's start to goal means that the central concept that we have already
conditionally independent k
first let's start with the independent i'm sure most of you know
how we define independence between
a pair of friendlies
if you have a pair of water
for example xmxb
we say that these random variables are independent
if this equation holds for every instantiated from of x a and x b
on no
novelty here so let's look at conditional independence no
essentially the same thing
but with that
a slight modification
the difference between independence and conditional independence is that the
atomic concept of independence requires to run via
the atomic concept of conditional independence requires three written by
and conditional independence
makes a statement about
two of the three
random violence
how how two of the trio one viable depend on each other
think state of the third round
that's what we're are going to see so assume instead of having random variables x
a and x being you have an additional random variable x
in the game OK
and now we are going to assume
that we
observed value or the realities asian of the inviolable x
OK we know
it's fixed
when the
the value of x e six
times only got this grid
the one that follows
this too
omega zero square
and the one that follows which i will call omega plus plus
going to be true
this claimed to have two
times only guys script
none of these
of course
but none of the resonance frequencies are coupled double pendulum were
there's no way
but you can even
look at this and say oh yeah of course
actually what did i do wrong
yes thank you very much
i have an omega zero there
extra credits
i've called omega s
if you want to change all the omega omega zero that's fine
but you cannot have one omega because you on omega
so this is the
square of the frequency of the single
oscillating mass and thank you very much for pointing that out
i want you all sorts of extra credit the centre of the night
i want to be able to get some extra credit
due to one of simulator and was the
the thank you letters square here
more people than one claim this one
all right thank you very much
so now
for any given value of omega
for any given value of you'll find three
and as you can see one
get two
you get c three in the steady state solution
of course
you get infinite amplitudes which physically meaningless if you to stay away new solutions from
in fact it is
but you see if you don't come too close to infinity
that the results that you get
are quite accurate for high
q systems
and so now
i'll show you
the three amplitudes
for this system
which will also be put up this afternoon
and so that the
three core systems
which we have set up
the only difference is the previous one is that
we don't know he only got divided by omega zero
the square
this book was provided
to me by professor which was
o eight o three
you will go
i will take for a time in a very kind of me
it's plot even and it is my request is very nice
car one is the first car
then the car two is the red one second car
this is supposed to be you don't see it but in any case if you
think that that's fine
then the the black line
so horizontally
is the ratio
of the frequency squared
so you see that the second resonance
it is indeed year
that what i have there on the
if we plotted above zero it means that it is in phase with the driver
if we plotted below
zero it means
it's out of phase with the drive
if no
look at this
that already at all because you see something that by no means intuitive
notice that c one
c two
nc three
all substantially lower than at the zero
this is in units of zero and not even the same to all three different
what i have participated that
i wouldn't
maybe to be the same for me not
all three different
and that's the case the all three different
when we approached residents things got out of hand
all three are in phase
and then you just crossed over the first residence residence they all three again in
phase but out of phase
with driver that's not so
surprising all by itself
now look at this ridiculous point
if i
right that system
raise the resonance frequency of individual spring with one last on
because remember this square is one and only god divided by because it also one
but that's exactly the square root of k over
this one will stance two
and these two
at roughly the same amplitude you could eyeballing looks like almost crosses over there
and it's about
is at zero
because it's about minus one
but i mean write it on the blackboard
that's quite bizarre situations
so that one frequency
so omega
because the square root of k over m
i get see one zero
NYC through about c three maybe even exactly c three i never checked that
and that is roughly minus
at the one at that
and to see that
it remains
so here
by take multiplying the one that you could take the role sounds and he already
has the same so if you take the difference is zero
think about it for a few minutes but
it's pretty obvious that this thing has to be zero
so what we know is
you know all i are nonnegative
the if if
we have the smallest so the smallest angle we can have a zero and actually
we have we have this angle zero and the corresponding eigenvectors are constant one victory
now there is actually very nice relations
already between the i vectors
of the graph which i finally zero and the number of clusters
and the relation is as follows
of course the i'm the matrix could have the iron value zero several times so
it could be that the in space is just does not only contain one that
but contains several vectors
and what turns out now is that there is actually only happens
in the situation where graph contains of different disconnected parts
so if f looks like this
so we have two parts and there are no connections between each other
then one can prove that
the multiplicity of the zero will be exactly two
because we have to connect the components and the iron vectors which correspond to this
to those two parts
are essentially
like the indicator vectors of the parts so if one i so if the vertices
or that this is the first group in the second before nine vector which looks
like this
and the second one
looks like this
and those trying to spend the space of five minutes
and actually
that already shows that the small eyeing vectors of
from eight of the class matrix might have something to do with the
number with with the clustering because we see that if if you would look at
the first two i vectors of this matrix
it is that they really contain the cluster indicator vectors of the two tools in
our data
and of course is only holds if there's not nice thing hear it gets more
complicated than that what spectral clustering about but that's really the intuition or that's that's
a very important observation
the nice thing about this
statement here is that the proof is actually very simple and very elegant and i
like it or not
and we would do it exercise
OK so
the matrix and we've looked at so far is
what is called the unnormalized laplacian so is one of the world normalised so far
because we didn't have any anomalous once but now we introduce two other versions of
love thousands which are normalized graph laplacians
so this would be the unnormalized version
and essentially we will see that later
we need many this one
so the normalisation what it essentially does is it normalizes matrix such that the iron
vectors are the angle is always in the same range
which is not
the case for the
the unnormalized laplacian
and many workers this matrix
where we normalized by multiplying the numbers of people to the front of
and if you multiply also out so you have l and i put e to
the minus one front
and here it can so that gets the identity matrix here
if qf t
e to the minus one times as so that part here
and the reason why i put this index are our reitz
because it's so it stands for a random walk so
but for those of you know what the random open graph is this is the
transition matrix of
so who actually knows whether random walkers
and going to the later so for those who know that's the relation with the
OK and there's also another normalisation but i don't want to talk about this actually
the lecture
just take it there's another normalisation don't
but the demons won in front but we multiply from both sets we e to
the minus one half
the advantages of this matrix is still symmetric the matrix here is not symmetric
but it
forget sort of so what is important is that the properties of the random of
both matrices are actually very
close to the other ones also both positive semidefinite and both have the properties that
this property about the number of clusters corresponds to the first to the
class to the multiplicity of the first i mean that
OK now i want to introduce
i want to show
the rationality OK so i think there
that's a very good question so
maybe we see that later i mean i will show later on by this i
mean right now it's a mystery i know so i will try to solve the
mystery later i think the most important point is really this this property we had
this one you have transpose frequent some as j
i'm minus j because somehow it is
it is so machine learning it is often seen as a regularizer because punishers function
on the graph there is a lot on what parts of the graph is closely
i mean there are very many really i mean there's a few call spectral graph
theory which does nothing but look at different matrices and how those properties of matrices
are related to the graph
and often this have because then you can use linear algebra things tool for example
compute how many comic connected component the graph has or
it's just a different view of looking graphs i think
and this one is just the matrix which turns out somehow to be very convenient
but it's nothing you can see on it's not obvious in the first glance it's
ready to go
the printer
determine how
how is explicit for link is contributing to the
in training squad
so this it
well you need to have a training data very know course
i don't need to know where
and it and it so i feel all i mean for every position there
we are we have to search the whole way back essentially this this could be
as long as the DNA maybe there a limit on the length but still you
can do you think i mean you can take this is not going to be
it was down to if you have a
in model
from this point on this quality constant and you only pay only penalized by the
by the point i mean by a factor of many look at how wait so
it's not like can allow maybe hundred k entrance here
maybe from that point on on your intron link model is constant and maybe
you pay only
so it's a bit but if you don't have infinite model then you don't pay
and all for the link
OK so how can we parametrize and so here we have a substitution matrix this
is simply bipartite metrics that four letters and the deletion like so we have a
duty of the mind so very like conditions deletion
so this is essentially twenty five primary
we also have these people function here of the length of the building and we
i mean it
i had a simple choice you be model that as a piecewise linear function
so it's quite simple to think about this choice is that all the time is
so we don't need cuts support doing this and then estimate one-dimensional functions piecewise linear
functions on
but then it is
so if you think twenty or thirty support points but these things
this just formula with the end we have prime directive which consists of these four
point is working on
and this substitution
so i for given beta
you can now compute the alignment score
four certain lines
so how can we optimize and how can you find these parameters
the idea again i would like to find parameters such that for non alignment good
alignment is much larger than what we need
from like
so and given in training examples
we have to solve this but i think the vision problem is that we would
like to find the parameters theta such that will be of good alignment is greater
than any problem
and he just have the same problem exponentially many constraints and we have this iterative
algorithm which can solve the optimisation
objectives might not
this is clear
so it's
so we we have a function which is computing the
alignment score for a particular line
OK so this function is linear in the
therefore these constraints are going to be linear
therefore this is just
but i think this problem we have maybe somebody comes billion years
and just how many constrained by iterating into it i can solve the
what we get in the end get parameter settings
which are good for predicting
the correct line
make sure you simulation example
so we need to be considered excellent results so these are real sequences which we
took from some database for four and we consider like sequence of px
and this what they told by blood and some quite strict alignment filtering
so then we cut some sequences
to make the problem in a more typical case we had
out the x cut some sequences to make the next one really short to be
between two with fifty nucleotides long uniformly distributed
the good thing about this kind of thing is that this place not really affected
so to ensure that the fact that most of the information about the license
OK so now we have artificially generated a
so to do this we now publisher assumptions on the risk on the covariance which
is what we're all always trying to avoid regression to this never felt right to
me has kind of a methodology right but there is a big literature on it
his user you know its practical applications of this definitely want to kind of
graphs graphs graphical approaches to regression is this
so a little bit more formally here's our regression
now otherwise is the response we have an initial covariance the goals define what's called
the central subspace and it just defined by saying well i suppose i could write
the regression
as just a problem distribution of y given the projection of x onto some matrix
so although i'm going to project on to be was straw that here
the one dimensional so here's my accent that can be
i get to be
transfer here and maybe once i know that i can predict y just as well
as five use text itself by the conditional independence
of x and y conditioning on the transpose x
so far to find such a b
i've kind of managed to project and not lose any information
OK so that's what defined to be the central subspace is this matrix b
the subspace defined by projection based gerbil example of that if you have logistic regression
in x one x according to look like that i then if you were to
just look at the x one corner project and the next one chord that you
get perfectly good regression and you would have lost in information if you're projecting next
quarter you've lost information so thirty one issues the central subspace bx one axis
right PCA of course kids project with state in the x one x two space
the PCA principal axes may have nothing to do with x one just depends on
the variance scale is which is related to x one
OK so there's tons of methods they're all interesting icon to regression particular is a
whole bunch of very clever ideas going on here
and i want to talk i would get into these little bit just tell you
that there are all interesting clever and there's this all publicity analytical theory for all
these under certain assumptions these all work
OK this assumptions are too strong however is get into a major is a linear
sum shorthand and even assumption or most painfully elliptic assumption on the distribution of x
is a very common assumption is imposed to just doesn't feel right to me i
don't imagine political they arise all that often in the x space not for regression
OK so we'd like to get out of that kind of a kind of web
of assumptions
right so now be really how this relates to conditional independence member b is our
projection matrix so we take axe let's fill it out of they the orthogonal complement
of that c has or called to be and then define you to be the
good stuff the projection and what we want to retain the VDB everything else
OK so the statement that begins the projectron the central subspace is equivalent to saying
that the conditional distribution of y given x
it's the same probably why given the transpose access the definition
i and that's the same as saying that this conditional distribution of y given
both components you would be light to reconstruct axis is the same as saying this
because you is equal to be transpose x for all y u and v
and that's just a way to express conditional independence of y and v given the
projection onto u
right so that's if you want to define the matrix b does this is equivalent
to find the matrix b that achieves conditional independence
OK so now you've got to do is find a way to express conditional independence
an objective function that you can go downhill in terms of b
so how do you express conditional independence is objective function that was our task that
we set out to try to solve in this line of work
right so we we did this using a nonparametric tools so let's come back to
you know we learned about represent progress faces by the work of many other people
to give a talk on this
and we noticed this is basically just a way to get the basis functions and
then competition efficient space without well the main some richer users of these spaces we
can maybe express operators on these spaces and look at those classic operators and see
those are interesting not just the functions in the space itself with the operators
and maybe they can use to go to lead us towards non supervised methods so
that's kind of what this talk really ended up with this line of research in
that have been the started with something called kernel ICA
and then when in this in this direction
OK so we could have and we're going to talk about conditional independence we use
represent progress was to characterize both independence and conditional independence and so we actually end
up to talk to talk about these kind of things we need to talk about
independence we need to speak to represent problems spaces one here one here two the
original data space acts another data space y
and they're going to map into the corresponding representing the kernel hilbert spaces and then
we'll talk about the relation among data points pairs of data in these two spaces
OK so you already had talk and rk stages i want to belabor this
the main thing about our gives you this kernel function
and the kernel has two arguments and if you fix the second arguement and this
is now a function of the first arguement that is an object that lies in
the rip curl curl her space and the inner product of another function in space
you just get evaluation is called the reproducing property i hope you've seen that somewhere
OK so now if you take into products of sophie is this mapping of for
you take a point xt mapping the function
that were the second arguement the kernels pin down so that's that's called give access
a feature map if you will and he now take into products of fever one
data point the for another data point that just amounts to kernel evaluation and you
can actually expand the basis functions are given by the kernel evaluated at particular points
i just kind of basic kernel methods
now we're not not talk about the kind of the points in the space but
the actual operators on the reproducing kernel hilbert space
OK the operators
that's the way you do this is order to define covariance operators and so you
look like at random variables on on the august eight you take that kernel function
and you can have the second arguement actually that is random and so we have
a random function now for every
for every choice of x we get different functions is random function
so that we can talk about covariance operators which are to give you guys i
covariances on on functions on function space
want to compute two types of things you want to compute predictions if you want
to know what this function do in other places in places where we didn't measure
so so to do prediction so again we use the likelihood function which was the
likelihood function say about those new predictions given particular weights and then we average over
the posterior distribution always try to have a high posterior somewhere then you get a
large the you get lucky the large weight to those predictions and if you have
a low posterior than those predict the prediction coming out of that particular setting of
the model would influence the actual predictions so we've seen this before
and another thing you might be able to might be interested in computing is the
is the marginal likelihood much like it was important for model selection talk much more
about that later on and again the marginal likelihood is is is
is that you get that by marginalizing over the distribution of the weight so you
can see the interesting things that you want to compute actually computed by doing integrals
over the over the weights
so this is where this is very always happens in
in parametric models
you can sort of see that there's something a little bit funny about the right
we're not really interested in the weights
the weights are sometimes called nuisance parameters right in these kinds of models usually uninterested
in the way you just want to know what other the predictions
so sometimes if you have a parametric model you might actually be interested in what
is the value of one of the parameters when we talk about the case when
i'm talking about you know complex nonlinear relationships and you want to know you know
what is the prediction not interested in the weight so the way gaussianprocess process models
works is it explicitly says well the prior here
notice that the posterior has nothing but the likelihood times the prior is proportional to
the likelihood and the prior right so somehow the prior is here prior on weights
right but the way it works is it induces a prior on the functions that
if you set the weights to something particular then you get a particular function right
so if you have a distribution over those weights then you get a distribution over
so what we're going to do differently here is we're gonna it instead of going
wide by the weights
which were not interested in
we're going to go directly for distribution over the things that were interested in over
the predictions
OK and in fact this is going to turn out turn out to be much
simpler than going by this two-step procedure introducing model weights and then getting rid of
them again
so you might think that that the way to to actually talk to get good
results here is to look at complicated functions to dream up you know complicated nonlinear
functions about of ways here to be able to do
you know very bad things and dream complicated priors on the weights and try to
somehow do
these integrals and what i'm going to try and persuade you today is that that's
not the way to do it but the way to do it is different and
it turns out that just involves gauss in distribution
before i can tell you about that let's make sure
we're talking about the same gaussians
so the gas distribution has location parameter means and has
a standard standardisation or variance
two examples here the two gas distributions in one dimension here
and over here i've i've drawn a picture of the gas industry mission two dimensions
in particular is the correlated strongly anti correlated to what i drawn here by the
two variables on this axis here and this is a good probability contours so there's
a high probability inside this region and lower probability as you move out the probability
goes down very rapidly in this direction but got goes down much more slowly in
this direction
so what i'm going to use on the talk here i'm going to use gas
distributions that live in high dimensional spaces
OK unfortunately i can only draw a two-dimensional gas and we have to try and
think of what do these distributions look like in much much higher dimensions right and
going to be part of the challenge
so i so i can draw those things
what can you do with gaston in distributions well you can you can condition gauss
in distribution so conditional distribution means that if i now know somehow that the value
of this variable has this particular the value of this variable sorry has this particular
value then what does that tell me about the all the variables right and of
course if the gas in correlated like this that tells me quite a lot in
particular tells me if i had this value value here is very unlikely that my
all variable would have would have values over here in fact the conditional distribution of
the other variables given that this variable is set to this value is again calsyntenin
centered over here
so that's conditioning and nothing we can do is marginalizations of marginalization just means something
out or integrating out some of the of the variables and looking at just the
distance the marginal distribution of the other variables right and here again in this two-dimensional
example here i just marginalize this joint galson by summing in this direction and when
i get back is again gas distribution turns out to be crucial that we can
do both of these conditioning and calcium in modernization and the resources of of those
operations are again gaussians
i've also given you the equations here so if i have this if i have
to just joined as distribution over x and y here with mean mean vector which
contains a and b and the covariance which can be schematically written like this then
i've given you hear equations for
the marginal distribution of one of the variables of the conditional distribution of one of
the variables given the other variables but let's not look too much of algebra right
but the slide is in there if you want to look at it later on
OK so now
what about what about the casting process is one of the gaussianprocess i'm going be
talk about distribution so far
so that's the process is just a generalization of gas distribution to infinitely many many
and the reason why we want to do that is we want to do inference
about functions
so we have to be able to put probability distributions over functions
this is sort of an informal analogy here we can think of an infinitely long
vector we can think about is being function right if i let's think about a
one-dimensional function if i want to specify what the one-dimensional function is i just specify
what is the function value for each input
OK then i specified what the function
the problem might be that there are infinitely many possible inputs to the function right
so the vector
will become very very long
OK but let's not worry about that for the time being
mathematically this the
function is sort of like anything long vector is not mathematically very precise turns out
to be precise enough for what i'm going to the way i'm going to use
so we simply think of functions as being infinitely long vectors OK so of course
you might start getting an uncomfortable feeling now because well i can write down these
things in my computer of course why because only has finite memory so i better
not try to do the right and i will try to do that
OK so somehow will be able to do what we need to do without writing
down those vectors
for the root mean square error or in this case even simpler you don't have
any intention section you have the integral of
of this area
so now for the next step our supervised that is
matching procedure where we want to map the detected lines to the mode number small
numbers starting by one two in our case twenty five
some might not be there
it might be the only ten modes have been identified by the engineer and annotated
is possible and so we have three strategies for this
the priority matching their you match
you're detected line
but in the order of the detection so you you first attacked line with the
highest values so the strongest line in the picture
so we could do this or you do agree the best fit
so you the line
we had between line area is minimized
and that's right to use the look research
which you could do on top of one of them
the first approaches
you could swap the assignment
in order to minimize you're our most
in this respect
and we have a data set a real life datasets
from right to voice
and we have two hundred and one campbell diagrams from
fourteen vibration test coming from one engine and we have some e if e pretty
iffy predictions and some level i which we used in our libraries
and we
performed three experiments one only four
assessment of the quality of the line detection so nothing to do with the assignment
of mode number
and then two experiments to assess the quality of our matching
so and dimension we of course detect light new lines which has had are not
in the background model not in the SP model model and not in the lab
model and they are not annotated and so we cannot ever evaluate them at the
moment we can because we don't have any ground truth for them so it just
so our first experiment to assess the quality of our line detection approach
so what we did is we
met our detected lives against annotation
because you want to calculate the integral of the and annotated line and the fact
that line
and and what you see here is
approach so our have transform with background knowledge using
the last they that background knowledge
what you see here is now the are you compare the annotated lines
and you could compare
this to the last model the last model is only predicting exactly what is in
the left data so if the left in the last few measure frequency of two
thousand just reading this without any machine learning nothing the problem here in general is
that you have only a few
let measurements
components and
so you could have per capita diagram only two months
of out of twenty five
so that means here we see that our
approach is quite good
we have only
comm is in pixel would be on the y axis
about two point five pixel difference in
on average on all images
from the two annotation is quite small it means our
i remember quite accurate in finding the right lines
we are seeing here is where we look at the st
model as the background
information we could compare that to the SVM model here and model has more prediction
so more lines
but it's much more inaccurate myself
so but still you see there is a different height difference between the two
so it has
two use our
model instead of only predict
predicting the if if the lines
the second experiment is
where we want to evaluate our metric
procedure so we match against SVM model
we detect aligned with our approach and then we will make it to the if
the model not to the annotation model
and this year we have only SVM data so we assume that there was no
measurements and we can predict four hundred seventeen lines so the recall you will see
is higher because if the model contains more
to achieve this performance by using the priority match which was our first
and we see here that our method has lower
our embassy which is good
that means however is smaller
and what i need to mention here if what we do
in this case in the matching case is that if you don't find the line
close to line
but we assume that the if the prediction is correct
take this line into our results
so some of the
after performance
can come from this this might be a problem
so we see it even though it had here to use
this makes strategy
in order to assign the mode numbers
last experiment is on
the matching
again here on the left it i would much much better
so the let let
one is much better you see here a our your
six thousand compared to
more than twenty thousand for the st model
and here we see we are comparable to the
if you wanted to the left model
but we can not
achieve better results
in this case
we cannot improve
the model but but the problem here is that we can predict only two hundred
forty seven lines it's much
the recall is much smaller because the if you dialect model is much
small so only
my number of lines contain there
to conclude we have introduced iterative
have transform using background knowledge
which allows to detect
blurred lines
and allows sources to
distinguish between i can with an expectation or as we saw that it has an
and you move from one to the other by gradually adding objects so that is
not as a categorical boundary here
so here for instance england to show you how to go
from the city to the mountains consist than step so instead of the city
and then we know little bit on the surface of this kind of stuff appearing
the sky because larger buildings become smaller
i gain no there been this because even smaller buildings disappear from one side of
the main on the other side the buildings go away from both sides but there
are still here are
now there are the remains but the buildings have been replaced by montanes
we have more maintains that because the smaller
the world is almost gone in the realm only maintain some of and half on
the mountains so there's a very gradual progression from one scene to another generally not
just by a little little by little suggesting that really had any categorical boundary and
the and you end up in a very different place
and of course the fact that there are no categorical boundaries doesn't mean that you
can not just categories is just that there are some transitions in which you may
it may be depending on what you want to do with the image due may
focus more on one particular aspect of the category of the scene now and then
another aspect so here is an example of images organised along a continuous space by
measuring things for instance the degree of expansion
what is the degree of perspective on the space or the degree of openness how
many buildings are blocking your view how open the space and you have a continuous
organisation that goes from very open spaces to close spaces or from very expanded spaces
with strong perspective to flat videos
in which you can move much
and categories will live in this space
with the soft transitions between them but there are some portions of this space in
which to can actually be quite confident about the labelled one i just described those
those images
this is the same thing for nature again you can measure in what i said
you can put the degree of elevation of the terrain
in the ordered axes commission again how open is the space and gained have a
continuous space that goes from one kind of image to another kind of image go
from coastlines and you can go to the forest by going through the countryside and
you get very different kinds of scenes
all of them by a small changes in their opinions and still you decision different
OK so now that we have seen how you can go directly to the scene
let's go back to objects
let's look at the more those of a context for object recognition
well the first thing is of course you then do they really then
you don't need to just context you can look at this image in everything is
going on here despite this subject is out of context it's clear that you can
the canadian jobs locally i you don't need to reason about the scene in fact
this object he has everything wrong even actually is wrong so they can even neglect
some of the local aspects of the object does not a problem
it is true that you can do this in many images but there are also
many cases for which is actually quite hard to do
so this is a picture of a dome by joan steiner
which is an that is that builds this small walls with objects that are not
what they expect to be and she composes new scenes
so in this case this looks like a kitchen but all the different pieces that
compose this kitchen are just with a different meaning
for instance this one
and this is what plug
this is
i can hear
this is nailed
and in many cases you need to make an conscious f four in order to
recognise what these objects are you have to look attentively to them and you are
always discovering new objects the more time to spend looking at the image the more
obvious will emerge and the reason is because juggling this global reasoning
that is really difficult to shut down but you can not that it takes you
a lot of effort to start realizing what the local instances are
she has many many different examples really really hard to see what the local properties
and in many cases also context is going to be very important because it is
going to define what the object actually is so here the have three pictures that
contain cars but not all of them are cast the first one is not really
a car is the picture on the cover of the magazine to canon drive that
one you can go there and opened the door
it's a picture
this one
is not the kind of game is just a toy
you can only see that you put that the poem relationship with all the objects
and this is real kind of this is that one you can drive
but this is only defined by context also contest going to what unexpected event is
so here am now in this case you know there's something strange but this is
not just going to be just the local information lead you do need to act
reason about the scene and know what is expected and what is not
or this seen here
the use of context has been studied in human vision for a a long time
so one of the
influential works is also by the man
so be the man to find that there are five fundamental kinds of context of
your violations that just may have scenes one is the support of disrespect to be
supported by some other objects like supported by the grounds on the set of rules
that they have to wait over a
in that position
crystalline phases
it secondly order what like my says of
the lumley phase
of liquid crystals which is very similar to that of natural they are organisation of
natural systems
the question is can we make
parliament networks from these systems more complicated systems
OK it's straightforward when we have such an effect and to make polymaths effect in
such a way of polymers surfactants such away
there are many different different possibilities we investigate or the system during the last twenty
years and with the systematic variation u
actually end up with all these structures that are known for low molar mass liquid
i will give you some
just some very few
experiments on some recent networks that has been
i have been synthesized by hand by some i hope
because i think it's highly interesting chemistry
here we have the construction
that's the problem big backbone is water soluble so hydrophilic
the polymer backbone
and then the cycle groups hydrophobic
in other words you see the typical hydrophilic and hydrophobic parts of specific molecules
and additionally
we have here one
and the ability of the nitrogen is that you can form sort
make it quite canonization and then you get the sort in other words simply by
changing the ph value of q
so solution of polymer soap solution you can strongly influence
the hydrophilic hydrophobic balance
all the water solubility of the system and additionally from a non ionic
surfactant or police effect on you
change into an ionic
so effect and of
polyelectrolyte and the polyelectrolyte
it has a very exceptional properties were not going to the question is whether this
can be done or not
it can be done here you see such a polymer in water
a typical phase diagram temperature concentration of the polymer here we have a pure polymer
and we see a nice exec interface in this temperature region brought miss ability get
where the system exists in two coexisting phases
to make it i should show you this result because this is from a highly
following one of mass effect and it's well known that
if you change the water-soluble of solubility of the hydrophilic part of the height of
folly public part you end up with all these funny structures with
right likes effect and spherical surfactants and so on
here we have strongly modified how to felicity and hydrophobicity of the system but we
only observe exec interface
always the heat signature space
independent of the so-called hydrophilic hydrophobic balance this nice indication
but not only
i don't feel kind of public part of surfactant
three times the mass aggregation
but also the geometry of the system or in other words
with the polymer chemistry we have the chance to tailor make the size and the
dimension of our
surfactants in so ution of the aggregates in solution
we have examined her face and when we start with the non ionic
of my at
for example hydrochloric acid or another is to make such as soil formation
as mentioned before we change the solubility
this has huge consequence of the appearance of the liquid crystalline phase
if we look at at the temperature
up to which the exact place exists we see that
would be or cosine data plus all i time or
sign data
which of course
will factor out and make it cosine data plus y sin data
now it was oiler took the decisive step
and said hey look
i'm going to call that e the i th data
he do that well because
everything seems to indicate that it should but that's certainly worth for
the best color we have which is what
get low here OK
nonetheless it's worth think
i'll even give him is do toilet
sometimes is called oilers formula but i really shouldn't be it's not a formula definition
so in some sense you can argue it is a well if you want to
putting the complex number in power and calling that you know you can but
one can certainly as why he did it and the answer i guess is
that all the evidence seems to point to the fact that it was the thing
to do
i think it's important to talk about that a little bit because it's
in my opinion
using this for the first time
even if you read about it last night
it's the most it's the mysterious thing
and the one needs to see it from every possible point of view
it's something you get used to
you will never see it on the fly sudden flash of insight
it'll just get
as familiar to you is more
common arithmetic and algebraic calculus processes are
but look what is that we demand if you're gonna call something an exponential
one is that we want an exponential to do what something the right
at expression like this the right to be called the to the i th data
the answer is x i know i can creep inside oilers mind
it must have been a very big day in his life
a lot of big days but when he
i realized that
it was the thing to write down as the definition of EDI data but what
what what is one wants seven exponential
the high school and so surely is
you want to satisfy the exponential law
now to my shock i realize a lot of people don't know in my analysis
class you know these are
some math majors graduate engineers in various subjects and if i say
processes that using the exponential law i'm sure to get at least half a dozen
emails asking me what the exponential or OK
the exponential law is
eight to the
times a the y equals a BX course one
the laws of exponents
that's the most important reason why one
that's the most the single most important thing about x about exponent of the way
what them
and this is the exponential function called the exponential function because it
it r
because all the significant stop is in the exponent
so it should satisfy we want first of all the exponential law to be true
but that's not all that's high heist high school answer
a an MIT answer
it would be what what is the role
i mean why is e to the exocet to popular function
well of course it does satisfy the exponential about pride and ferocity even more reasonable
thing it's the function which when you differentiate you get the same thing you started
with and it
apart from a constant factor the only such functions
now in terms of differential equations
it means that it's the solution
e to the let's build generous make it into the axe
the better not to use x because x
complex numbers tend to be called experts i let's use t
as more neutral variable with standing outside the fray as it were
it satisfies the relationship that
and related methodologies
and the connection with case analysis and i think this is a very interesting book
for you to to go and read consult
well at a few reading on the web or perhaps some paper copies for the
course participants
we didn't have time with these on the web before the course
so these kind of background reading is even beyond beyond the reading that participants have
o through
some textbooks
the best textbook
actually the only one in english
it's pretty much up to date by myself and charles writing as editors but with
five or six other colleagues
so called confusion compared to methods
you're assuming techniques
it is an obligatory reading for this course we're going to use it from a
to z
also going to circulated from for the non participants
just came out last year last autumn
actually we used are experience as in teaching these things
in order to elaborate the course i mean the
book so it's really
conceived to be used as a textbook for such a course
there is also for those of you read german for german
OK i quite number
there's an excellent textbook in
which is called
qualitative comparative analysis went fuzzy sets
i never fulfilled and then the and you know it's not involved
mit einem for fun chancery
you could also small
it's pretty complimentary to the english language textbook
it's quite more advanced in many ways so it's like a complement to the english
language textbook
it has some some additional
let's it bonds being developed
by constant that ontologies document or to german colleagues
so you might want to read both if you want to elaborate more some technical
hopefully this german
book on the basis of this book
i will be translated into some time in english some chapters and so on and
maybe available from some of you in english
good all of you please
right names
i think get that's why
is also a kind of all the textbook in french
by myself and the them i didn't bring it here
it's really not on the technical side up to date but if you're interested in
the foundations of course you
especially bowling brian logics there's some stuff in the in two
i want to use powerpoint slides throughout the course
and it be posted by the teaching assistants
as well as complementary material on the databases
a lot of data files
because accuracy is i'm show you pretty soon is
said also of data analysis techniques
for tabular data
related to cases
and so we can use a lot of data files
made of data or we live data from published articles and books
so you ask for those who want exposed to bring
we use key because we're going to give you some files also
we should be using the lab and so on and so forth
they will be exercises assignments also part of the course resources
and we're gonna use software
basically two software packages around they're both freeware
freely downloadable on the web
one is called the mind
it stands for
tools for small analysis
developed by lester confused and depressed russir two german colleagues
last is actually political scientist but also the problem
so he has developed very nice software
which is very much user centred quite user-friendly
it is the main one of the use during the first week and the second
software is called fist uses developed by charles region in USA
and st
and it's quite complimentary to to my
lastly we use a lot
a resource called combats
i have the time to go through this today
i to go to the core of the matter that compounds is a
derivations which is you have to enforce the constraints on the parameters properly
in the multinomial model
the probability of
the di coming up one two three up to k those numbers between zero and
one but they have to to add up to one
and when you take the derivative you have to enforce factor three years
and that constraint has been forced usually with the electron multiplier leads to this extra
term here the total number of coin flips if you don't do that you get
your ass
again not very deep but just to let you know that's important for us
this is not very common example
multivariate gaussians so the galaxy and is
it is very common distribution for continuous
because and has the property of being the maximum
entropy estimator consistent with first and second moments
so i tell you have some data has a mean mu and variance sigma square
please find me any distribution in the world
the tasmanian
the variance sigma square and trying to maximize the entropy the answer is yes
so the origin of the gaussians it also comes up
as the limits
the addition of independent random variables you have a lot of random variables together
their distributions tend to go the
i like to think in more engineering mindset if you add two random variables together
with you do distributions you could involve them
and if you take any sort of function like this and you can work with
itself over and over again what happens you get the gas
right so you can just try this you can just take a square wave and
convolved with itself or five times and you get to the
my systems and signals professor undergrad said that the only two approximations you need to
was what is lot of one class x one x is small
and how many times you need to all the square wave with itself before it
looks basically get
so maybe
maybe there really only two approximations you need to know about this you should know
that no one
you oh by the way
what is left
in fact the
among many help
back in one
namely we associate with the
but we digress i
maximum likelihood estimation of the galaxy and it's the same thing but now quantities are
continuous and categorical
and then you can go through the same kind of derivation you find a seemingly
trivial but very useful facts
the maximum likelihood galaxy in the two months of data is the gaussians whose mean
is the mean of your data
and use covariance covariance is the covariance
that sounds pretty good trying to ride
right for the multidimensional that's actually pretty good exercise
but that fact will serve you well
all this to a couple more examples here and then we can move on two
important things so the example now i'm going to do is linear regression
and this example is distinguished by having two nodes in the graphical model right so
for example they did which is one of graphical model so two kind of silly
see our first real graph model
and this is the third of june
graphical models so this is linear regression
and the idea is that you have some input x
and so output y
and because y axis parents we said that we need to specify the joint distribution
of x and y in this way
i'm here what arguments
and now
some pairs of x y
and i'd like to learn both the distribution in the distribution of
the joint distribution
in linear regression we assume that this distribution
he of y given x
is a gaussian
with the media which is a linear function of x
so here are just call this the transpose
covariance some very difficult to describe so for now assume that y is scale
so this is really the geometric problem of fitting a straight line to some data
when you start to to think about the problem you realize that you have to
be careful how you define
so how do you define the problem of finding some straight lines in the way
we define it here is to assume that we make the horizontal coordinates of every
data point perfectly
and we measure the vertical coordinate the output with some
which is gas industry
and now we want to maximize the likelihood going to see this
maximum likelihood in this galaxy an error model reduces to minimizing the square difference vertically
between each data point on the line
and that's the least squares
so when least squares is nothing more than the maximum likelihood of gaussian model
but when you do that you
realize that there is a big something you have no noise in your measurement that
and that
almost certainly untrue in many real world situations to make one revert something more complicated
like total square which tries to also incorporate access for now
in the simple case here
so each linear regression
so parents
and all the children are continuous value
the way we set up is exactly like i said it's against the distribution
where the mean is linear function of the continuous here
now if you had some discrete parents you have different
linear model for every setting the discrete that's relating axes vector which is married to
you might have z which is a binary variable which is also married to y
so we have two models here we have one linear regression model which is why
is a function of x y and z is zero and different linear regression model
with for y is a function of x y z is one
so you can make a continuous and discrete parents in your graphical model
as long as each setting of the discrete parents you have some of the continuum
the other way around is very complicated
having discrete children have continuous parents is a
the top row
to model that
so what
OK so
here we can see that the likelihood is that the squared error cost
you just get this by taking the log of the gaussians and
and the maximum likelihood parameters can be solved using these services
one of the most famous formulas in all of data analysis
called the discrete mean filter
and it gives you the solution to these linear least squares problem and that is
what is being computed in a numerically stable and efficient way when you do that
only for maybe I use yellow chalk so girl to only boy for
girls 3
2 months
and girl for
number 2
all makes that dashed lines not because it's different but just just to
so I act
Of course I'd like to create a matrix
that describes this this up
it's sort of a graph right
this is called actually the official name for this would be a bipartite graph so
these are nodes in the graph and the word bipartite means that's got 2 parts
the girls and the boys and all edges go between the two part
never anyway that bipartite graph this is the reason everything I say today there is
a host of
there just have the knack of these combinatorial questions that today
that that's
this is becoming a very significant part of modern modern mathematics pure and applied
OK so let me express the graph this way the 1st row will tell
that default for boys are allowed the 2nd row will tell us that only way
1 allowed boy for the 2nd will tell us that 2 informal out and the
3rd that only 2 ways that would be the matrix that so
so a i j equals 1 a i j equals one half girl ally and
here OK and otherwise 0
right here
it's not OK I know which
what's our jobs well a complete matching so let me introduce you these words a
complete matching would be
get everybody will get everybody married
thank you thank you thank you thank you
and their marriage problem is
when cannot be done cannot be done in this example and what's the necessary and
sufficient conditions for doing
OK so that
the Mac and of course 1 of after the last lecture you want a maximization
problem really it here so the maximization problem would be how many marriages can we
get maximize the number of marriages a complete matching means all married our problem would
be to our top if we can't our problem would be to maximize the number
of matches so this is like a specific question can everybody gets matched
if not the optimization problem the maximum problem would be to maximize the number of
and there's gonna be some minimum problems
and the max
will match the man that
duality at that the winner OK it now for for this specific that which I
would like 1st asked this question is a complete against the complete or when there's
a complete matching possible
up public access
and let's see that's not good question
visited we'll have a matrix and
well of course the matrix of all ones
so that would be a case where
everybody's will you marry everybody and the ranges 1
out my 1st thought was well what about the identity matrix well the identity matrix
a course that's a perfect we have a perfect matching girl 1 on
but they're matched their match their match the match great
yeah so somehow rank is somewhere hiding here
what about this specific examples
could I do a complete matching and if you tell me why not you probably
I guess that the
general theorem why not
the answer is no and what's from domain the reasons
well let's dance this question rank
and at all
the in in this language here of of edges
would the media that is a way of looking at the end of the words
I got all know the way to the end of the world that right OK
so now can we express that put that into our way that doesn't take out
girl to as like guilty for voice our whatever
the had and so on
OK but some of it
let start this sentence the problem is that girls 2 3 and 4
so again and allowed only like this don't like to avoid
we had 3 girls there that only can match
the only acceptable only only so matches over with 2 boys so you can't do
I would like
there's something but but I'll I'll stay with that language so my my my my
theorems will be complete matching of possible
if and only if the express at every
said that was the right right in here of of the girls saying say K
are girls
every set of girls every subset of girls whatever something you take a take any
group of girls say K of K
must work
much match and there must be at least k voice
that's clearly
right if I have a set of playgirls adopt among them like these 3 that
among them only connect
except 2 boys and I can't do it
so I got
it's like that duality weak duality that had before in some way half of the
theorem is going to be easy on me finish the state every set of girls
k of them like
collectively collectively
at least k
certainly necessary
not clear at all
OK and the final example for text i want to talk about is this statistical
machine translation
and this is a little bit harder not only do i need a large corpus
of english text upon and try to to translate into english but i'm trying to
translate from german also need a corpus of parallel text and when i was in
my hotel in berlin i was able to do that
but they had a nice collection of parallel text they get little brochure on one
side was englishness over german and now i can say that these are aligned with
each other and i've ever given
phrase in germany that i know
but this is a translation in english
but what i'm not given exactly that how can i use this information anyway
well i guess i've
i start off knowing that this is the alignment and now i want to try
to align word by word and one possibility is that these two words are lined
up according to each other and so assign probabilities to that but also might be
that there are lined up
those two words are are lined up inside probability there
could be all the way to the and or it could be one word
lives with two and vice versa so from one sentence i get a very broad
probability distribution all these things are possible
and then i just keep on adding them up over and over and over
and notice that she you know lots of times constant art occur
in sentences that are aligned and commenced in luxury did not occur often in the
probability going to converge
and eventually you say well that's going to be the right one
how well to hear some airbags
translate english comes out like this i've underlined the places where there's disfluencies so you
can go more than a sentence or two without saying here's an example of something
that's not quite fluent english text but is good enough that you get the idea
of what's going on in all the right who's doing what to whom is represented
similar kind of thing
there it's more like two or so disfluencies percent so rather than one probably reflecting
the fact that chinese is more
different from english there because
i had to go through the process
well we start off we go one character at a time first character
look up the probabilities for the alignments and he is the most likely know and
in this case i happen to
folded case together so he in the capital here consider different tokens
go to the next one
and we have set here
and now i notice when we want to the probability the stupa pillars we have
to deal with one is probability of the translation
from chinese into english and that represented by
these lists here
and the other is the probability that what we generate a sense of english and
that we test against corpus of english and in that case we we probably recognise
that the top probability here the latter is not very probable in english
but if you go down the list a little bit
his letter would be more probable
and so we be able to make that kind of correction there of course we
don't have to look just one character at a time can also combine them in
fact we've seen
this sequence before
and we have recognised that his letter at his right alignment and in many cases
for this more probable than the latter but we also notice that it's this also
is a proper name and that's more probable
and in fact in this case we've actually seen three character sequence corresponding to this
already so it is more cases of look then pasting things together
but for the rest of it now we're going to start pasting together with what
were essentially doing is trying to find a path through the history probabilities i problem
and this is just a chart here just echoes the first chart we had saying
that as we get more data this course keep going up and we have reached
the point yet
where the scores as and so there's still more to gain from the data
and i want to switch little and talk about the image data
and here's an example from google image search where you type in the name area
type to model is years results you get back pretty good but there's a variety
of ones there and who knows really what the best one
you know it's it's no secret that google like most of the other providers of
image search for the most part until very recently
had been throwing away the images and just looking at the surrounding words in names
and things like that and and for the most part that works pretty well
but we can prove that by looking at the data in the images themselves
and in this case what we're really looking for saying well there is a canonical
two this query and we want to be able to find that another on the
web very good at canonical
answers you type IBM
all search engines will give you idea dotcom that's an easy one because
not because of the contents of what's on that page but because of all the
links that link to it and so there good agreement that that's the right answer
to the query on the web itself with pictures that's not the case there is
one canonical model is image or or artifact in the real world but that's not
represented by one picture on the web is represented by lots of different pictures
so we have to be able to figure out which ones of those represent the
same object in the real world
and we do that by first looking at the images running sort of standard feature
extractor and then conceptually looking at all pairs of images and lining up which features
line up with each other and then we get to measure similarity between each pair
of images and of course you take shortcuts so you don't have to look at
all possible and square pairs but just the ones that makes sense to look
and now since we draw graphs of the connectedness between those how close each images
are to each other