cut this
parallel planes
they are to act as here can
then we can that this
OK you can offer
the label
there's a
this could have the same area
really amazing
amazing results
so there are lots of things
in order to understand the importance of the mathematical ideas you have to put it
local context that that's crucial for
because at the end of the book he started saying that the political dimension two
approach to the human and social constructivist conceptual previous that was not clustering
this first
the left wing party because of
and its historic striving for universal
literacy because i believe in universal literacy and that
but he was trying to make up
is on that side of the
well as the
is conservative it to a number of
one of the mathematicians were then
radically conservative
because politically
but i don't see the effects of
in nature mathematics economics what
is claiming that
in this view is right wing
a conservative and is a big surprise well
that's really bad
i given
to try to characterize things that way
it's a completely different book
by paul this
this come from
the educational philosophy
the type book i recommend the book
because the lack of references
so the point of view
and the students if you want to write an essay
you should ask someone to review
and so this is a good book to refute
because of this quotation
but i have here
and so from the
OK OK
but the article about the subject
the fact that these assumptions
have status of belief
well i guess
must remain open to challenge about
and i personally notable
well i don't think that's a valid argument
but it does
raise the spectre of
these beliefs that can be
mathematical assumptions of these beliefs can be very large
challenge time
or is there something more
absolute about
that this is the proper of education and is
added number of books and conferences and so on
and i do at the end of the book as an overview
the point of view about social constructivism and
we've looked at the same time
three points
is the mathematical fact
but is always embarrassing there
and so
so this was pointed out with on that you have have to be careful
when you put in some technical
o thing for example that you get it right
i recommend reading
finally go review because you spend a lot of time studying these books completely
we already
we know
one year
now call
and the
all o
it's not about
i mean
i i
right now
information from
it was red
a lot of logic the last part
this is originally
developed by philosopher
because there are not very happy
with classical logic propositional logic is called
because it doesn't take into account things like
and necessity
originally was just developed to take into account the genome but subsequently
and more and more
this is non classical logic
were developed
so a few of them are listed here
what what is traditionally called ontology
reasons about necessity and possibility
deontic logic reason about obligations
it is permitted that of the country one
temporal logic
it's about time so
it will be
sometimes in the future it always feature
and after attending logic
logic about knowledge
which i believe would be
covered next
next week one of the
OK i lectures
and there is dynamic logic which reasons about
execution of the program so
does this program ever
which state when it comes that law
thus there
from this is from whatever
two provincial adventure
race conditions and the can
dynamic logic will be covered in the article
the second one so you can also choose to attend don't
some machine learning course
well the
however now is just very basic syntax the time
so one give you may
a real world examples you see more
next week
for classical propositional logic
the mathematical model is just as we are doing one
from ontology it's complicated
because we have to reasons about truth in different modes
and one of the
very commonly used
it's not the only one
it is the so-called semantics this was followed by p
one of the
the perspective which is still alive
i think it is when i was twenty one years old
there's a lot of work
it's called the possible worlds semantics
so basically
proposition is true with respect to this can move among these walls
and in truth becomes
so a word
can have
many different interpretations according to which logical type which have these two point four
for example the temporal logic working disappointing kind
past future
for dynamic logic it can you state of mind program
and so on
an autonomous agent state where can be
the knowledge
the set of knowledge that agent
says put it
and more abstract ways
possible causes his relations structure
o point in relation
the syntax of modal logic is first
just take propositional logic two
unary operators
box operator
also used to denote necessity and dying
denotes possibility
and again the reading of the box can be different according to which which logics
that you are interested in example box
so what i say about the semantic web
i started hearing this
idea semantic web i think about ten years ago not sure exactly when it started
but it seemed like when people first started talking about XML
the notion of web based semantics was starting to float around the metric exactly the
prominence here
one ever heard of this thing the semantic web
they are
so i got the pitch i first heard the pitch from tim berners-lee in about
and i think in two thousand one to two thousand two
this was two thousand two hundred first are working for IBM
and to give a presentation and he said something like i'm going back car and
an image of business so so the the the light cruiser on its first try
as will have your eyes work
and i said OK listen
when you cut your ear off the mail it to me
so i did not think much of this idea
i mean doing KR since the mid eighties you know please what he what he
trying to tell what trying to some of you know there's nothing innovative here we've
been doing this stuff for almost twenty years
you always know if there's
and a i person in the audience because
that's the reaction to everything
you know
and the knowledge representation field no
knowledge acquisition does not scale
just doesn't scale
you can't
big knowledge acquisition from people is ridiculous
very complex let me explain to you the computer science complexity hierarchy
if you if you allow the idiots on the web two
build ontologies well look
you put that knowledge in a knowledge based system
it's going to be a bad system
all right so
i kind of missed
so here are some of the things that i was right about
you know actual reasoning you know what description logic OWL DL is exponential
by the way not tractable
case anyone was wondering
track anyway it's not tractable to very complex worst case takes a long time
people accidentally fall into the worst case
you know worst case part of the algorithm sometimes without realizing that they're doing it
you know look bad ontologies do lead to bad systems
first of all and i think most importantly
and i'm going to talk about this again
what the semantic web added and what was innovative about it was not that it's
just adding tags to some KR language
what it what turns out to be the case on the web is that knowledge
acquisition from
everyone on the in the world that seems to be scaling perfectly fine
who who who could have predicted i certainly
never imagine that that could be the case
a lot of people don't actually care about the
the complexity of reasoning because they are not really interested in reason and i'll talk
more about that
and then
the most important lesson i think this community can learn is that
there was an improvement here over the way things were before adding some semantics to
the way people use the information on the web really wasn't improvement even if there
are things wrong with
and by the way
even in this community i find that a lot of people don't know the semantic
web vision so the the original ideas it was explained to me was that
if you look
on the web depending on how you count web pages the vast majority of web
pages are automatically generated from some back in data
and the idea
was to publish the schema for that data and the idea was not that
o and then this is your i think they provide some notion of identity on
the web which i'm going to talk a little bit about so the important critical
averaged over all samples will actually be the true loss
so we can actually replace that he h
this expectation under ghost samples as a tilde
in here and then we'll have the empirical on the true sample and an empirical
ghost sample
but the expectation of that
so that's what we've got here the expectation under s
of this quantity here which is now this is the average
of this this is this expression here
which are now replaces this year h
this is just doing that simple
so now what we're going to do is to move that he as of that
and that's going to correspond to a genuine
increase potentially because y is that case
i mean just go back
the way
here we're having to take a super age which maximizes this expectation
over yes still there
if we move the
still there outside we can choose the age to maximize this
for both as and they're still there
and on average are going to do with query therefore going to be able to
get a higher value because we're taking optimizing h over all choices of SNS tilde
rather than optimizing h forgiven given as
and the average investor
it's clear
so this actually increases by taking it's basically jensen in type inequality we're actually increasing
by bringing that yes tilde out
and we're left with this quantity
and now
we can this is this quantity we can now introduce the fact that the this
is now symmetrisation
because if you go back sorry if we go back here
back here
there's nothing really to distinguish once we move the
he as in the s older out there is nothing to distinguish SNS tilde in
this expression
and so we can just war
elements between the two without changing any of the
of the values the
and so we can again introduced this idea of
actually doing that explicitly
and we do that by adding in
an expectation over a random swapping
of corresponding so sigma i swaps is plus one minus one
and therefore
actually swaps these two it's minus one just effectively changes the roles of that ions
that i told
in that expression
so here the symmetrisation is actually introduced by this expectation over the signal
and sigma xi set is the set of plus one minus one variables
which are chosen with equal
probability random probability
and those are actually what the name rademacher comes from these are known as rademacher
the sigma lies
so just think of it as symmetrisation and and this swapping permutations we had before
OK and now finally you can
upper bound this by simply
splitting the sum into two halves
and taking the super over both halves into independently
and that again is
is only going to increase the value because you can choose the age to optimize
both individually
and so you end up with twice
this quantity where you have the absolute value
now there is the trick you can actually get rid of the absolute value but
that's the detail i what
i don't think it's important the standard definition is with the absolute value
and that now is what you end up with
and we're just going to call at rademacher complexity so it seems a little
strange at this stage we just follow through the sequence of arguments and we've ended
up with this quantity but if we now put that all together
it actually makes a very pretty picture
because if i just get through to the results here
what we have is
expected value of the function is less than its empirical value plus the rademacher complexity
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
one announcement the weekly quizzes on tuesday based on
homework nine which will cover
glasses and chemical kinetics
speaking of which that's something we started
talking about last day
found this cute called
kinetics is nature's way of making sure that everything doesn't happen all at once
and we looked at the
great loss was generated large shown here
the rate of consumption of a particular
reactant goes is some function of its instant concentration raised to the power which is
the order of reaction
the specific chemical rate constant k
is the proportionality
and k can be influenced by temperature through this arrhenius
type relationship which compares
the exponential of the
activation energy with the available for energy
and we saw that we can integrate the rate equation and put
the data to the test if we have a first order reaction we should get
a semi log
i dependence and i think about that
shown here
there's data showed you last day this is just the normal
the decrease in concentration with time typical attenuation curve if we put it to the
first order test according to this relationship which you get a straight line with slope
mines k
and we saw that in
special case of first order reactions make sense sometimes talk about half life in particular
with radioactive decay
we also look second order reactions which have a slightly different functional dependence shown here
and then we went back and looked at the underlying physical chemistry of the activation
so we came up with this
model which we presented in terms of mechanical analog
and we saw that we could
look at the decrease in chemical potential has not been monotonic but as requiring some
and so we have here the
energy stated the reactance one value the energy state of the products at a lower
value and the difference between those values is the driving force for the reaction delta
if the reaction but in order to get from
the reactance state of the product state we first have to activate and physically there
are a number of things that are going on
and at the end of lecture australian example with reference to an automobile
exhaust catalyst what's happening in terms of forming some kind of an activated complex which
allows the reactance two
we organise themselves so that they can recognise that there's an energy
to be gained by their
reacting with one another and how catalysts
facilitates this
and specifically we see that
there's a tiny tiny fraction of the population
distribution that has enough energy to surmount the activation barrier
the inhibitor and the catalysts respectively either impede the reaction by raising the effective activation
energy thereby lopping off an even greater amount of the distribution or
facilitate the reaction by
lowering the activation energy thereby making a greater fraction of the
thermal distribution available for participation in the reaction
i think that's
that's where we left off last day
so today what i'd like to do is to continue the whole discussion of
what is broadly termed rate phenomenon
chemical kinetics
is part of a unit here three o nine one one call rate processes AR
processes are basically processes that involve
the rate of change with respect to time rate of change with respect to time
and so one of course is chemical kinetics we just
i spent some time looking at
chemical kinetics but
there is another area that we want to touch upon and it's area called transport
transport phenomena
and the reason for talking about this when we think about how we process
materials in order to achieve solids with
desired properties we have to think about the two basics that are required to sustain
reactions and those are matter and energy so let's look at what's involved in each
of these matters
energy we have to furnish these to the reaction
so we're going to think about energy in terms of transport phenomena that gets us
into heat transfer
heat transfer
we're not going to discuss heat transfer in real what i can do everything that
we do
look at something that's
representative of transport phenomena
and if you look at mass transport
and mathematically there are many parallels between heat transfer and mass transport
when we talk about mass transport if we're trying to driver reaction we have to
do two things we have to deliver reactance to the site and we have to
remove products from the site
if we don't do both the reaction could either star or choking good example that
early in the semester we talked about the annenberg
the hindenburg was a good example of a reaction that had a huge driving force
a hydrogen explosion but they never did not explode because we had seven million cubic
feet of
and in order for that to react explosively we would have to deliver seven billion
cubic feet of oxygen instantaneously and we could do that
i couldn't do that so
because the reaction was star thanks to
a transport phenomena
instead of an explosion what we got was the bird
very different and as a result two thirds of the
occupants of the
of the vessel were able to
walk off and
not so many parishes otherwise would so transport phenomena clearly important in the dominant form
of mass transport in solids is diffusion
so we're talking about mass transport in solids we have to talk about diffusion that's
we're going to do it so let's
so that the probabilities are equal to certain things and they make an exact copy
of this new by the maximum to be assumption you get the exact same result
because because you have not changed the constraints on the distribution
remember this ignore the whole first order you know issue i just think of the
propositional case
and that ignore even though the logical let's suppose that you're special just conjunction right
the features that you typically have in markov networks
what i'm saying is like
you tell me a bunch of conjunction their probabilities right i turn the maximum entropy
crank and they and they in a negative input distribution
and you can give me any knowledge base that you want as long as it's
equivalent to the first one the resulting distribution will therefore also be the same
right i could stay the same set of constraints in many logical equivalent ways including
redundant was just by the beginning statements as long as the constraints of the same
right you're saying the same thing about the distribution maximum entropy which have the same
OK so now let's look at how we can learn a markov logic networks
so learning as as a christian mentioned is no longer just the
data for learning is no longer just you know a single table
it's multiple tables
there is an is effectively a relational database
so in statistical relational learning you can learn directly from the database with multiple relations
without having to some russian born into one
and here i'm going to make the closed world assumption which is the assumption that
every atom that is not in that this is false
this is often true it's also often not true if you don't want to make
the assumption that you need the
two versions of the other things that i'm going to describe here and we do
have those impressions but i'm not going to again in the interest of time not
going to go into that
and of course there's two main learning tasks this learning parameters or if you want
to think about that with the weights of the form in the MLN
and then the structure i e discovering the formulas themselves
and learning could be then generative discriminatively and what i'm going to do in this
part is you know briefly go over each of these
so learning
let's start with generative weight learning
the big thing that we're doing in statistical relational learning is removing the assumption of
i data
and this is justified because if you look at any the always the case that
is not i i d
in social networks people influence each other in nineteen medicine you know there's epidemics going
on in on the web pages point to each other and that's something about the
topics in molecular biology this metabolic networks etc etc
so we want to remove the assumption
but but the
the downside of that is like
now everything is depends on everything now life is going to be very hard right
everything's gonna blow up
this was our few going in
as it turns out
the basic learning problem
it doesn't really change that much when you remove the idea assumptions
so we get a lot of power and in fact something that is not be
let's see
why that's the case and and also where you know the additional difficulties are because
of course they have to go somewhere
so what we want to do
we want to maximize the likelihood so i have a set of formulas i don't
know their weights and i have the database
i want to learn the weights for the forms that maximize the likelihood of the
data is
well first of all the good news is that this is a convex optimisation problem
there's only one global optimum right so i don't have local optima problems the bad
news is that there is no closed form so we do and even if we
need to do something like within the the centre lbfgs or you know conjugate gradient
one of those things
another great has very intuitive form which is very similar to the form that it
has four learning markov random fields
and it's as follows
the derivative the partial derivative of the log likelihood with respect to weight
it's just the difference
between the number of true groundings of the corresponding clause in the data that's the
sufficient statistics
and the expected number of true groundings according to to the model
so what happens is that if my model is predicting that this clause is true
less often than it really is its weight needs to go up
if it's pretty and that's more often than it really is the way it needs
to go down and once they all line up with that we've reached the maximum
likelihood solution
and notice that there's a there's this
a small but very large difference between this
and i i d case
in the in the in that i think is what i did was i counted
over my idea over my idea instances
what's happening here that's difference is that i'm counting over groundings of cause
which means that in the ideal case i have only one way of tying parameters
one way
across the instances now
i can type parameters anyway that i want to my heart's content
i wanted to find himself tied parameters i just find the corresponding one
so even though the math is still basically the same
this is much more powerful because now i have complete freedom to type things
you can think of the bias right the learning bias
in learning in markov logic network is that it is is the parameter tying happens
at the runnings of this was in the grounds of that
now of course there's the catch there has to be kept somewhere the catch is
that this is very hard to compute
now this was you know these expectations right requires inference
so those are already intractable in the propositional case but now you know this intractable
but they're going to be over an even bigger problem
so now i'm doing gradient descent with inference in each of the steps this is
probably going to be very slow
so the question is can i do something else
well when we have a problem that's too hard to follow a good strategy is
to change the subject
so one way to change the subject here is to instead of optimizing the likelihood
optimise what's called the pseudo likelihood right which is as the name implies a fake
the so called is something that's designed to behave as much like the likelihood as
possible while being tractable
so this is the likelihood
of state is just the
product over all variables
of the conditional probability of variable given its neighbors
in the state in the data
i e given the state of its markov blanket
so as you see this requires no inference
and if you combine this with you know fast in optimizer like lbfgs the learning
is actually quite efficient you can then you know large complicated melons in a matter
of minutes
of course the likelihood is not a new idea for something it works very well
okay so
the question was how bad way is it to just sample randomly from the parameters end compute the likelihood
it's very good for small datasets
that's a great way of approximating this but what happens is
this likelihood
under i models
it gets exponentially
shorter with more datasets around some parameter values
so sampling from your prior and trying to evaluate the likelihood
is gonna be like looking for needles in the haystack as they say
basically your priors putting its mass all over the place where you're likely it is
only sharply peaked at a few points and so that's sampler will take a very
long time is that it's unbiased
but it'll take a very long time to get the right answer yes
any questions
all right
so let's look in particular at this
this bayesian model comparison
four the polynomials case
i shown you these same eight data points again
well the zero to the seventh order polynomials
the blue
remember is the maximum likelihood polynomial
the green lines are samples from the e posterior polynomials
twenty samples
condition on the data
under certain priors
to be precise
i put calcium priors on thee
o my polynomial
with some
variance which
matters but
you know we can discuss how matters
an inverse gamma prior on the
noise variance sigma squared
now with those priors
i can sample exactly from
the posterior over the polynomials which are drawn in green here and i can also
compute the marginal likelihood exactly and analytically
and here is what we get for these eight data points and these particular priors
my marginal likelihood renormalize this scale here
but my marginal likelihood essentially is putting
all of its mass on
zero zeroth first second third order
and the masses are getting smaller and smaller fourth fifth sixth and seventh
you can even see them on the scale
and if you look at this intuitively makes sense
given the data that we've observed here
the most consistent hypothesis is that it's a quadratic
but it constant
polynomial is also quite reasonable because it could be a lot more noise for example
any questions about this
i can run a demo people want
thank you
okay here is another example
o another
eight data points
anne again thee
the best fits
so it's a fifth-order
i am the
in this case these quadratic comes out overwhelmingly
any questions that
maybe just to twenty data points
what do you think it was generated from
it was actually quadratic
happens if i do
right this case
so this with three data points
yeah question
yes i i have to be careful with my words here
we're not searching
anyone could be searching for the best model because
maybe we are working with the client
and the choir was see what model when they were doing scientific data analysis
and we wanna concluded in the paper that one model is overwhelmingly more probable than any other models
of course if we want to do prediction
what we need to do is average the predictions over the different models weighted by their posterior as
it's you know the better the same bayesian model comparison the bayesian model selection
because model selection basically implies it should apply some cost function forward you know which
you know
what would you prefer to select
how do i sample these green things
this relates to what i'm gonna talk about very soon
in this case
these integrals
because i chose what's called conjugate priors
the posterior over the parameters is also conjugate which means i can actually analytically
represent the posterior r it turns out that the posterior over the coefficients is galcians
so i just have this
draw a sample from a multivariate calcium
and then draw the corresponding polynomial with those coefficients
that's what i do
so what about choosing priors there are different schools farhat choose priors
there's a whole subfield of
is called objective basis
where they tried to come up with objective priors
and these tend to be noninformative priors that attempt to capture
some form of complete ignorance
and have good frequentist properties so for example you mention jeffreys priors that's something that's
a very classical objective priors it's been used
quite frequently
subjective priors
say that's all
we really wanted to they are priors capture your beliefs as well as possible
and there are subjective but not arbitrary so different
people could have different priors coming into
particular modeling domain
hand is not arbitrary because your prior represents your beliefs he beliefs are not arbitrary
and nothing is arbitrary but what you do afterwards because once you specify a prior
and you have your data and everything else follows from from the rules
hierarchical priors on these are not mutually exclusive i mean i can have hierarchical partners
around in the sixties
also pearl i guess in his book in the eighties in
they i
i spoke about the use recent passing of message passing on graphs with cycles
so your question was
if you have cycles how does the ordering of the messages affect things
cycles are where there is no clear answer ordering can affect whether or not it
because there can be multiple fixed points the ordering can affect which fixed point you
go to
there's been a fair bit of work there are some citations in the in the
book that i give you a fair bit of work on trying to make good
schedule means of belief propagation on graphs with cycles
some of my own work studied schedules in which you choose the tree of the
graph and you pass the messages along the tree and then you choose another tree
and you do that that can be better in some settings
some other people have studied what's called adaptive message passing where you you sort of
look at every note how much of the messages fluctuating in that region
they're not changing much then i probably don't need to update because it's you know
it's close to being happy was if they're changing like maybe i should pay more
attention so that's really an ongoing area of research there isn't a clear answer but
i think there's pretty good heuristics at this point for that
any other questions
OK so the question is why
these algorithms are exact for trees while the sunday to become inexact when you have
there's different ways i can explain this
one way is that
when i went to this derivation
right why do you end up taking the product of messages here
the reason the product is the right thing to do if you look at the
algebra is because when you have a graph
the does not have cycles
notes four and five there
you can sort of imagine subtrees growing off of each of them
right there might be part of a bigger graph
and if there's no cycle then i know that nodes four and five are
can be thought of as the roots of subtrees and there is no interaction between
those subtrees rooted at four and five
so it's because of that fact because there are no cycles there is no interaction
between the subterms
it's because of the that fact that the correct thing to do is to take
the product
if you had cycles you see there is an additional term that you're neglecting
that there be some interaction if there is an edge between four and five were
further down in the subtrees and that would lead to errors
another intuition for actually member yesterday we spoke about conditional independence properties
another way of thinking about these actually from the conditional independence point of view is
the interpretation of this message is that node three is summarizing to know too
everything no two needs to know about this part of the graph
now we know from conditional independence properties that node three is the cutset if i
cut node three out it will break two
and one of from three
no break four and five often three of great in this case would break the
graph into three parts
and when you have conditional independence so because you have the cut said it means
that conditioned on three
these two contributions are independent conditionally of each other so conditional independence when you
i have independent sort of means you should multiply things
and that's that's really and another sort of interpretation why the product happens the product
happens because of statistical conditional independence to different way of deriving the algorithm
any other questions
i feel like i'm a tennis match
o and i know there are results for so you asking for message passing on
graphs with cycles
there's only a line of work i think the first person who got some understanding
exactly on the single cycle graphs was you your y in i think nineteen nine
gavin hormone also in his phd thesis at caltech around the same time had some
related results on single cycle graphs
there's a lot of work on graphs now that are what are called locally tree
locally treelike means that if it's a it's graph that is not a tree it
has cycles
that means that if you're in and then you start wondering from one node and
you wonder along edges you'd wonder long time before you come back you find the
cycle and come back to yourself
so if if you build certain classes of random graphs you can show that there
there tree like locally
and they have girth girth is the length of the shortest cycle in a graph
the graph logarithmic in the graph size
for those graphs you can say a lot actually and that example i showed yesterday
with the code it was based on the graph that was locally treelike
and that's part of the reason why message passing work so well is because the
graphs are not trees but there's somehow up to some approximation they look like trees
yes so for instance the canonical examples if you do a grid or lattice which
i'm going to start with the left off
yesterday i hope somebody remembers what we talking about yesterday just in case you don't
we were going to do we basically has to be added
a very brief introduction to planning and then look a variety of our tracks that
the work
learning and planning as they can
and in particular the case of one which is talking about learning search control and
we started looking at the first look at the fact that knowledge based learning
planets with humans like the knowledge
do extremely well are compared to even the current best state of the art domain
independent planets which only have the main physics
so that sort of open source the possibility that are
learning techniques can be used to
improve that
the planning performance
so we look at the kinds of knowledge that
people have been handed down and then we started looking at the whole some of
what the sorts of that knowledge that actually can be automatically learned right now another
mentioned yesterday
not everything that is actually written by humans learn about so there are certain types
of knowledge in fact such as hierarchical task networks there not yet there are no
i think you them right now
effective techniques for learning experience however i can at least tell you the kinds of
things that we already know how to to do it and
and then the rest will be open so you get to do it and then
we will of course after that is all we look at learning the domain knowledge
itself if you don't have the in physics information how you learned and then and
situations where you have all of the fired
basically partial domain knowledge and so you're trying to learn what the domain knowledge
six hundred at the same time
and that's pretty much open right now
so we we were staring at this and in fact i just wanted to this
was the learning from the new using explanation based learning techniques we just started talking
about the last time and i just got this hundred replacement thing on my main
put in the day
do that what it does mean that you go through all of two minutes later
by the six hundred six times in the time and six and five times at
least one of the things went wrong and fix this kind of work so i
don't know whether they actually learn anything from the value but i thought it was
good thing
the idea here is that connects so in this case we were talking about a
search control of a third in
i'm planning problem may it turned out that this particular branch created and what you
want to learn is some sort of the tries rule which tells the learner which
does plan that don't ever get into this branch again
OK and we were talking about
this point that if you can somehow explain why this guy
and if the explanation is smaller than the entire line here which is very important
in fact you've explanation of you feel you is yourself if your explanation of a
plan plan uris on the constantinople and then that he doesn't work you can OK
if there is a subset in this
plan constraints that can actually be
used to explain why the plan failed then you can sort of see them through
the thirty three
looking at so for example in this case i this branch failed because this is
actually a partial order plan scenario this plan failed because you are trying to make
a step zero come before one but step zero except one valid is supposed to
come before zero
and it turns out those constraints while those constraints inconsistent and so that's the smallest
explanation of value for this branch with this this plan has been extended and there
similar failure commission there what you're doing right now
his explanation for failure back up the tree
trying to figure out who is to blame and under what conditions should do not
how gotten into the ground to begin so this is an example
learning search control using this kind of analysis for example as i mentioned yesterday
a rule that you could learn here
he is in fact the sort of like you learn here
i would say that
something like this so that if you are trying to achieve an open admission policy
and when it
goes away from you
rolling objects that's roll something down the hill
classic problem
very often you see that
on exams
whitaker ball
and we roll it down
an inclined
this inclined
the angle is better
he was the ball
the sphere
it's a solid sphere has mass and
israelis are
and in the solid
this is the centre
of the ball i call this morning
i put all the forces on that i can think of
is an engineer
at this point p
normal force
on the surface
and there is friction
this is the frictional force the sum of ff
and the normal force is what we call the contact force
that is the force
which which
inclined pushes back into the ball we normally decompose that
in the direction along the slope of the
these are the only three forces
that is objects
is experiencing
and i can ask you know what is a acceleration
goes down the slope
i can ask you what is the frictional force
i ask you it under the conditions of neural
well this pure only
it means that if this conference here
more one centimetre
at the centre of mass has also moved one step
so it means that the velocity
of the centre
so this velocity
of see
all moments in time
will be omega are
the angular velocity
which is changing with time
that is the condition of pure
at all moments in time
if i have a rotating
sphere or cylinder
will the circle inferential
speed the omega are
it could be standing still and is rotating like this sleeping like hell not moving
then the circum ferentials b is always omega are
if the centre also move was that seems to be only then do we call
it euro
if you take the derivative of this
you get a equals only got times are
the course of our
also being angular
all right we're going to write down
talk relative to that point c
if i take points c
i lose the force and g
lose the force and there's only one force
that i have to do is
relative to point c
the fact that the talk is in the blackboard is of no concern to me
i just want to know the magnitude
it is
times f
are times the friction before
that must be the moment of inertia about point about the points in times of
we've seen is now twice already
and so since all is a defined by our
it is i seen
divided by r
this is one equation
and i have a as unknown
and i have for now
there's not enough anymore
newton's second law always holds
the centre of mass
for the centre of mass
must always holds as equals and made
all i don't know where got the centre of mass and i say
what the forces which are acting down the slope i'm not interested in the ones
perpendicular to the the slope only to ones down the slope
that must be and made a non-negotiable because that is the quality characteristic of the
centre of mass
this one is uphill
and the only one that is down here is the component of g
along the slope which is angie sign beta
i call that the plaster action
so i get ng
sign beta
that frictional force
times age
and in in in terms of goals involves instead of looking at the original models
so examples are various kinds of neural networks actually converge to get across the limit
where the number of hidden units increases basically because you do a similar construction
the relevance vector machine is a special kind of gas process
support vector machines are very closely related to golf courses and there are a bunch
of other
examples of this is just one example
so the question is what about the but i showed you any non stationary
so i guess this one is actually started begin nonstationary because it has
of the behaviour of the and thought
so things like a neural network kernel is typical
example of a non stationary one neural networks will have the tendency that the model
the model to have a lot of action in the central region and then the
the sample function will tend to converge to fixed functions
as you move away from from the origin
these are the squared exponential kernel for template reverts back to zero
when you go far away from
from the data that you can but that's just the consequence of this that you
can have a look at the properties so they can converge to
six values when you move or this is something which is which is useful for
many modelling i think the squared exponential or the newer network rail actually
shown here
this quite interesting model to use
and it's a lot easier to use the counting process with this with the network
on is that training on
OK so here is
here's another example
which is
thought i would be appropriate i also promise somebody to to to talk about this
since i also talked about bayesian inference so
it's going to be an example about anything about
the the likelihood principle like principle says something about something like
that the
the result of the inference bayesian inference is only allowed to depend on the likelihood
of the data that you actually observed
and your observations and it depends on anything else then there's something wrong with your
procedure that that's not allowed
so the question was you know do any procedures we depend on anything else is
not completely safe
and i show an example where you were going to depend on something better than
that taken in a really out and
and i'll show you what bayesian fixes in that case
OK so
a lot of these problems were interested in evaluating intervals of the form we have
an in support some function of x
times the probability distribution over x
so there there are some examples here especially if you are bayesian you have to
do this all the time and for many functions that's nasty what you can do
that closed form
we don't know how to do that
here's an example
one example is you want to make you want to make
predictions from the model
then you have to average
the predictive distribution with respect to the posterior distribution
that's an integral that you have you have to do that has this particular form
of the prior distribution over the variables that you want to integrate out some of
the function of
no example is
you want to work on the marginal likelihood
the marginal likelihood is
the integral of the prior
the likelihood
again probably distribution over all the variables
and some of the function of the
and for many many many cases have many variables these designs in creating an extremely
integral to have to work out
and there are bunch of other examples as well
let's try and think about
how do you
how do you solve this problem
using monte carlo
the basic idea in monte-carlo is that you
things go
with the summer
and i have some
she evaluations of f here
and then i just take the average of those evaluation may take the values of
from the distribution
if i can somehow generate samples random distribution then i can evaluate sum
and none of them very mild conditions this thing converges to the value of the
interval here as t increases
in many cases
well if you can draw samples from this distribution and then you can just justify
that and that will give you an estimate taken of sample then
things will converge
in other cases it might be like not easy to draw samples from p of
x and if that's the case you can do
a little trick called or something
so you simply
something which is very similar to what happened in this morning when you multiply and
divide by some arbitrary distribution qx
and then you think of the you have you have you know
at times p divided by q times q
so that the slope of the degree distribution doesn't move but since power law this
funny distribution that can have infinite expectation what happens is that if
the mode is now here is you get a zero network grows the mold also
side of the mean of the distribution shifts and this gives you the densification so
that if you go back and analyse their at least two cases that can happen
one is the tale distribution gets better and mean increases the other one is that
you have that you have a specific exponent
but these last less than two the building and q i know infinite expectation which
means the more samples you get
the expectation of the distribution
there there
i would say
so so for example this is the
but this no
we have to have
so in this case write a very simple case seems
this is known to be connected to to all our other nodes right so we
could be here and to be always connected everyone knows that is connected to all
other what's right and then
and then this these nodes nodes so the nodes in here will be connected to
smaller portions but that would be more of
right so it's not
the degrees it really
so now instead of having zero one i can have here i j
the probability of having an edge
so i have like a probabilistic counterpart so i have no probabilities i do the
same the same multiplication and this would probabilities here
and then i can sample the graph from these by just these biased coins so
for every cell ago exactly
yeah so probabilities probabilities and now i go three coins to get the samples from
exactly exactly
is is
so you
i think
i was thinking about
it is doing
on the other hand
you could think of this process i don't give in to the hierarchy said i
mean hierarchy
right distract so you have this i communities right and then you have abstracted them
and over and they are all similar radionuclides so this is one way but is
just the input eleven but explicitly going for i wasn't planning to that
as well as
on the blog web page
so we have some preliminary experiments on that just a little situation for the bottom
line is that it is the technology blog
well what is going on the computer what it's like for weeks if you like
and then
michelle model which is like what political
and the reason is the
in in
in slashdot you're the cascades tend tend to be like che shallow and very
very wide like they tend to like this so that i know some sporting slashdot
picks up and then all these people say oh i read this interesting thing was
there's nothing happened well if you look at the political blogs because gauge that tend
to be
deep and not so wide
this is
what want some some observations we got so we found that the enslaved type of
blog cascades just wide
very shallow y here are deep and narrow some
but the plan to study these
so this is all
paul's school
so you could even looking at the
the message
but if you're looking for the maximum then you have to usually people have also
assume that the graph is connected otherwise you have these infinity problem right yusuf
the nodes are not connected and there are distance infinity ward they look at physicist
look at the
average so the average over the distribution of the of the shortest path
in football that there are
there are claims for that
one not proof
the children it slowly increases like logarithmically on log log n so
and what we chose
it was to do
basically we tried many different things and the idea and settle down with this one
but we also tried just the average we also tried to maximum
and you didn't make any difference is
these models
i don't think so
and even if this
one the say
kind of like you cannot rely
i don't know
i would say no
the work
what it is
as a whole
should actually
i would like to know
many most triples here
so there should be
there should be
i been on the main like incremental growth
and so that they have like independent samples in some sense
the other thing is
the future
that's fine but should have that should be here
you're the only thing is
he has this other rather weak assumption which can be described in words
as happiness selection algorithm needs to be better than random guessing
that's a pretty weak assumption i mean otherwise don't don't use any machine just throw
a coin so
this is a weak assumption this is strong assumption and then
you get this finite sample by the expected number of false positives
it is bounded by this very simple formula
so the formula actually wall he was clear so you have your top fifty variables
so you have fifty square divided by p
note if p is large this is a great thing here
so this is really geared towards high dimensional stuff
and then you have to think one of the two
pi treshold minus one
so now we to point around and you say OK like usually statistics be fixed
the type one error in significance testing is say five percent on now you say
i want to tolerate
expected number of false positives ten
twenty this is up to you
you keep in mind how many false positives you tolerate you go into these formulas
and then use all over europe i so this is the solution how you can
draw the line what is the threshold line such that eventually control the expected number
of false positives
this is a very very general theorem
the issue is really it works
i mean the only thing
and the first ten days
it just needs to be better than random guessing
and the second thing is it's not only for regression this work for any
selection problem so it can be a graph and you can ask me age is
in or out to can be a cluster can ask whether an observation is in
the cluster in or out for any in or out problem we can apply theory
so this goes way beyond variable selection in linear model is can be applied to
kind of discrete selection problem
arguably if you have such a general theorem there is no free lunch there's a
condition here
and the condition is very strong and it's easy to write down the condition harder
kind of
convinced that the condition would hold the condition is exchangeability condition and all what we
require is
that the distribution
that is the j th variable is selected by our algorithm and how you look
for all j for all the covariance in the linear model which are not to
be active so these are all the noise covariance
this is a multivariate distribution have to be exchangeable so you can permute
the labels for the noise coming in always the same distribution
it's simple condition to write down but it will be hard to be satisfied
OK so
the thing is maybe what i should say here
OK let's discuss the condition briefly in the linear model said
the first interesting thing is
i told you before for variable selection in linear model we had to design assumptions
and we had this debate i mean assumption which there's the non-zero relational coefficients need
to be sufficiently large
so here there's nothing like this involved
this is great
but the thing is this is only about
false positive so this is only one point of the middle if you talk about
false negative stuff you would miss
then again something of that sort that the signal is strong enough but even if
the signal is super week
in terms of false positive control you don't need to make any assumptions
and exchangeability condition is really restrictive so
for example you can argue in linear model
that if you have a correlation then it holds but if you go to more
complex coalition structure doesn't
the thing is if
this exchangeability condition and the whole theory is as of yet much too rough exchangeability
condition is certainly not
necessary and sufficient so we actually don't know where to bound is this this kind
of approach
so you should not believe because exchangeability doesn't hold the method isn't good
we still as through because the conditions necessary condition doesn't all the loss is not
here we don't know actually what the necessary conditions
so here is a numerical experiments maybe just before the sake the break i don't
know whether i that but i tried to do so
it was simply variable selection in linear models using the last so and we look
at a range of scenarios so what you see is lot here
well maybe explain the range of scenarios
p six hundred sixty is from a real data set design
matrix x from a real motivation data
max likelihood you just say the robots there and that's all i know
in the bayesian approach
you say that my wife particles
that's where the likelihood is you see this little bit of mass this overlapping here
the product of those three normalized
is that so my data believe is well somewhere quite close like if i had
more accurate census the width of this likelihood is the accuracy of my sense if
i would if i increase the accuracy of the centre which goes down of pulled
more towards
maximum likelihood solution if i'm more uncertain about where i was initially i'm full more
towards maximizing solution if i was well where i was initially people less towards it
so that is really odd situation for gaussians because what actually happens in common filters
for example are based entirely on this
that's some
you the gas in prague as you like in your serious calcium that's very unusual
normally you don't have a prime
to likelihood to steer where everything is the same distribution i think as is the
only example i know of
sometimes you get the same class distributions for your prior your posterior
and those are called conjugate models and that's really nice computational for a major criticism
of bayesian inference is that we don't actually choose these things
for what we believe we choose for tractability so we choose its conjugate models which
give us nice tractable
quality is not and i think that's about
make things faster makes the algorithms fast
so they are confronted by counting like thousand posterior
but if they like and is not as one approach is to approximate the posterior
with a gas so is it ever likely
you might start with the priors
over whether you think i'm going to say anything intelligent or anything down
in this talk and
you might be observing
if i say something intelligent that's an observation of one and if i see something
dumb observation of minus one now how
you've got an idea of where i am along this line so if i'm here
on intelligent and if i'm down here
i'm and rights
i'm down here the probability of something done is very high and the probability and
say something intelligent is one minus that market probability i'm saying something intelligent is high
the probability of say something dumb islam
or you could even think of this as well i'll come up for example is
OK so this is your prior to think i'm
it made up
and then what happens i say something intelligent
so you observe this thing this is not likely to notice not normalized in any
way or form this is the function
in fact the distribution of something discrete right so just sums the two are two
different things some to
one of the two different probabilities so i say something intelligent and then that the
so now you move a little bit you think well
you know
he he probably in this regime because i you know he's only one intelligent thing
and you considered by accident so
i'm going to assume is i have a a little bit more intelligent but not
that much more so one trick
i'd like to include a difficult if you do this model is once you've done
this is a really simple model but the x-box
ranking system for quality of players is based entirely on this model and what i'm
going to do next
which is to replace that
nongaussian nasty thing we think that they a
so truncated gaussians convolution this a squashing function of the gaussians with the gaussians and
the way one can do that is by fitting this halcyon to the pink curve
that we have before now i think that was a great until i saw some
of josh's calcium fits to his data sets for the film stuff that's really that's
about the same as the film fit but it can be really bad because these
gases can be completely truncated so this can be a bad thing to do and
i think what you've done so this is the trick
once you've done this you can then proceed with another observation
so you can then
you can then say something dumb and then you can drop down and rest
one thing to notice is because of the quality of some characteristics of these log
likelihoods here
and in fact it's the
log concavity of the
big so it's likely not log likelihood divided the logarithm you would see is concave
it has of nasty property i think for called science point of view i everything
think it's nasty what will happen if this likelihood is concave and most likely to
use r is every time you make an observation you become more confident about what
you see
so basically i think that's very counterintuitive for maybe it's
maybe it's because i'm learning all these good words i can see maybe it's because
of introspection and i think the way i update my beliefs on my myself thinking
there is not said anything really good yes so i just keep thinking not very
clever clever but then this is something
really clever
then i would increase my uncertainty
and increased my belief that i thought someone has said that i thought the person
was clear right that's what i would do i think i was wrong i was
wrong to be confident about what that person was doing
that's what these models because the concavity of the likelihood in fact they
their uncertainty in its all pretty much if you look at in terms of entropy
and pretty much
linear type away
even here i said something really dumb and really intelligent really don't really intelligent really
you just become really confident
about whether i was intelligent you would be like oh i'm completely at a loss
and i think that the intuition is that that's what you should be thinking about
how i feel
i have opinions and i'm very opinionated actually
it's can create
he's not quite as maybe that's not we thought
how many people have heard it can create
and yet so so he's he's not quite as famous as another famous englishman who was born
exactly a hundred years ago but
he is well worth reading he was basically reinventor of cognitive science and in psychology in in
britain and he
in in a classic work that he wrote just shortly before he died tragically in a bike accident his
really laid out this idea of a view of what kind of machine the mind
might be which is basically a simulation engine an engine built these kind of wonderful
mental models end users them fore
for all the different tasks of commonsense intelligence reasoning planning explanation and so on
and it's it's it's a fascinating view which then influence the tradition work on mental
models other other kinds of any i people who've been influenced by his ideas the
sort of qualitative reasoning tradition
which again is is one which has not been traditionally associated with say probabilistic inference
but another way to understand what we're trying to get at with these probabilistic programs
is bringing those traditions together
and ask them OK so let's actually put these interaction
how might you say capture this learning concepts from a few examples well somehow you
gotta take all the objects that you've seen here and represents something about the structure
of the domain the generative processes that gave rise to what you see
and link the concept is something in the generative structures so something like for example
but we a biologist might look at objects and think about the evolutionary process processes
that give rise to them
you might look at these objective organising some kind of hierarchical
taxonomic tree
that reflect some intuitions about
about which are what they have in common the generative processes that gave rise and
the parts that grow for example
and then you see
a few examples of a new concept like those over there and tree
and you make some gas
all the above aware there
where there were the concept refers to
the exactly how we capture is a bayesian inference i'm not gonna go into the technical details but basically
have hypotheses which are the branch point in the tree you assume that the possible
concepts each branch of the tree
end they belong to the branch the more distinctive it is for the higher prior
probability it has been labeled by word
and then there's a likelihood which is just captures the suspicious coincidence seeing those three
things all cluster they're not part of the tree
you can say well these these three examples here they could also be an instance
of say concept labeling background background background but then it would be a big coincidence
to see them all the first examples cluster
and without strong hypothesis space just a couple of examples provides enough statistical leverage the
figure out that the concept is basically just those things there are not anything else
and we can just as i showed you for the everyday predictions turn this into a quantitative predictive model
that we can compare with how both adults and children generalize words but but i'm
not going to tell you the details this experiment because i wanted to emphasize more
these deeper questions of where the abstract knowledge comes from
what leads to these probabilistic programs
so how in particular did you figure out that should be building tree means in
you know we but think about objects is organised something like a tree structure
there are taxonomic relations but there's other domains reasoning there
have other kinds structures
so in some very be work charles kemp did when he was
in a group
he gave what you could think of as a kind of hierarchical bayesian
approach to learning abstract structure different domains that is it may be the first bit
of kind of hierarchical bayesian program induction at least we worked on where we say
we what we observe is at the at the bottom here is some
features object system let's say the features animals are plants or something
and then
we assume those were giving rise to by some kind of
process operates some kind of stochastic processes operating over let's say a some kind of
graph structure let's say here's a tree structure
what we want to learn is not only the tree that underlies those particular argument
domain but that the general principle which says it's a tree as opposed to some
other kind of structure
and so charles' idea was to represent that's higher level knowledge is something like a
graph grammar so it's it's a principle
a little rule
that generates structures of a particular constraints sort namely trees
and then by by by by giving different kinds of graph grammars we can grow
at different kinds of structures like chains or rings are cylinders are grids and so
and by doing inference at
multiple levels of this hierarchy these these two you can simultaneously inferred
grammar that's most likely to have generated the data domain as well as the most
likely graph if you like the parts of the observed data under the grammar so
it's directly analogous to a kind of grammar induction and a couple problems with grammar
induction passing in language
and this is just a couple of results from this from this model
given a dataset animals and features this this approach was able to figure out that
it was organised something like a tree structure to learn kind organising principle
but say for example given
data on the on
voting patterns of supreme court justices in the ust was able to figure out not
tree structures as most appropriate but actually a linear structure here is you know that
might be there might be a little small see but here we've got e s
s supreme court justices who served under the rehnquist court
and you've got the sort very liberal ones here on the left and the very
right wing one scalia and thomas and so on over there on the right and
that this this album is figuring out
that's out of all the these different possible simple forms of structure for the data
that consists of how they voted on different cases
just as a tree structure is the most appropriate to think about animals and their
properties or one-dimensional chain structures are familiar left-right continuum is the most appropriate structure there
or for example given distances between cities it figures out that something like a cylinder
cross between it chain and ring
roughly corresponding to a constant latitude longitude is the right way to represent the data
so it beginning to show how hierarchical bayesian approach could learn something that we really
want call a kind of abstract knowledge
here's another application of this to a more causal reasoning setting where inaugural familiar with
the idea of bayes net learning has a kind of probabilistic inference we can say
OK so
i'm tom minka i'm going to talk you about approximate inference
at this point you probably very excited about graphical models and bayesian inference and you
want to run home and
implements some models
the problem is is you quickly find is that
many times exact and the answers are invisible or if you try to use something
is going be very slow
so what you like to do is do something which is both fast and bayesian
and that's what i'm going to talk about today
so for example if you want to do
real time processing of an online data set or if you have huge database you
want to process that through these methods book welcoming
so i'm going to be focusing on bayesian inference in this talk so let me
just give a quick overview i think basing so important and so useful i think
if you want a formal definition basically what does it mean to be bayesian it
just means that you consistently use probability theory for reasoning about anything you don't know
so if you have a latent variable if you missing data priors you'll always represent
that uncertainty with probability distributions
and and
i mean that's useful in a sense because now all the elements are consistent every
organ can handle these unknowns in exactly the same way you can make very general
procedures for reasoning about all kinds of different models but is actually another advantage which
is what chris talked about this morning which is much area so by using bayesian
inference uses actually get this very nice decoupling of different things so you can decouple
for example your model from your decision making process
so what i do is i like to think of bayesian inference is sort of
flow diagram
where you have data one and
and you have your model
and you put these two together
and you get a posterior distribution
right now if you want to make decisions as chris show this morning
all you need is the posterior distribution you don't need to go back to your
data so here loss matrix changes you can just go to your posterior and ask
what my decision b
or if you are priors in different classes change you can again just make a
decision based on the posterior already had enough to go back to your data so
it's always my in that sense it summarize everything you need to know what the
and if you get more data for example in an online streaming context
you just take your posterior you incorporated
use it as the prior to the new data you have to get new posterior
and again you know the data so it's very very efficient
we processing data if you think about it now but appealed associated businesses being slow
but actually i think of it as being very very fast processing because this property
so he decided basically summarizes what i just said
the posterior distribution is your friend to summarise everything you have learned from
the data
right so instead of thinking of data which i think about distributions
and essentially describe
your training data to make predictions you do online learning
the problem is
how can we efficiently represent compete with these posterior distributions because often very complicated and
so that's what i'm going to talk about how we can actually make this into
practical procedure
now the tool that we use today
is a very very important innovation actually which is factor graphs images typographical model
which is actually i think the best way of thinking about
approximate inference algorithms in terms of factor graphs so let me just give you a
quick rse summary of what it was another to give a talk on this but
let me just give my own take on a factor graph is so factor graphs
basically can be applied to any function it isn't it isn't something specific to probability
theory can might any function or does it just shows you way of factoring this
function into product terms and obviously this is not unique you can take a given
function factored in many different ways of take a polynomial for example i can factor
in various ways
and effective after shows you one particular way affecting the function
so here i give an example of a function f of x y z is
not distributions just a function it happens to factor in this way was y y
fuzzy ecstasy
and given that factorisation i can now use a factor graph represent factorizations so what
is the factor graph of this function well
first of all i have my variables
x y
and for each term in my factorisation just make box and i connected to each
of the
variables it uses so the first term is the boxes x y the second term
is the boxes lines e
and third terms boxes e
so that's the factor graph for this factoring of this function
there's yet another kind of covalent modification
which it which is the process of like oscillation
in which
a series of sugar side chains carbohydrate side chains is covalently attached to the polypeptide
usually on serine or threonine is using the hydroxyl of the side chains earrings of
readings to attack these polypeptide these are all legal sector right side chains
we we know from our discussion last time only go right means a an assembly
of a small number of
model right in each of these blue hexagons represents a model sector right which are
covalently linked and also modify the extracellular domain of this protein as it protrudes into
extracellular space so i'm just opening our eyes to the to the possibility that in
the future we're going to talk about
other ways in which proteins are modified to further
two not their structure to make them more suitable more competent to do the various
jobs to which they have been assigned
that's therefore returned to what we talked about the last time
the fact that the structure of the nucleic acids is based on the simple principle
here by the way i'm returning to the notion of this
numbering system we're talking about pantos nucleic acids
the fact that there are two hydroxyl is here right away tells us that we're
looking at arrivals
rather than a deoxyribose which as i said last time lacks this sugar right there
note as we've said repeatedly
the hydroxyl side chains of
of carbohydrates offer numerous opportunities for using dehydration reactions or as they are sometimes called
condensation reactions where you remove the water
we take out water dehydration
or we can call the condensation reactions
two attach other things and in fact in principle
there are actually four different hydroxyl so it could be used here to do that
there's one here is one here
one here
and one here the four different drugs cells the the one of the two three
and five
i dropped so are in principle opportunities for further modification
in truth
the two prime hydroxyl is rarely used as well discussed shortly but the main actors
are therefore this hydroxyl here in which a condensation reaction is created a glycol city
that is the bond between a sugar and on sugar entity
glycol refers obviously the sugars like i kitchen or
glycosylation we talked about before here upon has been made between the base and we'll
talk about the different bases shortly and
and the one prime hydroxyl of the rivals
over here
the five provide rocks yet another
condensation reactions
sometimes this is called esterification reactions
and again
refers to
these kinds of condensation reactions where an acid and base
react with one another and once again through a condensation reaction yields the removal of
the water
and let's look at what's happening here because not only is one hundred one phosphate
group attached
the five prime
the carbon to the five prime hydroxyl in fact there are three
and there are located in that each of them has a name
the in board one is called alpha moving further out as being the furthest out
is gamma
and it turns out that this chain of phosphates has very important implications for energy
metabolism and for biosynthesis
i'm glad i asked that question because these are all three are highly negatively charged
this is not going to this is in this is that you know
negative charges repel one another
and as a consequence to create triphosphate linkage like this represents pushing together negative charge
more it is these three phosphate even though
they don't like to be next to one another and that pushing together the creation
of the triphosphate change
represents an investment of energy
and once the three are pushed together that represents great potential energy much like a
spring that has been compressed together and we just love to pop part
these four three phosphate would love to pop apart from one another by virtue of
the fact that these negative charges are mutually repelling but they can't as long as
they in this triphosphate configuration
but once the triphosphate configuration
is broken then the energy released by they're leaving one another can then be exploited
for other purposes
keep in mind just to reinforce what i said second ago
the difference between rivals deoxyribose
is the presence of the x happens this oxygen
and now let's focus in a little more detail
on the basis
because the bases are indeed the subject of much of our discussion today
and we have two basic kinds of of basis they're called nitrogen spaces these spaces
because they have like
and if you look at the the the five bases that are depicted here you'll
see that they are not aromatic rings with just carbons in the like a six-car
rather all of them have a
a substantial fraction of nitrogen is actually in the range
two in the case of these primitives
and here you see the number actually is is four
in fact one of these
nitrogen basis
indicated here go on has actually if if one appear as the side chains
this is called i this is outside of the china represents side group and if
we begin not to make distinctions between the the ring itself
and the entities that
protrude out of the ring
they really represent some of the important distinguishing characteristics
it's important that we understand primitives have one ring and these are have two rings
in the the instead of five and a six membered ring
fused together as you can see the printings have only a six membered ring
and what's really important in determining their identity is not the basic permitting or appearing
structure it's once again the side chains to distinguish these one from the other
here in the case of side c
we see that there's a carbonyl here oxygen sticking out and the mean over here
we see you're still which happens to be present in RNA
but not DNA
which has two cardinals here and here
obviously therefore what distinguishes these two for one another it is this oxygen versus this
i mean
and here we see the timing which is present in DNA
but not on a on this will become very familiar to you shortly this looks
just like you're still except for the fact that there is a metal groups taking
out here
now very important for our understanding of what's happening here is the fact
this method group although it distinguishes finding from your c is itself biologically actually not
very important
it's there to be sure and distinguishing mark of t verses you
but the business end of t verses you in terms of encoding information happens here
with these two oxygen sticking out there the important accidents here here and therefore from
the point of view information content as will soon see t and u are essentially
so adding new rows or new columns to the data matrix is very simple
and it just requires more work but you once you've updated the upper triangular matrix
or have the upper triangular matrix updating is very easy matter in terms of adding
observations or adding columns
adding and also the leading variables that is relatively easy but this is the hard
problem and it can be done but it's much more sensitive problem that is the
problem of down dating if one has outliers and wants to throw out some of
the observations that you've processed already then that's not a very easy thing to do
for one thing you can see by throwing up one observation you might change the
rank of the matrix
so down dating can can really have a great effect on the matrix computations and
the thing is no matter what numerical algorithm proposing here i'm sure you're all familiar
with this
the problem can be basically ill conditioned so
let me just say a word about that
and how we
do work on that in
numerical linear algebra
it depends upon some perturbation theory we will hear more about condition later from from
our hosts
so here's the classical theorem
a kind of fear
you are given here and here is the vector b
and then you perturb the matrix a by delta x o delta is the matrix
and the vector b
it is perturbed by delta b
and so
or the ACT
is the reason you would have gotten if you have the exact solutions are tailored
is what you get when you substitute in this approximation vector to the solution so
here's axtell the here's delta a delta b
and here's the important results
the relative error
is dependent upon
various things but the importance of the guy that really kills you
is this a kappa square of a so there can be no matter how accurate
an algorithm you use you still have kappa square by entering
providing the
tension of data
it is an answer so far
if you just solving linear equations
tension square goes out tension goes out but if you're solving least squares problem then
this enters and the condition number square
enters so
something normal equations are solving least squares problems not the normal equations is inherently more
difficult and solving linear equations you're minimizing some quantities and quadratic form and it may
be very smooth at the bottom there may be many nearby solutions so
least squares is inherently more difficult than solving linear equations in n but here's something
that's been observed before here is that the residual vector the perturbation theory for the
residual vector
and that depends just on the condition number and this has been observed before you
can have a small residual and allows the solution
so having a small residual does not necessarily imply you have a good approximate solution
in maybe that only the condition number enters whereas if you look at the solution
then the condition number square enters so that's
important pointer
what about singular systems
now later i'll have a bit to say about cingular's systems or what's more difficult
our systems that are nearly singular so it's you know in mathematics you learn to
rank the rank of the matrix is are
numerically and computationally this seldom happens
you don't have the matrix are
of rank are you have
so almost our analysis of had before maybe i should
use that over here
here's a classical kind of example
if you look at this matrix
ones on the diagonal and zeros here
n minus once everywhere above
and below
now this looks like a nice innocent matrix
its determinant
equals one
the eigen values are all equal to one
so from the map the rank is therefore the rank is and
however if the so called this a
you can have a plus
a matrix of the order of
two to the minus ten minus one
times e this rank
is equal to n minus one OK so what does that say
so if this is
twenty one by twenty one matrix
then this would be to to the minus twenty which is about ten to the
minus six and others you can
as a perturbation of order ten to the minus six to this matrix and get
the matrix of rank minus one so very small perturbations
added to this matrix will make it rank and minus one and there are lots
of examples so
you know you look at this if you took a linear algebra course professor tell
you know yes this is rank and its determinant is one but it's very near
a matrix of rank n minus one
remember if
catastrophic problems can occur they do when they do computations i mean if you're nearer
that problem you get when you do the computing so that's something you always have
to be aware of
of the nonterminals into terminal
or some combination of of tunnels terminals the big difference is that in pcfgs
i assign weights
to the productions
sorry assign probabilities
and what does it mean that
and again the problem for all productions of the same nonterminals after about one what
this means is that
i'm assuming that the nonterminals produced one
of the other productions and only want
so this is the old version of those
so for example in the phrase could be produced is unknown
why is determined followed by now
so the first one is probably point seven because it's more common and the second
one is probably point three and these are usually learned from that
now you can also use what's called a weighted context free grammars where the production
was instead of probabilities have weights and the two are equivalent in economics convert from
one to the other and here if course it's going to be more convenient to
use weights
but if you have a PCFG can just converted to to the way form and
go from there
statistical parsing algorithms typically assume that the parameters are in chomsky normal form
which you can reduce any context free grammar to chomsky normal form means that all
productions are the former nonterminals
goes to non terminal and non terminal on ontologies to terminal or the channels are
the actual topics that appear in the input we can assume that you to just
just for simplicity
so how do you implement the statistical parts as as an MLN
we're going to have one evidence predicate which as before is just the evidence predicate
that describes the text it says that this token appears in this position in the
input string like for example in the sense that we saw before tokenpizza appears in
position three
and now we're going to have query predicates
the quadratic it's are going to be the constituents
so for each type
i'm going to have predicted to form consistent position position
like for example there's an phrase starting position i anything at position j
OK so for example in the inputs is this non-free for a starting position to
position four
OK and basically by computing the truth thousand discrete predicates we accomplish the pass because
that tells us exactly what constituents exists over what parts of the of the string
and then we can evaluate this using the standard precision and recall metrics of constituents
that people use in statistical parsing
OK so we convert the grammar into an was very simple and it's actually pretty
much the same way that in in prolog when you want to do the passing
of of DCG is so for each rule of the form
a ghost to BC
we introduce formal
d i j and cjk goes to a i
so this for example if there is an arms inference from i to j
and the very first from j to k
and there's a sentence from the article
so this is one to one translation of grammar rules to animals
now in addition because the millions are more flexible than the pcfgs we need to
introduce some some restrictions in particular to two for each nonterminal introduced hard formula that
says that exactly
one production of that formula holds of the
for example if this is the noun phrase it's either amount
or a or or a a determiner followed by in
and then of course for each rule of the form nonterminal ghost terminals
i just in to the samples of the form if there is a token a
position i there's consistent of you know of
type capital a from my so the question
if you want to
he might be
it is
it's a lot
this is
it's a matter of taste
so in addition business exercise to do is to is to see that if you
introduce these
additional assumptions
one becomes according to the other sense that any more than you could represent one
way you could represent the so you're right i could just say
introduced was performed in PIJ and gpgtk and as i can
i just think it's more intuitive to it this way but he could content
perform just as well
logic is in the following important facility right
remember back to when we talk about potential functions and features
logic is tell me what important features are
it's a common language for writing the features not just as in logic that is
that's a certain things are equivalent it's also going to be the case if that
certain features are equivalent but i'm going to have equivalent is beyond the logical ones
i'm going to make a set of features are going to be equal to another
if i can find the set of weights for the first one that implements the
same thing as the second one with twenty percent of what's it has so there's
going to be equivalences among those are free to choose it's still the case that
by writing this in either injective application form i've written something much much more compact
than if i just after to the probability distribution over the whole plate involving all
the nonterminals in the production
that would be building on a lot of useful of useless and painful painful parameters
you know
you want to
we can be absolutely so in some cases the intuitive the optimal are the same
sometimes they equivalent sometimes they're not the same and are equivalent and you need to
be careful
absolutely right
no miracles right there still a place for knowledge engineers it's easier than before because
they have more flexibility to be considered things the right way or the wrong way
and you know we're still discovering what the range of good bad things to do
you know there's certainly a lot to explore so once you've represented your grammar in
this way
and you have the evidence predicates and these query predicates doing MEP inference on this
network yields the most probable parse
OK so you condition on the input string and you get the results for the
consequence that are the most probable parse
if that is the price is invalid then it will have zero problem
no but that's implicit in the formulas that i wrote
this this is is actually one of the things that is accomplished by this formula
this formulation
i am saying that if the if the nonterminal holds exactly one production holds no
more no less
which basically means that i know missus things can happen because forbidden by this rule
but i can have like is allowed to things that shouldn't be there
is a nice exercise to
so we can do statistical processing you again just by writing in the and again
you can learn the weights for these formulas from data
just using the standard discriminative learning algorithms that we have
so now we know how to see how well we get more missions and try
to do some semantic processing as well
so the first thing that we can try to do is combine this leading to
but so if you pass texts you extract noun phrases from the text that potentially
represented entities
like george bush the president and the white house
and i want to figure out if these are the same one
this is like the standard problem of coreference resolution natural language what you can do
that by combining the statistical parts that we just saw
with the introduction of things that we have
and the way to do that just rules of the form known phrase i j
and maybe some other conditions here implies into your type e g