and the three
contains ship
seven both synonyms of each other so
the document should have some semantic similarity even though
they don't have any terms in common
and that's reflected in the reduced representation because we have
limited details like the same concept
expressed by one
by one more than one document and by another another document is omitted those details
are now
in this
improved representation dissimilarity
becomes directly visible
yes i think
that should work because i mean effectively what you're doing is you're compute your
i think the debate regarding the matter is that you compute the probability
argument continued the which in the document containing the robot
and that should be similar
in the reduced representation
see all these
i mean the same way of doing that what is suggesting which is is a
good idea to actually
do that
i mean here
in the reduced use so if your
the clean way of doing that person you're suggesting is to throw away these numbers
and directly compute here the similarity between ship and boat and you can see that
it is
quite high vital role the point
your faultless your point
well it's not
o point
o point one or
o point two i guess
well have to normalize so
but i think it probably would have to be around point five
so in this matrix you can
compute the product the similarity
comes directly
OK so now we have everything for latent semantic indexing
and i takes documents that are semantically similar talk about the same topics
but are not similar in the original vector space because they use different words
and really represents the in the reduced space in which they have higher similarity
thus LSI addresses the problems of synonymy and semantic relatedness
and the sun vector space and contribute nothing to documents and
the desired effect of LSI circuits and contribute strongly to documents from
and so on
the white house hostess related to dimension reduction because dimensionality reduction for system in a
lot of detail
and we have to map different words different dimensions of the full space to the
underlying dimension in the reduced space
the cost of mapping synonyms to the same dimension
is less
the cost of mapping synonyms to the same dimension is less than the cost of
collapsing unrelated words
because their distribution of happen system
svd selects the least costly method that's why it's a good tool for doing dimensionality
and i would say something about the optimality in a few slides
now this may
sound familiar to some of you know
what information retrieval two relevance feedback and query expansion
because those are the
techniques that can be used if we have a mismatch between
in this match in
which terms are used in creating a document that said
and so on
rather than expansion in those cases increase recall
and as i
in principle does the same it increases recall but it can decision
thus it addresses the same problems as relevance feedback in expansion and it has the
same problems so we can see it as is something that most closely related
as far as other techniques are concerned to relevance feedback and query expansion
although it is also different i can maybe comment about that if you have questions
first we compute the SVD of the term document matrix
then you reduce the space and compute reduced document representations
here we have yet another parameter that we have to deal with in this case
the parameters the dimensionality that we want to keep
in my example was to
in practice people usually choose numbers like one hundred or two hundred to three hundred
that means that the query into the reduced space so
we we need a way of
i mean we don't know what the queries on that's so
when a new query comes in
we need to be able to map it into the new space so that's why
we need this formula
and this formula directly follows from the decomposition so
if you take the decomposition formula into multiply by
first on the left and then
sigma inverse
then get the k
the query is like document
in the sense bases apartments o
if you multiply with this problem then
you get the theory in the reduced space
because of course the original query is in the original space and we have to
transform it into the reduced space
then we compute the similarity of two k
reduced documents OK
and output a ranked list of documents is huge
what's the fundamental problem because there is a big problem here that i haven't talked
does anybody see what that is
in the sea
what's the problem of the index
right there are no zero values
and so on
the matrix
before i had a matrix that i could transform into and out in the next
month and it would be very efficient and now i have a dense matrix but
no zeros
the way i put it is that we actually can use an inverted index i
mean this equivalent to what is that we actually have to
do this year to compute similarity of concave all reduced documents in k
actually means we have to go through all documents and compute
the similarity between the query and document for each
and that's much more expensive than what we usually do
in information retrieval system so
it's very difficult to make analysis system as efficient as as normal
information is retrieval system is
OK optimality SVD is optimal in the following sense
keeping the k largest singular values and setting all others to zero gives you the
optimal approximation of the original matrix c
optimal in the following sense no other matrix of the same rank with the same
underlying dimensionality approximates the better
the message here is the frobenius norm where you take all
this function here which is associated with that
so it's the same thing
lambda he's one of partitions
of n elements
that index
there were that representation
what do you want to do this
you can
that the key to to efficient here is to use recursion
and you have
the the essential element regression is to use concept
so you have because you know that core sets the they either composed the group
in two us some
union of course sets
there is
nine representation theory you have a relation to construct the representation of
as n
you can use bits of representations of the smaller subgroups
so this will be able speed up computation
so you need you can break this
in two you know small example in
in the
and the
in the subgroup is this
this is actually result from representation theory that you can
ah you know you relate the representations of the supergroup with the representations of the
of the remaining
that's why this
these are all down here means the representation restricted to that sort of
anyway you can
coke later this
and q
time this was result from regime
last year
and here you can do that
graph correlation can compare two graphs
the key here is that all this lots of those mattresses representing
the group
of permutation of n elements
they may be orthogonal
the were then results box
so many of the representations you don't even have to
performed the product
so just have to perform in this case here
you just take four
representations to do this product
to do this property
and this you can do in the
and four
scholar operation
so this thing is faster do
because you don't have to do
you would have to do normally all
count all terms
but many of them with is zero anyway so if you know that before and
you can just
you can just speed up the calculation
the the
the traveling salesman salesman problem it's the version of that of that problem that can
be written in terms of
finding the the
the permutation that minimize the correlation of
this graph with this particular those divisions metrics
with these are the graph here
so if you can rewrite you can rewrite some of the classical problems in graph
theory using using the
the language of harmonic analysis
and speedup calculations
o japanese parts or the
i want to go back to
he two
two convolution again
this these are
probably can't see anything here
get it
sometimes the most of work
it's more
well you cannot see right can you see there's this green line
c and the green line
so this is actually what the college
so this is for us you know we're doing the convolution of these
this will function
with the
red line
and they called the result of the convolution is this green one
as it grows when it's not touching each other when it gets in the center
here gets the maximum value
he was out of order of phase again it was
the value diminish
and here is the same thing with graphs
the convolution of the green and
the function is centered on this
there's a green line here
and this is the result of the call
the convolution here
is maximal
when you have these group operation here
in this case the group operation is a translation
so i'm just saying this show
it to find his mother child
in showing this because of
i would not have much time to to go through all the applications that
but this is of this form here
OK so now we have this additional information
and then we can have a two-step process in in translating sentence
so the first step is to segment
german sentence
and again to choose the set of the entries
and then have a set of these or sequence of these syntactic fragments
because we have a sequence of this tree fragments
the second step is to somehow assemble
these tree fragments into a full parse tree
so that essentially involves
something very similar to the junction operations i showed you on the talk we start
to see these
tree structures together with some costs
and we cover a an english parse tree
and some is allowed so that you have to move around the ring of these
different fragments so finally we get the translation
the output of the system is distinguished past
so that's the sketch of this model
a couple of things about this
so one is that the search process again we're going have some process the first
searches for these fragments
and looks at how to combine them
this can be implemented using essentially extensions of
algorithms used regular
so this is what i mean by translation as parsing problem was essentially
the translation problems decoding under one of these parsing models
and there's some potential advantages which have been shown in this work one is that
you build an english parse tree and have some control over grammaticality of the tree
so you you have some control over the fact that they need to subject and
object in all these different things
the second thing is that in capturing
the difference in between two languages
for example if we don't care
the fact that the subject comes after the before it in english
we can capture those kind of facts by reordering on these polls trees which is
called the natural way to capture real reordering in the two languages
so let's transition let not to inference of these models
so one question
left open
how we find the most likely parse tree under the model
i showed you
so here again actually the model form
a parse tree is scored by the sum of scores of these different junction operations
so the main point of this part of the talk
so dynamic programming algorithms exist
for TAG grammars
which actually rules for the TAG grammars i've shown you
i have very similar runtime two algorithms for PCFG
so for example cubic time
time in the length of the sentence
so that's some promising
unfortunately exact inference under these models are still very expensive
that is prohibitively expensive you can easily spend minutes pausing assumptions
and inferences about both applying the model to new sentences
and also during training of the model
OK because the training algorithms will see for conditional random fields generally require decoding the
training examples multiple times
as inferences about american training
so one solution which has been found effective many times in the parsing lecture
it is to use medical coarse to fine dynamic programming
for example charniak has been using this for a long time and parsing models
the basic idea here is to use the first past model
which is a simple computationally cheap model
to restrict the search space of the full parsing model
and this can actually be remarkably effective
and the models will see so let me describe this idea
so to understand these algorithms will actually go to another syntactic formalisms we've seen context
free grammars syntaxes
number token little bit about dependency grammars with dependency representations
so the top of the slide is the dependency structure
which can be thought of as an alternative representation to context free trees
so basically is formed bidirected graph
which forms a tree
this special node called star the nodes are about to star
at the root of the tree
and we have talks between
basically heads and modifiers
so as the dependency for example between germans or
basically corresponding to the subject dependency
the simplest form of this dependency structures
just as i've shown you there
in a slightly more fine for me might have labels on these socks might actually
have label same subject
saying that he is the object of saw
and so on and so on
so this can be thought of as an alternative
representation is again quite widely used in natural natural language community another way of representing
syntactic structures
a few years ago when mcdonald's
and collaborators
i came up with a CRF style
models for dependency parsing
so now we can score these structures
using again the serious star model
the school semantic structure is going to be a sum of the dependency on that
structure and that dependency gets school which is just another in product
features now track dependencies essentially any information about the input sentence
so one thing which is remarkable remarkable about these dependency structures
is that they have very efficient decoding algorithms
james joyce meissner
so for the structures to show you which have no labels the most probable
well cost dependency structure under this kind of model
can be found found in cubic time in the length of the sentence
very low constants
and the eisna came up with the really quite beautiful algorithms the dynamic programming algorithms
and they did compose dependency structures into subparts and quite ingenious way that kind of
dynamic programming bottom up search
so it looks rather different from say of context free grammar but the complexity is
actually very similar
to see if which also cubic and the length of the sentence
and was
this to great effect in training
discriminative models
based on these dependency representations
in fact these representations of fission enough exhausted parsing is really quite quite plausible quite
so what does this fit with the tax structures that i've shown you
so if you think about is
tag structures
they look very much like dependency structures
some additional information
so essentially dependency structures augmented with these spines
and also augmented with these positions of these the junction points and these points
so for example there is essentially a dependency
between the with environments
now it's mediated by these two spines in this junction position
so you can think of tank structures as being
more elaborate dependency structures essentially does the close connection between the two
and actually means that iciness algorithms can also be applied to this formalism
the most probable lowest cost house
the brain
this is the brain
in fact it's a specific person's brain
and what's interesting about the brain is that white mark there
it's her brain
it's terry child's brain
you recognise or more from pictures like that
and what a case like this where somebody
in the home is without consciousness
as a result the damage to the brain is the start illustration of the physical
nature of mental life
the physical basis for everything that we normally hold dear
like free will
more ali and and emotions
and that's will be in the course talking about how a physical things
can give rise to mental life
we'll talk a lot about children
this is actually a specific child
it's my son's akari younger son
dressed up as superman spider-man but it is how it knows not how it
it's more to say about that
i study child development for living
and i'm interested in several questions so one question is just the question of development
everybody in this room
i can speak and understand english
everybody in this room has some understanding of how the world works how physical things
behave everybody in this room has some understanding of other people
and how people
and the question
that preoccupies developmental psychologists is how do we come to have the knowledge
and in particular how much of it is hard-wired built in in a
and how much of it is the product of culture
of of language of schooling
and developmental psychologists use
many ingenious methods to try to pull these apart
and try to figure out what what what's
what are the basic components of human nature
there's also the question of continuity
to what extent
is that during that age
going to be
that way forever
to what extent is your fate sealed
to what extent could if i were to me when you were five years old
i could describe the way you are now
the poet
william wordsworth
the child is father to the man
and what this means is
but you can see
within every child
the adult here she will become
we will look in and ask the question whether this is true is it true
for your personality is it true for your interest is it true for your intelligence
another question having to do with development
what makes us the way we are
we're different into waterways
the people in this room differ according to
their taste in food they differ according to IQ's whether there
aggressive or or shy
whether they are attracted to males females both or neither
whether they good music
there politically liberal or conservative
one week different
what is the explanation for why were different
and again
this could be translated in terms of the question of genes and environment to what
extent are things the result of the genes we possess to what extent
are are are individual majors is the result of how we were raised and to
what extent are the best explained in terms of the interaction one common theory for
instance is that we are shaped by our parents
this was best summarized most famously by the british poet philip larkin
who wrote
they mess you up
your mum and dad
they may not mean to but they do not
they fill you with the faults they had
and that some extra just for you
the right
this very controversial you it's been a a series of a huge controversy in popular
culture the extent to which parents matter
and this is an issue which will preoccupy us
for much of the course
a different question
what makes somebody attractor
in the second part of the
tutorial we going to discuss compressed sensing so in some sense
we're going to jump forward in time by a few years by about twenty years
and so on
maybe that everybody comes back
right so we're going talk about compressed sensing
so the first thing i like to say about this field compressed sensing is these
days it's it's an enormous field
weighs thousands of research papers literally being published yearly
addressing all aspects of the theory great ranging from theory
two lots of algorithmic papers these days people exploiting applications it's an enormous field
perhaps a bit for additional so they have several
scientific journals published special issues on compressed sensing lots of tripoli journals publishing special issues
if you go to major international conferences and mass in in electrical engineering in signal
processing information theory also special sessions on this topic but there are several scientific conferences
discussed this devoted to this topic
an interesting thing is that the US government things to think that great thing that's
is investing a lot of money into
trying to realised in hardware promise
of compressed sensing if you go on the world wide web you have
several blogs dedicated to this topic
and so on and so forth
OK so
i'm just not saying this is this is is a very impressive of course there
is the danger that it's a bit vanish so time will tell whether it's
is that it should not
but it's a very big field were lots of people contribute
as we have seen these lectures people contribute hardware people contribute reasons people contribute theory
that people contribute lots of
very different things and because it's an enormous field with several thousands of papers already
i cannot give you an overview of this field what i will do it i
will focus on the early ideas that were at the premise of the has developed
by a group and to some extent by by david
so the motivation underlying compressed sensing is extremely simple
it is it possible
to acquire information efficient
that is
there is i wish to make an image and so
we can talk again about that you have which leads in r and so we
could think about it now has a digital picture i wish to acquire digital pictures
say that has and pixels introduces i'm going to make measurements about these objects and
so i'm going to measure
correlations between the object i wish to acquire
away waveforms phi k
and so i'm going to have a number of
measurements which is equal to m as before
so there of this form just linear measurements are going to be interested in situations
we have very few measurements before i do this
i just want to show that for example if i k then indicator function of
a little square
then y k will be pixel intensity
at pixel number k because it will just count the number of photons hitting a
little square sharing
we cannot be interested in situations where is number of measurements we can take about
an pixel image
are very small
and this
comes up in a lot of applications for example i may have you're few sensors
so in some fields sensors are very expensive to manufacture so for example if you
try to
build an infrared camera for example
a camera operating invisible
i have some entity called be
well yes i do
it happens to be in in three so prince three
if you ask what is saying
i can't says okay in my environment do i have some
the name
it doesn't find it so it brings out this cryptic message
basically says sorry guys i can't find something called eh
in the current environment
that's the key to the way python does all name binding
in general there's a global environment
you start typing the on
it just start adding and modifying
the bindings
in the binding environment
so if you type eight with three in taipei
know find three
if you don't i'd be was eight a-plus two
it evaluates the right-hand side
relative to the current environment
so it first looks here
and says do i have something called it
i it's an integer three
substitute back
do i know what to it as an end pluses area that's the thing that combines to it
so it decides that plus two
it evaluates a-plus in the current environment gets five
and is i'm trying to do a new
a new association new new variable
make thee
name be
o point two
this is evaluated in the current environment
so be is associated with int
then if i do this line it
evaluates me plus one in the current environment
these five in the current environment it adds wanna get six
and it says associate this thing
with me
so it overrides the be
which had been bound to five
and if be is now bound sex
so the whole thing the waitress variables
the way associates in the weight height and associate a name with value in a variable
is evaluate the right hand side according to the current environment
then change the current environment
to reflect the new binding
what it doesn't cases subroutines is very similar
when you say
so here's an illustration only in the local environment
is generated by this piece of code
when i say it was to
generates a name in the local environment eh
it evaluates the right-hand side and finds tool
so it makes a binding in the local environment where the name is associated with integer tool
i say define that's to be return x squared
that's more complicated
by says
and defining a new operation
it's a procedure
the procedure has a formal argument x
it has a body
return x times x
i'm gonna have to remember all that's stuff
i'm trying to define new procedure called square it's gonna make a binding for square
so in the future if somebody says the words quare it'll find out elsewhere i remembered our squaring
it's a procedure
just like the binding free variable
might be int the binding fore eight procedure
is the name of the procedure
then in the procedure which is some other data structure outside the environment
it's gotta remember the formal parameters in this case acts
and the body
and for the purpose of resolving
what do the variables mean it needs to remember what was these binding environment in which this subroutine was defined
so that's really that's the sour
this this sequence says make a new binding square points to procedure in the procedure has the formal
argument acts
it has the body return x times x
and you has the binding
it came from the environment you want the current remember
okay is everybody clear so the idea is that's he environment associates names with things
the thing could be a data item or could be a procedure
then when you call procedure
it makes a new environment
so what happens then when i try to evaluate a form
so whereof a-plus two
what i found us it says okay
i need the figure out what's queries
so it looks it up in environment and finds out that squares a procedure
five i know how to deal with procedures
so then it
three years out this procedure has a formal argument acts
okay from gonna around this procedure and what have know xmins
so makes a new environment here is labeled e to
separate from the the global environment e one
it makes a new environment
that will associate x with something
doesn't know what it is yet
it just knows there
this queries a procedure that takes a four argument x
so makes a new environment e to with exploiting the something
then pi on evaluates theargument a-plus to in the environment you want
you called square error plus two in the environment you one so it figures out
what did you mean by a-plus
and when i get on the right was
i'll just write down
this very page domain over two
he made the truth
and the factor to disappear results
in the transform domain
well this was accomplished right this was that this was really a convolution
followed by
the change of scale
and of course
in the frequency domain becomes the multiplication with the change of scale
change in the opposite direction
it was two t there will be only over to here i really recommend that
now there's a serious
suggested exercises that take the foragers it's just terrific practice
take the fourier transforms and say they get so you see that
we have may made every time we
let's take one more step this would be a major over two
now what could i substitute for
and i will make two
using the
the same
this recursively it would be a
over four times the
from four
pauses second because it's only
so nice in the frequency domain
but there are two routes nice but it's not
like self evident because it still is
change of scale
course i carry on
the nature of
two times a
four times age
eight and you can see that in the limit
this is a picture me or two
that's my formula
what this guy the tail end
OK i was what you know good question
so it became
became goes away some goes to one
why does it go to one
so there should be a fair share of omega or so i'm finding that this
this guy
no because if have zero right
because i can dividing by two
this is approaching
factors that the tail and so on so that about seventy seven terms in product
for over two hundred seventy seven
and it's made over to the surface so it's very near the speed of zero
and that's what
so but no
i don't know why why not
maybe it's because we're in the frequency domain
it it bears checking of course
so let's see
first of all why is fear zero one well that's the same as i the
convention mentioned
that was that
that's the
that's the right
so somewhere in here
let's see
i know it does approach one
i don't know the right
explanation to give you her
we're seeing
so this is
if i take j terms here so i
going along stopping to do the change eventually and this would be
this would be the only for each element
three jamaica
this approach feed of zero
maybe this is the point this gives the same answer good answer for each omega
well good answer this weekend product well
the world's is answered and then if we want to ask the question what we
have an inverse fourier transform still do
we like to do that so you can see that it's extremely lucky
if you access to get have an explicit solution not happen
and maybe
the question is this form would
you are
a way to tackle my
little convolution question
what was the question that we started with that
if i had
if i had the feeling e
would solve this equation
now if i can involve a chart with itself
and i look at equation
i'm trying to answer would be
the involved with itself
what works and why
because the transfer this domain
in the frequency domain one i
all this with itself what to do to capital h
we multiply by itself right
so then there would be a great square and feet times three
i have
that's where the frequency domain to go back i have
of cells
the convolution
up there
but this a little bit
tangential to the
central well
because the what we discover is
we've got an answer here
at each omega
so why do i say
the solution is in doubt
why do i say not always one i
produced and
and it does this product does converge is free to make
because the ages of if this is a low pass filter so i really need
to build the fact some
one of them is one
that's that's also part of my page
and this
these things approach one
product is converges but
so can i ask again
i can answer why should i say there isn't always an answer
that's right it can answer freecell many but now if i want to go back
and find the function
well by the way what was the answer when went for the lead
1 and group 2
and over here
the group 6 and 7 so those are the ones that are most likely form
ionic bonds OK not only did he proposes the quantified and what he did something
even even better but still
he defines
something called certainly partial charges
right now this is what government is what got the Nobel Prize
and partial charge and I'll give you the formula of X so this is in
your text and so
x y bond right
because that's what I tried to where
that is the group number
and so that is the number of non bonding nonbonding electron
and of that is the number of bonding electrons OK now let's take this and
look at what what we get of try chips right we know this is what
we this is what comes out of this
that 1
we know that this is going to be my measurement there's going to be plus
invisibility minus is going to be done it's going to be a dipole this processes
and we know that kind fluorine is 4 .
1 of
and size of hydrogen is equal to
2 . 3 0
well the plug that in promises to 1 of these before just do the fluorine
and by the way that if you do this for the hydrogen about the same
that's equal to 7 minus 6
minus 2
times 4 . 1 9 over 4 . 1
+ 2 . 3 and that gives you a number
for the fluorine minus 0 . 2 9 right now if you do the same
do the same for the
for the for the hydrogen
you can have the same number but it'll be plus
all right but the plus and so
then that what that tells us a chapters polar region of the image of this
OK so we did that and but now let's go back to what the running
of space must go back to let's go back to my and see what happens
see what happens there
let's go back to back nothing well the carbon is equal to 2 . 5
I the hydrogen again what 2 . 3 and so on
so what this tells us since these are people that tells us that the carbon
hydrogen bonds
is not well there would
this poll right hydrogen bond is polar
and so if we go in we draw this again this is the carbon here
hydrogen hydrogen hydrogen hydrogen like this then this is going to be a little bit
will work for us and this and is going to be negative right so we
know from our calculations that we can do over here that this this bond
is polar and this bond is polar but again as I alluded to earlier because
the carbon is centered in the text regions because the S P 3 hybridization the
molecule itself is symmetric and non polar
OK and for this he got a the Nobel
and I think 19 fifties
1954 OK not 1 last thing needed is that OK
what's going on here
well on the 1 hand we have ionic bonding where we have complete sharing
on the other hand if we have a perfect covalent bonds we have identical apps
equal shares but we know that that just by this calculation that we don't have
equal sharing so somewhere in between the bonds are we have a range of bonds
between ionic on the 1 hand and perfectly covalent on the other hand but there's
a whole range in between so what's going on there well he point also suggested
that for that case that the bonds are partly ionic and partially covalent and he
came up with a relationship
calculate the % ionic character right and I'll just give it to you
this is squared
you % right so there's a relationship and so you can see where qi comes
at work I comes in here and this is the the difference in electronegativity between
the 2 between the 2 the 2 elements
was time
OK he also that we see here also lastly of the that closes out he
developed an analytical expression for the energy that covalent bond which is really what we
want right so that the type of
on the bond energies that we can go and look up in the in tables
another group with the saying well
sorry that in this example
the group for the sake is only the sake
nevertheless it's it's cut and what's what's that cut down
that cut has
separated the source
the same it's it's literally cut the two apart
so that
the capacity of course is
they crossed the cut is the number of
times we click the image so we are trying trying to say the maximum number
of disjoint paths that measure how much flow we could do equals the minimum number
of cut of a kind of cut edges
you may use is the stronger there to split s
the minimum number of edges that talk to
separate this from this to this
to say that this is
a restatement maybe we could say why
why i mean this is
as usual
we should see a weak duality so what what did we could well the mean
weak duality which was usually the easy thing to to to see of just made
suppose i just made this statement
but i draw network
and i look at how many separate paths there are they don't don't share any
edges that's with disjoint means
from source to sink how many
and i looked at the minimum number of edges of cuts i had to make
to separate the two now it's so we should be
maximum less or equal minimum
should be easy
and remember it's
so strange that it's that direction that easy course it's the maximum of one thing
and the minimum of another why is that easy how do i know that
but if i have
the minimum number of edges to if i find if i find some images that
split the how do i know
then if i if i find any cut
any any any
a bunch of edges i could snap through
that would separate source from saying i count those edges and i get k
how do i know that the number of passes cannot be more than k
if f
exactly if
each edge if
if i manage to cut the same with k
you could be more than k destroyed has because i wouldn't cut one of them
when we say that again this is suppose
from this track
and can be
can be greater than k
this joint task
because there are more than k this tripe as an i didn't cut them all
and i have been separated
the source from the sink
so that would be their reasoning of the i take any cut that works
say OK maybe it's OK
separate edges to clip
than the number of disjoint paths could be larger than k because
and if it were one of those has isn't getting cut and and
we haven't we haven't separated from as prime
so that says that any
any cut that's acceptable
is large is at least as large as any counter destroyed past so we increase
the counter this trend has up to its maximum we decrease the number of cuts
to the do the best cutting we can and we have less or equal and
the point is we actually have an equal
maybe here's the way to
here's the proof of equal
i suppose
we have well the the idea of the proof is that if you have
suppose we have
a maximum flow
this is in the book and it's hard to take in verbally but if we
had a maximum flow
because we had the flow as large as possible
i want to see twice some kind of that size is holding this up
so we have max flow biggest possible
that night
keep with as some edges
some somewhere in s
some edges i might be able to send more troops
so long some edges i might be able to send more for example along the
edge i could say more
it's interesting OK now i'm going i may find another cut here
so i i keep my group with the s
all the nodes to which i could still send one more OK
the we see i'm the only users so with as i keep this note because
i could still send one more to that
now this is going to be tricky because i could now send backwards on this
square and we spend the entire lecture
on dealing with this age
changed only
we evaluated omega equals zero
oh my god resonance
omega very high values
there is no
constant in this solution
but there was one
that solution
now let's look at the
differential equations
that we were sold
so first we go
only under even system
under the names it equal zero you give given kicking and this led to do
his own thing
the differential equation that we then had was x double dot
as gamma x dot
because omega zero korean x
equals zero
that's the one we have
we solve it
and we found that solution there
then we were driving it
so now we drive it
what now was the differential equation
well we had annexed double but
karma x dot
was omega zero career times x
and now we had
this driving for
in the case that we
put the force on the object
then we had here
zero divided by
times cosine omega t because the and comes in because you divide by an right
yet newton's second law is made
but in the case that you shake the left side
raise your hands you're always is at the zero
cosine omega team another way
of effectively
driving object
we do work that out then we have here
at the zero
times omega zero squared
times cosine
but in any case
you see here
a driving term
and we
solve our equations and if you take this case
this is the solution
if you take this case than this
take place
of that
suppose now
i take this solution
and i substitute that solution in this differential equation
then i get
the result is zero
because look
to get this
so i put it in this part
get zero because if fits this differential equation
what is wrong with adding zero
if i had to these two solutions
it must be a solution to this differential equation
because you just add zero
and if you take eighteen o three
and they use very
nice terms they say yes of course
if you have this special solution
which is this one
you have to add the homoge neous solution
and these were homogeneous means that you put zero
and so the general solution
is really
the sum of the two
by adding this one
you effectively and zero
so you have nothing
but you get something in return
what you get in return you to
adjustable constant
you can deal with this situation
that t equals zero
you know exactly where
that object is and what its velocity is
so i will write down now
the general solution
which is the one
these are part of the election today
so x no
the function of time
the steady state solution
eight cosine
omega t
this is my
why i
that's waterloo elements omega
times including minus
come over two times t
times cosine
omega prime she
because of
and this is the real
of the oscillator
and this is my will
two different
omega as
now you can see what happens
you see that this tour will never die out as well as for ever and
ever and ever
but this one is going to die
so one of e decay time of two alpha gamma
and so if to overcome i happens to be ten hours
there you have to wait ten hours for this one can be done by a
factor of e
but if you overcome i happens to be one millisecond then all you have to
do is what weight one many seconds
four that were to go down by a factor of so this is the one
that will die out
that's why we have to wait
so this is called
the trenchant
and it will die out faster
the higher
and this is called then
the steady state solution
which ultimately
i told you
that a teen equals zero
x equals zero
and actually dot also equal zero
and i
was so nasty to say oh by the way i don't use all four x
and of
it will be very nice thing to do
will take your fifteen minutes of grinding
not so fast because remember
if you have an expert
you have to take the time derivative of this entire functions
you have here you have two there you have to substitute in there
time t equals zero and they you have to make that equal zero
and the q fifteen minutes and out pops in a value for x and the
value for all
haven't learned much physics when you do that you to algebra
so i've decided not to
i spend my time on doing that but in principle
you must agree with me now the device especially for specified the initial conditions
i don't have to call this zero i can call this axis here i can
do anything i want to i can give x any value i want to
then i get unique values for
x and for all five
that is ultimately
then what
the solution is i must
at the two
the bottom line and that's really where the physics is
and that has to do with problem two five that you have this week on
your plate
is then the following
if i make a plot
of x as a function of time
the solution
is really the some of these two
on the segmentation step but with the graph representation of the two images then we
define a recursive weighted graph matching legacy because we have to do the matching we
want to understand if the matching is OK with if it is reliability function is
it OK and so all we can as we can have some donkey the idea
that we we can process again
the segmentation step is simple and very fast that we
we want to that this step doesn't influence the rest of the grid and it's
it's possible because we have a stereo if you still image so we we have
this same scene looking from two different we point to point
then there's segmentation step is adopted that adaptative
for each major accordingly
lighting conditions of this period
graph representation
it is
is based on the we select the segmented regions from the previous step and we
identify the
i mean value of
for each original decides called the need to run a mask and we define this
way the two graph
for less than five each
we define some cost functions that depending on the call of dimension position and the
we apply
we so we
we will we want to we look for the best solution that is the solution
with maximum cardinality and with mean
lowest cost lowest cost
of course the ability of nature can be
but generally can be time-consuming and for these reasons we
apply some constraints for i want to be part of the graph matching
our constraints is to define a searching i because we know that
and adjourned on the left image and can have a maximum vertical displacement and and
the maximum horizontal displacement in this way we can use spots information and the color
information and so we can improve our matching in in order to have a low
execution time
it's the end of the graph matching
as i said before we have here is a list of mitch died and the
list of donkey idea
those ideas don't care don't care about this can be groper is a in addition
blobs so we can try to put together some blobs in the left image and
the right to major and two rules
five to two
to look for another graph matching for these combination of addition to blocks in this
way we want to use split and merge artifacts of the segmentation step
despite the competition is maximal call coverage of the corresponding correspondent regions
and so the disparity value is the horizontal displacement of
of those regions
the output of the algorithm is that it's better than that of course
but also a graphic also the performance this is a graphical representation of these performances
so we have brighter value for
one of four original it is related to higher performance venue at the end we
can apply some positive
two to improve our is
so what is the advantages of the approaches
all our approach to give these results
we don't have a problem in a uniform manner
we stable more of the in the case of vibration of a camera in this
case we move one two or three peaks we impose two forty pixels of vertical
misalignment misalignment between the left and right images and our results on the right
is enough stable in comparison with the other that can that have some problems
has some problems
the execution time is going to a ball with the other methods in this case
we have compiled composing elements only with dynamic programming and city because other approach that
is not good for her us because it's about five hundred seconds or
one hundred sixty but is not good for our framework at the end of the
day cost function because the graph matching is good for local and global perturbation of
the tunes
you other
kind of results that we want to people who want to test is a quantitative
results we have tested our algorithm and we have combined the with and this is
what to scale that are the most used in the literature it and we
we tested on their
realistic comedian that we have acquired from
mobile platform that is the movie that a show within to show it to you
in these newly movie we have a camera vibration like changing uniform obstacles obstacles then
we have defined the sound performance index because in the literature we have only a
also discriminated one i can reduce at least two ottoman
you can think of this
then if we think about this the interesting thing is how can we
graph mining to find property index structure
the first interesting thing i would say is
besides frequent subgraph mining we needed the discriminant my what's discriminant mining
i should apologize here this
this is three that's OK
i think different machine recognised this should we should blame know
bill gates
OK what
the original this year and this is just so
the general philosophy like this
suppose you are professor you want to select students suppose we already have five students
in europe you get a new applicant cup pass they want join group
what you're think
you would think is it's OK
suppose this f one f two f and is the current students current feature means
current students OK
if you get a new one comes
if this one
you ask him what do what do know what is your skin
OK if you find this guy scale
OK will be fully covered by your existing students
using this guy joined the group for not contributing new skills
he was oh i got enough people OK i don't i don't need you anymore
so you you're not be selected
but if the student got some unix scale OK
can be cover was the existing students you all
this is a very good addition to my group had better include u
that's the same idea same philosophy that means you will find discriminant structure means you
won't find your new features so if i got the problem i suppose
i got this act
i want find this access the common features if
my existing feature
OK can predict the acts simply says this axis is sensory or not but they
not you can get in so then
i would thinking
you know if this one is small enough simply says i can barely predicting your
probability predicting your skills then x is discriminative our include you so basically based on
this idea
we work out the frequent discriminant
structure my pattern mining and using this one as are index entries
so the interesting thing another interesting thing is
if you think the frequent graph mining you say oh i set up a stable
structurally actually this way it may not work well we really use is we use
a growing support structure
you may say oh you could be wrong you grew one use shrinking lines that
growing more OK so the first idea is to try to argue this this curve
is right this is when you're size is really small
like the size only one single or not
you political everyone
including some rare elements is very in your data set but as long as they
p appear used don't want to miss them
that time every single one suppose you're everything one would become or be indexed
OK then when the
when you start to become bigger and bigger
the real frequency
the rear explination appliances the pakistan come
two in combinatorial OK was stuck on combining to win three and four you really
get the star explodes and that's the part we become pick and pick OK we
try to raise the suppose that said if you're bar
i raised the bar if you're not frequent enough
OK i didn't even want to check
whether you're discriminant just thinking about this suppose i have a rare element this rare
element here already
they it but index only one node all or one edge
OK now you start combining with many many other things OK of course combine make
but since you are so rare
i don't need to index the very low product already ten radical
in the bigger and better reserved this index entry for those more popular because that's
the general philosophy so that's why we raise the bar here
of course this one if you really see the whole explosion curve is going this
way and then going down but we don't have to index that big structure that's
why we go up to certain state was done
so based on this we actually look at the same this aids antiviral structure
so we found the first interesting thing is if you use
past like a daylight or you know graph the graph grab them by dennis shasha
using this one
comparing to using this one you actually can see once the database size keep going
this structure this frequent structure
it's really stable
actually the frequent discriminative structure because you can further only the slow
so what you really need you can you can look at this you say this
is very efficient because you don't need them in index
then we look at how effective it could be
we use the very small index structures
but it would be as effective as you know exactly what you have
so this one you can see this is our g index
this is ideal case the actual match and inside
i really had this one i really
you know PN point to this one is or is impossible because you were not
really keen on them so it's is very close to the ideal
but if you look at the graph graph
even to have a much bigger structure with a return much
much more
candidates and you have to do much more you know match
that's the reason this is more effective
and also it is quite
good for incremental updates means you keep adding new elements to average to
could operate
in the index structure based examples when he was sent to use very very stable
those the the thing for the index
and then we go back to do the
to the cameras
COI we construct index
and then we need to get one more problem they say you go index is
i don't find exactly what day of an approximate one is thinking about this OK
for example
this structure
if you go to these chemical compounds found exactly the structure probably were not find
it but it's a i just twist letter i had this one from the carbon
them cross one to con to computing the conditional distribution of some unobserved random variable
given the observed data
okay and I think this is quite important especially when you start looking to more
complex models and and for these models the there's often not much distinction between what
is a latent varibale and what is a parameter they're all simply random variables that you
did not observe
so when are some examples of probabilistic models
I guess the let there's a very large class of probabilistic models called graphical
models which are very useful in terms of reasoning about
uncertainty in
this in
in our data
and graphical models can be visualized in these
and basically each node of the graph corresponds to a random variable
and each edge basically corresponds to a direct dependence of one variable on
another variable okay
and importantly
if you don't
if there's no edge connecting to random variables that corresponds to actually conditional
independence between the random variables
so in this graph for example it's because there's no edge between earthquake and burglar
that means that whether an earthquake happens or not or whether burglar
comes into your house or not are
independent events okay
so this is the Asian network and this is the alarm network and I guess
they're pretty
simple graphical models to to illustrate
what these things are
so I'll show you a few more examples so this example for model based clustering
is pro will actually returned to this
a few times over both today and tomorrow and this is a model for clustering
so what is clustering clustering is the idea that given a data set which consists
of heterogenous of
data items basically you can think of the data items as coming from different sources then
we'd like to cluster the data items into the different clusters each of which are
homogenous within themselves and
and the different clusters are different okay so to visualize so he if the
blue dots here are our data items then we'll let to cluster them into three
different clusters which corresponds to well
three different types of data items that we observe right
and this is a model
and we can take a model based approach to clustering and it's model based in the
sense that we are gonna postulate a particle at model
for the data items in each cluster okay
so the model kind of goes as follows
we're gonna assume
so x i is gonna be data item i
we're gonna assume that there're some latent variabes z i which corresponds to
the unobserved indicator variable which tells us which cluster this data item belongs to
and we're gonna assume the following generative model so for every data item we're first
gonna decide which cluster that data item belongs to
by sampling from a dicrete distribution with a prior given by pi so pi here is basically a
pi one to pi k with pi k
being the prior probability
that cluster k is
respon is no is the prior probability that data item i belongs to
cluster k okay
and given that we've postulated that
data item i belongs to cluster
k say
the this sorry is that is that a question
oh it's just a discrete distribution
yeah well it's a discrete distribution with probabilities given by pi so
the probability that z i
takes on value one is gonna be pi one
and the probability that z i takes on value two is gonna be pi two
and the probability that z i takes on value k is gonna be pi k
I would
yeah so people typically call that multinomial in machine learning but it's actually a bit
confusing because a multinomial distribution actually is actually a richer set of distributions than this
discrete distributions
because from this analysis analysis
in particular from knowing what the entering angle with this
this is the quantity that the girls wanted to measure
writer were really interested in the scattering angle
which turns out to be fifty point seven degrees
this first order diffraction
we're going to use the
knowledge to calculate the the wavelength
of the electron
four here
and we're going to do they have
because of this known condition
constructive interference that the difference in the distance travelled by the two ways that gives
the constructive interference to be an integral multiple of the wavelength
that's where we're at
so now
the fly
from random number two to the screen
call it the two
the tool
is the length of that line it's the destination
that the wave
trammell from adam to to the screen
d one
is the distance that the waves scattering from one
has travelled
the screen
i'm going to draw a perpendicular right here
trying to draw perpendicular from one
to this line two
here's the right angle
that's really nice
because look at what this leg of the triangle is then
it d two minus the one he
at the quantity that is going to be interesting to watch
right now
what you have to do
you have to convince yourself that this angle right here in the triangle
it is equal to the ringing of data
if you're going to geometry considered immediately
or you might have to think about a little bit but it is equal to
well that's good because now i got triangle right here
and i know the length of one side
the distance the spacing between the two nickel atoms in the crystal
i know what they is that with the listening grammar measure
pretty good i can use that
i can use this geometry
say a signed data
is equal to the opposite
the link the outside the two minus the one over the hypothenuse a
and now
if this is the condition in to obtain the constructive interference
and there expression
is comes from the geometry of the problem that i'm solving
this is the theory that the geometry
the problem solving
then and lambda has to be equal to the sine paid
and and therefore i can rearrange their to get lambda
and is equal to
eighty nine data
divided by
and now i can use this information here to calculate land
right i know all the scattering angle fifty point seven degrees
i know what and and it's the first order diffraction feature because it is the
most intense but it is closest to the zero order zero order is always going
to be normal to your sample normal to the crystal
so therefore i can plug some numbers in there
and i get for the wavelength one point six six times ten to the minus
ten years
right so this experiment that if you have electrons there are fifty four you need
an energy
the wavelength
of those electrons one point six six times in ninety meters
davis grammar and
so the
not only did they demonstrate the interference phenomenon of particles
particles that can man
but they were able to calculate from an experiment the wavelength the corresponding wavelength
right but now i just want to take a moment to site
to tell you that geometry that i illustrated right here is the identical geometry
we have is used in x-ray diffraction
x-ray diffraction is the interference the diffraction of x-rays photo
this is the electron diffraction
the geometry is the same the concepts are the same
the reason i bring up x-ray diffraction
is because it's very important technique
for you in your future whether you're going to be looking at material
get structure material
or whether you're going to be doing some kind of biological chemistry because x-ray diffraction
it is
used to get structures crystal structures particularly of proteins
and the reason why you want to know the structure of the protein
because their structure does give you some hints as to what the function of the
protein yet
and actually professor drennan who was going to watch in the second half of the
course that's specialty
is x-ray diffraction of
protein crystal protein
and i'm sure she'll tell you much more about it
right but in x-ray diffraction
what they
is they use those results not to get the wavelength
but they use those results to get this distance here eight
the distance between the atoms that's what i mean by
getting out the structure
in x-ray diffraction
are coming in with the x-ray beam
and they know what the wavelength is of their x-ray beam
so they know what lambda is
and then they go and measure what data is the scattering angle
and from those two quantities
lambda and data they figure out what it is
the distance between the atoms
and girls in probability measure and new one here is the measurement so the measure
which assigns volume on the real line
then this would be the gas intensity
that brings us back to
to what i said in the beginning there
one reason why we have to use measures in infinite dimensions is because many infinite
dimension distributions don't have a useful density
the problem here is
that the density
the density is always referred defined with respect to some measure
density is not standalone object you have to defined with respect to some reference measure
in this case here for the girls in the reference measure the standard girth density
the reference measure is this this flat back matter
and this kind of uniform
measure on the real line
in order for this to be meaningful
two two burke was this density in the way we usually
i like to work with this measure you has to be it has to be
it has to be flat
if you think of
if you you could very well right
one gaussians represented as density with respect to another gaussian say another goes measure with
different location parameter
but then interpreting interpreting this density becomes really hard
because it means that
when at the point where this goes in here has its mode
this density has to decrease
to make up for the
so you always have to when you want to interpret what large or small density
means would always have to look back at the other measures check is large in
that region or not
so in order for the for the density to be to be interpretable you wanted
to be defined with respect to some
some neutral
and this neutrality is is formalized as translation invariant so the back to measure of
the vision of the which assigns volume you can show it around on the on
the real line
and it never changes with respect to location if you have one you must the
same size at different points on the real line euclidean space it always has the
same volume assigned right there was a question
the case using
well almost so the question is is to measure the cumulative distribution
not quite so the cumulative distribution is
you start at minus infinity
and integrate all the way to your current point
whereas the
the measure can be
can be an arbitrary set so the cumulative distribution in that case would be is
a measure of the interval the open interval minus infinity up to your point
one of
yes so
the problem with the translation invariance is the following
i haven't finished it yet
OK so
in in in basically in euclidean space to the translation invariance is the property which
makes which makes the density the translation invariance of this measure measures property which makes
the density useful
now when you go to infinite dimensional space a hilbert space
then we don't there's there's no translation invariant measure on hilbert space
infinite dimensional spaces don't have translation invariant measure
and that's even even hilbert space even though he was space kind of the most
the nicest and most problematic infinite dimensional space
so there's there's no analogue of the olympic measure in infinite dimensional spaces
which is
basically the whole notion of the volume in infinite dimensions becomes a bit flaky
OK so
and that means that that in order to
in order to to work on infinite dimensional spaces densities are often not an option
so you can have something like a ghost in probability on infinite dimensional space and
that's because the process
and it does have density so you can write the density of one gaussian process
gives you
the interval
the right where
right after this
and we
also law
in most of the existing process of the law some kind of a random mutation
there is a small probability of
somebody's somebody that i
this summer
the size of his
strong the bands
on the ever dealt
if you want to
more precise
we need
the space of some other people
if you do too
i i get probabilities
displays of
i think it's
so sound
basic streaming format
the first one
his son
is useful
too slow by
the problem is
if you look for statistical theory of something
and by a sample of those
we need to know
the sun
number of observations
in the case of the history
this is not possible
number of iterations is
in data streams so we the sampling step
must be
different from standard
and are some
known problems
we with the
tasks that involve
the money starting distribution of string
for example we know that
sampling strategy has low probability of error
are anomalies
take this is an illustrative tech
sampling from data streams
there's been percent
eighty five five
he is the
so what sample
because he is
we want to
only for example of six
five k
the case
the size of the reservoir
this at first scale many elements
and after that
a new
that is
it is inset into this one with these probability
and when we said
but the point we must remove
another point in the
one so the with the at night
one of the things that's the
in the way the this is a very simple of
knowledge base that might be dissolved it's been proven that are much more complex that
is all
but the basic idea is that
we can prove that this is
four only for example by easily for example flat metric
one of the tasks or
in most
machine learning approach
one of the
not relations that is
very common is to come
we need to come from
number of observations really of the class and so on
a real concern
illustrative county
the problem in the case of string
the first one
is that
the number of
this thing follow
of a random variable
suppose that we
the domain of that variable is very large
for example in TCP IP address
suppose that you want to know
on many different parents
the IP
this is the trivial problem
if you do we don't have
memory problem
of the domain
you can see that there is very large
it is not possible
two of them
we have space linear up to two
what we want
is an
approximate solutions
look at it
most of the problems in
data streams
out of this
you have include the the wall that is very large
and you want
that is
and i multiply that
by the difference between my current p
this is my current guess
and the template the template that either
but the have and what i've been doing this i update my car p
with this delta p
and then i keep on in writing until
actually should BP converges not delta p my p convergence estimate p
essentially states that normally we just use a set number iterations so fifteen or twenty
but you can you can actually do a couple of things to profile things and
things like that but that's essentially the in natural very simple it is an application
of the gas and now we can kind of see here
but the magic and happens in how you framed the problem kind of framing this
as one big linear generative model
of how things to spice and then i converted
to try and work out the war
and as i said OK we'll use local patches something so that this is an
image of a scene from one perspective
another from another perspective and if we do
OK so translations are enough patches we can get disparity map
and so that useful for working at distances and depth and things like that
so this is one stereo vision
what it's also useful in
is along
so a couple of examples here of the of the learning for and this is
just right OK
and and if you guys could look this up in a couple onto map but
amazing how it works
so that
this is the final
so can be massively off and you can kind of see here
this is the wall and keeps refining refining
yes yes at the beginning so we can go and we can go over this
sort of so you can actually make this stuff would have have a bigger field
field of
reach if you take a coarse to fine strategy so actually if you subsample this
image down
you take gradients over over subsampled image
you can then use the pixel coherence assumption over that subsampled image rather enough on
image so if you've got a very again there's limit to how far you can
take that but this is for illustration purposes just to come to show that OK
this is my template with the image this is the thing but it is conical
cool the thing it to convert stream how tightly work so if you if you
do it well enough it really fails a big thing but here is how you
calculate gradients and i was talking about yesterday on that so if you can arbitrarily
calculate gradients
this can this can file because the grains might be noisy if you're going the
gradient function in matlab or i i i i prefer so using more regression based
techniques to do the to the to the gradients because it ends up being a
much better prediction because if you think about what you're doing you just have a
model of how
the template image there is a function of delta p
and then when i trying to work out what delta p is on this inventing
that that's all i'm doing so i want to make sure that linear model linear
generative model is a good one
so is every kind of fun with
so it's it's pretty simple but i think it's a nice illustration
i talking about
there's a lot of different extensions and if an changes whatever to the LK algorithm
have been proposed very good a colleague of mine was that same year he says
microsoft research simon baker he wrote actually a suite of
quite long but very interesting papers called OK twenty lucas kanade a lucas kanade have
the the twenty years on and they're kind of five five installments in the in
the papers and
i guess all of
about two hundred pages things and it basically it's all variants of that
so basically like how can i e thirty in his first first volume whatever he
goes through world in this is the least squares iterative problem one of the best
ways of doing for four different images whatever is the hessian always will right because
market bombing
should be actually tackling the phone instead of showing the forecasting rather than the pseudo
science and is there any kind of benefit and perhaps doing steepest descent where on
this basically the gradients and sitting and doing some sort of long search instead of
trying to do a new talk to make but generally for lucas kanade it's well-established
another gasoline approach one that are kind of
been talking about here is the best approach are unfamiliar with casting everything
that are so
and in in bakers baker's work whenever he showed
baker and a couple of other people he showed that for large
a lot of image domains in image top object sort of gasoline it the best
so that's something else you guys can read up on but with decision gasoline here
so now there are computational concerns so the lucas is going and then worked really
for calculating optical flow because most of the time i was dealing with small image
patches on my coherence my what was this translation was really doing anything too fancy
at all
but as soon as i even when get into like in the final
i start getting into some computational concerns
because if you can see here this j which is very important in my is
about actually has to be recomputed at every iteration because i'm updating this page
and i think this p every iteration so i have to keep only keep repeating
this j tackling this has taking the inversion
and and on the unreasonable fast computers is that it's not about when you're talking
over like couple of thousand hundreds of thousands of pixels with quite competitive awards this
can really slow things down so and in vision were all about doing things but
what about doing things they in real time close to real time and even on
the fastest computers at the moment if want account
do complicated war with lucas kanade we can do real time there might be some
hope perhaps integrating some of stuff with GPS and things like that but at the
moment it's still real problem
so is there any way we can precompute
so that's also can be done by companies he
in that case
i like to tell me that multidimensional scaling is a special case appreciate you just
like because because multidimensional scaling is over
anyway logically is a special case of kernel piece e eight
in the
and the
and can
it can be done with all positive definite kernels may be the same is true for much initial scaling
although whenever i see is multidimensional scaling is done before uh stationary kernels that depend only on the distance
history said
okay so logically it subsumes multidimensional scaling and in some some some other methods and
we have a paper about that
and we show that it contains uh
locally linear embedding in the
the last and i can map end in some limit
isomap doesn't always correspond to a positive definite matrix in some limit also isomap so
if you're interested in that had data
in dimensionality reduction and that's interesting
connection to look at
so much about his you
and we applied it to some problems but
in most other applications with by others i think has been applied in the
and i worked in the computer vision
so i'm not gonna go into that
well maybe just i think you don't see much anyway so this is
this was an application to super resolution where we
trained piece e eight on some
high resolution images
and then we took low resolution images projected onto to our learned piece basis
and this we could reconstruct higher resolutions but i think
on this so basically what you should be seeing
is that this reconstruction is sort of similar to the
original and it's better to these other methods better than these other methods but maybe
you don't see it on this
so now support vector machines any questions
but this part
i think we have enough time left for support vector machines
so you've heard about them several times the basic idea
not that enter the feature space compute separating hyperplane which correspond to a non-linear separation in the input domain
so i'll
in detail how the separating hyperplane is computed and hopefully i can also show you
prove a bound on the
we dimension or something
something like it
of same optimum modern or large margin separating hyperplanes
welcome to the programme
i was thinking written
by such an equation
hyperplane is a set of points satisfying this kind of equation where w is a vector of
it's not equal to zero w is the normal vectorp hyperplane
and bees and offset
and this hyperplane can be thought of as a separating one
because this quantity here takes positive values on one side
so in one half space and it takes negative values on the other side of the hyperplane
we can also define an optimal separating hyperplane based on
two datasets
and by this we mean the hyperplane which has
the largest distance to any of the points which separates the points correctly this one class the other class
and while satisfying the constraint that the closest point to the hyperplane
has maximal distance so the distance of the closest point is maximized
one way to get this is to take the convex hulls of these sets of points
and then there's the problem the shortest connection between these two convex hulls and that
will give us the normal vector
note that there is a scaling degree of freedom
in this whole business
we have a hyperplane defined by this equation
we can multiply this equation by some number that's non-zero
which gives us a different weight vector and the different offset
but this is the set of points so this equation is still the same
so there is a degree of freedom is like a cage degree in physics
and this thing here describes the same hyperplane is this thing
and then when k one way to remove this uh was the definition reuptake who said that
uh recall hyperplane being canonical form with respect to a given dataset
if the skating is such that for the closest points of the data set to the hyperplane
this thing here has more to this one
and then i'll talk about how to analyse the training year
and then finally all talk about how to analyse the test error the generalisation error
based on something called the margins theory
OK so
so let me go back to
this description of boosting that i gave at the beginning and give a little bit
more formal description of what the problem is
so we're starting out with the training set as usual with learning problems
so the training set consists of examples
each example is a pair x i y i
OK if one is the pair x i y i the size of the instances
so those are the things we're trying to make predictions on so
like in this call classification example the instances would be
the actual utterances that was set by the telephone caller
and the y axis are the labels
that would be the label that we're trying to predict collect call
a credit card call and so on
so in that problem there are many possible labels
the first part of the talking and assume that there are only two labels
and it's usually convenient to assume that those two labels are just plus one to
minus one
makes the as a little
OK so that's what we're given
and now we want to do is OK so
what i said before is that boosting works in rounds so we're going to have
a capital
eighty rounds
OK so capital t is the number of rounds
and what do we do on each round
what we do with the boosting algorithm does is it starts out by constructing a
the team
over the training examples so these are the indices
the training examples so here and changing things
a little bit earlier i said that on every round of boosting
which is a subset of the examples
and now i'm changing things a little bit and saying instead of choosing a subset
of the examples which is the distribution over the examples
so there sort of the same thing i mean distribution is sort of just a
softer version of choosing a subset and you can take a distribution in subsample from
and and created this a subset and so on
so what we're doing is we're constructing this distribution
and the idea is that we're going to put the most weight on the examples
that we care the most about
so the weight under the distribution is going to reflect how much we care about
each one of those training examples
for this particular round of boosting
so we construct this distribution dt somehow
and then we passed the distribution after the weak learning algorithm
the weak learning algorithm gives us back
a weak classifier what i was calling before rule of thumb
and we classifiers like any classifiers just for you know that each t
and all it is is the prediction rule so it says for any instance
in our space
the classifiers giving us the prediction which is either plus one to minus one
and what we want
from the weak learners we want the weak learner to find a weak classifier with
small area
OK so we're measuring a better way of saying it is that we are measuring
the goodness
of each of these weak classifiers
in terms of
it's error rate
so it's air raid with respect to the distribution dt in which it was trained
so we measure the goodness of one of these weak classifiers
as the probability of choosing one of these training examples under the distribution dt
such that training examples misclassified
such that the prediction of that we classifier around
example outside
is different from the correct label y i
kennedy noting that mary epsilon two
they should think about twenty is a fairly big number
like forty percent
so we do that for capital t rounds
and then finally we take all of these weak classifiers we combine them into a
single combined or final classifier each five
so there are two
really important details that i'm leaving out from the slide
the first one is
how do you construct the distribution dt
and secondly once we found all the weak classifiers how do we combine them into
the combined
class for the final combine classifiers
so here's how adaboost answers those questions
so first of how do we construct the distribution dt
how do we construct this distribution dt
well on the very first round and round one
we don't have any
information of any kind so just uniform distribution over all the examples will give equal
weight or importance to all of the training examples
so they each get way
one over and since there
so now how do we update this distribution
well suppose on round t
we have the distribution dt
we have the weak classifier ht that we just computed
and now we want to do is we want to update this distribution
so adaboost is something very very simple
are we going to do is we're going to increase the weight of examples which
incorrectly classified because we're trying to focus on those hard examples
we're going to cut the weight of the examples which were correctly classified
because we want to give them less importance because they work
just correctly classified
so for each example i saw trying to compute the new distribution
t plus one for the following round
so for each example by i
things off i think what we need to do
is consider
a definition i mean to define what love was
but then most of the experiments i'm going to talk about are
really focused more on attraction and one who finds each other
all of romantic interest that might develop into
i love
relationship but let's start with the definition of love and i'm going to pick a
definition from a former colleague robert sternberg
o is now the dean
at tufts university but was here on right faculty yellow
for nearly thirty years or so
and here is the theory of love that are that it's made up of three
components intimacy
and commitment to what is sometimes called decision
commitment and these are relatively straightforward he argued that you don't have a lot if
you don't have all three of these elements intimacy
is the feeling of closeness
of connectedness with someone of bonding
operational you could think of intimacy as you share
share information
with this person that you don't share with anybody else
that's really what intimacy is the bottom and that comes from sharing information that is
with other with many other people
the second element
it's passion passion is what you think it it does
passion is the dry we would say the drive leads to romance you can think
of it as physical attraction or sex and
sternberg argues that this is a required component
of a love relationship it is not however require component of taking a shower in
calvin college before
the third element of luck in instead theories is
what he calls decision or commitment the
that one is in a love relationship the willingness to label it as such commitment
to maintain their relationship at least for some period of time starring would argue it's
not love if you don't call it love and if you don't have some desire
to maintain the relationship
if you have all three of these
passion and commitment installments the
you have one
what's interesting about the theory is what you have if you only have one to
or two three
what do you have and how is it different if you have a different two
out of three
these are what's interesting about this kind of theorizing is it gives it gives rise
to many different permutations that when you break them down and start to look at
them carefully
could be quite interesting so what i've done is i've taken
sturm graz three elements of love intimacy passionate commitment
and have listed out the different kinds of relationships one might have
if you had
zero one two or three
out of the three elements that i'm using names or types that stauffenberg uses in
his theory these are really from some of these are pretty obvious
if you don't have intimacy if you don't have passion if you don't have commitment
you don't have love story recalls this non love
that's the technical terms and essentially what he's saying is the relationship you now have
to the person sitting next to you presuming that is sitting next to a random
person that you didn't know
the college is probably not a lot
if it's something else we can talk about it at the end of the lecture
or perhaps when i get to it in moment now let's start to an
let's and intimacy this is sharing
a feeling of closeness connectedness bonding
let's say we have that was someone but we don't have passion there is no
sexual arousal and no commitment to maintain
the relationship this is like kingston recalls it
and like
is really what is happening in most typical friendships not close friendships but friendships of
other casual kind
you feel close to share information with that person that you don't share with other
many other people
which are not physically attractive and there's no particular commitment to maintaining this
for a long period of time
now what if you're not in it
you're not committed but your passion
you feel that sexual arousal
is what story would call infatuation and that term probably works for you too infatuated
and so this is love at first sight
i don't know
no you
we've never shared any secrets because i don't know you
i'm not can not committed to
defining this is anything i'm not committed to the future effect not thinking about the
future but right now
but why am i attractor
that's that's that's infatuation and that's what what's removed by
infatuated the third kind of it's one element
relationship if there's no intimacy right no binding no cause there's no secrets
no physical attraction
no sexual arousal
gosh we are going to maintain this relationship we are committed to it for all
so called the empty love to love is kind of interesting