yeah what can can I just continue my conversational part without the formulas
I guess it seems to me that a key problem is
we're doing squares
were doing estimation where is that that satellite or that missile
and then we get another measurement
so that's 1 more bit of information
updates gives us a correction to the estimated position
because that
this is just 1 more bit of that information is selected somehow this at a
rank 1 change in our in our in our estimation problem and then we're looking
for the change in the answer
and that's what
a recursive least-squares the Kalman filter and filtering is all about
is updated
from new information updating the old answer with new information
OK and that's what we're doing here we can I guess and regarding here is
t inverse is our only answer
that we
that we've found because of especially easy
and now I'm updating by that much
and I'm looking for the new OK i'm just gonna write down the formula that
that we will see later so that you answer that I want is the old
incomes of Canada others k minus T
as this is this rank one matrix yeah maybe I'll just show just keep people
came minus I think maybe it maybe here is the magic formula
right without
my eyes I think it's gonna involve only 2
and I k minus T
and other team inverse
that looks pretty good
and now down below
I think it's something like 1 + choose
Italian number here
that was good
right down here 0 so I have to say with these 2 this rank one
matrix splits and so like can what made would enjoy give that vector
Italy's something that's
is that column vector and then this is the
and so what shows up down here I think it is
in numerous
or maybe it's
no it's the it's the other side because I don't end up with a number
it's easy transpose
In 1st iii
think that's right that might not have all the signs right
this is the beauty of that formula
right for
it's almost right and and about
about a hundred people have discovered this
and they all thought wonderful and the names attached to it so the formula that
so many names now
I could mention also maintained would operate
the old time remaining shoe over all the all out when I do this formula
properly I'll produce more but you see that it has exactly of what we hope
is because what we know what we know here we know T t inverse
so there's 2 universes and we know OK
and this is a rank one matrix and this is just a number down here
so we know everything here and it gives us the inverse of the new and
if I didn't write it would produce this correction this this whole stuff
would be this correction
and we would have already
OK now I don't know entirely satisfied because
the formula got produced under the name of I'm quite since it and what I
want to say is
this really looking ahead that that that this formula and the
that is the change in the matrix is some rank one matrix
the change in the universe is also rank 1 it's more complicated looking thing about
this guy is the right 1
so the whole thing is rank 1
and and there it was in this particular instance OK so I was quite happy
is the thing
thank you
one from
i'm not
and then
the result
i have a lot of that
i mean
and are people
thank you
around a little
i assume that are here
and then you
we're not going to
a lot of things
well known
o thing
i e
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
OK good morning welcome back on
what i want to do today is
actually wrap up our discussion on learning theory and
inspired by talking about bayesian statistics and regularisation
and then take very brief digression to save for online learning and almost of today's
lecture will actually be on various pieces by supplying machine learning algorithms for problems like
like approach to other problems go work on after you graduate from the school
on the topic of bayesian statistics improvisation
so remember from last week starts learning theory and we learned about bias and variance
and they get in the previous lecture was for most of the previous lecture talking
about more talking about algorithms for model selection
and feature selection itself has validation so most methods he talks about in the previous
lecture on what waits for you to try to simplify the model so for example
the features section out we talked about gives you a way to eliminate the number
of features of system reduce the number of parameters need to fit and thereby reduce
overfitting that feature selection algorithms
chooses subset
chooses subset of the features so that you have less parameters and may be less
likely to want to do today is talk about a different way to prevent overfitting
on and this is the magic of regularisation and is awaiting lets you keep all
the parameters
so here's the idea and we illustrate this example with arms a linear regression
so if we take
the linear regression model to the very first small we learned about right arm we
said that we would choose the parameters
maximum likelihood
and that meant that you know you choose the parameters theta
that maximize
on the probability of the data which is from stay that maximize the probability of
the data we have
and so
to get this so the procedure and this is one example was called the frequencies
procedure and frequencies you think of as as one school of statistics on
and the philosophical view behind breaking this down was we envision that there was some
true around the theta out there that generated yet exist otherwise it true data
they govern
housing prices y is the function of x
and we don't know what the value of batteries
and would like to come up with some procedure for estimating the value of data
and so that's the likelihood is just one possible procedure
for estimating the unknown value
the data
and in
the way for later this year the data was not a random variable
that's why it's so data is just some true value out there's is not random
or anything we just don't know what it is we have a procedure called as
like the first made
value for data so there's one example with color sequences procedure
the alternative to the
because the frequencies school statistics is the bayesian school
in which
when say that we don't know what features
and so we will put a prior
on theta
so so in the bayesian because is to say well i don't know what validate
chrysalis represents uncertainty over data with the prime
so for example
of high on data may be gaussians distribution
with mean zero and covariance matrix given by house where i
and so
two values as they in my
training set well
so say to represent my beliefs about what the prime dissolved in the absence of
any date not having seen any data
was the john nash is nobel prize
very nearly
not granted it was
i almost voted in an hour before it was supposed to be enhanced
it this is in october nineteen ninety four now i didn't learn that
when i was working on a
time story then
i learned it
not until several years later after i had in fact already delivered the first draft
of the biography
the whole nobel process
is a closely guarded secret there's almost never any leaks
and in fact
all of the deliberations are sealed
the nobel archives for fifty years
after the war prize
the final vote does not take place until the morning that the price is made
in in fact the reporters already milling around in the interior of the the
swedish academy of sciences
we have the final
you know which administers the prize and whose members
get to cast the final
vote making the prize official
it turned out
on october fourteen nineteen ninety four when ashes prize came up for what usually is
a completely full form of old
it turned out that many members
the swedish academy and most especially the physicists
i objected to
the idea
stowing his ultimate scientific honor
and that
there a
we're worried that john nash
would embarrass
the prize
at the ceremony which was to take place in december
and they were worried that giving him nearly giving him the prize would sully the
now fortunately for john nash and i think for the rest of us
there were some very courageous members of the academy who
i took the position
nash is mental illness was no more relevant to the question of whether his contribution
to economics married prize then if he'd suffered from some physical
and they
narrowly carried the vote
as an aside
the morning after the academy awards i call janowicz in that way
he said well so how do you feel
there was a silence about ten seconds john almost never answers the question directly
when you start speaking again all of a sudden he was comparing the
with the nobels
well he said
they both involve academies
and they both involve
a lot of politics
back to the day that the prize
it was announced i was sitting in the news newsroom the new york times
scrolling through the wire stories
had really
you know i hadn't really thought much more about this amazing story but when i
saw john nash his name
the AP story
i jumped up and ran over to my editor
i had not
i hadn't wanted to write the story you have earlier
when i first heard that our and fascinating arc his life
i felt that it was such a long shot that someone who had been out
of accademia for so long
that someone like me which would actually win
i thought it would be a real invasion of privacy
to write about his life in the new york times at that point but
having won the prize
having the protective mantle i was going to write
i knew i had to write that story
now it was a very tough story together
i worked on for about three weeks
none of the economists are mathematicians who i initially called we're willing to put national
schizophrenia on the record
you have to understand this is an illness
even in the nineteen nineties
it is so stigmatized
but even if
you have thought of as a quote
the most remarkable mathematician of the second half the century even if you had just
a nobel prize
the people who care about you your friends and admirers
i felt the need to protect you from the s word
and it was nashi sister martha
who finally decided
so to speak frankly about her brother's illness
and she had not decided to break the silence
nash is inspiring story would have remained
now i've got a tremendous number of letters
when the story ran which was that three weeks after nash got prize
and let me tell you about one
i've never forgotten
it arrived in this
envelope no return address
it was scrawled on this neon orange piece of paper
it was signed only berklee baby
it would never have gone past the new york times mailed after the anthrax scare
this letter
it turns out to have been written
by someone
in the mid nineteen seventies
he two
was diagnosed with paranoid schizophrenia
had been
the new york times rising editor at the new york times
since then
given up his given name
had adopted the name berklee baby and had been living
untreated on the streets of berkeley california
near the university
a set figure
much like the phantom final
and what he wrote was that he had read john nash story
in the paper
and what he said was
johnny cash's story
it gives me hope
that one day
the world will come back to me too
and that letter
and a lot of letters like it
i never got one
that was
quite that eloquent
that letter helped convince me
to go ahead and spent two and half years on leave from the times to
nash's biography
you should know
by the way the biography was not authorized
almost on the first day of my really hard one leave
when i just arrived in princeton
john nash sent me an email in which you inform me
most about two
actually what i talked about before
and the right to be one of the first one
i just half
how are
but don't can
so it's just measure
the how problem is
the first is also in the middle
the other thing is that
the complexity of
and what want to the call
half of the
the show
it is called
no it's not
so there is a
the same
what are the problems affecting established
actually which is why
woman which collection
they have
the usual
about hundred images
and they all have a right
of course it's lots of different systems with a
collection because it
the band
what the colour
let's try to search
the park
the became
they have
well picture
pictures first
they don't like this
well the that is
but in the last
this week
like the rest of their lives
my my
it looks like
o main just below on
and that are social
the reason for the
the result
so you can we collect
the other
you could
below a real big island
i mean it was a member one million just
he was elected to the to the but lost the election
from we are you and others that there
the river it was never
and the reason people
not only
you see is to participate in
there were some
let's make
here i'm
one of those people who
and now
the colour
and you know
in the commercial world you've got too many people writing new drivers
and not enough people fixing
if you take a team of people writing new drivers change their job description manager
comes in one morning and said congratulations from now on your fixing cars
maybe one of the leaves but the rest of canada
in the free software well you can't just people say well we've got too many
developed developers to any driver writers so
you knew
you've been volunteered to extend instead
doesn't actually work in the results
in fact it and you can use
find the good drink beer instead
so what
so we have this problem and it's a lot it's an image problem is this
idea that writing new drivers cool
everybody wants to be right right
we have the same problem on the biggest scale
because everybody wants to be involved in kind
so how can we can kinda cool project is the the cardinality depends on the
true everything depends on things like c libraries well
but i g live c
simply doesn't have the ring it doesn't look so good guide your CV
business card
even though it's actually probably harder project
it's a lot better documents
and it's far more important
you do have to do with all equities is also is actually a really nice
guy and then the GTC meaningless for you
the other places you people really really want to write a new drive
the windows developers desperately need more people
because expenses are very difficult times
which ended up with a big splash in extrinsic or
x became started
and in that they lost a lot of people got upset with the always thank
you very bad things would
and they have got nothing being done sensibly properly very rapidly
not picked up enough people
and that the next people got manual
people got manual
the car drivers need fixing
the got new drivers new writing
got people like HCI finally working with trying to right heart complicated three d drive
so if you want to write new co-driver k x people would really really love
this is
maintaining can seize the small detail record below
the way to maintain his campaign is quite interesting
nobody goes around in circles if you been elevated to the job maintain
because somebody dominant up like patches together
and if they are good at it and the the end of the ninety nine
we do not maintain its level kernel
which in theory tells you who is maintained
maintain this fact is not itself have maintained
this is occasionally a problem because it does get day
people really good so i will maintain
the really bad at remembering to remove themselves when they decided what
and sometimes people just disappear
as with anything else
politics people might occasionally something that catches my eye
we also have a good process for removing maintain just manage
sometimes we want somebody will be maintaining disappear six
although still maintaining my that nothing happens
we don't have the press i find it was now maintained
so have people disappear into google for six months and then suddenly reappear
i like what you
i have removed to maintain his entry in the meantime again
we have lots and lots of all code in the car
one of the problems with all code is there's always somebody still using it
in the commercial world decisions get made along the lines of
if we remove this drive we will upset
no point three percent user base
we don't care
in the face of the world is much more difficult
and the so
we tend to do is got people like aided by systematic trying to remove every
single piece canopy
on the basis that you find use
other people trying to stop it
and we do try to do when you got some small number of users
is persuade them to maintain
because if you saw it using the kernel
ten years
as a very small number users
chances are works
it will continue to work
and it probably never any match-fixing
if nobody is interested in maintaining sometimes can fall by the wayside because nobody can
be bothered fix
what some change occurs
finally break the point
and occasionally we just give up the class some architectural
so everywhere that we recently got rid MCA possible
you have the PS two your attic picture elements are about
one hard ones and if you will be when we get rid lice are possible
when we get rid of three things
we did try getting rid of three things present for around two point six
people object
because when people start running embedded system of everything she
well this result trying images
they've been a little bit
process without talk about later
so what to show you
we've all seen patterns of c
this is very since this
this is this is this
and this is constant so here we have the right
are they oxygen columns
this is cast at all
so we see the intensity ratio is also on
on this basis i would say more complex
the best
this is one important thing on the other hand of course
we have listing
the images are more noise was you
and this is not a ban on the
a lot of
whereas the higher
it is this one
more sensitive
so should remind
now so that the business at causes makes the king oxygen carbon which is about
fifteen percent one twenty one seven
can really resolve the difference in total number
between the two columns
just another thing about the specimens
well this is a situation we always
amorphous is there risk
i call this information there
which is composed of some
time trials
which the
we have a very fine control by is
no matter can crawl space
spaces and some of the problems
and that was the best she really really rare but we don't have the
but you can
yes this is what was here
here's one the i
i mean this amorphous layer and the house
the course
other things that you have to be like plasma etching in order to this hydrocarbon
thriller which
is the one which really caused the contamination
it was
actually introduction and then i'll show you
the results on
in the is that it is a cost
i was going to use these images
his something
the basic idea is a lot of systems
obviously this is an old one which is much more difficult
and of course all the images according to
the microscope
actually show
number one is that some solutions
so the solution in order
but it just random
so the solution which we use for atoms are incorporated into the
this matrix
of nodes on the simpsons
and this very guys are also
i don't know what does that
is very material shown
this is the solution that they
he gets into lot
so on a way that you can see his vision to
and if you look
closer inspection regions this
course if we exclude the possible opted spaces
so we start with the relation
you see this
and is a these regions
we're a science
well you should be true
not all
should use it on this is this this is not all that sort solution
and also decides to have larger and larger numbers
all the average
o seven hundred
one is sense
this is the essence around thirty four years
order be some work done recently
many years
it's about this type of
this is actually only matters
they can be used same individual atoms within a crystal
research on such a scale
another thing was faces
this is one of the combined work
well aware that i mentioned
it's also
so someone that materials
and this is a
and this is what i mean it's one one o o xo
that means that the question was what is terminating plate between the palladium is going
to try to
not just because of all nations
i was in were shown in playing tenuous oxygen between the palladium
and this is something that also included just based on the intensity
another thing that the study was
this diodes
which is
very important
replacing the
raise additional sources
well actually the right to use this
one parts
it's all the superstructure
let's structure which is composed of gallium nitrate
in early in the united right
function is supposed to be on the
and the question was
can we
resolved by using the inductance stand
those different layers which are only about three to six also the question was posted
does this work
if here
the first
we might as well you
this makes it easy to resolve these solutions
so what you see is actually an millions of
the magnifications since
this first these relations
very few people getting so she can see is that is a lot of issues
this one
which is the visible and said he was going to use all
these differences
it is see this image here
white's dark
so i would say
and signs
the started once the media
and the guardian
for right one
well it's a shame it really
quite noisy
one of them
and so
it may of my
i'm on a roll
you may be
i will
there are already
the very
they are
don't know
a year
three of the car
of all of
well on
one day
you might read the model
he is what he
all right
from here
he all
we're going to do is to to compute the posterior distribution of the axis i'm
going to make a very particular assumption
which is that i want
a posterior distribution on which is factorized
so i want to get i don't want to have a joint distribution of the
axis can be way too complicated to five hundred times that we have a joint
vision hundred things that's as unwieldy so instead i'm going to try and get the
marginal distribution of each of the axes
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
look for
a distribution qx one which is costing the next one
xt which is constant x two and so on
and the way i can ensure that is only to approximate my factors in a
particular way
only due to ensure that is a is the only factors that are really bugging
me so the factors that are connected to y
are really a problem because goshen and only one variable anyway
the real problem of transition factors the transition vectors connecting two axes
together and i don't want that
because if i want to multiply those together get a couple distribution
so we're going to do is i'm going to factor and approximate each of those
transition factors
with two separate
singleton factors going so
so if the transition factors this one
so this is the p of x two given x one
so these factors which cause coupling in my problem
and i want that so
what we do is going to take each one of those factors
it is used to be
if x two given x one
what i'm going to do is i'm going to replace that with two gaussians and
replace it with the gas in the next one and gas in NXT
that would be my approximation
i will call that
backward distribution for x one and the other one will called
the for distribution facts
just the right a different way
going to take it
this transition factor when approximated as
the product of two gaussians
one x one one x two
and i'm going to from the transition factors and it should be clear that have
done that
i know
i have just a separate gaussian distribution of my
variables right because this distribution here
was already quite friendly
was just p y one given x
which was already also in this case
and now i want you is multiply that with the background distribution of the
could i approximated by harold by distribution depends on both x one x two
i certainly could be the negative posterior which is
i joint function about x one x two so i said from the outset i
want i want just marginal distributions are not to each other variables
absolutely yes so if you want a better approximation you can use bigger and bigger
something so you can say that i want to use
the first two distribution what the first two variables to be in one of my
approximate posteriors second variables within one and so on and so do that and in
fact what you do in that case is you just simply not break
the transition between one and two parts they would only break the transition between two
and three part for example that would give you what you wanted give joint and
one to enjoy something more
so it's really just the choice of we want decided what you want your approximation
to look like how much structure you want to be in you then can you
doesn't work anymore for all that your semantic web people towards
and the last point is reason about the state of it you wrote from different
this is a standard problem is not something that was not
see there's a problem before the semantic web it's about integration problem OK and several
ways to solve it comes from the database community one possible way to so this
is a
writing down an abstract representation of all the sources this up the representation of those
to query from the top but we vote caring about the different of the sources
so you have an object representation that is the coupling the queries
from the actual representation of the different sources but connected
you have the problem of
merging the results extracting the
the information from the repository and merging them and if you do that then of
course the problem is solved because you can start making creating all over the entire
group of information so
drawing it here
the solution is physically
the lot of an abstract model
that the alone
the different sources down here
this one is musicbrainz is one is music awards
and this one is the PDB
to be represented at these levels of it you can write it freely
we're about to really caring about beatings
of these different representations
on the way evans represented this these
so the
you don't hear you have the different representations of things in relation of four months
things about a document things that are XML stuff whatever the case that it genius
in many
a different way than you have absolute more than p of application that use query
to manipulate it
what the semantic web in the last seven years is providing technology to address this
problem of data integration so
we have a way to do the abstract model which is using these
very simple data model which is rts
OK so a graph based approach to represent all the different for source of information
technology to move from the specific services
octave abstract model
and you see
agreed which is a way to move from from XML to what yes
and you have a way to expose like DFA
and if a
make data inside the neck
xml pages so you physically tagging the page and the data can distraught
so our technology to
to move from here to here
and then you have also technology to characterize you to more than in terms of
all an ontological language so the relationship that kind of resources you might collating and
so forth like rdfs how scores
and you have your query language
it was possibility to try to a from the top
and clearly that's more
so more going back to this picture from evil
you have on this board
they agreed that if a you have that you
as a way to represent these and not here you have this article about inference
as a way to access the for
so i mean
in these like what i try to do is really to show that the technology
of their so it's up to us to use them in the best possible way
to address real problems like the one that ten percent
the ingredient is software engineering i mean we are developing a semantic web application but
still a web application or is still an application OK so what we did in
this seven here it also
trying to address the problem of how we develop an application which contains semantics so
of course we start from aspartame more the like of the buenos but in more
which is represented here and i hope that you are familiar with these kinds of
things because it's too hard to explain them but the basic idea is that you
move from one prototype to another
iteration by iteration
to address a bigger problem so you first try to collectivity it's very easy requirement
to develop the prototype that satisfy them in a very lightweight that you try to
collect the more detailed requirements and then you develop a better prototype it tries to
satisfy them in a better way and you keep doing this and can you believe
that you got all the requirements and on in that moment develop their application
OK so this is the standard
four long way of developing application from design implementation but you do that on in
the end and the rest is fast prototyping spiraling out to the core of the
so what i will follow is our extended approach to these
it's basically the same thing but we put the problem of inferring semantics during the
so up here the first steps as we did that we have the user needs
to you try to understand what the big need the need will be broken down
into requirements but thing the first problem is very is very neat and then you
do something which is called risk analysis you try to to
understand if it's meaningful to satisfy these needs are if it's not possible OK so
if you go through the steps which is something that i mean we're not addressing
here than what you have to do is to stop the requirements we believe that
in a semantic web application you should care about two different experts on one side
you have a softer requirements as always
but on the other side you have very strong requirement on the content what a
drove there is the standard way to and data integration
so the data is as important as the software but does integration OK so we
believe that at this point you have to to distinguish these two parallel requirement phases
on one side you do the standard requirement analysis for the software on the other
side you do this same requirement analysis for the content
then what then you started designing and redesigning as more than software engineering is more
than trivial
so you start developing more than the more they will be guiding fuel through the
entire development process to implementation in our case we believe it is possible instead of
using UML and stand modelling frameworks to use
semantic web languages so OWL rdfs as a way to develop these models and then
use this model for the entire applications so as you do
well the UML diagrams and things like that when you design
the application here you do the model of the application ontology so the application ontology
i'm replacing working in american dealer was originally going to give this talk but he
had to
only had back home so
so i'm doing it for him
and this talk will be of quite a different nature because what be describing is
large scale machine learning application within microsoft with a little bit of context of what
the machine learning problem is why we need to solve it
what the impact is and then
drilling down a little bit to perform our bayesian methodology and if there sometimes
i'll i'll touch a little bit of one
i will address the the scale problems in this this is joint work with thomas
borchert ralf herbrich and
and keen on our online services and advertising research group in microsoft research cambridge
so here is the outline of the talk i'll give you first an idea of
the applications
within which we're working which is paid search advertising within the
the bing search engine
then i describe our model predictor which
over the last summer was introduced into the search engine is now driving one hundred
so the stuff that you hear about is actually
the stuff running
within our search and and then i'm not quite sure have some time for these
these are things
so let's let's begin by describing the task the the general context
just to give you an idea about the advertising industry business size
this is split according to various advertising channels here and you see it's been steadily
going out
and this is the GDP of denmark is microsoft revenue so that's that must be
the reason why why are management is interested in pursuing this despite the harsh competition
that's out there
but we keep trying
if we look at a little bit the growth figures just to give some more
motivation to why one would want to be in this business here the more traditional
advertising channels that people have been using and they all hovering at around ten percent
growth rate
per year
and this is online advertising
so again it's it comes from a relatively low level but certainly there seems to
be some great opportunities out there and it's well known that the budget is going
from from the sky over two
two online advertising as well
so this is our humble attempt to search i would recommend to tried everything now
and then because the competition certainly must be a good thing even in this market
and we have an advertising model that works pretty much like yahoo and google model
as well
so this is basically an explanation of those systems as well
someone enters the theory into the box here and there are organic search results and
then they're paid search results on top here and on the sidebar here and advertisers
are keen on getting those because there's a great targeting opportunity
because the user indicates some intent
through the theory and
advertisers would like to capitalize on that potentially offer their services and goods to the
do that through an option and they bid a certain amount of this time the
might one dollar this one minus two dollars and so on
in order to get their stuff displayed on the page because there is typically more
slots than there are people
so if you slots the people
interested in this slot but more importantly the top slots are much more interesting in
terms of click-through rate the bottom slots here which hardly ever clicked
and that makes for for healthy competition in that the market
so how does this work now to do we just sort these by these numbers
and then allocate those spaces no that's not how it works
there's an additional quantity coming in this click-through rate here the estimated probability of click
for this particular and if it was shown in this main line
to actually be clicked
because as a search and we're interested in maximizing the product of the bids
and the probability of click because expected that we
and again this is all true for yahoo and google as well for
and so what is actually sorted by is the expected revenue
based on bit and
link and now
we don't use the first price auction as would normally be the case but generalized
second price auction which creates a nice incentive structures for people
to be more likely to actually bid what they think the thing is worth without
having to fear that they are being exploited
and that's how these people are these figures you are i've at
and basically you can think of
the ordering as
we ordered by this product bid
times probability of click
so the one for the first guy needs to be greater than the one for
the second guy and so on
a which
and that with it you can see qualitatively has to decrease with firm size but
when one plants that we are paper it decreases
with the power law
the typically extends over five or six or seven orders of magnitude remarkably long range
of this power law and the slope is always approximately point
little as a little more
and this behaviour described not only as we as people later found out the firm
growth problem but a number of other growth situations even in which i will which
we can talk about privately later
so the quantity that we describe as the pdf of the growth rate given the
size of the company and that's this exponential class distribution it's much more normal is
to gibraltar
theory would have led us to believe so this overthrows the ten
if brought theory very dramatically because there's no way in which this tend looks like
a logo motivation
and the way it decays as a power law
very recently
when a user logs data became available
thanks to collaboration
with pamela lee and rick about me
and look and see an inference
it became clear that in in addition to this ten distribution the little deviations in
the wings which actually you can already see you notice reporting start to do this
block started to so about one or two
units of growth rate
there is a deviation and when you have and they do you can see all
friends and you can see that this deviation is very very real in fact ten
is the thing that doesn't look so real so what is that what is the
full distribution or just as montana found the truncated levy distribution with the gives rise
to power law of large right so here the ten shape look class distribution gives
rise to power law
at large in the tails depart exponent happens to be three
but don't confuse it with the other one because this is the PDF not the
cumulative so this thread is like other three but so far as we know they
have nothing to do with each other maybe someone in this room will find the
OK so
this is the new law of economics that cries out for explanation and we think
we have that explanation with the reason number of collaborators and i have pointed to
so let's make take message for this part of the talk and then we'll wrap
it up
the decline message messages the histogram of growth rates for in economics which is the
growth rates of companies impact companies is not brought all but is will plus in
the centre and universal
and that this histogram crosses over to a power law in the
there's is no
theory that for the exponent the describes the power law for the win but there
is a theory for the growth rate power law
so i think i exhausted my time i think it's good place to try to
summarise i think the key summary is motivated by these discussions i've had with some
real statisticians
here this meeting already and that is the statistics
if cycled over this
in general what the stream is not linearly separable
so now can you say anything is not going to be there is not going
to be any convergence here
because the stream can be arbitrary but can you say something about the behaviour of
the ag nevertheless
but this is trickier invisible
can say i mean this system is arbitrary and the other is not is going
to be
erratic going economic out they might be up to date
completely opposite
was gonna walk back and forth endlessly but what the point here but still
we can make visible analysis even in this apparently hopelessness of the situation
so the idea
o k
eventually in this is what i'm going to prove
and of course
it's a question the sky be infinitely many you so which one is fine
o work
should be questions before going
can get
the very is slightly inference
device different properties he was asking if you can
if but you know by using this as an optimisation problem if you can use
a different
up to that
possibly using real action may perform the update
but perhaps taking into account for the previous example
and the answer is yes you can and will be doing this
as an optimisation problem more closely
in in the in the near future and we allow us a lot about relationship
between the
let's say the SVM problem
as a problem in the online problem that
idolizing here
so we will explore a little bit the relationship between
optimisation of online learning and what
to the extent that to the extent that can understand them which is not too
much so
you don't need a lot of a lot of background in an optimisation convex optimisation
here so let's call it a bit the
comparison here
now that you know
first of all
one way to get to see some so let's look at more ambitious goal stream
there is no nonseparable what can i what can i say we can prove what
kind of book and about how in i prove political views into the picture and
he of y about minus one is the
the indicator function of found that
al gore brings to the perceptron made a mistake at he
so this is zero or one
according to
because the current hypothesis was correct or
wrong the
example example industry so one way to go about it would be OK i would
like to prove something like this
now now i think in general in between three not necessarily linearly separable
so want to bound the number of states this is just the count of mistakes
and what i found by something that could be something like this
some other ones
so what is this this is the number of mistakes
made on the same stream
made by
some fixed
it doesn't depend on the context the prior is expected
it is
runners has been affected by the difference between and counting the number of states then
it's on x x the first
maybe regularisation things and i think in the best of the best
linear classifiers for that
so this could be a patients so
to the extent that there is a good fit for something to classifier for that
i want to be
i want my number mistakes to be
close to with some small additional
this this would be a
now this is imprecise right but i have been impressed because not useful what's the
problem here
the problem is
you know
you might not have this problem here
in general this optimisation problem so give me a general
general said not necessarily separable i want to minimize want to find the apply at
play that minimizes the number of mistakes on this this this this problem is NP
the what is the number of papers i'm not going to get into the details
this is a little discouraging in this is that if you want to come up
if you want if you're interested in efficiency simplicity
you can possibly hope to get it said you approximate
so it's
it is not the right thing to look at should be looking at something like
the different
if you want
still two end up with the a vicious rules so first of all that about
likely to the perceptron is able to
is called and it's like an efficient algorithm and showing average is cool because even
the batch problem even if you're given history
it's already hard
in competition to so
this can change due this is the motivation to change this objective go
it something
if something is so you want to build something
that you already doing optimisation which is a relaxation of the problem is how to
relax the problem
he relaxes by
making that
making the right hand side larger so you want to compare
we allow a linear classifier
which is worse performance is measured according to different
a different measure than mistakes
so and that
i mean marionettes you know and cannot be talking about markov chain monte carlo said
just before i start could i have a show of hands who has actually use
in their work already
OK and i i know from talking to some this morning from you have stated
that i have i apologize that it might be a bit slow hope you'll get
something out of it but again to give you an overview of just why we
would do monte carlo of any sort at tall and
for those of you who already
no infinity might not see anything new intel maybe the second
so using a lot about the probability distributions graphs and in the morning and so
i'm going to start with something
very trivial it is i think probably the first
statistical problem given in high school which is how do you find the mean of
a bunch of objects a if i was interested in knowing the average height of
a bunch of people
i would go to measure the heights and i would add them up and divide
and are divided into the sum of the quantity is just the same algorithm the
IQ or for some reason john went after so what we're left or right handed
for the practical so there are people who actually go out into the sort of
the danger going to a lot of technical lectures about graphical models and probability distributions
is that you end up adopting the funny language so let's say instead of
knowing the height of lectures here i was interested in knowing the average height of
people in cambridge then
that's a some of the height of each person from the old people in cambridge
by by the number of people in cambridge and when you go to these lectures
in out of the language where you say this is an intractable inference problem because
it's very large computation
whereas we know that you know this isn't a difficult problem all you actually need
to do is just go and grab a bunch of people look at how high
they are averaged the heights and you have a pretty good idea of what the
average people in cambridge and
but a lot of the problems that we lost about how difficult they are
it's just as easy
to to solve problems we are interested and say
if you've got any integral that's an expectation is an integral over probability distribution of
some function you can play exactly the same trick instead of actually on your computer
visiting every little element of your space and measuring the height of your function and
adding them all up you can just take a bunch of samples from the distribution
the averaging over take the empirical average over the samples that gathered and get a
pretty good idea of what the end call is that the
ideas to implement carlo that is all montecarlo in
an application
so you you had to bayesian inference problem and you have some data and you
wanted to make a prediction about some new quantity then
predictive distribution is just an average you look at the posterior distribution over the parameters
in order to be a probabilistic model is and you say well if any new
those parameters i would know how to make predictions someone told me what the ground
truth current model if i make predictions so i do that for every setting the
parameters and weight by how probable and again you just you can do it by
just sampling the parameters from the distribution and take an empirical average
so monte carlo has an obvious application whenever you're doing great inferences tentacles like this
is difficult it also have applications in
all sorts of places where probability distributions come up so if you have to fit
parameters using an algorithm called and then you often need to compute statistics this can
be written as averages and geoff hinton next week my talk a lot about both
machines involved in machine learning algorithm involves the sort of something average
so we have to be a bit more formal and thing we just grab a
bunch of samples and then look at the average we can we can say properties
about it's a
the we can look at the expectation of this estimator and it
it is trivial to show that this is unbiased say
on average this estimator will get the right answer
and you can also say well happy
how much will
the estimator deviate from the answer so you can compute the variance of the estimator
and was knighted that it shrinks with the number of samples say if you want
to veterans who discover more samples you don't have to go and implementing new algorithm
is just wait longer
and because this is the variance in we normally interested and are about the error
bars shrink with the square root of the number of samples although you just have
to wait long you end up having to wait longer and longer if you want
your about to be ten times shorter you're going to have to wait a hundred
times fungus say is the trade-off
OK so
i said i saw this example long time ago i'm sure lots of people have
done that a concrete example of how something works
say we want to approximate pi
which is four times the area of
this red
area if this is the unit square so we can write this as an integral
which is the integral of the indicator function thing i would like this area averaged
over a uniform distribution within the square
so this is like the most stupid way of computing pi can possibly imagine a
vehicles four times integral can now approximate this integral by sampling from the distribution which
is straight points in the square and then just see whether you get one or
zero i red circle or not
and so without knowing anything really about geometry can get with twelve samples the is
about three and that sort of the feel of monte carlo you can just get
a few samples and you get the general idea of what's going on because you
ball-park figure
which can be good to sort of sanity check if you're doing something else like
EP or different approximate inference algorithm gives you completely different ballpark number you may have
done something wrong you can also be patient and wait longer so i could draw
ten million samples
and i would get the is three point one four something that is not very
accurate and is never going to be a way to get really precise numbers so
if you're interested in that we probably don't want to be doing college
i mean
if you want to compute pi by numerical integration you could just use numerical quadrature
and with only
a hundred evaluations or maybe a thousand you can get to sort of accuracy you
can represent
you really don't want to be the one carlo sort of a sort of indigo
and this is summarized by alan cycle is a funny guy and he this with
this quote with the opening to his lecture course on monte carlo methods
and he has actually done an awful lot of good work in monte carlo methods
as well and i don't completely agree with this quite well i sort of agree
with that but
i think you could replace colour with anything because if x is the method it
should only be used when all the other methods were so you can agree with
the homework that he had to do that night from eight thirty version of himself
bring it back to six thirty and it's done on time
OK so he does that he gets to eight thirty eight thirty cabins like
what i did do there's no time to do it it's bedtime and like women
who was supposed to do this the two of them the six thirty calvin eight
thirty calvin getting the time machine and they go to seven thirty and confront the
seven thirty calvin was sitting on his bed reading a comic book and so here
they are high
here we are at seven thirty six my past and future
the comic book and do our homework you get to work for a why should
i do all the work you you can do it too
but i didn't at six thirty in out seven thirty and thirty will be too
late the last chance you going start writing and we have the pound you
my future self will be the one that hurts
so of course they end not doing homework
all of them together
but really this is a story about PAC MDP near bayes optimal in the
please that's where i thought when i was laughing about it so
so PAC MDP is this idea that says the future self gets is this is
literally what it's like to get to the cartoon second the the first thing is
future self gets near optimal reward PAC MDP things as an experimental but now it
will be some mistakes now but my future self all future steps i need to
be getting near optimal reward k so you know i'm willing to do the homework
so my future self will have had the homework done right i'm going to do
learning i make mistakes now benefits will come later
all right so that's PAC MDP
which sounds kind of like the guy in the story anywhere near bayes optimal
says that the current self is the one that's going to get near optimal reward
so in particular it's not willing to make mistakes
unless they really are important now
it's not going to try something that may eventually lead to be able to get
high future reward
for future version of itself
it has to impact the expected value of the current page doesn't
don't even by just put it off because it's not me anymore somebody else
and we want around here this is the the
future selves count as part of the reward here but there are that they get
is kind of only attributable back to me
through the discount factor in for expected value so if it's even bigger if it's
far enough away
i don't care mistakes mistakes will happen later this is mistakes are allowed to happen
later so let's do that now
so with that kind of interesting and maybe feel like i always felt like i
was doing this PAC MDP stuff and it was the wrong problem but at least
the solvable problem this is unsolvable but
it's sort of the right problem now not so sure now kind of willing to
believe that this is a right problem for little bit of human literature it turns
out that human behavior is somewhere in between it's neither of these any kind of
pure sense human behaviour has been shown to be consistent with something called hyperbolic discounting
so this new bayesian is is using regular geometric discounting it says that the words
in the future words count
gamma two however far in the future they are hyperbolic discounting says it decays more
slowly than that
OK and the result of that is it's it's it's actually going to make some
mistakes now and make some mistakes later
and i know that some compromise between these two people just broke in or we
had entirely the wrong model but it's interesting to me that sort of neither of
these two when you watch
birds hiding seeds in the springtime and if it is hyperbolic discounting models
we have a learning algorithm that uses these bayesian priors to make decisions which i
don't think i have time to give in
any detail but let me just get out for you so
the basic idea is
we're maintain these priors
and to get optimism under uncertainty and to get this kind of
this PAC MDP kind of kind of property from it each time it takes this
every once in a while resamples the poster what possible models might be
it's teaches them together to form an MDP
chooses behaviours and it's the best of all the models in the samples that would
perform the with regard to kind of the union of all these models
and it's going to keep using the policy that learned until something new is learned
the posterior changes and they can resample from the posterior and and repeat this and
we were able to show is that
there are several different ways that you could achieve this sort of goal i think
but we able to show for this kind of algorithm is if the set is
big enough to the number of models that sampling in reasoning about is large enough
then we can actually get near optimality with high probability
with a polynomial number of samples
what's cool about this is it will
say C transpose X minus the dual objective then you can show that that's equal to
Z transpose S and that's actually easy to see from this condition if you multiply
this vector on the left with the this vector X Z then on the left you
get S transpose Z on the right because this is askew symmetric matrix the product
for this first term will be zero if you multiply with X Z on the
left so on the right you get C transpose X plus B transpose Z so anyway
if this is satisfied by X S and Z then you always have this equality so
this last condition is just another way of saying that the primal objective is equal
to the dual objective right so these together give you the optimality conditions feasibility and then
equality between primal and dual objectives is that clear and this should be a yeah so the second
part of this lecture will discuss barrier methods for conic optimization problems
so first some history so the history of barrier methods actually goes back to the sixties
there was a method called the sequentially unconstrained minimization technique or SUMT that was actually
developed for general convex optimization problems in this form so the idea is simply
that one solves a sequence of unconstrained optimization problems you take the objective
weighted with the parameter T and then you add this term it's called the
barrier logarithmic barrier function for the inequalities so you can show that this is a
convex function if the F Is are convex and the purpose is to of this term it's
a barrier function that traps X inside the feasible set strictly so you an you
move the inequalities and represent them indirectly using these barrier functions and then you solve
this for increasing values of T and so intuitively you can expect that if T
is sufficiently large by solving this unconstrained problem you get a solution that's feasible for
this problem because the barrier term will trap X inside the feasible set and then if
the weight on the objective is sufficiently large you get a very good approximation of the
optimum so that's the barrier methods from the sixties in the eighties there was a
sort of a revival of these methods following Karmarkar's paper on interior
point methods for linear programming because people realized that if you apply this method to
an LP and increase T in a specific way you actually get a polynomial time
method so it's a method that has a polynomial time worst-case complexity and then so
those are interior point methods for linear programming that we'll discuss a little bit in
the next slides and then in the nineties people extended these LP barrier methods
to just nonpolyhedral conic LPs second order cone problems semi-definite programming problems and so on
so we'll first look at the what these methods do for linear programming and then it'll
be easy to see how they extend to the general nonpolyhedral problem so if
you actually use exactly this idea and apply to a linear programming problem then
you use this barrier function for the non-negative orthant so you can define phi of S for a
positive S as just minus the sum of the log of S I so that's a convex function
of S it's defined on the positive orthant and then you apply that to
B minus A X and the resulting function psi is a barrier function for this
set of linear inequalities just straight componentwise linear inequalities so it's defined on the interior of
this set so if V minus A X is positive then that's useful as a barrier function
for this interior of a polyhedron right it's a smooth convex function exists
if S is positive it's convex that follows from the composition rules that we saw yesterday
and if you approach the boundary of this polyhedron then this function increases to infinity
because one of the S Is will be or one or more of the S Is will
become zero and then this phi function blow up to infinity so that's what we normally
mean by a barrier function smooth convex function that blows up at the boundary of the
sets and then later we'll actually need the gradient and the Hessian of this function psi just simply
from the composition rule the gradient of psi is A transpose times the negative gradient of
this function phi and the gradient of this is just one over S I with the negative
sign for the Hessian of this function you get something like this and all we'll actually need
to remember is that the Hessian of in the middle here is a diagonal matrix
positive diagonal matrix that's the Hessian of this function at the point S so the
Hessian of this barrier function is A transpose times oppose the diagonal matrix times A
so then we can so the idea of the barrier method is to do
unconstrained minimizations of the objective in the LP weighted with a barrier parameter T
plus this logarithmic barrier function and the set of minimizes of this are combination of
the two as a function of T is called the central path of the linear
inequalities so this unfortunately is not very clear but if I have a polyhedron and then
the dashed lines or the level curves of the barrier function so it's minimize somewhere
in the interior and then it increases to infinity if you approach the boundary of the domain
and then if I look at the path the set of minimizers of this function for
different values of T I get this curve through the interior of the feasible set
of the polyhedron and it leads to an optimal solution X star of the LP
and intuitively that's clear that so you have these two terms and the objective the barrier function
that tries to push the points away from the boundary and then you have this
C transpose X function that decreases in this direction if C points this way so if you increase
the weight on the first term you actually will approach the optimum from the interior
of the feasible set you also can get a nice interpretation from the optipality conditions
for this so this is a unconstrained problem the barrier's differentiable so you
can just set the gradient of this equal to zero to get an equivalent
parameterization or definition of the central path so the condition you get is T times C
that's the gradient of the first term minus A transpose times so this is the gradient
of the barrier function is A transpose times the gradient of phi which is just a
positive a negative vector defined as the slacks at that point so to compute the gradient
of X you compute the slacks B minus A X those are positive numbers and then you have
this optimality condition so theC points in this direction so you see
at a point where on the central path the second term A transpose
the gradient of the ba barrier is perpendicular to the level curve through that
point right so if the dashed line the dashed line is the level curve of this
barrier function then the gradient at this point is perpendicular to the it's a normal to
it's an area of machine learning it is really very crucial practical importance and it's
something that seems to require genuinely novel algorithms and novel styles of analysis
just two
motivated to little bit and just two
start specifying the model
a lot of the a lot of the work a lot of what is known
about classification is in this setting where every data point has an associated label OK
but in reality
it's frequently of very very often the case that the rule form of data is
and the label was something that you actually have to buy or you know actually
obtain it's some sort of expense OK so for instance if you're building a document
classification system you can download millions of documents off the web while you're away for
but labelling
one of these documents takes a long time OK you have some human being has
to say to look at the document and decide whether it's about sports or business
or health or whatever and it is something that takes effort
if you're building a speech recognizer you can just add a microphone down someplace and
obtain hours and hours of speech but if you wanted labelled and some human being
has got to look at the speech waveform and decide with each phoneme begins in
the next one ends and so on which is very painful
OK so these are all situations where you can easily obtain masses of unlabelled data
but labels come cost
and so what motivates the model in which some distinction is made between unlabelled data
and labels that are subsequently obtain
so here the general picture then you're in a setting where
there's some vast number of unlabeled points
in regular supervised learning what effectively happens is that
you get if you get labels for some of them and you ignore the rest
as a result the size of the dataset might not be all that large
but you ignore the rest of the points and now you try to separate these
in in fact in this case the
many ways to do that
more recently it's become
sort of
you know there's a lot of people have started looking at semi supervised and active
we're just as in the supervised case you labels for some of the points but
now we don't ignore the unlabelled data
in a semi supervised model
what happens is that you just choose to some of the points at random to
get labels for
and you take account of the locations of the unlabeled points as well so for
if you want to build the classifier just on the basis of these labels points
there are many ways to many places where you could put the boundary
in this case if you were to also take stock of where the unlabeled points
it constrains the choice is somewhat because they seem to kind of p two clusters
and you really want to put the boundary somewhere between those two clusters
so this is the sense in which in a semi supervised model you get this
additional information about the underlying distribution from the unlabeled points
in active learning you go one step further
once you have a few labels what you do is you try and find new
adaptively choose which point to query next so you look at you look at it
and you say oh you know i think about is going to be here may
be very informative point to query would be this
instead of say this one which
we're pretty sure is going to be read
OK so the hope is that by a you know choosing these these points very
intelligently you quickly converge on a good classifier is that we have to set up
so let me just give you a couple of examples of sort of recent case
studies that have involved active learning the first one is one
which was authored by
the previous speaker manfred environment
along with gunnar raetsch and
and a bunch of chemists and the setting over here is some sort of computational
drug design because the idea is that you want to find
a compound that binds to a particular target
and you have a vast library of compounds from which you can choose OK so
in this case the pharmaceutical company has got a lot of compounds can choose from
some of these virtual
you know the things that have never before been synthesized but can be synthesized on-demand
OK you have some examples
of compounds that bind to the target and you want to find more now one
way in which this would be one way in which this what what happened
is that a bunch of scientists today down
and they look at the look at which compounds seem to bind to the
the target and the come up with some hypotheses about you know what are the
chemical properties of the compound that make blind and then OK so based on the
when they do and you crawl they could just compute that score
and and they don't have to deal with millions of queries right of computing query
specific score but it's of course also weakness because what we're saying here is that
certain pages are relevant
just based on the link structure irrespective of what their content actually is right and
what the query was
in that respect right you could you could be that imagine that few keywords show
up on a page
that is really not the most authoritative page on that subject but is just overall
an important page and a lot of people link there
in that case
you know it might just not be optimal like
of course nowadays that you know they doing a lot of other things that look
at anchor text information for instance very important and you know tons of other things
but i mean that's kind of you know these are the two most important ingredient
school in retrieval and the
right well in that case you basically just always random
just random
this teleportation thing if there is no i think is a unit that and
right you always
you always just use in a sample of random page point
four one one
is which is
what is
well you know one ten billion is something you should be able to handle
or when you need
you can do a little bit more efficient when you look at this transition matrix
y ten billion times ten billion pages and only let's say on average three or
four links of the same page
of course you wouldn't do the matrix vector multiplication what you have matrix
i have a lot of constant entries basically this entry here whatever you know one
minus of over and ends up being is just almost everywhere and then at some
o point you have significantly larger values in these right so when when you do
the computation you will take that into account right to be a little bit more
but on the other but but but but then yes i mean that's i think
what you do
right here
and you can do it i mean it's not
you know what i mean
if you google you can do that that's the least of your problems two two
to apply this poem
well it's trying kind of reverse engineering and what they really do
not sure about
but it can be done very efficient
railway here
OK so let's look at the second approach
which is due to fly called the
perhaps approach or hyperlink induced
topic search something like that so here's another approach if you could take two exploiting
hyperlink structure
the motivation here as as jon kleinberg sport but it is to be better
to be able to better deal with so called broad topic queries cases in other
different types of queries specific questions similarity queries and what not more women interested in
is broad topic queries like you know i want to find information on its own
each german philosopher and there's a lot of information out there on this topic and
i'd like to know what is really the
o point and authoritative work
and what not so with broad topic queries were facing this abundance problem as he
he is
the story
you know
you can
what you
all the
can you
i don't think you
three which are
thank you
you can
and you
video machines
in nature you
and what have you are interested in the test description
you bring and these are the
what you see here
so what you
and the
what you think people in the world
they is many ways
two ago
to talk about
thank you very much
just part
that's not
brain regions
using the
and works
and here
the we
as you can
so the brain
thank you
patterns where he's creating tree structures out of these queries
like a followed by b followed by c combined with in nodes of these followed
by operators and one top node which is the tree root of whether complex event
created and dealing with this
more meaningful structure you can detect quite lot like overlap
and so on
and this is his methodology
there is a
and again cyclic workflow of creating these patterns like generating them first and then the
recommendation of
what other people
have been doing so finding similar event patterns
in the system and then execution which is the run time phase which create statistics
so i have written the pattern a followed by b followed by c but c
never happened so i can only detect this after the execution phase so we're mixing
design time and run time by creating this cycle of event processing evolution then is
the way of
saying yes
i might have modelled this in the wrong fashion let's
strike the sea
and just to take a maybe which then brings back to the start
of creating this new patterns
and there's semantic modeling i don't want to go into too much detail where we
model events an event types and we want to model complex event patterns and the
problem space so that we can get this semantic
vocabulary of talking about related patterns i think that's that's enough and this is about
the product based inference engine
so we're doing rule based
complex event processing with on the fly
reasoning so
if i get an event of a certain subtypes
i will for example immediately be be able to detect this event also in the
pattern of the super type so so we have proper inference and which is very
nice feature of of this problem based
the event processing engine which allows me to write more declarative patterns so i can
i can detect events which are in relationship to other events without explicitly modelling a
very very long pattern which lots of if then else
which is more in the sense of of knowledge management
and there's different dialect
event processing languages
most notably
the SQL sequel dialect was amended by many people
for example by the s four open source engine and which again provides you with
select from where syntax
which is a very nice starting point for creating an event processing system so if
you ever
you have to create a streaming system as a prototype for example in java
and this is often the way to do prototyping which is a nice java library
with no graphical user interface suggests import this into your program and you can
right new queries like to select a followed by b followed by c and you
will create the java classes a b and c
and you fill them in real time into this library and the library will call
the trigger
once the complex event is detected so this is a very simple SQL style processing
engine and
the rest of these are all commercial
most importantly this is an enterprise service bus company in the US
which is famously selling complex event processing to businesses