its velocity certain decreases as a result of this collision
but that's not the end of the story
that's not the end of the story
what happens here is that this electron that's excited is there in an unsustainable basis
it's just a one shot deal so the electrons wants to fall back down to
the lower energy state and it does it falls back down and when it does
so it gives off that energy in the form of a photon
so we have emitted photon
and it has energy each of new on H C over lambda 4 inch Nevada
and it is the set of these emitted photons that comes from studies on Armstrong
was studying these emitted photon and clearly there is some relationship between the wavelengths that
he observed and the energy levels within the atomic hydrogen
and all this this whole process is subject to a conservation so let's get them
with some make sure that we don't violate any basic losses were going to say
that the energy of the incident electron will then be spread across
the electron energy of transition within the target and whatever's left over will remain with
the electron some reduced
and what shown here and 1 applying it to the experiment that strong conducted in
which accelerated electrons but it's the same calculation for any particle
so this is for all incident particles be subject to the all incident particles at
all incident particle so it could be obviously electrons we can accelerate protons we can
accelerate neutrons we can accelerate alpha particles we accelerate argon ions there's a host of
incident particles the consider them only as bearers of energy the energy transfer vehicles and
the transfer energy here provided that the energy is high enough to cause excitation
there another way of looking at conceptually is this is a probe being April being
or maybe a stimulus and the integral of
the energy of the particle after interactions and the emitted photons that collectivity is the
this is the response
this is the response so what is this made this means that we could interrogate
Adam of unknown identity and on the basis of these values in infra deduce the
identity of that species and we talked at the end of last day about how
this is applied in analyzing the chemical composition of stars
so the radiation goes a long way
and were able to use the information contained therein to conduct analysis
let's see how this will help us to reconcile the boar model to bombers analysis
of angstroms data so let's see I think we have to go back to to
the boar model to go over to
things decided that wants to sleep time finally see it's Friday the computers decided it's
a goof off a little bit so we're going to use a partial No. 6
in order to help elucidate what's going on here so we can then resume here
and say that delta of the transition is the energy of the final state minus
the energy of the initial state that's always the case we always say that the
difference in those final minus initial and we can represent that of the product k
squared 1 over n final squared minus 1 over an initial square and conservation of
energy says that must be
the value of the energy imparted to the emitted photons so the emitted photon if
the photon this is emitted when the electron cascades back down and that will be
h c over land so let's look at this thing around let's look this thing
around and we will get there as new bar
1 1 over lambda then will be the case squared over the product of the
Planck constant times the speed of light 1 over n final squared minus 1 over
n initial squared now for the Balmer series for Balmer series
we have a set of lines for which the end member was always equals 2
so we're dealing with the comic hydrogen so let's put z equals 1 and let's
put the final state as any equals to
and furthermore if we evaluate k over H.
using values that we already know we get 1 . 1 times 10 to the
7th reciprocal metres so if you put all that if you get 1 . 1
times 10 to the minus
is we tend to the plus 7 1 over 2 squared minus 1 over and
i squared and i has to be greater than so that necessarily means that it
must begin at 3 could go for 5 etc. will that's exactly the ball in
we got the ball reliance
out of the formal
identical to ball
so border has been able to reconcile with angstroms data taken at half a century
earlier but furthermore boss suggests other experiments for example does not bother you that the
lines and at n equals 2 you know that according to the energetics here the
electrons have to keep cascading down equals 1 uses some funny going on in in
Sweden maybe electrons in Sweden there'll be nervous maybe it's winter maybe they're afraid to
go down and equals 1 how come we don't get any equals still
well let's look for a 2nd here
you look at the
the sleep function is kicking in
this is hard drive the rico so let's take a look at the electromagnetic spectrum
this is taken from your book and you see again I've thinking about you all
the time I got on my pants and his and of and the doctor says
this is the to very good
so here we are with the wavelength on the upper trace showing wavelength increasing from
right to left and energy increases from left to right so high energy is lower
wavelength 1 point here that irritates me that the SI unit of of frequency is
hertz which means that beats per 2nd it's it's not the perceptive and this is
a little
sloppiness on the part of the text and so here we've got is at the
very very low end of wavelength very high energy gamma rays cosmic rays and then
over here at the low end of energy or the gentle
forms of radiation radio TV microwaves over here and then in the center drawn is
visible light 1 expand and here's the visible spectrum which in round numbers I'd like
you to know a little bit of so they get educated person should know a
all networks framework and i want to know about the brain i i went to
the extent of actually getting a peachy in neuroscience because i was interested in how
the brain works i don't care how the brain works and he was much more
fun to do machine learning
so there was a community that came into the field through the route
there is a community that came into the field from databases
where they had lots and databases and they wanted to do interesting operations on those
databases there are more computer science e in their thinking so
they are more the data mining community
community there's the uncertainty in artificial intelligence community which came out from graphical models
there is
the ice email community which is machine that they i people wanted to machine learning with
rule-based machine learning originally
and the interesting thing is there
well and then there's the statisticians let's not forget them
the interesting thing is that all these ships were on a collision course
so now
there are doing much more similar things but when you go into
the data mining conference the flavour of things that you get is much more
historically based on the idea big databases large scale but simple forms a machine learning
that's that's one question i can move on i don't need to question go ahead
model comparison to the
yeah i mean
okay this is a very good question i'll come to this in in admitted
in model comparison here at least
if i wanna compared to models what i need to be able to do is
integrate out the parameters for those two models okay
but if i have a larger space of models
and then one of the tricky things about bayesian inference is that i need to be able to somehow
ah enumerated either implicitly or explicitly all the models i'm willing to consider
this is sometimes called the closed world hypothesis
you know
i have to
somehow specify generative process over models that could be very sophisticated for example
you could have a grammar
over models that would generate more and more complicated models
as long as you're the probability mass that you associate to all possible models in
you are in your clothes world are universal models sums to one
are there are at most one
so it's a very good question
yeah the question
i it seems
i have and i use the symbol key
uniformly on this page okay
which means
they all probabilities
is the probability of the data given the data
a lot of people confusingly say
the likelihood of the data because it you know they use the word likelihood closely for probability
probably if you look in any statistics textbook this is the likelihood of data which
is it's a function of data that is not a probability function okay
you know alternatively four bayesian
the likelihood of the data is just the probability of the data given data
yeah it's it's that this is
properties the probability over theta log likelihood is not a probability over theta
the likelihood is not a probability distribution
right let me move on
so that's it but it's not totally
here the questions i want to address
so first of all
you know what i he
what are the foundations of bayesianism why are some people
using this basic methodology i actually think it's weird i don't like the term bayesian it makes it sound
different somehow
like it's some choice
you know we don't say why are we all calculation lists
right because we use calculus
you know i i think that this is basically
you know this comes down to why why we using probability theory to
answer questions from probability theory well
you know
what else could we use right of-course there is the question
are there are other ways of doing data analysis and modeling and that's certainly true
right there are many other ways of doing
data analysis and machine learning
so i
a lot of people
well you know
are worried about this question prior come from try to talk about the
and then how do we do these integrals is the practical question
here is one way
that you can come at the
bayesian framework and this is if you want to think about artificial intelligence problems
imagine you have a robot ann
in order for this robot to behave intelligently
he needs to
be able to represent its beliefs about some propositions in the world
thank you know
you know
whereas the charging location nor is this
sensor malfunctioning or something like that is about get shot
the question is now not a question about statistics at all it's a question about
how does the robot represent beliefs
we want a framework that
we can use to represent the strength of these beliefs numerically in the brain of the robot
and we want to know the mathematical rules for manipulating these beliefs
so it's basically like you know the rules of logic
right but extended
captures transitivity
so let's
start with china
describe what we mean a little bit
let's say be have x represents the strength of belief or possibility and some proposition x
and we're gonna say it ranges between zero and one will be a lexical zero
means there
the robot believes x is definitely not true
but doesn't have to mean that x is definitely not true this just a statement about robots belief
being x equals one means that
role believes that x is definitely true
and we're going to be a xed given why
to represent the strength of belief that x is true given that we know
otherwise true
so now
we want to be able to manipulate these beliefs
and if
if you do
accept certain axioms
and these go all the way back to cox in nineteen forty six
and i've been sort developed over time by james and there's a really nice
more recently by the harder
so it goes on these lines if we're gonna say
strength beliefs degrees a problem plausibility are represented by real numbers
and we want some qualitative correspondence to
really common sense in terms of how we manipulate these things
OK so what we did now the
let's say that the document first we went to see scores
the site suggested a couple of things that he does not about is good if
you could enter
so there
that it considered in part based on
but it's not about corporations
you know i really really analyse the document it's using these
already using this information with the and two
and new concepts you can that it holds
applicable to the
well let's face it finishes and thing
seeing analyse
having the same sort of
OK it's done now
OK so another thing you can see the document concept
so this is a list of all the things that appear
in this article in the basic
this is the most prominent funny sitka systems
there are also other like area
a billion
router and so on
then we can be control
these parameters so we can go from
more specific
so would be
o devices that actually mention here to ones that our generosity civic landings of the
legalization taxonomy
in inanimate objects
organisation for example
it's more it's a more general
now that
the company of his car business this is
the concept for the of them
this is one thing we can control
the other thing is frequencies so of with the most frequently courses course system
official everything down here
this is
all the things that are identified
you got more general than legend
and i think it's because he here is this disambiguation
problems for example
essential here is if you go to
each equitable nice
you to make it work really hard to find
it's the boom is both part
little MG
and let's make this distance
and now
we're going to
we do all these calculations
we start completely from scratch
the sum of all forces
x direction has to be zero
no change
and of must be
f of f
now the sum of all forces in the y direction has to be or not
so now we have that and of q
must become larger
must be equal to
capital and
please little and
times g
so the maximum
the fraction
which is mute times and q
now becomes mu
times and
i'm to sort of maximum friction goes up
we need to talk and i think my point q relative to point q
well the first two terms
i haven't changed so i have enough
times l
sign of
and one l
times the cosine of
but now we have a third term
namely this
position vector
and this force
so now we're going to get this distance which is the cosine of five
so we have here
and g
times the
cosine of
that now
equals zero
so i'm going to take an of
out of here
i can take
g cosine of out
so if i take the cosine of out i have
ml divided by two left over
o mt
and then i have to divide by all sin theta
the number of
and so now i can
right for cosine of divided by sign of i can write code tangent of and
i'll bring dl
inside here
so i have g
attention of five
and over two
they and
divided by l
and that now must be
the frictional force because and p
is still
the frictional force
but me make sure
that i have these rights
i do
code engine of m over two little and the of l
that is the frictional force
notice that the frictional force
it's going up because this term is added
and we didn't have that term before
before we only had this term
and you see here
so your first thought maybe that the situation has become more dangerous
because if there is more friction
and then i will set exactly at the critical point is hanging on their farms
so if the friction
goes up
you may say
my goodness
it will probably start slide
which overlooked then is that the maximum friction has also gone
and so
we have to evaluate this now
in comparison with the maximum friction
and the best way to do it
is to think of this first
as making decl zero
so we said the person starts at the bottom of the ladder
and we asked this person to gradually climb up
i notice when d equals zero
that the frictional force is exactly the same
what it was before
there is no difference
that frictional force has not changed
and equals zero
but what has changed
is the maximum friction
the maximum friction has little and it
and that's independent of the there's nobody anywhere here
so if the maximum friction goes up
and the fiction itself remains the same clearly the never has become more stable
how scattered around are are the search results right how many how many other Web pages are inbetween
our disconnected search results and once we'll have this we'll be doing some machine learning to
do predictions on these graphs
so this is one type of question you can ask right I I take such results I create they give me
such a sub graph right these are the box the red boxes are such results
the number in them is the rank so this would be the top rank search results
second rank search results third rank search result and the question is is this
a good set of search results or not so if if given a query and all these webpages
you go to a human and ask for every webpage tell me how good it is for this
query the question is now can you predict the the the quality of this search
results or another another type of question you can ask so given that user typed
in some query and this is the the graph of the search results he gets will the user
change the query or not so will user like this set of search results or not so
these are the types of questions we can answer
the experiments I will show we have two sorts of web graphs one can consider one is a
URL graph as we call it which is a normal web graph where we have nodes as webpages
and edges as hyperlinks and we have a decent portion of the web or some portion
of the web and then you can have a domain graph where nodes are now domains and
there is an edge between the two domains in there is a webpage in one that points
to another one okay so this is sort of a  more more condensed way of
the URL graph the thing the nice thing here is that we have complained complete a web
domain graph of the web so these are all the domains of the on the
web and there is an edge between between the two if there is a web page
so here is an example of what I mean let's if we take query
subaru and we find all the results this is the graph we get the colors
here are go from red which is perfect to blue which is irrelevant and this labels were
assigned by humans okay so this big search engine companies do this on a regularly
basis so they can they can train their rankers right they they use machine learning
to do the ranking so they need is to say okay this is the most relevant page
for query subaru and so on okay so this is as what we call a projection graph
and when you connect it using some other web pages that exist on the web we call this a
connection graph okay the way how we connect these so how you would like to do
this is to introduce us few of this additional nodes as possible and this is
a Steiner tree problem which is NP hard and what we do is we resign to
some heuristic of how we connect this and it's not really important but the idea is that
you find this additional web pages so that you make the whole graph connected
and then what we will do is we want to do sort of prediction on graphs
and there are many different ways how you could do this and we choose sort of a very a very obvious way
to do this so the idea is to classify this graphs for example this would be
a graph from the positive class and this would be a graph from
negative class and what we do is we describe each graph with a set of
features so that then we can go back to the models and see how do
different graphs what are the features of different graphs
so this is the  pipeline as as I explained right we'll take a query we'll take
this projection and connection graphs and then we'll do learning and now I'll explain how how are we doing this learning step
and what exactly are we predicting
so there are we explored several problem domains but one is predicting quality so
for example you can take top twenty results for each query and top forty to sixty results
for each query and you you can try you can try to learn how to differentiate between
the two classes or you can try to predict the rating of the highest-rated document
in the set this is a different task and you can also go and try to predict user
behavior in a sense that just from his graph you're trying to say whether user
will change the query or not let me show you what I mean I can skip so
just for the data we had thirty thousand queries and for each of these thirty thousand queries
we had two hundred results labelled by relevancy by humans
so this is the task given two graphs for example for this
graph I want to predict red because this is a good set of results because
it has a highly relevant result and this is a bad set of results because
there is no red or green or yellow result here okay so this is what
I what what's the task and just even before before I show show anything more
you can see that here we have this this results of highly connected the that are
the good results are in the centre while while in the bad
set of results everything is everything would be disconnected and it is it is not
a search result that is a hub right it's a it's some other web page there
on the web
so these I we would want to predict good and here we would want to predict poor and
this is these are our results is just classification accuracy on ten fold cross validation so
if you would predict just the common class then this is your accuracy point five
if you would be using so this is three hundred fifty features that Microsoft is
using to train the ranker so if you're using those features this is your accuracy
so this is a very strong base line this is what they're using today but if you are
using these these graphs I showed you your accuracy goes up to eighty three per cent so
we get a significant boost in accuracy from if we don't consider the graph
okay so I'll skip this so all I basically all I want to say
is that just the graph itself without even looking at the content of the Web
page is enough to say or helps a lot when saying whether this is a
good set of results or not and as we'll see it's also good for
query formulation task so the question is predict whether the query is likely to be
reformulated or not so user types in a query we return him a set of results that are connected
it means that you select the height of the interaction only after you have selected
all of the smaller interactions places constraint which is often happening
people use a lot in nineteen of section
that's a start simple things first
and what i've been able to do is to use existing work from when you
to design
convex sparsity inducing norm that is actually achieve that
OK so i won't go into the details for that for the
the paper essentially we are able to bring up in their lives instead of minimizing
instead of minimizing
all the WV we when we take the bible v
we also penalize all of all of its descendants so essentially is thinking that's a
one three alone
we select the good one three and all of its descendants
we saw all the goes with some the number those goals as is the effect
of putting some of the zero
so this would have the effect of taking some these and removing all of their
it means that you will just put that
by removing points with all of all of the descendants
so what is left to you is set which is connected to the
which satisfy my constraint of being
finding no the selected
only after all of these ancestors of selected jesus simple way to implement
my constraints according to the dagger
essentially what have shown
if that we could design a polynomial time algorithm for this norm
OK so bear in mind that
the size of the size of these huge to be able to design an algorithm
for that
you can you please
launching that people can play with sparsity inducing norms namely consistent support recovery condition
we have applied to variable selection
and we have obtained good scaling between p q n and just
what obtain
it is that what's important is not the
the size of the data is the number of critical components and the maximum degree
of the DAG
so this is what we have shown here and i won't go into the details
this is something you can find
so of course this can be extended to other kernels and that we have considered
it doesn't cover because it's simpler to consider a simple to use but of course
this can be used to any type of cancer that people have been using the
so we to be a few years ago there was a lot of people that
taking the problem
thanks a discrete that's like stream
designing and as colonel
and saying that the cool thing that can that
it allows to consider a lot of features OK in an image image a huge
feature space but we have two weeks to complete the can only an efficient way
OK so here
what i'm pushing for it that do the opposite still still consider that you have
a lot of features
but not global them in begin to know that try to select them
by everyone knows which type one so essentially so we're exploring
the last spaces that people have been considering in the literature
by the the case of string instead of saying that
all possible strings are important problem this selected substrings
which are being relevant for the problem and this is
something we are trying to do right now
so in a sense the detection problem you make it explode in a lot of
features and news convex optimisation two
essentially find any in the in the haystack
so this has been extended to other types of structures and hierarchies on
and this is his usual and wanted to norms you saw these sentence types of
groups so right now people have been considering
non overlapping groups similar to the partition of groups
and what we consider here is that you can use it for that
you can use overlapping groups so if you use overlapping groups so what you have
always the same we can if you've been analysed by the sum of the norms
of groups we tried to tackle some of the groups and sends them to zero
so we take
one WG set to zero take another one thousand two zero
so at the end but you obtain in terms of zeros is a new union
of self of a certain number of groups which are said to
OK take some groups
put them to zero
is that it's more like you create sparsity by moving parts of the space
twenty which you obtain is a union of groups from you from your producing
so just to make things very clear
if you take she selected by a mausoleum
organised sequence so each other available
yes hello first of all
before nice slides linear for me to apologize they couldn't cope has some health problems
could and just the plain
nothing really but just the plain is content station
given his slides and led me is a very peculiar style
as a result
i'm a bit
i'm will not block someone like flooding as the only thing you can do
this surely slides and try to explain what i understand them
and i think have some
ideas about that
one day if get the changes civil engineers still because it's very provocative and can
be quite entertaining
so this the set of lights up with this summary
and if you the summary you realize that
and it doesn't care too much about machine
you guess about learning
and now includes learning machines which was
we have been studying for a while but also learning by humans
what are the things that humans can learn
and how why
one particular all the men of learning is scientific learning
you have some
fact experimental facts and you're trying to construct an understanding of these factors
and that theory is a theory of learning of machine learning is supposed to apply
to everything
so in this recent
is being moving from looking at learning from computers to learning in general and is
very excited because he believes that
the appearance of computers
is making a big change in the way we live in a new way science
they always
the way this crisis is that before computers
we were able to learn the simple with few parameters simpler model
and that the the and the
i availability of computers
and understanding of learning theory gives us the means to learn what he called the
complex world that is
whether you have many viable
things like
some people call we sciences because
well you know humanities all social science you have many many families doesn't people say
all we count mobility is statistically not your so there is no more than that
and the other thing that we if things that
because we have computers can handle the many variables because we have theoretical understanding of
mathematical essentials of learning we can do it
and this is about shape
so is extremely excited about this this explain why so i would support
is so reasoning start with the pattern recognition problem this is the pattern recognition problem
like the
those of you fly that is that the simple problem that contains sense of learning
and while say we go beyond that
he wants to explain that these methods go beyond the classical concept of science and
this is what the talk is about
maybe i should start
right to the content
after as we pass in this slide the first one
it is and it even found the classical problem of learning
the second part is transitive inference and show that by asking different questions
you can get situations in which you can learn more you can explore
more complicated function spaces more parameters
more capacity with less examples
and then you don't five set of problems and as the end of the talk
about two
well it's been over
proposition one is called universal
and the other one is called the mass of the master learning
and they look like simple more than the quite essential masterclass learning is
if you believe the learning theory two days
students are was was teachers
slightly worse you control how
clauses to then comes the teacher
if it was like that in real life would be in trouble
this you
can this
there was no that was
she and that was when at UCSD the PDP
research group
what used to be known as the bible
and is now more like the old testament
the they basically
put neural networks on the map and that started a revolution in
machine learning and i was over in england and i was really fascinated by neural
networks so then from my phd i went to UCSD
by the time i arrived in most of the research group had left to other
places but there were still some
people have studied my phd
then at the salk institute in san diego with terrence sejnowski
went to post in around the world a bit and ended up here about one
year ago
needless to say nobody
in machine learning
his most neural networks anymore
but actually not all that much has changed it's just the buzzwords are different
there are some new techniques around but under the hood it's still
pretty much
the same i think as as a back when i studied these things
before i launch into my talk i actually want to
give you
an introduction about the things i don't want to talk about
so i'll talk about them at length
basically what i'm concerned with is
the engine
that drives machine learning and so bernard in this talk as i told you about
empirical risk minimization right so that
the typical way you set up a machine learning problem is to find the function
that measures
how much error you're making on some training data
and you try to minimize the function
what interests me is how do you actually do that minimisation
how do you how do you run that and how can we make
that engine that drives machine learning efficient
how can we get answers fast
optimisation methods
it's what i'm concerned with
we can distinguish optimisation methods we can classify them
whether they're using gradient information and what kind of gradient information they're using
does everybody know what the gradient
it is
anybody doesn't
i mean i can go back and explain OK quick introduction we have a function
and let's say it's it's the kind of function we would want to minimize in
machine learning so it could be an empirical risk function so i'll just call it
f and also there there's some parameters theta over which we want to optimise it
and maybe it depends also on some inputs x right
now the gradient of that function if that function is smooth and differentiable we can
take the gradient the gradient is defined
the limit
for some h going to zero
of f
feet are
plus a ge
also this is the direction of the gradient
yeah that's OK
i'll start sticking here a unit vector in direction i OK so the unit vector
in direction i
is all zeros except that it has one
a single one
and this is in the i th position
OK this is the unit vector in direction i
so we have to the parameters
h times the unit vector in direction i and we measure the function at that
mystic in the inputs
we subtract from that the function the original point
and divide by age
if you take the limit as h goes to zero
this is
the gradient
of f
theta x
with respect to
the i th component
of the parameter vector
the i th component because that's the part component perturbing
so this is the definition
it looks like this
if this is your functions
we are
at a certain point data
what we're taking is now i only have one coordinate so this is my
the coordinate and perturbing
i'm going to add a little bit h to that coordinate measure the function at
that point
subtract from that the original function so i'm i'm taking this difference here
and divided by age
and and what that actually gives me is the slope of the tangent
at that point the tangent on the function
how could that be useful
for minimizing a function
well if we know the slope of the tangent we know
which way downhill
we know that if we go out in this case to the left
we're going to
reduce the function
if you just have function values it's hard to tell
so you can classify optimisation methods
in two
direct methods
and these use function values only
the next one would be in direct gradient methods
which use this this gradient information as well
and i would
and as the third category second order
and the degrees centigrade
you take this column with zero hundred
he divided into one hundred equal parts
and that is postulated to be the temperature
anywhere between zero and one hundred
if you've gone seventy nine percent of the way to the top
from here to here
the temperature is seventy nine degrees
so the degrees introduced and that's the centigrade scale
and you guys know that are different skip kind of the fahrenheit scale you can
have any of scale
in which is what you want to call the freezing point is different somebody thinks
zero somebody thirty two
and you can again called the something else
and you can divide into into two hundred parts hundred and eighty parts of the
body like philosophy is the same
you have to fight two points which are reproducible
and the way the region between them into some number of equal steps
if it hundred equal steps said the centigrade scale
probably the lowest one is called zero
so you have thermometers
now there are some problems with this
one problem is that
the boiling point of water
does not seem to be very reliable
because if you boil water on
in aspen for example
you know it doesn't seem to boil it seems more and more readily
in the planes
you can ask how do you know that maybe they're still doing the same thing
i know that because i try to cook something
cook some rice
vegetables i find they don't cook at all
denver points before it cooks
that way we know it's probably boiling earlier in the mountains then in the plane
so who is going to decide what they
the temperature is
so you have be more careful when you say boiling point and freezing point
because things don't boil
they don't seem to boil at a certain
predictable and fixed temperature
this is very
the arguments i've never appreciated fully when i learning the subject is also click definition
because you may not know
the temperature is changing because this is the moment by postulate it's going to be
the temperature by definition how can it be wrong
what's wrong is that it's not you know it's not a reliable method because
physical phenomena like when you're a swim called
not only produced by the boiling point of water
he cooks
in the planes doesn't cook in the modern so we know the boiling point is
to blame
prices the rights
that's so we know that that's not a good measure so now people are much
fancier measures
and i'll tell you a little bit about that
for a long time this was a very good start
don't worry about the fact that water boils
differently in different altitude you could go to sea level
and that's a good enough definitions sea level is pretty much constant of the world
and you can see the pressure at sea level is the presidency level
yes the road to the atmosphere
OK so that's the usual
definition of temperature
now the trouble started when people realize
that if you make a thermometer with your favourite fluid maybe mercury
and they make one with alcohol
they will agree it's zero and they will agree eight hundred because that's how you
fixed your read of zero everyone says zero and everyone says
but how about seventy four degrees seventy five degrees
i said seventy five if my fluid claim before the way to the top
at that point yours may not have claimed before the the way
the what you've got two things
two graphs
with zero one hundred degree
one graph may be like this one like that so that when i think it
is seventy five you might think of seventy two
one hundred people agree because we have cooked up that way
in other words it's not true
all liquids expand at the same rate
so you will have to then pick one liquid and safe
we used to wait wait that liquid
and when delegates going halfway
we would sit fifty degrees
so have typically liquid you have to have an international convention in the alcohol lobby
and i don't know alcohol lobby they argue
finally the founder of much better solutions than his liquids
they found out that diffuser gas
you can define temperature using gases
which have some very very nice property
and this is the
gas thermometer
i'm going to tell you know
yes said you build the gas thermometer
you take some gas in a container
container for me and all
whenever to draw anything thermodynamics is going to be gas inside some cylinder
with some weights on
and that defines the pressure of the gas
of course the pressure will be the
mg of these weights
divided by area of the cylinder
if the pressure
plus atmospheric pressure
the volume is this
whatever the volumes based on height
we ask you to do
take the product of pressure times volume for any sample of gas back some gas
put in this tank
and now i put it on different surfaces
like hot plate like this though
robert water
and measure the temperature using some standard method
up to that point like a mercury thermometer
what you know this
is that
the temperature measured by some
reasonable scheme
shows that the product p times
lies on the straight line
you connect the dots
we find the product pv is linear
in this temperature vt
and this is zero degrees
and this is hundred degrees
now here is the beauty of the gas thermometer
if you take a different gas
and it put different among different gas in different cylinder
you get some of the graph
may look like this
well u that's the one that's hundred
the most important thing is that's also a straight line
there's also a straight line it the following implication you guys can prove
but you only easier
which is that
if i think that my guess claims
fifty six percent of the way
the site the top
the temperature is fifty six degrees
i ask what is your guess
the find is also playing this expression with property straight lines
you can show that if it was straight lines
what whatever be the slope
if they agree
this is zero this hundred got different slope
when you're playing
the halfway point
proline fifty degrees and as what any gas and they were all have claimed the
halfway point
from the zero point eight hundred points
there was gas thermometers
not only agree with the end points where they must
by construction
we seem to agree all the way in between
but that's one equation
and so we can write that down the distribution of x is called the distribution
and it just takes this form when x is what when is one mu when
x zero it's one minus
we can do things like the expectation the variance of the distribution very easy to
compute in general the expectation of course is of some function f is just the
weighted average that function weighted by the probability of observing the value of x or
the interval in the in the density case continuous case
the variance is just the expectation of how much it varies around its mean square
value so this is f minus the
expectation all squared and then we just take the expectation is that if you expand
that the square
then you can see it's the expectation of f squared one this expression of f
so for the boolean case there's the distribution expectation is just new
and the
variances mu times one minus mu so this is a function which is zero if
museo one to five the coin which always gives the heads always gives tails than
that the distribution is zero variance
and the is maximum when musa half
and that's reasonable so the biggest variations of coin which is equally likely to land
heads or tails
misconstrue through this fairly quickly because i think this is pretty basic stuff but but
stop me if i find not clear
OK so that's the distribution that right the likelihood function so got data set of
independent coin flips and of them of which landed heads and minus and the details
so independently the likelihood function which is the probability of the data given viewed as
a function of mu
is just the product of the probabilities for each of these independent events is given
by this
because the because x zero or one and this is just a new
raise the power of the number of times i see headstones one minus mu raise
the power of the number of times i see tails
that's the likelihood functions mutism some power one minus mu to some other
now we need a prior distribution over mu
and it's going to be really convenient i can get a whole lot simpler if
we choose
a family of prior distributions which has the same functional form is the likelihood function
OK this is a simplification
and so this was mu disempower one minus mu to some power
so let's choose a
prior distribution which is mu raised to some power a minus one one minus mu
raised to some power be minus one so the the minus one to just convention
it's called conjugate prior to a conjugate prior is the prior to his functional dependence
on the parameter is the same as the functional dependence of the likelihood function
respect to the parameter
this this is the this is a proportionality here we have two
the coefficient in front to make sure this integrates to one that coefficient turns out
to be this ratio gamma functions and this thing called the beta distribution is the
conjugate prior for the newly distribution
and again we can be its expectation which is just a very plus b and
that's the expression for its variants
there some plots of the beta distribution for various parameters that you have one just
constant and these are different values of a and b
so this is the distribution over parameter which lies between zero and one CMU is
the parameter that we can interpret the probability the province coins heads
we don't know the value mu were uncertain to describe by probability distribution to probability
distribution over the
values of the unknown probability new
so now we've got the likelihood function the private right down the posterior distribution we
take the likelihood function is a function of new multiplied by the prior and then
we need to normalize
this is a really simple because we chose this conjugate form for the prior so
this is the likelihood function
new to the m one minus mu t n minus and beta prior is new
to the wiki practice alpha norton beta nought
so it just takes this form so gets muta somehow one minus mu to some
other powers again it's just a beta distribution so the whole point is we start
with beta prior we multiply the likelihood function is a conjugate prior we end up
with another beta distribution and again in the sequential
bayesian view of learning we observe some more data you multiply by the new likelihood
function and again we end up with another beta prior to the nice thing is
that as a keep observing data we keep absorbing the evidence from that data the
functional form of the distribution doesn't change is always the beta distribution it's the premises
of the distribution which change
because this has the functional form of the beta distribution we can trivially normalise because
we already know how to normalise the distribution so is a beta distribution with parameters
a and b n and
these are the
this is what we get just by inspection
this equation so
a parameter for the posterior distribution after observing n coin flips is a plus an
and for the
for b and b not plus the number of tails so we can interpret the
parameters a norton b or a sort of number of pseudo coin flips the coin
flips that was sort of inverted commas seen in the prior
so it's as if we've already seen a nought heads be not tails that we
observe some new data and additional heads and minus an additional ten
that the general results you'll see
was in moment
so the plot of what's going on here is his prior distribution
beta distribution we multiply by all the newly likelihood functions in this case we have
observed ahead so this function that this one data point is just new is the
function just a straight line from zero to one we multiply this by this
we get and then we normalize
we get this shape
so having observed a coin flip of heads it shifted the distribution to the right
from each other constraints
so put a minus x are only to these constraints
at the moment for the phase one problem change the objective function forget about this because
i for phase one i don't care what the objective is i only wanna get something that satisfies these constraints
and once i get our reinstate object function and start what call phase two
which is the algorithm i just showed you the primal simplex methods
we put the x not on
and so here it is
x not in here
okay so
this is feasible
why is it feasible
i can let x not be a large number
end x one x two x equals zero end
i will satisfy these inequalities
it's a feasible problem
but this is not a dictionary solution that's just
this assertion that there's
that there are solutions to this problem
so i would like to solve this problem using the simplex methods and if i
get to the point where the objective function is equal to zero
the name means that the original problem was feasible because that's not how i changed the original problem
and so if i can make the change the original probably called zero
that i've got a feasible solution there's no problem
the final
dictionary or the final basis if you like the basic variables versus the nonbasic variables
the final bases that you get from this phase one problem can then be used as the initial
starting point for phase two
you just throw away the x zero put the correct object function back in and continue
if the objective function to this phase one problem is strictly less than zero
that means we tried to maximize minus x zero
and we in the end didn't get
two x equals are exactly equal to zero we get the eggs are we call
the something positive so minus x are always negative and
that means that there is no solution to the original
problem that means the original problem is invisible
and so on
so here is how this goes
we can show that the problem with x zero and here
and if and applicant i developed for this
two phase map that shows both e
the original objective function
there are many
phase one objective function right below it
and we do pivots
for phase one
even though it shows the original objective function we ignored
and we just look at the phase one objective function with the x minus x
zero we do are with this one
and with the right hand side here but the first one is different
because this is not feasible even for the phase one problem is not feasible because
we've got these negative signs here
so the first that in this algorithm is special
the first is eggs are all winter
the most negative one will leave
that's just one that you do there
and we do that's
it automatically gets all these things to be critical zero
and now we have a dictionary solution
further from the phase one problem and so now we go
and we put in
we u is the second wrote to the phase one problem
and so we pick the forums are entering variables that's x one enters
we go down here and look at all these things
from eight going down route four from six going down right to for to an
area seven turned w five is the one it's zero first so w five must
be the leaving variable
so we do the pivot
and there it is end then we have x
still has a positive coefficients are
objective here
and by the way are
think object functions value at the
at the dictionary solution is minus two are trying to push this up to zero
so the three
and next to is positive so it enters we look through here to another three
three going around two and a half so now
x zero is they one that had zero first one i do all those little
so i have x two enters end
x zero leaves
i'm done with phase one
so again let's first in the propositional case and not worry about lifting and then
so the propositional case here's is an example that will hopefully you it'll give intuitions
for what's going to happen this is the same running example that we have coming
from the representation part let's suppose that i now tell you that i AM and
our friends
OK i just give you that additional facts
what that fact does is make these two worlds impossible right now the world's from
these mountains with bob are is not friends with bob
nine possible
so that leaves only these two worlds
the potentials in these two tools are still the same that before it's one for
point seventy five per day
and if you ask the question
what is the problem the body is happy given that a number of our friends
well that's just this anomalous probability over the some of these anomalous probabilities so it's
one over one plus point seventy five it's point fifty seven
so to summarize
what we do here
it was to say
if you tell me that the problem the not friends and above were happy about
this point eight
make the maximum entropy assumptions then it follows that the probability that happy given that
enable references point to fifty seven
we're assuming we conditional on and being friends with bob but we don't know with
certainty that that makes bobhappy because there was no probabilistic
as a result of which the conclusion also now has the probability and we know
how to compute
now that's the propositional case but of course the interesting case is going to be
the first order
what happens in the first case well suppose that instead of just giving you that
alpha blob i give you all for everyone
so i say forever you know like i just so you know
p of not friends in x or have the access point eight
right i
and the meaning of this is that for every x every person in the world
the probability that this statement is true this point eight
you can think of it as creating a whole bunch of copies
of this thing
one from all but now also one for charles one for a and one for
everybody else so not just have a whole bunch of copies of you know these
these guys being highly probable in this guy this world here being less probable
but of course the interesting part comes when i have different evidence about some objects
than i do but others
so let's suppose and this is indeed the typical case when you do logical inference
or probabilistic for that matter that i have this general rule
that applies to everybody
but then i i'm just all the n is friends with bob but i still
don't know anything about anybody else what does that mean
what that means is that this big stack of things breaks up into two
the first one is the case that we saw for bob with these rules are
impossible and only these two are left
and then for everybody but bob i still have the case where we don't have
this knowledge
notice that in logic the only substitutions that we need to consider as institutions of
the form x equals blogger x equals y
but here
we also need to consider the case where x is not equal to one
it's actually very important thing in lifted probabilistic inference that the people first noticed in
two thousand three is that we need to consider the entire substitution as well as
the substitution
so this is unlikely small no graphical example let's let's get to the actual machinery
was about diagram that i think summarizes the current state of inference
in you know probabilistic logic languages or another way to say this is like what
we can do with probabilistic theorem proving
and you know if you remember only two or three things from from this tutorial
you know this one is certainly should should certainly be one of those two or
so this is diagram with three axes
the this axis running from left to right on the left it has decision problems
and on the right it has counting problems
the axes running into the back goes from latest to weighted problems
and the axis running from the bottom to the top goes from
and lifting propositional to lift or first of problems
so here in the front left lower corner which is half satisfiability
it's the decision problem it's a weighted and it's proposition
propositional theorem proving is reducible to
was one of the legislation
there is no one was all just this
what was it
but you know so essential to this
very very fast
the general theory
OK so
there are extensions to this
o operations
well said so
we just the
usually refers remember we say they are the ones that
thing was to that so many designers of
to that end in
that says the school
the first place
this is this is sufficient conditions
it's not a relationship between
this is
so what's that
this is because
this is the list
four hours is like
the last one
is it
and of course there will also that
so what
these the results of your next turn
it is sometimes essential
to deal with with these issues to build themselves
a typical optimization all the
two months
i swear that this the the
it is true
we don't have an organisation is not enough to really run the sort of
it is
one then
what i want to
it is that it is not a story
o how the last
all right
so in the next lecture
some results from
this is like you see
already know talks specific examples is one of
optimized solution your
yes so
one of the
we want
all of these
going from
here wrist during using
that's why someone see what is not is not the right thing
so you have
this is the basic
and what
but what was the bacteria
that's so that we will
how many lines in you know these are all functions
leads to different type of decomposition approximation is to make
so that's one of the oscillation
the approximation probably class and it is a major problem
this the sort of new complementarity linear zation
equations middle this middle one
and uses eliminate
w i believe lie more eliminate
so i limited w
and only a delta x delta why left
and now the whole
system equation looks like that's which is similar to what i had before r
i had eight i a transpose
i had w why inverse you can almost still read
and up here
i had something positive definite
o minus sign missing or a minus sign here
it's probably because the minimum maximum or something yes there has to be one and
this has been applied positive and there has to be
i i actually introduced the term quasi definite system fore
the system of
equations that can be written
in block form like this with the matrix is the transpose of the matrix
end and and and the positive
semi definite here and negative definite there are or vice versa
and it turns out that that's better than they did these being both positive semi
definite that's actually harder system itself
so we solve this reduced cake katie system
and we short steplength as necessary and we update to a new point and we just iterate and d
everything is the same basically
because you not with the view
interior point methods for convex problems
find the globally optimal solution
i'm gonna tell you in a few slides about
some changes to make to the algorithm which will encourage a defined at least a
locally optimal solution when the problem is not convex
but what is not convex now it's the
it's difficult
i think we
algorithms that exist are fairly reliable it five
at finding a feasible solution if one exists in course that's also hard
and then find the fact that that's probably the hardest part and once you find
it funny we optimal solution but what is local mean there's no
proof that you know this is
this is you know the closest solution the closest locally optimal solution the point started at
so it's all love
just tried is just trying to find
eighty solution
which might be close to started
i don't remember if i have a slide here that elaborates on this
quasi definite property that so many finished this that what i have here in the first time out
a mention why
having what it is positive definite no negative definite is is
is better than having both in the positive
o so the next slide here are convex versus non convex
so we
the including extend are
class standard problems to include some with equalities and some with inequalities
a problem is convex
if we're really qualities it has to be a find function
linear function with and not and some right-hand side that doesn't have to be zero
but this linear constraints
if if it's equality they learn here
if it's if you inequalities that
the thee and we write is greater equal to those the functions age supplies have to be a concave functions
and if a minimizing the function f has to be convex so it's a convex
nonlinear programming problem if you have these conditions
alcholics smooth if all the functions that we see are twice continuously differentiable
so if forum at situation that's a con the convex situation that's
almost as good as linear programming but it's not quite as
simple there are there's atleast one another subtlety that i've dimension
actually quadratic is still okay you actually go nonquadratic but still convex before the subtlety appears
it doesn't suffice to choose the step length simply keep u
from going negative
here's a trivial example
to illustrate this simple point
consider minimizing this function
i don't have any constraints
no constraints
the function of the variable x is a free variable i can go positive and negative
he iterates of the interior point method which in this case is just exactly newton's methods
do exactly
what's shown here
and i can maybe
speak a little picture here
what's happening
this function here
the square root of one plus x squared would look like
it's one
and when x equals zero
end as x goes to infinity
one becomes irrelevant looks its asymptotic toward
and is asymptotic to minus x as you go minus infinity
it's a very fun function i like it very much
anyway if you write down what they interior point methods do for this that would
do exactly what news about the dust because
there's finally another weird not we're the any other complications
of nonlinear programming
end newton's method
approximates this function with the best
quadratic function to approximate so barnstar way out here this is almost a linear function
the best quadratic approximation is almost linear function
looks like this
and i find the minimum the minimum of that which is way over here
which now i take that's my next point is and i take the best quadratic approximation to this
after this to the original function
here was even closer to a linear function
now i do the quadratic approximation
and as many we are here
and it gets worse and worse
well i'm far away from the optimal solution which is x equals zero
and in fact if you look at the iterates six tell you exactly that's what happens
you the next iteration is the negative
other cuba the current iterate
if i started
the next one will be minus eight
and i can even qminer say in my head
the national be eight cubed
so it grows fast but it lacks starts out less than one
the net converges to zero extraordinarily fast
given q
we use bayes formula again
pq is constant for community
we always
ran for particular so we can make them at this time
he is
often used as a prior
or it can be the same for all documents
one possibility for using it as a prior would page so we can say
you can enter it here is the pagerank of the document that
pagerank will be integrated into the bank
the probability of q given t and this is this generation probability that i talked
about before
with probability the language model corresponding to document the generation
the query q
assumptions we made ranking documents according to PQD PNT p q is equivalent so
of course what we really have is experience want to know what's
the document
what we actually using the base baseform rule
what we actually rank is
either this quantity of this quantity
OK how can you compute pqkt indeed
you make the same conditional independence assumption as in there
although it looks a little different but it's basically the same so
here we have created given the
language models sometimes i'm going to use the
to make clear that it
this is the language model correspond to the document and other documents l so the
representation of the document is the language model
q can write is t one the
thank you so
there are q
words in the theory and that just newman here
and the
independence assumption here is that the probability of getting the query a whole given the
is the same as the product of the individual terms given the model
that's the same
essentially the same
binary independence assumption of binary independence assumption we made
now this is equivalent to this
but this is course through the tokens in the query one by one
this goes to the distinct terms that occur in the query and it's clear several
times just
those factors are put together
and raised the power of tf t q which have to is the number of
occurrences of the term in the query
and this is
a multinomial model
we are maintain a constant factor here the constant factor there
it tells you how many different combinations of these
constellation of three terms can order
but essentially it's the multinomial model so language models
the language
the approach in IR is based on martin on march
the missing pieces parameters p
given and come from
how do we estimate the probability that a given time t is generated by the
document model
we start with maximum likelihood estimates
the maximum likelihood estimate is simply the relative frequency of the term
so we can't often does the term occurs
and divided by the length of the document
relative frequency
now again we have a problem with zeros the same problem we also had with
and model
because a single t in the query both peter given an equal zero
well makes
this zero
so if we
if if you have a theory
and one of the few times doesn't occur in the document
the document will get a retrieval status value of zero
so in effect giving single terms in the community to call
which is
basically a conjunction conjunctive flavor of the
of the language model
but we don't want that usually
for example for the query michael jackson top it
a document about michael jackson top songs but not using the what hits
i would have
zero retrieval status value in that span
so we need to do something against eras
what we do is moving
the key intuition is in this movie that a non occurring terms possible even though
it in the car
but no more likely than would be expected by chance in the collection
basically using the collection distribution as a background distribution for smoothing
this is the collection models
CF is the number of occurrences of t in the collection
and t is the
total length of the collection the total number of tokens in the collection
then we can estimate the background distribution the distribution of terms in the collection as
a whole
again the relative frequency
it's simply
the total number of occurrences of the term in the collection
divided by
all the tokens in the collection
and we will not use the CFP this
relative frequency the collection to smooth the relative frequency in the document
and we certainly do that by
doing an interpolation of the two
so this is a linear combination of
some magic numbers so magic nuclei
where you have put on neutron which are magic for example you could ninety
you have also dublin magic nuclei which are really interested
so potassium forty
led to eight and thirteen one hundred the most famous one
so how do you treat from the microscopic because could become a point of view
how do you treat the nucleons so it means that you treat the nucleons in
nuclei want in interaction
so here it's the strong interaction
so you have been two problems the first one of the many body problem
when you're dealing with more than a few constituents then you don't know how to
solve exactly is the problem
so it's quite general problem so
we know how to solve that for and lower than four but for
bigger system bigger than ten we don't know that
it's because
imagine if i i i i want to talk to you i can talk to
each of you
i can to a group of two three four
and then you can talk to each of your colleagues or two three four so
there are so many combinations
but it's impossible to treat that exactly
and for in you only we see that the are pheromone so you have to
adjust symmetrized that
so we don't know now how to solve that
so that's why there are some approximation so the most commonly used approximation are associated
coming from atomic physics
and the approach is based on the mean field
the philosophy is completely different between them from the show with what you consider you
that you have particles
so constituent that do not participate
only consider a few
that are pertinent to the others
completely frozen
on the contrary for the mean field you don't have frozen body you don't have
enough to core
but you neglect to learn the correlation interaction between the nucleons
so this is
that depends what you want to do so
this is very well adapted for small system when you can
i really do that this
good as you are very aging this is better for
large system
and you have another problem here which is the nucleon nucleon force that is known
as i told you yesterday
so these two problems seems to be adequate non correlated
but be careful since you are doing here some approximation
before you use will be anything before so far is valid for the approximation that
he was
so in fact these two problems are
are trying to so you should be careful when you use the force that is
effective and valued for the approach that you've chosen
so this is the difference was that to make physical where you know
between electrons that you have this coulomb repulsion it's difficult to treat but you know
the forest
this is specific to nuclear physics
in more detail what about the nucleons so
you know that there are quantum objects so they cannot have all the energies but
they can
b on a non discrete number of states
so they are fermions so that means they cannot occupy the same state suppose printed
the shown with the first show what it was the plot in nineteen forty eight
for the
for nuclear physics in it was my uncle from a year
and she said that in analogy was atomic structure
one may postulate that in the nucleus
the nucleons move fairly independently
in individual orbits in an average potential
so what people have done is that they have deduced from experimental results potential which
is this one
so this is what we call wood saxon potential
so negative here
you have parameters the zero big air
so this is broken here this is the of air
you have this in red wood saxon potential
it's quite difficult to to have the results to obtain the and analytical results of
this wood saxon potential so what people do that
this amplify the problem with a square well here in blue
our army negotiator in rate and the regions the
the depth and range
the reason that delivers do not depend so much on the precise shape of the
potential but you chose
when you have the potential you can calculate the the labels
you have different quantum numbers that characterised the nucleon states
so the quantum numbers are the principal quantum number big n
the right quantum number small and that characterize special extension
you have the orbital moment the azimuthal quantum number l
spain intrinsic spin glass minus one
to know how to feel these labels you have some selection rules so that you
know how to feed the different what is the degeneracy of the labels here
and what we introduce in the total angular momentum which is the sum of the
orbital moment mississippi
so this is an example of a stairwell so
these are the states you have big and zero one too small n one two
l here
this correspond to equal zero p
p two equal one exit around
so you have the differently abled
what has been added in nuclear physics is the spin orbit n l s who
playing in order to construct j
that change and to be the delivered so these are really the labels that are
used for nuclear physics
so you see that you have a situation where to feed the different levels and
you see that sometimes you have gaps here for these numbers eight twenty twenty eight
be careful twenty eight this gap is created by the spin orbit there is not
the case for the other one that is created
by saskia will
what does it mean this gap it means that if you want for example
to have a system where is it produced two body you have to take a
lot of energy to put a lot of energy in the system
two had these clues
or if you want to promote one
but get to here you really have to to promote to give a lot of
energy so that's why they really stable it's because of these gaps
in single particle labels
more precisely how do you describe the ground state of a nucleus with these approaches
so it's easy you just feel
today we continue this for for
the first course ways introducing by six
tools nationally and then the second course trucks introduced empirical risk minimization
or what are the third goal condition that we have
the calgary twenty is that when we do machine learning we are not doing completely
crazy things
the slide you have i show yesterday when i was the two
the two
so i show you
why we need to know algebra
probability trees so
as i show you in the in the examples of machine problems i show that
we have a limited amount of examples so that a source the answer to the
there is also noise in the measurements probably which is another source of uncertainty and
there is a row randomness also of course is inherent to the observed phenomena
i'm going to to give a quick
fast introduction to the basics that we need in gravity effects at the end of
the week walking network and then i will give you
more advanced course
OK about by using the probability that a lot of things
so the first
i'm going to give you some vocabulary that i found that it's
interesting to have
because the
we always talking about these things without knowing what what i mean
so what do we mean by inference
inference is drawing conclusions from experiments involving
uncertainty is exactly what we do in fact machine learning
it's really of it's really close to what is called inference and statistics
what is the sample set is the set of all possible outcomes of an experiment
we're going to always
will be
always playing with random variables which useful for our mothers and what's the random variable
is a variable was value is determined by the
outcome of a random experiments so we will encounter two different kind of random variables
shared the discrete random variables and the continuous random variables
discrete random variables
really from experiments where you can count
but what are the outcomes why wait continuous random variables
yes description it's for example like that i still see
callings or tossing dice way continuous random variables
arise from from measurements you have provided no
you measuring
the weight of
that is an immersion of that feels bags was coffee automatically what will be the
the weight of the
coffee bags
that would be also a random variable
because there's some
random process and there
and that would be a continuous random variable
another thing that
you will probably encounter or you have already in countries that
different views of probabilities
which is the frequentist point of view and the other by using point of view
usually there really in terms miguel one with the other so
it's not completely far apart but
it's two different point of view and the probabilities
the frequentist et cetera you see the probabilities as frequency
of random repeatable events
well by using interpretation of probabilities is that the probability is a measure of uncertainty
and you don't need to have ripped
the principle of event behind
OK so first going to talk about discrete random variables
and for that let's take a concrete example
let's say a
we have two boxes one red and one blue
apples and
these orange apple
and the experiment is really as selector out of the box
because food look what's what is it and then replace the food in the books
i can utilize the experiment was to
random variables
the first one is the identity is the book of the books it is easy
to read books or is it the blue books
they have have selected
then the second of a random variable
which is the identity of the fruit
that i have selected using the box which is why is it an orange or
an apple
OK so in the frequentist point of view which is mostly what i'm going to
present here
the probability of the box
of taking of selecting the red box
it is seen as the
if a repeat six this experiment number of times
a lot to learn lot of time
the probability of selecting a red the red box is is equal to the number
of times the red boxes selected over the number of trials and that when the
number of trials goes to infinity
so that that's how
all the
lines the vectors to report
so this is like religion nationally and it's because of the
that might not even know I think I would take is this is
but that the 1 with the majority of the world
and that
you can also multiply you can also cut the matrix in the
and location might want to get so
useful as I
collecting money
and not going
like many of present
on the cabinet which imports were not supposed to to work with this
state and analysis and the whereas
I think
but the size of the what they have to do with matter
you certainly won't so here's the rule of law
this is loss of life of of any of maybe
1 and 2 and 3 and 4
a here and the loss of being 1 of the things we really
then the end I can find a lot find that what it tells what that
what going be quiet was about multiple
what's going on that
might be this kind of like the matrices might invite 25
with a lot the
the take the case of a lot of things
and what is the moment of what and what to here's what's what's the what
the what the answer
it is 1 of the ones that matrix and this is the right side of
the environment and
what's the what 1 of them
aid to be theory is just like a lot of times what
I don't know nobody not even down to the end of the war
but somehow of we tend to all clients
were doing the same thing most likely
so this is familiar with page is what we're really doing going to we do
about column by column by column and row and
OK I just like to get the rules and for many more
the Committee for the
for this year's end of the frame
and you have a square
OK so I'm going remain
and it may or may not have the been right not only to the head
and the fact that the most important question you can ask about matrix is affects
you know what
is invertible or not it is invertible and then there is someone matrix
the holidays
and 1
what if any of so this is it the beginning it wants make
can be really central of figure out whether an image of the power
but what's
what you I have the effect
this matrix as a and this is what the idea
and little more a normal
I mean that right now that's like 1 is sitting on the left but really
and inverted in 1st would be on the right as well so that
this is true
that is inherent in practice is not a problem
this is something that is not the true what works
that alleged that the square matrices a left inverse is also a
if I can find the image from the land that is the identity also that
for rectangular matrices will see 11 universe that is the right from fact the state
will know what square matrices states of our and hand
if focus so
give something
the at the beginning of the year but let's talk about the case with
so this is it
the matrices called internal
or not you
and 1 of the issues identify how would you that and I'm talking about the
welcome everybody
please ask when i when i talk to ask questions stop me and it's something
i when i cluster wikipedia something we stop so my name is you really skill
that's currently i'm my post-doc at cornell and i'll be joining stanford CS in full
as assistant professor and basically what talk about is how to model
and large social and information networks so
basically what the goal of the tutorial
the goal is to basically introduced statistical properties these networks have how to think about
this problem is and how to model them on how to then exploit these properties
so do certain types of tasks better because we know what is the structure of
this of these networks and parts of
so the parts of work
can be done with a bunch of other collaborators or people i borrowed slides from
and so on so
this is this is the so what i'm they talking about these networks graphs but
graphs as they meaning that the data that will be working with natural forms in
enough or not naturally comes in the form of a graph so what we have
is some nodes in some relations for some edges
between them and the there are many kinds of such data that naturally occurs in
various domains so internet meaning around talking to one another that can be looked at
the graph safe state scientific citation networks right so i have papers but the nodes
and i have citations references between them that also again defines very rich and interesting
network with every node is like a document and all the all the words in
the time of publication the authors and everything they have citations between them what about
web meaning of web pages and hyperlinks again is a big graphs who dates to
whom can be thought of as graph who has sexual intercourse with whom again can
be thought of the graph and so on the right so these are all different
types of data that actually comes in the form of a graph as computer scientists
we are especially interested about in in network data because of one one thing and
that thing is that we have a large on line computing applications where they naturally
can be can be represented in the form of a network what i mean by
that is that we have online communities online social networking websites that have like hundreds
of millions of users like facebook myspace linkedin and so on we have a very
rich communication networks is the messenger instant messaging because of that forum has billions of
users email again is is very rich communication network to be a very interesting temporal
dynamics also another very rich source of data is news and social media data meaning
blogging and basically user-generated web two point o type of contract people are now generating
content creating links and so on and again this content is highly there then emigrated
each naturally defines me network
there are also many other domains were networks come come come into play especially in
systems biology health many where again i can represent interactions between genes in the form
of a network and so so why would you want to look at the data
in the form of a network and the reason for that is because you can
think of a network as some kind of you have entities that typically weakly interacting
or some somehow related to one another so you have sort of moving away from
i i d cases you like and there have been a lot of success stories
showing that using information helps a lot for a lot of the value a prime
example for that is probably web search right sort of google realizing that you can
rank web pages based on the link structure right or you know
topic detection classification where you know links between between your entities so your data points
so this is why you want to work in networks
so just to show two slides on
what kinds of networks data there are
so i talked a bit about information networks so what the web of hyperlinks citation
networks i mentioned or if you have a blog networks in a sense who who
gets who copies information from home
then at the very source of such data is a social networking they expect especially
now with the emergence of social networking website and applications you have you this can
scale to hundreds of millions of nodes so before sort of before the emergence of
the web two two point o if you like
these networks are usually were heavily studied but they were usually small because somebody had
to go on the field ask people place name your best friend or you know
they would have to conduct interviews give out questionnaires and so on so you think
that collecting that would be sort of it sort of was a very hard task
now we develop and everything the network they just comes to us for so
organisation networks in the sense of relations in companies communication networks who talks whom who
talks to whom call funds to whom we most whom which experts who with whom
collaboration networks this can be for example is saying if you collaboration networks in terms
of who writes where in the next two authors if the right people together i
mentioned this once and they have topic here
the other routes source technological networks what i mean by that is so for example
power or water distribution networks meaning physical pipes or cables connecting different locations that defines
network neural networks and even networks and line networks extensive looked at where again for
example in networks my airports are vertices of the graph edges between them are basically
not like flight
so that's about five from one airport to to another i create and of course
the search actually for example weighted i count how many planes fly how many passengers
fly how often they fly things like that telephone networks have been looked at internet
autonomous systems and here is sort of pictures of this
and then the other set of examples come come from like systems biology so biological
networks from like metabolic networks food webs so who eats whom neural networks gene regulatory
networks language so words documents can be also looked in the form of a network
either in terms of sort of semantic network where you are connecting concepts that interact
or appear together or you can just sort of create network based on the sequence
of words and see you can see a lot of very interesting things about the
structure of the
of the document and software has been looking for of for network either call graphs
or you know which which had file includes which had five and so on so
this is sort of the network types of network data and to motivate why would
you want to study natural they here sort of a quote from jim gray right
and he said the emergence of cyberspace where and what the web is like the
discovery of a new continent right so he was trying to say that this networks
you know phenomena they are not some kind of engineering designed fact that somehow naturally
occurring so there are some kind of some kind of phenomena or genuine data that
is what to study so one question that that gets motivated here is what kind
of pattern sort of kind of properties what kind of common denominator all these different
sources sort different kinds of networks having what aspects of a similar what aspects of
the different so that sort of one common question people have been asking
another question then is you know we want to get this loss of
the motion of the web right so as a senior statistical irregularities were better and
i would like to understand why they are there
so what i want is i want some kind of statistical methods that will allow
me to first quantify
so i'm would look like
well you're going to see something
like this let's take a moment
equals zero
so cosine omega t
plus one
so we're going to have occurred like this
he goes up to
the y zero
like this
and this year
is that my two y zero
these points
i will never move
always stand still there's nothing like a traveling wave traveling wave these points will see
to wave goodbye to go up and down they nevertheless they sit still
they have a name we call the nodes
let's now look a little later
let's look at p
equals one quarter
over periods
the cosine is zero
so it is not a single point on the string
that is not zero
string looks like this
he took a picture of the string
even though it's also just a straight line
and i
if we do
look a little later we look at
equals one half
the period
then the cosine is minus one
now the curve look like this
so what does it mean
if we just
look what he happening
this is what's going to happen
it's just doing this and the points that stand still nothing is going like this
nothing is going like this
you see this point going up and down up and down up and down and
this will do the same and these nodes
we'll do
that's what they a standing wave look like and i think the name standing wave
is a very appropriate name very descriptive
because it's really standing it's not it's not moving at least not travelling along the
x direction
can we make a standing wave
yes we can i will do that
standing wave
can be made by
rotating in that fashion
a string
have string
OK i
that's the string to the wall there
and i move it up and down here
it always goes in
i do just this like the rotating disk
the wave travels
the wave is reflected
and so
i have always going in never wave coming back
not always going through each other
and if the conditions are just right
then these reflected waves this one will reflect
what are the right here it will reflect again goes back again and it will
continue to reflect
if the conditions are just right
then these reflected waves real
support each other
and they will
generate a large amplitude
as i will demonstrate to you
but that's only the case
four very specific frequencies
we call those
the lowest possible frequency for which this happens which we call the fundamental
will make the
the strings vibrate like this
the whole thing che
o che che i recall that the fundamental
the college also the first harmonic
if not to increase the frequencies
then i get a second
resonance frequency
and a
note jumps in the middle there is already a note here
and there is an old here
this motion of my hand here is very small as i will demonstrate to you
for all practical purposes you can think of is being the note
so now to string
in the second harmonic
also made like this which which
this is the second harmonic