we my normal hard margin where c is less so we can allow for some
terms being non-zero
it's like variables OK
so that's my man my minimisation tasks slightly different from previously
i have the constraints now slightly relaxed because i've got this term in there
so it's been like before
that's why l as before
but i know these two terms
these which come from my constraints
and finally
i have this additional term here
because i do dictate
that my
xyz must be zero positive zero positive there is a constraint on there
and that being the case any constraint must add corresponding lagrange multipliers so indeed do
two types of controlled now
so that comes about because my size must be positive OK
i didn't have been positive
b actually favoring points be messed up story basically so
that's my l
so i do my normal trickery of working out the one jewel dual formulation have
got an extra condition here
which is a of that is just as before
but i have this extra
xi separable floating around to deal with this i extra condition
we substituting back in the first of those two equations
i get the same objective function as before
we must be positive it is the crunch multiply
look this last equation i got to the bottom of the previous slide that must
be positive which in turn dictates the alpha i i must be less like to
in other words the previous constraint which i had is now replaced by this
so i support formal proof that that is the only change i make for the
l one
error norm OK
and there is one way and use the soft margin
now i'd say there's a second we're doing it will just before doing just some
some patterns will actually lie
the alpha
when i do the learning task alpha actually lies between the two
our first these as non bound whereas patterns actually hit up against the constraints like
sequence africa c
i call them as found that found it might indicate that there are not like
this these influence but it might be the case
they are now
now the optimal value c
well i say can be found by using experimentation of the validation set
she come back you can actually use the theorem to find out what the
well see should be
trivial a one-way finally what the sea should be
will be as my previous parts the island fit data
i simply have some holdout validation data
i estimate the validation error
on this date as a very c
and i find where the minimum is
and that's the minimum perceived value i would use with test data
there is a variant on the
l one error norm
which might come across called the they called new SVM OK
a different type of w
this is a quadratic you notice a quadratic in alpha OK so is a convex
the new SVM was invented by alex smola and i think the initial cough maniacs
and different type of maximisation subject to different well some irish constraints OK
this new
must lie in the range lies between zero and one
this variant on the l one error norm says the different type learning machines
it was introduced because it does actually give you better
interpretation of what the soft margin parameter should be
c the fraction of training errors is upper bounded by the new which introduce
and it also provides a lower bound on the fraction of support vectors
in a somewhat improved interpretation of the soft margin parameter OK
one of interpretation just now when i had to see
it was not clear
the game received value where the minimum is that what men
but this had a little bit better interpretation
this is just a variant
it is worth noting is this
the other type of
o normal want to introduce is l two error norm and is assigned the same
as l one
it said
rather than using a slack variable xi
i have xi squared OK that's it was only difference
now the words
just now
i had an equation
one minus xi OK which
and all these points here
that was the l one
l two is just square top
that's it so that's the difference
so the story for the l one l two norm
pretty much the same as before
so rather than linear inside it squared up
and that's the only difference
this equations got messed up here
i think just are designed as before
the same as before
but i've got that different
this was due to create court is i think actually
it's a long time ago she
note it is of minor comment in the paper
right so we
if i made a small change
and is a little exercise you to do
you would actually get w vlrtual which looks as before
exactly as before
but it's got this extra term tacked on
that is the difference comes about when introduces i squared OK
if i lambda you one a four c e
i can actually introduced this to
into here
if i make a small adaptation of my
OK if i shift my k value
if you notice
if the wise opossum minus one that obviously why i squared we pass one OK
that's one further observation but
i'm saying this term here
can be sucked into this term here
after all
i'm go i j i like second in here
you probably see if i just do one small change
the kernel goes to the kernel
where lambda is that she would be one on on to say
OK the half talking about somewhere but that small change OK
will give me the
w had on my previous slide that change
the that choice of lambda ix one
two say would make
equal to
my normal
w k
that's the full proof of
the this second type of soft margin
OK so these the two types of soft margin i introduced
to lessen the effect of outliers or noise in my data
can typically i would you see
one further comment phys so the leaf soft margins
if i'm doing a typical problem
i may have two types of errors could be
words on the page classify and then
we use only the labelled data for that by the way
then will allow both of those quest to go through the of labelled data in
pick just a small number of highly confident
examples where it's highly confident of its prediction
and then people get added to the self labelled examples
and will iterate this process
intuitively the reason this works well is that
suppose this is our one of our first examples
and we have let's say
only a hundred million on labelled web pages
even after this one example our hyperlink class the fire could become very confident that
if it sees the hyperlinks that says exactly my advisor
um then it's going to want to label the page that points two as a
faculty page
now when we search through the labelled data if the system happens to find one
other my adviser link
then that which is probably going to point two web page that looks nothing like
and will be web page where the word base where the page classify will be
very uncertain
so part of what works in our favour here is that
the hyperlinks that we've seen before
in the labels that happen to a co-worker with web pages that we haven't seen
before and vice versa
and so the things that class of is very confident about tend to be things
the quest for b
and so they can both help each other in this kind of bootstrap
so that's the idea of CO training
this actually works
for example here's the simple case where we had twelve labelled web pages
a thousand on labelled pages and we iterate that simple quote training
learning algorithm the error
on the whole don't test said
classification decreases from on the order of ten to fifteen percent down two
five to ten percent
so it's kind of practical advantage we get
in fact
since then i
people have found
stronger results but even here if you think about percentage-wise
improvement in the air it's pretty substantial
so let's spend a minute
talking a little bit more
looking in a little bit more detail at the
real structure of this problem are because i think that'll let you actually see
even in the case of this kind of page classification there will be problems with
this works better works worse depending on some subtle piece of the structure
OK so what's really going on there actually let me let me talk about it
this way has the best way i know of explaining what's really going on with
so i think of
our document classification problem or the web if you like as a very very large
by apartheid graph
by partake just means there are two kinds of nodes in the connection go from
one kind to the other kind
in our case
these nodes are web pages with words on
these nodes are the hyperlinks
like my adviser
if you think drying the them
think of representing the web this way or any collection of web pages that you
and we'll put in the edge between
a particular
hyperlink and in particular web page just in case those co-workers an example so each
edge here's an example
of course some of those edges we'll have labels for
somebody might tell us this is a positive example that web page in hyperlink pair
other ones will be on labelled those are just the edges that have no
labels on them
others will be labelled as negative and so forth
OK so you see the notation i'm using
now let's think of how we would how the training process would work
if we use the world's simplest
learning algorithm what's too willing to train two rote learners
one rote learner for the hyperlinks
one rote learner for the web pages
what happens
well these are labelled edges i'll say are my on labelled examples
in the labels they have pluses and minuses on the initially labelled subset of the
so what's going to happen
so on the first iteration my are
well of pages will learn that this page is a positive example
and are that this one's negative and this one's negative
and then it gets to look for other
examples that it can confidently label
so here's one
here's another
page pair
which involves the same page so it's going to label that here a positive example
this hyperlink label will label this
example is positive
and the next iteration of the rote learner will learn that this page is also
it turns out that
four consistency to
be true
we need a uniform large numbers
and that is uniform over all functions so here said that this is true for
any fixed function bit more specific about later
and we needed uniformly over all functions that the learning machine can implement
so i sort of glossed over this before but
i get to this nine
so uniform convergence automatically learning machine
and you have
so the whole set of functions that can choose from a set of functions empirical observations now
you would choose function based on your observations
e to these functions will have a certain risk
so the expected error
theta functions would have a certain period research training error form of a given set of observations
and the law of large numbers of classical
for every fixed function as
the training error will converge to the true error
in probability so the probability of
large deviation you get a zero
actually exponentially fast
it doesn't
all this doesn't imply
we keep increasing the observations sorry because observations parents are changes
so this and running out of every here
this curve you will change
in this case readily
in all
points we get closer to this goal
but this would imply that minimizes the
most with minimalist surprisingly
the reason is the difference between uniform convergence pointwise convergence end
i think the mathematicians among you will
immediately see why this is the case
can explain now
the go through more mathematics uh tree because this
next just
this is just to get a little bit
in the first place so i guess you can imagine if we have a uniform convergence so this
curve converges to this one at the same speed everywhere
and also the minimum will converge
which is basically what we want
okay so
so sometimes people
how to choose that set of functions
and that we should do or inference we
so what kind of functions you are learning machine e
able to implement
and the things we may be don't know what is the problem we want to learn
we might be tempted to say well
how it taking all functions that take our input domain then domain and plus minus one
and and that actually turns out to be impossible
it is relatively easy to see
once you think about the convergence
and as follows
so we have
as we have a training set like before
and in addition we already have that we have test inputs
and explore
and let's assume
for simplicity disjoint from the training points
so in a
continuous problem
the problem
and this will be
almost always true
this probability
it's not true with zero basically
and then
in this case is no overlap
of course when you give me some function after give function every time they are
in this is a good solution for problem
so i looked at the training set and i came up with this function if
i think this function will be good
i can give you an star
which is
defined as follows or which is constructed as follows so far
agrees with everyone all the training points
but it
disagrees with it on all the other points on the test points
the joint
so these joint
one such function in
no restriction on the class of functions
so now based on the training set is no means of choosing which one of these two functions is better
this is exactly the same that is that of results
therefore if u
if you go back to this picture
these two functions will have the same appearance they have the same training error
but that is
but it could be arbitrarily different so they can
very different characteristics
if one of these functions
nature is that was supposed be characteristic
other one might have an actual risk that far away from the empirical risk
we will never be the case that these curves
are close together everywhere
so in this case uniform convergence will be impossible
and this
kind of observation sometimes called
f of
y j
we can also write it as the sum over
i phi i p of
x i
so let's let's see what this is correct
so if we substitute the f in here
or let's let's do it here so remember remember g was
sum over
but they
OK of dot com are y j
nine the we substitute x i
so we get this thing here and now we have some of the phi beta
j k of x i y j
which is exactly what we had here
OK so we know we know this inequality is true to show this equality you
do basically the same thing and also use the fact case symmetric place the same
just by direct substitution you can prove that these two quantities are true
so what does this tell us
well first equality tells us
that this quantity of this dot product here
is independent of the of
because here the f only appears directly expansion coefficients of f
other fast and also the expansion points x either don't appear anymore
so here we can see
it is independent
i phi
x i
likewise here we can see
the dot product is independent of
but i j
and x sorry
y j
OK so this is something that mathematicians like to they like to show that these
are well defined maybe you are not worried about this to begin with in which
case i didn't want to get too worried but if you are worried about whether
it's well-defined and hopefully you convinced that this is well defined and also note that
you know order to show that this is well defined we didn't have to use
that the kernel is positive definite so far we didn't we didn't use that at
that's nice
anyway so the next week going to show that so now we know that this
it is well defined
actually we also know if we look at it that it's by linear are because
just by construction directly i mean if i had another term here
in the number of kernels then it will just show up here is another and
if you multiply with a constant it will just you will get this constant art
and stuff like that so it's it's what people call it by linear forms
and if the kernel is symmetric it is symmetric by now form the product is
a little bit more than the body now home
on a little bit more than symmetric body now form so it's also symmetric because
the kernel is symmetric and here these coefficients of course i can also interchanges just
a product products are symmetric
so we know this is symmetric bilinear form
now we have to prove that is the dot product and for that we are
going to use that the kernel is positive definite
so do this in two steps
the first step is actually to prove that this kernel is
well that this is the first step is to prove that this by linear form
here so this thing that we've defined here is actually a positive definite kernel on
the space of functions
so how do we prove this well we are going to use are
conditions that have to hold true for positive definite kernels so up there so this
is a positive definite kernel the space of the exercise
so i said no i'm going to show that this thing that we've just defined
is a positive definite kernel on the space of functions
so let's take some functions
this figure could an expansion over the coefficients come
goodman j
and then functions fi fj
and these all function functions of this form but they might have different expansions just
some elements of all of all vector space
OK so let's work this out what do we do about all symmetric bilinear form
we know that symmetric by linear answer since by lee we can take sums in
and out
so that's what we're going to do
as before
OK so so far only use this by linear
so now again the same triggers before we we see this is the function here
is the same function as this one here let's just call this function f
OK so now we have the by linear form between f itself that's not yet
enough we would like to say that this is this is nonnegative we want to
prove that this is lower bounded by zero
if we knew that this thing where dot product then we could stop now because
this direction
but means
the romans fours fl
which in this case with the currents
times the length
of this
are which is the length of this bar
times b
that is the force that i have to apply
if i put it to right because that forces to the left
so the force of waterloo in
is the same
but in this direction
i have to overcome the force
the romans force
in this direction
so it's clear that i have to do
i have force in this direction
and i moved within the direction
so i do positive work
what happened was that worked well that comes out
in the four
of heat in the resistance of this conductor i'm creating a map
the current is going to flow
and the power
is the EMF five current
i square are comes out in the form of heat
if i change the direction when i push in
velocity is now in this direction
then clearly the current is going to
change direction
and so when i push in
the lawrence force will also flip over
so to forcefully will flip over so again i have to do positive work
there's no such thing as a free lunch no matter what i do when i
pull this way or pushing
always have to do
positive work
and that work is always converted then
in the resistance of that loop
so the work that i do
let me express it in terms of
of power
the power that i generate
is my force
dot product with high velocity remember from a total
the work that i do
is forests
over a little element bx
the power is work unit time so the x eighty becomes velocity
and my force and my velocity always in the same direction when i push
they're in this direction and when i pulled and is regularly do positive work
and so the power
that i
generate is my force that's the magnitude of my force
which is i l b
times the velocity
but that must also be the EMF
times the current
note is now
that you may have therefore
and b
i'm sorry
so now i have shown you that you may have
is exactly what i found before in terms of magnitude
but now i have not used for
this is purely a derivation based of the work that i do
and the work per unit time
it's interesting that you can also think of it that way
we check
he i ask where i can live with that
force dotted with the velocity
i be it is the magnitude
of the EMF
and that's fine
if i
have a conducting
in this case
solid disc
and i move that
i try to
moving through a magnetic field north or south pole
this is the magnetic fields
so there we go here
little we there
i movies it
then the comes the time when this disk is here
that magnetic field lines
through this portion
that means
the magnetic flux through this surface
lens doesn't like that
prior the fire they doesn't like them
so what's going to happen in the current is going to go around like this
not so easy to precisely
determine how to current exactly flows
subject predicate object is just one way to write but you need to write them
all in the same way but before going in that direction
let's understand something more of what does it mean that i ever subject to predict
help in logic it means that is true
but these relationship among these three
elements or
OK so you can write to predicate let's say it's true also that me knows
it in
that's it
nothing more than that so
well also saying that when you have the tree when you have relational database the
logical representation of it but brooks down everything in its true
that the subject predicate object of related
in this way
everything is a URL or a uni actually
which means that you can write them in all the possible ways is pieces belong
this is the way to europe using the base URL and this one is using
namespaces will always use this one because it's the one that i believe is more
easy to read
the values
they this can be like a string
you can type so you can write something like three dot fourteen is the floor
and you can even use language that this stuff here is written in japanese
OK so i mean it is nice way to represent the true in in the
broad sense and you don't have to give
in a matter every node so if you don't know how to name in order
you can just leave it blank and the seat system will assign a unique identifier
to heat normally use the square brackets to do that but you can also use
this notation with an underscore and then
then this underscore means you are free to assign
i don't want to care about it
for instance
you know i'm declining all the namespaces so this is my name space which each
points that you
my website
EV DVD
is the name space but
works for these four five RDF five
RDF is the a name space of language for for is the namespace of these
tell about ways friend of school so perhaps things like knows the name of the
it is it right
of type of some
these oftype which is great in RDF can also be abbreviated using a since every
moment my phone tripos these
which means that me
is a person
OK just a shorter way to express
and you're very easy way to show blank nodes so you're saying that to me
know somebody
and this somebody which i'm not even a uri as a name which is in
so as you can see is not that there was an basically also easy
one system
could include
so abbreviation
when you have the same subset you can use the same color so you know
you have a means of person and minos CNN which can be written like the
it's a personal
and no serious
OK using the same because i will use this so mean this is the reason
why i stress and when you are
you have more people objects you can use the comma so you have to me
no zero in there and minos w
and is the way you can shorten it to me knows in and that you
see the comma is a way to put multiple object of the same property
so in the end
if you do take is XML
OK that talks about the band and artist saying that they be does is the
band that they comes from musicbrainz and actually they perform three different styles british invasion
rock and she for
OK so this is the information that i got from music it is the way
i can represent the same stuff using out here so i have the subject these
URL coming from here
and then seeing it's the band
using the music namespaces and then saying that the label of this stuff is the
i'm using these illiterate to the labels
and i'm in saying that this ties that they perform these three different objects
british invasion rock and
this was to show
but i mean
if all of us got that this was useful
and plenty of pages outside in the web but don't like these
well i mean it's not that
to to use a different representation which in an abstract one so is good for
this layer up here
that doesn't sound
more complex or more variables than the original one
if you want to read more input here the
the links this life would be somewhere in the preceding i guess but if you
like you can also download them from the from our website OK good i guess
i mean you the to so you can click on them i guess an open
the pages
from RDF two
the question of
so this one is not to say a few role of the tree
you don't need me to tell you
that human civilization is very very old
nevertheless our knowledge of the earliest stages of human civilization were quite limited for many
centuries that is until the great archaeological discoveries of the nineteenth and twentieth centuries which
honors trust the great civilizations of the ancient near east of which i have drawn
remarkably lifelike map
here on the board
mediterranean we start with the mediterranean ocean
and i'll river
the tigers and the afraid is so the great civilizations of ancient egypt mesopotamia and
the area we refer to as the fertile crescent
of which little part here about the size of rhode island is came OK can
and cannot
and archaeologist in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries were stunned to find the ruins and
the records of remarkable peoples and cultures massive complex empires in some cases the some
of which had completely disappeared from human memory
their newly uncovered languages had been long forgotten
the rich literary and legal texts were now indecipherable that that soon changed
but because of those discoveries we are now in a position to appreciate the monumental
achievements of these early civilizations is the earliest civilizations
so many scholars many people have remarked that it's not a small irony
that the ancient near eastern people
with one of the or perhaps the most lasting legacy
it was not people that built and inhabited one of the great centres of engineer
eastern civilization
it can be argued that the ancient near eastern people with the most lasting legacy
is the people
they had an idea
it was a new idea
broke with the ideas of its neighbors
and those people were the israelites
and scholars have come to the realization that despite the bible's pretensions to the contrary
the israelites were a small
and i've actually over represented here i'm sure should be much smaller a small and
relatively insignificant group for much of their history
they did manage to establish the kingdom in the land that was known in antiquity
as canaan
around the year one thousand they probably succeeded in subduing some their neighbors collecting tribute
there is some controversy about that but in about nineteen twenty two this kingdom divided
into two smaller and lesser kingdoms fell in importance
the northern kingdom which consisted of ten of the twelve israelite tribes and known confusingly
as israel
it was destroyed in seven twenty two by the assyrians
the southern kingdom which consisted of two of the twelve tribes and known as judah
managed to survive until the year five eighty six when the babylonians came in and
conquered and sent the people
into exile capital jerusalem fell
conquest and exile were events that normally would spell the end of a particular ethnic
and national groups particularly
in antiquity
conquered peoples would trade their defeated god for the victorious god of their conquerors and
eventually there would be a cultural and religious assimilation intermarriage that people would disappear as
a distinctive entity an effect that is what happened to the ten tribes of the
northern kingdom to a large degree were lost to history
this is not happen to those members of the nation of israel who lived in
the southern kingdom of judah
the demise
of their national political base in five eighty six
these rights along really among the many people who have figured in engineering eastern history
the sumerian is the acadians the babylonians hittites the venetians the hoary in the canaanites
they emerged after the death of their state
producing a community and the culture
they can be traced through various
twists and turns and vicissitudes of history
right down into the modern period
that's a pretty unique claim and they carried with them
the idea
and the traditions that laid the foundation for the major religions of the western world
judaism christianity and islam
so what is this radical
new ideas that shape the culture and enable its survival into into later antiquity and
really right into the present day in some form
well the conception of the universe that was widespread among ancient peoples is one that
you're probably familiar with people regarded
various natural forces
as imbued with divine power as in some sense divinity themselves the earth was the
divinity the guy was the divinity the water was the divinity had divine power in
other words the gods are identical with or a minute in the forces of nature
there are many gods no one single god was therefore all powerful
there is very very good evidence
to suggest that ancient israelites
by and large share this worldview
they participated at the very earliest stages in the wider religious called the culture of
the ancient near east
over the course of time
some ancient israelites not all at once and not unanimously
broke with this view
an articulated different view that there was one divine power one god but much more
important than number
was the fact that this god was outside of and above nature this guy was
not identified with nature he transcended nature and he wasn't known through nature or natural
he was known through
and the particular relationship with humankind
an idea which seems simple at first and not so very revolutionary we'll see that's
an idea that affected every aspect of israelite culture
and in ways that will become clear as we move through the course to learn
none of the bright light but in dark adapted conditions you actually have one photon
very impressed
under appropriate conditions like
sound receptors
you get sound receptors in your ear
and there are beautiful rug talk about the meaning like but there's the there's little
flappy these these little spiky things going along in your ear and they can translate
vibrational energy
coming from here including area here drum being translated into vibration in the fluid in
your ear into a physical motion
of of these
little receptors there into an electrical motion
into electrical signal that goes into year so all that
o pretty impressive stuff
we're not going to talk about the details of it but i invite some of
you want to learn more about this particular MIT students taking find receptors to be
really quite remarkable kinds of devices the focus more on this intermediate step here of
a generic nor on
so here's my generic neuron and the first thing that has to be said is
there are no generic neurons neurons are all very specific
but i mean just use the generic neuron for the moment
and the important features of the generic neuron here
it has these funny little processes
on its cell body
there are called dendrites
that's where it's going to receive
signals processes to the name for things that stick out
so these processes are called dendrites
here's our nucleus of ourselves here's our cell body with label this year cell body
with the nucleus and
we have this very long
called it acts on
the axis the wire here this region here
is called the axon hillock
and it looks like a little hill that's what hilo means
so feel like region here and that's where all the electrical signals from the cell
body or integrate and a quote decision is made about whether to fire
and the normal then fire signal down the length of attacks on
and then will get to the end here
where we have these terminal processes
there will be some saying on other cells here
these are called nerve terminals
we'll make connections either with other dendrites
or maybe with the muscle
you wouldn't see both of those occurring from destroying is for illustration purposes here and
it will send the signal and these points of contact are called synapses
so nerve or muscle
that year general picture of the synapse apps
which transmits this is an electrical signal
this is typically a chemical signal
and as you might imagine
the presynaptic cell is this guy
the postsynaptic cell that guy
it's also presynaptic
post synaptic
and what nerve biologists want to do is understand how does this all work
how does the initial signal impinge upon the dendrite from snaps how does that signal
get collected integrated into decision about whether to fire an action potential that runs along
the nerve and then how does that get transmitted from electrical signal back chemical signal
which then
restarts an electrical signal in the next cell et cetera et cetera et cetera
those are some of the kinds of questions asked now i said generic neurons cause
there's really nothing generic about
some neurons are very tiny
some neurons are very big but the typical size of the ordinary you carry out
acts on liver cells
the ballpark
the minimizer of the regularized risk or rigorous here
is close to the best
and the only way you can make a meaningful relationship is by introducing restrictions or
assumptions are you on this
OK so there is no contradiction here is just that
all these things are valid but they
don't tell you that this quantity would be small
just tell you that this quantity can be related to some of the point
maybe large
OK the question is what is what come under assumptions for respecting the probability distribution
of one people one is to assume that there is no noise which means that
at each point perfect lassification
and you can in addition but this would not really help
but in addition you may assume that
the target function
this this far right so he started the one that minimizes
you would assume that the star
to some class so maybe belongs to
this is difficult or maybe some bigger plan
and this would be i mean this is the
standard type of restriction that to impose that you have some kind of like something
that belongs to
fixed class that you know in advance
and the distribution is derived from that
which means the labels are i mean the labels all thing by applying this
but then there often you don't have really restriction of how the axes are distributed
apart from you know they are in the involved
OK the question is is that the same assuming that it belongs to the prime
is the same as assuming that our as looking for g in of function
i mean
you have all sorts of results so you have results that are just like you
you're working with the class g
d and u
i'm looking for these gn in the same class
and you say well what if my true function belongs to this class like this
these are the best areas
well i assume that
the best classifier is linear classifiers
and let's look for
one such a classifier and c
how well we're doing there
other cases is
you look at
prime that is that contains
like you're trying to approximate c
a polynomial of degree two ways
with linear classifiers or well i mean if would look for something where g is
dense in the prime of the deep discovered from the slightly larger class but then
you hope that this
these classes he can approximate arbitrarily well right
there can be all OK
and i think that the of question
o back
mentioned these three ways of using the bomb i either looking at the actual value
of the bound
are using the value of the bond
choose between different models or
thing to look at really in qualitative where the bomb
the the the first case the problem is that
you know
it's not easy to capture what happens with all these fluctuations because we have a
large class of functions we already see that
you know we when we look at the binomial there's it's not an easy formula
to work with
and you imagine that you you know all functions would have added a slightly different
behavior because they have different error
and they are all interrelated
in the sense that
you know if you look at the function the errors that they make are not
independent in the sense that you know the cause of they are the
the same year the more similar the air
that they will make
two which means it's all right this is empirical process is very complicated is it's
hard to
really get something
died or you know i have an accurate estimator
the population so
this is one reason for why the violence usually have large value and you know
you lost large constant very hard follow
the techniques that we use them in the only thing that we can say about
them is that they are sharp in the asymptotic regime so we can prove that
you know the square root of pain is part of n is the right rate
asymptotically but
four finance
values of and we might have you know
in the case of the training role which had told you is the right measure
for capturing the the deviation of the inference process
you think have some constant in front of the integral
and this might be very big and also when you in when you compute the
covering numbers
computing the covering numbers is not an easy thing and also in this covering numbers
you might have very large constant because you always are forced to kind of overestimating
i mean there are
slightly more precise techniques that than the ones i mentioned but again they are even
more complicated
we implement
in the way you want to have
there's this trade right you can have
well that are
very large and very nice to write like you know this kind of thing or
you can have found that there bit smaller
in fact the too margin point six
OK so the problem is that even after this time and the reason is because
at this is difficult to analyse
and it's because usually what you do well the margin doesn't increased at every iteration
a kind of bubbles up and down the visual tricks don't work is usually what
you do is you add up the increases in the margin you know each iteration
you see whether got to the maximum but in this case since it goes up
and down you can do that
so we really need some kind of new approach
to understand the convergence of the algorithm
and so i will give you in suspense any longer
the answer is actually no
it's exactly the opposite of what everyone thought
in fact at this may converge to a margin that is significantly below the maximum
and what's even more interesting is that russian actually were were
they were even more right than they thought there are bound is actually tight
so in other words not optimal adaboost
you can you can actually get to converge to exactly the rebound
so i can get this to converge to exactly and margin of wire rope in
very specific limiting condition which i'll describe a little bit later on this theorem down
here a specific is the more general theorem which i hope to be able to
see later but what i'm going to do for the rest of my talk is
i'm going to prove this here
the question
OK so i will introduce notation and image so be able to answer your questions
so this is an overview of my talk the first thing i wanted to do
was get the full history about the margin theory producing and i finished that know
what i'm going to do is give introduction to adaboost i know you've already seen
it but i know that a lot of you have haven't seen before yesterday so
i'm going to go over it again
and then i'm going to spend the rest of my talk giving the proof of
the theorem that this doesn't always converge to the maximum margin solution and the proof
of the theorem consists of reducing adaboost to a dynamical system in order to understand
its convergence properties so in other words we have analysis problem we're trying to understand
convergence of the algorithm what we did was we converted into a physics problem in
order to solve it
OK so so here is simple problem you can keep in mind just to have
something in mind
OK so what do you have a database of news articles and the articles are
labeled plus one of the categories the articles entertainment and negative one otherwise
and what did classification setting goals given a new article which is not in the
database we want the computer to automatically be able to find label so to tell
us whether legitimate or not entertainment so just you know wait for classification we have
a bunch of algorithms first first you know following this kind of problems and we
have boosting and
listing can be used as i mentioned in two ways the optimal case in the
non optimal case you can use that you can use the algorithm to do most
of the work for you
for example with this text
you can be sort of very basic features and come up with some combination of
some very basic features or you can use it as a wrapper for another algorithm
you can plot but on top of the decision tree or neural network which would
mean that you're probably using in the non optimal case
see here
so just to formalise the problem for you as usual we have this
training data which is in the form of ordered pairs return to paris randomly from
an unknown probability distribution on the space express negative one
and you remember access the space of all possible news articles are negative one one
of the labels
and so you know given new article
what's what's the label
and how do we construct classifiers course we're going to do the usual thing which
is we're going to divide our our space x into two sections based on the
sign of the function
and the decision boundary is going to be the zero level set of functions so
what we're trying to do is we're trying to construct a function in a so
that level that is in the right place to be in this decision boundary
OK so now we're going to go into thing what they that we have a
weak learning algorithm and remember learning algorithm produces weak classifiers and you should think about
we classifier as a rule of thumb
so for example
if we're studying these articles into entertainment not entertainment we classifier might be too
take a look at the article see whether it contains the term movie and classifier
based on that so take a look at the article if it contains the term
movie so you entertainment
the content removing not entertainment and of course this is you know not a particularly
good way to classify things but it gives us some information at least and so
what we're going to do is to introduce a couple more weak classifiers they you
could check for the term actor
you could take for the term drama
but instead of using any of these weak classifiers individually you want to combine them
so that you can get something stronger and that's what that's why can use that
because it's going to combine classifiers in a meaningful way we classifiers in a meaningful
way so for example
the function f is going to be the final point four times each one plus
three ten sixty two plus point times age three
so that if the article contains the term movie which means each one is one
it contains the term drama which means village three is one but it doesn't contain
the term actor which means should minus one
then the value of this side point four minus three point three so it positive
one so we say that this articles entertainment you know it contains two out of
these three terms and even though it didn't contain the last term we think that
you know contains two of these three terms it's an article about entertainment
so what i'm really trying to say here
is that you can think of boosting algorithm as doing the following
you can think of it as taking in
which is
the weak learning algorithm
which produces these weak classifiers h one h two and h three
and it takes a large training database of labelled examples
and outputs the coefficients of the weak classifiers to make the combined classifier
so at which point four point three and point three
OK and so just to go over what was that again
so with adaboost
what we do is we have these labelled training examples
and we're going to assign an importance each
training example
and at the very beginning o and the way the weights on the training examples
are going to tell the weak learning algorithm which examples are going to be important
and at the very beginning we don't know which examples are more important than what
other examples so we give all the training instances equal weights
OK so then we take the weighted training examples and feed them into the weak
learning algorithm and it gives us the weak classifiers
and the class register also
it's we week australia says he should be positive and should be negative
so if you're wrong
because there's only rule
in fact gets one from
so what we're going to do is say OK at the next round we got
this wrong so we're going to make them more important
and everybody else get there which produced because we got the correct OK so we
repeat this over and over again we can take a weighted training examples to them
into the weak learning algorithm receives a weak classifiers
and it gets most of examples right but this is if you and so we're
going to increase the weights on those examples and increase the weights and all the
others and then we repeat this over and over again until we're completely blue in
the face
and the and we can only make a linear combination of the weak classifiers obtained
all the iterations
so our final combined classifier look something like this in this case get all the
training examples correct
OK so the final combine clusters of this form it's
because this holds for all closeness et al so in particular it holds for the
courts which minimizes the particular sequence you get
so how can you construct such code well it's very simple
basically first
and called so you list
all the coast in here
let's say there of them sold in the list goes from one to n and
the first thing called the number
using the uniform code that takes two log n bits
and if you do with the way we call it a b c d here
with the same number of bits for each outcome you can coat
an element of the set was
m elements by log n bits of then
OK be look and where m is the number of elements
in the set curly l
and no matter what they do you get your overhead compared to the best code
for the data is logged the tools no matter how long the data sequences
so for long data sequences quite nice
now we make the crucial jump from universal codes
two what has been called universal models
suppose i have
a set of probability distributions now now we're getting a bit closer to statistics machine
learning a probabilistic model but for the moment we also assume that finite later we
will look at more realistic infinite models
using basic notation
i can describe more more like this it is
you don't want to see to so
we've just seen that there always exists a code
relative to a set of codes such that i have
overheads finite overheads
OK compared to the best coach in that sense
so now what i'm going to do is i'm going to turn this set of
distributions into set of codes
by the trick i described earlier so each of these distributions induces a cold
so for all outcomes
link is minus log the the probability of the outcome
this means that if i turn it into a set of codes
i can now construct a new coat
no matter what outcomes to get the number of bits and need is more equal
and minus log probability of the outcome according to any of these the test class
k where k will again be for example org
this is a universal code
and now i can also mapped back again to distribution
and that is called universal
model universal distribution in information theory literature
and what i do here is i met this back to distribution
because for and i can do that for any code there must also be distribution
such that for outcomes minus log probability of the outcome
small equal to minus log proactively outcome according to any theta plus the constant overhead
so if i exponentiate on both sides this means that this distribution is actually dominates
this set of distributions there are some constants such that no matter what outcomes i
get the probability assigned to this sequence is large equal the constant
times the probability i sin two theta for any time i model
and such a distribution which dominates the set of distribution is called universal model are
universal distribution
for the set
so now something like terminology small side so there's something confusing here because when i
i call this that curry and a model that's common terminology in statistics so model
is a family of distributions but information theory the word model is used to single
distribution and universal model is an information theoretic concepts so o
a universe so they are using information theoretic terminology so when i a universal model
we mean a single distribution
but this is a single distribution which acts as a representative for set of distributions
said that dominates it
and the set of distributions confusingly also called model
so now we've already seen one example of universal models this was basically is worked
if you look at it in terms of code by coding in two stages first
recorded index
of the set of codes and then you quote the data using
the code with the index
you just think of
but and this is crucial
inside again
there are many more universal models and that these two part way of coding is
just one way of doing it and actually often not the cleverest way
so another way which may be familiar to most of you
it's coding by using a bayesian mixture
so suppose i have some prior distribution over my set
of my model my set of distributions
then i can define the bayesian marginal distribution
the marginal likelihood in this case but the defines a distribution
because if you some over all sequences it becomes one so this is the weighted
average of the probability of the data according to see ten times the prior of
the heat
this is the common
bayesian way to define a distribution over
sequence of data
this distribution
defines a universal model relative to the set curly
because we have the following for all outcomes of all links
for all theta set career
we have the code length if you code to data using the code corresponding to
this base distribution so that minus log the probability of this distribution is by definition
minus love this sort of of this sum is efforts
there is some is larger than each of its terms someone's love of some smaller
the needs of its terms
so this must be smaller equal and minus log the probability of the data according
to particular seat
minus log the prior theta and this holds for all theta and you're set
so this means that the code length if you code using
the code corresponding to the base distribution
it's more equal than the code length corresponding to any individual
element in your set of distributions
plus a term which does not depend on and so this makes it universal again
because if n is large this remains constant
you see that's
in the end you're doing essentially as well as
the best distribution in your model because this holds for all theta
in particular the theta which featured data best which gives the highest probability
and therefore the smallest code with hindsight to data
let's compare the previous
universal codes we've seen
in which we will now
not really and saying that the goal here is to compress data as well as
good as possible compared to some set
of quotes
and i'm saying you can do this in in different ways
so one way to code in two stages first recorded index and then you could
data with the code corresponding to the index another way is to first define the
mixture distribution
so the first met the coats to distributions then define a mixture distributions and then
map that back to cope
that's another way of achieving the same goal and because
what what will happen now as we will see two more ways
of achieving the same goal and then we'll start comparing
so not comparing this bayesian method for constructing code is the two-part method we do
it in two stages
and so
course you can extend this two-part method also
so using a prior on the set of the task
because each distribution on the set of features and uses code for encoding the task
with code length minus log prior theta
so then if you could the data by first according to peter which maximizes the
probability of the data
world series from interacting with peter hunt group in auckland new zealand who were the
first start to
large anatomical models of the whole ventricle
part based course on experimental information and represented by tens of millions of grid points
into which was then possible
to introduce
the equations for electrical excitation that we developed set levels to produce impressive reconstructions in
this case is the spread of electrical excitation through the whole ventricle
and then later
two reconstructed with arrhythmias this is from the work of peter cole my group
get to tell you try another
in the united states in which they reconstructed the
fatal arrhythmia occurs
you had to be on the golf course
and the ball hits u
the chest just in the wrong place in just the wrong time during cardiac we
polarization they introduced french
activated channels which can be coates analyzed experimentally in the heart
to initiate
this re entrant a risk here in the
model of the whole ventricle
so what you're seeing here
is re-entry text citations and determined by
but the equations the cellular activity
the anatomical arrangement of those tens of millions of critical points in the anatomical model
and of course the incorporation of the stretch activated channels that enables the process in
this case to be
session panfilov later went on to have a look at the way in which such
as we enter into a written is to break down into the phenomenon of fibrillation
is every entrant arrhythmia now breaking down
into multiple wavelengths which the heart would no longer path
like this but but simply shim
and ceased pumping this recording by the koskie using voltage sensitive dyes
on animal park showing the same kind of phenomena
that works all being done
in animals recently with
and the group
sasha and often because they tend to share in
utrecht we collaborated and put together
humans model
and this nice simulation in the next slide
from august and ten two shoes works
simulating every entrant arrhythmia
in the human heart
and i notice incidentally was lovely abstract page sixty four abstract but by custom revealing
how modeling can help one to understand the differences between human and animal parts in
relation to the process of population
so the last two or three minutes
i want to give you the last three principles
no programs genetic programs no programs at any other level
if you like my
metaphore of the music of life then it doesn't have a conductor
i was delighted when oxford university press
this lovely
by the japanese paper artist he had and i don't
a violin butterfly
he's a brilliant paper artist so this is actually a cut-out and the shadows therefore
real shadows and you notice that the
violin butterfly
is being played
but there's no player
that's a lovely
illustration from michael because part of what i'm saying is of course the
organisations like doesn't have conducted if you like the orchestra analogy then it's like one
of these orchestras that can play effectively
without to conductor the review by thomas limberger in and reports that says more about
that which i think is full of insight
eight principle no programs at any other level including instant to break many people to
whom i i lectured on the subject and try to introduce some principles of systems
biology we tend to say to me then you may be right about viruses you
may be right about policy might even be right about simple animals but my goodness
is surely the programs here
well i think that concept is also incorrect and i explained why
in chapter nine
i got some very very distinguished opponents include francis crick
who once
there were poised for the greatest revolution of all
consciousness and it is
comments rededicate by
his colleague of course in the double helix work jim watson there are only molecules
everything else is sociology but tell you is that true then all i've been doing
for the last forty years is just sociology
it leads to very big mistake
and it's the one is illustrated by this last quote from create just before he
he said i think the secret of consciousness lies in the cluster
thank you
classroom is a thin layer
cells in the cortex and the reason is selected this was is connected to almost
everything else
there is no such location of consciousness there's no such location of the program of
that nature
and that itself is a fundamental mistake is a mistake in fact very similar to
the one that was initially made in western philosophy by
and they can be thought of course that there was an actual separate substance which
the set of of points into a kind of you have of planes if you want
you know f
so that the sum of the distance to the lines are and are being
the function we're looking for
i k means we'll just put a whole bunch of prototypes all around the surface
seems perfect but it does work in high dimension of course
ok so this concentrate on this idea sparsity
so fast learning is uses this energy function this type which has to
organize what is the input and the other one is a quote vector which is related to variables are
going to infer
and the energy function
is the square reconstruction error we multiply a vector by a matrix
code dictionary matrix and then we add or regularization term which is the sum of the two
values of the components of the
of the code
if we know a picture matrix
are given why we find z here that minimizes this energy on tion and gives us
feature vector
is going to be high dimensional how
shown sparse
so has a non-linear mapping one that maps y to the optimal z is on the mapping
but it's so to compute because you have to do this are in operation
you can learn addition a matrix of course with doesn't field told us to do this on
time ago
using just as he basically just as casagrande sat
to minimize this over the overall average energy of a collection of samples training samples
columns that you have to minimize this to work
and the manifold assumption as hidden behind the sparse coding is basically that the data
is fits sort of union of flow dimensional planes
with dimension image plane
corresponds to the number of components z that non-zero
once we do this musician
so in general though we have several ways of designing unsupervised learning algorithms one is
number one is to construct energy function so that the volume of stuff that takes energy
a is fixed because the problem we have is that
we have to build this energy function
so that has low energy on the points on the data points on a manifold higher energy everywhere else
and is easy enough to
treat the parameters of an energy function to take the values of the points ok just
to a
great descent
but how do you make sure the energy is high everywhere else
and that's basically it's basically the
the a partition function problem you know that people have been
getting in graphical models of luggage is very similar in spirit
your to construct well when method was strategies construct energy so that the volume of low energy statistics
so that if you give low energy some points the other points automatically have
a higher energy
ca one of those k-means is one of those
the second strategy is to push down the energy of the samples and push up on the energy of earth
else this is a strategy used by contrast divergence which is used to train
restricted most machines
also strategy used by maximum likelihood when you have a partition function
as contrasted term that pushes up on the energy of
all this stuff is very expensive to
if your partition function is not tractable
where does not tractable gradient
to use kernel methods stuff
and the third one is to use a regularizer to limit the volume of stuff that can take low
energy so basically building a neural in such a way that it has a regularizer
by minimizing a regularizer is sort of shrink wraps
the of the stuff of low energy into sort of a small value fuel and that's basically what's task
and does
sparsity term
limits the volume of stuff that is allowed to take low energy
that's essentially does
ok so this task learning method is or what we call the decoder only method goes from
has a simple function to compute goes from the code to the input
which means you have to run musician algorithm to figure out the optimal code
for a given input
so we're going to do is we're going to
to this a sort feed-forward function that goes from the input to the code
and we'll will tend to predict
what the optimal code is
this function would necessarily have to be non-linear
decay firstly we call this qz which means predictive sparse decomposition
which gives you know various architectures for this it's a simple neural net some kind
and so here is that the algorithm running this is the algorithm running on a set of natural
image patches what i'm representing here are
each square here
is a problem of the w matrix represented as
a as an image of the same size as the input
so you get
in the end of the training you get sort of going to give order to detectors
which is which you're x
more as expected
now to due to design this encoder
this g function
from oppose my progress is really brilliant idea
essentially iminating algorithm that we know will produce the optimal z cold fista or stuff
iterative shrinkage thresholding algorithm
and the algorithm basically is this kind of iteration where you take the input multiplied by input matrix and then you
as it were shrinkage shrinkage function
each component
multiplied by square matrix which is you could think of as a lateral inhibition matrix
added to the previous result you had iterate this group
so it's kind of this recurrence here
f what we're going to do is going to learn
instead of using
you know this definition for s and that definition for that you eat which is
to learn as and you eat
so you can think of this as a recurrent neural net some kind
which matrices w in s going to train this
recurrent neural net which has bounded o complexity to do the best approximation can
of the optimal task this works really well
interest of time and to skip a
just to say that we've apply this to kind of various things including one where
we have criteria
that combine this reconstruction sparsity as well as
the its prediction
and a recent paper by just roles
myself a clear yeah conference f and this produces very interesting results we have seen before in
sort of a s an alternative view of this ok
which is derived in the size but i'm really not going to go through
the derivation is the following we can think of this quite
and as saying we have some objective function here which is
the squared error ok we're trying to minimize that
and at the same time we want to keep the magnitude of the weights
bounded ok and this parameter data sort of the inverse of lambda
ok so what does this mean okay how do we visualize this
we basically we do the following in general will like the
weights to be close to zero okay so you have this red circle
over here around the origin that saying i on the weights to be
small okay and we have a sort of point over here that's the best
fit based on the data ok now what is the best solution according
to this quite and well it's where these circles intersect ok
and that's going to be on the sort of line that unites
these two centers or you know if your many dimensions can be hyper
so now what happens with the regular izations phi
ify make lambda very small ok data which is one over
does very big and the circle that's around the origin is going
to blow up ok and all solutions are acceptable essentially
ok otherwise when we shrink this circle
ok we really want the weights to be close to zero that's the emphasis
and so the weights are going to migrate away from the point that's
best for the data towards the point that's best for us this prior
ok that's to regulars h
so this is actually quite nice ok if you find a good value for the
regular zation parameter this helps you avoid overfitting
if there are irrelevant features in the input
then you're going to get a small weights for those features
typically ok without having to do some kind of complicated pre-selection
procedure where you just keep some features and so on
but their weights not then be quite zero
k the kind of stale little bit away from zero because there's nothing
really encouraging them to be all zero okay we're working with
the magnitude of the weight vector rather than particular weights
so there's a weight to to actually get these weights to be
equal to zero okay that's called one regular izations
ok and actually show you the picture first
ok the picture for one regularization is that instead of
using a circle around the origin we use a little diamond
ok and so what we require is for the weights to be inside of this
time and so now you have the circle here it's going to touch the
diamond somewhere along its edges ok but one can actually formally
show that you're more likely to touch at the corner
went to touch in the middle of on h ok
now that's actually kind of nice because here
if you're touching at the corner that means that one of your
weights is actually zero and only the other weight matters so
if you have irrelevant features then those irrelevant features essentially
will have zero weights will be thrown
so large class of methods called lasso
very popular statistics community works very well with linear
approximators doesn't works well with non linear approximators
because this kind of constraint is actually a little bit ugly
okay and optimization procedure is
significantly more elaborate ok the type of constraint that we have
here is that the sum of the absolute values of the weights has
to be bounded by parameter data and data again controls the size
of the time so now why is this more complicated well you can easily
see that if i take this absolute value and expanded and all
possible ways we get a lot of these constraints you still have
a sort of in principle nice optimization procedure but with lots
and lots of constraints and so where is this
useful where that depicts there are some things that are that going
between where people use sort of l one style regular sation some
parts of the space and i'm smoothly going to one l to
these are called huber arise losses some in some cases those work
better than either one l to the advantage of delta is that it eliminates
completely features that are irrelevant and so in some applications
that's actually useful for example if you work in medical applications
doctors really want to know what error the three different symptoms
that are determining the diagnosis sort of five different
is that determining the diagnosis and don't want everything
OK so we had
i see the person
viewpoint lighting
we have lots of axis here
the things my very on so you might say OK
the PCA is is too simple what i want is the multi access decomposition
but does a similar thing is linear decomposition but it will will divided that it
along several different axes and build character
characteristic models
in that way
so yes such techniques exist
equal to interfaces tensor analysis
so you can build things that have a particular characteristic directions for changing identity people
changing illumination these kinds of things
but still linear analysis still fairly simple minded
the way you do this is kind of iterative algorithm does this feeds along each
axis alternating right
so it's not very complicated to do
OK and then a whole slew of non linear dimensionality reduction techniques which tend to
get applied to vision problems but
i think in terms of faces
the more toy techniques and then the
really useful things
but certainly the first i submit papers the first
local linear embedding paper
her face that sits in the
people people have been using this and it's a good example because you can see
what's going on
when you're doing embedding
these techniques can be thought about of course is a whole slew of other
variance of these techniques these days
now on to some modelling
different ways the systems in different ways might model motion
so before we saw an example best humans data
OK you can do the same thing with motion
so if you take a training set of people in various composers
you have your detector
and if you can detect things like this
so the difference in the rates of the person being you can t into your
training set of motions and therefore is to make what the movement of the pose
of the person was
so this was an early paper that does
works actually with HMM based model
over the whole sequence some optimizations to try to pull out this this whole sequence
the motion suggesting that the to be start of algorithm to do that
and it was that reasonable estimates of motion the person
you can also then
and more with more linear methods priors
four motion
so i guess and regressive processes for example
here for dancing motion so this was all done essentially the learning was done in
three d
but again i got example kinds of things using
just was see a similar example
this is pure example of purely
learning motion models for the second c the kinds of tracking
the commonwealth
the school
as well to move
so this is two d
so it's time model
tracking down sequence
existing pretty well it's fairly stable tracking if you want to annotate these particular example
of three d poses and you can get out and this to the three d
pose which is rescued crew it is OK
you can do things like sports analysis with us analyse motions of people much the
same thing
we've we've just got been using exemplars here we've got an articulated model of the
person has been put into the exemplars by hand and it can reach say that
one of the things that season the image
even if you want to do sports analysis
of soccer players who are only a few pixels high twenty pixels high something
you can't really building articulated model
the person
no television is this of players just to
i don't really know what it is we can still build an example model of
in the signpost is an example of model which will only be approximate because you
can resolve the and some things you get approximate body pose and you can use
that for example the recent size
difference of the sequences in the original paper the guy used to replace the sock
also players on the team with himself
so it's quite bizarre
which we don't have the video so that
OK so another sample based methods that you can use
is that you can just record dynamics
so this a got some kind of three d motion capture system human movement the
kind of things they movies to capture three d motion
then you can record of the database that
and you've got some kind of reconstruction of some kind two d
that they can use that to t into the database
and if you find over short sequences time you've got a similar motion
you can easily predict the motions going to continue like that
so this is just a purely sampling based methods that looks into the database something
tries to reply that
but nevertheless it gives you quite good
it is also true for the video for that here
so the mouse stopped working his
so it's got
the type of motion is
coded by the colour
you can see that encoding fairly small fairly fairly good walking motion
so all of those models for purely exempt purely examples being used to
two to kind of reply
i think you see in the image
now we get onto most structural models
someone has gone and input in some kind of structure by hand and then of
often you have to learn some parts of the model
so here is what's called active appearance models or in particular
vision of an active shape models to typically will be control model the person with
an active appearance models also attached
model for the parents of the person those contours
and you're able to from that
to fit this parametric model
with much parents and parametric geometry
and then when she fitted the model you can do things like
six will be a the person one person would look like under certain circumstances the
if such object is in the image but we want to look for it and
she she component of this task is the localisation component so here we're looking for
or detecting cars and localizing where they are
another task would be identification
this will be related especially to the individualisation of objects within as a member of
of within the category category for example here we know there's
even if we identify this is a human face was still want individualized this particular
object we call it identification
going beyond identification we have the task of categorisation where this is more in a
what we have seen play has told us that different members of similar after different
members of the group participate together to form a class or category and we want
to categorize for example in the real world image all these different classes that are
present in this in this image
and of course
categories of objects or individual categories of just come together to describe visual scenes such
as sing sing club scene categories or even context or we can imagine moving beyond
our events and activities and so on especially towards
and towards the future of visual computer vision high-level vision research we would like to
write stories of images and videos so objects are very important building blocks for these
recognising objects are not easy and here is one of the tabbouleh some of the
challenges we all face and apparently human visual system have dealt with very well but
as designing robots and come machine vision algorithms we face a lot of of the
following problems one is viewpoint in fact variation
our physical three d
all other things and when you view it from different angles different perspective they render
very different images on the retina or on the computer on the camera image
so that's one big challenge
can you tell this is the same person
maybe some of you can buy trying to find some specific feature on the face
but just at a glance
it's not easy to tell at all
and this is because there's a lot of illumination changes in the world that rendered
the part our images and we have to deal with that in object recognition
in identification in categorisation we would like to tell you this is the same person
is another problem
objects don't exist
ten not exist in the world by itself completely clean and free environment of in
this world we have a lot of clutter and the objects occluded by other parts
of this this world and they can even self occluded when you have especially quite
articulated objects and so on so occlusion is the problem we can not only in
this room are algorithms can can recognise an object when the when the thing is
fully insight we would like to take care of recognition in under this under this
scale is another problem
the same class of object my have very different sizes
they might come into different physical sizes or they might just be geometrically rendered differently
when you're a far or near from these these objects but you would still like
to understand this is from the same class
deformation is another problem like i just mentioned especially articulated objects we have a lot
of it articulated objects in this world including our own human body animals and as
stringy objects and we would like to recognise that we would like to somehow express
these articulation and the deformation
background clutter looking for face may not be so simple here especially for any face
recognition algorithms
and it's because this world is very cluttered and it makes it interesting and fun
visually and beyond so we would like to recognise and categorize objects in in this
you know all this variations it was quite quite challenging task for the computer vision
scientists to deal with the recognition of objects and in terms of the history of
our field people started looking at this problem of cell is a single object recognition
especially those objects that are relatively plain relatively textured with a lot of with a
lot of the characteristic patch appearances and and some of the objects will have a
rather planner frossard and some of the
david lowe in nineteen ninety nine propose one of the first really quite successful
algorithm for single object recognition and from then on there was a whole series of
papers that have pushed this problem as far as as they can and it's been
very successful that some of them are even put into robots now
to recognise single objects
in terms of object classification we face
all the problems that single object
recognition interfaces from the viewpoint variables to illumination to scale and everything and on top
of that we're dealing with intra class variation and this is a typical
problem you will hear in computer vision how to recognise chairs
look at this i'm not so sure if humans can tell the or chairs and
this is the kind of
of course this is pushing the problem a little bit to the extreme but it
really demonstrate how tough we have to deal with the heart of this problem is
how do we deal with this intraclass variability so
are they object class categorisation and classification focused on some of the most
useful probably and
to have one note that misbehaves and violates running intersection
so this sort of tells us not aggressive junction trees this graph does not have
a junction tree
so we need to understand what types of graphs do have junction trees
because those are be the kinds of graphs that we can deal with
and in the end we can see that we can convert any graph into a
form in which it does have a junction tree by by a certain process of
adding edges and this is is actually bringing us useful full circle back to the
elimination story
OK so
what turns out to be key here is is the notion of triangulation
and again this is is a very intuitive notion
all you mean is that
the graph basically consists a bunch of triangles pasted together
so this graph is not triangulated whereas this one is
and a bit more precisely what it means is whenever you have a cycle of
length for a cycle of length four
or possibly longer what you need is you need to have watson's according need to
cut it into a triangle and keep doing that until you just get triangles everywhere
so here if i start cutting this and then cut that cut that i'm adding
edges here
number that's key when i add edges i am changing the complexity of the graph
but if i do that actually get triangulated graph where all of these four cycles
here have been cut by a court in half
so what's key here this is deep graph theoretic result we won't go into details
you can show that a graph has a junction tree if and only if
it is triangulated
so that sort of gives this intuition why we run into problems here
we ran into problems because that's the simplest example of a graph that is not
right there is this cycle that you can walk around the should be an edge
one of these edges should be there to make the triangles it's not there and
then lo and behold we ran into problems we failed running intersection when we tried
to make a junction tree
right so this is a very nice results because it has an important practical consequence
what it says well i can always make a junction tree from any graph this
graph does not have a junction tree
because it's not triangulated it's got these four cycles but this gives us a constructive
procedure in this this is a very practical method to actually make a junction tree
and this is what's known as the junction tree algorithm
so any questions about triangulation junction trees
sort of what we're after here before we jump into
the junction tree algorithm
you should doing more
that's a very good question no there is not
as i mentioned earlier
this is the problem of finding the best elimination ordering is NP hard
and this problem of finding an optimal triangulation is actually equivalent to that problem
this sort of these edges are being added are very much like the edges that
are being added during an elimination algorithm
that that's the connection
so in general finding the best triangulation
o come back and discuss in more detail later that's a hard problem but as
before they're very good heuristics that are used in practice for finding reasonable approximations to
so this is the junction tree algorithm
it's a very nice of them due to low attendance beagle halter
and it's quite simple
this is the high level it's quite simple
so there's four steps
you can be given as input some undirected graph
the graph may or may not be triangulated
if it's triangulated you're happy because you know that you can then go off and
make a junction tree at least in principle
if not then you have to go around and you have to add edges to
get rid of things like four cycles you have to make it look like a
triangle everywhere
right so going back to that question here on the same at the edges in
some way
it's going to be notion of the optimal way in which to do that but
let's not worry about that for the moment that's actually hard think about we add
edges in some way to make the graph triangulated
so let's
look at this example this is a pretty simple example of a sort of segment
of the lattice or grid model
and we can see this graph is untriangulated because we've got all these four cycles
so the first step would be triangulated
so i could for instance at edges here here here and here
so adding these four edges
for some reason i've also added another edge here between two and eight
what did i do that was necessary
so think about this graph if
suppose i deleted this edge here this arc
with that graph be triangulated
why why not
whereas the is not going to be triangulated
so without that edge you have to be careful there the cycle by adding edges
i made a new cycle two
august two four eight six two
that's the four cycle
it doesn't have a direct record if i don't have this arc i could have
to go to a node five that doesn't count
i need something directly that cuts it in half to make a triangle
so you have to add that extra art
so triangulation can be a bit tricky because when you add edges you can make
it's size in this example it's
toy but it's already getting a bit tricky
it's also worth thinking about this is this is not the best triangulation that i
did this is just a natural one but there is actually a better triangulation whereby
better i mean
adding fewer edges making the cliques
not grows quickly
OK so
we've done that step where we're triangulated and now our previous results is that we
all males together
confer conspiracy make you feel
everywhere inside zero
to nontrivial results
all right so now we know that the field inside is zero
so this is what are
smaller than are
let's not go are
larger than are
everything i told you hold for sphere which is outside
this hollow
everything all the field here must be the same everywhere on the surface the eighty
eight parallel and parallel
so i can write down again that four pi
or scratches the surface area
the electric field vector must be q inside divided by actually zero but this q
is that q
a lot of zero
this charge inside
so now
i know
the electric field e
in terms of its magnitude
is q
divided by four pi
are square
actually non-zero
and we know the direction
if it is positive of course it is radially outward and this is negative is
radially inwards
and this
is unknown
all result
we've seen this before
if i had put all the charge
right here at the middle of the centre we would have gotten exactly the same
and so we've seen that before
in other words where the charge is uniformly distributed over here
what are the chances all of it exactly at the centre of the sphere that
makes no difference for the field as long as you outside the sphere
if you plot the electric field
as a function of are
and here's capitol are
and this is the
the field strength
then you will get that the electric field is zero insight
john stewart maximum value
and this falls off
as one of our square
proportional to one of our script
if i go back to the situation that the
charged that the electric field inside
is zero
you may say
isn't that a little bit of a cheat
there is no charge inside but have you really use the charge outside
and if you have
use it how did you use it well i have used it
i use it for my symmetry arguments
the symmetry arguments
take into account
that the charge is uniformly distributed
if the charge on this if had not been uniformly distributed i could not use
the symmetry argument
and therefore the electric field inside would in fact not having zero if there is
more chance this here then there is there in the field inside the sphere is
not zero
so i have it was all the charge
by using my
symmetry arguement
god's law
and coulomb law in a way i the same law
they both link the electric field
with the charge q
he is the fact
that the electric force
falls off
as one of our square
if the electric field strengths did not as one of four square
goals law wouldn't even hold
and the electric field inside
this uniformly charged you wouldn't be zero
so what is the meaning of consequence of the fact
electric forces fall off as one of our square
gravitational forces also fall off
as one of four square
therefore if you take a planet if it existed
which is a hollow spherical a spherical planet with hollow inside
it means there would be no
gravitational field inside that whole planet
so if you were there
there will be no gravitational
force on new
david is spherical
if that planets were purely local
the gravitational field inside
i would not be
you say well big deal was a to one we always take planet
and then it sort of far outside the planet we put all the mass and
we consider it as the point
it's not a big deal for you
it's not a big deal for me but it was a big deal for notes
he intuitively senses
that it was correct
that if you have a planet
uniform mass distribution
that you can consider it as a point mass
long outside the planet
but it took him twenty years to prove it
and he finally published his results
it will take is now thirty seconds
he didn't have access to gauss law
came about a hundred years later
but the net result is
that you see in front of you
that if you have uniformly charged distribution
you can draw a parallel with gravity
that it's you get the same electric field outside
that you
i would have gotten if all the charge
is at one location
at the centre
this is
spherical symmetry
number one that's the easiest symmetry
that we have in
o eight o two
now i will present you with the second form of symmetry which is a flat
horizontal plane
and i want you to work out most of it would help you a little
bit to set up
suppose we have a plane
which is very very large
think of it for now is infinitely large
it doesn't exist of course infinitely large
and i put on this plane
and i put
a certain amount of
charge density
which i call sigma
is an amount of charge q
for every is
so only a certain number of cool
per square metre
energy uniformly distributed the whole plane everywhere has the same number of coulombs per square
metre micro cules will not cornwall's whatever you prefer
this is a play which is huge
you're being asked
what is the electric field anywhere in space
just like we before
we ask what is the electric field anywhere inside the sphere and anywhere outside the
sphere now i want to know what it is anywhere in the vicinity of this
it is now you pick
clever girl surface
the answer pops out
very quickly
if you choose this sphere
as you go service you dead in the water you get nowhere because there is
no spherical symmetry
i will define for you that
go surface
things can be brought to bear on actual behavioral data from human subjects to show
yes this really is a way to think about basic learning and inference behavior and
and then will
go to most more interesting problems like the problem i started with learning concepts from
examples which is an area where we're not we're going beyond just textbook bayesian statistics
basically to the frontiers of machine learning it's an area where machine learning has made
a lot of progress but where there's still a lot of progress to be made
in coming up with more human-like systems
and then probably some next time we'll go to these large scale systems of knowledge
like intuitive theories
OK and i understand people sometimes like to ask questions so feel free to
to jump in these lectures compared to the other lectures will probably be a little
bit less
for the technical specifics partly because i'm trying to build on on what i think
are technical
things you've already learned show you things you can do with them but you know
that feel free to ask jump if if there's something that seems like i'm not
being clear not sure exactly what technical idea i'm referring to
now these this idea of viewing cognition as probabilistic inference is much bigger than any
of the work that i have to tell you about here in the work that
i've been involved in this is side i prepared for NIPS tutorial a couple of
years ago on the same topic
and i was just you know taking all the different areas of cognitive science where
people have made progress recently by viewing them as as probabilistic inference i didn't have
time to update the slide since two thousand seven so apologies to those of you
who started working on these things since two thousand seven but i wouldn't have had
room for names on here anyway the point is this is an extremely active exciting
research area and it's only getting more active so it's good time to to get
interested in it
what i tell you about here just a couple of examples from work that i
did mostly with tom griffiths we which was which is again trying to look at
the basic cognitive capacities that can be
analyzed from the point of view of almost textbook bayesian statistics really really simple elementary
things that you from machine learning point of view they are that's trivial but there
are the place you have to start to show that these ideas actually apply
human cognition i won't go into some of the history here but there's a long
history in psychology of going back and forth between viewing the mind as a kind
of intuitive statistician and people being extremely skeptical of the idea so within cognitive psychology
there's a lot of work to be done initially to just established the groundwork that
that these ideas from from probability theory were
appropriate and useful for describing basic cognition
so i give a couple of examples on one will start off with an example
from from causal learning this is again a basic thing this isn't just about bayesian
statistics one of the basic things statisticians want to do is establish reliable relationships between
variables you might just be interested in the correlation although increasingly statisticians we don't just
want correlation they want to know is actually a causal relation cannot intervene and manipulating
make something happen
but you know here's again textbook problem you have data that comes in the form
two by two
set up like this there some
variable c and some other variable e there are binary and you observe
instances where c either happened or didn't happen either happen it didn't happen and you're
interested in whether or not see causes so you know example might be whether injecting
some chemical causes mice to express certain gene that's
semi scientific example but it the experiments that have been done with people are you
give them data sort of as if they were assigned to doing an experiment a
data coming in either in the table are online
and you basically ask them to make a judgement about that question on a scale
from zero to one hundred
traditionally people have been so clear to me if you if you want to know
what if you might think if you're thinking you look at the question does c
cause e
great judgement on a scale from zero to one hundred
and if your first thought as well i'm not sure exactly what you mean that
can mean different things that is part of the point that i'm trying to make
the psychologists weren't originally very clear about that but now that we've we've tried at
that the each component of Y as apoisson distribution the corresponding component of A
Xhas its meanand why is that wellbasically this represents attenuation and superposition that's
what's going on and that's captured exactly inthat in thatthe model so providing your counters the the
whichever you are collecting thephotons in they don't have any dead times and providing things stationary
and so on and this is a pretty pretty good modelso we have
our X isdoingtwo difference spaces herecause X is in the body so that'sthree-dimensional
coordinateswithintwo- or three-dimensional cordinates within the body indexed by S and then
the arrayof detectedphoco photons is measured in the space in which you are collecting the
it the the photonsand I'll call thatT so A T S is the A T S is the meanamount
of sorry it's the mean number of counts detected atT from the
units source and the unit time atXs so that's a precise physicalinterpretation capturing all
those effectsand we've you knowwe've got some reasonably good modelsfor whatthose
numbers are now how is it possibleif you everthought about tomography butI think this
cartoon might help a little bitthis is a two-dimensional cross-section so this is
looking down on the patient's head if you like and thistwo hotspots different degree
ofhotness andhere's thegamma camera it's aone-dimensional camerain this case looking at
the patient collectingphotonsin these binsand youcan seethe pattern of intensity there
and whatI what I've got in this model isthat there'sthis essentially rectilinear
propagation together with somespread which is to do with the photons interacting with body
tissue and avoiding spread out so I get on the basis of that view of
the this body I get thisand of coursethat's not enough to infer very much if
Istopped moving the camera I start building something up
okay so canseeas I go aroundI'm getting a view from each direction
and the patternI'm seeing is obviously a representation ina slightly strange space
of what is going on in hereso these high spots here for example
came when the camera wasover here somewhereand down here andthese two
hotspots were exactly in line andthe higherone was nearerso that's why it's hotterthan there okay
so this is this is the dataactually there's no I thinkthere's no noise in
this butthis is the the mean of the datathis is along-run data
what I wnat to doisto use these data to inferthose those sourcesso clearly it's
not trivial but I hope it's believablethat is possible because there is there is
a transformation from this spacethis is the X space to this space which is the
the Y spacethis is what they actually look like in reality this is ascan of apelvis and I've transpose
it so this is the angle and this is the linear dimension of the detector
and what you seen basically is superimposedsign wavesand essentially as for a single point
source in the body you get an attenuatedsign wave as you goas
you move the camera around andwhat you what you observe is a superposition in
all thosetime wavesplus noise and this is this is an example so this is
calledthe signogram for obvious reasons the kind of priors we use well we've tried
various things and sometimesgaussian priors but this is quite a good choice this this
prior it's a sort ofmedium informative kind of prior which is encoding something
ratherslightly unspecific about the smoothness of the truthif you had
is sort ofthis log coshif you had a square then this wouldbe a gaussian prior