this is the
energy per second that we are consuming
what is this
this is the energy per second the power station is delivering
two us
what is this
that's lost energy
if i screw or the producer
in this table
it goes into the universe is gone
sorry economy
the men's that we try to make this
as small as possible
this is the power that is available
but you get the loss of power in terms of the minus sign here
you get less
in boston
so how can you make this i square are low
what is the
the resistance of the wire
that is rho which is the resistivity
time the length of the wire
divided by the cross section of the wire
so you have several options
you could make a very large and very thick copper wire that expensive
you would also make the wires out of goals has lower resistivity
than copper
that's also expensive
people are thinking of making these
transmission wires
of superconducting material they have to call them very low temperatures
it's outrageously expensive
that's the way you could get
the resistance down
that's not look
the current
what can we do is the current
suppose we consume
hundred megawatts
not unreasonable number
so we are consuming
one hundred mag
and just for the sake of the argument suppose at the
the potential is wonderful
so v
it's hundredfold
what now is the current
current time potential
it's me power
so my current is now
and is
that the potential be
in the wire
is a hundred thousand four
a thousand times higher now the current
is only a thousand mps
is the same
our both cases in my consuming iterate a hundred million joules per second
i square already lost on the way from the power station we
is a million times slower in this case then in that case
because i is a thousand times lower
and the lost because i square
so now you understand why
electricity when it is transported
from one place to another
why does it done
at the highest
voltage possible
when you get to boston
you obviously got to do something about this enormous potential
because if you were to deliver
a hundred thousand potential difference there
the population in boston
will execute itself so now you've got to come down in voltage which you do
with transformers we'll talk about that later in the course
so you bring it down to a comfortable voltage which is
in the united states about hundred and
and falls in europe it's two twenty
now comes the question
how high can you make
he of a
the higher you could make it
the last lost that would be
along the way
well you've got to stay away from the
breakdown electric field which is the three million volt per meter
if at the surface of these cables
you get three million volt meter you get corona discharge that's a big loss want
to stay away from the
and so typical cables
have about a radius
are there is no are is the radius of the cable
of about two centimeters
given the cross sectional area
i think about ten to the minus three meters square that's correct
and the
potential v
is roughly three hundred kilowatts
and with that configuration used a
comfortably below the
electric fields
of three million volt meter
you don't get the corona discharge
the length of the cable al
there were something like thousand kilometres
not an unreasonable number
thousand kilometres distance from
if we get our electricity from niagara falls
not a reasonable number
you can calculate now
what the
resistance of that cable would be
but that was resistance are
because times l divided by age
take up
that has a resistivity of two times ten to the minus eight
as i units
we have length of ten to six meters of cable
and we have a
cross sectional area
ten to the minus three
square metres
so that
thousand kilometre cable
we only have the a resistance of
twenty arms
and to make the numbers of the easy
if we
however current
it's a of three hundred and years
then the power
the power station produces
we take the three hundred kilowatts for now
it would be
three hundred cannonballs
three hundred and three years
and that is about
ninety megawatts that's close to my hundred that i had in mind earlier
you can calculate now with the losses
the losses i squared or
you know are twenty owns
you know i
the three hundred mps
so you'll find out that you have about two megawatts
that's not bad
two out of ninety
so we have about two percent energy loss in transportation
you can also calculate know what the differences in potential between the power station
in boston
a minus b xi are
you know i three hundred and
OK so could conclusions about some work that we have temporal observations post popularity dropoff
follows a power law
topological observations is we find parallels in degree distribution cascade sizes and the stars are
much more common than chains
and we also generate had to cascade generating model
based on epidemiology the best are based in epidemiology allergy that matches frequent cascades and
size power laws
so the next work where will point two in case studies
it has to do with outbreak detection
so the idea is that there are two two isomorphic problems there's first the problem
of finding sources of contamination in water network
and then then i similar problem is finding hot stories and blogs and the the
goal in
the protection and we don't the water network is they want to minimize the time
time to detection of the population affected
and we also want so we want to be able to maximize the probability of
detection and also minimizes his replacement costs we have a whole lot never just plan
censoring everybody's house
there are only
the decay cost money to put sensors in the water network
and since similarly
we want to minimize the number of blogs and we have to we have to
look at read every day two
to actually get a good idea what's going on in the blogosphere and get in
any given idea for everybody else finds out about it
so they call this algorithm cell and
is that
so is the host pronounced
during on this
OK so
you only read the paper did not
to the actual acronym pronounced so given graph
comment budget budget sensors and data on how to commit contamination spread over the network
which should be
already made adjacency matrix and
in the blog graph
we want to minimize the time to detect the outbreak or the time that
the time that an outbreak occurs in the blogosphere we want to be able to
see what's happening before before it's old news
so some of our algorithm main idea is that uses some on some modularity and
lazy evaluation and the full citation is here
and they did
experiments on both water water water contamination networks and and blogosphere
and they found that the using the self algorithm is better than any heuristic methods
of blog outlinks blog and links
the number of posts in random
i think it has to do with the size of the cascade
and that if
the minimum number of people that have already linked to it before before we have
we actually read read that long
for that topic
so according to the self algorithm the best ten blogs to read
our instapundit done server and some others and
so the
here the here the scores
the self algorithm identifies and here is number of posts number of in links
blog out links and all out links which includes
links to
web pages that are necessarily blogs
so some interesting things to note is that
is it is in this argument finding that have small cost that is that the
number of posts is is small
so we don't have to read that many posts to get somebody to get some
of these blogs
and we would still be able to
identify some hot stories before before they catch on
everybody else
is not
is this
this show was
he was
right thank you for bringing that up i put i knew it the best in
quotes for reasons that are
right so
not everybody spends
the whole work reading blogs right
all right here
if you have another thing to note is that michelle malkin has twelve thousand in
links so
chances are she starts a lot of arguments or some sort of so something like
that you have a lot of people reading lots of people linking to our
and therefore
despite by nature of having started a lot of cascades
despite her having started a lot of cascades you might
i have
got the highest score in this in this method because it's no time she picks
things up in no time because she is the initiator of lot of
so the next
next case study is how can we extract communities and
first we
the first paper that all
go over in brief is using PCA on structure
so we have the cascades take on different shapes there again served by frequency
but how can we identify how can we use cascades to identify communities
and the way we do that is to perform PCA on cascade types who have
a sparse matrix
do we take all night online thousand cascade types we have some isolated post
two no cascade
three star etcetera and take longer count
helpless won and project onto two principal components
and we were able to observe that the content of blogs and cascade behavior often
related that we have projecting on two principal components musings some hand labeling we have
conservative blogs and we humorous blogs
so we we generally think of our our principal components in this experiment is corresponding
to stars and chains allow the humorous blogs have very short very short stars
and the conservative blogs general generally have a lot of very very long trees
of arguments
and the full citation is here last year's ICWSM and so i'm not going to
OK thank you i should warn you all i'll have nothing whatsoever to say about
the the optics of light
what i'm going to talk about today is some work by my group on unsupervised
learning for language
i'm not going to make any cognitive claims whatsoever in this talk but i'm going
to on cognitive analogy briefly so please forgive me
as humans there are two ways that we learn languages
you've probably done both of these
one is to learn a language in the classroom that look something like this
you tighten
rules you get shown examples you told how everything works and you get all the
irregular verb forms listed for you and so on
at some point you take a test and you have to to do some combination
of regurgitation and generalisation
OK it turns out for humans is it works great
but this is one of the ways we have and this is basically what supervised
NLP is like
the other way we learn languages as humans
something like this
and in this case basically the data washes every you will this is the kid
the data washes over you and you sort out for yourself what's going on underneath
this is what unsupervised NLP
should be like and could be like and i'm interested in building systems like the
system on the right
pick apart and figure out for themselves what kinds of structure is going on underneath
my goal in this talk in this talk i'm going to
kind of illustration by by several examples
i'm going to talk about inducing various kinds of linguistic structure that are not in
the data
for each example is going to be slightly different but they're all going to show
the property that kind of structure i'm interested in is some kind of complex linguistic
in one case this will be syntactic parsing in one case become reference in last
will be translation
these are going to be kind of rich interacting combinatorial combinatorial structures
and we take a lot of data and trying to figure out what's going on
underneath that data in a way that's not annotated in the data itself
the characteristics those are basically the characteristics of the problem
the characteristics of the solutions that i'm going to sketch they all have something in
common and the thread that's going title together is some combination of incremental or hierarchical
learning and i mean that very vague way because what that means is going to
vary from case to case but i find this to be a very important tying
thread that you either can't or don't want to learn everything all at once
this also the solution is i'm going to sketch are going to involve a very
careful and often iterative choice of what to model
and sometimes even more importantly what not to model
so we'll see a a couple cases where you can model everything you don't want
to model everything and one good way to make progress this works very well in
our group is to kind of look at what your system is doing build something
simple and then kind of only introduce the variables that you absolutely must model
so from here on out going to talk about several concrete examples
going first talk about the task of unsupervised grammar refinement
this is
related to but not exactly the same as grammar induction of talk about this this
i will talk about coreference resolution and finally some work on translation
so hopefully many of you were at mike's invited talk earlier
and you talk a little bit about syntactic analysis
syntactic parsing i'm going to talk about the same
the same problem
the goal here is to take sentences and remember most sensors are actually very complicated
so i'll show simple examples but please don't take from this that the examples in
practice are simple so here's the basically an average length sentence from newswire hurricane emily
howled toward mexico's caribbean coast on sunday packing a hundred and thirty five mile-per-hour winds
and torrential rain and causing panic in cancun where frightened tourists squeezed into musty shelters
OK this is not he saw the cat right if it were he saw the
cat this would be easy
this is hard because for example those winds and rain and panic but it's not
all the same
it's not a conjunction of three things here and you need to sort out what
the various pieces of the sentence are and how they combined together and that's going
to be the job of the syntactic parser why do we do this we do
this we do this because it's kind of an important intermediary step between
surface language and semantics and is also these kinds of tree structures are very useful
for a lot of problems like machine translation
OK so back to simple examples but please if there's nothing else remember from this
about syntactic processing please remember that the reality is very complicated and it's not always
he was right period
that's going to be the training example here
in particular
if you want to get a grammar and you would like to be passing these
structures we you might look at them and say those look awful lot like context
free grammars to me
and then you think well where my going to get a context free grammar well
i try to brainstorm one in terms of the work very well i could have
a bunch of annotated sentences like this where somebody has been kind enough to painstakingly
mark out with the syntactic structures are like this to say well there's a noun
phrase and it contains the proposition and contains the pronoun and so on
OK if we had a bunch of these and we do these are called treebanks
we could read off what the rules are from the grammar so if i had
this tree i would read have well there is one instance of a going to
sentence there is one instance of a sentence going to announce phrase verb phrase followed
by a period and so on
i'd like to emphasise that if you just take for example we have forty thousand
past english sentences and i look get just the noun phrases alone there are thirty
or forty kinds of noun phrase rules there are ten thousand and you find new
ones as you look at new sentences and this is because of all kinds of
phenomena interacting punctuation and all kinds of modification and all kinds of complexities that don't
show up in the simple sentences and their entourage and combinatorial
OK so but you could take this these forty thousand sentences you could read off
in the centre of mass frame
before the collision because after the collision there's nothing there zero
in case of a completely inelastic collision
there's no kinetic energy left
in the centre of mass frame
so we go to the the centre of mass frame
so we first have to calculate what you want
well u one
equals we one
the centre of of mass
and we know the centre of mass is
it's right there
and if you
or subtraction
it is by no means difficult
you will find and two
five by m one
plus and two
the one
you check that i hope
and now we go to
calculate you
we want to know what the
the centre of mass one
that of course is v two
minus the centre of mass
this was zero
it is and what
divided by n one
plus and two
thank you want to the difference is only one upstairs
and the
now we are going to
calculate the kinetic energy
in the centre of mass frame
that equals
one half
of n one
you want create this one half
thank you to create that's all we have
before the collision occurs
by the way this is not my this is a plus sign
and this is minds
this one comes this way
and this one was in that way
now i can i can calculate that for you you know you want to you
know you too
suppose of hindsight makes no difference because they cancel any out what is going to
one have
divided by and one
plus and two
the long creek
and this is exactly the same way that we have there
so what you see here
if you allow me for having to get some steps algebra
you have to do a little massaging to get from here to here
you see here this is the kinetic energy before the collision and all that kinetic
removed went
two heat
is the maximum you can never lose
and this is what we call
internal kinetic energy of the system
so going to the centre of mass is then you can always immediately
calculate what the maximum heat is that you can expect from a collision
we can take a very special case
and we can take two
going to infinity is like having a piece of body
i slam on the wall
get stuck
and what is the maximum
it that you can
produce that's all the energy there is
if m two
become infinitely high then
and one can be ignored
two councils and two you get one half feet
and one
he one created
that's obvious
that's completely trivial i have a piece of body slammed against the wall it has
a certain amount of kinetic energy where you see the your reference frame or in
the reference frame of the center of mass it's immediately obvious that all the kinetic
energy is lost
and that's exactly what you see comes out of these equations where do you go
to the centre of mass already do it from
twenty six one hundred
and i would like to return to the
air traffic and do
several completely inelastic collisions
with you again
we have to assume that momentum
is conserved
never is completely that we can come close
and we will
i have two cars
so we're going to not completely elastic
you know that
so they hate each other
and they get stuck
i get a certain
velocity which i put into the first car
it's the second car
and it gets stuck
and i see there
what might be primus
see there on the blackboard
but if the two are the same
after one year
one and one here that's the ratio
so the outcome is that the prime
must be one half
so this must be
p one
now i have mass which is half the other one
i into the other
they get stuck together
and now i get
divided by one plus two
i get
one third notice in both cases i get a plus sign
that's of course obvious
if i blow into something
and they stick together to continue in the same direction
so now i will do the timing in exactly the same way that i did
except that now
i have completely inelastic collision
i don't have the time t one
i will have time
the prime
the cars have a slightly different
two thirty seven
plus and minus one gram
and i have one
that is four hundred
and seventy four
plus and minus one gram not too different from this
i have
two of these guys
and i have one of these
and first i'm going to slam
these two on two
each other
and so when they
i expect the speech
to be half
so i get a certain amount
p one
thirty one
the prime will be
twice as long because
this goes down by a factor of two
so when i multiply
this number
by one half
i would like to get number back
he i get
time for this car
the first one to come in
this means time
when they continue to get up to speed is
three times slower
so this time will be three times higher
with far fewer number measurement that you thought where possible we can actually
i guess the quantum state of the system because you can use the low rank
structure of the system to do it
OK so what the girls did was to use the tools of matrix completion to
actually show that you could solve this problem
and he did much more
OK so these are problems like this in quantum mechanics and people actually using these
techniques to actually interfere quantum states from
quantum state tomography measurements
OK so
i'm done with matrix completion in the second part of the talk i will talk
a little bit about robust PCA but this part is of course much shorter because
we introduce most of what we need now
OK so first of all it and if you add noise to
matrix you could say yes it's interesting to recover matrix which is exactly going from
those less data but in practice and i'm not exactly low rank plus i have
no data alexa like the ratings are contaminated with no is it would be a
pity if the whole theory we could not accommodate
inexact measurements and so what you do when you have an exact measurement you do
what you always do we don't enforce
equality constraints of course now you DIY's inexact so you can only enforce an approximate
fit to the data among all
low rank among all major is compatible with data you can pick the one with
minimum nuclear norm and when you do this things work that is you get an
error which is proportional to the noise level in another way of saying this is
that one matrix completion from those less data of curves then if you have a
small amount of nicely will be small as well
it's a big field of research again by no mean we are the only one
to work on this many statisticians including martin wainwright who will be here i think
next week or tomorrow forgotten
who has done
a lot of important work in this area
right so we can actually we require recovery matrices steeply from from noisy data
OK so now i would like to come back to this matrix problem to motivate
the second part of the talk and the reason i started to work on this
is because the first time i gave a talk about matrix completion there was a
gentleman in the audience who raised his hand and say you know many something you
forget and the thing you forget the that there's lots of bogus ratings
in this data matrix
he said i don't know why but there are people who enter ratings have nothing
to do with their own preferences
and so is is only dangerous that use these ratings to actually predict all the
ratings when these ratings are completely bogus
and i said yes it is it is very dangerous i didn't notice so what
can i do
so now we have a slightly more complicated problem where we have actually part of
an observation about the low rank matrix in the netflix matrix but we also have
a sparse error term on top of it which corresponds to entries that are completely
OK so i need to deal with this
so the problem is now i don't want to make noisy matrix completion robust because
of the small additive noise like i want to make it will buses have very
bad stuff that could happen
now this motivates us to introduce a problem that i like a lot which is
the blind deconvolution problem which i'm going to state again as simply as i can
in this problem
we've got a data matrix which is available to me it's available to the statistician
always machine learner and it's some of the low rank matrix
and the sparse matrix
right so what that says is that what you see is is some of the
lowest matrix and sparse matrix so what do i mean by this means that this
is a low rank matrix that you cannot observe because some entries have been corrected
can the corrections is exactly carried by zeta
the only thing you do is you observe the some of these two matrices
and what i'm playing would be nice to recover l and e accurately
again seems impossible and he would be great to do it because if i could
do it i could i could detect the raining and apply matrix completion to such
good ratings and complete my matrix accurately
OK so it would be great but what would be great it would be great
essentially because had we do dimensionality reduction so typically
what we all learn is principal component analysis and i'm sure everybody knows what it
is what you have is you've got a data matrix and which is the low
rank matrix plus
perturbation and so what we think of this is if the points
we have a low rank matrix and we look at the columns
of this matrix
and what we think about when we the principal component we look at the column
vectors and we say well you know in fact this column vectors live in very
high dimensional but actually clustered
along the low dimensional space
and the goal is to recover low dimensional space and the way you do this
is by principal component analysis as i'm sure you all know so what you do
is you say well how my good to look at the recovers the low dimensional
in this high dimensional data set well i'm going to try to find a matrix
which has more rank which is as close as possible to the data matrix you
gave me and it looks like a horrible communism communist
combinatorial problem because we have a rank constraint which is absolutely and friendly but this
is the only hard combinatorial problem i know how to solve because i know the
and the solution is just calculate the SVD
don't small singular values and you're done
OK and that's what we all learn to every undergraduate
taking a course in statistics at stanford
contained into the characteristic vector just say
just looking into the characteristic vector just look whether it is zero or not is
close to zero
but in so doing we are actually
we're not using a lot of information
because the components in the characteristic vector this is an empirical finding
the second thing a lot of information about the structure of the class
actually we we so empirically that
the components of the characteristic vector provide us with information about the centrality of the
objects within the class
so the more central in one sense
the object is within this class to higher would be it's components
this is pretty interesting because it allows us to
there is empirical observation not
but we empirically founded several occasions several different locations
this means that
we have an empirical
and heuristic way
for extracting the prototype from the cluster
in a purely pairwise certain framework is not
if you working within the central clustering framework
object is represented in terms of feature vector
we we get the cluster
so we get on a cloud on the one-dimensional space
then we can compute the same prototype by for example computing the centroid
the centre of mass whatever the club that would be your product
well if you walk in the only pairwise set
you don't have the notion of the centre of the notion of control
for example if you're objects
are characterized in terms of graph
what is the centroid and graph
so actually in the graph you really to have been some attempts at defining this
notion of try but you know it's war heuristic what we do
if we have at our disposal feature vector
if this is true
so this means that when i find clustering dominance set if i want to extract
the representative prototypes for four percent i just i can just look at the
so the characteristic vector and defined the prototype is the component corresponded to the highest
this empirically says that
object is more central for the world than the others
so to convince ourselves to of course we have to
you with the actual real
we did some experiments either synthetic or not
we generated two thousand nine season goes to gaussian processes and of course
if we start replicator dynamics from different starting points you may end up with different
so what we did was to run the replicator dynamics from
randomly chosen kind
and for example it converges to this class
this is the dominant
then we run the algorithm starting from a very distant point and then we get
we end up with the other class
so if we
around the replicator dynamics from randomly generated by this example end that we got this
one or this one
let me show you the
these doesn't
OK this is
the plot of the characteristic vector
of this dominance here
and this is the plot of the characteristic vector this so we just blocked
values in the convergence factors
so you can see
this blue one corresponds to this
set of course we've all zeros here which correspond to this one
but the nice thing is that you don't have that distribution of
the more central is the point
the higher is the value so we have a sort of bell shape structure
so in one sense if i if i want to extract the representative for this
class i just take the the highest value here that would be represented in one
the most central one
know how this is the same happens here
this is zero this is the class zero then you have this bell shape function
so this is important practical applications for example suppose that we have a large database
of images
and i know you horses dogs whatever we want to cluster the images into categories
category down category or whatever
then we have now a query image
we want to know which category seem
there's a horse dog whatever
we might want to compare this image with all the images in the dataset is
quite time consuming
you i want to
compared to query image with the product instead
if we have a problem for large data datasets will allow us to
to save a lot of time
for example you can these images the from
well there are several ways to do that for example you can
for example
think about shape actually
this is a bit misleading because we never said that we are not talking about
the images and then we have similarity between images
so we don't transform the image
and to point is the key point
as we are working on completing very one set
what we need to do is a measure of similarity between
so there are several ways which we can compare
images once you have that can learn from
thing which is worth noting is that
remember the starting point and stress in the spine which is quite important
we started from the beginning
from a very different question we ask ourselves what is the cluster then we derive
the notion
while the other approaches asking different different question how can i divide organised
partition is a partition the talking to partition the data set into the best possible
OK if we do this way i mean if you the partition one
we have no way of solving
very important problem in computer vision which is the
background foreground color
how can extract the foreground objects from the background and it's the particular case of
image segmentation
way which is different from one i four
we're not dividing the image into different segments just extracting
not just from that
so now there's is evidence
both psychological
is logically that
they were
visual systems quite good
in extracting foreground from background
you for example in this
receptors scenes
you have some not
noisy lines was we can
extract very easily history circles here
the shape
and even if we are not here
history circus
but that is about problems
if we take this example
and i should say the reason i'm putting this
image processing in
it is because the what we've sort of traditionally called image processing has
really evolved and merged in many ways with lots of other activities
so going back we've had a lot of work traditionally in the signal processing community
on this topic
and more recently in computational photography
where fact computational photography more lasses image processing which is published and siggraph
right so
that's another way to think about it so one of the key concepts has recently
become very popular is this idea of non-local means some of you may have heard
about it
not going on the computer vision we've had
algorithms have been developed in the in the vision community for anisotropic diffusion world
probably familiar to some extent or another with these things of the bilateral filter which
is now found applications in lots of places including graphics
i'm going to graphics there's been the idea of moving least squares
four interpolating three d scan data into smooth surfaces
people have been using the same graphics for a long long time and it turns
out we've been using an image processing people business and using similar idea which calling
it different things
and then you have ideas from machine learning and statistics including boosting spectral clustering and
various other concepts that have found their way into
well we traditionally called image processing
and also in applied math
fairly recently there's been a lot of interest in fact the siam journal on imaging
sciences new journal that publishes image processing things with the a heavy mathematical so really
there's been a convergence of ideas across a lot of different fields and hopefully
my presentation will give you a little rough idea of how these ideas all relate
to each other
OK so let me at least from my spirit perspective give you an overview of
the computational problems in imaging that we deal with so typically you have a real
scene which gets blurred and down sampled and noisy
and the measurements may look like this and then what we might call inverse problems
or reconstruction problems could be
just denoising could be upscaling or interpolation could be learning
for the purposes of this talk the concentrating on the denoising problems but a lot
of what i say will have applications in fact direct use
in a bunch of these other areas as well
so the framework is general enough to sort of subsume algorithms in all of these
different applications
so let me get down to the specifics of the common
framework for all of these concepts is basically nonparametric ways of estimating functions
o or point estimation procedures as as they are known in statistics
the problem is in data fitting problem so let's imagine like i said that the
problem of denoising we are given an image
or video and you like to reduce the amount of noise present in the data
so let's say why i here are the pixels
better noisy
e of x y
our pixel values at some position x i and e here is the air so
the data to model is like this so as i said these are the samples
this is what we call is what we call the regression function the function we
should try to fit
and the noise we just assumed to be zero mean i i d noise what
we make no other distributional assumptions so i'm not assuming the noises gaussians neural plasticity
and or anything just that
so if you look at this picture the idea is that you have a bunch
of data points
and what you like to do is to estimate the value of the function at
particular points
given this data so now this data i denoted here y one y two through
y and this data could be the entire image
or it could be just some patch of the image right so essentially what you're
interested in is
estimating the value of one pixel
given either the whole image or some patches which
and the particular form of the index is going to remain unspecified for the time
being and this is actually part of the strength of this is that we are
not using a model based approach in typical
traditional approaches and in image processing what we've done is we've sort of assume some
and I said, Rick I need some help
and he put me in touch with with the
top researchers, who were developing melanoma therapeutics and and these guys had some very, very much more
interesting offerings, but none of them could tell me which one was best for me.
and that was the challenge, that's where the guesswork comes in.
what I wanted like any good AI researcher would want is that at each point in
my cancer journey
to be able to have all of the world's knowledge and resources together with the decision
tools to be able to make the optimal decision.
and then because I am
public minded I would like to capture the outcomes good or bad and at each
stage so that they were there to improve the decisions for the next patient coming
in the end, though, I had to make a gut call
and I put my, bet my life
on a clinical trial that failed.
and what's what's interesting about this is the whole notion of clinical trials, which the
entire drug industry relies on to develop drugs, it's very expensive, very time consuming it's where a lot of
those fifteen years go.
but the problem with clinical trials and a disease like cancer, which as I said is very
heterogeneous, is that when you recruit a hundred or a thousand patients for a trial you're really dealing
with a fruit cocktail of diseases.
and so when a drug, you know, works on forty percent of
patients and another drug works on ten percent of the patients
is the forty percent drug better for you?
well, not necessarily, it depends whether you're more similar to that ten percent of the
patients or the forty percent.
another serious problem is that many, many trials fell because they only helped one or
two people.
so, come on, what disease did we cure,
these people have that we've cured?
and these learnings are typically lost
so this is another opportunity
to ask ourselves, you know maybe we've already cured twenty percent, fifty percent of cancer, who
knows? we just don't know it yet
and I wanna ask a question which i'm going to repeat several times today
do you think a little AI can help?
and this kind of problem in connecting
excuse me, results to the people who need them?
that's that's
where I think we can make a contribution. when i talked about we have much more
knowledge about cancer. today we understand concer at a cancer at a fairly deep level
in in terms of interactomes of genes with other genes with proteins, proteins with
other proteins, we have signaling diagrams
such as this one. much of what we know is probably wrong or incomplete, but
we know things and here's a couple of cancer pathways that are responsible for a
large number of melanomas and on on the left the yellow pathway is a MAP kinase pathway
it's the one that makes the gas pedals stick on, so the cells proliferate and on the
my left, my
right, right here, is
the PI three pathway in blue, which is a brake pedal, it's supposed to make
the cells either arrest the cell cycle or destroy themselves
if they're going out of control. the BRAF pathway gene at the top
of the MAP kinase pathway is implicated in about sixty or sixty five percent of
melanomas and just recently there's been a drug that's been developed for it. so we can in
a very targeted way find the mutation and hit it and it will arrest those cancers, they'll
melt away.
the problem is that cancer is smart and it will find ways compensatory mechanisms and
and then
you know some of the surviving clones PI three K might might mutate so take
the breaks off and we've gotta hit that too, unfortunately, there's just now a drug that's coming into
trials for being able to do that.
so the ability to be able to analyse cancer at this causal level
and be able to
place bets by taking drugs and then capture the learnings and use that not just to treat
the patient, but to be able to improve our understanding of whether this causal model
is right is the big breakthrough and leads us to the possibility of trying to treat
to win the war on cancer in a different way, which is one patient
at a time.
so the the basic idea is to do what I wanted to do for me to
be able to tell you for each patient, take all of the knowledge and resources in
the world
and try to
understand what it is that's the best possible treatment for that patient
at that moment in time?
then apply the patient, apply the treatment and see how the patient does and capture
the learnings, not just over that patient, but over all patients in order to drive the
field forward in general. so that's the paradigm and here is basically how it works.
I think about this as taking the fifteen years and the billion dollars and shrinking that down
to the time
and and the dollars the an individual patient might have. so if we're gonna take fifteen years
and shrink it down to a month or two
we're gonna have to make not incremental improvements but major, you know, slices, slashes
to to this timeline. and the first is to get rid of clinical trials, because
they really don't make sense in heterogeneous diseases like cancer, and replace them with deep
genomic analysis of individual patient's tumors.
and then the second thing we're gonna have to do is
to we don't have time to develop new drugs, so we're gonna have to work
with the drugs that we that we
have on hand, but that's
actually a much bigger space than it appears, there are five thousand drugs have been approved
by the FDA and similar organisations around the world, not to mention the investigational agents
that are currently on trial. and many of these drugs we only are, we don't
even have the vaguest idea what the mechanism of action are
for those drugs, even aspirin, right, we're continuing to find new uses for it. so they
the probabilities are pretty good that if we apply computational and systems biology, we can
attempt to find a match
for that patient against some drugs in our in our
either used as intended or used off-label or used in cocktails.
and then when we find something that works, we can test it on other patients and see
how many others it works for and ultimately find subclasses of patients who respond to
particular therapy. so we have the blue patients and the green patients, they respond to
their respective colored pills
and that's what we're trying to do.
someday we'll have it all mapped-out. we'll have what are called treatment guidelines, which are
basically a decision tree where a patient comes in, gets their tumor tested, and depending on the particular
mutations that they have
can get treated with the right drugs. unfortunately there's a large part of
this space
is currently unpopulated, unexplore and that's the opportunity that we have and the challenge that
we have is this to fill out that space one patient at the time.
so I'm going to next talk about how we're doing that and there are
other people who are doing this.
I'm gonna first talk about collabrx one, which is a personalized oncology research service
that I started with my colleagues, mainly Rafael Lehrer
at collabrx.
and then I'm going to talk about cancer commons, which is a rapid learning community,
the goal of which is to be able to capture the learnings from every cancer patient
in order to be able to rapidly grow the field.
so collabrx one starts with a patient and their doctor. patient goes in and gets
a biopsy or surgery and we have some tumor specimens. we want to apply deep
genomic analysis and I'm talking about genome wide snipped copy number expression analysis even
which is becoming, the the prices are imploding, it used to cost a million dollars, five hundred
thousand dollars just five years ago, fifty thousand dollars today,
five thousand dollars next year, I mean the world isn't even
recognizing what's happening on the imploding price crib, we've gotta be ready for that. get
the deep analysis of the tumor, do the analysis of the level of the wiring
diagram that I talked about earlier,
make a recommendation for that patient, feed it back in the report to the doctor.
and then it either works or it doesn't work. if it doesn't work we have
a new data point
and it's not data point in a mass
it's not even one data point, it's thousands of data points from this genome wide analysis.
go back and try to understand now more about that that space that wasn't filled
and of course doing this over multiple patients gives us a chance to really analyse and understand and do leaning.
so the interesting questions of course occur with the outliers, the one or two patients who
responded when no one else did. again what disease did these patients have that
we've already cured?
or there are patients who didn't respond, to go back to the scientists on whose recommendations
we based the treatment plan in the first place and ask what did you not
understand about the disease or about the mechanism of action of the drugs in order to
have led to this result and what can you now learn from the new data
that we have?
the result of all this learning we're trying to capture in a reference model,
which is basically a way to populate out this
tree that I showed you. the reference model here's a picture of a reference model for
melanoma as it stands today. there are set of some types of melanoma, each of
which corresponds to a mutation or a combination of mutations tying back to the pathways. and each of these
subtypes are actionable in the sense that there exists a clear
a clear approved laboratory that can be used to determine if a patient
is in or out of that subtype and at least one rational therapy that could
be applied. these don't have to be proved in clinical trials by no means, but
there has to be a rational argument that said if the patient has this biology, this drug ought to work.
and then the goal is to do some some carefully planned experiments, namely patients
come in, we find out what subtype they're in, we give them one of the approved
therapies, we capture the learnings. some patients are going to respond, some won't and that's going
to inevitably lead to splitting those subtypes.
this list that you see here is the seed list that was created by talking to a
lot of experts and then doing a meta-analysis of the research literature and the data
and there are ten of them. in fact the bottom one has already dropped off
there's only nine, but
I'm pretty sure in a year or two we're gonna have twenty or thirty or
forty, I don't know how many. and the interesting thing is that some of those
subtypes are going to look a lot like subtypes in other cancers that are
not melanoma
and that's where we're going to be able to get the cross learning to
so I'm now gonna talk about cancer commons, which is a grand experiment to
be able to take the learnings from collabrx one and everyone else who is working in
personalized oncology,
which is a field that is really beginning to take off, it's at the very very
kind of leading edge of the innovation curve.
and basically the goal is in this rapid learning community to give each patient the
best possible treatment for them at this moment in time, capture the learnings, analyse
try to do incorporate those learning back into the into the causal models and try
to drive the field forward in this way.
so cancer commons is not only that community, but a platform for real-time translational research in
cancer on which this community can collaborate with each other and the community includes importantly not
just doctors and researchers but patients and all of the ecosystem of service providers
that are needed in order to be able to get them to do this
guerrilla war, this aggressive style
of N of one research.
the cancer commons platform is lives in the cloud it's very scalable and we've used it for building
communities that many different scales all of which are connected, so we've used it first
to implement collabrx one, the service I just talked about, and the important thing there is
that this is a completely virtual service in the sense that I don't have any
laboratories, the closest thing I have as a lab
is my kitchen.
but we do we outsource everything to different service providers in that ecosystem this bespeaks
of my e-commerce background. we've also used it to together a community of
researchers, who are involved in helping to develop the melanoma reference model and we're now putting
collabrx one together with this reference model so that we can use the reference model
to guide the initial treatment of patients, and then when patients don't respond to take
their specimens and put it through the very same research process that was used to capture the model
in the first place.
we are now hoping to move forward and use this same platform to connect many
groups like the group was involved in creating the initial reference model in order to
be able to explore
different combinations of melanoma therapies, different combinations of investigational agents which are on trial
which is truly revolutionary because drug companies traditionally have not allowed their drugs in trial
to be tested in combination.
but like AIDS it's often the case that these therapies won't work as monotherapies,
they have to be used in combination so we're trying to put together a
community built on the cancer commons platform so that when a patient comes in, they
will get routed to the trial that's most likely to help them.
well according to my name tag i'm andrew blake
and so this must be the vision lecture
i know you've been working incredibly hard i have to admire your stamina to be
able to keep going four thousand and still come back for more seems to me
incredible and you know the evidence of how hard you work is that of the
air in this room seem to have been breeds already
but i have there's enough left for to just you know one more burst of
of concentration
so the organisers gave me
you know very broad brief computer vision
you can't talk about the whole of computer vision but you know i'm going to
do a little bit of scene-setting with respect to computer vision first and then sort
of halfway through today funnels and fairly sharply to discuss one particular problem innovation and
how to model it probabilistically
how to do inference
with that model
because you had a lot of different views now
of different ways of setting up probabilistic models and doing inference and the vision community
have their own i guess you probably say somewhat perverse way of doing things and
what have singular would be will be more polite
and so that's what i'm going to tell you that
so what is
vision what we mean by
you this is the problem we want to solve with vision but i thought i'd
just show you a few
things in vision that the work because there are many more things that we
i like to have working for example i'd like to have this video working the
sony career knowledge but i can't get down to work so i think i have
to act that one out but you know this is this is a very in
fact contrary to appearances i am it's only career robot just rather big size and
that's why i'm so very kind of mobile and you know my joints are very
human-like and
i can dance and catchable when it's thrown to me and all this kind of
thing so that's what that's that's that's you know be good to make the japanese
particularly because the honda as team and various other japanese robots the japanese actually hold
the show every now and again a sort of national show a bit like you
know we would have added big games something that you have a robot show where
all the japanese public come and sort of interact with robots and the robots to
soak tested for robot that has managed to run around four hundred and eighty days
without you know being rude to anyone or falling over is allowed in the kind
of very public area of the show and the robot it's not quite so services
that gets sort put in the pan you can look at the people but not
actually get too close to and so on and this is the sort of this
national sport so the
the japanese clearly one of these very much
i don't know if i want
sort of human looking thing serving drinks in my house you know that sort of
old-fashioned view of robots but you know i think may be more reasonable view is
that you would like a little box on the floor that you know when you're
older and you fall over or common sort of take a picture of you and
hold my telephone to your mouth so you can call the call centre and be
rescued i mean you know people taking that kind of thing pretty seriously and
fair enough i think
what else might we like to do with vision well there's the
these kinds of things this is the
the stanford robocar
this is the sort of next generation of the one that won the
dark challenge in two thousand four cross crossing the harvey desert you sort of read
about this and following this that you know there's is that the challenge was to
go on a hundred mile course and
you GPS to tell you where to go but lots of unexpected obstacles and sort
of sheer drops and all this kind of stuff and
anyway this version
and that one have vision to to help detect obstacles different kinds of vision and
this one has vision to help it sort of renegotiate its environment even when they
are moving of the moving parts of the environment so actually
in the is that they could do this kind of thing so if you if
you're coming up to another robot and you want to take it the course organiser
came out the great big red button stop the whole race and you know that
guy had to stay well this guy was in past and you know that was
that was as much as they could do couldn't deal with moving obstacles it wasn't
in the room in the rules now that's the kind of
a great sort of demonstration i guess of you know the robustness of visual inference
can be embedded in engineering system
you might not one of those yourself because you have to be a little bit
nervous of of driving a car that was driving itself not not even asking your
opinion about about where it should go so maybe something more acceptable to kind of
spin-off that you might expect from that kind of research would be
this your cruise control from daimler-benz you know daimler daimler benz are really in the
forefront of your combining vision and radar and all kinds of sensors to make a
car whose default behaviour is
more natural so the most primitive kind of cruise control the steering is the is
the castor action of the wheels in your car you all cars have this the
wheels tend to snap to the to the forward position that's because they're mounted slightly
obliquely and so they can mechanically some mechanical intelligence building but imagine if that sort
of behavior is controlled electronically and in response to sensory data and so on
what this one is this is the mercedes-benz
so you be quite nice
to have a car did that i guess
the disturbing
so so not not not not everything's peachy can kind see here
that is cynicism sort of inclusion for the guy got to could drink which we
what i see me trying to stop the students
system falls apart consider this looks nothing like it
to there again
and so on
to to get around that we go back to our friend the robust error function
parameter function to actually help a lot with that it slows things down but essentially
what we do we should register function again this instead of making this least squares
you kind of put a cap on how much appearance variation each pixel can have
so if something comes in and so it's the across something it's extremely outside the
realm of what the the pixel variation should be
we don't high that as much weight as we would with the least squares
robust error function is we shown before
and this was some improvements
required for
you can kind of see here the traditional i
falls apart
things but with the robust i am everything's basically could
we've got some interesting useful applications software
someone is standing before about a mass replacement things so we've actually got so it's
not something like this
essentially what we did with i with that kind of set of
basically using someone's head in terms of rotation
in terms of being able to define a point and so
we had some and sit in front of the camera the kind of this is
moving head around and you can actually
moved to different points and when he blinked you can actually click on the point
things so
it's kind of cool cool them i i don't know if it's going to be
replacing mouses anytime soon but
things then
we also did some stuff from gaze tracking
if you in car and stuff and just like you want to make sure what
does the driver have is always in the right looking at something else
actually did an experiment to see that we can we use the i in in
terms of so we added an extra couple mesh points and they are incorrect to
work out what he is looking at so this is actually what he is looking
at a face and i interact so it's kind of noisy but you can actually
the there's a reasonably good job following the target across and things and hopefully system
applications in impacts drug-safety we're we're we're working with the car company in japan on
applying this sort of stuff
another thing that this is really useful for
is normalisation
so essentially like kind of
face moving all over the place here
and so if you want to come to do could face recognition like we're showing
for the dam active principles of right and normalising ties
as long as most pixels are still there so that's that's actually the real time
variation you can see that as soon as you again this is why i think
i think one of the first kind are i was reluctant things because well registrations
interesting things but i think there's a lot of other interesting things in computer vision
can be doing but
like you look at something like this and if you do the registration really well
all the other things he could be appointed really advance machine learning techniques to kind
of deal with all this pose variation things that if you just register the face
probably no falls apart i why what you need to anything things so not saying
not to trivialize the other portions of the machine learning because it's definitely places where
this falls down but registration is extremely important for computer vision and hopefully
are they emphasise that
a bit during this stage during this talk
and then we also did some stuff on animation generation like this is someone doing
something and at the time
the what a cartoon
things in
it doesn't it doesn't pretty good job
actually this guy here in in math he's actually currently over whether
if you guys know what but it's the company that peter jackson started lord of
the rings and so he's been working a lot of so
if you look now lord of the rings sort of a very expensive to try
and do like column and all the other actors and things like that and so
what i love maybe maybe companies are very interested in is automating this basically can
thrown holy factors
in my essentially so for the next kind of animation
big animation movie
and perhaps is automatically animated avatar without
so someone walking in this acting walking out because there's a lot of the time
also it's extremely difficult because you have to actually get all these points in the
end you have to be accurate every time you do it
and things
that's another possible
yes he is applied to i think
another type is when a person has been defrauded
and the bank which transactions did you actually do
and they decide well to compensate themselves has to make to clear here the own
transactions is being fought as well so they can get the
the money back
so the chances of fraud detection they then there's an issue that before the change
reacted to to detect all these to detect and prevent
there's a technical issues of the
these are simple time series we have full credit card fraud these data streams and
by that i mean that we have data coming in order not read the article
intervals are coming at a time someone from the transaction we may not have all
the data concerning or an individual account when we have to make that determination
in kind two ways we need to make decisions quickly as possible
so so these are online systems but there is the a possibility is missing in
this talk we can do some of the processing in the back to of learning
but the the other
potential ways of getting around problem of time in this as an anecdote i heard
when automatic petrol pumps or gas comes in america first started sleeping according to the
machine and start delivering deal
there was a time delay between the maxi but according to them to make the
simulation where they should be allowed to continue this transaction so they decided in this
simple case was just two automatic allow
fifty cents or dollars worth of fuel into your car
and that was to estimate the time to
to make the decision about whether to allow the the transactions continue any further so
as an example of where
custom to inconvenience was trumps the actual losses to fraud
thomas again in form four in the four quickly as possible a
can starting to defrauded
as i said it's not the same amount of time that passed but it's the
number of transactions really that foreign transaction to be missed before that is being identified
finally there's the issue of imbalanced classes again
australia in the last year
the prior announced that they had about sixty five percent of the total number of
plastic card transactions
were rules
and the issues behind them that being discussed this morning and previously
with the caveat that david said about this disgusting little bit brought this this is
roughly two brought the four to ten bits four detection using statistical methods to supervised
anomaly detection
supervised methods take historical instances of fraud and b search patterns again
and again broadly speaking there
so these patterns that finds a lot more likely before the list less likely to
have falsely flag which is the transactions of for using this approach that support and
this page is that course which has been taking
on the other hand these techniques
can't find new talk before so this is what normally takes comes in and so
don't stop instances build profile of usual behaviour of the customer
any significant deviations from this profile
it is considered as potentially fortunes flag is that
again there's plenty of situations where you might do something which is
unusually for what passes
this shows that there is more potential for
falsely flag transactions as forward
but they were ultimately has potential to that to changing patterns of fraud and this
is the approach that my quality of true
it is time
so big last confidence in the anomaly detection sort of area
well we don't do this
we don't build a profile on individual account holder we just look at other accountancy
who similar
and the idea that being that if historically a certain number of people
have been behaving similarly we assume that invites him for a while in the future
so we do monitor an account with respect to speak of similar accounts and if
you if he can deviate significantly from
those people members then we assume that enormous behavior we might flagged as potentially for
so simple toy example of this
we this much we had data for one particular account which is just the amount
this person spent two weeks on their credit card for
in the in weeks we
no n minus one
data may be is for free
and just to ten point everton we're looking at a particular account wanted become call
that the target account
now people should know whether on the week ending the map they spent is anomalous
somewhere on the texan technique would take over
the whole previous history there will be some some kind of maybe updating method with
some subset of the data which is initiated at the bottom there
and just build a simple program to see whether the value y is an outlier
but this has the potential problems example would be
the week was actually the period of the christmas in the UK
and the and we had not not profile to for an entire year's with the
data so this likely personally spending an awful lot more
so one way to get out of that is assuming that the
the bank has more than one customer
i guess i should like to joke about northern rock at this point
if you have any other customers
well we can and
basically each column there then represents one week
the final we we can we can just basing standardised data on that basis we
can just do some population standardisation just to remove these kind of effects from
from the data
so pick just take this one step further what we what we do then take
the time period from one to n minus one
and with disorderly accounts with respect to the similarity to update the target counts this
function pi
pi one then what would be the index of the account is most similar to
the target account has appeared from time what we want to we can minus one
so simply what we do is just take the k closest which is shaded in
gray in the final column that
on the final weekend and we just to see what value y is is enormous
compared to an outlier compared to those values x y one and two x y
k in that column
crucial issue about finding outlets appeared is that the the allies himself this necessarily lost
the population is an example of someone who did on full protection
what we have here is a day along the sort the only
x axis
on the y axis
and i can calculate now what the angles are
where on the screen here on the wall
the maximum of four
those maximum
and by the way there will be
based on the nineteen ninety of the zeroth symmetry
and these men are so small that you will even see only see the maximum
so let's calculate what angles we will then see the first
by the way these things have names we call it
zero order
and we call it the first order
and we call
this one
the first order
and we call the second order
and this is also called first order but it is on the other side so
we call these orders
on the specter
so you can now calculate the sign of data of and
it is and times land divided by d
and so when
when n is zero
that year
you zeros you get of course maximum
what is zero order
we call zero
now you first order
is when the sign of data one
is land that divided by g and i can take my lab which in my
case of my later i have to tell you
i land
five hundred and thirty two nanometer
it green
so i can calculate what they don't one is and i find sixteen point three
and then i can go to the second order
they are two for that color is different for different colors
and i find thirty four degrees
and i can go to the third order
i find theta three
is then fifty seven degrees
and there is no fourth order
that would make the final state larger than one that only
zero order and then there are first second and third order
the grain that you have
i always carried out with me
no matter where i go it's easy to to
fourteen your calendar
and so i will show you know by simply shining through this
thirty is great
also either on the wall
zero order would fall
right smack in the middle so to speak first order
sixteen degrees away so if you know my distance to the wall you can calculate
how far it is the only need enough
so you'll see these
this is extremely narrow
i value for n
well speaks for itself i have two
i rotate migrating to make sure that the groups are in this direction
the groups are in this direction the spreading is out in this direction
so you see
so one that you see
right now on the right side of the screen there is my zero order
you can tell that it is zero order because they have only one color
and then you see
one with the little you see the first order now on the right side of
the screen
and that angle should be very accurately about but i calculated the sixteen degrees
and then you see on the blackboard here
so it right here
you see the second order
and then you see in the order if you have good eyes and the fourth
order doesn't exist
and imagine that between those maximum
if i really u sixteen on lines there will be fifteen hundred and ninety nine
point with exact zeros and then all the silly minimax semantic you don't even see
that is the power
of grading when you use
many lines
if i use sixteen hundred lines i use eight hundred two
times more lines than when i have a double slit interferometer
double slit interference will be extremely different from this
that's why those locations i so narrow
because it would double slit interference you will get
cosine square function
and so you would see
the maximum will be a hundred times brawler
and this
that's the power of using
a hundred lines
now i want you to get your gratings out
and i wanted to look
simply at
and the reason why i want you to do that is that
i wanted to be
because you may not see
what you erroneously expected
that is zero order
incredibly narrow
it is not
its brain it's the lamp itself
of course if you light source
in angular size is way larger
then this angular size you cannot expect to see the light source gets more
in other words
clearly the limiting factor of seeing
zero order
very narrow
is only if the light source itself
it is small enough in size
so when you look at this light now
you will see all colors zero order
that's one thing that's important you just see the land
that year zero the maximum that's the red blue green yellow violet that's all of
and then you will see
on your site
will appear
first the blue
the square in this exponential you integrate what you actually get is a quadratic form
that looks like this
so this tells you that the normalisation constant in this case
is just a quadratic forms
in data
this is a nice little relation i encourage you to do is an exercise if
you take the dual of the quadratic form that involves q inverse
the dual will be a quadratic form that involves q
so q goes to q inverse when you do duels that's that's in isolation to
so if we put the pieces back together what we're going to get is that
in order to
do inference we should actually compute solve this quadratic programme here
and if you solve that quite quadratic programme you'll see that you
get the unique solution of new high schools who inverse times data
and it's worth
remembering now remember how motivated things to begin with i said since they you want
to compute a
the matrix inverse problem that's basically what gets you an inference is it to compute
the mean you have to do matrix inverse
what i said is one variational representation would involve the quadratic form
if you solve this you get this solution this is the the gas you mean
you can check
so what this is saying is that in this particular case we we took our
general principle
and if we specialise in go through the the step of calculations
that in fact used to cover what already is familiar very rate variational representation to
so what was easy here a couple things that are easy
it was nice that we had an explicit form for the dual function
and what was also easy these mean parameters these are expectations from user expectations of
these guys
these were just unconstrained here gauss you mean can move wherever it wants right there's
no constraints on against me
so that's why this problem and have been very easy just an unconstrained quadratic programme
OK so any questions about the example
if you want to get experience with sort of duality calculations just working to this
example is is a good one it's it's pretty simple not too much algebra and
it's something that pops up over and over again tools of quadratic forms are an
important special case
it would be more ambitious and we also learn the covariance
number now i had
sufficient statistics where the matrix of sufficient statistics like this
i had a matrix of parameters like this
this examples of trickier to compute but it also leads to another kind of convex
programming that's interesting
sort of one step up from quadratic programs
so what i'm doing here is like compute the log normalisation constant i have to
integrate this thing but i i have matrix this
it represents the inner product of the matrix with this matrix of sufficient statistics
so if you actually do this integral
what you find is the dual function involves a log determinant of the matrix of
mean parameters
and for those of you have experience with kelsey entropy
you recognise this is exactly the the negative of calcium entropy
one interpretation is that
determinant tells you something about the volume
enclosed by something else seems like a big ellipsoid is what sam showed us and
the determinant tells you something about the volume of an ellipsoid
the volume volumes bigger than the uncertainty is somehow bigger
so that's why it's intuitive entropy should be something that be like log determinant it's
logo of the volume of the uncertainty ellipsoid
that's the interpretation
in this case if you sort of stick the pieces back together
putting the entropy function in our dual calculation
and remembering that we had the semi definite constraints on the matrix member i i
had that constraint an earlier slide what you actually get in this case is a
log determinant problem to solve
and if you solve this you'll find that you compute exactly again the gas you
but you also compute the covariance matrix
so what you want to take away from this is that we would have started
with this
general variational principle right here
right this quite abstract thing
and we can
do this kind of inequality so remember with this inequality come from
i told you before that an optimal separating how are separating hyperplane in canonical form has this property that
the positive points
for the positive points this quantity here is at least plus one or larger
for the negative prices quantities is minus one or small
now if we multiply
o thing here with
the label
we can write both inequalities as one
and the inequalities will exactly
look like this
so shattering means now
that no matter how we put the labels
we can always satisfied
uh inequality by the choice of some w that satisfies the constraint that length
so shattering by canonical hyperplanes with this constraint means
no matter what the labels are
we can always satisfy all these inequalities
with such hyperplane
so let's assume that this is the case and then see what follows from it
it turns out that
something follows about the business dimension
and the proof will first and show
the more points we can shatter
like this
the larger a certain quantity must be
is this quantity here
in the next step we will show that this quantity is actually upper bounded in terms of
the radius of the smallest sphere and if we put these things together we forget about the missing dimension
so we all we first get a bound how many
points we can at most shat
which gives us the damage
so let's take this
o thing here
and the summit over all are
so we sum over all points
the which gives us and are
on the right hand side we have the one before
and here we just have the sum of these things
going back and forth we have more than why inside
and here we have someone why i x i
so this an inequality here
on the other hand we can
up a bond
this quantity using the cushy schwartz inequality is this dot product is upper bounded by
the length of the first arguement
times the length of the second arguement
now the length of the first arguement by assumption is upper bounded by lambda
now we know that this thing here is upper bounded by this
the same time we know that the same thing is lower bounded by are therefore
are is lower bounded by this
more are divided by long ties
lower bounded by this
you tell me if i'm going too fast or too slow just ask whenever you
get stuck
so that's all first results
the very elementary
the second one is
also simple maybe a little bit less elementary
and now
by assumption no matter what the labels on the can do that
so we are free what to do with the labels
this inequality is always true
let's consider a particular type of labels
labels that take the independent random variables
take taking values plus minus one
these are also called item variables this kind of random variables
let's see
this quantity
which is the quantity that we had on the previous slide
let's see what the expectation of this thing here
it's like a square root
okay so
we first there rewrite
this thing here is the dot product of the thing with itself
and then we can take expectation out
well we can we keep it out sorry we we take the sum of
we can do that because expectation is a linear operation
and we take one of two some solid and then we take a look at
how does this thing here behave inside
and well how does behave they actually two part of a
one of them
in this sum
and one of them is the parts where the labels are
in this is different from here
and one of them is the part where the indices are the same
and let's deal with them separately
so the first one
where the indices are different
and we can put together with the expectation in this term
the second one where this is
the same we put together like this
now it turns out that the
the first term
for symmetry reasons because these wires are independent of variables so they will sort all cancel each other out
whereas the second term is something that's left
and the second term looks like this
and so this is our second term here this is just the norm of this vector
of course the why is don't change the length of the don't change this non so indian we just
left with this exciting squares
and we don't in expectation anymore because everything that's random is gone
since now we use our second assumption which is all the points are contained in a ball of radius are
so we know that this is true
looking back
so we had
we know that this quantity here is upper bounded by this
we know each one of those is in a ball of radius are
therefore this quantity is also upper bounded by
well and we have
lowercase are times
this all squared
we end up with this thing here on the right-hand side
which we have derived
using a
which are which holds true for the expectation over the random choice of the labels
this is an statement on in expectation
now we want something that's
we want this expectation to go
we wanted to combine this with this other say that we had about this quantity
now if something is true for an expectation then there must be at least one
set of labels here for which is also true i mean if for all the
labels this
if an inequality is true expectation then
there must be at least one instantiation where it's also true because if you were
violated all instantiations and we take expectation over it
and then in expectation would also be violated
so let's take that one probably many but let's pick the ones that label
it's one of those sets labels for which
this inequality holds true
so far we haven't fixed the labels
now we fix them
that once said this inequality is true
and this is what we're going to combine
so now in the first part of the proof we have shown
this is true
in the second part we have shown that before specific set of labels is true
so the first thing was true positive of labels
this was true for a specific set of labels we're gonna use that everywhere else here
and now we combine these two things
forming clusters of similar points and the start merging them
points that are more similar to the clusters
and so on
so you see that
two clusters in the data
the internally within each cluster
small clusters
marched at some level similarity
and so
as mentioned that the
interest in
data clustering and this is supported by
two way
so far
history and the color
six thousand hits
also the
and on the
science like
we live like this
so why is clustering so important for
but is not feasible to label large collections of objects in our life
the simple
prior knowledge the
in the data
the clusters
what what time people of
posting news items on the left side this only problem
and then cluster the organisation provides an efficient browsing as recommendation
so every
internet company search for me and so on
there's a lot of effort
it just
but wisely
so some examples
clustering users the the on the face of three hundred thousand status of this permanent on tens of thousands of
and what is the price the clusters
based on the topic of the status message so it can display that not only is interested in nineteen
it was also
during the postings on
when i nineteen
it is clear from the articles on
on the of the
a new cluster is created in the
and the list of articles that have
in the i
on the
the individual
the images associated with those articles
the also
and example illustrated
the ability to the
video on youtube design start displaying other individuals
which similar to the video
he was popularity
many properties
here's an example of clustering more efficient image retrieval
if i want to get this image is
twenty seven images
in the two of them seem to be
related one
food items
but if i
the clustering of these images and then
in the same way
the more relevant
images which
it is
so the two accuracy food category
without the average precision is forty seven percent
so basically show the organising data
using this one
this is extremely important
processing it is
what about the clustering algorithm
i should say that hundred thousand dollars
so that when you now
the other
he published
but if you look carefully designed
different from
the act said she
be published
many of these algorithms are admissible
what the united
this is a theory
it will is admissible decision rule is admissible if is no other
decision rule which always outperforms it
so that means
the simplest
these results children it
the basis of it is better
spectral clustering or any of the other
was discovered in the early nineteen fifty
like the independent
the light
about a mixture model
comes in the
you want
the approaches
the first
and in some sense you can see he's a special instance of sun
he's spectral clustering and these two as well what currently is the
recall there a very important it is
the area of DIR system in the middle and and they are very useful in
different real-world application one of these is the topographical map people interpretation it is this
specific application the some case study using data mining think that we have the dust
to the centre topographic map in this case we can show objects belonging to different
and what happens is that when we look at the moment we wanted to enter
the scene was that we see in the my so these very few what's so
the meaning of my interpretation when i look at these i immediately recognised in my
mind that a area that is the blue color is typically press nineteen even like
in this case so this is what happened when we wanted to put in my
obviously is very easy to interpret to some symbols time a encoded was meaning is
encoded by the muppet creator so there is typically allowed to say OK the blue
line are for something very very but the problem is that of interpreting them up
in order to this school the discovered some objects that are not explicitly represented in
the for example looking at this map and recognise that if if there is some
industrial area or not or not to
so here is where the mining can be useful and can be useful to know
when it is integrated with DSS system this means that typical difference in IQ of
women age meaning visualising exploring querying geographical data is in some time integrated with the
typical meta mining cup capabilities and is is that the many companies can be was
was used for for example for mining the some operational definition of the geographical objects
that are not directly six percent of the metadata and the use these operational definitions
to to quickly descended although
on the
there you just to the finishing of the system and in this case the system
as some training from united also to learn not operational definition objects and also the
script from right in order to discover discovered some descriptive of the architecture of the
system to looking is that i have found that architecture for especially the mining ceased
and we have the user guide it is designed to just two for an expert
in an expert system and we have a special databases where we still notable for
special data and and special
and the user management tool a tool need to use user profiles so they were
different users with different reading a book or two to the user that is the
amount to the user can also all using GIS functionality of the user that is
that the mind that is able to perform data mining task
my management for the many acquiring four
and the population of acquiring the data writing data a simple query just to visualise
objects belonging to specifically is all the leading and these is very important for us
assessing quality into since the dot in this case the user can also relate to
each request to as system especially the mining query language this provided to or interpreted
squarely by checking is called that is going to from the syntactic and semantic to
you and and the film which is means that interact with the special databases data
mining to see that the reason that we did special mining about that sort of
thing the results
the more alone there were that we have adopted to represent them up with this
is diseased case is that the solution to political model is the establishment is divided
into a grid of side length and is to simplify
the localisation process look to localize its object within a specific assembler and whatever it
is you object organised in two i give physical and logical physical one went describe
it geometry and logic women tend to describe the semantic of the geographical object representation
for the physical i want to learn the legal wife ontological anarchy differently so that
some experts that have some colleague of the department one is to combine have defined
it as interesting for a specific task that wrote philosophy and so on and they
can be also found that specialize in these is that you can
this is a representation of the ways of translation in object relations bayes and we
can look at the map is a collection of science and what is interesting is
that the logical object to describe the logical i key in this case we are
presented is there you keep by exploiting the only from more fearsome it is defined
in object relations that the more than so we have when in i of type
in this case and the physical information is represented as the geometry that type filter
to store and the index and so efficiently query all physical data
the problem
the first thing that we have a working this on his architect and we have
to deal with the different technologies
one side of the mining on one side is the object relation DBMS the activity
of the enzyme one we intend to store and for the court
query but the discovery and in the classical GPS system and the problem is that
we have to integrate all of this technology in a way that is transparent to
from the and users some time is not very expert user
it can be the typical user of as system the solution to the design in
this case is two
the mining query languages to interface to women manage aged interfacing between you and the
entire system and i different technologies that are behind these systems
so in this case the user can formulate a mining query equity and in this
way it's it's completely it was not in charge of the problem of the representation
of the topological physical representation because it's inside the
system and all the proceedings should be chosen for transforming the data and the understanding
of this data
mining on the training of this interesting part and presenting this part use the old
is defined as the inside the typical of the mining process that are completely summarizes
in the query and are not
individual use that so in this case the user can discover some part my from
query and i exactly the same way that a user can discover they can extract
the data by performing quite clearly so if the is queries to query a simple
but the point is if you sort of attach penalties to these constraints
these penalties are are real numbers again adjusted these are actually the lacrosse multipliers the
what you can show that the solution there is a solution to this problem presuming
these constraints are OK
it's always going to have this kind of exponential form
so it's going to be important
that you get things in this kind of exponential form
so this is the sort of leads into exponential families
as i said these are some of classical thing in statistics
and the way they are specified is we can have these collections of local functions
are prose
and those are typically called sufficient statistics
there sufficient because they they are not to specify the family
and then you have the vector of weights are parameters stated you have one of
them for every one of your sufficient statistics so alpha is an index here
and then you simply look at a parameterized family of densities
that takes this kind of forms
you've got to some a weighted sum of your potential functions
and this guy all i'm doing here is rewriting the normalisation constant this is just
log easy
but it's so is traditional to write this in a slightly different form as a
where if they is log of of this normalisation quantity here
so if go back to example here
right if we look at these two particular functions p one and FT two being
x and x
for the previous page told me is that if i solve the maximum entropy problem
what i would get is together
family of distributions that looks like this
be proportional to the exponential of data one times x stated two times x squared
and x here would i'm assuming will belong to the real line
right so what kind of random variables is that thing there
probably seen things like this before
what if data one more zero inflated to remind minus one if you plotted that
thing what would it look like
right into normal or gas that's all it is
this is perhaps a slightly different form that you might not be used to what's
going on here is that the state is
can be expressed in terms of the moments the music
you could be used to seen in terms of of this
in terms of its variance data one here would be minus mu one of the
and they two would be
and this a plus minus one the variance squared
so if you substitute that in in rearranged find the more usual form for the
right so all that says is that
this is the well known fact that the gaussian distribution is the one that has
maximum entropy subject to constraints in the first two moments right what we did here
was constrain the first moment and the second moment
and then one a particular case of what we said is that at the end
of the day you get again year
and you can work to that the details as a little exercise
right so
here are some examples these things
probably many of you have seen before this is the one we just gaussians
the random variables on the real line
we'll worry too much about this measure here
this device say that distinguishes between whether continuous
in which case we'll say it along with respect to live that measure
or for discrete that's with respect to something that puts mass on individual points but
the weight loss of p of x it would look like this for gaussians
for bernoulli
that's the variable that just like a coin flipping variable we spoke about the last
time it would look like this
and you can also look at exponentials plus on spiritual is
so there are lots of things that basically there also called loglinear because they up
to this normalisation constant there's sort of a linear in the parameters here when you
take log
so that's that's what exponential families look like
right so the point now is that we can really think about many not all
but many
graphical models is just the exponential families
right these cases are all
these are all scale these are just a single variable
member graphical models were most interested in the multivariate case we have many random variables
so we have the whole graph and we have one variable each node
but you can really think about
just taking something from an exponential family of the nodes my people newly might be
and then by combining these things together
we can get a larger exponential family
and what sort of key here is that the sufficient statistics these things these fees
that we were talking about before
what we need for it to be a graphical model is the fees have to
be local
and they have to be local in the sense that the graph tells them to
right so it means that you should only have functions on cliques for instance on
one two three i shouldn't have any function that a function of both two and
what i mean he
is there is often a physical quantity that you are measuring
it is living on some object in space
one dimension two dimensions whatever the has a certain amount of symmetry
all right and the periodicity of the non is a consequence of the symmetry of
the object so it's often the county meaning the second so here you have
say someone has some physical quantity is not always but often enough physical quantity
a region
we have symmetry
the region itself repeats region itself the repeating pattern
all right so the periodicity of the finer the periodicity of the physical quantity that
you're ring is a consequence of the fact that is distributed on
on its over some region it's itself
has some symmetry to periodicity
arises from the symmetry periodicity here of the order of the of the physical quantity
measuring arises because the periodicity of the of the symmetry of the object were treated
with example from the symmetry
the net effect giving the example of example the really started the subject and will
study this
is the distribution of heat
on a circular ring
e g
the distribution of heat
on a circular parts of the object the physical quantity that you're interested in is
the temperature
the temperature in a certain region and the region is
all right
the ring has circular symmetry
around OK so you're measuring the temperature
on the ranking
and that periodic because if you go once around at the same place of the
temperature is periodic as function as a as a function of the spatial variable that
describes where you are on the right time is not involved here position is involved
riodic in space not periodic in time
in the spatial variables gives you the position in the periodicity arises because the object
itself is symmetric because the object repeats
that's why this sort of example is why one often sees in this this actually
turns out to be very far reaching and quite deep that fourier analysis is often
associated with questions of symmetry
in this sort of most mathematical form
you often find free series developed in and in this context and free transport developed
in the context of symmetry so you often see for analysis from to say
three analysis
analysis is often
associated with problems are just all with with with analysis of questions that have to
do with the absence of like symmetry
so most often associated with problems
with symmetry just leave it very general this is the very first part of the
problem the distribution of heat honoring we solve the problem that was the problem the
fourier himself considered are either introduced some of the methods into the and also that
that what everything's alright so again it's not periodicity in time
his periodicity in space
and for those of you who had or may have courses in this that the
mathematical framework for this very general we're looking for a fourier analysis is group theory
because the theory of groups in mathematics is the way of mathema ties in the
idea of symmetry and then one extend the ideas for all policies into
to take into account of groups that is to say to take into account the
the world you feel better than you've ever felt before
that's the only way that your body rewarding you with dopamine up here is one
of my father's stories he's in fact has a different theory
he says vigorous exercise you know running or or cycles a bike is like banging
your head on the wall is said it feels best when you stop and and
the feel that you get at the end of the vigorous run is your body
saying thank you for stopping that african torture that feels much better
the researchers disagree
the reality is it's it's dopamine now you give someone you catch them and you
give them genuine recognition genuine recognition
i like the job you did on that proposal and the reason i say that
dot dot dot is not enough to say you're looking great today
no value or you did a good job
no value
we all
when somebody's flattering us
you meet somebody say have you lost weight
and inside your head you say get african life
get out of it i mean they're not gonna get me with something is is
that have you lost weight and the reason i ask that is that the last
m i so you were bulging over the top of the straw another falling off
you know you're on to something
when you give somebody genuine recognition when you catch them doing something right you give
them genuine feedback on it you trigger that release
of dopamine
triggers the amygdala says hey whatever you did just now
do it again i like that
so it reinforces
that behavior here's is the reality
none of us get told often enough that we are good at the things we
do and when somebody tells us that
not only does the cause that squirt dopamine it makes us them then again
i want to deal with you again this is the charismatic equation they feel or
they do better as result and it can be as simple as giving them some
positive feedback and if you can think of anything else to say
well complement to repair and
even complimenting somebody's appearance but you notice you need to be a little bit specific
that has a positive impact upon when you sense people are in they that place
where they in their darkest where you just know that there's something going on just
the smallest complements small bitter recognition can make all the difference in the world do
yourself a favor
i checked that movie out it's also for the ladies at the lovely little love
story it actually i i must be getting soft on my own page but i
i felt my eyes well up a little bit at the end of great fun
great fun
this second recognition is not only chemical
but actually psychological
there is nothing the marketing people
as the norm of reciprocity
what that is simply means what the psychologist mean when they say that is when
you do a favor for somebody
whether they wanted to favor or not
what they value the favor not whether this solicited what they like you are not
even if they don't like you there's a part of them says i want
i told him return favor i owe him reciprocal action i owe him a favor
back you give somebody some genuine recognition that little squirt dopamine say that's pretty good
they measure i o one
that is the ninety nine percent of people respond to the normal reciprocity go into
the biggest department store in
go into
actually go into the cosmetics department
and body eventually you heard of la prairie
and if the man had library anybody know if you haven't don't
learn anything about it it's very expensive cream for ladies comes in small tubes and