mu sigma squared data to be minus one half the square would see was with
then g of to this expression here
it looks like we're going to absolutely nothing
because i've turned a perfectly good and well known expression which is this one here
into something absolutely atrocious
and there
just for the sake of algebraic reformulations
well actually have gained something
because if i later on
i want to make this expression here depending on the location or something similar
like what you would do great as good as regression
the in
this function will be extremely handy because it will be convex intellectual army nice optimization
and dreaming up that function well i couldn't remember up in my worst nightmares
so you will
in this way in a systematic way
stumble across a nice convex optimization problems that otherwise you wouldn't find
and but some others that is the physicians before have tried designing such estimators and
they didn't follow this track they dreamed up the wrong functions and the problems when
the convex
it's actually quite convenient you know why
you have to pay a price but afterwards also the implementation get nicer
anybody seen in almost division
multinomial distributions
well you've seen that those two
so that's basically for instance if we have
this joint events like in different one click if i toss the dice and then
will be six
which only occur with certain probability
now i could go through this entire expression expression like what we have for the
binomial distribution and then we derive it or i could just tell you the answer
so let's the pain
and what i'm going to tell you is that this map here
which maps x
into the victory x
is the right one to give us a multinomial distribution
but what does this mean
well the inner product between EU x theta
just takes out the corresponding in training data
so for instance he three
in proc with theta would pick up the the three
so in other words i will get into the three minus the normalisation
and that's exactly what i have here g you theta
is the law of the sum of e to the theta i's
and that the game
is an exponential family distribution
the advantage of doing it this way is that we have now covered
a rather wide range of distributions
which all can be dealt with
with the same machinery afterwards
so for instance if i have some convex the some optimizer it will not care
so much about which particular distribution and i'm putting into it
well it's just different
feature map and all that
and afterwards i want to tell my soul what the form of g if theta
is interest happy optimise away at it
so i can basically build one optimizer
i can deal with multiclass with regression with normal distributions with
two different events and will see a lot more others
in the same framework
this is great if you're
writing software
the distribution over ten different events OK
it depends only in certain cases
even for a normal distribution you want to do you they be this form
yes i think that if you want
not always made it it is really very much on which probably trying to solve
so what you need
here is that in certain cases
they well defined
i mean do not lead to well-defined normalizations g of state over the entire domain
like for instance normal distributions with negative variance don't make sense
or so so so that that's the type of thing that you want to avoid
well up class distributions where the number of atoms keeps on increasing doesn't make sense
but other than that
it's just fine
now let's look at some others
let's look at the price of distribution
plus all distributions look very much like a plus distribution
in fact
well the sufficient statistics of those
are exactly the same ones as what we had for the past distribution just go
solve five fix here was one of six
and he thought ethics explic which is also called minus six and
flip the sign of data
but there's one key difference between the
what's on the class distribution
with the price of distribution at the discrete domain
so it's not just the
positive half
it's just the set of all integers critical in here
and what this does is it leads to
and in addition to that they also have different measure here on the domain which
and this one here
so i don't count every observation the same
the count them
well count the small times higher than the
larger terms
so this is exactly where i told you initially that well you can hide away
p zero europhysics in any way that you want as long as you can solve
the integral
that's one of those cases
it just leads the in
two quite different normalisation is the normalisation is e to the the theta
but before we had a lot of state it was me and minus log of
data it's e to the data
so depending on how you
define domain
you know you play with the normalisation
i mean so how you play with the measure you will get quite different normalizations
that's probably the most
relevant thing in this context
this point here
play around with the measure
so what does it look like this one here
almost looks like in the most efficient
it's essentially the coolant from the most efficient for the discrete case
you know if you wanted to harvard square and you see an out-of-work harvard grad
the handing out examples of square roots to give you an example and you can
see is the square root of two one point four one five two nine whatever
and you get left harvard jokes strong stop in the second here right
right so one of my trying to say here it doesn't
yeah exactly were staying away from that really quickly especially with the cameras rolling what
i try to say it tells you how you might test something but it doesn't
tell you how to
and that's what imperative knowledge is
parrot of knowledge is
a description of how to do something
so let me give an example of a piece of imperative knowledge
all right is actually a very old piece of imperative knowledge for computing square roots
is attributed to heron of alexandria
although i believe that the babylonians are i i suspected of knowing beforehand
here is a piece of imperative knowledge
i'm going to start
with the gas
the ecology
and then i want to say if g
is close to x
in return g
good enough answer
to get new gas
we're taking g
x over g
adding them
dividing by two take the average of gnx g don't worry about how came about
here and found this
that gives me new guess
and then repeat
a recipe
as the description of a set of steps
notice what has it has a bunch of nice things that we want to use
it's a sequence of specific instructions
that i do in order
along the way i have some tests depending on the value that test i may
change where
i am in that sequence of instructions
it has an intense something tells me when i'm done what the answer is
this tells you
how to find square roots is how to knowledge is imperative not
that's what computation
basically it's about we want to have ways of capturing
this process
o canal is now to an interesting question which would be how to y
build a mechanical process
the capture
that sort of computation
so i'm going to suggest that there's an easy way to do it
i realized that the boards in the wrong order here
one of the ways i could do it as you could imagine building a little
circuit to do this
i had a couple of elements stored values in that i had some wires to
move things around i had a little thing to do additional little thing to do
it's something to do the testing i could build a little circuit that would actually
do this computation
strange as it sounds is actually an example of the early computers early computers
well we call
fixed programme
meaning that they had to pieces circuitry designed to do a specific computation
that's what they do
we do that specific computation
you've seen these alot right a good example of this
it's basically an example of a fixed
program computer
does arithmetic
to play video games on good luck
i want to do word processing on good luck is designed to do
specific things are fixed programme computer
a lot of the other really interesting early ones similar have the flavor give an
you never know how to pronounce this
and as i
nineteen forty one one of the earliest computational things with the thing designed by finding
that as of basically solve linear equations
and the thing to do if you're doing it you know one
right or eighteen o six or whatever you want to do those things in
all i could do that was all those equations
one of my favourite examples of an early computer
was done by alan turing
the great computer scientists of all time called the bones
which was designed to break codes
actually used during world war two to break german enigma code and what it was
designed to do
was to solve that specific problem
o point in trying to make is fixed programme computers is where we started but
it doesn't really gets to where we like to be able to capture this idea
of problem solving
so let's see how we get there
so even within this framework of given a description
of of of of computation is a set of steps
and the idea that i could build a circuit to do let me suggest for
what would be a wonderful circuit build
taking care of another way
but i'm going to cook up the domain and interpretation out of gamma
in this
in this way under the assumption that gamma is consistent with that
it's going to be the
the but it's just such a proof
start with the
easy bit
let's start with the additional
calculus so less
forget quantifiers forget variables
forget evaluations
OK forget the mine
we take simple case
we just have axioms
one to three
and this what the interpretations come to
it's just good old truth tables
which is
incorporated in the other more elaborate definition
the semantics of first-order logic
so and usual truth
so OK
now what i'm going to do
start with
and we use the consistent
and we want to find
and interpret it
of the language
which can everything in gamma comes out true
just thinking about
propositional logic for them
do we do
we construct some sets
we construct a big set
a set of formulae
in the following way
it's the union of a sequence of sets
delta zero
there are different ways of starting this you can take it the empty set gamma
has taken to be
to be the
he said
which is
we go through the action at each ten is that we have constructed delta psi
and we're going to construct delta psi by plus one
how however what has are going to do
well we're gonna make reference to
an enumeration
a one a two
in you know the formula
it doesn't have to be a lot
structural properties just every formula comes up exactly once
it's a
infinitely long but that's all right
hundred number of clusters say okay
before we take this k goes to infinity limit
we can as imagine that there's kind of a very large value for k
so in particular if k is very very large then it will be
much larger than n but
n here is gonna be our data set size basically the only the n
data items in our data sets and if k is much larger than n then we
know that there are at most n clusters which will be occupied in the
sense that n clusters are gonna be as
associated with the n data items okay
typically there will be less than n clusters associated with our data
but there can be at most n because every data item can only be assigned
at most one cluster
right so
we know that because if
k is much larger than n most of these k clusters will be basically empty right
they they won't be assigned any data items at all right so they they're empty
and we can kind of lump them all together
okay just to make our competitions more efficient
and if you do that then the conditional distributions for collapsed Gibbs sampler will look like this
so for a cluster k which does have some data item assigned to it
then n k will be positive and the conditional probability of that i equals to
k is gonna be again this conditional prior this is unchanged times the
conditional likelihood of x i
given all the other data items assigned to cluster k
we'll also have the conditional probability of
data item i being assigned to some cluster
which is not
associated with any other data item and you can compute that by basically looking at basically
summing over all of this empty clusters so for each of the empty clusters as we're
gonna have a conditional prior of alpha divided by k
divided by
n minus one plus alpha and we have a conditional
likelihood which is basically
the probability of x i given
that there are no other data items being assigned to that cluster yes
k star is gonna be the number of clusters which
have some data item
assigned to them okay
so these are the non empty clusters so that k minus k star is the number of
empty clusters right so when you sum over those probably these you're gonna get k minus k star
here yes
I'll come to that later actually yeah so basically alpha is gonna be related to
what you expect the the number of clusters you expect to see in your data set okay
I'll come to that in I don't know ten
slides or something
the larger alpha is the the more clusters we we tend to expect to
see okay
we know that k star is the number of occupied clusters and it
will be at most n and n is gonna be much smaller than k if
key is very very large so now we can take k to go to infinity
because in these two equations here when k goes to infinity we see that alpha divided
by k is gonna go to zero
so that's gonna go to zero okay
k minus k star divided by k is gonna go to one
because k star ha is upper bounded by n and k is going to infinity right so this
sta here this ratio here is gonna go to one so that's gonna go to
one alpha times one is just alpha okay
so this is
the infinite limit of the collapsed Gibbs sampler
and basically this gives us a collapsed Gibbs sampler for an infinite mixture model with
an infinite number of clusters okay
and you you can actually implement this and it'll it'll
it'll work very well okay
but actually it kind of doesn't make sense okay as the model itself doesn't make sense
and the reason is because if you look at any particular
cluster in here it'll be assigned basically a
prior probability of zero being
there'll be a
basically so the probability of that particular cluster being assigned to
explain a particular data item will be basically zero okay
and basically the reason is because if you look at the prior the prior
is a is a is a symmetric Dirichlet so the prior probability of cluster k being
particular data item will be just one over big k right
and over big k is gonna go to zero as big k goes to infinity okay
and basically
the wh
the math that we kind of have to go through to actually
derive the Dirichlet process are basically kind of better ways of kind of making this
infinite limit
construction precise what what does it mean what does this infinite limit mean when we
take big k to go to the infinity okay and these two ways
are basically
different ways of looking at a Dirichlet process kind of better ways of making this
precise okay
and basically we can think of a Dirichlet process as a basically infinite dimensional Dirichlet
distribution basically is the think of it as the prior as the limit of the
Dirichlet prior
in our
over the mixi mixing proportins as the number of clusters goes to infinity
okay so I guess I'll move on
to define what is a Dirichlet process okay
before I do so
perhaps I would actually spend two slides on some probability theory
i took in the literature for different nuclei
you see that all these processes are competitions in all these different nuclei have different
intensity different lifetimes
for all these particles decay
because when you want to know is the lifetime of the nucleus
you have to consider for example the least one million two hundred twenty six he
can indicate either by any from capture
alpha particle emission of becoming stick with different like here partial
you don't think the biggest one or you don't take
the some of this life the relation relationship like that so so you have to
add the inverse of the lifetime to deter mine
the last term of the nuclei
so these are some examples of life lies
just said that they can span many orders of magnitude
so included sixteen if you think the well-known carbon fourteen which is
used a lot for the patient
is thousands of years
to tell you for example which is then for twenty eight years
now that i explain what are stability i
what is artificial
which which are rejected which began with one
this one so i have two questions
do you know why be stable nuclei
he knew law
not for all of these and you will be line
why do you have more reach a neutron rich nuclei then
it's beautiful young men and d
and so second question why do we search for new nuclei
concerning one stable nuclei do not follow this line is because of the coulomb repulsion
which is later iterations
so it's not you lose energy when you had a proton because of distribution
so now why don't you have only
neutron neutron rich and reach it because i told you that the proton neutron interaction
then neutron neutron or proton proton
so that's why have in
brien between
nuclear proliferation and proton neutron interaction which is bigger than your
and why do we search for new nuclei
so there are many reasons two of them are
because of the
the nucleon nucleon interaction that we we don't know
we have it in order to have some input some
new discoveries or to know that the behaviour of the
interaction for example for very heavy nuclei
or how it is in
neutron rich we had we need all this new experimental data this is for example
is to see how the spin the evolves when you add new transit is something
the other region is related to the nucleosynthesis pass
because if you are
goulding was astrophysics are stars and you know that many processes
i've been a a few processes been
invoked to understand
these nucleosynthesis and for example you have here is that process
which is capture
of the rapid capture of neutrons and then you have k
this it goes through very exotic and very neutron rich nuclear so if you want
to understand this nucleosynthesis you have in fact very precisely all these exotic nuclei
which had
played which had played a role in the past
for creation of structures and things like that
so where do we look for
all these exotic nuclei
all around the world for example here in san is like these
so they do a lot of experiments i will show you examples of measurement friday
of nuclear i
and many experiment concerning these neutral reject the dignity you have also stipulated to win
which we
in in
you have change then
the project in the US so you have many many
so you have some some facilities that are working on that are under construction
how do we experimentally study a nucleus
so you have different ways
this is one so
soon after what i've presented first concerning the rutherford experiment so elastic and inelastic scattering
you have the project
whatever it is electron positron proton neutron
or maybe i and
that's and then you can detect these particles here
and you have your spectrum depending on the excitation energy and you see some people
that do in fact correspond to the excited levels the state of these new
then you can determine the momentum transfer if you have the energy in different angles
you can determine this momentum transfer
and then you have the form factor
close to be intensity using these different but
you do like for you transform
the last part of this
is related to this
collaborative filtering in transferring but here we try to use a different source data
instead of using the same
collaborative filtering domain reading more
binary data
try to use
wikipedia for example as the source domain and the target domain is the same is
still reading them and and we asked whether it's possible to transfer some knowledge again
to help with the data sparsity problem OK and this is the work done together
with my student change you
now so let's look at some details of this
and this paper is also included in the workshop proceedings so everybody can
already get that from the web
OK so the motivation of
is the following OK
suppose we are interested in helping with recommendation doing better recommendation even one hour reading
data is very sparse
but suppose we don't have
another reading domain to help us with so let's turn to something that everybody has
OK which is the wikipedia
now on the wikipedia
we have
a lot of data which we can model as a bipartite graph of users
and product
the products can be anything can be a document can be an event and in
this particular war we focus on movies OK because them we can we can look
at moving so so we have movies here in the target domain and we look
at the subset of wikipedia
web pages that are about movies and each of these pages
i have a number of editors and these editors are people who have spent their
time and effort in describing this movie in commenting on this movie so you know
they have given some readings
on this movie
and another way
we can look at
whether the same user commented twenty from movies
and use this knowledge to link similar movies together
OK so then intuition becomes this even though we have various bars user movie rating
now it's almost like using wikipedia we can relate some movies together and we can
relate some users together OK so symmetrically the movies link different users together now however
we cannot guarantee that these user and these users are the same but we can
these movies and these movies together so let's focus on using the relationship between movies
so it's so think of it as a consisting of a taxonomy ontology that really
movies so as a result maybe we can do better recommendation even though the data
is very sparse OK so this is the intuition
we had to work
if you look at wikipedia pages about movies we can see many many of these
examples like kung-fu panda there's already a page there
this is a popular movie
in some less popular
i don't know but maybe so there there are other links
OK there are other things
all right so
we can represent as i said users
and editing information as zero one so one means this this editor edited something about
this movie
and we have this matrix here
the experiment we have here is really focused on a simple question so we call
this system
call it can call it
the name is rather long so you can read the paper about it but generally
it means if we have the extra information about
the wikipedia so x is the original data then we can append a part of
this matrix to this so you can see the the users are different but the
movies are
aligned because they have the same name and so on
so when we do this matrix factorisation hopefully this is better than not using this
however the states along this path of type
and i want i think that's in that this brain might be successful for all
branches of successful
this goes
that's ok your infinitely often
i know it's all for you
but there is still play the game with the example
if i want my branch
because you
so far the branch opened
my computer city
so imagine
here is the branch
there's no way
you will have here branch was just q a
and she
the column
twenty one
it would be one
this input
classified and a
like you
boxcar that when i mean topics canvassing with a topless women talk
does that nokia infinitely often in this set
this is even
so it will be accepting here
is not successful
the entire cover
so actually what does this automatically
portraits in this automaton accepts
it will accept
which is a branch of the tree
you will not
he was it to be
which means that this is the one
you will not be even and you will a o
with this notion of contracts make you another example
so this is exactly what we said
for example
that you will eventually hit a while labels
this is
all successor remained that really have to fulfil
part of the formula
but does in this set but does it to find out what has happened to
the events related opportunities to this
for me here
OK let's do this
this article so i want an automaton
of trees and what is it with infinite one is enough
at least one
so let's see what with
i have three states
they'll q
it's it's
the thing so whichever state in which is not
if is a
well i'm happy actually i would like to see more often
i can get
you have a choice
one of the automaton
on the same thing
because nondeterministic it to be accepting
why it is accompanied features
this transition of this transition
the following when i
meat and a
in the past where
b either
in the left subtree of
so if my guess
so that
i want it with this
the square to go and do away with his q
q eight expect right OK
i got to say state q
how to tell me that they have met b
interested in exhibiting one best
so at this step
when i mean to choose
by choosing this side of this size
continues on the left to right subtree
so imagine my my my input is correct there is that there is the best
for each training point we will lear in the combination of training points that created
the weight vector so there's one alpha for each training point and
so this is now I M M I'm using to denote the size of
the training set and X X primed is is also an M by M matrix so now we can actually write the dual solution it's a it's a
a very similar problem to solve it's a set of linear
equations we need to solve but but as I said before it's actually of
different dimensions to the the set of equations we were
solving for W and now if we want regress on a new point
what do we do okay we we take X primed W but now W
of course is X capital X primed times alpha that's how it's
expressed so if we now write that out explicitly
sum alpha rhi xi by the linearity of the inner
product we can bring the sum outside and we actually express this G of X as the sum
weighted sum of the inner products between the test point and
the training data okay so now the key observation here is
that we actually only need to compute inner product between
test points in training data and this matrix actually only
involves inner products between training data the entry
the I J entry in this matrix is just the inner product
between the I and J training points that's
because remember the rows of X were the training data therefore the columns of X prime to the training data so
the I J entry in this matrix is the I throw in a product
with the J column which is just the inner product
between the I and J training points in the input space
the way I've done it okay so the key ingredients are you now I'm using this K a little bit sort of a suggestively
here kernel to denote this because as I said the K I J
entry is just the inner product between the I J training
points the evaluation of a new point is again now the
weighted weighting of these inner products with new test point and the training data weighted according to this alpha rhi that we got by
solving this set of equations here so the key observation
here is that both steps this step here and this step here only involve inner
products between input data points okay here we have X the test point and the training data and here we just have inner
products between training data so remember what I said
before the kernel provides a short cut to compute the inner
product between projections of data points in to a complex feature
space and then take the inner products okay cool well here if we just substitute in some
feature vectors phi of X I phi of X J and similarly here phi
of X phi of X I some feature vector then all we're needing here is the kernel function to
compute that inner product it's an inner product of projections
into a feature space of input data and so we can substitute a kernel function here I suggested by
this K and similarly here we have a kernel function
between the test point and the training data so this is the key idea so it only involves
occurrences of the inner product a kernel function
computes that inner product in the kernel defined feature
space and so we can apply the ridge regression algorithm in
that high-dimensional potentially high-dimensional feature
space by just substituting the kernel function for
the computation of this matrix here the I J entry of this
matrix here and the kernel function for the evaluation of
this new point so it's sort of a little bit a magic
you kind of apparently operating in this very high-
dimensional space without actually explicitly computing in
it by using this this trick okay well you may say do
such functions exist I mean give me an example I
mean maybe this kernel function is gonna be just as
difficult to compute as actually computing these explicit
vectors and taking an inner product so what I wanna do now is show
you an example very simple example just to convince you that yes you know there are
very natural ways of using defining kernel functions
that do correspond very interesting high-dimensional
feature spaces so here's the first sort of nontrivial
example of a kernel function it's the so-called quadratic kernel so what you do
is you simply take the inner product between the feature
vectors in the input space and then you just square that
number okay so it's one extra computation one extra
jeff questions about you know products
so this is the first very very very simple classifier
so imagine that you have two sets of points
two sets of labeled points
from each year from four from from which you're going to to learn classifiers so
you have the blue points here
the red one here
those are your training points and those are the points that you're going to use
to construct your model
and don't forget the details for not just what the very simple thing as i
say that i'm going to take
in the middle of the
red points here in the middle of the the blue points here
i'm going to draw a line between those two in the middle points and i
say that i'm going to say that
if the point
it's closer to
c-minus than c plus then i'll say that these points should be classified as an
as minus
as it has a negative point otherwise if a point is closer to c plus
than c-minus then i'll say that it should be classified as a plus
it is very very simple
there's nothing to do it and you'll see that the the
mathematics is also very simple so
here you have the
centre of mass
it should be something like that
the centre of mass of the price point the positive points and the centre of
mass the mass of the negative points
so yes he plus that is just the mean of all the exercise
you see plus
seen minus which is
the mean or the average points of all
the minus points
you have
the middle of c-minus and c plus which is just
one half of c plus plus c minus
OK this is something that i told told you about just before if you want
to to compute the mean of two points you just add the two vectors and
you divided by two and you have made of the point
and the vector that i'm going to use to to do classification
is called w
i think i'm consistent with that are always call
classification vector w
one of the the slide
and so the decision function is very simple
i said that i would classify points test points x according to which of the
two class means c plus or c one c minus is closed
so it's very easy to do that
you just take the inner product between
w here
and the vector x
again if those two vectors
o point to the same direction
then you're going to say that that the inner product is positive and you're going
to say that the the point x is positive or otherwise it's just the other
way around if the the inner product is negative then it means that x minus
cnw point two opposite directions
and you're going to classify
as minus point
but then again if
and the classifier is just these very simple function here
so it's based on these on these real valued function
which is a measure of x
which is exactly equal to w inner product with x minus c
and you want to predict the class just take the sign of these these values
these inner product if the sign is positive if the if the inner product is
positive then you say that x x should be classified as positive example
if the inner product is negative and you say
that the the test point should be classified as as negative as the negative point
and the decision surface is induced by these decision rules
it is just
these hyperplane
so remember that what what something told you
just a
she told you that hyperplane in the dimension d dimensional space just a d minus
the national dimensional space
so here it is the two dimensional space hyperplane is just like
in three dimensional space hyperplane is
the plane
now we're we're are going to go into the details of computing hf x
again this very easy to be freaked out
here if you compute edge effects
i say that this is the inner product between w and x minus c
what i do here is that i place
one more
because of my view or
and some of them
i mean
in the area
what we're seeing or be or
we're i going why to be
one of the problem users
we are not
what we
you one
so that they are
some of
the phone content is provided by MIT opencourseware under a creative commons license
additional information about relations and MIT opencourseware in general is available OCW MIT the EU
the molecular orbital theory
remember what the key idea was there
the key idea
let's take the wave functions
atomic wavefunctions wavefunctions on the atoms that are going to form the chemical plant
take those functions and let them overlap
let them
constructively and destructively interfere a rather ways
they can constructively and destructively interfere
we saw last time
when these atomic wavefunctions constructively interfere
the result was a molecular wavefunctions that was a bonding
one way function
consequently antibonding state
so for example in the case of oxygen
we hear
two s wavefunctions i need to be isolated oxygen atoms when they
they can constructively to tivoli interfere
to form a sigma two as finding wavefunctions
and consequently sigma two s
finding date
and there are two electrons in there
and you remember that we label the molecular state
with respect to the symmetry of the wave function around the molecular axis
that way function with sigma
if that symmetry was
cylindrical around the molecular axis
it was part i
here in this case from molecular oxygen
when the weight function
it was not cylindrically symmetric around the bond axis
and we also saw what happened when these two wave functions come together they overlap
and they destructively interfere when they destructively interfere
we perform what we call the nancy bonding
the weight function
given designations
in the case here the two as electrons are away functions and oxygen this form
the sigma two s wavefunction the antibonding wave function its energy
is higher
than that of the
atomic state
for the two separated oxygen atoms bonding state is lower in energy into finding state
is higher in energy
and so this was for the two s electrons
well all this
right lower energy
because the more strongly bound are though one as atomic states
and the molecular states formed by the
constructive and destructive interference with the one as wavefunctions i didn't draw there
US that higher energy
and finally here here the two p states that are coming together and molecular oxygen
forming a sigma
two PC
and then two
molecular states pi two PY and applied to px
and then in molecular oxygen we also saw
that there was one electron each
here in the US
hi star two px i start PY
OK now
i just wanted to say a few words here about
the physical significance of these energies here
so this is the molecular orbital
in the case of molecular oxygen here this is the
molecular state that is highest occupied
right what we mean by highest occupied is that it is the state
that is the highest flying in energy
is an electron in the highest flying in energy
what this binding energy means
what this energy means
so you can prove this by induction could prove this by induction saying well
base cases one equals or one OK that's true
OK and the induction step is well if i know that and minus one so
let's suppose that and minus one is order one
that implies
which is an minus one
plus one
well that this is order one
and this one is order one so the whole thing is order one and and
that's true if you knew that and minus one was order one n one is
that one then their some is also order one but this is the false proof
you can't you can inductive abigail's what's going on here is that the concepts that
are implicit in here changing here you bigger one areas in big o one you're
probably doubling the constant in that every time you do this relation if you have
a finite number of doubling of constance no big deal just the concept to the
power number of dublin's but here you're doing n dumplings and that's not good
the constant is getting
the cost is now depending on and so we're avoiding this kind of problem by
writing out the constant we have to make sure that cost doesn't change
so good
OK so now written not the costs and i should be safe is what what
i need to prove this is assuming it for all k less than them and
i have to prefer k equal there
so i'm going to take
and i just expanded can going do the obvious thing i had this recurrence how
to expand here than that of most even over two and i know
some facts about human over two because to two is less than n
six pantera and is four times the of two
was and
and now i have an upper bound on this thing
from the induction hypothesis
so this is
time c
times the argument q plus and
i have a feeling
by the end of last lecture
his blackboard so
what's gonna
OK how have board
i'd like to say my super-human strength but i believe it's from the quality of
the blackboard
the hinge is OK so continuing on here let's expand this little bit
we have
OK so we end up with nq over two q and to keep his eight
for eight years i have
so we have to have
times c
time and q class and
and what i'd like this to be
is the bottom would like to go is that this is at most c times
and q
that's what i'd like to prove to establish re-established induction hypothesis for and
so what i'll do in order to see when that's the case is just write
this as what i want to this sort of the desired
value see times and q minus whatever i don't want this
called the residual
now i have to actually figure this out c where c and q but only
have cm cube here so i need to subtract off half c q
to get that we term correct and i have plus and a minus here says
OK and that's the residual in order for this to be announced this i knew
that the residual is nonnegative this is if
and the residual part
is greater than equal to zero
which is pretty easy to do because here i have control over c
i get to pick c to be whatever i want
and as long as c is at least to
and this is o or one
at least i have an cubes should be greater or equal to n and that's
always the case
so this is for example
this is true if c
is it atleast one
and i don't think it matters what n is let's say
and there's atleast one just four
OK so we get
what we done is prove that he then is the most some constant times and
q then the costs is like one
so that's an upper bound is not tight upperbound we actually believe that m squared
and it is
but you can still means here have to be a little careful this is not
the the answer is and just means it's most mksp government q
and this was approved by induction now technically i should have put the base case
in this section is a little bit missing the base case is pretty easy because
t want some constants
but it will sort of influence things the base case
if you want some concepts and what we need is that is at most c
times one q which is c
and that will be true as long as you choose c to be sufficiently large
so this is true if c is chosen
sufficiently large
now we don't care about constants but
the point is just to be a little bit careful
it's not true
the teevan then is at most one times m squared even if you're all we
need is this is at least one for the base case to work c actually
might have to be a hundred or whatever t one s
this would be a little bit
careful the
it doesn't really affect the answer usually won't but because we have very simple base
cases here
so let's try to prove
the tight bound
order and squares
i'm not going to prevent make about where you can prove in america and spread
and as well using substitution method
this be satisfied for now
the upper bound and square
so let's try
to prove that here this the the same
recurrence i want that
so i'm going to
do the same thing already bit faster consists basically copying
so now instead of three i have two
so then i have you then
four times tumour number two was and i expand
this team in order to this is that most four times see times and over
two square loss and and now instead of having to queue to have two squared
which is only four force council
i can see
times and squared plus and
and if you prefer to write as desired minus residual then i have c and
squared minus negative and and what i need is that i want
this to be nonnegative
it is damn hard for minus ten to be nonnegative is zero or happy version
this is an induction on it's got hold for all n greater than equal to
this is
less than or equal to
c and
notice the temptation
it is to write that this equals big open square
which is true for this one step
c times m squared minus
mines and what i mean these are both order and
this is order and disorder and spread certainly this thing is order and square that's
true but it's not completing the induction to complete the and actually have to prove
thank you
four of
five for while
o five
well here
he also worked on the
thing here where we've found over x we can basically bring the summation
inside here and just some you want over
equation two
and divided by equation three
on the left-hand side what you get is
joint probability of x y and be divided by the probability of y and b
and we know that
by the definition of
conditional probability that the probability of x
given y and b dividing this by this
on the right-hand side when we divide this by this is what we get when
we get whatever that cancelling
we get this factor g cancelling
and so we get this expression
so what was the point of all that
well the interesting thing about that expression is
the right hand side of this expression
is no longer functionally dependent on y
this doesn't depend on y
and from that it follows that
it is independent of y
given the
this thing here
no longer depends on y and so on
we can
basically defined that to be
the probability of x given the
and if we were to compute the probability that can be directly we get we
could write this equation is well from that
and therefore
the fac torisation we had in equation two implies the conditional independence in
in this statement one
right this is how we generally get from factorizations the probability distributions statements about conditional
independence and we we can apply this simple logical argument too
basically proof
essentially all the claims i'm going to make about conditional independence for
factor graphs directed graphs undirected graphs that in the same kind of reasoning
like we did in the previous slide
all right
so that was factor graphs let me now talk about undirected graphical models which
are older but very similar to factor that
so in an undirected graphical model
the joint probability over all variables can be written
in factored form
so we say the joint probability of all the variables represent that is the vector
going from one xk
is some normalisation constant times the product over j
of factors j
where each factor is just the function of
subset j
of the set of all variables one
so are subsets of the set of all variables
and the notation
x with
with the
it's one of the subset is just
think of it as the vector of all the axes that belong in that
that's what except cj
so here's how you specify a graph
an undirected graph starting from
knowledge that you're trying to publish crucial factors in this way
you create a node for each variable
and then you connect nodes i and k
if they exist
sorry if there exists some set cj such that both
i cj and k is change in other words if i and k participate in
common factor you connect directly to each other so in undirected graphical model doesn't have
two kinds of nodes is just
you know like we saw in the first slide
the nodes with undirected links between them
all of the variables in some subset will be connected to each other
so all the variables of the cj for example the connected to each other
and that means that these that are formed
cliques of the graph in other words they form a fully connected subgraph
of the whole graph
undirected graphical models are also called markov networks still hear that term
markov got his name associated with too many things i think so let's call the
undirected graphical models is the more descriptive than
markov network
so here's an undirected graphical model
the undirected graph here basically a third that
the joint probability of these variables factors into the product of
a function
this is clearly a c that simply connected subgraph this clique PCD another point directly
so i'll i give you a hint
so imagine that had vectors and
and that is that was wrong from
from the normal distribution
we here the identity matrix so we know how to sample that guy because we
just repeatedly sample of value for of its dimensions OK
if i if i multiply guy by matrix face a times OK and i call
this vector
OK what is the covariance matrix of u
so the covariance matrix of u
is equal to the times transpose OK
if that's the case now i almost know how to sample from from a multivariate
gaus right
indeed any two i need to sort of decompose my covariance matrix
in two into something that looks like
times and transpose OK the sort of the first
that's sort of the first step so which which the compositions could i take of
of the covariance matrix that would help me
as one of the slide
so i could take the i can the composition right but is there any other
thing i could do
i could take the cholesky decomposition for example
or i could take
some new form of
the matrix square root or basically anything that that the composer sigma into the product
of two
matrices modulo transposed right
the interesting thing so it's OK so let's just this is costly right i i
do this i i take the i can value decomposition right
and i take sort of
sort of half of it so to say right so i take the
i can vectors and i scaled them by
the square root of the eigen values
right and then what you get is again is orthogonal basis OK and now that
bayes actually is the base that is going to rotate my
sort of
my my round
is going to scale and rotated basically
so the interesting thing is that
this is actually
very related to PCA
so in which ways is related to PCA world
if we were to walk
backwards in a certain sense so now we're starting with the covariance matrix before we
see the data right was sort of say well that's the covariance matrix that i
want because this is the gas distribution i want to sample from right
but now things could be things could be different right i can sort of say
o i've seen as in data
OK now i compute the empirical covariance matrix of these data
and you know that this is the first that when you do PCA right this
second set when you PCA is you go on and do this
you give yourself
you sort of learn with the directions of maximum variance our
OK so this is like
using PCA backwards to sample from gauss
sampling from a gaussian is is nice it's it's exciting perhaps perhaps not but the
interesting thing is if we want to model data
what we want to do really is we're gonna see some data OK and when
we're going to ask ourselves what is the mean and the covariance matrix
one of the gaussians the generated that this data OK
you can you can simply
you can simply write the probability
of the data
given the specific choice of parameters for multivariate gaussians already the if we did this
and we saw three datasets and we tried three different values we can go in
and evaluate the likelihood
on the specific choice of parameters right
and now if we did this in this case we can see that
the model that has the highest likelihood is actually the one over there
it's not very surprising right
so using the likelihood function
what we can do
actually this
again in this case if you if you were to assume
that the samples have been drawn independently
you can just take
that of being wrong
and i started from section to section right
wise our
d dimensional vectors
so what would you do if it if that thing was an i i d
and what we want to learn is the properties of the function
OK so learning corresponds to finding
a good covariance function
this a little bit different from the way people talk about learning support vector machines
we think about learning support vector machines acted find the support vectors find a separating
for fixed
again this in this scenario in mind not finding the kernel
OK so so how would we actually do that so let's say we have covariance
functions that have some parameters and show them on the next slides if we had
that we have a bunch of parameters that just try to optimize the marginal likelihood
with respect the from
the computers
don't worry about it
let's try this example so you have the covariance function
which now has some promises and say that the green function here is it has
the same form
but i introduced a bunch of problems that is l
which is called the lengthscale
now also in the interest of the media was related to the amplitude of the
of the of the thing
now the covariance function
tells you
what is the covariance between the values
as a function of the input the function of the axis
what it tells you what the covariances between the
the function that we've been using so far as it has this is the squared
exponential form
the idea is that if x is close to each other
then the corresponding values should have high compare
it should have something to do with each other
whereas if the axes are often each other
then the the the covariance here is very close to zero
the corresponding eigenvalues
i don't have much to do with each other
could be independent
we haven't really
i he said well what do we mean by close what do we mean by
far away
and so i introduced from l here which called the lengthscale which tells me exactly
what do i mean by far away
so tell me scale
the on which to measure
distances between x and x y
so by doing this
i can see i can now say to my my learning algorithm i can say
to my process well i think underlying is my underlying function is small
but i'm not so sure exactly on what scale
this is something i would like to know
well this is something that we want to learn about
l three parameter here
and we want to do inference for
so similar to this problem is less interesting this just gives you it's me the
overall magnitude of the covariance
it's actually gives it may be the variance of signal so whereas the problem here
sort of structures the the the the x-factor the b
values of structures the y
let's try this out
let's try out doing inference
on a particular dataset twenty
data point here
now i just tried to do inference and i just want the mean function
the posterior mean function
based on the data points for different values of l
and that he will happen
OK so let's let me try first to take very short
thanks so else be a very small number
i forget exactly what number is
then i get
the following the following me but i get the red line
the red line kind of
kind of looks good from the point of view that it fits the data very
the goes
almost through every data point is very close to every data point
but i i and we might be worried about
about whether this is actually a good fit to the data might be that this
is actually it's actually picking up a lot of the noise in the data set
maybe we don't really believe that the thing is sensible
you might be happy about the fact that it cannot actually represent
something which is quite complicated
and that's why to pick out to be very long
we have very long lengthscale
in that case we get a little bit
the problem with the properties that doesn't really reflect the
the distribution of the data very well because it forces things that are quite far
to be highly correlated
because i think that things should be really far apart before the correlation
go away in that case itself struggling to model the data
and there's a good length scale the the green line here
this is actually the length scale
that optimizes that has the maximum value of the marginal likelihood
and that has that gives some of them more visually and more
it's the data
this comes close to something we're talking about our yesterday
that the mere fact that you can fit training data you could get too excited
about that
the red line actually fits much better
the marginal likelihood doesn't really like
but in favour that as well
but there's something wrong with your complexity in that
let's fine fine look at that
a little bit more than happy so again this plot showed before sure yesterday
in this case
yes it does
much more intuitive
nation of what these functions look like so again i have a much like here
i have all possible datasets on the x axis and today and even more abstract
representation because it's all possible
observations you could have for any function
this is that this is pretty weird
o thing
but the interesting thing is that the marginal likelihood is the probability distribution over the
data that the data sets of size
now the
the the two simple
the function here correspond to
situation where you can only model that very small subset of the data
for example happens for the line here so long lengthscale
somehow corresponds to a very small model class but you know it can only model
but extremely small things
whereas the red line here and do
and how can model of a lot of different functions can agree with allowing spend
a lot of different
in this blog
the columns don't match i realized that this party
it's a very weak line from before
and actually gives
and significantly nonzero marginal likelihood to lots and lots of different
but because of that
the the the actual value of this thing because it has to integrate to one
actually quite low
the when are of particular data set up here
the marginal likelihood is not that high
thank you guys
this is
joint work with alex is and higher jonathan gross and markus schulz
carnegie mellon
i'll start by
explained very
if you very simple
o thing we all know
we will have encountered
o finite support signals
our experience and we know that we can compute the discrete time fourier transform
of those
this formula right here
that is we can actually compute
this value by some polynomial whose
quite efficient are exactly the entries in the signal by developing this polynomial over the
unit circle
a finite version a finite representation of the
can be
computed by evaluating the same polynomial
only in the roots of unity
that's the
the discrete fourier transform
o of the signal
OK we can say that as the length of the signal goes to infinity the
discrete fourier transform approaches the discrete time fourier transform by the fact that
the sampling of the serious is finer and finer
OK but that's not all
usually when we talk about
four year transforms of the signals we assumed implicitly that
the signal is extended periodically
and as a result we have the circular convolution
and this in turn corresponds to see click
the cyclic boundary conditions so
this is exactly what's depicted in this picture so if you were to
find out what is the next value of the
o of the signal we could just turn back to
the left and the whole thing is being
OK so
the question that we're this here is how can we design transforms
that imply more general
other than periodic signal extensions of boundary conditions and
we can do that using the
the framework of algebraic theory of signal processing
and we will now show here how we can design a large class of such
transforms that
corresponding to non circular notion of coalition and singer extension
as the signal
o thing infinity they will approach the
discrete time free transfer
and they afford fast implementation or light blue
square them and as
we know they could even go to from the
classic free
OK so
what is this algebraic theory of signal processing
has been explained introduced in a paper large paper by by mark mark this challenge
is more in two thousand six
and now it has been published in the united drapery transactions of signal processing and
it has
the central
elements central concept
a set of filters
linear systems which form an algebra
now to run by the way is a vector space which is also a weak
so you can use the same
o operations in the UK you can use the addition
vector space and you can also multiply
and the other a central concept is the set of signals
which is an a module
and that means
it's also
the vector space but we can afford we can have an external operations from the
elements of
eight to the elements of m
so what are the
the notions
in signal processing
what is the correspondence with his algebraic setting
well start with
with the signal
namely for this module which is a vector space we can pick a basis
and we can see
signal as a linear combination of
elements in the basis and
we can actually
find more
the more concrete representation foresight to signal by taking the set of coefficients
so here the set of indices could be finite or infinite
this the filters
the elements of the algebra as i said before
and in coordinates there will be represented as matrices
and this makes sense is consistent with the fact that applying the filter two
signal you get back signal so applying matrix the vector given
the impulse
impulse response
our own
trivial you define what's more interesting is the notion of fourier transform
OK so
our module as
vector space can be written
as the direct sum
small dimensional vector spaces
and they are indexed by this
coming my here
lots of tables ready then we expect to see even more tables in the future
so so you can also work out the EPP F of the of
this two parameters CRP yes it has to be between zero and one we
know that if it's greater than one then this thing may not be well
defined if there's only one customer at the table yeah yeah
you can do that except that the model that you would get would not be
exchangeable anymore it was to be projected because this is a sequential process but
it won't be exchangeable and if you want exchangeability then so far as we
know this is probably the most general form that people have worked with anyways there
is kind of a generalization of this Pitman Yor process called species sampling models which the
probability theories have looked at and that gives us that gives you a bit more
flexibility so we can show that the EPP of this two parameters CRP is of this form
and you can also see that it will be projective because it's sequential and it
will be exchangeable because this EPPF doesn't depend on the way that the customers
are labelled it only depends on the sizes of the clusters and the number of
clusters and again because is projective and exchangeable we can apply De Finetti's theorem and
De Finetti0s measure that corresponds to this process will be the Pitman Yor process and this
is a generalization of the Dirichlet process I guess the idea of power-law properties was
really mentioned a little bit yes yes for clustering
type of problems it seems that you probably do want to use a
Dirichlet process over Pitman Yor process unless you do believe that there are huge number
of very small clusters they do have
different effects so alpha just changes the overall number of clusters the D parameter
we'll come to this actually in the next two slides will affect the ratio of
the number of big clusters to the number of small clusters so the larger D is
the more there will be very small clusters there will be lots of very small clusters yes
sorry think of D as a regulizer I tend to think of
D as a way of putting a prior over the kind of over the data basically
you're kind of saying that you expect your data to x exhibit power-law properties and
D actually controls the power-law the structure of the power-law so I tend to think
of it as a prior instead of a regularization right so it's again
related to this idea that we have a rich richer property of the Pitman
Yor and a property that if we have lots of tables then we tend to
see more new tables okay so both of his properties if you put them together you
find that there will be lots of tables with a very small number of customers
because if you have lots of tables then you have to have necessary lots of small tables
beca you because you only have a fixed number N of customs and it turns
out that if you combine these two to together then you get actually a power-law property
of Pitman Yor processes okay and the nice thing with this is that because there's lots
of natural phenomena that has power-law properties it's makes it quite a natural model to use
so far as I know I think people mentioned that they hadn't really explored models
for that have this sort of power-law property prior to this this rediscovery of the Pitman
Yor process Dirichlet learning community so here's kind of a demonstration of the
power-law property so this is the original Dirichlet process where D equals to zero
and we see that the number of tables grows quite slowly okay here we have
a Pitman Yor process where the D parameter's set to a half and alpha is
set to one and we see that the number of tables grows quite quickly
compared to the a number of set alpha to be one here otherwise
it would have blown up to be a few thousand tables instead of a few
hundred tables okay and we see that there's lots of this tables out here where they
are very sparse and what that says is that the tables has very small number
i think we should
we try to prove this one as well
this one hand
this one
so let's
well it's actually if you want to control them but maybe down here gets a
bit more missus and this one is relatively difficult
this one is and what will the mathematicians
this is easy this is easy but so let's say try to
to some of those
up to here
the interplay between the definition
end i have some hints here
maybe for the first one i don't give you a hint
therefore the second one had this hint written here
so the hint is that you have to write down the ground matrix remember the
gram matrix or kernel matrix is the matrix of
the dot product between all training points
he the training points on the x and ex-prime minister two by two matrix
and then think about
the above properties this this matrix sorry determinant have in the case that the matrix is positive definite
the hint is
you can prove this one by using this one so it has proved this one
these to our basic elementary
by substituting into the definition so i'll give you
another few minutes and and play around a bit between it and then we'll see
maybe taking how many of you have solved three or more problems
how many have two or more
one or more
zero more
you're not answering my questions i
okay i give it to my minutes and then we'll do that here
looking at that's the first one and i want ask a question i wanted
and so the case that in all these cases are positive case have enough positive definite kernels
so that's the assumption
it's a sequence of all the
problem of positive definite
and if the limit exists but
i mean you don't have to prove this one
if you if you go up real it's enough and we went gonna need this one still here
so that's the first one the first and we're actually going to need
someone have an idea how to do it
you can either do it he'll just tell me and i'll do it
i'm sure some people have solved the first one
you speak louder
okay so i think i i think you're saying
one of is to be one and end
everything else zero
more equivalently you could say
you just
i want to take one data point
right because here
and we say that
with the laser pointer again
any set of training points so in particular it could be said that only is one element
so that's the that's
so we take only one element so the sum goes only from one to one
we can remove the sum
we only have one way we set it to one
so we get one times one times payoff
x one
it's positive
so we done
so the first one was easy it
and it means that the diagonal elements of such income
and of course also for kernel matrix are always non-negative
so if you have negative diamonds you know it's not a positive definite kernel
so let's look at the second one which is a generalization of the
cushy schwartz inequality that you probably know from dot products
so any ideas how to prove the second one
this fact
so that you construct the gram matrix four
the training points
x x prime
so let's write down a grammar tricks
okay and now
okay gram matrix is positive definite
is non-negative front
so the gram matrix is positive definite in our notation
which still includes i value zero therefore the determinant is non-negative
straight line is that the term is nonnegative and then
we calculate the determinant
so the determinant is this times this
anything else
this is greater than zero and now we have to use the fact that case symmetric
so this is actually
okay x x prime squared
and now if we take a shot look at
what we have here
it should be
the same
so we move this to the other side
and then we have the upper bound which is this thing here
it's quite okay
any questions
so let's do the next one
any ideas hard so the next one
also from the determinant
so you are
we want to compute the determinant or you want to what you want to use this one
you can use the same one right you can
so you can
you can simply say
i subset i write this one down
well maybe i don't well let's let's write it
so in the general case we have we know
this is true now
and we know that this is true
now if it's the case that cave x x is zero for all x
in particular is also easier for x x prime
it doesn't matter anyway this thing is zero
so the we have an upper bound on the square thing which is zero
therefore the thing itself is also zero
should we do they other ones as well
not x i think it might not be using them but
relatively easy so we can briefly to them
i five times kate
how do we prove that's
you know
is okay
with the
we you
okay so he's saying it's easier to do all this for visualizing the archaeologists
they follow directly so
there's a few additional within the arcade maybe that's the easiest way
only one one note of caution
radiation will go through beautifully
and this will then be the value of c
the value of k
is negotiable
that value for kx
must be the value that i had earlier where is it that must be by
divided by
eight let me write it down again
so for any equals one
k of x
must be by
so far what this crazy
that just itself
sort it meets the boundary conditions kx
does not just itself kx has no choice
kx must meet the boundary conditions so that the vector
vanishes is actually closer when x equals
and so
solution must lie on this curve and so it kesey that pays the price
and that
just itself
so keep in mind that all radiation with frequency above this value you
i can go through this gap
there is often a misunderstanding among students they think that they are resonance frequencies that
i know resonance frequencies
any frequency above that value can go
through the get
you can immediately see here
that's the phase velocity is larger than c
because the phase velocity is only god divided by kesey
so when i draw this line
then this slope here
omega divided by cases that slope is larger than this flow
and that
correspond to
speed c
so you see things this slope
this deeper
the phase velocity is larger than c
and you see that when you read the situation that casey becomes zero
that then
you have
this is only god divided omega a case zero and so when you reach
this crazy
cutoff frequency the phase velocity
goes to infinity
also notice that the tangent here
is the group velocity
that is the only god k
and notice that this slope is smaller than this one
that is why the group velocity is lower than c
and also notice that when you reach this kind of frequency
that the tangent is like this
that means the group velocity is zero
nothing can go
the gap anymore
so i now want to write down for you
something that may help you later if you want to
i understand you notes
i'll put this back up again
i'm going to do the following experiment always you in my head
i started with a certain frequency omega
and i'm going to
lower that frequency i do in my habits duncan experience going to write down step-by-step
what's going to happen
this point will slow to go down and so we will come down this line
and finally we which here
i probably can write it yet it's is nicer for you
because then you have it all together
so i started his omega which is larger than omega c that's how i start
to give
and i'm going to law omega
the next thing that i'm going to do
it's going to look at the moment
when when you lonely guy
it must remain quiet over a
because it must meet the boundary conditions
therefore case gets smaller
going down this line indicates he gets more
only guys casing
always k time c
so clearly if only guy comes down
OK must come down
and that means kesey comes down in this case because kx is not going to
give up
and so came gets more
and if k get smaller
then of course
let those two pi over k
disaster strikes
o god becomes omega c
and when you reach that point
casey has become zero
and kx is still built by over a
OK places
there is now zero
and kx
still pi over a
so now k itself
this kx
and several other now
is two pi
divided by
that value kx
and that means
two pi divided by kx means that lambda them now
he calls
two a
it means if i have a different frequencies
which we do have here which i cannot change i have ten gigahertz
and get pending covers has the wavelengths of three centimetres in fact