like were like a a a a a a a a right now the other people who are low on following a with
all over the world but also catalogue acting but also did
not have the time and he had a a offered its head of each
other but I don't think it is just ps pp the Howard and given that the wrong sitting better exact algorithms
we need to result approximation so many many applications
we need to consider the possibility of schemes so idea is simply to ignore the
fact that we have a graph general for of tree training just apply that
belief propagation algorithm that some products algorithm
to the general graphs so just keep propagating these local messages around and
see what happens the problem that is that it might not converge um make
converges make version of that all set on the other hand we
may just the updating these things forever nothing city
interesting happens and this is very much open research
issue nobody really I'm to a lot of research on this topic at the moment to try to
prove theorems all understand the circumstances you might
get convergence and so on some progress has been made that
is still some of the problems that is a very interesting problem because the wrong
examples of an example of company decoding algorithms
interoperating codes in which the state of the art
algorithms corresponds to this this procedure is just
really believe propagation you believe propagation to
prosecutors so all the sum of all the say that all of these
ones situation in which is the best known of the algorithm
and of course at the track of interest so it's easy to
apply it may or may not work so it might be worth trying to find the most difficult to say much more massive and
that I'm a decided not to go through the junction tree
algorithm in detail pot because even a chance to starting
to look very a short and I think of the Socialist I find
more interesting overall talk about the notes I think a recently self contained again the Renault priest in here pretty the user theorems
news news is somewhat time consuming laborious so that the
idea is a fairly simple you just read viewgraph military
the flavour of the geometry of of summary of the focus on working towards from thinking about variation inference as
a as a as approximate inference framework so that's so I'm stocks in that direction so let's just think a little bit less
than 1st kind of abstract to sort of do these across the initial
independent properties all very abstract it's all seeing
very far away from the machine learning so analysis not
make some links between the things the familiar from
machine learning some of the techniques for the graphic
models and then that will take on world thinking about
restoration methods so according this this is just going to be a revision so
that we can go through this reasonably quickly so let's
suppose that X is all because the policy we're measuring
and we have a capital and observations index of the set of
all these observations local D. that's all data set of
training data set out in the simplest case these
observations all independent and so we can write down the
probability of the data set and you in terms of some with and the song parametric model so if we have a a parametric
model for x which depends on some parameters dataset than the
probability of the data set is the product of the data
points of the probability for each observation given data
and we take this quantity if we view this as a function of
theta but it's called the likelihood function and the the likelihood of a word and used and in all sorts
of ways in this is the regret definition of likelihood that is the
probability that a given the premises viewed as a function
of the premises and notice that is not a probability
distribution of the data this just a function of the you
know the simplest procedures in very widely used which
using these parameters based on the training data is the
list of learning the parameters of the model is full
maximum likelihood that it just as it will assess the premises to specific
them to such that it maximizes the probability of the data set and
practices convenient and thank the logarithm and published in America reasons but also converts this for brought into some and uh can simplify the these expression sometimes but it is completely equivalent because law as a moment of
functions the maximum likelihood solution is just obtained
by a maximum maximizing the love of the likelihood function
and then given that solution we don't want to to but the
training phase now we want to make predictions that was the
it's quite instructive to look at
what different
results these two learning algorithms could have
unfortunately it didn't the ten factor lecture that he talk about an example for the
difference between off policy and on policy
alex where you there
did explain it quite well or
that could help so this very nice example also by certain and
by sutton and barto
which is a relatively simple problems
you know most of these reinforcement learning algorithms are never really tested but only tested
in so-called great world but the favourite toy of reinforcement learning researchers so
this is the particularly
great gridworld example
in which we have to start state and the goal state
and the agent is required to move from the start state to the goal state
and whenever
the agent moves
he gets the reward of minus one
because that cost something so to speak to move
the goal state is absorbing so the episode is over once the goal state is
reached and if the agent runs into the so-called in this class
if you like when he is taken back
to the start state and incurs a loss of minus one hundred i think that's
from this thing to incur if you fall off the cliff
well it does the trick and no one can i ask how what q learning
and sarsa behave differently
if we use an exploratory
absolutely greedy
say with absolute to set to ten percent so in ten percent of the cases
the agent would actually not the best thing or what he believes is the best
thing but would choose randomly among the other options of actions
and it turns out that
so is an on policy
it uses as its policy
something that looks
like this it takes the
it takes the safe route to the gold
now why is that
it is because every now and then
the policy that's being evaluated
in ten percent of the cases chooses not the optimal things
is just shows this variant here
then it would fall in ten percent of the cases of the cliff
and would incur huge loss
so is the consequent
as a consequence the values that have been in the state action values at the
end recommend this policy here which is carefully and totally avoid falling of the of
the edge because it stays away from it
now in contrast hue learning
a different policy
q learning
is not permanent
it's not terminator is at the classical mistake that policy
so you're learning
finds this policy
which of course is the shorter way but somewhat more dangerous and if you look
at the
reward for the two
you'll find that
so plotting the reward
over the time of learning you for that
so size
actually does better
then q learning
because q learning false
in the learning period falls down this cliff quite often because he chooses which is
this risky policy if you like but of course that doesn't really matter because once
we've learned we switch off the exploration
we then go to have an equal to zero
and then this policy of course is the better one because it is shorter in
christmas loss if you like and you never fall down here because you don't have
this random exploration factor anymore so what you see here is that there's really the
difference between what source and q learning can do and of course if you you
down the epsilon and union down the learning rate
the learning rate alpha here they will eventually converge to the same thing but in
practice you may never get there and so you could expect different policies to emerge
from the two learning algorithm
this is the principal difference between off policy and non-policy learning
OK so here's an example of
of whole learning proceeds i'm choosing for illustration purposes here tabular representation of the action
value function so this is the q table
OK now
why is it so useful because posterior distributions often have the form rights you often
have some sort of
which has some prior distribution and you're going to observe a bunch of data
why i given x
and this will be
you're going distribution of y and x
so so this sort of factor product and actually arise and that's why that's my
photographs is useful
OK so let me just show an example of of fascist fashion graph that arises
in probability theory or machine learning suppose we just have to girls observations of some
unknown means so we have this a variable which is unknown and we made observations
of that
but suppose we make idea observations that so
now you all know how to write it down algebraically you write that the posterior
distribution of
given a bunch of axes
it is going to be proportional to first of all the prior on
and the product
of the likelihood of all the axes
that's second nature two guys now
but what is the factor graph for this problem
i've given you the posterior distribution of showing you how factors so should be quite
straightforward to manufacture have can anyone give me the factor of this problem
so effective
and all the axes
one factor
for each x and what does it do
next to each one
are we done
yes one single factor for the prior
OK let me give you another brain teaser suppose we have a markov chain
so what's the formula for markov chain so i have a bunch of
and we have a distribution for the first one
and then we we'll have a distribution for each x
conditional on the previous acts
so that's the that's the joint distribution for markov chains
while familiar with the now what is the factor graph
this market change
a chain of squares and circles OK
and there's the prior years
so x one
x two
x three
OK and this so this box here just to be clear is the prior x
one this box here is the
conditional distribution of x two given x one
in this boxes x three community
and i on the order of ten factor graphs you're halfway there
yes so just to review
one so there's two sort of big problems one is what graph actually use a
particular dataset i'm not convinced that all assuming that you figured out how to model
the data already
then there's the second question is given the graph and the data
what does it mean for example what is the past what's the posterior distribution and
there's a very different organs you can choose from and the other and i'm going
to be looking into their
what are called message passing type algorithms in particular expectation propagation variational bayes
OK so i'm going to illustrate his arguments with a specific country problem
which is seemingly very difficult problem if you look at it from exact inference but
actually quite easy if we look at it from approximate inference five u
OK so
this problem is one that i have used a lot in my papers which is
called clutter problems
so in this problem you have this unknown x scalar variable which has gaussian prior
and you have a bunch of observations of this axis but the observations are corrupted
some probability so half the time
the observations are discussed in observations two minutes act
said before
but half the time the observation just plain noise avenue that's all it is why
i distributed from zero to normal distribution
so what is so it's sort of like a problem we have background noise some
of your points are actually meaningful the the foreground points to the ones i actually
tell you what we try trying estimate and a whole bunch of data that just
says nothing about what you're trying to just random stuff that was run
we don't know which points in which OK so
what is the an organ we're organ observed
the point of these why is want try to estimate x OK so this point
you guys can buy tell me what the pressure of his for this problem
factor graph this problem
so we have a bunch of wise
we have access
and have
likelihood contracts the prior acts
OK now
what is the
x what is the form of the exact
posterior next to this problem
so we give you an data points
what form does have world as we know it's going to be
if x is approached by y given x
OK now
here is again why i given x is some weighted sum of two gaussians
now what's what's going to turn into our thesis of i have
if i have seen
two data points
and i'm going to get
girls in times the product of two terms and another product in terms of expand
that i'm going to get four terms
my some of the gaussians are gonna multiplied to give gaussians org seems to have
a mixture of four gaussians
in my posterior distribution is that clear to everyone
let's of i two points
i get for gaussians
doesn't sound too bad overweight five points
how many gaussians i have in my posterior distributions
two to the and like
so that doesn't seem very tractable
so if i gave you a hundred points are already carry out of luck with
an exact inference here so yes you can enumerate all those gaussians computer giant mixture
but it's going to be
disagreement is going to be replaced with
the difference in losses
next over y
and an asian each prime here but they're both run it are somewhat triangular inequality
miles choose one h
around the
the rich
so only managed by a factor of two in
we're doing analysis were factors of two don't really matter that much
OK so a big disagreement coefficient a big generalizes coefficients
it means that there are
near optimal hypotheses which
substantially disagree in terms of the loss
this incurred
OK so
given all that
we have the minimum loss
known as the loss rate
we can prove about like this so we have
his new team which is under removable
two lower bound
right so we we have some
the minimum
amount of
labels we must ask for because our minimum error rate is not zero or minimal
loss rate is not here
and then we have
this coverage of t
many of these waters so
this is this is not quite as good as well as it substantially worse than
we got a zero on this
but still less than t right so we used a lot here
and now we have
a reality
we lost a little bit in generalizing to other loss functions
so i should mention that i'm not at all positive this analysis canonical
this is the notion that it's possible to
active learning to work with other loss functions it using these importance weighted approach
so the answer is yes
but all the loss functions where i know how to achieve lower than
i have a very special structure
where the losses are very discreet
which means that
for variations in the parameters of your bosses
the loss don't change very much
so this is a slightly different analysis of the
the claim is that you're going to compete with supervised learning algorithm which has t
labelled examples
so the have on a set implicitly by the supervised learning our
so this is talking about the number of labelled samples used in the number of
labelled samples used simultaneously
which is which is why this maybe a better form of analysis
but you have to think about where the epsilon
OK so
the reason why
i felt like it was the time to inaccurate tutorial
it is because we have addressed all of these cancers theoretically with this actually has
in fact experimental is now possible to
a active learning out the
which is consistent
in the nonseparable case
and get label complexity improvements in practice
so the several ways you could do this one way is
if if you look at if you think about the
loss waiting
rejection threshold subroutine
there a special case where things are easy so
if the loss function is convex like five like logistic loss
and the representation is linear breaking w dot x
the competition is is easy
so is the caveat to that but basically you can use
a simple approach to
to keep track of what the version spaces are near
attractor with the version spaces
another things you can do
you can go back to the initial skeleton and you can think about
that's pretty much said about the same for the rejection threshold says that the probabilities
above some minimum
and you're going to be consistent
in this this opens up a whole bag of
possible our rhythms to solve the problem if if you as a human know that
this region
it is particularly problematic in any more samples
and you can design your rejection threshold subroutines to go there and settle there more
often than elsewhere
this is going to come to point about make so we really have no black
box view of machine learning if we have to think about each problem domains separately
and then i think a nice way of knowing our beliefs to generate data from
the prior season matches our expectations if it doesn't try to figure out how to
improve our prior so play around with the prior for a while before you actually
exposed to the data i think that's seems rational way of doing things that i
feel that even vaguely cinema you may be shy about using them but they will
actually be very useful
so let me talk about this sort of black box view of machine learning
and i think you know there really are two different at least two different schools
of machine learning out there
most of the field the machine learning out characterizes being in this black box view
so the goal of machine learning is to produce general purpose
algorithms for learning
i should be able to put my algorithm online
you know many of us do this so lots of people can download it
if people want to apply it to problems a b c and d then it
should work regardless of the problem basically like it should be robust to
you know classification or regression are
clustering problem you throw at it because we don't know what people are going to
any user should not have to think too much right we provided the tool
the user downloads it runs it on the data
and this is why male most machine learning papers
i have a table of results at the end of the where they take
some algorithm and they apply it in fact to problems a b c and d
and they show that it works better problems a b c and d then some
you know
ex-prime which is whatever the
an algorithm is out there
so this is how
most machine learning papers that
now most statistics papers
i feel least follow this approach the more case studies
right and so the idea here
is if i want to solve problem a
it seems silly to use some general purpose method that was never designed for a
so i should really try to understand what problem a is
i learn about the properties of the data
use as much expert knowledge as i can only then should i think of designing
a method to solve
so here's the question that we can think about
you know maybe this is
they are actually
actually realistic a lot of real problem cases
they're in you talk about this with me thinking about what
what's the problem
a lot of time
and then after as
after you get to know and then you develop a model and you say you
behold i can model my data
that's true i think it is even true for bayesian straight you know i i
would be impressed to find bayesian who has the disc full of data and you
know it is strong enough not to peak at the data for you if you're
that bayesian raise your hand right now
i think most of us speak at the data but you know we we try
to quickly forget what we see
that it right i mean that we do not
it's probably you know if we want to solve the problem well
then you know peaking at the data
you know probably helps
right i might point out things that are grossly wrong about our prior
and i think the problem is that is one of the things that you can
and one of the things i want you to be bold
well let's not
so there
we can do that well
i think more philosophical and i think you should always believed that they want to
be in business rates they don't want to be you know they don't want to
be replaced by machines
right whereas we are trying to build machines to replace statisticians and so that's why
the black box view if we can get tony o'hagan inside the black box then
we have a pretty good black box out there
you know
you know but you know in that sense you can see where you know these
views can get blurred right in the if we have a clever enough black box
it should be
you know it should be able to come up with original set of models
that you might be able to work on lots of different problems
but you know that's like
back to the AI problem
and also it's hard to put in domain knowledge into the black box records usually
people to supply the dataset to some matrix of data whatever
but this is interesting i mean i think about this quite a lot because
you know if i'm really trying to solve the problem and not just going to
take it you know i really care about the results have acquired or somebody who
really means
no good answers
i don't really want to apply some just standard algorithm unless that you know unless
i don't really want to get you know i don't care about getting really good
answers i just want to get answers quickly that person
this sparse terminal a grant multipliers
hand you can use the trick the i
outlined to convert that's
in from
it's really difficult when you start dealing with the ground and the class
so this is a low class e and f
which changed it is
contains below ground multipliers
this is the same trick before
we keep using actually
to move between
the trace multiplication between the distance and a sparse connectivity matrix
hands they look classy and and in the product matrix
so i briefly outlined at
on the board there
and the reason you can do that's because the laplacian has this null space now this classy and
is the same as the previous l class you
of diagonals are the ground multipliers now rather than these adjacency elements which were set constant or set
according to
some calcium function that we had before and the diagonal is just the sum of
the off-diagonals giving us the standard plus in full
you also get no you also get this term appearing yes so this
needs to be combined in here
and there's a gamma i appear in there
that's effect and making a proper probabilistic
because the question how the null space and the constant i can value
so in the constant i can vector so it's not
they on
valid cover invest well valley
as this will turn out to be the covariance so this is why the base
distribution is needed but you can consider the limit the gamma goes to zero and
also gamma doesn't affect the i can vectors so it doesn't affect and the later
analysis but this is the maximum entropy distribution
and this is in fact a guassian random field so it's a guassian random field
the covariance this thing is the inverse of this sparse model this sparse class yeah
almonds determine their
to normalise
okay hits the review how you move between those two representations
minus traceability grant multipliers times the distance is equal to
in our definition because the diagonal the distance is zero trace out is unaffected by diagonal all
it is equal to the trace civil times ti because we've set elements are well
off diagonal three negatively grant multipliers
and this is just this little proof i was doing before
because that's the case
you can cancel those two terms and recover that's
the maximum entropy probability distribution
on the these distance constraints between neighbors is a calcium random field
gauss markov random field with this covariance hit
but the one thing i want you to notice about it is its independence across data features
not data points
i love models like this
because they just blow away all the standard statistical analysis that people tend to do
and show that a lot of it is nonsensical
because it's just about model definition it's a funny thing to do
because you're saying instead saying independence across data points
saying independence across data features
but this is emerging from maximum entropy i haven't made this up i said please give me the distribution
and it just gives me independent across features
so i'm not so
uh this is emerging just from the mass
so at laplacian matrix associated with the neighborhood graph that we've already seen before and
the off-diagonal elements this laplacian within the grant multipliers from moment constraints
the gas metastability specifying is independent across features but most applications against models are applied independently across data points so
people have done this differently this is as you and ghahramani and lafferty who looked
semi supervised learning myself with the detail view and will talk about next time and
charles kemp and josh bound with a relatively sparse gas random fields in the context of
cognitive science
the the point about maximum entropy
if you're not familiar with it is that if you want to know the parameters
the ground multipliers it always equivalent to maximum likelihood
so these two things the
maximum entropy knowing that the ground multipliers is equivalent to maximum likelihood in this model
but there's something funny about maximum likelihood interact in this case because the something i
call the blessing of dimensionality so everyone knows that if you have a large peak
small and that's very bad
because what happens is that your parameters become badly determined you've got all the people
parameters and only in data to determine them
that thank you thank you
OK here's lecture 10 in linear algebra
add 2 important things to do in this lecture
what is the correct an error from lecture 9
so the blackboard with that awful
it is still with us
and the 2nd the big thing to do is to tell you
about the forest subspaces
that come with a matrix
we've seen to subspaces the column space in the null space there's studio
OK 1st cannot
and this is a great way to recapture and correct the previous lecture
so you Members
I was just doing 3 I couldn't have taken a simpler example than our 3
as I wrote down the standard basis but that's the standard basis
the basis the obvious space
for example
three-dimensional space
and then
I wanted to make the point that there was nothing special
about that basis that another basis couldn't have it could have a linear independence it
could span a space there's lots of other bases so I started with these vectors
1 1 2 1 2 2 5 and those were independent
and then I said 3 3 7 would do
because 3 3 7 is the sum of those cells in my and I put
in 3 3 8
I figured
probably have 3 3 7 is on the plane is which I know it's in
the plane with these 2
and probably 3 3 takes a little bit out of the plane
and its independent and gives the basis but after class
to my sorrow
student the way that break that 3rd 2 3 3 8 is not independent
and why did she say that
she didn't actually
take the time didn't have to
the flying
what combinations of this 1 and this 1 gives 3 3 8
she did something else
In other words he looked ahead because she said wait a minute if I look
at that matrix
it's not invertible
that 3rd column can be
independent of the 1st 2 because when I look at that matrix it's got 2
identical roads
I was square matrix
it's rose
are obviously
that makes the columns
there's my when I look at the matrix A that has those
3 columns
0 3 columns can be independent because that matrix is not invertible because it's got
to equal rose
and today's lecture will
can reach the conclusion the great conclusions
that connects
the column space
with the rose space
so all those the row space is now going to be
another 1 of my fundamental subspaces
the row space of this matrix
or this 1 well the row space of this 1 is OK
but the row space of this 1 I'm looking at the rows of the matrix
L anyway I'll have to equal rows
and the row space will be only two-dimensional
the rank of the matrix with these columns will only be 2
so only 2 of those columns columns can be independent
the rows tell me something about the columns in other words
something that I should have noticed and I did
OK so now
let me spend down the 4 fundamental subspaces
so here the floor
fundamental subspace
this is related the heart of this approach to linear algebra to see these 4
subspaces how they're related
so what are they the column space
the vector of the null space
and now comes the rows space something new
when we find the i going to add it
create a list of concepts of we don't have one or going to set the
concept this is to consider the because it's so the of this process was the
which takes a string in l
and encapsulate
series of cyc concepts which this string refused to
so you can see the
reuse that if we run
on a piece of text
it does
something like this so
it's going through for each of these strings at the top
so just one two grams from some brief piece of text and finds these concepts
not all of which are the two meanings of the words like i guess close
to it and i happen to know didn't come up in the piece of text
is talking about the somehow somehow can
the interpretation something which could the text so talk about that later
see the
so now we have there's another class in there
you've got thousand which takes an annotated document which is the document broken up into
ingram's with this
concepts and at its concepts to work it's them both in this form into the
and the cycle form like this for the purposes of
was that it was over the easy
so we're going through the strings
in the document or the ingrams and the
by the side of the grammar
getty and then getting all the concert
i'm going through that and those concepts two
a concept for the document
so it's like a tag found a new with meetings
this is
the result of doing this for this brief article cycles from the news
two or three days ago
these are the results that you see that some of these concepts
if group for sure is relevant first-order administrative free agent summer meeting leadership something friday
sitting of paging
being social learning
beijing municipality OK clearly relevant
things which are relevant to this quote is not doing any disambiguation what's
in terms of doing all the possible meanings disambiguation is this too as an exercise
for the reader or for me when i'm actually doing my job
so we're really simple but we've got some pretty useful tags somewhere but what's even
more useful is it
o things like what sort of thing
beijing is because then we could say does this
article mentions in the cities we can say that about because we don't know if
it's going be cities but we generally
we can
so give me all the news articles which mention cities will give me all the
news at ten
we we don't have that we don't have that in this way we can
we aware of them and this is for those of you who are not a
i e
in particular it means you see something like this
i looked at
this representation of a concept cloud revealed the ottomans this is just some document were
for ingrams broken out of it and concepts additional is grams
we've looked at a site we look in the right side with service which is
as of this find we service
and of course we have language
like semantic networks and so on
and also in softer we can find
a lot of i mean that's a
projectile of cleanup these exactly with this experts how how to help
view to softer is this huge graph huge changes through time
what kind of what types of network we
so we have the before mentioned already directed networks and we have also on
then with the graph this would mean that multiple edges are between two nodes this
can also be an interesting aspect
then hypergraphs edges connecting with people so that is not just
rdf movement usually connect just two notes but
relationship can be a bit more complex than just connecting two nodes
bipartite graph so this would be
this type of networks where we have
two types of objects which are interlinked
weighted network so that
weights on top of them and eventually we have also this evolving door networks which
we are discussing here in the context of eq two there
nodes and edges are
it are even the weights would be basically over the whole network is change for
this would be
quick selection selection of types of networks we are dealing with
because network which i mean you could you have endless
types of just we didn't put this
the slides
process or
the practices with sort of course it is also
the first option
a little bit on the historical sites so traditional approaches would
the ones from sociologists
which were first studying networks in the past and the idea was basically tools to
study connections between people to understand the functioning of the society usually these societies were
so in this presentation people certain people are nodes interactions are edges with the interaction
this was
in the past and it was very hard to get this this kind of data
and typical questions were actually centrality and connec tivity so
between the nodes of centrality in the race important also nowadays they drink and with
all this algorithm to estimate importance of the web pages but some are now
this notion of centrality went far beyond this old
so in the past this was limited to small graphs like in the range of
notes and people are studying properties of individual nodes and edges now
this a new approach so they what is interesting nowadays for the research community
it is actually studying the large networks like that internet online social networks we'd really
millions and hundreds of millions of nodes later on you show examples of
the old questions are
not really useful anymore so let's see if in the past we ask the question
what happens
if a node u is removed now
the relevant question would be what percentage of nodes we need to remove tools
that's a fact some connected so it's
seen similar kind of related but subtly and far from being the same question
and actually the focus is moving
from the single note to the statistical properties of the whole set
sub networks and description of the whole of the whole
but the set b
and certainly we cannot draw any more small networks so this is really an object
which we can just study and we cannot visualize easily actually we are dealing with
hundreds of millions
as many parameters as we let us you need help as index into the
OK this
assume independence between the position
this zero order markov
OK so
o can estimate the parameters vary he from training set you can simply look at
whole lot here at each position
three b c i mean you can't which an example
we look all the positions led here
and then the entry for each of the
and for classification you would estimate this
four years for the positive class and for the negative class separate
OK then you take the
look what ratio for discrimination three take the probability for the positive class divided by
the probability of the negative log pick the lock this is something which is positive
or negative right depending on whether positive or negative you can classify all positive one
this is a very simple example of the probabilistic one
so i mean that what much more complex models
just assume we have an
how can we use these kind of model for defining a
i actually other questions for this you
for every
OK so the idea is that the the second of the idea is that the
takes some parameters so we estimate theta point by the simple estimation technique for you
so we have some maximum likelihood estimate for this problem
it's the
and then for every teacher every week reading we compute the so called fisher score
this is the derivative of the log p theta x
at the position you take it
OK so we need
i mean you had the probability
we have the property
the probabilistic model here
we take the derivative with respect to all the time which we have in the
at position
well i like
this is a vector which is as long as we have the parameters in the
the use of this feature that
i mean this feature for discriminating
OK so
from this we can define
so we take this feature that you have some additional metric here because of the
fisher information metric and the future of the other
essentially what you think
this derivative this computing some kind of picture describing how the particular example is using
the term
this feature vector is then used to define the the
typically the fisher information metric is very important and i think of the garden and
this is
whitening formation
so this is escort describes how each parameter contributes to the process of generating a
particular data the intuitive idea behind
so the project can be reused the fisher information metric is invariant under change of
parameterisation of the model you can come up with a the different privatisation of a
probabilistic model and
and the kernel classifier going to protect problem model that contains the label of the
latent variable is
at least as good as function of days but the probabilistic model
any hope of course that might be
OK so in practice we can just compute the features
i can just replace
fisher information metric with the identity matrix
so we don't need to
so let me show you want a particular example where we compute the fisher kernel
one particular probabilistic model which is that it was his position the brain
and it turns out of out at end up with a great degree
i think we want
i don't think that we have a sequence of fixed length link
we have the position specific going activities like
so this is the probability
even with
so fisher score
and carry constantly
CNF of be this university and
this district is one of the
so this is the procedure for computing disjunctive sorry distribution the distribution of conjunctive forms
assume that the input that two
former which already conjunctive form
a a c and d
you don't have to do any
so you just be
b over c and p
it's just that
corresponds to to in
this debate
it says that
of the conjunction though
what you do is you
from the conjunction calling for me
one of the key
and symmetrically in b
the conjunction new distributed
eighty or
if there are
we already have
the class disjunctions
for example when we apply the procedure interested me
to say this
simple example
so you just check case by case
if you calculate
never is
we call it
call recursively
because it is a question
distributed on
you know
x y
can try to calculate yourself
see that
this is actually
x x
and then you just distribute
first distribute this of this
x x
y x
and remember the disjunction is associated to
quite right but this does is x
x y
i think it's very simple operation
and you can also
so disjunctive normal form
really the dual conjunctive normal form
which is the disjunction conjunction
so it is the conjunction which is disjunction
sorry it took the conjunction inside the disjunction is
oppose from the tools
and again you can just
the transformation instead of distributing
disjunction over conjunction
we used to be
also distribution
and the algorithm is that exercise
for any questions so far
now i'm going to look at the proof procedure called the rest
so what does it you if you give it
well this is what this formula is unsatisfiable
so remember that
satisfiability is two
this means that this procedure can be used to
for that
taking the negation
so it is said by
to simplify
president and
we usually represent
conjunctive normal form as a set of sets
remember that conjunction is
commutative and associative
the order in which don't
parent is is around which can jump
this means that can represent
the conjunction has just said
for example
x y
six people and x
six people into
the order and
so our
and the way in which you write down
one doesn't
this means that
this actually the same as the set because in the set
xe axis so that's one
perhaps this
that's about the last time in the
i want to talk about these things
it's more interesting to talk about why self-reliance i'm going to say let's just fall
on the slide the slide
imitates what's going on here
so let's see if got a couple of them i want to try let's look
at for starters all b
well look at all be someone started the origin and come out to the point
b and i've got a vector on this it's emanating from the origin out to
and what does it say to do it says
i define vector from the origin to the point of the line
she is the smallest set of integers and said oh no comment so i put
the origin which conveniently here is the origin
out to the point along that direction so the vector all be as written we'll
go from there
how to what is it goes to one
zero i have
but then it says on
let's see no commas enclose in brackets and clear the fractions they don't like to
have fractions when you're talking about lines so clear the fractions multiply through
so the natl just double two
zero one and you could say what are they doing actually if you can imagine
going out one more
one more unit cell this line would actually go through the point
two zero one so you're just looking at the projection along here just multiplying and
then it says no commas enclose in brackets
OK this is called the brackets
the stable like things are called brackets
so that's the direction to the direction or b
let's do the
see what's the other going to do
was that a all
they all
all right so it says you have to move the origin to the basis vectors
of i want to do a all
i have to
i have to put the origin of here
at the tail of vectors of this is the origin i'm moving actually what i'm
not moving anywhere in the
x axis but i'm moving minus one and the y axis and minus one and
the easy axis in order to get this direction
so really going zero on the axis i'm going minus one in the y
one minus one in the z
and you can see since we don't use commas putting minus signs would look
cumbersome so
in crystallographic notation the minus sign is represented as a macro macro align over so
this is zero one bar one bar that's equal to minus one but crystal crystallography
use the term one bar so this is all one bar one bar for this
a down to towards
so that's
that's all that stuff and then it says i assume we can denote entire family
of directions by
so let's do that
i want to suppose i wanted to say
when i got there all of the body diagonals how i get the body diagonals
body diagonals
this is the origin i want to go up the body diagonal it would be
out one unit one unit of one unit so it would be one one one
would be a body diagonal right but suppose i want to say all body diagonals
that's one one one this direction one one one that direction i want to get
this model diagonal going to get that body day how do i do that i
can do that by putting carrots
these are called carrots those of you who have done some editing proofreading all these
OK so care so this is all body diagonals
this is all body diagonals
we could do a few others well-read suppose i wanted to do
all the face diagonals
all the phase diagram for like this like this
and then over here
like this like this well what's face diagonals
zero one
zero one so all face diagonals would be
face diagonals
what about all cube edges
what's the cube edge cube edge could be this one
zero zero one
so this would be all
so what does it mean it means write this out in full so that's all
part partly all one
all one bar
all one o c and using alpha zero
i'm clue when you enter crystallography first talk that's how they talk all one bar
so can be really happy if you end up in an elevator with a bunch
of crystallography first OK and there's two others here one o o
and one bar all o
well how many faces are the
six how many
face edges six and we're just going to the the permutations and combinations gives you
exactly the number that you should have this is mathematics imitating reality
that's good
that's good and likewise here if you go through all permutations combinations of zero one
and one bar you'll end up with all the possibilities for face diagonals all the
possibility for body diagonals i think i've got
cartoon here that shows there is
it shows all the different
diagonals that are possible when you mix one and one bar
OK that's good
so that so far so good that's pretty simple now let's look at planes
let's look at plans for planes we use something called the miller indices
miller indices for describing planes
and they're named after
british mineralogist
william howells miller
the dangerous tool because it's only true
the force
spring forces are also conservative
but for instance friction
it's not a conservative force
if i move an object
from here
two here
let's suppose i moved this object
and i go along the straight line
and friction is doing negative work i'm doing positive work
now suppose
i go from here to here for this routing
you can see that the work i have to do
is much more
friction is not
the conservative for the frictional force remains constant
dependent on the friction the kinetic friction coefficient is always the same
the frictional force that i have to overcome as i move
so if i go all the way here and then all the way back
to this point where i wanted to be then i have done a lot more
work than if i go
along the shortest distance friction is a classic example
of the force is not conservative
you look
the sum of gravitational potential energy and kinetic energy is conserved for gravitational force
then it is immediately obvious
where we put the zero of kinetic energy
the zero of kinetic energy is when
the object has no velocity because kinetic energy
equals one half and
three squared
if you object has no velocity
then there is no kinetic energy
how about
potential energy
well you say sure potential energy
must be zero when y is zero because that's the way
that we defined it
you see MG y
its gravitational potential energy so you would think that
this is zero
when one
is there not unreasonable thing to think
where is y is zero
is why zero at the surface of the earth
which is why zero at the floor of twenty six one hundred
which is why zero here which is why zero roof
completely free to choose where
you put you equals zero
it doesn't matter
as long
as point a and point b are close enough together
that the gravitational acceleration g
very closely the same for both points
the only thing that matters then is how far they are separated vertically the only
thing that matters is that you be
you a
you be
you a would-be be gh
is only the age that matters
and so
you can then
i simply choose you zero
one two
it's easy to see
i he point eight
and i viewpoint b
and suppose this separation
was a ge
if you prefer to call
zero potential energy
i have no problem with that
so we can call this
you equal zero here
then you would have to call this you
you have to call it plus and gh
if you say no i don't want to do that i want to call this
that's fine
then this becomes minus ngh
if you prefer to call this zero
that's fine too
and this will have a positive
gravitational potential energy and this will have one that is higher than this one by
this amount
if you say really i like to call this hero
of course the same holds
what matters is what the difference between
potential energy is that
is what we need when we apply the conservation of mechanical energy that is what
we need in order to evaluate
do object changes its kinetic energy so where you choose your zero is completely up
to you
as long
as a and b are close enough
so that there is no
a noticeable difference in the gravitational acceleration g
before the end of this our
also evaluate the situation
that g is changing when you go far away from the earth g is changing
12 . 0 1 1 as the atomic mass so we have here they all
have the same the same proton number but OK but different a different name which
is means a number of neutrons vary right so that means they're found on the
same place on the periodic table so far from the same place it's so Topol
so these are called isotropic isotopes have the same chemical identity but different nuclear
the properties
1 of the units here we write 12 . 0 1 1 writing 12 .
12 1 1 it's either grams per mole and I'm not making a mistake here
most of chemistry has gone side so every man should be in kilograms but occasionally
there is this 1 little remnant of the old CGS systems so cm grams seconds
and this is 1 so this is 4 . 0 1 1 grams per mole
Ward 12 point bold 1 1 atomic mass units atomic mass units and and you
want you is defined by the end user defined as
of the mass of the mass of 1 12 of a carbon 12 atoms the
mass of 1 12 of
so I talk about this this concept of moral here what is the more moles
more practical value something that we can handle tangibly and how we get to the
value of the moldable is something that was also defined in terms of carbon and
the mole is defined as the
the mass of it's the amount the amount of carbon 12 waiting
exactly 12 .
programs so you can see the atomic mass units of all
the view that the atomic mass unit would be 1 point a weeks at differently
this'll be the definition of the mole as the amount of carbon way exactly 12
grammes so I'd like to know now how many particles from carbons are there in
that mold and 1 way we can get to that is by looking at 2
pieces of data in the first one again Faraday Verde who conducted electrolysis of silver
electrolysis of silver but in aqueous solution he passes electric currents because a silver alliance
to deposit and for metallic silver and he measures how much charge is required he
has current right we know that charge is equal to the integral of the current
times the time and he knows the current you know so much time in many
ways so he's able to weigh the silver and compare it to carbon and against
that scale defines the solar ways a 170 grams pursues 12 grammes
for carbon so that's the ratio now the only knew what the electron brought him
he'd be able to divide through and calculate how many species there are in a
mall in order to determine that we had to wait for a few years until
1909 1909 Robert Millikan doing experiments at the University of Chicago conducted this interesting
effort where he took atomizer filled it with oil and then squirted fine droplets of
oil minister in between 2 plates that could be electrically charged the further
charged the droplets by radiating here showing actually used x-rays use various forms of high-energy
radiation in order to make the droplets bear a charge so now you have the
situation where
you have a droplets that is net negative or perhaps a net positive and it
lies suspended
between 2 plates and I'm able to vary the voltage on the plates
making this
for argument's sake negative this for argument's sake positive so if there's no charge on
essentially what you can do it you can update independently does the state component at
each each compare each comparator fires because that's actually quite nice
so that was basically
for MCMC so it's very quashed course introduction we might have been too fast
so just to point out there is a lot
mcmc is feel that action is very old
OK this has been going on for fifty years
people used to this news actually far too often
still and so that gives samplerank metropolis that actually do not scale do not take
hold for the rights to model which are used basically in the context of machine
learning you have to be careful when you're basically dealing with complicated models
there's another way and almost all of the MCMC using some kind of more flexible
phisticated idea like i'm doing an MCMC and something so i think the
kind of
because of the recent like increase in computational power folks like due to GPU
i think there's a lot of things that could be used as well but comparing
is not new sixty idea any more
but basically because one of the central computer it actually used to take ages knowledge
we have GPU
basically some of the techniques that i apologize basically should be basically consider on i
think i'll have a lot of potential for actually complex machine learning type application so
that's it for MCMC
or after MCMC
basically look at SMC so i thought i we do everything honestly one in one
of the was impossible
well we discuss
four basically
the remaining offline on
tomorrow i will discuss
in nineteen eighty
to mark him of calorimeter which is essentially the so called large class of numerical
techniques have been developed in in the statistics and machine learning
this the closest sequential multicolour methods
so we know where you actually want this techniques are doing on also so
i will have time show you can combine those two powerful ideas to come up
with MCMC type algorithm which for example or
come in which are basically quote for example come up with like i water that
simultaneously one thousand highly correlated components OK so
that's basically what the the story i'm going to tell you
here is the point i'm going to consider
so what we've been doing
for the first two hours
on off we've been looking at you give me
the target distribution pi x
no not a normalizing constant
on what i want to do i want an iterative algorithm
OK this is going to generate approximate samples from it
so that's what i've been looking at this MCMC
not i'm going to use to look at the pollen which is
closely related so different
which is basically the problem we're now instead of being you know one single target
distribution pi x
you given sequence of
pi and so and is going to be kind of time indexed so if you
want algorithmic time index OK
all these target distributions
of increasing dimension so essentially
the argument of target distribution pi one time one be x one
the argument of target distribution pi two at time to me
x one x two
the argument of target distribution of pi in time and be x one x two
xn on i used the matlab notation OK x one
similarly like an MCMC i only assume
that each target distribution
is known up to a normalizing constant OK so
i'm going to assume that
prior to put together was zn where these guys to give me x one x
two xn i can evaluate it
OK i carried on numerical value it but i don't want to compute the integral
of gamma and all the x one x two xn that is the normalizing constant
what i want to do
OK i want to come up essentially
we've approximation by monte carlo approximation
of both
actually the target distribution pi and OK
so i pi one i will approximation problems at all approximation of the normalizing constant
which i wasn't doing before
before and just sampling sampled from prior never presented you
methods to approximate the normalizing constant they're quite different in the MCMC called OK
so i want to do that
on the additional constraint i wanted that sequential
OK so
i want a time want to go an approximation of pi one on its assisted
normalizing constant time two by two unnecessary normalising constants also force that's what i wanted
OK so that's the big
i mean we've actually widened discover quite plastic only
OK not only what they want to go to distribution of we are actually moving
target essentially all its dimension is increasing over time
so you need obviously numerical methods obviously
we can use MCMC OK so for each target distribution
you could run MCMC egoism
that's basically target pioneer
so you can do that
but for most applications going to deal with it's actually quite slow
on top of that it doesn't imply the river this debate the normalizing constants are
quite happy with that is not already
what i'm interested in
so instead
basically we gonna basically pause
discuss and class of techniques which on the interacting particle better although sequential monte carlo
methods or indigenous particle filters
so the key idea what we're going to do
is actually fairly nice thing actually is to say well all the
following on look at on the going to do some examples later on
is that you have a sequence of target distributions like pi one of x one
y two x one x two by free of x one x two x three
on the time distribution they're not so different from each other OK so essentially
what are we're talking about today is my dissertation dynamics of large networks ITV that
current i was right
quite useful
so basically talk
go about
hartson about three things dynamics how things change over time
large scale
and networks in the US
let me start so that's what is the web today we have this wonderful they
on line computing applications so for example
we have a social networking website for sharing websites
one recommendation size things like that we also have online social media
so mean block
we lots of people want
so we have like
keep the
and and so
we also have virtual worlds like one of warcraft EVE online so
and i have a lot of online collaboration and communication tools applications like google
so so
the question is whether these things gone
so the first thing the
large scale like millions or hundreds of millions of users are using these applications
the second one is that they
so coming from this point of philosophy right a lot a lot of it is
user generated content so it's not users just can't consume content that actually interact the
website content
and the thing is this content is high speed constantly updated and changed over time
and because is going on computers so you get this message
and then the
set of human social activity
he also collective
so what is this
each interactions between users and content they create and these interactions can actually be model
i mean i have not which is present humans of some kind of entities and
the edges between these networks to prove the present interaction communication and things like that
and this is basically the object to make this was
network as a
so what want to bring system today when is like the first
hundreds of millions of people people at once so
for example what you can do is you best traditional social science opposite so for
example like the degrees of separation of the small world hypothesis way today you
you can around the experiment of on the basic water for millions of people who
were actively using microsoft instant messenger and perhaps surprisingly you find that the average we
are separated by six point six halls and the like you can reach ninety percent
of the messenger population which can be bought on this map of the world basically
represents an x y coordinates of the use
and the density of dots represents the number of users location basically you can reach
ninety percent of the users in a cost from any given node that network which
is kind of surprising
so one question is why should we study that networks and i think there are
two reasons why to do this
the first is to be understand and theory of online content is being created because
consumed so basically the question is how do users create content and how they interact
and how they also interact with one another through this
like online let's say computing
the question that comes up is that can be used this
understanding to be better conditions so we can design better and better services and can
be developed
better algorithms that take advantage of the structure of the underlying data
so that's basically what what we want to do this
so to talk about what has talking been the topic was exactly metadata data and
dynamic network and there are two
aspects of of the network
first network evolution right so if have a graph or network that wasn't changes all
the question how the structure change some of the structure itself facebook social network change
over time face gets that
the second question is a bit different so you can sort of think of a
social network or network has been expecting but now have some processes that are also
released that so i think of like a wide spread like a virus disease spread
in the network on the web what is spreading misinformation so instead of having disease
epidemics we now having
information feedbacks and trying to study and quantify those
the go more into this city
in each of the two parts in the in the slides and and what you
want to also see this three parts which which parts of the question is you
know how can i mentioned the data
how can i developed some intuition what is going on so for example on the
network evolution the basic question is how does network structure changed as networks evolve and
what we found is suspect all five is the network specify which basically means the
number of edges the number of nodes of time follows this particular
all relations which basically says that we should is increasing or time and many perhaps
surprisingly what you also find is the diameter of networks trees which basically says that
the graph is large distances tend to be small which is kind of counterintuitive so
as you go see measure something like that then you can ask what to
how could i have some information
and for example the model developed is called the forest fire because of a simple
genetic mechanism so you find node you want to create edges it to create
it is located the network
but soon followed
or one of the system
the network
you know because way
and then attaching to
you know what is
and what is what is interesting about this process you both network densify and that
would have shrinking diameter property OK so now we know what's going on in the
channel so what what you can do
so for example one thing that we can do is say OK how can i
generate realistic synthetic graphs right so the
goal is basically given the network how can we generate something synthetic scene and and
it's sort of the solution or what is what we need here is becoming a
sort of embed this interface to do some sort of
composition of these of those two approaches and you get a method that has the
the first to convergence time behaviour
OK so
one more thing i mentioned it because it's going to come up again at the
moment is ultimately what you can show is that if these methods are converging OK
they the xk is all that the iterates xk all end up on some sort
of reduced manifold
so for instance if your regularizer result is the one norm and after you've taken
in a whole bunch of steps and getting pretty close the solution what you're going
to find is that most of the components of the xk going to be zero
and some are going to be negative and some are going to be positive but
after a while you can identify which ones are nonzero and which ones zero you
going get a pretty good idea of what those two sets
and so if you know if you want you got that estimate of what the
optimal manifold it is
then you can do something fancier
you might for example just ditch the the slide
and restrictions of explicitly to whatever manifold decided is close to optimal
and start doing something else with their flag some sort of newton step requires step
something not talk about methods like that in my mind
and i can really help the the convergence
of these approaches
now as i said as i said number times you often are interested in the
solution of this problem for a range of values of the parameter tau
and it turns out that in many settings these problems easier to solve when the
towers began in other words when you're trying to impose more regularisation on the solution
the problems tend to be easier to solve because they tend to give you a
solution lying in
small dimensional space
so that's known to be true surname compressed sensing that when this is the one
and the towers large the solution only has a few nonzero components and it's pretty
easy to find very rapid convergence
on the other hand when the towers smaller the opposite is true you often have
solutions are more likely unconstrained solution
got more degrees of freedom in a sense
and they tend to need many more iterations of this kind of methods i described
so what can we do about this well it turns out that first which is
one of the accelerated methods i just described
it's actually pretty robust to this effect in other words it the number of iterations
it takes is not that sense
the choice of ten
whereas the basic
gradient type methods for consumer meaning method is pretty sensitive OK
but not all is lost because you can speed up but it's incredibly naive continuation
strategy you can start with the big value of tau say tell zero
you can solve the problem for the big value of ten as i said usually
it's pretty easy in that case then you can just decrease tell by some factor
use the solution i just found was the starting point for the new problem with
the new reduced value of tau
so it is in essence you can just sort of chase a sequence of solutions
and you keep decreasing tell
until you reach the target you looking for
so this is a very kind of dumb strategy has been analyzed very much but
but is very dependent on the heuristic here how much do choose to decrease tabloid
each step
but fundamentally it works pretty well and really rescues the behaviour the poor behaviour these
methods for small town
it really tends to fix them up pretty well
there's more work to be done in figuring out why this works
OK stochastic gradient so there's this pulls together a couple of things that i mentioned
namely the case where you don't have access to the great which have been assuming
for the last few slides you only have access to an estimate
but we just talked in the second part of the tour right before the break
about what you can do with stochastic approximation methods we can take as much of
the great you know maybe averages of all the estimate you've come up with so
you can do that here even when you've got a regularisation term
so you can former subproblem here with
the average values of the gradients or subgradients you found so far
and the regularizer just appears here explicitly
no change at all
and then you've got this
so it shows up in primal dual averaging it sort of is approx that analyzes
how far you move from x
so you can put all these ingredients together as a recent paper by showery does
this and refers to the astros region results in
a number of other algorithms like DJ singer one thing from two thousand nine which
is also related
and what you can show that this is the in expectation
the value of this objective
approaches the optimal value out one of the square of k right
OK so this is the kind of right you see in the primal dual approach
even when you've got access to deterministic exact gradients so they don't seem to pay
much price for having an average grade
so here are some references there's really only scratch the surface is a huge area
of investigation hey designer regularizes to get the properties that you want to design an
so this is our
morning after dark as very happy to have structure theory
and dark about
OK thanks for
right well good morning
thank you for getting up early to see tutorial and boosting
so this is a theory and applications of boosting a little bit more theory than
applications but they are both
this is a tutorial for people who know
little or nothing about boosting so let me start at the beginning with typical kind
of problem
this is the problem i worked on
when i was at eighteen t so
the problem here is to automatically categorize the type of call
requested by the customer so the idea is that somebody would call up eighteen c
and maybe they want to make a collect call our third number call or whatever
it is and
the idea was to build a system where people could just speak naturally to the
system rather than if you want
this first one if you want that just two and so on
so when the person says something we need the computer needs to be able to
categorize what kind of request the person is making so if the person says yes
i'd like to place a collect call
long-distance please that's a collect call
i i discovered recently that
since everybody is cell phones now there are a lot of
people younger than me who don't know what to collect call and third number call
and so on so these are just kinds of calls so you need to know
in the old days you make a collect call third number call so person says
operator need to make a call but i need to belittle my office is being
built with third numbers so that's called the third number call and so on
OK so if you think about it
for a problem like this if you just look at examples like this then
immediately start to realize that there
rules of thumb that will
often be correct so for instance if you just look at that very first example
i have point
so strong enough OK if you just look at the very first example
you know you can immediately think well of the word collect appears in what was
then predict that to collect call or the word car appears in what was predicted
to calling card call and so on so you can immediately start thinking about these
rules of thumb
which will be pretty good they're not going to be perfect but they should be
better than just guessing at random
what's harder is defined just the single
prediction rule which will be very highly accurate so the idea of boosting is is
to somehow use these weak rules of thumb
in combination somehow so that when you put them together you end up with the
prediction rule which is very highly accurate
OK so here's the boosting approach at a very high level will certainly be going
into more detail that had a very high level here's the idea of boosting so
since these rules of thumb
are not so hard to find
we could think about coming up with a computer program that could look at data
and derive rules of thumb from the data
and we can apply that procedure to a subset of the examples
that would give us the first rule of thumb
then we could do this again to the second subset of the examples get second
rule of thumb
and you can imagine doing this over and over again repeating this city times
so there are some
important details there are being left out here
so first of all as we choose the subset of examples on each one of
these rounds
and secondly
once we've
gathered all these rules of thumb how do we combine them into a single prediction
rule that will be very highly accurate
OK so again those two questions to the first question again is how should we
choose the examples on each round to train this procedure on
and here the main idea of boosting is to concentrate on the hardest examples
and every round we want to concentrate on the hard examples
and what are the hard examples with the hard examples are the one
are most often misclassified by the previous rules of thumb ones that we got wrong
the most
on the previous rounds up until that point
so that's the first time
the main idea in the first question we have to answer and the second question
again is how do we
and learn this model
and learn this model and using the gas in units here just so we can
compare with PCA which is also used as units
the new units
and you do this
you learn for models unsupervised you put the transpose weights there
and one i learned these models and just using cd one that is i'm going
down reconstruct the to reconstruct and then activating the hidden units again so we know
these things we construct those things quite well
and and therefore we know that we get quite a good reconstruction and there
so what comes out or to look something like what goes in
of course is subject to the constraint has gets really thirty
this year
and indeed
it does
so if you do
so we can take now the same set of digits
we can use all classes of digits using PCA and go down to thirty dimensions
these are the reconstructions you get from the PCA
it's not really fair to do that because we know the pixels of between zero
and one
so you can do logistic PCA
which we did by stochastic gradient descent because we have the code and that does
considerably better than PCA
but nowhere near as good as using this deep autoencoders
the deep autoencoder actually produce reconstructions that are better than the data
well you know it does look at the site you see is slightly flaky in
the data and now we've got something better
that means of course i should be on learning things are always move but in
and in some cases not the data but it's pretty damn good
we can now apply the same techniques to get little codes for
so we start by
converting documents into a bag of words
as usual
and then we use a bunch of hidden units to model what's going on in
that bag of words binary hidden units
and we use lot less like that
i should just mention the result has just been accepted by nets which is
in marion ross figured out how to compute the partition function for these boltzmann machines
pretty well
if after you finish learning you spend a few hours doing it
so now we can measure the density of held out data in one of these
balls machines
and if you just learn a restricted boltzmann machine with one american units the simple
and you compare the density that you get
with topic models
it gives much better density for the bags of words for holding bags of words
it's not surprising because the much more powerful representation topic models really saying each document
has to be generated by one topic
so each
so each word has to be generated by picking random topic that word generation
OK here we are concerned just not to model the documents well but they get
down to short description
so this was the model he learned
one model
we have ten numbers in the middle
and he showed these ten numbers do much better
then the ten numbers
if you do latent semantic analysis but is if you speak essentially PCA on local
one plus the word count
in fact ten of our numbers i think about a hundred of them person
the curve
he did lot of big data set
the first time this paper got rejected one of the referees complained that we'd use
data data set was too big so it can be compared with other methods because
they didn't work on datasets is big
here's an essay ten years that a hundred your code is one hundred real values
and here's your autoencoder ten real values and it does better
another thing you could do is actually take you down two units
to see what's going on so we can take it down to just two real
values here
and that's going to be good for visualization
we're saying give me two real values that contain as much information as possible
about the world can factor
and then we can lay this too
two values out into d
and we can unsupervised layer bunch documents out in two d
and then in somerset county provided the labels we can come up
by the labels
and see if we found the structure of the
class structure
so here's what happens if you use PCA
there is some class structure here obviously
here's what happens if you use the deep autoencoders
this better class structure
this is for a subset of the main categories in the reuters dataset
so when you look at these green ones initially you think
boys discovered lots of very complicated structures that actually need to bear in mind that
this isn't showing all of the data points and so these gaps you may well
be filled by other classes right
it's not that it chose to put these long way away
even though it could put in place in these repelled from other classes in here
anyway is found the cluster too much better
and this is then the hilbert space representation
as a distance
and it turns out this kind of representation works for a slightly larger class of kernels
which are called conditionally positive definite
so it turns out
the all algorithms that are translation invariant
such as compass ieee or are lesbians
can actually be also be done with conditionally positive definite kernels
some examples of kernels that are conditionally positive definite but not
positive definite so one example for instances
well just approximate example
in the early days of support vector machines
people were quite interested in
this kernel
which was the
hyperbolic tangent of
uh the dot product between x and x prime plus some
and that this is actually not a positive definite kernel
if you compute the kernel matrix with this and you know the i can values
typically find a negative igon value people work right
bother with that but
it like that because it looks like the activation function of neural network
in those days was still
when the when when we wrote of his papers about support vector machines
the reviewers would ask us to compare against neural networks
and then at some point
maybe six or seven years later
they would ask everybody to compare them methods against support vectors
and there are now
i don't know maybe the wave is swinging back again to neural networks so maybe
we have
mary mixture
all sorts of methods
anyway so this is the thing was a bit funny
but i removed by at some point that i was a student
i looked at the values for which this actually worked
it didn't work for all values are being
if i remember correctly so the hyperbolic tangent is not something like this
for me it only works if i had a negative be
which means shifting this curve to the right so i actually had the curve
a bit like this
end and if i looked at how best where it also had to
make sure the data is normalized in a certain range
and then at some point i noticed that
they range i was operating with looked suspiciously like a polynomial kernel that sometimes use just shifted a little bit
now it turns out if you take it if case a positive definite kernel
and then actually came
let's see could also be a negative number
is always at least conditionally positive different
so therefore the even though the hypertension is not positive definite
can be well approximated in a certain range and maybe the range where the data lived in our experiments
but conditionally positive definite kernel and that's why
it it worked also with support vector machines
but then it was forgotten
and people didn't worry about neural networks anymore
until recently
then they returned
this is an example of a non trivial kernel that we were playing around with at the time
and we were
interested in handwritten digit recognition mostly was mostly
about images are very simple images in inferences we have these kernels that we found
work a be better than standard polynomial kernels that
because pyramid kernels
and our
in computer vision people are using
as the standard model that works based on
so classification problems is a permanent quality pyramid match kernel i think it's not exactly
the same thing as this but this sort of a similar idea
but i think this
they have reinvented everything and maybe it's appropriate that are different
but this is one the idea here was to