this is kind of sort of
cognitive science perspective on active learning
and the picture that you should keep in mind with this is traditionally you might
think of a lot of such studies in cognitive science are done this way they
present the subject to adjust stimulate and then the subject's response but the stimuli are
presented kind of randomly and so forth and the person or subject is engaged are
all in the process of selecting what stimuli getting but that's really not how we
interact with the world at all so the idea here is to conserve closing the
loop between the computing in this sense
and a great example of this where there's a lot of work is in the
area of visual perception people have estimated that our capacity
there's about forty four bits per columns and they
if you are interested in that that the authors going to a little bit more
of a definition of what i mean by that but the takeaway messages that has
worse as i'm looking around this room i'm really not taking in all that many
bits of information and so how do we perceive reality from so few bits
this is the idea of interactive vision
so vision is exploratory and predictive we very selectively move our eyes around we're not
like a a camera that takes everything in and so that's the interactive vision
church remember trying to insert now nowitzki have some very nice work on that so
the idea is when we look at the scene we actually very selectively scan that
seem rather than just taking an image of it into our brains
the philosopher andy clark has and i sort of metaphor for this he says we
established visual contact with our world by an ongoing process of active exploration in which
the world acts as a kind of reliable and terrible external memory and so
i think of almost like a database out there that we can query is needed
to help understand what's going on around us
so this is a classic stay as a little bit about it but here's the
painting and subject ax to look at this painting and what is typically observe when
you use an eye tracking device to see where they focused is something like this
so those red lines show where i moved around when the subject was shown this
image on the computer screen and asked to
a study in some way and depending on what the
the goal is we get very different eye tracking results so here is a collection
of results from this study
so the same picture this is when the first subject is just shown
the pictures that take a look at it
and they just kind of skin around if you ask the person to estimate the
material circumstances of the family you see this kind of scanning pattern and so what
you might pick up is looking at the clothing some of the furniture maybe some
of the decorations in the room if
the subject is
asked to
given the ages of the people
for me
strong but you get this pattern and so the focus is really faces
as you would expect if you want to know how to hold me as you
may be what they are faced with a have appeared how tolerant and so forth
if you want lies with the person is doing before they had expected this very
kind of look at where they are positioned and so forth in the room remember
the clothes they wore you see very strong focus on those clothing
the wearing member people and objects in the room time looking over and so on
and so forth so the point is that
when you find the subject you say attention to this or that or the other
thing how they
interact and how they select information is very very different and this is a good
example of active learning in humans
here's another nice example recognizing faces so here's the face and and here's a typical
scanned so this is how the eyes move about when you ask them to look
at the face and so you see what's happening is there looking back and forth
between the eyes down the nose at the mouth and we i mean i'm not
expert in
face recognition but i know that a lot of the things that people use are
distances between prominent features like eisenhower and so forth you can see how perhaps this
we see that
so and we've got
why i so we've got some conditional probabilities x given x i minus one
also got some
why i was given exercise
now we
we may want to
express those distributions parametric models in general be some parameters theta governing these
given these distributions are very often we want the data to be common to all
of them in other words the the parameter itself is is not a function of
time steps
and so on
the parameters shared across all of emission models in in almost all cases
now suppose we want to adopt a bayesian treatment for bayesian treatment we put a
prior distribution over theta so data is no longer parameter which we make a point
estimate it's now
the random variable and has
prior probability distribution and that expressed graphically in this form so there's theta with a
prior distribution
and these conditional distributions
four why i depend not only on x i but also on these
we might do the same for all the transition probability so you might have some
other products
site and now points at
these nodes here perhaps the the first initial state has some of the parameters and
so on
so we can very simply express these more complex naive bayesian models using is graphical
representation very straightforwardly and we can make an interesting observation which will as we'll see
later is very important in going from
that model
that model something important has happened to the original
maximum likelihood kalman filter a hidden markov model is a tree structured graphs there are
no loops in the graph and it will turn out that inference on tree structured
graphs is very straightforward
when they're all loops in the graph as we have here
then inference becomes much
more difficult
and so for graphs like this
exact inference could very quickly become intractable and we resort to approximations schemes in the
one that will be discussing in detail is variational inference
so i variational inference for example have been applied to bayesian state space models of
the of exactly the kind of just wrong
they all sorts of other games
in this markov chain if this has n states and this has n states this
is an m squared matrix of transition probabilities
subject to the normalisation constraint
we may wish to have a state space which has quite high dimensionality
but without allowing
all possible
transitions to exist
and one way to achieve this is to have multiple
multiple chains so
the nice thing is we can draw
this particular graph and understand the probabilistic structure very readily be much less apparent i
think we just wrote down the mathematical expressions for all conditional distributions that define the
joint distribution
so now we have multiple
it chains and each of them can have
it has a separate variables so if if all the variables had if this had
in states that had and states madam states then there and q configurations
of the
of the hidden state
at this time steps
we could
represent this equivalently
as a sort of flat model with just a single
markov chain down the middle
in which each node has q possible states would have one variable that has
exponentially many possible states but clearly that's going to get
and we'll be very quickly whereas this allows us to have a very complex and
in state space
and you have a model which is
although not exactly tractable very close to being tractable
so this is the model which has been used and explored quite widely mention at
the end i think we discuss variational inference looking at two
treat the model of that kind variational
so you can play lots of games with this kind of of those are all
directed graphs to give you an example of an undirected graph this is probably the
most common
undirected example of markov random fields which is widely used in image processing attributed images
so in images just the vector of pixel intensities but has
the important property that nearby pixels tend to be very strongly correlated much more correlated
the more distant pixels and we want to be able to capture that property in
the probabilistic model
and so we have two d spatial
markov random fields which captures the property suitable for example would be
the regions of images for example to measure have
i have an image
we might
in the simple case divide the image up into
let's say
he show
so we've got you know picture the house here or something
and many this
trees is the clouds and so on
people stick with my day job she would become an artist
well this is the architecture i don't know no don't cannot go much into the
case yugoslav because of lack of time
but everything is very much like saxex except for
the but in the middle that states the annotation performance
t one tn
what is that
for each
OK case for example
of music played by a human performance now what we have is twelve temples
each example has been played at twelve different tempos
in such a way that even when we have an input performance at it even
anyone who desired temple dedicated temple
the system will be able to retrieve some precedent where there is this source and
target but which are close to the source and target them of the problem
and what the system will do is will check for the differences between the annotated
performances of the precedent case
look at the differences what was different when the human players played that eighty or
a hundred PM's and transfer
again imitates transferred to the to the input of the input problem these differences and
apply these differences to random
these input problem at the target tempo
so this is an annotation for example
got associated with is one of these the labels is the saxex system
so that means that the note in the score
not just a sounding noting in the performance of the node really was something the
performs maybe
and in with some of the beach the direction
the onset the brought together all these qualities all these values are associated which behind
each one of these days but they wanted also to look more closely to the
old and the indices because this was not things was not in saxex
here we are no longer than just balance is just and this can be hard
work can be people can be and in this type of this style of music
in the style of just it is very common that in all these fragments
or not is consolidated conservation means
that's not that repeats like we see we listen to this like that but i'm
here to be installed times may be consolidated into one single node in the performance
and the fragmentation is the reverse
they belong to what is fragmented into several
types times the for the same not of the same beach right and all means
ornamentation it is often that the amount of ornamental know is that that was not
in the score so this is for for this the style of just these these
are quite common resources
so you can see is that she that for example you can
for example all the nodes
i mean this
little notes that have
very short duration but just
right before and he also i will
world because the environment is set to
to the right it is this sound like one
and this this and this sound like one single
so as a set what does the system is well by
several phrases that i will get into detail it ends up with some with at
least some phrase to give someone just to the left box on the bottom
the segments cities is a case that has already solution that mean that has been
played at the two different at the two different tempos the target and the system
that shown there and therefore we have the performance annotation of these two temples and
at the bottom you see the inputs with TTT here
but we have only performance for the
so this temple of the system has to the performance annotation for the telling it
which could be be it
by covering all elements together
so this is the first problem so there are some algorithms developed to do so
there is another problem which is to maintain
k class two
but not only the centers of clusters
but also information
about the contents of the cluster
number of individual
the centroid and some information about the rate which is
more rich
reach fn and the first problem
so the
the problem
of clustering
which is also a problem for decision trees but PCA
one important problem for
data stream mining
it is what we call concept three
is that
the distribution
of elements
is stationary
it's OK
if you have an incremental libraries
it's the that very often
the distribution of elements
may change with time
so that's what we call
concept drift
in this case
one solution is window
it's sliding window
if you define the sliding window
you make the assumption that it's stationary within
the sliding window
it's better than
assuming that it
from the beginning of the stream
so the
solution i'm going to present you
solution apply
which you can apply to data streams
which we provide clusters with statistic on their come
and as the solution to consider it
it will
provide it will enable the use
to define
any portion of the the stream
in the past and provide the clustering
as exactly
as it it would have been done on that portion
which is not defined
at the beginning of the stream
so this is the
class garrison which had been designed by
a guy while and it and in two thousand three
it can be applied to numerical variable on the
it has two phases
the first phase
and on phase
so it received
the elements of one stream
and in this phase
the idea is to maintain
a large number of classes
it's a large number of clusters we
can consider that bizarre michael plastic
large number typically
several hundred or one thousand
this micro clusters would be described by statistics
on the context
so this is the
first and continues
when the user needs a clustering of history
very is
phase which is done
and the system uses a
it uses the micro clusters produce
the final cluster
this is the first principal also
i meant in terms of micro clusters in venues of these micro clusters
to build
in order to solve this problem
giving the possibility
to obtain
the clustering of any past portion of the
there is a mechanism
to keep track of the story
of micro clusters with time
so as before
the representation of micro clusters of course the system
i cannot keep track of all elements belonging
two each
micro cluster
elements are discarded
so what is kept
for each micro cluster
it is
what they called the cluster feature vector actually it was not introduced by
i got what but by the previous algorithm
called the dutch
so for each micro cluster
is kept
and it's kind of summary of the micro cluster
we have
of elements in the micro cluster
and for each variable
the sum of values
of the variables within the next
course they get and the sum of squares
chinese is an instance of language works
park is actually working with the international linguistics community for fifteen years
testing the theory that there could be a universal
language platform that people can write their grammars knowledge for the different languages the first
which is the world on top of
and twice a year this helpful to come together and take a tackle on different
kinds of projects ways of expressing things and at this point there are actually grammars
in english french japanese german chinese norwegian and many other languages very diverse kind of
languages and this appears to be working pretty well
there's many aspects of algorithms and syntactic theories in represent the system and then the
to draw community knowledge resources as we show and this technology can be applied to
many different kinds of applications and the one we've been emphasizing here
it's consumer search
this is a little look at the kind of functional structure of the language is
extracted from the text as we pass the web and this showing functional structure where
you see the predicitions on the subject and the objects
even down to
you know that it's an active not passive type because
this is the basic search architecture
for natural language search so we begin with the open content
pass it using the lexical functional grammar and XLE which is the park core technology
combined with knowledge resources that are either manually or
acquired to become miss machine learning
semantic mapping
that content is all indexed
the semantics looks like i was showing you that the actual
screens by
so the kind is an index in a very large
scale semantic index
our semantic index draws on
both the the large scale indexing techniques used in information retrieval
and large scale search engines but it's actually also combines the semantic type of information
representations so stored in one of the same index are words as vectors and where
they occur
and semantic concepts in thematic roles and their relationships
and we put a lot of work into being able to essentially formulate these complex
queries large scale and returned results in real time
so then when the user as the query that query is parsed and create converges
semantic map using the same processing has done for the text
two ultimately get the semantics of the query
which is then translated into
a query execution plan thrown at the large-scale index retrieved and then we employ a
set of ranking techniques ranking is certainly one of the major areas in search and
our ranking takes advantage of the kinds of ranking the using search engines today
and also takes advantage of all these new features information that's coming out of semantics
finally the system that presents the results of the top ranked so objects or clusters
and as you seen with some of the other demos i'm showing and because you
have a whole new level of semantics and you have aligned elements of the query
with elements of the corresponding semantic graphs there's a whole new opportunities for presentation
and so is required this large a large scale
is this really a lot of scalability according computing to thousands of machines a lot
of work and system integration different kinds of data resources
a lot of knowledge resources being pulled together
and many acquisition strategies for the knowledge resources
finally fair amount of work in user experience to set users expectations right because these
systems are going to be useful but not perfect and may require some change behavior
to get the most value system
OK now i'm really reaching the end here and want to point two where i
think that this
all can lead
we to start the talk by talking about the chicken-and-egg problem the semantic web
now i think with these kinds of natural language search engines once becomes commonplace and
you have a large scale commercial successful natural language search engines that do not require
to be to be commercially deployed the semantic resource in the first place then you
can really let the wisdom of crowds to accelerate the development and deployment semantic web
some examples here as if i was in the crowd work so well is the
current crop were today
on search engines is through anchortext so
everyone every person person writes a web page and links to the page puts in
some text
and that text is actually then used by the search engines and to know that
something more about that page
this is how a lot of the problem of navigation queries was solved search the
IBM homepage may not even say international business machines anymore
but because other people wrote nationally international business machines forty two IBM then the search
engine knows that that content is actually it's actually on or about that page
in a similar way now
publishers who put alot of work into optimizing their pages to be linked in expert
search engine so they can get traffic
will be able to upload ontologies to get more traffic
so you can imagine being a publisher of say sports
and you already know all the different players and teams and owners and the rules
and what they'll do
if you upload that to this kind of natural language search engine then whenever users
typing in more specific words vocabulary concepts to ruin OK could describe the player by
the center field or something like that even the word may not have appeared on
where you learn a density model for the positive density model for the negatives and
then you compute for any new thing the posterior probability by comparing its relative densities
under the positive model of the negative whereas this doesn't really look like that here
i'm only giving you first of all three examples that it's hard to learn discriminating
function for example you could learn something if it was very simple like linear but
i'm not giving any negative examples so so naive discriminative approaches are you know most
discriminative approaches even very not naive ones are not
may even be applicable to this problem
and even generative approaches where you say learned density model of the positive examples these
are very complex objects what however gonna represent these it's seems like it might be
a high dimensional space with three points you know what density model are you going
to learn so it's kind of puzzle
on the other hand you know it's not insignificant that i also give you all
the other examples i call this the test set or we could call this semi
supervised learning problem did you guys talk about that kind of semi supervised learning book
about so that people know that terms
so again excuse me if i'm going over ground you covered but there's a lot
of interest recently in problems where you have a lot of unlabeled data and a
few labeled examples so the unlabelled data make it like an unsupervised structure discovery problem
but the actual task you to solve is defined by the small number of labeled
and the the the the interesting computational challenges to figure out how to extract something
from all the unlabelled examples that will help me generalize in a much more useful
the concert and learning from these labelled examples and i think one way to approach
this problem that takes is pretty quickly to the state of the art in machine
learning is thinking of this as an interesting kind of semi supervised learning problem
so we'll talk about talk about that but the particularly the bayesian approach to semi
supervised learning that they were interested in really makes it an unsupervised learning problem it's
really about it in the sense maybe my initial fame the problem was a bit
of a cheat but it's really about what can we learn about the structure of
the world from these data
and then you know will use these labels and some
a clever way to to governor but the real work is being done by coming
up with the right hypothesis space in the sense from the unlabelled data now here's
a very simple approach to solving this kind of problem
just illustrated naively with the picture
so let's say we've got it at you know our objects are points in a
two dimensional space here so each of these data points is one of these objects
and let's say you you
so you get mostly unlabelled data and just one labelled example so that one here
and i say that's applicable or to file here it's a blicket OK so which
are the other blickets
you tell me
OK so this is a blicket
that like it
that wicket
look at
right good that was easy alright so what so what makes it easy well
basically you look at this and you see
these three clusters kind of pop out at you right and if you are able
to identify the clusters
from the unlabelled data which in this case you work and you but you have
some prior abstract knowledge that tells you that were labels pick out clusters the clusters
you can identify then all i need is one example
right to tell you and only one possible example it's basically just telling you which
is the right cluster label
and versions of this approach have again been developed in machine learning the the first
one that i know about was again worked zoubin did in grad school but a
lot i get a lot of the work that we're doing is kind of footnotes
and ghahramani
but i that
just kidding but but as you know zoom in
i really like this technical report and i don't know if it was ever published
outside of the ten but it's very t are maybe there was paper something that
in which have been talked about i think it was the first paper i know
to use
you know gaussians mixture models are more or multinomial mixture to think about unsupervised categorisation
and also supervising problems which are essentially the semi supervised problems in using EEN back
when that was like
so just making but still ian was the high and more recently you know there's
a lot of interest in these non parametric mixture models so i think you i
started to tell you about dirichlet process mixtures and so on and i think he
he didn't quite finish telling you about them but i'm going to assume he told
you about them but i think for the purposes of what i'm doing you probably
know most of what you need to know
but anyway the basic idea is these are models which unlike the finite mixture have
actually infinite number of
of of components
but in a sense when you do posterior inference conditioned on some finite sample only
of small finite number of those infinite components are effectively present the act effective number
degrees of freedom is is much smaller and kind of always just the right size
for the for the data you have
you know something that the model
predict the model assumptions expressed are appropriate so radford neal introduce some of these things
but also karl rassmussen and in the starting about ten years ago
so that's so that so this this is one place where according to scientists again
have been inspired by the same kinds of ideas machine learning people have been developing
with finite and infinite mixtures of an interesting thing is actually
the psychologists thought these things first in a certain sense so there is this paper
by friday in holyoke in the in the early eighties backwards overnight were like in
high school or something in which they proposed it was a little bit less elegant
but they propose to basically i e like algorithm for learning in the gaussians mixture
that essentially was a model of
unsupervised and semi supervised categorisation and then there's another psychologist john anderson proposed something which
was mathematically equivalent to
dirichlet process mixture but he had no idea what that was but he just kind
of derived from first principles it's it's pretty remarkable he's smart guy
and and he showed that can be also used to describe human learning others illustrate
a little bit about how how this goes this is a typical extremely boring tutorial
can be computationally trivial category learning problem that people have studied in scotland psychology going
back to the fifties
again this is this looks more like a traditional machine learning problem that there's a
few positive examples of few negative examples so this is the category label here the
training set and test set the actual stimuli in these experiments
are formally represented by a vector of a few binary features
what they actually look like in in the year in the light of versions including
the first things which were done by jerome bruner and colleagues
are these things which look like basically cards in the game is that people know
the card game set right
right now you raise your hand if you do i'm just curious
OK i guess is more popular in the states
it's a it's a game with
basically these cards and they have one or two or three
shapes and there either circles triangles that kind of thing actually ovals whatever they have
different colors they could have different shading and there's some concept that defined in this
low dimensional
discrete vector space
right so how you apply
so because this is this is this is scalar so we can we can actually
put this here and because the number of u is equal to one then these
things cancel each other and what we are we can we can we can put
the expectation operator in the middle
and it's to
and so now what the expectation thing here is nothing but stick the correlation matrix
we've seen
two things first of all
principal component analysis basically boils down to looking at the correlation matrix
of course the covariance matrix usually this cells
and the second thing is that
it boils down to something like an analysis of some kind of quadratic forms
the next next slide is then how to maximise this kind of also actually we
want to minimize the quadratic form a quadratic form
now again let's try to understand this
so what do we want to minimize this kind of a quadratic form under the
constraint that the norm is equal to one another and with the gradient of this
so this is the this is the the condition
sorry i said to your school talk conversations but actually i think that's kind of
exaggeration because that those are the more general conditions that are used in inequality constraints
that this is just like the the classical like harsh conditions
so we have the gradients mine is proportional i minus some constant times the gradient
of the of the constant equals zero
now it happens that the gradients
well OK michael also use is not gradient but the
that the transpose of the gradient which is more properly speaking the derivative but it
doesn't make any difference and so that the data that is equal to its action
is the corresponding linear function
this is an interesting point that because the
the gradient of the quadratic form is the corresponding linear function with same matrix multiplied
by two
and then he well it's had the same thing because it's also quadratic with an
identity matrix in the middle
so this this equations when we just put this that the tools out and with
this you on the other side it gives you this
and this is nothing but the definition of an idea value of the matrix
this is actually a very general general phenomenon
usually when we have some kind of a quadratic functions
as a result of quadratic forms
or to maximize the solutions will be given by some kind of like like and
because you just get this centers kind of equations and here well then it depends
on what depending on the situation it you have different i can values that you
want sometimes you have the largest eigen values sometimes the smallest values sometimes something in
the middle
so what happens here
is that
we should actually find the
the largest eigen value
sorry in this case for you you should correspond to the smallest eigenvalue of the
correlation matrix which is a bit confusing actually w what we actually wanted to find
in the first place which is the origin of variable corresponds to the largest eigen
what the point is that we can do PCA
by taking the correlation matrix and then computing the nineteen values
and this idea that the the core of the eigen vector with the largest eigen
value when you ask this principal component
and as i said in the beginning is basically recursive c so you first now
have just shown how to compute one principal component
but in in dimensional space you will you can define in in principle components
so the first
i define simply so that's not so that's
so that we
some tracks the produce projection that we had in the first place from the data
so we reduce the dimension of the data by one and then do exactly the
same thing
so what we is that we
well in this two-dimensional case it is not very
very obvious but the international skating international case we are successively computing components that give
us the best approximation
the best approximation of the data using this limited number of components actually it can
be proven that
the first
i k principal components give the best approximation of the data that is possible with
a k dimensional subspace
yes it is one problem with PCA is that's the result depends on the units
of measurement
yes again this is not about the problem and the matrix correlation coefficients as defined
in statistics as correlation coefficient as defined here and signal processing has that had the
same problem of of depending on the scale that it depends on scale but yes
the classical way of getting rid of this problem is to simply define the scalar
variables so that uses you say that the variance of each variable has to be
equal to one
yes i mean that that kind of cells the problem but then i mean it's
unique answer to the problem but it may not be may not be the answer
to the second question that you want to ask in the first place because in
some cases the units units have an intrinsic meaning and you don't want to risk
but it depends on the situation
this but says this is the case first principal components give the best
the approximation of the data in the sense that the new project the data onto
the subspace defined by those principal components the me the expected squared error will be
minimal so that's why
PCA is used for dimensionality reduction
so if you have data that has like ten thousand images for example
and let's say for example that you want to do some computationally intensive methods that
cannot really call ten thousand dimensions and you need to to reduce the dimension of
the data to be able to use
you may your favorite method then
PCA is the classical way of reducing the dimensionality PCA you can reduce the dimension
to save one hundred
and you know that you have the best possible approximation of the original data that
the best possible with one hundred dimensions
no of course this is
best is always extremely relative people always true some kind of optimality results for different
kinds of methods but of course what this optimally of optimality is always in the
well this year
requires some
my friend
i was advised to
it says
met what
how to make
i will leave june twenty minutes
i was advised to
to clarify
what i meant for that
it is sort of a
allowed title
i wanted to
to draw
newspapers do
at least here for a number of years now
this method part
it stands for meta programming
i say
meta programming is
is a
technique used frequently when one is trying to do what
i'm about to present here
and then you say that what
i o
that's why it's here
the second part is definitely
i mean
how to make things language and twenty minutes
strange funny
i mean
how can one expect to
to make language twenty minutes
well not very likely
the best one could hope for is to
make up several words
make a dictionary of the future and then someone with
large begin imagination imagination
you can call it language
this is actually called a domain specific language
and this is what this
but will be about
there are
many definitions of
the main specific language
like the one made by my father
programming language
it is it is a programming programming language
i forgot
how it was
i started the reading
it says here that its expressiveness is limited
and it is focused on a particular domain
and this is what it's all about
this yesterday so
i want to be
a bit of explanation
what the newspeak is actually
it is a language that is based on english
but has a
and the simplified grammar
now that is for four
the people who have
i read the book or seen the picture
which was accidentally made in nineteen ninety four
and start by
john for that
anyway this
the purpose of these newspeak was too
abolish all the words
that was supposed to well that could inspire someone to
think differently too
well will
so the words like freedom
anyway i don't think this cell caused
the authorities in
as yet
one can divide
actually that this
simple features vector contains the the number of matches the number of mismatches and the
number of drops of alignment in predicting bioinformatics you can use many more complex model
for example
four parameter model what can distinguish between gap opening and up
extensions so if the gap starts or he continued
some more sophisticated more than is the one that parameter model where we compute if
you think about forty just as you need put each possible of
another example of a design features in sequence parting
and even for example these three is possible and all the possible set of rules
for three
and in the future vector contain the affordances of features or lower in the tree
for example that you look at one time
so what i mean define features induce way
such that they decompose well on this monograph we can
b compute we can compute prediction very efficiently so solving there are lots of these
for example for sequence labelling we can use the the and the first was alignment
the need to my wish i could forty five
the CYK algorithm
i show
the approach that we propose for solving the structure of output
and later
this is an extension of fisher discriminant analysis two
learning in structured output and later the approach by georgians and others
that is an extension of some a vector machine tools like about learning
in our approach the idea is to
and not
an exponential number of possible output vector yk given an observation
so how do we
unable to to characterize the distribution of all possible scoring a back way
we did we decided to put it simply the moment so simply the mean the
violence of these distributions
there's somebody i think we see that what they mean and dividing can be expressed
in function of the weight vector
and the mean vector and covariance matrix c
can be computed efficiently with dynamic programming technique
since we
we approach we design our optimisation function for learning
we decided to minimize the number of output vectors that that ever score higher than
the score of the correct
that we decided to what you might function the scarlet press
this the parish want to separate as much this part of the carbon layer input
about from the mean of the the distribution of my life was the standard deviation
interestingly the discard can be expressed as a function of the parameters w
we approach we got to this optimisation problem
an equivalent optimisation problem is shown on the right side
four in the case of one input output
i don't know if you remember the formulation of fisher discriminant analysis that we saw
this morning this is pretty much
an extension of what we saw in the morning before
replace the feature mapping by simply you
from interacting point of view what we are doing is we're minimizing an upper bound
what we call the ranking loss
that counts the number of sequences the score i have been school of course the
input output values
so we're aware of the objective function is one of his last exactly as we
this morning i mean the loss of the machine is an upper bound on the
zero one loss
we have the optimal lost that is the ranking loss is not
differentiable so all we need to
well defined enough about the we can three
we do not support invasion
i believe
so this final opera optimisation problem that to get
for the training set of input output pair and
what we saw idea is
maximizing relation
because these approaches that about the discriminant finite and we solved by
matrix inversion
indeed since for practical applications since we had to deal with
number of features we ought to develop a way to speed up
these are the design approach because investing very large
governance man this is not convenient
of course what we need is not the only way to please
factor about the learning that many of the possible approaches
depending on the last that choose
because we choose to minimize the number of
you input output page that score higher than the score of the
correct input output b
but in some other people choose to minimize the number of uncorrect micro labels for
example this is what is done by conditional fee
and nice
approach that things work well in tactics
it is what
has been proposed by task islands
all the proteins inside mitochondria are imported from the cytoplasm i e
these vestigial or bacteria
rely on proteins coming made by the cell large the import into the mitochondria to
supplement the small number of digital bacterial proteins which are still made here inside the
mitochondria and used for central functions in energy production
here's the golgi apparatus in the golgi apparatus appear is used for the production of
membranes as one learned throughout the semester
the membranes of the cell are in constant flux and are being pulled in and
remodeled and regenerated the golgi apparatus is very important for that
here's the rough endoplasmic reticulum that's important for the synthesis of proteins which are going
to be displayed on the surface of cells you don't see them depicted here or
going to be secreted into the extracellular space
here the right songs which i might have mentioned briefly before and these writers some
of the factories were protein are made again we're going to talk a lot about
and finally several other aspects the cytoskeleton the physical integrity the architecture of the cell
is maintained by a complex network
of proteins which together are considered to be the cytoskeleton and they enable the cell
to have some rigidity
to resist tensile forces and actually to move cells can actually move from one place
to the other they have motile properties are able to move from one location to
another the process of cell motility if that's a word you'd like to learn
here's what a prokaryotic cell looks like by contrast and i just want to give
you feeling first of all it looks roughly like mitochondria and discussed before what you
see there is the absence of a nuclear membrane there's the absence of the highly
cycle architecture cycle always refers to cells there's is the absence of the complex of
architecture that one associates with eukaryotic cells in fact all the a bacterium has
what is this area in the middle it's called the nuclear oil
a term which also will probably never here in your lifetime and represent simply an
aggregate of the DNA of of the chromosomes of the bacteria and most bacteria
the DNA comes is consists of only a single molecule of DNA
which is responsible for carrying the genetic information of the bacteria there's no membrane around
the nuclear oil and outside of area where the DNA is kept are largely right
sums which are important for for protein synthesis there's not there's a membrane on the
outside of is called the plasma membrane
very similar to the plasma membrane of eukaryotic cells outside of that
is a a mesh work that's called the the outer membrane sometimes called the cell
wall of the bacterium which is simply there to impart structural rigidity to the bacteria
making sure that it doesn't explode and holding it together and then there are other
versions of eukaryotic cells here's what plant looks like and it's almost identical to the
cells in our body except of for two major features
for one thing it has chloroplast in it
which are also one believes now
the vestiges of parasitic bacteria that invaded into the cytoplasm of eukaryotic cells so additional
condition in mitochondria
which are responsible for energy production in all eukaryotic cells we have the chloroplast
which are responsible for harvesting light
and converting it into energy in plant cells the rest of the cytoplasm of the
plan to looks pretty much the same
one feature that i didn't really mention when i talked about an animal cell
it is in the middle of the nucleus here you can see is a structure
called the nuclear lists and nuclear less
or the critically listen eukaryotic cell is responsible for making the large number of private
songs which are exported from the nucleus into the cytoplasm and as i mentioned just
before the rhizomes are responsible for protein synthesis
it turns out this is a major synthetic effort on the part of most cells
cells like our own have between five and ten million write the songs in the
cytoplasm so it's an enormous amount of of biomass in the cytoplasm whose sole function
is to synthesize proteins
and we will learn also proteins that are synthesized by the riva sums don't sit
around forever some proteins have long lives some proteins have lifetimes of fifteen minutes before
the degraded before they are turned over
one other distinction between ourselves that is the cells manzoor and modified are the cell
walls analogous to the cell walls of bacteria this green thing on the outside as
i said before we do not have cell walls around bacteria
and we will have a semester goes on
go into more and more details
about different aspects of the site architecture during the first half a semester
here for example is an artist's depiction of the endoplasmic reticulum why it has such
complex name i can tell you but it does it's called the ER are
in the past twelve street the you are in the endoplasmic reticulum is a series
of membranes
keep in mind not the only membrane the cell is the plasma membrane within the
cytoplasm there are literally hundreds of membranes which are folded up in different ways you
see them depicted in one set of these membranes often organised much like tools represents
the membranes of the endoplasmic reticulum which either lacks write the songs attached to it
or has these right prisms attached to it which causes this to be called the
rough endoplasmic reticulum
to refer to its rough structure which is created by the starting to write the
songs on the surface as we will learn just trying to give you a feeling
for the geography of what we're going to talk about this semester these riders sums
on the surface of the endoplasmic reticulum are dedicated to the task of making highly
specialized proteins which are either going to be dispatched to the surface of the cell
where they will be to display and sell surface or actually secreted into the extracellular
many of the proteins that are destined for our body are not kept within cells
what are released into the extracellular space where they serve important functions
and so
we're going to focus very much on them here is actually what some of these
things look like in the electron microscope to see whether we can either believe or
fully discredit the imaginations of
the the artist here's the rough endoplasmic reticulum i showed you in schematic form before
and you can see what's called ross all these black dots are iverson's attached on
because if you solve this using an Cholesky factorization method matrix
with this dimension it'll scale as N cubed because A transpose A will be a matrix
of size N by Nand if A is dense so it will be at least
N cubed to solve this and that's what a general-purpose solver will do if you
give this to CVX for example CVX will convert that to one of the
standard forms and and that this matrix A transpose A now then problems like this where
A isa very wide matrix so it has the number of rows is much
smaller than the number of columns this is a lower rank matrix has rank M and
you can use a trick to solve linear equations with this coefficient that's also used
in or that's very common you can also rewrite an equation with coefficient matrix
to get something in this form where the matrix in the coefficient is an
identity matrix times A and then a second term A times diagonal matrix times
A transpose and that's a trick that's actually also used in support vector machine training and
that you may be familiar with it you have a linear kernel and the number of
features is much less than the number of training points you get something similar in the
standard a similar trick you can use in the Q P and the SVM training problem so but
the point is that instead of this large matrix A transpose A of size M
by N there N was the larger of the two dimensions you can rewrite the equations
and reduce it to a smaller system where you have a matrix A times A
transpose with the diagonal matrix in the middle but that doesn't make a big difference
so now that's M by M
and of course there's much reduce because the cost is basically a cost of
forming this matrix at each iteration for a new diagonal matrix D that changes at
each iteration so that takes M squared N operations to just multiply A with A transpose
and then you will have another M cubed to actually solve this using Cholesky factorization so by
just focusing on the linear algebra in each step and instead of solving the standard problem
that the general-purpose solver would obtain as the Newton system in this case it can
exploit this structure in the fact that A is a very wide matrix with M much less than N
to do it much more efficiently and then if you use an interior point method
and compare the the time it takes to solve with a general-purpose solver you see
it actually scales much better for different phis of M and N this is MOSEC that's one
of the best commercial quadratic programming solvers and this is just a custom solver that
uses this trick to solve the newton system fast and then what's the limit of such
a customized method well in this case for the problem we consider here at this
regularized least-squares problem the limit will be your ability to form this matrix A A transpose
a dense matrix of this size and then do a Cholesky factorization of it so that's
probably around for M several thousands and so you can scale this quite far
that when you reach ten thousands variables or matrix the dimension of that size
this can become too expensive but certainly you can scale it much more or much better
than a general-purpose solver by developing an custom solver so that's the model of this last
section are there questions about this chapter on interior point methods sorry
are there solvers which it's difficult to do it to automate it that's a very interesting question
if for example a modeling tool would start with this it will be conceivable that it actually
checks the dimensions of A and then chooses this or the other methods depending on
the dimensions you're restricted because you have you're using a general-purpose solver but
you can this is not the only quadratic programic formulation you could do something
similar where you introduce equality constraint you call this is Y is A X minus B and then add
equality constraints and then MOSEK will do a little better right so there's actually the formation we used already
in the second column so there is some choices that a modeling tool can make and then
can have a big influence on the efficiency but they would not be able to
actually developed a custom newton equation solver right that's something that's difficult to automate
yes a quality that's usually high but in the problem you have inequ equality constraints so is it possible to to problem where the equality constraints are formulating the dual form and inequalities and somehow some times depending on the methods it can be
easier to solve the dual than the primal and these primal dual methods it doesn't make a
big difference because they treat primal and dual symmetrically so actually a full fully symmetric primal
dual method would be a method that's actually in variants respect to switching primal
and dual so but depending on the algorithm used it can be more efficient to
solve the dual and I think YALMIP supports has some support of that where
you can actually automatically dualize a problem so that's nice a feature so then this
is actually a good introduction for the last part of the tutorial so here what
do when you s reach these limits than the linear algebra for an interior point method
becomes so expensive because you have many ten thousand rows and columns in A so
you can no longer solve these systems these newton systems then you have to go to
first order methods and that's the topic of the last part of the
tutorial so first order methods are so let's start with the and then we
also look at some dual techniques that actually are one illustration of that question right
so let's start with gradient methods so first order methods are basically the canonical
or the simplest first order method of course is a simple gradient method that's
the simplest oldest optimization method so at each iteration you compute the gradients of the function
you minimize you figure out a good step size either a fixed step size of from
some line search et cetera and then you make a step in that direction so
that's a method with many advantages so every iteration is very inexpensive you don't have
Newton equations to solve you don't have second derivatives to compute but the problems of
this are also very well known I think so it's often very slow very sensitive
to scaling of the problem and another problem is that it doesn't handle non-differentiable
functions right and so that's something you probably seen in optimization courses if you have
a simple quadratic problem and a parameter gamma here that controls the conditioning of the
well what they are
starting on we might be
we find
i don't like since i i would like to say
when i started to ask the UN i
we're doing poster for the
one of the results that would still work with PCA
which is
that internationally well known
i mean that doctor
new models PCA so well
along with my
he so this is just one trick pony
by that well with my soul
six years eight
coming up with you
which is not the way
signal processing
and more like
well that happen to know because he
taught me on this equals
well as
you might
thank you very much now for excessively kind introduction
good morning everyone
as it turned out
i simplify so this is what i want to talk about today let me be
brief outline the vision that means that he will get
the rule is in the first half sets but
this to atlanta too hard hopefully
but i don't think we'll get all goes as far as we can
so i want to start off with
so the simple prolog if you like to set the scene that bayesian inference and
what might want to do it
so consider this
the sort of the sequence you get the opening of the bond film comes for
the credit
and it would be quite exciting
i just want to motivate what we're going to do that
and then i'll go back start looking into very simple problem and then we'll sort
of build up the treatment
this sort of linear a simple linear regression problem all start looking about how we
might tackle it
in a bayesian
and the idea of this talk is that eventually we get start off looking iteration
we get back to it in the end we may have to push this into
the second lecture
let's move on to the programme
so for
start staff with some minor interaction whose head of the idea of of arrays
most but not everyone
so some very brief history
there was a theologian and philosopher william of occam which is a village in surrey
in the fourteenth century is supposed to have said something to the effect of this
so what
that's my latin pronunciation but basically he said
when looking at solutions for problems the entity should not be multiplied unnecessarily
the in form of translation that could well just be down over complicate things
so his
he was thinking very much in the theological and philosophical context time
i'm sure you're familiar with some of the very complicated
explanations dictated by religion and theology
a certain physical phenomena such as the
going around the sun
he was basically talking about really we should be looking for solutions that the data
yet which are quite simple
and a modern context
this is still very much valid philosophy
with trying to solve data modelling problems and we have a number of potential solution
and ideally
we believe we should be choosing the one is the simplest we see no reason
to overcome
gets a little more difficult
let me start thinking about degree of solution
how good is the solution is not necessarily the case that we have
it's either right or wrong sometimes we have sort of degrees of accuracy
so in
monday data but we're interested in doing
want to find good solutions to problems
some trading off the
accuracy of the model
with its complexity and we'd like to do that and well principled and effective effective
and what i have shown this talk is that the
the ideas of bayesian inference
effectively embodied
so let me start off with just
kind of contrived example
sort of fairly simplistic
but it's intended to show the underlying mechanism at work
so imagine we have a binary communication system two symbols in theorem one
so we have to do
we have a way of sending messages is going to start off with taking an
arbitrary length string of zero
and then anyone that string at any particular place were allowed to place one of
these four symbols
we have a bit for bit two bit a single bit symbol
and we can construct a message
according to the system by placing those anywhere
even overlapping and then we simply or
we acknowledge the fact that in our system
we may have transmission errors which you will just say can be independent inversion of
imagine that
that we receive this particular sequence tendency
we're interested in knowing
what's the best decoding
i thought best in inverted commas because obviously that's a very complicated
we might need to be a little more formal and how we define
but for now we want to ask the question
what was the original
set of symbols generated the sequence received
so i think this
it's quite appealing intuitive one
obviously this is generated by four bit two bit symbol
the question is is that the most likely all the best decoding in any sense
can we show that form
so let's have a look
it's impossible to coding
so i think for
obviously that you can probably cook up hundreds
if you that knowledge
i pick for sort of have an obvious appeal to them in a certain sense
the model one is simply replace six bits required positions as we need
so if you like that's the most
of obvious model lisa
model two is that we place three three-team sequences
where we need
so that's the perfect depending in the data
all three which i hope
appeals to most intuitively
four bit symbol
so those three models are all perfectly coatings nothing
but also we might consider the factors we set the could be some noise so
let's just have a look at the model that requires some noise
in the decoding of the assumptions
this model just seems to single a bit sequence the most simplistic model
in that sense but it requires two in the these two bits are assumed to
be familiar
we're just looking at
some potential choices three which
became the sequence perfectly
and so forth
the simplest model
but it doesn't actually sequence precisely we have to make an assumption that night
and so if you take this point of view
the kind of algorithmic consequence of that things like supply lines
kernel methods
reproducing kernel hilbert spaces by the kernel k has certain smoothness properties
l two regularisation in subspaces and so on
these are the kinds of algorithms that arise out of this basic insight
now there's a second
o point of view
and the second point of view is the point of view not of smoothness in
the classical sense
but the point of view of sparsity
smoothness is has been known for a while i think at least since the sixty
so and sparsity the point of view is this that people realize that maybe the
function you're trying to learn is not more than any classical sense
but maybe it can be represented
in a sparse way in terms of
some basis functions
as a sparse combination of some basis functions
and in this setting too with might be possible to learn effectively
OK in other words this is the inside that the function depends on the few
relevant features perhaps
and this has an algorithmic consequence do if you take this point of view and
you think of things like wavelets
like l one regularisation
less so
compressed sensing
and these are algorithmic developments that somehow
the march out of this realization that sparsity is a good thing and can be
so that's the second point of view
and the point of view which has
the the the most recent of these
is the point of view of geometry
OK so that's what
try and explain what that means
and this point of view also has an outgrowth consequence
so just like small smoothness makes you think of supply lines and kernel methods and
l two regularisation and sparsity makes you think of anyone and compressed sensing less so
and so on
when you take the geometric point of view of the algorithms that the margin of
trying to exploit this point if you make use of the notion of graphs simplicial
complexes laplacians diffusions and so on
and we will see these objects
over the next
our so
OK so what is
the geometric point of view
so this is
somehow the
geometry pieces of data analysis in very high dimensional spaces OK
the central dogma is this
it's an argument in two parts
so the first part of the arguement says
that look
in very very high dimensional spaces the data is not going to be distributed uniformly
that's absurd
so in fact
the data will not be distributed uniform the distribution of the data will have some
if there is some shape perhaps there is some geometry to be done if you
want to understand the shape
maybe it concentrates around certain kinds of structures may be these structures are low dimensional
and this is going to be
general fact of natural data sets
the natural datasets are going to have
particular shapes in the high dimensional spaces
and that's based on the intuition
the natural data tends to be generated by systems may be physical systems are non
physical systems that have few underlying degrees of freedom
so that's the first part of the arguments of the data has some shape
and the second part of the arguement says that if the data has some shape
you can exploit the shape of the data the geometry of the data in some
sense to define suitable classes of functions with which to operate
the geometry motivated and adapted to the shape of the data
and developed representations
and develop algorithms that are adapted to the geometry of the data
and if this is done
this might allow us
the geometry of the data
to enable efficient learning
one is setting in which one can
explore this geometric teases
with some clarity
and i understand
what are the consequences of this teasers are
is the setting of the manifold
is the setting of manifold learning
so manifold learning is not a single problem
but rather it a collection of problems unified by some common assumptions
and that common assumption is this the data lives
on or near some low dimensional manifold
embedded in this high dimensional space
and we'll talk a little bit about how one can relax this
and generalize this further
but this is our first attempt for the first time the community has made to
try and make sense of the notion
so funny
chain closed set
take take
if x is in its then why is it that y i just
catch it does
so this is a big man to understand the tissue
this is for all n the man behind this for this as it is true
of all this stuff
these two answers that which are actually all the
all the positions that they can catch
starting from x closing
this is an example of what can be expressed or second OK and regarding labels
how it may so that i can for example
i else will be able to define that
so this is
just notation i don't think the
so in p
now x
the formulas say in my tree position x satisfies this formula
in terms of
to explain so this formula mean simply
from x is the path
come to a position where POV hold
soldiers later a
this can be expressed so i will not that it but
your first two
do this kind of tricks
you may try to play
because we can this is the part of my lectures so
four second talk with its two weeks if you want
but the idea is that you you have to express the first it's said that
think which was this equation we had and also to that is the least because
in m is easy to define inclusion in between
between sets
the popular actually this is the formula
but they can write if you prefer writing in this way the inclusion of x
in y
this is the formula one is it true
o and for every time i take x
well if
x is in x
in one
after a difficult
so that's because now what you have in so you have to kind of able
to have first of i've also reveals a second bibles
the sets of individuals
and you're able to define
formulas are in all of
so as you can see the inclusion you can talk about the list
set such that
and as i told you
the fixed point equation that we had the idea was to talk about that
set with given property and search one
combining then you can
you can see them so
express what we will be able to express the making
so what do we know about them so because it was questions
so it seems to be very very so the main base very very big results
about it
so the first big result is
OK in general
if you take out because structures
the vectors
like this
and you it is an MSO formula
but is interpretable in the structure mean
then you can not
because the site in terms of companies computational
i mean it is
we cannot compute whether this formula also the model
two what's and so
in general
so the big results like
characterisation of some classes of structures where it's footstool understandable it all the classes of
structures where you can inside and code have become really
so you have the domain
like and square
and you have relations like
i'm your less success all down
just to move along the way
and he would be undesirable for example
the good news to
is that
for this kind of structures
like the linear structure
and the binary tree
and so decided to go with
it's not the same as the women it's different logics one has only one of
unique success
and the other one has the notion of left and right to so you can
also have an arity
trees you need to know which one of kate exist relation what will
so for k
that's all it is the same means that you give me
it existed that is the blah
what else can i tell you this
there is also
and yes something really want to know is that the two big results very powerful
different ways you can think of an SVM is a big quadratic programming problem but
no one ever solves this like like plaits method or two
actually do that in in to make that
to be able to handle them properly in memory
so you can actually do a reasonable job with him and neural networks to some
degree and neural networks krause earlier on things but obviously it's better to do everything
batch because you can handle living at the same time but this is not feasible
and classifiers that are computationally expensive to do
exhaustively search
so the first successful one was done by
henry rally who he's google mail
and my boss moments ago canada
and they had a lot of success in applying artificial neural networks
essentially all the people
what's that
they went through
and there was looking for something in translation and scale
they say that every i six pixels in translation
they subsampled image rather than substance classifier this subsample the image
and the way they subsampled these in gases pyramids again to guard against using work
we touched upon before and what they do that they go through the candidate across
all those different kinds of you can think of essentially searching like a big
set of points in in in what space
i think that's a much more constructive kind of thinking all these pyramids and things
that sister what space on the sampling through
and in each of these individual points they have candidate image
and actually do some perhaps my stuff here the critical i think so take the
mean the going away
we also did some nice things actually where they fit in a least squares planes
so you can actually look like a plane across images of elimination is kind of
going like that you can actually fit leastsquares plane and remove some of the elimination
artifacts that way
then the histogram equalised essentially they put into collecting all school work and i think
it was three like everywhere
multilayer perceptron
and in situation that and they did some
they have some kind of funky stuff again because it was difficult to train the
classifiers the features they sometimes use like actual strawbs of images and things like that
rather than using each individual pixel things so they had a lot of ad hoc
measures in that but for the time know you know it was quite advanced and
the big thing with this and the big thing with a lot of these detectors
wasn't so much schooling to
i wasn't so much the learning to make it was really the data
and when you can look at these things whatever
four for a lot of these things it's really data specific if you've got a
really good data
a lot of the time you do better
rather than kind of perhaps playing too much with the learning algorithm when it comes
to this sort of stuff that's not rule one because obviously there there's has been
a lot of improvement in face detectors and things and there's a lot of kind
of several things that you can do but in general if you got a good
dataset you cannot do better than with the weak dataset so with these sort of
things that has benefited a lot from having thousands if not millions of images thrown
in general as well
and see this some examples is collected classic once again because it's not paper because
people can dress finally if and everyone space think got negative examples here
people walking off even this is kind of
i don't know if this is the result or bad found
i why they put in there but they have the found smiley face so i
guess i can find ronald mcdonald to one
the first jump into using support vector machines for this was by a sort of
freud in accuracy in ninety seven face detection
and i think is about this in this kind of
my editorial rather than fact i think so what it was a lot more elegant
because essentially instead of kind of choosing heuristic features choosing things hawkwind things that this
entry just
put the pixels in this put the pixels into the classifier and then led to
its business and as we know experience a lovely for this sort of stuff because
can deal with last mensional problems instead of being built by the cos dimensionality we
have this lovely margin thing become cyberspace and so
essentially they had a nice heuristic feature selection and obtained reasonable results but there regional
results for non linear SVM
now the problem with that is that obviously with the linear SVM i can kinda
sum up all my
support values and my support vectors and put into a single template which i can
then evaluate really quickly across the image but this is that non-linear computational costs go
up and this is the real problem with the with the first what
it was quite computationally expensive
as it could contain hundreds if not thousands of support
was proposed was cascade classifier cascade crest was not new but again
the big thing with it wasn't that is going to form any that it wasn't
going to be able to separate one class from another class the big thing was
the search was that can i still maintain reasonable performance while doing effective search
so essentially what a cascade classifier and the kind of course spoke about four
is that you can kind of a great deal so
you might be extract number of features from your face image things all you might
be able to say
to simplify is being same only two or three support vectors rather than or in
support vectors
and what we working threshold to decide these two three support vectors and i've got
threshold that no amount to classify say
ninety percent of all
why a training set reasonably well in the other ten percent i i can still
to do
this corresponds to
these this
this is the third operation
which is very important when you're looking at the
stability problem interesting graph relations
it's the
projection operations so
the idea in the project several operations that take
relation a binary relation to
what of the relations
make it
smaller by eliminating some of the columns
so the reason why you might be
interestingly in many columns is for example
in this case so if we are talking about the recently by two actions here
in this section but taking the section then possible
basically societies
maybe maybe we are not interested in the intermediate states or simply want to know
what states
here are examples from these states here
some unspecified intermediates
it is in terms of relational operations what we are interested in is the choice
of the projection operation relations so the project these
relation to columns zero cool
eliminating column y
other operators in the reasonably thing we will be using these
this is predictability
well it's a b
restrict to
he stays zero one
so this is like one joining his former this one here we
a zero and the zero
so we have
these relations here
and now we are interested in those states that can be reached from that initial
state by
these two actions
so be
project this relation to the third world eliminating the column zero or one
and what we get is the formula
that represents
these two
well yes
and that's the
set of states that can be reached from the initial state by taking those actions
it's about people with doing so
in some of what you will be doing elementary school
as i pointed out that corresponds
initial states
and then we'll have relations
that correspond to different actions
and we compute
all possible states that can be reached by
taking on one of the axioms in one step
then for the fourth step three steps forward and so on
and then interesting whether we have already
because this what we are simply interested in this sense of space that can be
reached by taking one two three four and so on
for these purposes we need
projection which
so the projection operation
eliminating call
that is the projection operation
these logical
o operation that does exactly that
so basically what happens is that
we have a formula phi
in this case
propositional variables is zero
baby zero a one b one
and we want to produce the formula
only says something about the second column here
and this will be a formula works variables one b
variables easier and easier
logical operators will be denoted by
exists are
where are you the
of frozen variables that are really for
it turned out that this is exactly corresponds to the
relations of production which
that is so simple that is almost ridiculous
so the elimination of one operation simply takes place by
making two copies of the formula
and one copy
replace the the variable y
because that's all i mean the article being replaced the former that problem that the
are able
why because falls and then you his former boss
from the fact
that's it
this and related operations
that that extends laterally from ocean there's also universal approach operation is the same except
is that is time to have contact something real
do not using this
in this
so this is eliminating one
variable formula
this notation here
we had a set of variables so the variable is eliminated by simply by simplified
and in doing so else
i mean
the result the same so essentially same this formula by
as many copies of this form of quite as they are the values of these
variables here
and in each copy
typical this one falls
this example
we have two implication a implies b
and the by c
everybody knows you
also also a policy
you can use that
now that i said that
i hope that's OK but i'm making it OK
anyway and so that they take a different tact which is and it's an interesting
where you say how
how positive is something how negative something how nature something as
OK so that's what i've the also
i'm going to point out of paper later that has the similar idea of having
fuzzy membership in these categories
there's many other ways many other related kinds of definitions and annotation schemes and just
for example you could do an motions is a lot of typologies of emotions appraisal
moods humor as are related you could have different structures and human how we were
interested in
not just the individual expressions of opinions but what is the reason that you have
an opinion you know a bigger structure coming back to the seventies and eighties where
you had like twenty minutes work on plot units had structured structured opinions in many
ways so there's a lot of other things you could do as well
my our focus is on the linguistic subjectivity and we would hope that would match
up with the kind of media with people that are
working on representing the actual opinion or private state that's being expressed also in and
we have a section enough to be able to go through and product review mining
and they often structure things specifically with respect to attribute and
the product and attitude towards the sun
you make point about gold standard
so gold standards meaning the thing you're using to evaluate system
so you can derive them from manually annotated data obviously and given annotation schemes you
back to sentence level say is there any subjectivity in a sentence or whatever also
very interestingly people have used a lot of what i would call found data
so the people
and by the way when i'm using these keep putting examples
and putting a citation these are not
an exhaustive list of citations i just kind of found one or two and put
them here
so blog tags
and all these websites for complaints political arguments and so on so
amazon dot com reviews
complaints that comes
there must be a lot of fun to read complaints that can
but you know their complaints
we have to learn to use these bitter lemons that com which is you know
when you get on there which is the
it's from the palestinian or israeli point of view so it's found in the sense
that the tag is given to you
right it does
so with humor and it doesn't interesting stuff like that so anyway there's a lot
of that and also people can
they often compare the results of their system two
word lists that are out there for example the journal inquirer mention the second so
there's different ways you can define the gold standard
now it's really interesting i don't know get so that's what will always contextual polarity
it's what we're talking about so we define prior polarity to be what you put
in the lexicon so without that's prior the prior probability without any evidence from any
text that is going to be that but in the context of the overtaxed many
different things can flip it around there's a really nice paper that a lot of
light in the spring symposium on attitude and the fact that we had in two
thousand four by pliny insane in
and they talked about polarity influencers all these different things in in context can flip
around the polarity
my guess i give this example because it was a real example that we found
is only they had failed to break their spirit
so spirit is good
making his spirit is
failing to break his spirit is good
but then
if only they had
it takes away that it even happened so it's really there's about two two groups
have done some kind of social experiments using lots of features
we did that we kind of got better than baseline but there's a lot of
work to do in that area
so although i would say in that case it's not half bad you know what
i would like to see
i'm not really talk about it but
so you have word senses as the extreme and then you have something like a
construction which is not necessarily
a fixed phrase that you put in wordnet
but it's a usage
and so
past that i would think you want to let you want to be able to
try to find that as the usage is that because it's not really completely open
to the context
but the and as usual one is that's good you know that and as usual
and as usual that seems really open so this is continuing from
the dictionary all the way to pure context
which is interesting
so lots of work to do on this
probably you know well
could use that made could use the positive
falls and this is
the wonderful world of independent component analysis
so as i mentioned yesterday
that kind of
historical background for ICA is this idea of blind source separation so we have a
number of sources sigma that emit some kind of signals and then these signals could
somehow mixed together in some medium and that we want to separate these sources
in a blind man we're blind means meaning minimum a prior information on on the
source signals minimum pricing information on the source signals or the mixing
so it's a very simple simulation example where we have these
also signals which are then mixed up together by random linear coefficients
and then using ICA we can then recover the original signals
as the independent components so how does this thing work
well what this works by defining
a linear latent variable model as you might call so x i
he's x dx i are random variables
there instance random variables and each of them is modeled as a linear sum of
certain hidden variables called as i j
and the point is that each of these observed variables is a linear combination with
one of these sort of these independent components with certain coefficients in the i j
so x i and they are random variables whereas the AIJ are parameters that give
us the properties that the unknown parameters which we don't know and the whole distance
estimates these unknown parameters a i j
and once we know that the parameters i j
we can then possibly kind inverts this linear equation and then of the independent components
so this is the case
his an unsupervised learning books
this the case in unsupervised learning which means that we are we only observe this
these variables x y or one of the random vector x i mean if this
if we for example observed both x and s
and the only that the only thing left would be to estimate the AIJ that
would be a classical case of supervised learning which people to solve by basically by
linear regression because this is completely linear equation
but we all know x and we have to recover both a and b both
a and b s
OK so
well this is of course not always possible
we have to make certain assumptions
well the fundamental assumption well for simplicity let me first say that i think this
this condition for simplicity we say that this matrix of the mixing coefficients the mixing
matrix a square but that's kind of just kind of simplifying assumption well what that
means is that
is that we can this that we can simply invert this linear equation so when
we know the i j we can then in the equation and redirect gets to
see the coefficients that we need to use to get the s s j
but then
these two
the statistical conditions are really
the whole point in this matter as well first of all as you may have
guessed from the name independent component analysis we assume that these component these source signals
are mutually independent mutually statistically independent so again statistical independence and not not for example
linear independence that we are talking about
but this is what this means basically is that this sort of thing that should
be somehow
create heat or indeed i mean this is the first
processes that create this sourcing should be somehow for example physically independent from each other
if we have like two different entities that produce these signals without any interaction physical
interaction with each other then we might assume that the signals are independent also statistically
independent but then what is really
extremely important here is this assumption
that's the the latent variables the independent components are non gaussian that is that distributions
are not
those gaussian are not normal
and this is really what makes the whole technique completely different from classical statistical models
i mean this this kind of this kind of linear models
well we only observe x i have been investigated in statistics for a very long
time actually i just attended a centennial meeting for factor analysis because section just nineteen
hundred o four spearman published the classical paper on factor analysis where
where we have very similar
very similar equation
but once once we say that these components are nongaussian everything changes and certain fundamental
limitations of factor analysis of PCA
completely vanish and we can actually properly do blind source separation
so some restrictions
some determinants have also been to be taken into account first of
this is i j only defined up to a multiplicative constant well that's quite simply
i guess i should have mention that we
conventionally defined the independent components have unit variance because the scale is completely undetermined so
we can define it however we want to this people's identity so what this means
is that it is sometimes a delay transpose equals identity thus eighty is
an orthogonal matrix
there's also a matrix has approximately half of the degrees of freedom
compared to the full matrix
well these not very simple complicated but it's something like one
know this
this logic also shows why we can do i see on gold standard why we
really have to assume that the independent components have non gaussian distributions
well this because as we saw in the last lecture
the multivariate gaussian distribution is completely determined by the covariance matrix and the mean mean
vector but the mean is assumed to be zero so basically is completely determined by
the covariance matrix well we so that the
four girls in distribution was some normalisation constant
times explanation of minus one half is
the times the inverse of the covariance times is
so once we know so
every covariance matrix corresponds to exactly one gaussian distribution assuming that the mean zero and
vice versa
so in the same distribution however
however many observations we may get we never get anything we either the there is
simply no more information in this distribution than what is given by the covariance matrix
for doing this kind of transformations as we see in this equation three doesn't really
give any new information these new covariance we don't have any new information actually they
would be a simple deterministic simple but they will be deterministic functions of the size
of the core of the covariance
and this is really the reason why
all the classical methods for estimating this
linear mixing model for
because there are simply they they use
factor analysis and PCA
they just use the covariance matrix and they simply don't have enough information
from which to infer the main mixing matrix a
in fact analysis people
talk about
the fact the rotation in deterministic
so that is that means it's just the fact that that there is a certain
kind of rotation
the this week given by this orthogonal mixing matrix a tilde which you cannot recover
well for various reasons people in fact others have
kind of learning to live with that problem and so on
they do fact quite happily and then they just three let's say that well we
have this factor analysis problem and then they figure out in different kinds of heuristic
methods of finding different kinds of rotations
but from the viewpoint of blind source separation for example
in factor rotation in the ministerial really
it's completely unacceptable if you take if you take some kind of source signals like
like this here
and if you make an orthogonal transformation on all the mixing of them it just
like you know
completely arbitrary mixture come it will complete garbage the fact that the mixing is orthogonal
doesn't really realistic restricting in any any intuitively comprehensible way
there is something wrong here
this PDF file doesn't have
the proper images notes
i realize that in you are in print out this there was something missing in
the figures but i thought that it was on independent process but it seems that
this file is corrupted in some way we should have backscatter from lots of different
distributions here
well well well
and yes i wonder how can that can be and
well i tried to get well perhaps i i
well maybe the problem isn't
so my name is caused by reason and phd student of professor bunker at the
university of bern
in switzerland
so this talk here considers
the general graph matching paradigm of graph edit distance
so first of all i will talk about graph edit distance as a graph matching
then i will briefly talk about standard procedure for computing the graph edit distance by
means of a tree search algorithm and then the next i will talk about munkres
which is in fact an algorithm for solving design problems in polynomial time complexity
and then our contribution here is that we adopt this algorithm for solving assignment problem
to the problem of graph edit distance so i will talk about this
then of course we will provide several experimental results we have achieved
with our new algorithm for computing
graph edit distance and finally how to draw conclusions
so the main contribution of this talk are work study provide very fast algorithm for
computing graph edit distance
and this algorithm is sub optimal in the sense of finding not necessarily
the exact graph edit distance
so suppose all of you know this a standard definition of graphs but nevertheless i
mention it here for the sake of completeness and there's one thing that i really
want to point out to you and it is this concerns so label alphabet
so as you see we have no restrictions concerning the label alphabet for both nodes
and edges so the labels can be added to the set of integers set of
it can be to real work to space it can be a set of discrete
symbols or it can even be a combination of two or more label alphabet
hence the parties are objects to be transformed into graph based representations are manifold and
they range from physical or logical networks two images and chemical structures
so this flexibility in
in our
definition here is based
in our graph matching pair than that we apply
and this is a graph edit distance
so in graph edit distance to the similarity of the distance of two graphs is
basically defined by the minimum amount of distortion that is needed to transform one graph
into another
so in fact these distortions are given by edit operations and these edit operations consists
of deletions insertions and substitutions of both nodes and edges
so here's an example
we have two graphs g one and g two
so we have now an added sequence which transformed she one completely into g two
and such
sequences commonly referred to as edit path so we
possibly delete some edges we do need some notes
three d insert notes reinserted and we substitute nodes and edges so finally we have
transformed she one completely
in to g two
with this edit so of course not only one edit path exists between two graphs
but the number of different edit past so for instance you can think of an
edit path you delete all the nodes edges
in g one and insert although it's the edges in g two this would be
possible and path through
so formally
the graph edit distance is defined as follows
let us assume we have two graphs given g one has the source graph and
g two s the target graph then the graph edit distance between the source and
the target graph is given by the minimum cost path between source and target so
obviously what we have to define here is a cost function which measures the strength
of a given edit operations
OK and this
is a cost function should of course
reflects the intuition that two nodes for instance with very different labels should
have a higher cost and to a substitution of two nodes with very similar
so we can
conclude that graph edit distance provides us with a very general dissimilarity model
for graphs which can handle any kind of label alphabet
so let's consider now the possibilities we have for edit distance based
classification and we distinguish two different ways of edit distance based
classification so first of all
of course you can apply classifiers directly in the domain of graphs but in fact
if you do so you are
you are restricted to this and then nearest neighbour classifiers
but however we can also define graph kernels based on the edit distance so in
year three
so for four
and since you can define a trivial graph kernels in conjunction with an SVM
so what you have to do is you have to change
to transform you dissimilarity of graph edit distance into a similarity measure
this is an example here
what you can also do is you can extend standard graph kernels for instance the
random walk kernel with edit distance only show the house as shown in his phd
that this is how this might be a good idea
for instance the random walk it could
and the third possibility you have this graph edit distance is that you have used
information about gravity for graph edit distance to embed your graphs explicitly in real vector
space so this will be the topic of my second talk on wednesday
so for those of you have already worked with gravity this and
distance know that its computational complexity
it is it's major drawback
so in contrast with exact graph matching algorithms
the nodes of the source graph can potentially be mapped to any node of the
the target graph
so this might be a problem and consequently the computational complexity for graph edit distance
is exponential in the number of nodes of the involved graphs
so it's well known that for graphs with unique no labels the complexity is linear
but they do not consider these graphs here we do consider general graphs
so the computation of gravity distance is usually carried out by means of a tree
search algorithm
so the idea is that you use the search tree as representation formalism for the
optimisation problem
so the
root note of this research represents the starting point of the research then in the
nodes represents partial solutions
and leave nodes represents complete solutions means complete edit path transforming one graph completely into
the graph
since the complexity of the exact graph
edit distance is
exponential in the number of nodes of the involved graphs it's a matter of fact
that exact graph edit distance is feasible for small graphs
so however in order to speed up graph edit distance and make it also applicable
larger graphs several suboptimal methods have been proposed and in this work here
the approach we introduce a new suboptimal methods for graph edit distance based on the
assignment problem