and you can you have a map of what Delta T and then you can
it forms a two sphere around us
and you can expand this in terms of le jean denomious YLM
just as you would for a radiation pattern
and the coefficient of the YLMs
is ALM
and if you summon sum over the different Ms
of ALM squared this is defined as C sub L it's the power in the
on wave number L on
multipole L
now this will give us information about the total mass density of the universe
because it's something known as baryon acoustic oscillations
something very interesting occurrs around the time of recombination
before well before combination the universe was ionized
when the universe was ionized
the photons
provided enormous pressure in restoring force
for if you would try to move a baryon around
so any perturbations in baryons would've oscillated
like acoustic waves
after recombination the universe is neutral the photons travel freely they are decoupled from baryons
and perturbations can grow leading to structure formation
I have
that wasn't supposed to start yet
oh well let me start it over
so this will show
the evolution of the profile
of perturbations in dark matter in black
baryons in blue
and photons in red and neutrinos in green
so that's the end point let's start it over where we start with
ok we started there
dark matter stays behind but the photons around the time of recombination is dragging the gas
the photons decouple and then travel to us
the photons have a memory of the original perturbations and
in particular there is a lens scale
that's imprinted on this pattern of perturbation which is the sound travel distance
so the sonic horizon the sound horizon
is known it can be calculated very accurately in terms of per cosmological parameters
so there is some
sound horizon on the last scattering surface
and today we can view this
sound horizon responsible for the peak in the microwave background radiation
and the value that we would get relating the angle that we observe it
and the physical size depends upon the geometry of the universe
for different geometries
corresponding to different values of omega whether the universe is flat space of spherically curved or
hyperbolically curved the peak of angular power spectrum
would be at different values of L
this is the result from
the latest W map results
showing this beautiful acoustic peaks first predicted by Sakharov a long time ago
and from the position of this acoustic peak
the value of L
you can determine that omega total
is one to about
well to one per cent with an error of about five per cent
and there are also other observations at larger angular scale
that give us confidence that these acoustic oscillations are there
there will be better data on larger angular scales
a smaller angular scales larger multipole moment from Planck
for the past 20 years the predicted launch date of Planck has been exactly the date
when the first collisions will be seen in the LHC
although the schedule change this tight coupling has remained constant so it will launch in two thousand and eight
they think on exactly the date when the first collisions are seen in the LHC ok so let me go to cosmic subtraction Omega
total is one it is determined by the CMB
there are many methods to determine the total matter density in the universe
you can look at the dynamics of galaxies and clusters of galaxies I'll talk about
this in the third lecture
look at the result of weak lensing
the measure the temperature of x-ray gas in clusters
CMB tells us something about omega matter
compare large-scale simulations to observations or to look at the power spectrum
all of these results are consistent with Omega matter of point three
so here is the subtraction cosmic subtraction
one minus point three is not equal to zero
one minus point three is equal to point seven
let me repeat that in case there are string theorists here
no they're not used to
numbers so this is the total this isn't matter that's not equal to
zero this is exactly what is deduced by looking at
the supernova results
so there's evidence from cosmic subtraction that there is something in the universe other than
matter and that is conveniently described in terms of dark energy
usually lists of documents
from one side we usually want to see the most relevant document from every side
two was still in documents from one site
so it can be a bit more
smart martin began group documents not based on document idea but based
and it more
so in this case architecture of retrieval box is a bit more complex
so what we do about doing in this case
small search engine
and it
it does everything that we discussed in this lecture
so it gets wearing
doing this of course needs
from index
doing molecule a marriage
can do
you can still for example we know that
we don't need more than ten thousand
results from every walk because you combine
so everybody
has some upper limit not more than one thousand documents and resources
everything is very good with box
they're standing areas into result aggregator that this result aggregator is
pretty complex piece of software because
it's supposed to do supposed to do something
version of this results based on ways to get
from retrieval of
but it's also very
well it's also to go and i can
show you the most of search engines right now are are using now the same
very very close to this approach
the disadvantage of this approach
it means that every query
we need to say to all of
if we have all clusters of documents
we divided into
ten books
of course the real time beautification because we need to let
but you can for example
this document not on one about and the number of books and doing some
duplication or something like that but in any case
every query
should be sent to all
we have documents and what's going on
if you look into statistics
of all queries
usually it's not very uniform
and what you will see this is
you can balance cluster around
queries are going to work
and all boxes are doing the same in this century
so it's linear scale so it's horizontal scale
you need to use all computers in your class
and maybe you can do your job
i went to see if you can select in this way
that you can send queries on the number of people
and the way the you can do
that based on this
we can do partitioning
the simplest example is
what we can do begin decided OK
it's an example
there are two types of users users harder for queries and use for not porn
and for queries summaries but if
so what you can do
you can
create a classifier for in any case need to do classifier for queries if you're
doing public internet search engine for unknown reasons
also you have the same classifier for page
and you can say OK
this is a partition of
for internet
and this is a partition of normal increment
so if user is that query
many users are
so they don't use four class
so if you can default have saved search these family feuds or whatever
so we created this
partition of called the internet
results for
and reports
two thousand boxes into this partition so we have a lot of redundancy and it's
pretty fast
and we have
smaller palms partition where all water so much more lauded what quality of georgia's national
not important here
everything is much simpler than
the greatest partitions and we divided it into
this is example of partition by document quality
so we can
do this but usually we can support
very good documents in one part waterfall system and by default standing query to this
if you don't have good document high quality documents there is sending this query to
bigger and slower partition of
low quality documents
but the intuition behind this is that if a user is doing collaboration he
she is looking for a high quality documents
and usually the internet there is no such exception of high quality documents there lot
there lot of sizes
low quality
high quality documents are usually on a number of so you can you can create
this partitioning don't send queries to all boxes in your in your class
you can do it based on geography
you can know from IP
what like asians uniform
and according to the whole cluster bomb
divide the document that belongs to this
and dad hopefully
unless they're making a joke right
so so how does that work i mean
if you think of it as a math problem there's some infinite set of objects
there's an infinite subset of those that set of courses and the child is able
to mostly grass the boundaries of that subset from just a few points randomly sampled
was and if you want to have a sense of what this is like
as an adult
you see we show you these objects here and then we give you a couple
of examples in have two five
this these are objects from an alien world and that's a word in alien language
and i have a pretty good job are you can do a pretty good job
of telling me which other things are two which are
so let's try that have about this one yes or no
this one
more certainly there
that's why you bayesian OK
right so most people said no on that one but there was a brief still
a little bit of hesitation which is one way behaviorally in the lab to diagnose
uncertainty reaction
so here you have a demonstration but again from just a few examples in this
work basically the same if i give you one example you can get almost perfectly
correct with a little bit of uncertainty kind at the edges of the concept how
does that work
to go back to the scene you raised
you know that this is the slogan according to theory aerodynamics bumblebee can fly well
you might say according to conventional statistical learning theory like you know that nick's theories
of generalisation error or balance PAC learning theory this should be possible you should be
able to learn a concept from just a few examples let alone just one positive
example whereas all the negative examples where the masses of data that you know the
positives and negatives that something like the perceptron needs to find the right maximum margin
to take another example where i think we need to raise questions about our conventional
theories learning think about the oldest problem in statistics learning about the causal structure of
the world from evidence just so we learn the basic statistics class correlation doesn't imply
causation it secured causation with in some cases saying the right randomized controlled experiments can
identify causation but what people do do we go out and conduct randomized clinical trials
with extensive datasets well you think about intuitively how you might make causal inference the
kind of thing that's a clinical trial what do we know we are always trying
to make inferences like this like you know i get called somebody tells you about
some new herbal remedy does actually help you get over the cold more quickly or
not well you know i might do a little informal experimenter might not even think
about this consciously but sometimes i remember to take the drug in time other times
i don't i can keep track of whether i had a short called along cold
and i might make a data table like this you know unconsciously of course
but people are going to be making inferences from very very sparse state i mean
just a few examples just a few data points in each cell
which you know if you compute kai square tried to do conventional statistical measure association
it is going to give you anything particularly meaningful but we'll see tom griffiths we'll
talk about this i believe later on in the
in the course
that people people's causal inferences from very little data are surprisingly rational and reliable might
have something to do with how even a young child is able to learn about
the causal structure of the world from not just
this little data but you think about it to to take an example from human
how does a child learn when they first touch a hot stove not to touch
stove again
but that was touching the stove burned them
so do they do something like this do they keep track of all the times
in which they came up to the stove in the either touch to didn't touch
got burned didn't get burned no
once is enough
right or to take another example there is actually a button on the wall but
let's say there was and i went over here in press it and just at
the moment i pressed
the screen started to go and so what we think well everybody here would think
i guess this is what makes the screen go
probably makes go down to present again
or suppose i press the button and like all the lights in the auditorium go
well then just that one suspicious coincidence combined with all the other stuff you know
about how causal causality work somehow auditoriums work is enough to say OK i think
that what makes the lights go off maybe turns back on again and this ability
to infer new causal relation from one example this one suspicious coincidence is really quite
powerful i mean almost to the point that you have a misguided or what potential
for misuse of the power you think about all the causal relations you could infer
from this suppose i oneof here in press this button
and all of a sudden
the two have the other terms are split and these and the chairs on the
over here over there and underneath was revealed the swimming pool
has anybody seen it's a wonderful life
the gym is chemistry what actually happens very high school gym
that's where i got the idea but you know these crazy italian architects they could
think of anything
i mean that's possible that happened ITO that's the button
that makes the auditorium split in half to reveal the hidden something for us
so from the terminal state
so here everything about the terminal state would see the value that achieved
at terminal a blackjack you only when i was in the end you don't get
an immediate words
and what you need to know anything on monte carlo methods is that
these are typically independent of the
the from one state is independent of the size of the state space right nice
probably of among others however if you would a very state of course this upon
the state space
OK now i just talked about how to
evaluate the policy using monte carlo methods
but really blackjack you don't want to violate the policy you want to learn the
best policy
OK so how do do that it is a policy iteration framework for start with
some current policy pi
great evaluate the value of pi
in there and try improve policy but we only have one problem we get an
improvement steps
what's more sampling let's say we don't have the condition function
OK but the best example so it's in the general problem
we don't tend to function could be robot
if you only have the value function
it is found
so let's let's look at how we compute the policy earlier
i said the policy
with respect to some value function v
state s
is the argmax
that is the argument a which maximizes the expression here
the company
are as a
what i get for taking this action state
discounted reward which is
gamma time to some role next state
the probability of getting the text states
given the current state and actions
policy undervalue v
the value i
i believe or no i can get
that's fine
OK this is just sort of that
the back of the wrist
working with
we actually have a which maximizes
this value
as priors next day
you get or to be in the current state
OK and then you look at the best action OK
then assuming actions sticks or that you evaluate max if police action in individually in
action disperse their next state
it's not for probability the text eight times the value to get the next
and you would take the action a
maximize is this
this is what call these key values
the quality
of doing
action a in state s so you can also see
the policy as the argmax
over a
qs a
now what's the problem if i don't know the transition function
ten i computers five dollars transfer function
first of all where the transition function here
it's this thing right
that's too
how you get next is given you current take action
so what's the problem if it if i don't know
my transition function t
calculate this policy
right OK you you just don't know these probabilities
OK so
it's interesting when you come up with a solution to talk about values the
when you look at
are all solutions you most often talk about two that because you have to
so here's the idea
now look at the bottom equation the q value
i'm not going to join the estimate the value of all actions from all states
q that's under policy pi
looks just like the pipe before
the only additional constraint is that i'm sure the first actually i take
actually a number actions in the policy pi
which i take for articles one to infinity but t zero
my initial action is a
OK i see only given to that the definition of the q value
take the given action then follow policy after that
so that you get
now it turns out that i can easily compute the q values as i did
that i had added the state values
this means that i sample now for every state and action
and what about the q values you can see that you don't need a transition
function you can just take
the argmax actually ready to determine
the policy pi
OK so right i'm designing for simplicity probably that that they are functions given but
you might want to ask if it was not given
then you can also sample from that that's fine
because in the mind of is the q value here you december from
is it OK
so again my two values is just sampling
who wrote
so far values assembled from this the value function just among states for q values
december in this part thing which just includes the action the first action
we can use monte carlo algorithm again just keep the average returns to see first
team action
and think the argmax
where this one
that's complete darkness
and there was this spot
the second starship full rights query on one
has darkness if you bring them closer
your brains will say
no that's not sources that's really only one source
and we call this
the rayleigh criterion of resolution
and that really criterion of resolution therefore
is that the separation between the two
light beams bars or the headlights from the car
separation has to be larger than this angle
and is the function of a if a is larger than
that angle
can be
substantially smaller
and this is what we call
the diffraction
on angular resolution
it doesn't matter where you have the pinhole
or whether you have a lenses
circulants that we use these telescopes or whether you have concave mirrors which we use
these telescopes
in all cases
you always stuck
with the ideas
at best that's the best you can ever do
that is the angular separation
that theta
quality the fate of one
is that one point two
divided by a that is then
if you take a lens
which has a diameter a
of about twenty centimetres
then that translates
in two with theta one
of about half an hour second for five thousand angstroms
so i take
five thousand angstroms and from ten to the minus
ten metres
so if anyone then becomes
half arc seconds
o point five
arc seconds
the document is one sixty is over the art degree
and our second is sixty times lower than that
and so if a
two point four metres
telescope two point four meter telescope that's a real biggy
then theta one
would be
approximately one twenty fifth
of arc second
so the larger you make your telescope the better angular resolution you would have
this angular resolution is twelve times better
then this one
because a is twelve times larger
so now you may think that if you take it to point four meter telescope
on the ground and you look at stars
the two stars equally bright you will be able to tell them apart
if they are
so far away from each other than one twenty fifth of an arc second that
is not true
contrary it's very bad you can even tell them apart often when they are half
a second apart
and the reason for that is not the the diffraction limitation is going to kill
you but the reason is that the air is always turbulence
and is the turbulence on the air
that makes the
the diffraction limited imitates itself is very small move around on new photographic plates it
moved it around in a matter of ten seconds over an area which itself could
be as large as one second astronomers call that seeing
so when you look at your picture the whole story smeared out over an area
which is in angular size one
our second or maybe half an hour second best so you can never achieve this
from the ground
so all telescopes from the ground without exception
i can do it best half an hour second they cannot do much better because
of the air turbulence and this is not the great thing about the hubble space
is up there may be down there whichever it is i don't know where maybe
jeffrey knows what it is but it is somewhere
hubble has no air
and so
doesn't suffer of the air turbulence
hall of mirrors are indeed diffraction limited
and humble
has a mirror which is two point four meters diameter and indeed at five thousand
angstrom i checked that yesterday was people table space telescope in the is diffraction limited
and bubble has an angular resolution of five thousand angstroms which is about one twenty
fifth of an arc seconds
and at shorter wavelengths it's even better
and the longer wavelengths it is a little
and so i would like to show you least one picture of hubble without going
into the details
of what
you're seeing of the astro
if you astronomy and that's the one that is coming up it's a very famous
hubble made
several years ago
this is a picture of a supernova explosion
john if we can have the slide
you're looking here at an explosion
called supernova nineteen eighty seven a which occurred in february nineteen eighty seven
this object is hundred fifty thousand light years away from us
that means the explosion
really took place to place on the fifty thousand years ago
but we saw it for the first time in february eighty seven
and without going into the details of what you're looking at which is of course
very fascinating but that's not the objective today
i wanted to appreciate that this distance here
is one
arc seconds
and look at the incredible detail the table
show you
of those already but we'll we'll we'll obviously talk about some more such as the support
vector machine and so on so this is the the the sort of big-picture
we're aiming at it's sort of  plug and play approach to to analyzing data  I mean
maybe I should also mention that you know there are many sort of  extensions of these ideas
that are subjects of  current research for instance you might have multiple kernels how do
you deal with that how do you combine kernels and learn a combination of kernels
as part of a learning process how do you handle problems where your outputs are
more complex than just a classification or a regression maybe there's some structure in your output how
do you learn that and so on so there's you know a whole range of
research going on that are extending these methods and you know using unlabeled data to enhance your learning
and so on and so on but I'm not gonna talk about those I may just allude to them as we go through
okay so what I wanted to  a little bit more about preprocessing now leading
up to kernel PCA as an example of an algorithm preprocessing algorithm that can be
run in a kernel defined feature space but this this really this slide is really
a caveat and it's a general sort a caveat about kernel methods and if
you like it's one of the key weaknesses of kernel methods in some sense the point
is that actually doing feature selection in in a kernel defined feature space is not
possible and the reason is that up to any orthogonal transformation of your feature space
if there was any change of basis the the kernel is remains unchanged so your feature space is
only determined by the kernel up to any orthogonal transformation of your representation of your
of your basis and the reason for that is is very simple to see let's
imagine we take a transformation of our representation by some orthogonal matrix U to
create a new representation phi-hat so U is a transformation that satisfies U prime
U is the identity well let's compute the kernel kappa hat corresponding to this new representation okay
it's U phi of X U phi of X and if we just multiply that out
of course U prime U disappears we end up with kappa so basically the kernel is
only determined up to rotations of the coordinate system so in other words if there's
something about you coordinate system that you like and you think is very
you know tells you something about your data then you gonna loose it if
you use a kernel method so this is a you know key weakness I think of kernel
methods if you think about for instance language there's something very specific about words and they're very
you  know informative if you now just make a vector space of a words and use
a kernel method over that vector space you're throwing away that information as far
as the kernel method is concerned  any linear combination of words is just as
informative as  just a good as good a you know a basis
as the basis in terms of words so you're losing information there indeed you may
so well that's very strange I thought kernel methods were very good at doing topic classification
and the are but the key to making that work is actually in some
sense a bit of a clutch which is to re-weight the important words in
relative to the unimportant words by this TF-IDF waiting which I'll I'll talk about
later on in in the kernel section so in a way I think there's a you
know there's a mismatch there which is sort of glossed over in that particular application
but there is a real problem if you have something about your application that is
telling you you know your representation that you feel is very informative and if that is the
case and you think for instance there's likely to be a small number of
features that are involved they're very special features and they've been chosen very cleverly then
you know maybe kernel methods isn't for you and you should go for something like
boosting or a one norm regularized learning where you're looking specifically for small sets of features
that will actually do the job for you so it's just a caveat and but
it's also good to be aware of that but you know doing feature selection in
a kernel defining feature space is actually doing subspace selection because feature selection doesn't really
mean anything so what we're really thinking about is finding a subspace of the feature
space and projecting into that  subspace in this part of the preprocessing
so there's several ways of doing that and just to mention a few principal
components analysis I'll go into more detail that's the sort of the classical method and
we can indeed do that it chooses directions that maximize variants we've already seen we
can measure variance in the feature space so it makes sense so we'll  able
to do it and indeed we can canonical correlation analysis is looking where you have
two views  and you're trying to maximize choose a subspace in both views
the correspond the maximize the correlation so this can be quite useful if you have
two representations of your data and you want to somehow which may have different types
of noise in them and you want to clean the noise away and focus in
on the on the core representation that's a very effective way of doing that so this
this again can be applied in a kernel defined or kernel defined feature spaces in
this case Gram-Schmidt is a a sort of greedy approximation to principal components analysis that
chooses vectors one  at the time there are also sparse versions of principal components analysis that
that somehow in between these two that are better at optimizing the choice Gram-
Schmidt actually corresponds just to to doing a Cholesky decomposition of the kernel matrix or a guided
Cholesky decomposition of the kernel matrix so the you know the dual form of Gram-Schmidt is
is is Cholesky the dual form of principle components  analysis we'll see  is actually
principal components analysis but on a different matrix and canonical correlation analysis corresponds to a generalized
eigen value problem partial least squares is a very interesting method that is somewhat similar to
principal components analysis but uses labeling information to guide the search of the subspaces
so whereas prinicipal components analysis doesn't use the labels it just uses the variants
of the data itself to choose the directions partial least squares uses the labeling that information
to to help inform the search and so that again is a method that can
be kernelized and but I won't be talking about these three I'm just mentioning them
I'll I'll just go into  this one  here okay so principal components analysis so what are
we trying to do we're trying to find a subspace or or projection directions which
maximize the variance now I'm gonna ignore the I'm gonna assume that the data
is centered so that this we don't have to subtract the the mean square
and so on so it makes things a lot simpler to to present so I'll
quite nicely focused around the value had the optimal in the sense to stop and
the actual spread the distribution which started to get to look quite OK
now traditional statistics is actually concentrated on looking at me
and the typical sort of consideration is
the consistency of algorithm and the consistency of a classification algorithm a is defined to
be the property that the limit
as n tends to infinity of this so the sample size tending to infinity the
expected value of this distribution of errors tends to what's known as the the bayes
the bayes optimal function is essentially the best you could ever do
in the classification algorithm because it simply classifies according to
the label it is more likely
so it covers the case where
you might have noise in your data sets so that particular example might in some
cases because if i both positively and negatively with different probabilities and in that case
obviously you have to pick
the label is most likely to and that's what place
when does yes
this should be the generalisation of the base sorry that you're right sorry that should
be the loss of the base expected loss of the basis function this i thank
well spotted i see that
you might want that
so you should say expected value of the loss of f based on x y
what i meant was that the
you know the the function essentially it converges to
or you could just say you know the limit as n tends to infinity in
ASR is based
so that's the sort of
the study that i think you know from the previous slides you can see if
you know the problem with n tends to infinity is that
it's as long as the piece of string you know i mean
doesn't happen the million that's happened a billion you know i mean this this
what we want to know is what happens on the finite sample
finite sample generalization
has the distribution depending on the algorithm function class and sample size
as i indicated above the traditional statistics is looked to the mean of this distribution
but i think we
hopefully i have seen that it can be misleading
across the local all cross validation is another example where
you know you you can prove properties about the expected value cross-pollination
the very nice but obviousy in practice you can see that if you take a
low fold cross validation can get quite serious
errors in what you do
and that's due to this variance natural
so what statistical learning theory has prefered to analyzes the tail of the distribution so
rather than look for the main event distribution is focused on trying to estimate if
you like
the worst case
but how far out you might go
provided you're willing to throw away a certain amount of probability
so let me go back to one of those pictures and i think it should
be clear
so what you might say in
statistical learning theory is you want to bound says OK
i'm willing to accept that
one thousand or one hundred times
i'm gonna
completely messed up
i just be unlucky training set will just be so weird
i i will be able to learn
but i want to be ninety nine percent confidence that i'm going to have an
error about something so if we take that example here what we would say i
mean this this is actually
a thousand simulations so it cut off the top ten
the best we could say it would be something like about point six five
so you mentioned
you know with will align ourselves the luxury of throwing away the the tale of
sort of worst case it runs and then what is the best
what is the worst error we can get o point six five so this is
the kind of estimate that we might expect from
the statistical learning analysis and clearly there is a very big difference between that and
the expected value which is still there
way in the o point three
similarly you know if we go back one more
maybe the top ten here might
bring us to that point five but the expected value is still well well close
to the to the true value o point two
so you can see that there is a very great difference in what you actually
doing in some concrete cases
so in a way we can see it a bit like a statistical test
it was significant at the one percent confidence that means in statistical tests that means
that the chances that that data rose if the hypothesis is
if you cut each time you get speech decide these but interesting enough it's a
joint 2 words and section not just things tied these meetings tag beach in Thailand
and again example combined structured unstructured data together you can do this in flicker you
can if you like attack but most about tags just place names of spelled various
variations of and and there's really no good way to do a join intersection search
entitling separatist conjunction of words but if you actually know this and this is the
destination this attack was the author of this is a date supporting the powerful Internet
search and so this is our another way that pays off now a strike back
a 2nd you know Daniel said I use Lotus in mind Web technologies I actually
did need a lot technology from some members some of ideas but I really wish
I could have used a lot of semantic Web technology
I would say to me a lot of time and money and on the first
one was why don't we have a standard
our database of a destinations released an ontology for accessing such databases the being there's
no proprietary advantage to have a particular version of the world dismissed knocking insisted that
no 1 ever about the catalyze such a thing and the CIA in had reason
get 1 day owning there that kind of loss that that is to be open
source in some way and so we need some kind of a ontology they could
say by the way this is where destination is what apparently is that it's not
clear all by the way I mean there's those things like but thing is city
is inside a state states a U.S. concept is administered district all kind of stuff
is get worked out that someone worked about then we'd have a resource on the
web we could all match on
the other thing was you know with the demand that the destination database done right
it would be cheaper for other say destination oriented Web sites snapped a bad grid
and to make up their own so for instance we integrate with farmers just makes
his travel guides and they give us all the content for free exchange for Ofarrell
exceeds a good deal for us but they but we had to do the work
to figure out of that our destinations various nations in suggesting same thing with advertisers
where thing was tagging is not a core competency of a travel blogging site while
I have to make up my own tagging structures crazy if we had a tagging
ontology and tagging Mr. Web Web services at work was really done right and it
would be that the economics of the thing would force would cause there to be
a specialist players there would be tagging add-ons bijugatus mix into your site the a
network of would cause them to discuss the adopted and and then even without even
with those who still have the Google's and Yahoo's and we will play their own
way of course because they won along mountain positions that's cool because if you have
a status as would tag is so smart guys in the wall this is how
Yahoo's notion tag maps to the standard way or this way and so on December
rules motion numerous and then we get translation services as we evolve but also of
this kind analysis
now he is an example of stuff that really did help and maybe we should
include from that I have the 7 people in the company and we have millions
and millions of users enormous leverage and Internet start-up like this now they comes from
the fact that we can build on the giant chosen Johnson powerful databases is raising
you I libraries all the stuff no way we could ever do ourselves and is
the culture of the social Web to do it this way which meet injected the
culture it would be adopted there's no resistance to it's a culture reads their thing
is not just for use of just Ross operability services a small motion of Web
services the based on announcement below both forced make it happen tank so let me
just a step back now they're gonna finish with a single a questions with proactively
now I've given my Spears with that's where about can do some work stuff crew
we get to do security to really contribute to collective knowledge systems ecosystems by mentioned
text-based cost taxpayers syntactic reject this is kind of a no-brainer this hasn't been .
com and by the way if we don't know if it will get done in
some other way like performance because no about Mike value string URL it's a uses
the syntax we were not the actual syntax of euro as as part of its
semantics is you match the last string bits of the to stay with the tag
it's attempt overcomes spam but a and this guy community is gonna processes that research
the problem is that the it's not going to it is by solution will you
or your eyes anyway and the Salonika so the goes on but is the whole
point of my performances that expedient and they're looking for early adopted so network effect
and so we log out there and do something else that's what should we win
destination to corners anything it's as global data you could and since the thinking about
as the the the symbolic machinery problem and that this thing about how able of
global repository like the gym project Human Genome Project didn't happen without a standard for
the data data and that by community is a meaty takes and but healthy they
have their act together that's data exchange and use ontologies are another thing is portable
identity reputation as a project that could this is a really important problem for the
Web really important and that and if if we just leave a symbol of all
agreements it's not going to solve the relating dig down say for an agents to
be represented with some urbanity bag backpack they can carry around them in such a
way that we've thought through the implications for privacy and everything that thing is really
by my side has really no new Google has of adviser has written everybody has
he is a relation
so i went back
the female
that was a
all of this is
and you or i
these are
in he's
well actually
these are
look on the
and it really
people are
the rest of
the one one of
think of it as a memory but keep in mind that of course it extensively
x direction and is everywhere the same x direction over the whole length eight i
cannot change that i cannot make you see that
and so for instance
the two one mode
i would then be
if i make mary through and i make nancy one
then in the y direction i would have
the complete note surface
which runs all the way from the box
entirely sealed box no x x component of the field and this one would then
these new direction and this will be built in this direction and will go like
and then if you have the two to mold
this is the two two mode
so x is in this direction
then you would get this
you get one homolog surface you know component
now x component of the vector no x component of the vector throughout the entire
throughout complete x
and then this will come to you this will come to you this would go
away from you and it will be the standing of living way
now independently
i can now look at the y component of the field
because i only looked at the
x components
let's now look into why direction
and that's now
ask what is the problem with you y value y also has to become zero
when it
in the plane becomes the tangential component
and therefore y must be zero when x equals zero
and when x equals h
and one thing equal zero and one z equals c
if you y
in this direction
must vanish when x equals zero
it must twenty four x equals a and must also in this from place equal
zero and in the back plate z equals
so now you can come up immediately
by by parallel you can immediately come up with a
relationship i will call it now
l as in lyon
four x
then for the i will keep the and nancy
so don't get confused so that is no c
i'll do it in terms of squares
and then i'll get
over eight
overseas squared
that's it
for now i have another
infinite families
of values from aladdin lion and nancy which give me the resonance condition
the y direction
and so if i had linearly polarized radiation
i could have in the x direction in the polarized radiation which would then have
to obey
i could have linearly polarized direct variation in the wind direction which would have to
obey this sequence of frequencies and i could do one in the same direction which
of course you can make up for yourself
it is also possible in any linear combination of those would be fine but of
course it is also possible
that i have an effect or
which has a component x y and z
and that's simultaneously
all boundary conditions are met so i don't just radiate
polarized radiation only in the x direction and only in the same direction but now
i say aha
if no i make only guess crayons
if that now see squared
over a squared
plus mary l mary y
over b scribd
plus nancy by
over c square
then i can have an effect which is in some random directions well maybe not
too random because i have to beat
this condition
and now we have a whole
family of infinite number of resonance frequencies
which are not only defectors in x y or z direction did i make a
slip thank you very much i this is clear downstairs right
isn't one of actually non-zero museo
thank you
i appreciate it really i do because it's so nasty
this led so we are or have been our ideas i
all right
i'm going to change gears
because i want it
to find a way to demonstrate this
i'm going to change gears
and i'm going to make this box
going to ask myself what i do resonance frequencies
for some
sound is longer always
so sound has no
linear polarization
and so now
i can immediately right down
the function of the overpressure be over and above all an atmosphere albedo and atmosphere
because now i know
that's at all
for surfaces
i must have pressure and notes
artists also ninety six tool
a single as the eighties
tensor functor it to itself of october nineteen ninety six
we took a hundred thousand documents from writers corpus so basically this would be roughly
two thousand
two thousand to three thousand news stories per place more-or-less complete corpus
extracted the most
frequent named entities so most tricking them into this would be in the proper names
which occur
most frequently
so here you can see mainly the names of the countries plus maybe was three
these are the bill clinton and maybe some
other name but not too too many other names
many countries plus the most popular
fifteen obviously and what's three this because there's a good sector of
good good good portion of reasons for using cyc
OK what we can do with this method
so again we can observe what are particular topics about
so basically this area here would correspond to
southern american pop this would be more like asian topics
and this would be more like financial topics and here in the middle so this
more like us and so
one possible u
would be
showing the trace showed traces can see how
one particular name entity moves through time
so what does this mean
it's the name entity which appears
in many documents in these documents
changing topics
as much as well through the news topics change
and also through time
argentinos argentinos always described the
news articles
it appears
this is this news articles are changing its focus also the profile of the typical
profile of argentinos changing and this is you see that that's which go through time
hall argentina travellers on this
and since argentina's very covering very soft some american topics then you may need moves
in this area of the men that china would
move more on this
upper part there are mainly asian topics that's a while the if was not
in israel
well it's in this area of france for me let's see
it's more francis more generic topics so it covers the whole part of the map
and so on it's a bit cleaned up
was american president is involved in many
many topics
the film
jump here and there are different in different parts of the map
now if we move
this slide there through time you see that's how this bill clinton really
it's travelling so between ten and this is the point of the time it's
and this
part of this
forbidden and you can also check
relationships to other
name entities
now if you go with clinton and so on this line between bill clinton and
this would get describe
with a set of keywords so we take all the documents were
the clinton and russia appears
copious and so this would be sent three the
a set of documents of section to this cluster
and the typical keywords we describe this relationship will be cleaned clinton years in russian
could always deliver teaching and so on very clear to the russian us-russian
type of topics from mid nineties well let's see if we were to move
if you check relationship between bill clinton and chicago
we would see a completely different type of q likely to convention democrats republicans and
so on so it was obviously the time of
elections and then the this keywords
this keywords of the election type of keywords would you and you can easily see
that clinton appears
with different name entities in different relationships let's see
china it's about tobacco smoking whatever this was
so this is one way how to how to visualize also the
text corpus pretty large text corpus in very simple way
and also visualize this time dimensions
and also relationship to other
other named to other and this in this particular case we had this name entities
so much about this
but this them on the this is roughly i would say
type of software type of techniques reach
i used also in all other most of the other more sophisticated exposition
softer side
this what we do may be just a few words so we take documents transforming
them into this vector space model we perform
clustering car this that it semantic indexing this is one one way how to perform
physical clustering
you use
the whole corpus from these hundred thousand dimensions roughly
one hundred two hundred dimensions and then we performed
method called multidimensional scaling
compresses this
the two hundred dimensions down to two dimensions which you see here
and we try to preserve regional
original distances between the documents so
if two
methods were in original space
in these proportions that we try to preserve his
relationships also in the final features so this is a description of what do because
so an outcome from a set aside that's if you give them all names obviously
binary or link
this outcome can be communicated in other to
i will again
this is
based on battleships
but slightly more building being game i have had to read than battleships
it's called summary
the separating wall
submarine is hidden somewhere in the ocean and then you have to start firing at
it just like in battleships to try and find long submarine
so let's run submarine
here it is
let's have a game show
i've built in some shannon right so we can see for every possible thing we
could do you can find any square
because it tells you what the probability of getting a yes is that you hit
the submarine summary is just one square at sixty four
and the problem sixty three over sixty four that's right hand
sixty through sixty four of the square
and sixty three six four for this one
all right so
the same
because we don't know whether summary is okay
so could actually find this square form
it could interact with the probability of the outcome happened fired
three which is now
no discovery
first outcome
the probability
that's response the
was no
sixty three hundred sixty four
so the shannon information content of the first
log base two
o one over at which is always to sixty four
over sixty three
all right
and that's slightly below are
number had zero point
so what's going on with the disorder
trivial examples weighing problems where of-course you wanted to be a third third third one to think about it
we looked at
identifying underwear with binary strings all
again for sixty three
every week on coming to fifty announcing what about the world with probability uneven
shannon says when you find that's where i got no
you've got this much information point o two two seven bits
it's not obvious that that's right is
so let's carry on playing and see what happens
so far the square
now the probability of getting yes is one over sixty three
and the is sixty two sixty three shells
what happened
the probability of getting a know
this is what happened
sixty two
sharing information content with long to
which was
slightly more
so i know point
three and the right hand column is keeping track of the total information we've gained so far let's
right now
and as well
so little information gain
so far
there is no basis in the
sixty three o
sixty two
we carry on playing
i can
so i write down all these
could have just
going for a while
we could go back and try and find the square the probability of getting a no is one
probably yes zero
now give us no information content so we can write and nothing happens
you can carry on doing that in
the problem that
okay what's happened a five at
half the squares
what's happened to the shannon information content when you add it all up so far
i got lots and lots nose
and the final one that just ask
as long as thirty three
over thirty two
semantic shared information content just got the total so far we still haven't found anything but
adds up to one
that's the one bit
what's going on
it's a bit like playing sixty three
achievement at question is the number one
so it is zero you want it to the three threshold going very silly strategy and sixty three
and we get right
and is
the thirty one
and the answer is
no it's not very well
got the great thing about this and that's just the same as asking it less recalled very well
which from bit
so this is consistent with what we already opposed completely obvious
all right so that's promising
this has added up to
he wanted it
very painfully acquired information content but it makes complete
okay shall carry on that they wanted to
from from from
so we did it
as a surprise
and what happened
last log
one plus
the band
attempt was that this actually happened at
who you would just about to expect another know which we had a probability
nineteen over twenty
the latest thing we just
did that god knows
the information content
twenty one or twenty
but then amazingly
we got some an enormous fall into bit according to show we got
o point three bits of information content or some
and not lot to
one is
the the
so i think the
rather than actually
this is something seems to be so
so in
this is a
it's a she
which is why do i really
so the we see
it lies to
g c u which is the
so that the sum
when he wants to
you can also look each
well we
this is a huge
it's very easy
and that some of the
it's like
he is also
i mean
it is
so t
this is
all of these two
fifty one
the team
the future
the change he said well
the only change
so there's
we need to do
so you to change your
well to
we do
that this
you want to
in two one is
one two
so what
this is
it's difficult
also for
what is this
single gene called the SRY gene for sex determining region of the y chromosome which
will code for the development of the testis
in the absence of the gene and ovary will develop
subsequently the bone marrow phenotype will then determine the brain's phenotype by secreting steroids hormones
so the male testis will begin steroid production very early on in humans it will
actually occur during the second try master sometimes the woman doesn't even know she's pregnant
in the absence of steroids brain will develop as the female phenotype
in our role models
or in some circumstances of happen in humans we know that if we give the
former we can actually change the phenotype of the brain to the male
by giving male hormones i like to think of this as mother nature being rather
clever and saying i don't really care about the genetic sex of the organism i
want to make sure that the going have sex and the brain sex are well-matched
because the purpose of course is always to promote effective reproduction for transfer genes down
to the next generation
this changed to male versus female female phenotype of of the brain occurs very early
in development and as i said in humans it will begin doing the second try
mister very early on in our role models we know exactly when it occurs because
we can manipulate them and what you're looking at here is that the blue peaks
and valleys are testosterone circulating in the fetal circulation many people tend to think of
testosterone and estrogens is hormones that only appear at puberty but in fact the whole
hypothalamus pituitary canal axis is fully mature
in utero
and completely active so the male fetus will begin producing very copious quantities of testosterone
which begins in the rodent embryonic lee in the last couple days of pregnancy and
continues the first couple days after birth
in humans a newborn human male baby has the circulating testosterone of the twenty five
year-old adult that that testosterone will go away as that reproductive axis is silenced and
will remain silent hopefully for good
twelve to thirteen years until puberty re-emerges
we call this early period of hormone exposure the organisational period and it will determine
how the hormones post world war act on the brain the activation of period one
of the advantages of our own animal model is that this period does extend into
the postnatal period so after the animals are born and we can identify was called
the sensitive period for this organisation we identified by giving injections of testosterone to female
rats and asking if their brain has turned into a male rat brain once we
get outside of the sensitive period the female no longer response to this injection of
testosterone program will forever stay female
so how do we connect brain sex differences to sex differences in behavior
it's very challenging because we can manipulate the brain in the same way we can
do so peripheral organs but what we can do is determine the cellular mechanisms so
if we know that humans are causing brain changes and we think brain changes are
correlated with behavioral changes we want to identify what it is that the hormone is
regulating to change the brain and subsequently the behaviour just call that factor x because
it differ for every different brain regions and point it can be different factors and
one of the things that we can do once you've identified factor axes that we
can block and show that it blocked both the brain change and the behavioral change
and that's how we make our logical connections it's really strong convergence we can absolutely
prove or hypotheses were working in the brain in this
nature but we can use strong convergence
so to return to the type one of sex dimorphism carburetor behaviour in the rodent
is highly sexually dimorphic the males show amounting behaviour of the female and the female
debs sexually receptive posture called low doses so they show up very different motor response
when it comes time to copulate
and we know exactly what the brain area controls as in the male is called
the pre optic region has nothing to do with vision it's only names that because
of its proximity to the optic nerve this is the brain region where neurons are
full of receptors for steroids so they are very responsive to steroids and if we
lesion this brain region the male will lose all interest in sex if developmentally we
put the streets only in this brain region he will become asking lies in terms
of his sex behavior if we give females testosterone very early in life in adulthood
we can get them to mount i can mail when we give them activating levels
of testosterone a second time
so as i said some brain regions are larger than others but also the synapses
are different in males and females and one of the things in my laboratory has
focused on this particular type of synapse called the dendritic spine part of the reason
that we focus on it is because it's easy to measure easier to measure than
other types synapses because dendritic spines are what they sound like the these little tiny
protruding of of neurons and once we visualize the neuron we can actually just go
in and count them or we can use the quantification of proteins that are found
only in the spines and ask if are different in males and females
so what we did is we just as the very simple question is there are
sex differences in dendritic spines in the newborn brain
of rats and this is what that looked like when their newborn little pink is
so we collected them on the second and third day of life dissected out this
brain region and then quantified
and what we found is that the males had almost over twice as many dendritic
spines as the female were quantified this in two ways one is that we measure
protein in the spines called spinal filling foot spine loving what you're looking at here
is what's called the western blot each one of these little black dashes is the
pre optic area from a single animal so you can see they're all of the
males have much more this protein then all of the females we also visualize the
neuron through an ancient process called gold impregnation is actually develop the eighteen hundreds by
romani cahall and his colleagues his colleague old and what you see these little feathery
things coming off of this process those are the actual dendritic spines and we can
go into account and they match perfectly to the protein males have about twice as
many as females
so once we characterize the basic sex difference would like to ask how did it
come about and was regulated by hormones so if we treat the newborn female with
male hormone injections will she then have a male pattern of synopsis
so we treated her on the day of birth the next day and measured at
now which is usually the case
because for independent independent variables they are probabilities are simply the product of the probabilities
the definition of independence than what we have is this kind of
and this kind of a product of the probabilities for each observation
so for example let's say that we want to estimate
the this mean parameter u
for a gaussian distribution so then the probability of all of the sources of the
samples will be
the products
of these expensive is exponential function of x of the observation minus mu
the squared divided by two times and sigma
sigma squared and then we have a normalisation constant which is not important here
so now
now let me explain you so the point is that
the reason why we use what we want to use other things all the time
you simply that
now when we take the logarithm of that's
this probability of word given all of these samples
sorry all these observations
but it would be some
of the probabilities
now the point is that such a much simpler to work with them products for
example now so we have here parameter
the so much for example when we want to compute the derivative
so that we can find the maximum of course then the
well this thing
of the many people
of the sum is simply the sum of the derivatives
and so that's the story that's
that's it suffices life very much we basically just need to compute the derivative of
the log probability and then some of those together
and as we saw this is this
the situation becomes very very simple when we have a gaussian distribution because then the
logarithm is a quadratic form and when we take the derivative will actually get the
linear function is actually what we get is things like we get like linear equations
solve in the case of the estimated that this would go some variables are very
nice and popular and everybody likes them
so here
now were
we have taken the name and logo isn't it the sequel to one of those
articles is zero
taking the derivative well this just as this is even simpler because this is one-dimensional
so we don't have the quadratic form we seem to have a quadratic function
and while the derivative of the square will be simply the identity function is
you cite and we see that
yes the the we see that the maximum likelihood estimator formula it will simply
the the average
of the observations
which is reasonable because we knew that
new is is the mean value of its distribution so it's reasonable to approximate that
is estimated by the average of the observations
sorry i should go there so so that ends basically the
introduction part
and now i think i really
try to get some more slide so
same is the case then
yes mica
well i'm a bit confused about i should say that this is the first
few slides to show you that what is actually to be made
the basic idea of what is really difference between ICMP c is actually more if
you don't remember anything from this lectures
then one single sentence
which may be quite reasonable expectation given my my boring way of speaking well you
remember the the
this is really a very different thing from principal component analysis
it is well
the persons who first proposed ICA the kind of thought that well it's kind of
the same thing as principal component analysis so they gave the name that's rather the
similar body test it leads to a lot of confusion
it is really what this talk what these two techniques have in common is that
they are i mean that apart component analysis that is through both analyzing data into
components and actually i usually do it in a linear manner
but the way these components are computed and
uh the objectives in computing this components i mean the purpose of computing these components
are completely different and the principal components are good for certain things and independent components
are good for other things and the there's hardly any overlap between these two things
the way
i see it was considered in the first place it was in the context of
what is called blind source separation
so this is
and this is a problem and as you will see this has
nothing to do with the fundamental problem that we try to solve with big PCA
PCA we want to solve this problem at the estimation by a limited number of
components by the separation is has nothing at all to do with that kind of
there this this is a bit similar to this idea of to what i so
you know very very beginning well i had a different images that were mixed together
says that all have the same orientation at the injection site meaning of this site
it was a site that like vertical tuning than other cells that like particles
we are all connected to the site and you can show that this is the
key property for making pinwheels
in the auditory cortex
there is no vision in the normal animal and all cells
connect to each other that like the same sound frequency
cells that fire together wire together that's the principle by which
the word influences connection
in the rewired auditory cortex connections are much more like the visual cortex and not
at all like the auditory cortex
so as long as you have this substrates for transducing
electrical activity from the word interconnections
the brain uses that in order to form networks
this is the way it must be
because there are not enough genes to make every synapse
so my genome
it landed as me has about thirty two thirty five thousand genes
and the human genome
they have only about forty five thousand genes so only part more genes
in people compared to my eyes yet our brains have at least two thousand possibly
ten thousand more synopsis
genes cannot do it all
genes acting together with the world that we live in all the world that grew
up in or the environment
we must have a role in shaping
the networks that are made in the brain
and these networks
must be made by molecules that are sensitive to electricity
and electrical activity and the
and the pattern of activity
takes information from the world and cries brain
the only information
that auditory cortex has about the world is in the pattern of electrical activity in
its inputs OK it has no other information
and it uses the pattern of activity
given by vision make one kind of network driven by audition to make another kind
of network the same cortex but in a very different networks depending on what drives
so then
we've learned a little bit about how
the brain by itself
we have learned that that this to and from cortex associated molecules
and cortical networks shared by input activity
and how might be then two together with the media behaviour not going to tell
you a lot about this except to say
rewired animals
do we use
cortex to see
there are different kinds of experiments if you can demonstrate that
so the lesson from all of this
so so this is the picture of the rewired auditory cortex
and you can't tell it apart from normal cortex
this is also a picture of the dot like
grain that i told you about these other the kinds of pictures that romans used
to derive
his images of where might one part of the brain
i one function or another part might derive another function
but what
this work our work and the work of others in i feel suggests that cortical
activity the networks derived function from the inputs
the auditory cortex can function like visual cortex depending on the nature of input during
development that wired networks in order to process that
people can be what to
it's not simply that it's that the wire
but there are people who are congenitally blind
in in home
the visual cortex doesn't just said
it does other things processes
for example the this is the work from marc pallot and you the russian labs
so is the opposite of our experiments to complement about experiments if there are so
that is the dynamic
aspect of brain development where the inputs and pathways and networks are constantly being shipped
one by the other
if we can make networks
in the auditory cortex
become like visual
it is possible
that we might one day
the networks in a dish
if you can provide it the right kind of electrical stimulation
think that's the fantasy but not unrealizable
and so
these brain cells
from the visual cortex of rats growing in addition to the the synapse
and in my lab
in collaboration with barbed languor
we can make brain cells grown in microelectrodes are so now
that's not why is that are bringing the pattern of activity from vision into the
into the auditory cortex but electrodes that can be stimulating says that are growing on
them in order to help them self organised that
make networks
and here it is
a kind of network that is made by
cells that we are recording from here the cell
we record from it by by by catching onto it and here are stimulation sites
and in this
in this case it was certain pattern of stimulation given
and you can see that the cell
is driven much more by this electrode last but that not by that this is
what is called the cell's receptive field
and it's actually if it is affected by this
for its inputs to make it
and if what is called a low pass filter
but it is the most elementary of computations that we can create conditions
we can also lay down to is on biodegradable substrates
shown here and then lay down neurons and stimulate them and helped them organize into
networks so we can make pact with and networks in substrates and one day
it is possible that these will serve as implants for recovery from strokes
what do these experiments me i'm going to spend the last five minutes
talking about
why it is unlikely
so when i talk about this immediately as
you know i find
to create a brain
and with this being intelligence
and the answer is no
i don't think so and the answer has to do with the deep structure of
the brain and mind of cognition and in five minutes i'll take you through that
what does it mean to have in mind
and that's a hard question
the mind fundamentally
it has to do with extracting meaning from the work
and from the world of stimuli
there are two examples
the great examples of extracting meaning or semantics from the web so
four for a long time the part about how the brain creates the mind and
free knowledge just found just golf
fanciful idea
OK various ways to speed it up but also there's a problem with the fact
that you have multiple local minima so there isn't a unique global well maybe a
unique global solution but but there are lots of local minima
in the in the white space when you're looking to optimize
the performance of the network
so you're into quite difficult
situation in terms of
actually getting this thing to work in practice in reliable and
verifiable way and
correspondingly the statistics is also more complicated and less
less understood
so in contrast the kernel methods approach which was developed much later but well the
idea actually was in the sixties put forward in
papers in russia but
USSR but we're not
seen in the west or understood the potential is not fully understood
when they were first proposed but anyway believe that the site
as far as the sort of west is concerned these came to the fore in
the nineteen nineties
so it's a very different approach to solving the same problem so as i mentioned
the problem is capacity
how are you going to get
flexibility into your function class
and then you functions in the input space and not well
OK let's try and project the inputs into more complicated space
and the hope is that the
the more complicated space has a much higher dimension
in the input space and in high dimensions
linear functions have more flexibility
basically the flexibility of linear function class is actually proportional to its
dimensions so by putting yourself into a higher dimension you create more flexibility i mean
intuitively if you add extra features you can do more with by just combining them
in a linear way
i mean that's that's what we're trying to do
so this is a sort of you know
good idea let's try
so here's an example of what you might do
so we take our input vector which might be a two dimensional vector x one
x two
and we map have to more complicated vector which has x one squared x one
x two x one of these two are the same it just that way to
to make it sort of easier when we come to look at something a bit
and x two square
now if we write a linear equation in this space
so this is the feature space now
we take this input method into something a bit more complicated four dimensional
let's take a linear function of it so a x one squared plus b x
two squared c
we have the equation of an ellipse
and that is not a linear shape in the input space so the input space
linear functions in the two dimensional space straight lines
so we managed to create a function
that is not a straight line in the input space by taking a linear function
in this
in this feature space
so we can see that we have actually increased are
flexibility by adding in these extra features
now i'm going to give you an example of how this might work
so this unfortunately doesn't seem to work when i do it
here in the
how point here again OK so
here's a little video to show how
here what you have to think is that you're trying to
do classification problems
these are very visible but these red dots in the middle these blue dots on
the outside
and you're going to try and separate the red dots from the blue dots
you know as a classification problem clearly with the straight line you can't do that
OK so
so what do you do have so
here the video show you
so you turn it into a three-dimensional problem
by projection you then do linear function in three dimensions which is now a plane
that cuts across
the three-dimensional structure
and when you go back to the input space
you've got a circle
so what was a straight you know linear function that feature space actually becomes nonlinear
in the input space and can do this more flexible job for you
i can try again now
OK so
o thing that gives you a flavour of the kind of
an intuition of what's happening
OK so what do we know what we know about capacity of of functions classes
i mean linear function classes
as i mentioned before the capacities is actually proportional to the dimension and there's this
theorem says OK given
and plus one examples
in general position in an n dimensional space
we can generate every possible classification the thresholded linear function so what i mean by
that is here is a two dimensional space
not very well
orthogonal these axes and all that isn't so that these these the hyperlinks like there
are three points here
and we're going to try and do a different classifications for instance let's say that
they are all positive
OK this hyperplane this line here
with this the positive side makes them more positive
the same one which is the positive side a small negative
OK well what other things could happen well this could be positive in these two
could be negative OK well this line does that for us
by just saying this is the positive side of the negative side and so on
every other combination there a possible
combinations that you might have
and these four
the lines will realise every possible combination
so you've got this flexibility there
to do whatever you like with three points in two dimensions three
you know n plus one examples in m dimensions two
and is two in this case
and we've got three examples and we can do what we like and that generalizes
up to
any and
so in other words
you know by by moving up to this high dimensional space we've shown sort of
with an example that we get more power and here's the theorem tells us yes
you do get definitely a lot more
and so yeah OK looks like we solve the problem that we started with that
was the problem of having too little capacity in in the input space
linear functions in input space
so that's good news
so what we're looking at is functions of this type
play by contrast could keep the ball for six point racing they also have five
losses four keepaway and had this distinction between the learning
and here is five was for people where really should get in another demo of
reinforcement learning problem and my against how do you think about how this is a
reinforcement learning problem and i think about what the senses are the actuators are what
the reward function is because the three basic elements reinforcement learning from sensors actuators reinforcement
serious texas we will play this is about one by
drew bagnell and jeff schneider and
i you should be able to see the
the block is falling but using the actions you seeing
the block the the where the block lands and so
the sensors in here are sensitive inform the the the agent about the shape and
the height of the blocks on the floor and the shape of the object the
location of the objects falling and the actions are to remove the object right left
the obvious falling or two
push it all the way down
my usual things that you would do it you play interest
the reward function would be for example one unit of reward for every time step
game not
so maximizing that would then lead to all these sort of optimisation
just take those problems can make reinforced concrete now let me step back and talk
a bit more about the history in place of reinforcement learning and i will dive
into the markov decision process framework
in some ways reinforcement learning has has
has had input from and
actually output ideas from multiple different disciplines analysis some of these here because i
it's actually touched on
some of these ideas come from these different disciplines what we talk about neuroscience let
me begin with that i would talk much about that so i mean
say a couple of sentences about it and then we want that this is particularly
over the last five years or so we have a great deal of excitement the
intersection of neuroscience reinforcement in particular there has been a
part of the brain the basal ganglia on the dopamine system in particular that has
been shown pretty convincingly now
to actually implement an algorithm tell you about today the temple different thing out
so the part of the brain
that's a fairly convincingly
is shown to be implemented the TTL
so as you can imagine this is very exciting for reinforcement learning researchers process being
very exciting neuroscience people because now they have a connection to all this wonderful i
think pieces of work and enforcement learning that they can
map their ideas by that i just want to a whole bunch of other working
in neuroscience that has ideas of reinforcement learning really want talk about if you're really
interested in that sort of that's direction i can mention the name
probably fall on the names petered and d year y and just two google search
to find and
from his papers you can make lot of connections
OK a very strong intersection exists between operations research in reinforcement learning in factored markov
decision process formulation the ponte formulation come from operations research was a very strong interplay
between operations research to reinforcement learning and so the researchers some very good researchers reinforcement
companies community and a bit
contributions back to this community from reinforcement obvious connection to artificial intelligence
much of the origin reinforcement learning actually started mathematical psychology
bush was stellar i can show you quote in a minute from mathematical psychology
has an idea of the reinforcement of the ideas
and finally
control theory properly control
intersects operations research and reinforcement learning because in some sense the reinforcement learning view of
the AI problem is that problems in optimal control
this is a very strong
and obviously into intersection that you'll see
develop some of this is the quote that i want to share with you this
is from thorndike law of effect and really from way back in nineteen eleven captures
the essence
the idea of reinforcement learning and i'll read it to you and of course is
fall on the screen and the basic idea of several responses made to the same
situation those which are followed by a company closely
in time
my satisfaction to the animal will other things being equal be more firmly connected with
the situation
so that in the same situation we could see the reaction is more likely to
and the opposite for the opposite
right so this idea of
temporal coincidence between the situation and effect for my satisfaction leads to strengthening of that
has been around for a long time and essentially is a foundational principle of the
of reinforcement learning and i'll and you know and i will develop this talk about
temple saying i want really believe much more about history but there's a whole lotta
history of
people building reinforcement learning ideas in
in the field of computer science and artificial intelligence starting during really all idea programming
can be learned by trial and error biscuits on and i what's what time this
i promise i'm going to get to some very far work very soon i want
to continue building the connection between reinforcement learning and other areas for a few more
slide so here we are trying to do is distinguish reinforcement learning from the other
is the machine learning that more people are familiar with which is supervised and unsupervised
learning so supervised learning and learning from examples
learning approaches to regression classification unsupervised learning our learning approach to most induction density estimation
and so on
in this context what reinforcement learning reinforcement learning is learning approaches to sequential decision making
learning from delayed reward
so let me explain this distinction
a key
key question the reinforcement learning asks that is not passed
by supervised and unsupervised learning is the following
imagine you play
the game of chess
o rules and you know it
is that
will be very small
what about half of all of
so that's what we already from UK
and that's what we observe
o you
i don't know
on the day
the number of all
and i i
this is the
the right of
it is
out of that
in fact
so do we
are not
and these factors
that a you may right
wrong that
and back
is that depends on what you do that all the variables
the data
very well with all the way back to the one
you need to do is read
by the way
that's not
and q
that the
so in order
and i want to move any does not the
all right
one that we use
about the
it's not really fair to
you know that they can actually
my name is one
all the the way we are
know are
are correct
there's no
that's what we want we want to be able to estimate that the thing that
it's called the input data
expected risk
so because it's unbiased let's try to to find the best function
all over our training set
according to the empirical risk this is called the empirical risk minimization principle
and there
in fact it's also
computing the value of the of the
the risk of the best function we could find on the same data
it's called
the training area so in general what we call the training error is
you have a training set of
for example you have a set of functions and you're searching for the best function
in the function space according to the training example set of examples that you have
so you minimize the error on your training set and you get
minimum error the air that you get is the the air of the best function
in the function space the best being the one that minimizes the loss function so
now the question is is that training are a good estimate of
the the expected risk because what we want is to estimate this
and unfortunately the answer is
it is not and in fact it is biased it is
optimus optimistically biased basically which means that the
the difference between the
the there is the the expected risk of the best function you found and the
training error
is positive so the expected risk of your best function is always going to be
than the the training or you've got so so if you just minimize friction over
your version space or a training example of examples you are going to think that
your function is great it's going to have a very small training error
great but in fact it's not going to be good according to the real data
that you have not seen so
this is the very important because otherwise learning would be easy basically
so that's the big problem and where we're not happy about that
fortunately there are people who try to to bound the difference between the two we
know that we the air that we made on the training example is going to
be much smaller than the real error of that function in example that we have
never seen but how bad is the difference between the two how big is it
the good thing is that we can bound it we can we can try to
bound on the difference between the two
and this bound be depends on some very important concept in statistical machine learning called
the capacity
of the set of functions
so two
explain you quickly what is the capacity of a set of functions
it has been defined for the classification case but it can be expanded to any
any possible OK so in the classification case we call the capacity
of the set of functions
the largest number and
such that you can sort out there exists training example training set of example of
size n such that
you can always find a function your function space which would give the correct
classification discriminate discrimination for any possible labeling
so what does that mean
it means that if ten is five
i can always five find high points
four which
all possible combination of labeling say class one one one minus one minus one or
minus one one minus one with all possible combinations for all of them there would
be a function the function space that sort of that task
so this is called the capitalist so it's the biggest number
that that would have this this characteristic
what we should understand more in general is this that this capacity reflects the the
size of the set of functions the complexity of the function you could find into
that set so the more the bigger is that function space say
compare the function space of polynomials of order five with a polynomial of order two
obviously the all the functions of polynomial of order five this percent is much bigger
and can solve more more task are more be happy with more training sets of
examples that and
but you know have set of order two
and in fact one is included to get one with the polynomials of order five
there's always this subset of polynomials of order two and that's very good you see
anyway what's important is that as soon as we have defined this capacity then there
are several theoretical scientists that were able to bound what we wanted so the difference
between the
expected risk what's going to happen to a given function
on the that we have never seen and the
the training area which is what we
what we expect we saw on the training data and we
we can bound that so the maximum value of the difference is going to be
borne by some complex
function here that includes
the capacity
the number of of examples sorry the number of examples
and some at the parameter which defines how
well how risky want this bound to be
so if you want to the predicted to exceed that bond is is the is
very high you can have a very very small value but of course this is
going to be very very high so
so what it means is that
the bound exists but unfortunately it's very very large in general is not
truly useful worse than that even if the bound exist it depends on that page
and and that h
the capacity
why it's easy to define
for some classes of function is in general impossible to compute precisely for most of
the interesting set of functions
not all of them so for some of them places for the linear a set
of function we can compute it but for most of the set of functions we
cannot compute compute that h so
this is only
mainly theoretical for most of the case but it helps to know that the difference
between the training error and test error the generalisation error is bounded and it bounded