each voxel at the time you just go into one voxel and then you for
example see if the responses are significantly different in the two cases you just the
ricci tensor something like that now
these maps
partly coincide
but there are independent because i mean the the classifier is more general ultimately you
will always be able to pick up a brain area ways we see an average
increase because the classifier will also be able to respond to an overall increase
and this you remove it
which is what we typically do because we're interested in these two is orthogonal axes
how one axis is the patterning and the other axis is kind of the DC
component across the area and i don't have this image here but what you find
is that this is not always the part of the brain that where the overall
activity is increased
you know
so if you know what i mean with the of what way we don't get
information of the individual works level more
if you plot the selectivity
what you see all show you slide further down what you'll see is if you
plot the single voxel selectivity
what you see is that the effects of each walks all of the univariate just
thanks very very small
and the you have the juxtaposition of voxels that prefer one or the other conditions
so it's true patterning of the signal is not just kind of overall effect or
something like that
but also in the because of the covariance if you if you if you neglect
the covariance then you know classifier straight strongly breaks down so there's information actually also
stored in the code
exactly but the point with the classical october analysis is just that it doesn't have
the sensitivity
for example you find in in the study of show you in a minute i
actually have taken all these slides out because just to shorten things because normally have
the slide show you the the normal effects as well as classical effects in the
next video show you know there's a very clear dissociation you find the brain area
that doesn't show an overall increase during the task it just shows change in the
and that's something if you were to one i heuristic for example could be i
i only look at those parts of the brain that showing higher activity when you're
doing the task
but that's not good because these are only partly overlap in these areas
yeah exactly
is that these are the different possibilities one possibility is that the whole area goes
up or down the classical analysis
and was
so what do you mean
now that's that's what i said just now there's very weak information if you just
look at that if you just look at the information of the single voxel level
it's very weak
but the point is that the point is that if you go back to this
scheme here
back to this this graph here
is it
this one
it seems that the case is more like this
and like this
this will be where you get a single voxel if you get an effect
hey you wouldn't see an effect and the effect is more like this than like
well i mean there's a thresholding thing here so you can threshold this at different
levels with different levels of degrees of conservative party
and if few threshold this with the kind of law degree of sense selectivity sensitive
conservative party features each is a lot of pressure higher threshold then you you you
see more visual information i can show you in a second i can show you
another slide where you see how this builds up doesn't mean that there is no
information what it shows is particularly hard a large amount of information whenever any neuroscience
techniques to use
has a problem with negative findings based don't find anything doesn't mean there's something in
the brain area where somebody could be in small cells it could be in some
aspect the firing that you have investigated and so we always have this problem is
not finding
well that's what this do this what this does
and the object is immediately free because there are people using the output
is there wait until point some future time we know that
everybody you point must stop
and at that point you thrown objects
so you may use a lot of extra memory one
well in terms of both the days she would take over
but you avoid avoided locking
this is the things i ever written order
and there is nothing of importance in this direction
can talk about this
a little bit already
look at any modern device driver and look at where the existing few drivers model
the going we're trying to fix
the current model is trying reach devices
actually enumerates the bus
so the PCI the figures what PCI devices exist
devices are not so much functions table so you look at PCI device drug use
PCI vendor identify society
that is
so usually supposed to be always not quite
that allows the
thank say well i should try to destroy
and their exported user space modularity can also look through modules
this PCA device idea i should this module figure with which kernel drivers
when you know the driver
everything existing that is called kernel function or
similarly when you are
when you remove hardware is removed that whole thing
to clean up the article like
if you remove the driver rather special routines
we fight the remove recall remove three
o devices saying this is going to play this correlated
so there is no special cases like know
we see that everything on your system is essentially dynamic
how management is an ongoing one
it turns and you want the case not so long ago the next management with
windows XP and certainly with this
was also
we were
way way behind in terms of
the collapse of life
very few particular et al do some work on it and somebody is really really
sitting in the tree
but it's not just about getting hardware not just the kernel space
you don't stop the process
one process have multiple power states
and there are different kind of idle state CPU
but it takes time
and energy move even if inactive i believe that the longer you can stay i'd
and this is taken to the extreme things mobile many which was the only thirty
seconds of time
the CV essentially to know
because pretty good so you can figure out the power level we should be you
are said to have management governance
to determine how we should move between power
actually gets dried powder in too
should we try to figure out what i was getting work done
there are some difficult questions that have managed to gain
because if you're in the middle of the quite scales
whatever the latest preferred mass
that was the case
and your machine size of we doing okay we just turn CPU speed and it
can be quite nice not you actually the circus
so you set strategy on
but most of what determines
four is how often you wake up person
now we can fix some of the car race cars like that's all for the
most of the necessary way users
i think i application field customers flash animator
programs like the temporal point some of the clock applications on the desktop
used to wake up about fifty times a second to with pocket change
but maybe the second
something like that more practical
o if you turn the second of one minute is what it does now
and i alert you when you start looking for the you can start to reduce
the power to heal she material
and there is a project few what
that's all
which has some tools things out of which we have to tell you
what what is causing wake yuichi
which software needs fixing
only now ahead windows have management we weakened
because we are in this situation we could fix all these space applications
that is to be going in all sorts of people
because systematically working on this
in the microsoft case all i can do share the people who produced the right
pieces by itself we don't care
they like you are causing problem
with another reason you are
again this is this is what problem
if you have the power to you want to turn things off
the all model we have
similar symbol
really designed for embedded systems is that which is like the things off
the problem is you've got all the good for example to this control
so PCI slot for this controlled so there's an order
this for example
plus this cash to this
ten of the farm
based on the controller son of trouble this universe
and turn it back on again in reverse order
so we we using the bus device hierarchies we got to myself to try and
do this
still one needed in this area things that some of the spens stuff spend this
particularly spend around still like you
this work being done there
fully interesting things
because the mainframe to mobile phones even some of the same requirements
the last time you wait things are
that's about three years ago
of blog posts which i will have been
between the model which resisted and data
that's quite high overlap as compared to
other categories which are french and in that
not infringe like this can be presented difference between
influential and active bloggers because if you look at this two and s three
you can see there is high chance for influential bloggers to be on big
as compared to
non inferential barack obama
but different provide the distribution of
the blog posts and they
on the left and
and that happened the blog on the right
very are compared the different parameters that we had in the market
so in this chart of maybe did this chart was we
compare the top twenty blog posts from our model and the twenty from the biggest
spectrum of the categories they belong to
in this case for the last six months we have been engineered five different configuration
similar to the previous case where you have no links no comments not things no
blog post
and all the parameters that
as you can see four
o for all the parameters that have the highest overlap
so even if you remove any single better the or decreases distributed
so this suggests that although
important but not equally important so you can figure out
elements order of these parameters based on the overlap and based on the country different
which is shown in the world
which is you
i have links as the most important parameter
and then comment which is the kind of
discussion denoted by different by this blog post and then of things which is nobody
and the local slant which is
and the block was which is somebody so basically you can also improve this morning
by using
different quality statistics may go
so the analysis of these block fixed rather than just having the numbers of block
because you can also have spam blog which
so putting the things for some reason we don't mean anything
there are we there is some room for improvement in this morning
so the
this is again something called papers
which we
so these are the list of references
and find
so let's look at the
i mentioned before this is sort of the a framework which we use for
finding the familiar strangers
so given about
generally though
clusters and then
we try to find
similar markers for this guy
using the cavity nesters and the wisdom collective wisdom
it was there was basically share knowledge which is right by individuals and groups together
and they can use can be used to solve problems
this is derivatives group is the most quintelligence
we this for blacklisting because there's a lot of users in it content
on log and this is probably prominent feature of social so several users tag and
categories their blogs so
use their in their submitted information as
OK activist
so why do we use the obviously there are some other traditional approaches but the
problems with these keywords clustering produces high dimensionality sparsity
and they require the number of clusters a private and then similarity measure
so we can study on
block taxonomy which is is not catalogues we downloaded from blogcatalog
so this is an amazing this way you have look these on the top and
you have the popular tags then you have some recent blog posts
snippets of his and blog posts and each of these blog posts have their own
tag which is about that
as you can see in this you have the categories we use these categories to
generate category deletion graph
as indicated here
this graph this is an instance of this graph is basically generator based on the
number of users which can different categories so if a blogger blogs in category c
one and c two we weakening these together
and the numbers on the edge indicates the strength of these connections with the blogosphere
that computers and blogging related
so we consider them as
one graph
so based on these are user submitted categories
we generate the generated this kind of
getting relationship graph
the categories they follow were taxonomy like this one it's not comprehensive taxonomy but you
can go to block catalog site and you can look at the taxonomy
not not very big but it's quite comprehensive
so we constructed sets based on different versions of
these taxonomy like this to
first level of the whole taxonomy are we split some nodes based on the pattern
based on the frequency of blogs in those categories
so that the collected data is
like we have for RC bloggers and then we grant their social network in the
first fashion
so another obvious question is
these forty bloggers sufficiently enough to
comment on the
so we did some analysis by
decreasing increasing in the number of the blogs so we did for starting from one
to six months and as you can see in the graph
as you had four five and six bloggers the
the amount of data collected and that so
that gives an indication that
even if you start collecting
data for one more number of bloggers you're not
it had do this is by a large amount so you can have
are they
less included dataset
so we started the study for four numbers
the different editions which is stalking or was the top level in the taxonomy on
all categories in the taxonomy of minutes split just one node which is the portion
or based on
the skew distribution which is this chart which is basically every blogger is using personal
as the category so
a lot of bloggers that's going into personal because you know they don't know what
the categories are definitely which was
but there are several sub-categories and the person so we split first two different sub-categories
and then
we do experiments
so far these these three different on dataset questions we'd and experiment
and then we come
after generating the
getting relationship graph we use different clustering algorithms like
k means and had to compare
a singer that performs better
so i've become benefit of baseline approach which is the x based clustering so we
get the
it's a pleasure the pleasure for me to introduce
cristina conati this morning
christine is associate professor
of computer science at the university of british columbia since two thousand five
her research goal
is two
integrate research in the official intelligence
human computer interaction and cognitive science
two may complex complex interactive systems increasingly more effective and about to the user means
harris interest including adaptive interfaces user modelling affective computing and intelligent tutoring systems
christine is the
outstanding c which she received a lower here
computer science minor can lower than at the university of milan italy in nineteen eighty
eight and then masters and ph d
intelligent systems at the university of pittsburgh
she has rich experience of research in companies research institutions universities
in italy and in the united states before joined the university of british columbia as
assistant professor in nineteen ninety nine
over the years cristina conati has received many awards and recognition for the quality of
research shows served as program committee and reviewer
four major a i in human computer interaction conferences tournaments she was program co-chair of
use of the user modeling confidence in
and also have seven
she's conference co-chair of i u
i this year international conference on intelligent user interfaces
over forty articles for a server said that paper she wrote a were awarded the
best paper award outstanding paper award
but is there
o taking more time out of representation
talking more of her research and achievements i prefer for it to pass
christina and let her percent radius in use on the new challenges in the elections
of intelligent tutoring systems thank you christina for your personal testing
graz jena for the kind introduction and things
o to the conference organisers for giving me the a chance to be here and
talk about intelligent tutoring systems to this very nice audience
so i want to start my presentation by
mentioning a seminal study that educational psychologist benjamin bloom conducted in nineteen eighty four
the effectiveness of the learning effectiveness of students that we're tutor
in a one-to-one fashion by humans instructors against
the learning gains tutors they received instruction in a regular classroom settings on the same
and the results that found was that the average student achievement in the one to
one tutoring condition was better than ninety percent of the achievements reached by students to
turn in the cluster this result is well known as a two sigma effect and
what is surprising is not so much the fact step
one to one tutoring turned out to be better than classroom instruction but it's actually
the minds of defect to respond so
this would say well then it's great we found that there was a great way
to make people learn by giving them individual tutors but of course we all understand
that having private tutors what instructors than can provide each of us one-to-one instruction is
definitely not sustainable solution
one option is to actually try to have the computers
provide some contribution towards this this final goal
and that's what intelligent to do research on intelligent tutoring systems try to do that
in today's system is
interdisciplinary field that combines integrates research in artificial intelligence human computer interaction cognitive science and
education with the goal of
creating computer-based tools that can better adapt to individual learners provides the benefits of one-to-one
instruction by
autonomously and intelligently adapting to the interaction to the specific needs of individual learners
so what i want to do in this talk is to provide some background and
basic definitions related to the field of intelligent tutoring systems
then i will describe some achievements of these fields up to now
and some new research directions and i will illustrate some of this new research directions
describing sampled rodgers' from our love
so let's start with a little bit of background as intelligent tutoring systems are not
the first attempt to provide computer supported aid to instruction
the precautions of intelligent tutoring systems are known as high system work i stands for
computer assisted instruction
and you can view this field as intelligent tutoring systems without the i components
what OK system does basically i'm going to try to illustrate how the were just
to give you an example of what is the cycle that cases to go through
system usually has the educational technologists defines
a curriculum as sequences of topics and exercises that the system that student should go
the case system just reads the specification
takes the current problem there should be presented presented to the student
the system also known as the designer has to specify all the correct answers for
exercises that
are given to the student so the system
get student answer
compares it with the known solution that is provided
and then
what is specified in the program is also what kind of feedback should be provided
for every possible combination of student answers and comparisons with the non status of computer
solutions and this feedback there is presented usually if the student answers correct usually the
student is advanced through the curriculum if it's incorrect there is some remediation given and
then again perhaps different that is specified for the student t
as you can understand the problem with these systems is that all the branching in
the programme for how the interaction should develop needs to be suppressed prespecified by educational
technology basically occasional technology needs to specify all the sequence table topics and exercises all
the relevant student answers that this is the system should be able to recognise and
all the possible to tory feedback actions that the system should take in response to
the solution process the system cannot understand can monitor the two dissolution process can only
understand the final answer and another issue is that usually the system doesn't know
i cannot tell why student is generating certain answers specifically for instance why is doing
is making mistakes
so this kind of approach
can be fine if one wants to provide
opportunities for students to do in practice activities on simple domains to chester instance of
basic math operations traction addition division
but it really doesn't scale becomes quite manageable if one wants to provide
i'd like to thank you
you evaluations they were very useful to me
i already send email to
about fifty students
and at some interesting exchanges with some of you
many of you are very happy
with their education structure that's great
many are moderately happy
maybe that's OK
but there are quite a few are very unhappy with the recitation
if you are very unhappy with your recitation structure you are complete idiots if you
stay in that investigation
we have thirteen
recitation instructors and i can assure you
it will be very easy to find one
that agrees with you
you can come and see me
if that helps
some are better than others that's the way it goes in life
some students
i would like to see more cut and dry problem solving in my lectures
i think that's really the domain of recitations lectures
and recitations are complementary
i prefer to go over the concepts
and i always give numerical examples to support the concept in way
that's problem solving
and i show demonstrations to further
the concept because seeing obviously is believing
i tried to make you see through
the dumb equations and admittedly
my methods i sometimes somewhat different
from what you're used to hearing MIT
i try to inspire you
and at times
i try to make you wonder
and think
and i want to keep it that way i believe that
hard probably problems problem solving is really the domain
of the recitations
many of you found
the exam
too easy
and many of you found in example too hard
some complained it was too hard because it was too easy
quite ironic isn't it
they say we want more mass
we want more standard problems
one more math i'm teaching physics
i test you
physics i don't consume activities
if you digest the homework
and that's very important you make the homework part of your culture
to study the solution
the solutions that we put on the web today four fifteen
solution to know before we go on the web
believe me they are truly excellent solutions not cut-and-dried to give you a lot of
if you digest those solutions
then the concepts will sink in
and now
two fifteen minutes
if you really want
which are complicated math
clearly not
i could try that next exam
but then i may have to buy myself
a bullet proof vest
to be safe
is what matters
well i gave my exam review here i highlighted the concept of these little problem
that i decided he was extremely simple
they were not so simple
but from that point of view
clearly i cannot cover all the subject in the fifty minute exams i have to
make a choice
so your preferred
topic may not be there
some of you think that the pace of this course is too slow
some of you think it's too fast
the score of the average score was three point eight
four point zero would have been ideal twenty one we could do
i can accommodate
all of you those who think it's too slow
and those who think it's too fast
three point eight is close enough to ideal for me
four point zero
and so
i have to leave it the way it is besides that
keep in mind
you are now at MIT you no longer in high school
now the good news
there were quite a few students who said the homework is too long
not a single person said
it was too short
i can fix that
i will reduce all future assignments by about twenty five percent effective tomorrow
i have already taken off assignment number five
two problems you down out to seven
and i will do that all assignments
that are coming
my pleasure
i'm going to cover was you something
that conceptually is the most difficult of all
of eight o two
and you will need time to digest
and if you think
what you're going to see is crazy
you're not alone
the only good news is
that conceptually
it's not going to
become more difficult
remember the earth's that in eighteen nineteen
discovered that a steady current
produces a steady magnetic field
and that connected electricity
with magnetism
a little later faraday therefore suggested
that maybe
a steady magnetic field
produces a steady current
he did many experiments to show that
now not to be so
and one way to try that
this is followed
he had here
battery which is which
and here
we had solenoid
closing the switch
the current will flow
and that creates
a magnetic field
in the solenoid and the magnetic fields
maybe it runs like so
on the right
and we do not true reflection
you can do that by reflecting the light of water
or the last
or plastic
or paint
metal bands light metals
you will not able
you will see later
that's indeed the case
so here
is a plate
and i have some lights
fall into place making nice people light
so might
we use these light guns for that
and so some
also want
nine people right
coming in
from some lamp here
used as a reference line a line which is
perpendicular to the surface
but they can use that for ninety degrees angle
this line is a reference
ninety degrees
it is
and we call this angle
in physics
so you may get
angle of incidence
if this is class
of all the last with exactly the same way
garden-variety class that you have only your windows
and if this angle is fifty five degrees
and the light is reflected
a hundred percent
not all why that is
but is hundred percent
this angle he was saying was that i was always the case
when light strikes
bounces off
just like a billion people
bounces off the edge of the data
we would say that the angle of incidence
it's the same as the angle of refraction
this angle is the angle of reflection and some of the light goes into the
in fact most goes into the glass
that is not
four this is really only the light and reflection
that is
on the percent
if you want to look into this light
so here is your i
you see the light coming to you
the light coming to me
all these unpolarized light coming to
like there might be some like like that
and the ensemble is on
if i look here
it might be
after this reflected comes up to me
now on the percent for rice this direction
i will demonstrate that
and the angle of fifty five degrees depends on a little bit of what kind
of glass to use
the difference
the larger to the smaller
if this is the water surface
englewood b fifty two degrees
which is not so different from fifty five to
i have here
they don't like
those of you
and we'll see if you're
and i can rotate that
i wrote like this
and here have light
so light strike onto this
piece of glass
i don't know about that
that's not going rise
so i will go in this direction
that is the likely to reflect it
you see it on the centre street
and i can change that
i can make the angle close to fifty five degrees
in which case
the reflected light will be
practically hundred percent polarized but i can make the angle
smaller than fifty five degrees lot more
and when i do that
we have a situation
that the light is partially all polarized
all right
what that means is
that always comes out like this
a lot
but there maybe also some like this
and some like that
but if the dominant amount is in one direction we call that partially problem
if everything is in one direction
we call it a hundred percent
and that fifty five degree angle
it is very closely two hundred percent
the angle is not exactly fifty five degrees
so we're going to have this like
the first on
the light so they know doing
so when you see it shortly
make making completely dark
by the way you think of course that was you linear polarized
we will be able to see
the light that hits you is on the percent for the answer is you can't
the reason for that is that as it comes off
these spores
but when it
bounces from this screen back to you it politician so you cannot see
but that's why i have here a linear polarizer which encode all into be
so we're going to turn all the lights of make a star
and let's see what we can there is the light
the reflected light
and there you see
the light to go straight through all
i'm not interested
most of the allied activities goes straight through
only a small fraction
is really like
this is the light
that's reflected i can see it now
look into the reflected
so the angle is now not optimum i put the angle there somewhere at random
and i will show you the diff i hold this
a large sheet of all
into be
and if i rotate around
and this is what every rule uses right remember also in our mamdani controller one
regulation of the input variables for temperatures was actually that was car power small medium
and high each of the rules is the same as membership functions to to abandon
that five minutes each rule is free to choose its own membership functions allows us
to better model local properties and the reason for that is just saying if
down here
i have a lot of that are very very different
but actually you
this is a large area this is all
i don't know high output
and and you have no
no it doesn't make sense for the rules that describe it makes sense for the
rules that describe this this this effects down here to very fine renovation on on
that the x right but for the stuff up here it doesn't make sense for
me to have an equally fine international of x is you can just use one
large fuzzy set describing all this stuff you don't want to use a couple
that's the idea behind free fuzzy rules
and they also not going to use all attributes for rules in mendel automatically since
you have this global grid you're going to use all of the attributes for every
one of world's not going to do that are the reasons why do that obvious
it's an interesting and that's why i think it's worth this day
that's essentially what you're doing business the just go through that briefly i think at
the time it's also in the book if you can miss desire that would essentially
doing it's exactly our that goes through
all the training examples that you have and tries to introduce create new rules when
you actually need them
and similar to the higgins goodman our in the tries to look for the maximum
error then introduces new will there and just the rules and then it sees conflicts
so we'll start off in interface very then we don't have a rule that explains
the training pattern independent of training data just introduce a very general rule that just
says if true
then class k whatever this pattern belongs to right
this is what happens here if fall training examples of the do that's the main
if we already have a correct rule of class c that's what this pattern belongs
to classify right trying to build classify if you already have a rule that we
simply say well this was already correctly explaining our pattern happy so we increase the
main we just count how many pregnancies of the explain and just the core region
of the world so if you look
on these rules
i want to
if you sort of have a bird's eye view on these rules you can always
imagine what is having the core region
the building rectangular what's this is the relation to the rule fulfilment is
we are equal to one right and then you sort of have and the support
region around it
you just essentially looking bird's eye on top of an apparent pyramid with the chopped
to this is where the degree of membership gradually declines and here is
it on this area and we are just right
so this is the area where we have a degree of fulfilment above zero and
this is the area where the degree of filaments of one so much
but i mean what if a correct rule of class c exists that means the
pattern x lies somewhere in the support region correctly covered and now
in case it's not already in the core let's assume pattern x lies somewhere here
we'll just to adjust this core region a little bit
just it so that it also covers this pattern
the parents next that's all that's x announced and that's the case i mentioned before
if you do not have a correct rule get
or there's no rule around that covers this pattern the nice inside the support region
but just insert a new one which is the point so there's just one point
scorers the point x
and the support is in fact it's covering the entire just say OK this covers
everything you of course is nonsensical rule but it will be fixed in step three
which reduces the support of all rules of conflicting class the cover x so we
actually have will
terms of the VC dimension which is what people often state these kinds of bonds
and but we might as well stick with the only upon if you prefer but
people have evaluated VC dimensions for a number of learning machines
make sure myself and certainly go of people have been evaluated VC dimension them in
front of learning machines the neural networks and things like that
so it sometimes convenient to have the bound in this form
so let's wrap or wait for a second and think about what we have done
so far
so we started thinking about this principle of empirical risk minimization saying in machine learning
we would like to minimize the actual risk
the expected error on future test examples
examples that are drawn from the same underlying regularity as the training data we've seen
so we would like to minimize this quantity that we noticed we can't even compute
this quantity we need some kind of induction principle two
something that's close to minimizer of that quantity
the simplest possible induction principle was empirical risk minimization which said
after we have the training data so let's just minimize the error on the training
data and hope this this will lead us to a small error on the test
so then we analyse this empirical risk minimization conducted principle
it turned out that
this will only work if we have a certain type of uniform convergence
on the function class can be implemented by the learning machines
so think of the learning machine as a function class plus the way of picking
a function from that class
given the data
so we noticed
we can only do this if we have a certain
bound on the size of the function classes
we have a uniform convergence of
that will depend on how large clauses so we need to somehow measure the size
of the function class and it turns out that the way to measure the size
of the class in this in terms of capacity concepts seen several such things like
shattering coefficients grow functions
and these are mentioned and then we plug in the VC dimension and we get
on that tells us something about the consistency of empirical risk minimisation tells us that
we do in paris minimisation and we have a function class with bounded capacity then
we can guarantee that with high probability also test error will be not much larger
than the training
but now that we have this we could actually say well
why don't we actually directly try to minimize the right hand side of this rather
than only my minimizing this quantity and evaluating this quantity
and that's something that but in the intervening and i have of course also proposed
once they had these results and this is a roughly roughly speaking but i just
fix this quite useful structural risk minimisation
so most of the time people don't actually evaluate these bounds two
predict how well the learning machines will do so that's a little caveat for practice
because typically these bonds are quite loose
nevertheless sometimes the behavioral of response
as a function of the parameters that you're looking at it will be indicative of
what's going on in the learning procedure and sometimes you can use such powers as
modulation to design learning algorithms the balance can tell you
what kind of quantities to minimize in addition to the training error
in order to control the generalisation ability of your learning machine
so a b one more thing
might be useful because i remember a couple of years ago there was this big
discussion on
so maybe this about what kind of statement learning theory makes
some people were misinterpreting
statements saying that they guarantee that whatever the problem is that we are given we
can generalize
so in the way these sponsored they tell me tell us that whatever the problem
is that we are given
if we use the learning machine of small capacity we can generalize in the sense
that the training error and test error will not be two different from each other
however this doesn't mean that we can learn any problem so for instance if you
tried to learn the mapping from a name in the telephone directory to the telephone
number you try to predict someone's telephone number from the name which is probably very
hard task
then you would find that either you
i have to use learning machine
which has a very high capacity
so if you say you can take telephone directory you will need to very high
capacity to memorize all these telephone numbers in your learning machine in this case is
reconciled be very large bond will not
tell you anything non-trivial or use learning machine with a small capacity but then you
will find that you won't be able to achieve a small empirical research on this
problem so in this case this term here will be large so you won't be
able to cheat this would respond whenever tell you that you will be able to
learn such a problem in the sense that you will have a small test error
it only tells you that you can learn the proper in the sense that test
and training are are not too different from each other these statements are relative to
the training error
and it's also a big difference between these statements and a lot of things like
minimax results that have been done in statistics
they don't have is relative to the training and i think that's one of the
things of learning theory that these statements have this form
so now i told you that
it's important for machine learning to find a good function class is you need function
which has a small capacity
the brightest part of the car is the reflection of a window which normally you'd
expect to get dockery of the can
so anything that says OK when does the doc is going to fail and that
kind of thing
and then
if x to deal with scale
so it is natural images kind of forests and things that people sometimes partially cleared
one another
this is the person here
the people change in scale and if you move this person here down to here
know things things are really coherent
but you still sets the person of the person to take to protect find person
but it's not coherent with the same
so you could easily find false alarm like that
and in the same the famous scene from cyc physics and how many people have
managed to understand what's missing it
put your hand up here
i see from your singapore
but it normally takes people
you know the seconds also to figure out the first time they see exactly what
and as far as recognizing that kind of thing
we can can can do
is everyone now knows that this is the dog
OK just
if you choose the wrong scale things
you can get very wrong answers
so now interesting properties of human vision
and the reason for talking about these just
to kind of give the feeling for the
kinds of things human vision does
maybe is hence to the kinds of things we might want to do with it
when extracting features from images
human vision
it's very very large research field in its own right
it's very complex it's very difficult to get clear
results up from many things
i would say that really at the moment only the first few stages of visual
processing really well understood
and even then know well-understood was disqualified
but nevertheless there are some valuable less lessons there
there's a couple of points which seem very critical first of all almost all the
you get when you get into your brain the coded differentially so they contrast with
respect to something else so if you're doing intensity decoding its local contrast
using some kind of spatial
the fringe difference in type filters all spatiotemporal filters because also motion is called differentially
so there's this various types of the center surround baffles installed filters velocity filters
is code in an opponent way
so that means that instead of just having red green and blue
pixels or what you might have in your
brain having some kind of the difference signal
which allows you to colour constancy so this room in sunlight
you wouldn't have the difficulty of telling the difference between this room and sunlight in
this room and fluorescent lighting
but if you work on absolute colour you would have difficulty because the lighting is
different colour temperature and things like that different surfaces have slightly different colours so you
can you can be mistaken and if you're trying to do things like take skin
and images
which scanners around characteristic distribution intensity of colour
but it varies a lot with the lighting so you need to correct for that
so colour coding
and then
at all
both spatially so within the image
and also temporarily over time
this accommodation processes the run kind of building differences in contrast to make you used
to stuff that you see that you didn't really want to see so we can
focus on stuff that's new and this was just happening right now OK so we'll
see a few examples of that in the next slides
basically everywhere
the responses to compressive so
if you signal coming in
typically the signal has very large dynamic range may have extreme peaks like specularities very
the first step in the period
this is simply that people
the incoming messages just below
so this one
this it simply multiply the
you can show
exact marginals
and this is this is
message passing which
OK computer matching
the influence of tree structured graphs
this a similar system in
this trick is not to work because it's was complicated models
so just as humans quickly
so if it doesn't
the key
solutions just go interesting
for the last few days what this is is just
the distribution of taxes and disease
these axes of disease
you know you know this is and is is exactly this graph
this is
if you look wikipedia
this things is
this and i will
because of the sum of the two
this is exactly a special case of talking about the centre of so this
this is going to
this is just
that cannot be efficiently computed the of the solutions
shows what is to be what happened me
i mean you can compute that
that's quite small
using featuring so you know if it is essentially to all of this
the second thing and this is known as the kalman filter
so he discovered several times in the past
so as with many extensions and so this is the basic
in the sixties and seventies competition for the nineteen eighties
instances of this
as an example of a problem with this expensive school history and a problem
so differences and this and you can look at this
so this was in nineteen seventy two
see these
have to understand this structure these things it's
this seems to functions question
the message
so so if if it's not as if you like this fact
next step is the next step use
these messages
of course i those once
and i want to the set of nodes so that
my left child is labeled by a
my right is also labeled by a
because this is the first iteration of
if you don't like this
you can write it
zero one
you must be labelled by a you must also have
both child labor a
and so on which means that your level by a human have both shown labelled
and the child the children must also have children both children labelled by and so
on so is basically
set of nodes where
whichever path
you start from
the path is
labelled by a all along
so this is exactly this form which says
four but i can be considered
this that is globally living by a
so you already have good patterns in the calculus
and now we're going to mix
and this is a bit mean more difficult to understand what
what they say is that
remember that with this new y
i could manage to say that
i have fourth and pb share
it's the title so
during the way
mu gives you find computations was something that all must hold eventually
but on the computation
and you
gives you let's infinite computations was something
is something environment
if you have this feeling
i'm not so good performance here but
here with the new hudson
g like
globally something
and we knew have f
eventually some that's that's the idea
so here
if you remember that
there exists a path
something happened of infinity of fun
do not try to you find in here
nineteen ninety and it's very simple to write infinitely often
you say that
you always eventually i mean you always eventually he be
that's the additive formula
so wherever i go
in the future when he'd be
what am
that's been now or in the future i go to the future it might be
and i make one one more step one again i will eventually which beat so
this is infinite graph
so this is
the standard notations of these ones
and i can tell you there exist a path
well he's he's
in favour of
so in the mu calculus that is to say that they have something which is
globally true
and this thing is the property which is
some eventuality
so the idea is that will kind of nests of greatest
and at least fixpoint because it's a combination of the two things have explained before
so what is the combination of k
i write my pattern
which says OK
you have to have two so if i say
there exists something which is globally true
let's call it
and c would be
something like this
what fossil again how qubits that
that means that this doing this way so here
if you want to say that there exists something which is only true
so this something
it's very difficult to explain this one just on the basis of the two previous
ones explain but let's try so
the idea is that
and i'm tracking this laser and i'm trapping and this will get you down to
kelvin bit lower so
and of course what i mean by lowering the temperature is
you know i slowed down
the temperature of the gas is related to
how best to the moving
by slow it down on cooling the air
here is the first step
and getting the atoms to condense the first step in cooling the down
then there are many others
and actually
people design and one of the individuals who
accomplished that feat is right here in the physics department one of my colleagues wolfgang
can generally many of you you will get to meet wolfgang header picked you might
even be teaching the section they don't want
recitation OK alright great maybe i'll tell you more about it if you haven't already
all right so
both the home and some
so now what we saying
what we're saying is that radiation exhibits both
the wavelike behavior and the particle like behaviour
and just in general
where the radiation produces the change in matter like the photoelectric effect that the change
in manner right the electron gets ripped off of the material
experiments in which the change
in the matter is affected
in that case usually the radiation exhibit particle like behaviour
experiments in which the radiation interaction results in a change in the spatial distribution of
the radiation
well in that case then radiation exhibit it wavelike behaviour
and so
you know not
really a proper question appropriate questions
it ask whether light
the particle
or is it away
the appropriate question is is it ask whether light behaves like a particle or behaves
like a wave
depending on the particular experimental conditions
this kind of wave particle duality with the ability of it to behave like a
wave or a particle is not a contradiction
it's just the fundamental nature of life
it might seem like a contradiction to you
because you're everyday experiences
doesn't allow u
we that both properties can be you're everyday experiences of the particle
were it away
but this is a part of the
the nature of our world that you don't have any experience with every single day
so it seems strange but it is the way
white work
like someone asked me what is the more of the full
and when you ask a question that's fine but you have to realize what you
want for an answer is to draw an analogy
that photo is something that you can experience every day
the bottom line is you can draw the analogy correctly because
the photon is
that you can relate correctly two-year everyday experiences the different parts of nature is just
one that you don't see every day which seems strange
so you have to be
you have to be willing
two it's that kind of new rules new phenomena
there are just outside of your everyday experience
we're out there as you delve into nature
the more
these will be to the torah lectures on convex optimisation
most of the material in these lectures is developed together with stephen boyd stanford
this part of the book and then also as part of
slides from different courses at UCLA and also stephens courses at stanford
i'd like to start with
just some general introduction
to explain why convex optimisation convex so important in
i think everyone's familiar with the general mathematical optimisation problem of minimizing some non linear
function of n variables subject to
several nonlinear
inequality constraints
we call this a mathematical optimization problem or nonlinear optimization problem
it's extremely general
it's a general model of could be any design problem or decision problems
estimation problem
it's extremely general is almost universal
in applicability
theory in practice of course there are limits to what you can do with mathematical
and basically there are determined by the answers to these two questions
first is only mathematical model of some
actually optimisation problem so it's only useful if the mathematical model is sufficiently accurate
as also very important optimization is the accuracy of the data that describe the model
that are needed in the model
so because in practice often this
substantial uncertainty in the parameters that describe the model
and that's since we in this optimisation optimize
assuming certain parameters
any uncertainty in the problem can have comedians are very sensitive to
small changes in the data
and second of course this
it's one thing to write down the mathematical problem it's not to solve it so
the question is can we actually solve the problem by existing methods
and then that
leads to two
so the main activities and optimisation research
one is
people in optimisation goal modelling
and then we are trying to formulate a generic
before formulating optimisation problems and applications for example generic methods for dealing with uncertainty in
optimisation problems not just in machine learning also control or circuit design
and saying of course this research on algorithms that tries to expand
class of problems that can be handled
scale of the complexity of the problems that can be handled in practice
convexity is important because it's central concepts and sort of modeling and algorithms
so we see that roughly speaking
convex optimisation problems are
roughly speaking the optimisation problems that can be how efficiently that are tractable
and at the same time there was
quite general and it's class of problems sufficiently rich to to be useful in practice
so that's the reason why convex these
such an important topic
the as i mentioned the general optimisation problem unfortunately is intractable
we don't know algorithms for solving the general nonlinear optimization problem
and that's unfortunate but that's just the fact
and please you
for people who are new to this area
it's often too that even simple
optimisation problems
can be
very hard to solve
two examples of that are for example quadratic optimisation so we know that if a
quadratic optimisation problem with no constraints it's very easy to solve is that it is
equal to zero you get a set of linear equations that you can solve to
get cancer
as soon as you add constraints quadratic optimising quadratic constraints it becomes much harder
with one inequality constraints or one concept can still be
solved efficiently it's more involved but they can still
be solved efficiently but as soon as you have several
constraints it becomes very difficult to solve
another example is
polynomial optimisation so
if you are just interested in minimizing and
polynomial in one variable
we can just take the derivative
it is also polynomial
compute the roots of the derivative and find one that defines you
it as soon as we have more than several variables it becomes also very difficult
to minimize
so in general you have to visit the down on the problem is difficult to
solve the is one of well-known and famous exception that's the linear programming problem
it's a special case when the objective and all the constraints are linear
it was introduced by a
six or concept formulated and practical method for solving it in the nineteen forties that
the simplex method
and then of
that meant that so that i became widely known people started to use
linear programming for modeling
a different applications not just in operations research which would applications that dancing had in
mind initially but also many other applications that
go beyond the applications he
i intend to initially
in engineering finance and so on
so it's very easy problem to solve in in a theoretical sense there exist a
polynomial time methods for solving it
also in a practical sense
in the sense that it's easy to find good software for linear programming free and
good software for solving
linear optimization problems
there is also extensive theory that relates to
duality of
for linear programming
one important point is no closed form expression in general
but that's not really a problem because you can solve it efficiently in practice using
numerical methods
and so people with some edits have can be proved to have polynomial complexity
and in practice people also solve linear programs with
several hundred thousands or even millions of variables and constants
so the convex optimisation problem is more general so here we have a non linear
cost function on the constraints
but restrict the problem to
objective and constraint functions are convex that satisfies this
that's all seem more about in a few minutes
so this includes linear programming is a special case for the constraints are linear functions
are linear
and the properties are very similar to linear programming
so the idea are very similar complexity is similar
but it's also much more general than many more problems can be written in this
form then you programming
the history
a brief history so it all started linear programming in the nineteen forties
then in the nineteen fifties for a while the development followed in more less predictable
path so first extension of people considered as quadratic programming
and which
replace the linear objective with a quadratic function
and a quadratic programming keep the constraints linear
for each
one of the brain that we want to me
you know exactly
OK so
well what features
and recycle their you
she was one of
we're want to show the i wrote
with what
you get
you have a lot of
after that
see that
you know
so we have
we need to give some to model
one of the most important
and you
the will
what what what you really
you know what
what really
they are
one well i suppose
but you you
one of
i decided to place the monitoring stations of the target two target two customers in
social networks
and then i see the
targeting another person
then you get another person this now we do me lot of bad news
you can get private health no on the other hand if i wanted target more
people and i can see the targeting the same person
again will cover the same area but now
the marginal benefit that would get these is it that i would like to cover
the new people y here six OK
so here are a part of the same person help you
we have much less right
formerly this property goes under the name of similarity it's also known as diminishing returns
so you can think of it as some kind of community analogue of concavity and
basically all it says is that
the gain of adding an old
it was small set high edit large
and this is the part the destruction x y
and if you go back to the original question of how to find influential blogs
which blogs to read to be most up to date
the idea here is debated each blog covers part of the blogosphere right blog covers
a set of topics so
just to illustrate what i'm showing you here is
a set of blogs so each dot is a blog so and now i be
like sequentially making one log after another so we thought when i think the first
one this is the guy here i get basically detect
i that all the stories about the detective so my daughter
but then for example is the second log i think another block covered this part
of the blogosphere and then the third one which is here is that we are
with these other parties before we call very late and so on right so the
more i think each one covers a bit of space but the the benefits getting
smaller and smaller
OK and and the saw so for example if i decide to pick them blogs
and is like them blogs that i would advise you to read really know pretty
what is going on in the blogosphere
OK and now if go compare
i would like to and the war basically the fraction of the story catch without
much has some other heuristics
you can see the quite well so for example if we would decide
to select blogs at random we do poorly if we will decide by the number
of things which today is sort a standard measure of influence
he wouldn't be able to do very poorly while our thing which means you go
and optimize
that's quite well
and moreover i show you but we also have a way to make these
the the very scalable so if i show you the number of blogs we select
is the running time exhaustive search which finding an optimal solution explore very quickly
greedy scales quadratically but we have something to basically scales linearly with a very very
small nation
so in in
this this optimisation some very practical in
just because they showed before this question so here is a different question with the
same the same thing applies so now the the question the i have a city
water distribution network so now these houses in are physical fights between the
flow of the water flows so
the end what we have is the data on how for example some contamination started
his house how contaminations spread through the network OK
and the idea is to place sensors in these networks to save lives protect them
exist as possible so the idea is there is an epidemic starting here
then hits my sensitivity and a reason why is like a very realistic problems
there are many people cannot
and to make the whole story should
again we can use the same attractor
we developed as so
if if i plotted the performance of our algorithm was just like some heuristic is
that could producer for example saying i concentrate on high population areas i place my
sense randomly because you are quite well
and actually there some competition
i will be our approach called best and basically beat all these approaches
done by national labs the sort of experts in this while our
simple basically
did not meet
OK so now i i think the second one and they have some time so
i showed this article
everything is fine
OK the slide thirty nine
thirty nine
OK so last
so what i'm showing the last but is basically what are the benefits of working
with large and i show you three different so the first thing is that if
you like best hypothesis that this planetary scale so here i show some something something
really don't six degrees of separation
because you can there's is no one on the whole
i thing that show is something about the network community structure people assume that nodes
in the network group in group in this sort of by cohesive groups and i
show you how
what you can see start looking that large networks
and the last thing i'll show you something some indication of web search sort of
interesting how much leverage can you get from just looking at the structure of the
OK so
first the one thing
so the question here is or
probably all know this it's like
you know this is numbers so it can be good experiment for game and so
on and so the idea is we have small world experiment from the ground sixty
seven where he gave people
in nebraska letters send people in boston and the idea was you can only for
about your let the let to your friend and i hope that eventually he spoke
broken must
and the question is how many steps does it right so i have the social
network of the united states
this is nebraska in the master
you can get you can assume you can assume that people look for is that
this train two to reach the target in some number of steps and then with
be another person in nebraska who sent the letter some other way to
what milgram experiment did he created this sparking his papers
sixty four such letters can into the end
he kept the average which was six point two and does this is now known
as six degrees of separation like an average find
and any american inside six
so we can do the same thing on a much much larger scale we can
microsoft instant messenger social network
that has two hundred forty million people all over the world and two hundred fifty
five billion exchanged messages in one and it's like that by today
composer network out of this and they can
create sort of the same experience so now if i'm showing i'm i'm looking something
similar to this is the distance the number of short number of that sort of
probability of that this two people who get haart certainly does
and the observation that you can make use for that
it's a lot here so
but newton
i thought that the colours were pre-existing in the prism just
separates them
and this was his crucial experiment to decide between those two theories
you see what he did
he drilled a hole through the board
and let through only the red light
and put the second prism there
and he wrote here three times he wrote it here
and also here and also here
next bari at looks from the core which means
the broken light
does not change its color
so this proved to new
at least that time
the light is the substance not a train of pulses
what do you think that proof now
the the light is a substance or trade policies but at least you can see
that in terms that that was a crucial experiment really important experiment that's the kind
of experiments will try to talk about in the course
experiments are indispensable in organic chemistry it's an empirical science based on observation and that's
why you have to take the land
but so is logic
that was number three and number four the ways knowing logic is important too
so i believe what i tell you here
only when it makes sense to you
don't just cram
make sure it makes sense
what if it doesn't
now here's how to succeed in killing one twenty five and will take as our
model science student samuel peeps
how many people have heard of samuel peeps
if you're going to a scientist
what did you hear that
but the association with and be
right in this period right in the heart of the
science growth but what you know in four was his diary
which tells all about
everyday life in restoration
he was actually is the sixteen year-old present when charles the first was beheaded sixteen
forty nine
now what's the connection
you know where this is
so anybody been there
the world often whaley avenues
those are named from four three
of the fifty judges
the condemned charles the first to be beheaded
and they were the only ones that lasted very long after the restoration
and they last because they fled to new england
and were hidden on west rock all these roads are heading west toward west restaurant
OK so that's the time to the same period but he got his phd in
cambridge and sixteen fifty four and a masters in sixteen fifty six and he got
a good job he became clerk of the acts for the navy board which meant
he was the guy guided purchased everything for the royal navy
all the rope all the tar all the lumber and so on
and on july four sixteen sixty two minutes the fourth of july but it's more
than one hundred years before they became relevant
he writes in his diary by by comes mister cooper made of the royal charles
of whom i intend to learn mathematics and do begin with him today
he being a very able man
after an hour's being with him in arithmetic my first attempting to learn the multiplication
we then parted till tomorrow so here's a guy doing all the purchasing for the
royal navy and he didn't know multiplex multiplication
let alone vision
but he worked hard at july nine five days later
he's up by four o'clock in that my multiplication table hard which is all the
trouble i meet with all in arithmetic can do the other things pretty well
a july eleven up by four o'clock in hard my multiplication table which i have
now almost master of
christmas right so six months later
so to my office practising arithmetic alone
and making it end of last night's book with great content eleven at night and
so on the suffering bed
or a year later
also use motivated
he was diligent
that's good
a year later on a sunday i below by myself looking over my arithmetic books
and temporal so my wife arose and on and she and i all the afternoon
and she has come to do addition subtraction and multiplication very well
and so i purpose not to trouble are yet with the vision
right so we worked with the study part
and that's crucial
and isaac newton
does they recognise this book
right the mathematical principles of science natural philosophy
but there's an interesting thing on the title page
samuel peeps
is the one who gave permission to publish the book because he was the president
of the royal society
now six years later peeps encounter problems with dice
the reason was he went to coffee shops every night for dinner
and the gamble
right people propose various kinds of bats and he couldn't figure out this one so
he wrote newton for help
so this was the problem that he wrote new in the twenty second of november
so a has six dice in a box
and he has to throw is sixty five
ron right b has twelve dies and he has the following two sixes
and c has eighteen dies but he has to get three sixes to win
the question is whether b and c have not is easier task it and even
like that is if the dice are loaded or anything
who has the better bet
how many people think
that is the same
don't be shy
how many think it's a
how anything b
that's the
resonance frequency which we call omega zero is not exactly the frequency
the response of the object
is a maximum very rarely ever will that become an issue
i want to show you now a
transparency from your own book don't take notes
this is from french
you see here
the function
a but it is divided by a zero which is that have zero divided by
so that's the amplitude
four zero frequency
so when you start off it's one
the ratio is one by definition right because it's a omega divided by those is
zero and horizontally psi omega divided by omega zero
so by definition
right here at the one sign
is that point that i put omega zero there
you seem
various curves
four different values of q
and the one that i made green
q equals ten
and no surprise
that the height
is at most n
because we predicted that it is a few times higher
then the amplitude when we have low frequency you see indeed
that the red one
very close to ten
if you look
at the one that has a mark q equals three which is this one
if you look very carefully you may see
that the maximum
eight shifted slightly below
the value
which is omega
only guys because you're but
even for q recall three
the difference is insignificantly small
and then at the bottom you see
the delta function the face the domain
object follows the driver at very low frequency
delta is zero
resonance is precisely by over two ninety degrees very hard to imagine that we'll try
to show it to you
and at very high frequencies they go
like this
they are a hundred eighty degrees
out of phase
so now comes the question how do you
apply force
a system
it's nice to say that is the force but you have to think of a
that you can actually
i do that
and i'll just this because one case was you
and then i will try to demonstrate it also
if i have a pendulum
and i want a force on this object
then i can do that as you will see
in our work
by starting to move my hand here
you will see how that translates into a force on this object
i move my hand i allowed the drive
my displacement now
this in inches
not to force that is in inches
is the pendulum
the length l
mass and this is the equilibrium position of my hand here is the object
but i'm going to move my hand
anyway at
he calls at a zero
times cosine only t
that is the frequency that i decided i imposed that frequency on the top of
the pendulum and the amplitude of my hands in terms of inches
four miles or light years
that is a linear scale
at the zero
it's not for us
it's not of forced displacement
well i take a picture of one moment in time
and what do i see
i see that
this is what the band looks like
this angle is data
the pendulum is displaced over distance x
from equilibrium
and the top
is displaced
the distance at that this is one of the following
i am doing that i and there was my hand i can help with this
is where i am
and this is where the object is
i want to put in
all the forces that i would
i'll move it up a little bit because i one
i have a little bit of room for my forces
o makes the legs a little shorter
the object
user of
there are only two forces
on this object and that is
which is mg
and that's attention
things are different because you have a lot of bloggers data you can see the
interaction between the different bloggers
the main challenge lies is in discovering communities
within these individual blogs based on interaction
so this is different from blog clustering because blacklisting
focuses solely on the action part two
similar text
blogs are closer together so the but this is different because you have your about
the interaction between different blocks not just the content
so basically you have to do some are technically can link analysis
this figure basically gives you a sense of communities are different bloggers
so you can see different communities emerging
different bloggers as leaders
the nodes and the leaders of the blogs
and the different are
blue notes
the members of these communities
so they said before
researchers identify these code is based on two things
links which is this really the network the hyperlinks that allows interaction
between the these different blogs and then begin to identify which communities from these different
some studies by greenberg and on
the study the community of the pages based on these interactions
by fienberg
used authority in hopes who explore communities
quite extended the idea of for the parties including qualifications
who identify all instances of graph structures that reflect these committee characteristics
some people also studied contains content based similarity basically they used in in
you see the what the bitumen transpired so many
blogs so they can see all these blogs is related so it's an implicit link
assumption between these blogs so once you have that you can establish that between these
blogs based on some events and then you can again try to find out the
community between the law
some books they
also study the blogger behavior while descending the communities so
they it by using a blog
thirty years of a so once so they defined
the readers of the box here
the offer blog site they give them a question and try to find out whether
this community is this blog site is actually a community and there are actually having
a community like environment there
some of the research is the
also studied newsgroups and discussion forums
the fine whether to substitute their domain of blocks
because newsgroups and discussion forums are also make blocks in terms of interaction with this
user i mean that you see a lot of
person to group interaction as compared to person-to-person interaction
let's move to
spam are issues in blogs
which is one of the major rising concerns and blocks
thirty percent of
recent studies indicate that thirty percent of these blogs are going to spam they have
a lot of spam blog spam comment
so and this is actually not a problem for the comments on the blogs which
is also as valuable as the blog post itself
some of the
blog site the
don't allow any guest
comment so they allow you to sign in so they don't have anonymous access to
these blog site so data can prevent
show of spam but this really defeats the purpose of blocking because it is an
open environment so they were want different actions
so it's more like a problem if you try to cut the
interaction then you defeat the was are a few old interaction then you
i have a lot of spam issues
spammers make most of their money by getting viewers to click on the ads that
ran adjacent to
their nonsensical text
and again open standards and low barriers to publishing escalates this problem
and besides degrading search quality and also things natural resources
some of the initial researches applied them spam link detection approaches
to distinguish between nominative pages and spam pages based on the statistical properties like number
of words have the length of words anchor text titles keyword frequency tokenized URL of
and some researchers they use pagerank score to find whether it's spam and
there's also some works based its the blog post as a static webpage and then
they use both content and hyperlinks
information to classify with a blog post is
spam or is not spam
but there are some differences between differences between web spam detection and spam blog predictions
the content on blog site is very dynamic as compared to
that of the pages so content based spam filters not that effective
moreover spammers can copy the content from different sources so
you can't really see whether they are actually spam
so link based spam filters can easily be beaten by
creating legitimate links to other blog sites
so there is some work which considers the temporal dimension of blog posts
and the propose self similarity based splog detection algorithm which is based on the characteristic
patterns found in both blog posts
given the model class you want and we were just going to use against process
prior and we can choose any any casting process that we want to of course
i have to tell you
about ways of making smart choices about this will come back to that but formally
speaking we just need to specify
what that gas process prior looks like an and parameterized in terms of mean function
which in this case i just to zero again and the covariance function yes question
is the
the thing to do
so i'm sure this was a little little shorthand maybe a little bit too short
for let's look at the likelihood function again right so the likelihood function basically says
it's a product over terms and e to the term's has this form is interested
in the square difference between the observation
and what the function is doing at that point but notice that the total likelihood
here only cares about what the function does at the locations where we made observations
OK and this is just my
my very compact notation for the for the same thing is the joint gaussians centered
on the left values with this model
OK and then we maybe we need the gas in we get improper priors over
functions so that will give the casting process prior and see what happens
what we need to do we need to compute the posterior we do that by
multiplying the the prior with the likelihood
so now the likelihood is just just the regular gauss in here and the priors
it's funny kind of and is infinite dimensional gaus
OK let's just go ahead so we multiply to gaussians since we get nothing else
get and unnormalized calcium when multiplied to regulate how since we get one of these
we get
the unnormalized regular workouts and if you multiply against in with one of these infinitely
large scale since we just get an infinitely large gas
informally this is just using the standard the standard way of multiplying together two gaussians
and what does it actually mean intuitively know the posterior distribution is what
it's said it's an infinite dimensional
so what does that make sense
well it makes sense because it's supposed to be a distribution over functions right accounting
process is a distribution over functions
like so we started with with with the random distribution or functions and then we
said well we now have some data that is telling us something about what the
function is doing and also had gauss informed right we multiply together those two and
then we got this infinite dimensional gas here
so now what so how do we actually use this thing right we use the
thing to make predictions
and how to make predictions well the predictions are just an interval
over the the posterior distribution or we just we just want to marginalize out the
the values of f we interested in here right so if we choose a test
point x star we say OK let's just marginalize out the rest of the of
the infinitely many variables and just look at the one that we are interested in
it and then we do that by just throwing away the parts of the covariance
they were not interested in
OK i won't drag you through the actual out properties of this is the only
thing which is going on it and when you get the predictions the predictions here
i just comes down to this one dimensional gaussians has meaning
which is the number in this case it's vector times the matrix times that here
and they can be the variance is just a number
OK so it's just a one-dimensional
gaston distribution yes
that's correct
OK so the question is i've computed what the what a posterior distribution over the
predicted value is that a particular point but i was free to choose anywhere anywhere
one right so i just computers sorry
we are here
no this is this is the general this is that the posterior distribution over functions
this is not a particular x here this is the exhibition just the just the
just the placeholder
this equation works for any value of x
it is a gaussian process is a distribution over functions
but it gets
conditions for the very reason we have
go distribution
in your mind
one person additional
what the distribution of functions because you can choose to
look at
you know what is the function doing any number of locations that in any number
of locations the distribution of the function values are jointly gaussian that because the processors
but let me know if we take your question then i'm going to draw pictures
of what this actually means why because i would rather not so easy to digest
significantly more questions that you will be
so this question about you know how how about how big is the matrix that
we have to compute right and it's true that the matrix here is depends on
the on the covariance matrix here which has the dimension which is the number of
points square right so if have ten thousand training points then this matrix is a
big matrix
that's true
but it's not an infinitely big matrix right it only scales what scales quadratically with
the number of data points right so you want to use this for very large
data data then you might not want to use this naive implementation so that's a
very good point the most ago
bad but when you look at these it's like proportionally there's a lot right canada
has a lot Scandinavia has a lot Australia here something
Greece Crete especially and so on but what is funny is then if you go and
ask what is the so this is would be one of the few highest countries
with the proportion of the population so thirty five per cent of the Iceland population logs in
to microsoft instant messenger in june right and for example spain iceland Spain Netherlands
Canada Sweden Norway they have like one quarter and these are the biggest so then
here's a gap france and UK have like eighteen USA and Brasil have like eight so this would be the
fraction of the population that is actively using microsoft instant messenger in June two thousand six okay
I think these numbers are quite high and then another visualisation is just about
so here he idea is that you have two people talking so you have
have two points and now you just draw a line between them and increase the
intensity along that that line so this would sort of say what are the main communication
exits okay so so whenever there is a conversation from U.S. from Europe
to yes you would like to increase the counts of the points on the line
and now this sort of shows the the how high are the counts and what is
this basically says is that so if somebody stalks Japan Japan to U.S. goes
here so it doesn't like wrap around but still you can see that this seems to be the
main communication line I don't know how to explain this this makes a lot
of sense right from from from Australia New Zealand towards U.S. towards Europe
right here but I don't know why Brazilians would
I don't know I have no explanation for this so another thing I don't know I lost
the title another thing that you can do you can ask is this so
it's how similar people how does the I don't know some how does the similarity of
age or gender affect communication so what I have here is for example this one
is a bit easier to explain so so the thing is if you take two people at
random and you ask what's the probability that they are of the same age the
probability of being of the same age is point three now if you ask from all the pairs
of people that communicate if I pick two random random people what's the
probability that they're are of the same age or you say the same gender right it's the
same then you say oh do they come same zip code if you pick random sets
of people they don't come from zip kode if you peak from the ones that communicate that
communicate it's much higher or for example for country or language again like here is very small
this is like I don't know twenty times larger or so right so this is the
probability of the among if you pick two people that communicate how that they
have they speak the same language and so this is in the terms of probability
this is the correlation so now I'm asking what's the correlation between using the same languages
two people communicate if I pick them at random and this this what this picture shows is if I'm
picking random pairs of people then my age distribution looks like this right it's still
peaks at these particular value because I have the most population here but it's
sort of has no has no diagonal trend while in reality the you can see
the diagonal trend upwards right which basically means that the more similar you are in age location country
language the higher the probability of talking to each other
so now for the second part I want to show some properties of the
graph right as a so we have there are two kinds of graphs one you
at least that you can create from this one is called the buddy graph where
you put all the people and there is an edge between these two people if
if they are buddies on the network right if you if one has the other
in the coontact list okay and this from from the data you would have
two hundred fourty million nodes and you have nine point five billion edges so this would be like friendship links