and then you have the charge density
here so
how the particles
in the in the nucleus and you see that it's not the shop to face
but it's something she was
you can so this is one way you can transfer particles so for example if
you have project and which is the product the interaction then it's a neutron in
the output
due to and then pretend
and the data can be
this is a scatter plot
and what we do also
is gamma spectroscopy so then to excite the nucleus
the way you want either by
by projectile
and or you can do fission
and then you look at its decay
so if we need photons and they
for example in germany in particular
this is a typical spectral so you have here is a member of typically four
tons depending on the energy
in may gary caldwell
and you see some things
you see that it's very spatial spectrum this one correspond to states
that are that correspond to rotation about very simple very different traditional band
that's why seems to be equally spaced here
so you have a very deformed nuclei
one is the ratio of the two
other ones which emit photons
this is the interpretation
so then when you have these these peaks
you have the energy and intensity so
you can
i mean it
the labels can so for its nucleus we have these little kids so this is
an example of late two
so it's just an example don't
don't look at the numbers you have the
here the energy and here you have
the the transition
so it's really look like their code in the street
it's true
it's a good picture it's very good affinities
all the nuclei do have different levels schemes
these are some typical nuclei just to see that there are different these limits himself
to be able better
i'm not completely different
from somalia and one hundred forty eight
and getting the one hundred sixty
you see that here
you can see two things first
they are different because they are equally spaced at the beginning and here
it will see that correspond to different shapes of the nuclear
you still feel that they are organizing bands
it's what we do with experimentally so theoreticians do
when have some very big transitions between states
we say that they do do correspond to the same structure so that we associated
so that's why
you can see in different nuclei different
sometimes it many transition on unleashing because the experiment
you don't see all the transition so
even in the well known nuclear
a lot a lot of new transition can be discovered
especially is a difficult one
i will
again you some applications of these nuclear science
because it's i think it's something very important in all the cells after we keep
you i'm going to talk about
fundamental physics what we look for fundamental physics
but nuclear physics has made a social contributions to different
part of the society for example
in energy production
so for example the electricity generation
many research are made either fission or fusion
on fish and the new research concerned new generations of
new fuel cycles for example the
to look at the story embedded cycles
it's a
after the research
you have
this reduction by transmutation of the long term impact of the nuclear waste to produce
we don't know if it will be eighty years old gen four reactors
but this will be decided in the future so you know that eighty is an
accelerator driven system
and jennifer four
reactors based on fast neutrons that are planned for
to the two thousand fourteen
so what we are looking for also for the far future
so this is solution so then you have a vision of the time for example
the time for
i presume it project
that is under control construction get irish
in france so
this is only a project of physics
then for
if you want to connect that to
two four electricity for for everyone but it would be
i don't know two thousand eighty so it on the prototype for to study physics
then they planned to protect them more to study
for me far
industry but is far far future that
plan to have electricity by solution
it is also used for me
izer diagnostics
so you know that a lot of diagnostic medicine
thanks to nuclear science for example that you can use the detection of the decay
of radioactive isotopes so i
spect single photon emission computed tomography
of the expected positron emission tomography
these are some examples
you have also we do not want to read the irony imaging by magnetic resonance
one thing is that the power in noise
it's going up with the bandwidth that you're looking at because i said the band
is everywhere
you can avoid it and therefore if you use of wider bandwidth system
you get more noise coming into it
we have a certain amount of power that you're willing to transmit a certain amount
of light and the
and the
the number of bits per second you can transmit is going up with w
but look at this effect with p here the effect would pay
his is logarithmic which says as i increases parameter and i put more and more
bits into one symbol
this quantity
is going up exponentially which means the logarithm of this is going up
just linearly
with them
and this
gives you
if you look at it carefully the same trade-off is the simple-minded example i was
talking about
OK but simple-minded example does not explain this formula are all this formulas rather the
we probably won't even completely proven this term
what what channels result says is that no matter what you do no matter how
clever you are with this noise that exists everywhere
the fastest you can transmit
with the most sophisticated coding things schemes you can think of
is this rate right here
which is what you would think it might be
just from the scaling in terms of w
and and were when you increase in power goes up
exponentially it's the same same kind of answer you get with a simple thought experiment
the fact that you have a one and here is a little bit strange
we'll find out where that comes from
but the idea here is that this noise is something you can't be noise is
fundamental as fundamental part of every communication system as i always like to say noises
death and and taxes
you can avoid them there
and there's nothing you can do about them like death and taxes you can take
care of yourself and live longer
and with taxes
well you can become wealthy
and support the government
and make all sorts of payments and reduce your taxes that why or you can
or even higher could account stating in the things they are also
but those things are still always there some say you're always stuck with this
and one of the major parts of the course will be to understand what this
is a much deeper context we would otherwise
OK some
save that come back to later
we have the same kind
of layering
in the channel encoding my talk about channel encoding i'm just talking about not talking
about any kind of complicated coding technique
six four fifty one talks about all of those what i'm talking about is simply
the questions how do you take a sequence of bits
turn it into a sequence of waveforms in such a way
the receiver
we can take that sequence of waveforms and map them reliably back into the original
there's a standard way of doing this
which is to take the sequence of bits
first send them through a discrete encoder
what the discrete encoder will do
something like this
and maps bits one right into bits of the higher rate
and this lets you correct channel airs a simple example of this
as you may have zero
and to zero zero zero
one into one one one
and if the rest of your system
this part of the system
it makes a single layer at some point
this part of the system escape from
OK let me
so put these on one slide but i can
OK this takes a single zero
turns into three zeros
these three zeros
go into this much later which maps this into some way form responsive to these
three zeros
waveform goes through here is gets added the modulator the tax those binary digits comes
out with some approximation to these three zero every once in awhile because the the
noise i one of these bits comes out wrong
again because they come out wrong this discrete decoder
i know that
what was sent putin was either zero zero zero
o one one one
it's more likely to have one area they have two areas and therefore any time
one error occurs
i can the code it correctly
now that is is a miserable code
the guy by the name of
it became very famous
four generalizing this
just a little bit into another single error correcting code which came through
a a slightly higher rate still corrected single errors
he became an only famous because he was tireless self-promoter
and people think that he was the person who invented error correction coding
he really wasn't
kind areas will probably here
anyway coding
of this time namely mapping binary digits into longer strings of binary digits in such
a way that you can correct binary errors
has always been a major part
of of communication system research
a large number of communication systems
i work in exactly this way
in fact the older systems which use coatings tend to work this way
this is a very popular way of trying to trying to design system you would
put it in total
total layering across here
namely this part of the system denote the coding going on here
at this
o point where you're going discrete the coding you don't know anything about what the
detector is doing here
doesn't take a lot of imagination to save you have the detector here
and there's this
symbol comes through here noise gets added to it
we're trying to decode the symbol
and this is calcium noise which is just sort of spread around you know it
usually when errors occur errors occur
just barely
i mean what you see at this point is you almost flip the coin to
this is these non around
the hardware landscape is changing rapidly ant the
from the closest data to the father's data
is expanding
right and i haven't even talked about systems like tape drives right
which are there
glacier for example
when say shoebox i'm taking it as a given
that you're gonna be thinking about
but for management on steroids if you will in this large-scale work
i would say that do more about storage today i'm afraid them
what analysts
also don't make the assumption that everything is going to be in your nice little shoebox
people will keep it and other places maybe because they want have private data
and a bus stop the club
maybe because for various reasons
they can't bring all the data
from it's ring-fenced auditing compliance
in two way you want them to put so you need to support federated access
most importantly
the ecosystem of analytics is exploring the number of types of tools
this large and growing larger
at people wanna be able to use all these tools on
the data
how do you this
right the spectrum goes from signal
just last week there was a panel on sequel on how to handle a half
a dozen vendors we're talking about the products that bring to market in the space
stream processing
business intelligence machine learning graph analytics
the main
many more
at the top of the slide
how do you know this
the bottom line is yukon each of these has we do them pretty assignments
that's my fundamental business
you're gonna have to
do what we did when we built
various data analytics in the first place or file systems
right we abstracted some commonly is
and reuse them again and again
in building different analytic tools
we need to do the same kinds both
for this new generation of systems
add today i will spend some time talking about the computer fabric here
the ubiquitous commonly on top of that you can build sequel machine learning and so on and so forth
all right
you also want to be able to collaborate share selectively all the things people already do
but again i won't say too much about the
one slide on my employer
if you look at microsoft
the current state
already reflects many other points and make
right there's a product called polly base that allows you to issue sequel data
in a relational system
and baby sister
and simultaneously
axes data that's in exterior first system that small
but you don't have to know the data from the it's the first slide into the relational site
i integrated by tools
to excel at the end point there are plugins
they allow you to roll up and draw down or literally
one hundred million rules
policy was interactive visualization
so if you put all these pieces together
you could do interactive visualization land rover down
all the data and how do
using the stack
it's not just microsoft
as i said
they hosted this sequel and battle last week
number when this
it is striking to see
the architectural pictures
look very much like the layer cake
i talked about just
asterdata data
basically if you look at the back
that's what they called by the way that's tell you pronounce it
if you look at
any of these companies schlumberger google hot and what's microsoft see
the whole system
they all share this mission
and what this means in terms of marginal distributions is that all the pairwise marginals
had to break into products of the singleton marginals
that's because everything here is independent there's no dependency anymore so everything breaks into products
that's what your approximation is tell you to do it might not be the right
thing but that's the approximation says
and if you specialize the variational principle that we had this is the mean field
for this particular case
what you see here is you see is some over nodes
and these usually recognizes newly entropy is
minus bernoulli entropy is
and that's coming because you have completely factorized distribution
so you have one entropy for each node and entropy of the product here entropy
takes log see some terms here
so that's where that that entropy term
so that
that's what you get because you said i restrict myself to special distributions like this
you get a very simple approximate entropy it's not exact anymore
these constraints
coming here
you should have these joint terms in this linear form
but because of these constraints you can plug in products these terms here
and that's actually where the non convexity comes in when you have constraints that look
like this
if you sort of think about them they look kind of like hyperbolas or something
it's you can you can see geometrically won't be a convex problem
so the nice thing here is the mean field algorithm all it is a very
simple way of optimizing the function
so the simplest way possible as coordinate ascent you fix all variables except one
and then you optimize over one variable at a time
so here the variables are nodes so it's just like that picture we had before
you fix one note
we pick one node
if you fix all the other nodes
and you do the best possible over that node
and if if you can just go through a couple lines of algebra
you'll see the coordinate ascent is exactly this algorithm here and that's the naive mean
field algorithm
the upshot is that these updates
what this means is those updates will always converge
because the problem is not convex
they might not go to the global optimum but they will converge because you're always
moving up
and what it's trying to do is trying to find the best approximation to your
model that's of this form that's that's the form using this naive case
so any question about about mean field algorithm
these your are
so sort of wondering about this picture while i drawn this inside the original and
right so remember the original and is the set of music that i could get
from any distribution i want
you can do whatever you want you can have
any markov random field to never fully connected graph even if you wanted
but what i'm saying here's your i'm restricting you lot i'm saying in this case
you can only look at product distributions
so you're looking at a very small set of distributions and i'm asking you what
you generate
using that restricted subset
so that's why you're always looking at a smaller set of possible news
this is sort of a high level this is the picture that you want to
take away from mean field i mean sort of analytical details aside you want to
take away that it's restricting its use in an inner approximation
that gives you a lower bound
and it's using the non convex inner approximation those sort of the three key things
to take away
and all contrast that in a second with what belief propagation is doing is doing
something quite different
but something can also be interested in the symmetry picture
i just one last thing about mean field i won't go into details
the whole hierarchy of mean field algorithms depending on how complex the subset of distributions
the naive versions are based on sort using fully factor product distributions
but of course you can use other ones for instance if you remember i talked
about coupled hmms last wednesday these you might use for audio video fusion
and this is a hard model to do inference on
but what people have done mean field on it for instance
and naturals
substructures this to decouple the chains like this and you mean field on this structure
and this is again easy because each of these is the change in their decoupled
and so you can again derive updates for one on the structured mean field
it's again trying to find the best approximation of the form
for model that looks like that
so the whole hierarchy here but of course the trade-off you pay is the doing
the updates gets more complex as you start using more complex structures so this is
in some sense is an application dependent issue how much you want to pay to
do updates how much accuracy do need some cases naive mean field is good enough
other cases you probably have to
the structured cluster field algorithms
OK so let's let's do belief propagation and is actually not much work to do
because we already done some work on the tree
what belief propagation is doing from the variational point of view on arbitrary graphs pretty
what it's saying is
that makes bounds are of this form
you have an extravagant factor here
and the chaining approach
which also works
obviously classes
i would get because of the logan
and the other from that you may want to recall is
when you have you know no noise in the case where your target function belong
to the class and you have zero noise in the kind of ideal case
then all these bounds i mean you can get rid of the
query and you can get something like
the over and
and here you can't get rid of
so that's the
optimal k so ideally
the ideal case
that's the best you can do in dimension d obviously them into the and that
in january
these are things that it is good to have this kind of remarks line
and using bound
but the last comment
it's important to understand that
they are saying that we can and i mean that we might have with intentionally
in the bow and arrow things that come out from really the learning phenomenon and
those things are
you i mean you should be
training or you should train yourself to
really detect which is which when you look at about
finally the most important messages
the goal i mean if you want to justify something to avoid assumptions because as
well as i mean it's fine to introduce assumption when you want to understand things
but you don't provide justification anymore
what assumptions
you can't ever
very these assumptions like even the fact that somebody like something to something that thesis
is independent this you can't even verify so anything beyond that is
even less verifiable anyway
if you have an assumption and then you get a justification if you use assumption
you get understanding can still what happens if let's assume it might target function where
a linear classifier
what would i do that
doesn't mean that i mean maybe you have an algorithm that for which we can
prove that if the target function is that the classifier is the perfect
but then what if it not the case
the important thing the geometry
and again repeating the same things again and again hoping that
will enter your brain and get out of
the last thing
i'm sorry for this advertisment but i have to two
do it but maybe we can start with questions and then i will come back
to this
after one
OK so the question is i'm saying that the geometry of the most important thing
in the bound but
the geometry
of the function that depends on what you know about on your prior OK so
what i'm saying here is
if you give me a class of course you have presented so if you tell
me i'm using
you know
the RKHS corresponding to the adoption kernel i'm using SVM with gaussian kernel and that's
my classification
that's perfectly i mean that's your choice but now what i'm saying is that
even this function class
OK i these this function classified the RKHS
the geometry that time
referring to the geometry that is induced by
the distribution
when you look at the plant
two functions in this class
would have from
intrinsic metric
distance between them
which depends on the probability distribution which
i don't know for sure but i can
you know
knowing these and maybe
looking at you can even look at an empirical sample
and you can see how the solutions you and then from that you can measure
how big is the class and how the function in the past in a this
is no longer i mean this is
ok so this is a i have a webcam here and square the images and i
can point this camera very things so the point it that's
this computer and this is not book ok it's right
as a right to have this monitor yeah this monitor
complete keyboard
it's mouse yeah about this remote control
chose to yeah one of those how about this
ipod ok that's actually a some some galaxy as well
it does not have to phones and both something x this for this one
is a set of four which is more correct
ok but is black so it's a set of farmers it's y is and i
so at i store little piece of history here pretzel current a ok
so i know it's know it knows it's kind of
history some kind know can eat it
so may ok because you know a non plate know is to
with this what about all ok as one of our this question kohima yeah
as our right have this matrix which none really really doesn't
know that actually on to those that phones
remote-control always got he's on it might
this to loop so that s yeah this is an class know ok that's
and help computer of course because it's
you know others and some widget and actually have
a ok this this
learning to as their yeah into for me properly
loafer as a enough you know this is to so the idea
what's ok and where we say this actually
library a ok why he's ok
monitor as close enough cash to know
right as is so right you get the idea let me show you another
similar demo
but this one i on
the probabilities well so that so this is trained with
cross-entropy loss on it's like not the last you could think of it
as much to learn to question so you get you get
you probably to estimate
you think of them scores really so calibrated scores really that's
what they are
ok so this
so i can train so i can point camera something or nothing
like this and making quick learn loops and to get to focus
and it's kind of learn this so if i put a simple cells it's doesn't
know but if i can back to this it focus here we go
right now i can put that are less right side of the room so the
room depending on the point of view so you are category b
and you guys the other side
and number you see here on the right side is the number of samples
that are used to to train so excited c
a is low light so that this was how time
i myself have a very different from the rest
yeah of those pictures and you know i could use whatever
ok so we have this project whatever it is
yeah yeah and we have this little screen down there we have
the right so the room we have this and
and you know i train this with a number of categories just a few
examples what this shows is that so first to tell you how this
works right so you take the core of the commercial net chop off
the last layer on retrained last layer
are using essentially what else nearest neighbour pasan window classifier
essentially by just storing templates so we on the bottom stores
template compares
right so back to
the talk in and and hoops of the direction and
so you have humor things there is a really impressive application
of this to image imitation to show because on tell you about unsupervised
and since this is a three hour talk have to our left so so
ok so as learning ok so what is unsupervised learning that's kind
of the question we might ask and
to me the way i like to see unsupervised learning is that capturing
dependencies between variables and essentially one possible way
of capturing dependencies between between variables
are observed variables is to find so it's very likely that the
data comes to you is going to the living in
manifold or some surface eventually surface in the space
and if you find if you if you can train a function that tells you
when you show it a vector whether it's on may fall off the
manifold or even better which tells you which direction to move
to words to get closer to the manifold then you basically sold
unsupervised learning because of capture the dependencies between
variables ok and the bet one best first to do this is to an energy
function to tell you offer you often manifold
ok contrast function some kind so imagine your observations of those
blue deals here here this ought to know this is a kind of
two different learning algorithms to different parameterization
learning algorithm learning that sort of changes an energy surface
so that the blue beads have lower energy and everything else
so this guy here stops flattened and the sum of those areas
push up so that to get you know have are with roof
this guy a the energy is designed such a way that already
in a filling in a drug down differently this but they have and i can
only guess so an object to be going belong to the ural river and alter
the layer of from automatically belong to the layer of a drug it is sort
of a superclass of these differently this particularly when a transform that in the business
scheme i have a table for columns of the a table for physical objects and
there is a relation between logical and physical object so the part of all the
efficiency of its physical object is part of these logical object when describing the context
is specified object type so if the object type is that i automatically know that
the reader is defined as a type of i draw graffiti that type of logic
i don't have to solve automatically i can obtain the a hierarchical information of these
all these easily
so it's quite different from the typical expression of bayes when we have a table
forty should differently this is true because a lot more than that we are considering
but in this way is quite difficult to represent i information different object in this
case we want to represent information because for the first version of discovery task we
are able to deal with these and so we thought we have the design these
schema because we suppose it is a adopted find the four percent think these problems
yes but is not by in the sign of the babies with the definition of
product time if OK one time i decide okay this is not to pass he's
not a musician with a drug but it is in is a relation with orthography
it's not impossible but looking for documents i have to change in the design of
that obeys the definition of c that is not the type that is that i'd
rather but it is the type that is or graffiti
these are the objects
much structure
the distribution on
yes you can
we all this
over here
for you
OK this is exactly the i ching OK do
system started the project with these people of by mistake department and they give the
specific problem in this a OK i'm interacting modelling this type of data and exactly
this type of data so we have designed the these ideas he i don't go
on the specific the
requirements begin answer anyway it's the the sound and the sound is very simple to
be extended if i decided to introduce new avalon i have two of the allies
or in order a academic into by following stuck same procedure is only the example
that we have defined these specific project but really know what is important is the
idea on the same is it we can define a very general i his son
for the next nine it's
yeah an example of descriptive in our several study of the different descriptors and the
unknown example from a practical point of view it is implemented as it appears well
proceeded to dismiss that descriptor is like a function that can be caught in this
world clearly
so this is the
we we in the dust from a practical point of view and practically an example
of competition we wanted to deter mine the because fidelity of line and the descriptor
is typically computed on four object belonging to developing countries will these years because the
experts said OK in this case it's interesting for us to all
no to characterize these particles shape window
the line and this is the idea that very simple and public to business line
is the line we computed in goal of each segment forming this slight difference between
and they for this difference is greater than a threshold we defined it is like
musical style or not is it because they tend to be confined to an entity
called topological
and computation computational topological properties and relations
OK the different types of queries we can compute is a salary query because the
case was sent back to all the objects belonging to a specific assembly as in
this case are in this case we selected exactly all the objects that belong to
these are at eleven million eleven query that these means OK for salem not interested
interesting in all the possible object about an interesting on only to the object belongs
to the drug traffic and the construction only because i don't really interesting for a
specific task so i that although objects belong to the user specifically and
to the typical form query that we can define object level query can we can
say that
we interesting to the
two the object belonging to the about of the layer and in particular for the
road we interested to the world
that induces sparsity and as specific properties that is not only
set only about and the set of old and the for the road only the
four for which of these properties is satisfied and the therefore each site uses
selected for each cell of the model
why did the risk is we have all the objects belonging to the geography and
construction only the to
OK the second parameters is that we define is that the kind of knowledge to
be minor so the key words in this case is mine the kind of part
to be discovered that can be as additional rules and classification seems more at this
moment throughout we look and example for the classification rule about it's quite similar for
official discovery
in the classification rule and so the classification as part of a is the name
of the city to the club to the part to the set of pattern to
be discovered to be discovered for the concept to be learned for example OK i
wanted to know classification rule for the class concept to fluvial landscape so to characterize
all the objects belong to the class four landscape
all right if i wanted to classification rule for more than one concept i can
specify the different concepts alliances select set of descriptor to be used in generating the
logical description of the object selected and with this group doesn't specify exactly this discrete
can actually prove the generalisation is possible
beautiful branch of mathematics which in my opinion to represent the best possible intersection computer
science and mathematics
learning experience
and then there's you know
many many years the VC dimension and active learning activities in some roughly speaking about
this space is not too complicated it has a low capacity in some formal sense
and for training set is large enough and we do well on and then you
can bound the probability
during significantly worse on test data
having said
i told you about all this you know beautiful
the formalism we're now going to do something very simple
you have to crawl before walk right so we're just controlled by adding a a
penalty to lost
we're going to say a certain parameters which i think a lot more complex those
back in the other parameters which i model to be simple and those of an
all-out because and that's the job of the function p so he looks after him
and not
i don't want to make public for the purpose of finding simple
and then we just take the sum of a loss function which is the training
error and the kernel
parameters and this is called penalised regularized learning and that's how we control so good
to the data
to get
training error but also going to by itself
towards the end of
so this is just a picture to drive this
you focus on the right hand side here is
it's true tables
so let's say i gave you
this training data it's a function which has three binary inputs you are
x one x two x three and a single line of the white line
and the training data i tell you the zero zero zero there is zero
if the input is zero one zero one sort of lines field
for an overnight stay
please use your fancy machine learning techniques to predict for what you was going be
when the input is zero
are one
so when decision starting to get really scared
you should be thinking to himself
this is ridiculous it's good so arbitrary truth table writing this value could be either
i mean how many are you not what this value is right the these values
you have nothing to do with the prince
that you don't understand if you don't make assumptions about the world you can never
learn anything
example where the fact that you have to make an assumption really are really comes
and slaps in the face of course you have to make some assumptions like maybe
this function is conjunctive normal form
or maybe use some of the two cause of the rules
make some assumptions about the form of this and then you can start to fill
in these values because there's only one function which is consistent with the training
this is a picture where
the fact that you have to make assumptions doesn't seem so obvious imagine given the
training data which were these circles here
and i told you we predict the value function somewhere between almost would have no
problem doing the right thing to do to draw the line like this through the
and tripoli on this line
drawing the line through the data
is exactly the same as making
some assumption to fill in the truth table
don't fool yourself because you have big visual cortex like smooth things this is you
know more natural assumption assumption make you get when you draw a line to interpolate
you are making assumptions
you're making an assumption that this function is smooth in some very simple
you know l two sets of size k and that's fine that's actually really believe
they are
no you're making some
so an unbiased learner can never generalise if you don't make assumptions about the world
OK so
enough for me to do
pontificating i want to get moving probabilistic
first here so given by
what we can think of learning and doing is estimating the joint probability function samples
from those
classification and regression supervised learning are estimating the conditional density of the output y given
the inputs
from should representation of the image and you tell me whether they should be word
counts in the standings in the email
you can think of just density estimation
you want to estimate
but you know in the central object of interest is the joint distribution between the
input and the output between inputs
and the maintenance of the is compactly representing the joint distribution and robustly learning exchange
from small number
and our inductive bias is expressed as prior assumptions about the distribution
so in a probabilistic framework everything is about estimating large joint distributions between inputs and
outputs as the whole game and all of your assumptions are prior assumptions on what
these distributions can can be represented prior
i prior distribution for the parameter the distributions of class distribution
so the main computations we're going to need to do in the probabilistic approach
are efficiently calculate marginal and conditional distributions from whatever compact representation of the joint distribution
the o
here focusing on
the first was to represent the a joint probability distribution PX compactly even when there
are many variables
so just to drive this home imagine you have a one megapixel images from the
this species are recorded sixteen bits of information each color channel
and now you want to ask how many possible images my camera shake
well that's one megapixel
raise to the
three hundred sixty
that's going on the mind-blowingly large numbers so i just wanted to represent the distribution
of images by saying well
for every possible image is going to have a probability and probabilities are just numbers
and summer have two
OK this is going to be in deep trouble because the probability will be thinking
as so many entries that you could never write down
not only because computer every and even if you could write down there would be
no way for you to estimate the distribution because you
it's all like you know all space that only trained on the two thousand images
to have a few thousand these observations in the
billion billion dimensional space how you're going to do that so
just wrong representation of joint probabilities is never going to work
OK so you need to make some assumptions about the distribution so here's the simplest
assumption you could make the distribution is completely factorized
so the probability of all the
joint probability of all the observations x is just a factorized into the product of
the marginal distribution the
now this is completely
this it says
for the data as the conjugate the multivariate bernoulli distribution
is this beta distribution this is exactly analogous to what i showed you
the discrete multinomial distribution and the dirichlet distribution the
bernoulli distribution is just a discrete distribution we only have two choices
and the debated distribution is that it exactly a dirichlet distribution when you only have
two possible outcomes
so this is the sort of a special case of the dirichlet that we had
except that we just have a parameter beta j and on the other outcome is
one minus
i remember this term here is the normalisation constant for that
beta distribution or dirichlet distribution and we have a hyperparameter alpha j beta j
which i have to tell you how to do that
before you observe the
the query you have to be able to that the
but these represent our sort of
prior on where we think are
concept might end up
in the space of possible data
now the nice thing about
conjugate priors that exponential family distributions
is that
we can multiply
this prior by the likelihood
and integrate out the data and we get an analytic expression for that in the
and in fact
that's exactly
an expression of the form
the normalizing constant here
OK because there is no one because way we got that was by
integrating this stuff
from zero to one
from data going from zero to one
that the normal i think that we need to get the whole thing to integrate
to one
and so
it's exactly that kind of indigo that we need to be able to compute any
of the marginal likelihood that i mentioned in
but before
so i can go through that in detail but eventually
with just a little bit of algebra
you get an analytic expression for the score of an idea
which is a ratio involving all of these gamma function
which would then be
and what is the gamma function
corresponding to
the parameters of the prior these alpha j beta j
those parameters
the range of data before we observe the
query that
and then we also have parameters
still the ambady g tilde
which represent the
range of the parameters after observing the query that
distribution posterior distribution of the parameters after observing the query which is also part of
asian so
albertville the j
it's just alpha j one
the sum over the items in the query that
the features of the g featured in the item and they don't feel the j
is the data is the same thing
the sum over how many times that feature did not appear in the group
so all we do
it is essentially for each of the features
under the model we would have to count how many times it appears in the
i we find it doesn't appear in the query that n is the number of
items in the query that we can compute the output over the data the very
and then we compute the score
now this still looks very very nasty
but they can be dramatically simplified because
the gamma function is the
it is a generalization of the factorial
and so a lot of things that have allowed
so if we do that
many different ways different realms of thought
domains of expertise or whatever
here's a real life example
this child child is building something in
here are seven or eight things that this
the girl may be thinking
what if i pulled out the bottom block
should i help him with the tower knocked down
how would react to that
can i reach the arc shape block that's here
i forget where i left the arc shaped block maybe she can't quite see it
and so forth how it feels to hold three these three blocks at once and
so forth
every one thinks all those things
we don't know if they think them in parallel rapidly oriented
you switch between them or whatever
but to make a machine that has common sense
it's going to have to be able to interpret each event
in many different ways
late last year i finished the book
about this sort of thing and i recommend
did you read it and email me if you have any complaints
and you can either buy the book or
almost all of its on my home page
a slightly older than the published draft
and probably
better in various ways because in the last stages i smooth things out and try
to make the language better
and probably made it more obscure
i'm always trying to organize what i'm going to say and
changing my mind at the last minute
and gerry sussman just scolded me for that
so i'm going to say a little bit about
what are the popular things in artificial intelligence today
i call them fads because
i think most of them will go away but that could be wrong
here are eight of them
very few people today work on the kind of symbolic reasoning
that was needed first legal and bob rose and
those other old program when the grids
programs that i mentioned before
most efforts are
in the direction of saying that i don't want to have to program everything the
machine does
that would be dead and maybe would take millions of years
there must be a better way
so let's find some way for the machine to develop itself by
perhaps by experience with the outer world
being immersed in in a real body in the real
so let's see if we can invent away for it to learn everything
well in fact humans don't learn very much from experience
all that we know about children
is that if you have a child who is
disconnected from other people
left in its own physical world
it will grow up
as an idiot
now there is no evidence for this to speak of because it's illegal to do
that experiment
the amusing thing is that if you want to find out about feral children
children who grew up
being raised by wolves or
in nature
or with no human contact
the most detailed story and the most cited one
comes from seventeen fifty
about the wild boy of have their own who was rescued from a forest and
apparently had been
raised by wolves
but and was very abnormal and never learned to speak
and so forth
but we don't know anything about such children because
the most likely case seems to be that the child looks so retarded that it's
parents just left out to die and didn't
so no one knows but i suspect that children do not learn much from experience
and they learned most of what we call common sense
by being told or shown or
four taught and they don't
very much by themselves anyway nobody knows much about
the most popular kind of learning theory is to have the machine do things at
and you press a reward but when it does what you want
you directly control how many support vectors you get home any points outside the tube
and just a few pictures about this
so here for instance that's
the dataset generated from the sinc function
x values are think uniform in this interval in the y values are sink of
sign side of x over x
and here we
and it's zero noise and here we have quite a bit of noise
the underlying function the green one
and in both cases
trained and new support vector regression where set new
twenty percent to twenty percent of the points are allowed to lie outside and you
can see that in this case the epsilon ends up being zero
the SVM notices there is no noise in the data in this case the epsilon
inside the rather large
maybe i'll skip
if you have the next slide
rather than going into much more details on support vector regression i want to tell
you a bit about some other algorithms and also i want to is mention the
representer theorem yes
so the a three hard the training procedure
training procedure in the way i showing here is is that strange procedures
training set that's w
you could say that they are
so this is unlikely that all of these properties online
we are more
parts of the input space of what you do not need to know
OK so that's a slightly different question
if you were standing on scenario would be
you just get one point out i don't know the on different parts of the
space point that this
now the situation where to model noise in different parts of the space
which is say roughly speaking with a lot of lies somewhere you probably one lot
size if we only
this is in case you need a small size
that would be handled automatically
we have some methods that it over
which you can use if you have a problem about which parts of the space
which part of speech you would expect a lot
but this in this case you put in some prior knowledge could think about how
to generalize the two
the that also in the sense that size is automatically computed as a function
o point space i think we need lot more data that is more suite of
what i need to be
OK so
just briefly tell you about represented here because there is also a bridge between the
price of a lot of room
so this is the original home classic here by chris wahba in the seventies i
believe is a classic people can and often buy it
and i'm showing a slight generalization of this theorem
so in theorem were given a positive definite kernel
training sets
a strictly monotonic increasing real valued function omega
we will use this function omega
to determine how or regularizer
goes into the objective function
and an arbitrary cost function c
which takes as input the whole training set and
the outputs of f on the whole training set
the the statement is any solution to this optimisation problems of the optimisation problem of
minimizing this thing here so this thing has this original cost function
anyway the most general you can think of and this regularizer which is
objective functions for instance quadratically but it could also be different
any solution to this problem admits a representation in this form
he would say that we have
sorry even hundreds of thousands of features of variables
the whole thing might be easy
on the other hand so
text is highly redundant so if you remove half of the data
from the document would still be able to understand or tool to make something out
of the
this text analysis tasks
we know this from everyday practice let's see if e
newspaper articles and if somebody would remove either half of the words
and even for the
according to alphabetical order would still roughly know what's what's the text about
so this is this redundancy of which text has inside
and what's interesting that's a lot of very simple approach is actually a
can get a
really interesting results
and so basically a recipe for
so the text mining can we deal with the first
extract some
meaningful words
units of text phrases words or something like this
find meaningfully related words so this is something which connects different pieces among other between
documents and kind create some sort of summary so this is the recipe basically four
almost every text mining category is just that's what are
this phrase is what relationships and what what is the our so this is the
question we can
of course like in very simple ideas already works or something
but with more sophisticated algorithms and you can get
or more complex summaries more complex results so we'll see see some of the best
so which areas scientific areas of engineering careers are in this text analytics areas so
one sites
we have
machine learning text mining so this would be
the area of are coming from
in particular these areas the roots and analysis of the textual data not not so
much in this area is color other
other aspects of x then
even older area
the text natural language processing which reduces the linguistic aspects of text usually
natural language
processing unit is one sentence and then they try to pass it tends to find
really deep relationships between species of
of words phrases and so on one machine learning takes a whole bunch of the
whole corpus of documents and then does some analysis on the
then next very important area is information through information there is basically about the search
engine so
c will all kinds of search which you can find knowledge based on
one of them
usually so people
working in this area which would belong to this information three with
and the last one kind of the newest one with be semantic web which appeared
five years ago and the more recent brother of semantic web this web two point
zero which briefly touch afterwards they do it's smaller semantics of
text and connecting
text and maybe some other tool
vocabularies ontologies to
two to the more abstract libraries of more abstract
because concepts
so altogether let's say
we can say that this is a text text analytics
the area which
at the end tries to
and bring someone standing in the text in various ways
OK as i said so machine learning is about data analysis
natural language processing about computational linguistics
information theory is about search in databases how to store text and search
the top of this
storage and
semantic web is more like about the knowledge representation and reasoning tagging concerns
there are three major dimensions of text analytics so three major aspects which we need
you know if the let's say if we try to do this
so one is representation so how
how to represent text
usually on the input we have text in asking for more
bdx or in some kind of semi structure are completely constructed before and so on
this document needs to be represented in terms
and there's some and so we have on a very simple side
character level presentations are we presents
document is a sequence of characters
and sequence of words and someone who very complex ones which we see later on
which would be a first order theories which again is just another representation of text
but much more complex and for some tasks
it's enough to represent text just as a sequence of characters
while for some other
task may be first order theories wouldn't be in techniques
the station is only one very important aspect techniques
then we expect positive distance when the class is is
in the US
class and we expect the negative distance and no class ocean multiplied by water negative
this narrative
this is the vacancy
OK so now
we have this likelihood here
given some distance
which is a step and if that distances at all
the the the wrong side then we say zero
and if is on the right side we say it's one
and that causes problems when the data is not linearly separable
like in this case
we've got this
step function like which i had there while ago
and the solution to this is something which
which is mentioned here
with that we can use
a regression technique
minor look like what you're used to but
we can use a softer version of this step function
so it's not quite so harsh on
points which are
just one side or the other of the
of the boundary
and if we choose this function in the right way
then we can have
something which
when it's right on the boundary
the zero distance from the decision boundary that i likelihood is
is point five
as it moves in one direction or the other
it becomes close to close to one zero
so the class of functions we use here are called sigmoids and you know a
common choice is the
logistic sigmoid
which gives us this mapping from
positiveinfinity to negative infinity in a kind of squeezes down to the
zero to one range
all right so you could use that form of likelihood
it gives you slightly more robust
results when you have data which is not linearly separable if there's no single line
you control than it does the right thing
that's something called logistic regression if you're just trying to
maximize the likelihood of parameters given all the data points and that's something called logistic
regression you can also do bayesian logistic regression
we do the process that we've just
but with this likelihood spot instead of the step function
OK let's think about another few ways that we can extend the scheme
and one thing you may be thinking
OK this looks like we've got some simple speech recognition that can
recognise two different words
now what i thought it was three words what if you want maybe
or or from the entire the entire language
you know what we can do with the line in that case
and one thing you might
OK if you've got
if you have like a third class here
you know one kind of obvious thing is
you could do
one split here to divided up into two classes so you don't have the circles
on the side the pluses and triangles on the side benefits on this side you
would learn
another decision boundary dispute of those two classes
again something you could do
and in that case you would have
you know if you decided that if the classifier give you
this side of the line here
then you can go ahead and learn
like a second decision boundary which
what's all those up
so you could keep kind of adding lines to give you multi class
might become a bit cumbersome if you've got many
many classes but it's still something you could do
and one way with this is actually particularly effective
is constrained case
where you make all the w point masses so let's say
i'm going to constrained
all my
all my life and i've only got two cases and that is
and it's say a
it's either that
or is that
and if i take instead of lines being able to go at any angle anywhere
i instead restricted to just these two possible combinations and b can be anything
then what we get is decision boundaries which are always aligned to the axes
so in that case we get
our hypothesis space
now it looks like a bunch of lines which are all
which are all axis aligned
so the only thing we can choose its which axis we want
and how far along each
access the
the the the boundary is
and if we have
he plunged into darkness
alright thanks
if we
make this kind of constraint then it becomes possible to evaluate different
some different likely it seems to be some discussion here lighting conditions are
now one thing we might want to do is
now intuitively when we're
and sure about the decision boundary that
if we have a
some data which
some data which like this and are possible space of decision boundaries is all the
lines anywhere along here and all the lines anyone where long here going to be
interested in lines which somehow split up these
these groups are going to be interested in line
so so
it so
OK can
that's why i'm not
so i have a
you can kind of tell us
so can
have a quantum gravity theory was fundamental scale cannot be below it TV
this gives you very quickly hawking temperature which is in the TV show
and of course an objective temperature
what about if TV normally will disappear as instantly as it was used
so unless you believe that hawking radiation
it doesn't happen which would
b against all our field theory calculations now you shouldn't worry too much
about these things sleeping lake lemon forty he founded in geneva
OK now
so black holes have a temperature and then the rest of the argument is very
straightforward well if you believe in thermodynamics there is the first floor which tells you
that the change in energy
is the temperature times the change in entropy
here energy is the mass of the black holes so BM is the age times
now remember ph was
expression involving minors show we can integrate this formula to to define an entropy
as of the black hole
the entropy of the black hole has a very universe and more useful rewriting you
you can write it in terms of mass and charge of course but they prefer
to write it in this form because this seems to hold always in all dimensions
four theories
these are i think that the entropy of the black hole is the area of
the whole arise on
four by
our last square so there is in this sense the canonical entropy per unit corsi's
an area divided always but by four eight bar times g your
so one over four h but is the unit of entropy horizon area in all
quantum gravity theories brains
and again notice that the entropy divergence of course in the classical limit where h
goes to zero and it is a huge entropy because is very weak
OK now this is called the bacon's time hawking entropy and
now let's go back to some very elementary statistical mechanics entropy in usual thermodynamics and
statistical mechanics is the derived quantity if we have microscopic description of the system
we can actually compute entropy and here is a very simple example of how you
do these
and one which will point to a couple of points
many later so let's think of one of the simplest
systems we have in thermodynamics that's the paramagnetic some material which properties to the magnetic
field b
and now let us assume that we have some microscopic description of this potomac for
instance let's assume that it is described by n impurities magnetic impurities which correspond to
non interacting spins seeking mike that he has been seeking
in this
piece of
and interacting with the magnetic field in the usual way namely magnetic moment dot
the magnetic fields not just to get rid of factors i have here put the
elementary magnetic moments to be equal to twice the four-minute
so i have written down this people that energy functional energy function which is the
sum of all spins magnetic moment times magnetic field
how do we compute the energy well that's very simple i just have to count
how many spins are aligned along the magnetic field and how many in the other
so the total energy is the magnetic field times and plus minus and mines
now how do we calculate the entropy the entropy in quantum mechanics and quantum statistical
mechanics is simply counting problem just count how many states you have with the given
energy that's what the answer is
the more the number of states you have given energy the higher the entropy
actually you have to compute the logarithmic this
in this particular problem it's trivial counting just you can't the number of ways of
choosing plus out of n the total number of spins you take the log out
if you find this very simple expression
and it's
extensive it grows of course with the volume of the number of bins the system
linearly and then there is some expression involves the energy density
divided by the magnetic field as everything here
now this was a very simple calculation because they shown spins that don't interact if
you try to do the calculations taking into account interactions of spins it starts becoming
harder of course because now
i cannot choose independently
this all over the place you know nearby spins with line and so on and
so forth
so the problem is harder but the basic
the a technique
simply what can we just have to do it if more technical work and the
perturbation theory and you will find some expression that starts out to this one then
has corrections
if the coupling of the spin spin interactions is very strong on the the other
hand then
thinking even of spain's as the microscopic degrees of freedom
maybe altogether misleading and then
you know the score calculation may be irrelevant
for the problem however this is simply because we we don't have
in nice microscopic description that can handle if you had some other way of doing
it like lattice calculations it would still be OK
OK so this is how we do entropy calculations to statistical mechanics now one do
a similar calculation for the black hole actually what we have an entropy
the bacon's steinhardt entropy derived in a very indirect way as crucial for this
until in calculations
but to have a very simple expression can we understand it through some
counting problem like in the case of the potomac
now let's make a comment here that
in the case of the paramagnetic sort of
so this the preimage
and this the post image
post image
if you look about halfway down the left hand side is learned about yin-yang yang
first post image
three which is to preach
you might call the seeing a machine that will be confusing
OK so now what we did allan jepson and suggested he said well you turn
it on
sparse translations
why don't you give it transparent images so give it sparse stop words but some
don't translate one way some documents translate another
and we know what happens when chose to people
if the two directions the translation quite similar within about thirty degrees this in one
if there are more than about thirty degrees c two motions and emotions repelled from
each other just like
luckily the
roman didn't know that did this work and he was slightly irritated that they were
repelled in his data and i was good news radio
it's good news having model that doesn't work if a psychologist because maybe people don't
the same way
so we tried it on
but just one translation china
then we have the second rule
which we encourage to be sparse
all unsupervised the second thing that i learned units that are tuned to
the direction of motion so each unit has a preferred direction in job-loss kind of
the way
you comments
decide what is network perceiving
by taking all those units and the second in two directions
and adding the beliefs of all ones the all
actually wait how how much they want to be on what they believe and then
you get a distribution over directions i believe
but everything certain unsupervised
and the answer is when you presented to dot patterns if within about thirty degrees
it sees one motion
and it's more about thirty degrees apart is these two motions against two peaks and
what it believes and the slightly repelled
so that proves that this is how the brain works
OK i'm not going to go to time series models that's very that's one kind
of enters model
most people in our community when they want to model time series when actually like
to use non linear distributed representations because a much more powerful and interesting
but they kind of hard to learn especially if use directed models
so what they do is they fall back on the old faithfuls which are give
up on distributed and markov model will give up on non linear and nonlinear dynamical
now if you could go a little bit further non image should call systems
that you live
but what we're going to do is learn a far we cannot give up on
mathematics and learn a thoroughly non-linear distributed representations
so it's kind of like this
on the right-hand side you see the standard restricted boltzmann machine it has visible units
the some hidden units
and the states of those units are conditioned on previous time slices
so we we regard the history as
fixed and not changeable and what the previous time slices have conditioning connections which in
effect change the biases of the visible units
that's called water aggressive model use linear visible units
and they also have condition connections which change the biases of the hidden units
so this i dynamic biases that depend on the previous state
you can learn this
you put data in a given the data the previous station the current of the
hidden units are independent so you can sample estates
he then reconstruct just the current visible data
and then you activate the hidden units again
and use the difference differences statistics
and you take the you would have used to change the biases of the hidden
units visible units
and you back propagate that derivative to change the weights coming from previous
states the visible units
so you can all of these connections quite simply using contrastive divergence
once you've learned you can generate from the model
and the way generate from the model is you have to initialize the few sensible
and then given the previous frames
what they do is simply determine the biases of the visible and hidden units and
then you do alternating gibbs sampling
but you don't have to give a very long because we strongly determined biases there
are many places and really go to it has to fit in with what just
so you don't have to go for huge length of time
and then you just samples state the visible units in action is visible frame and
so you can keep some
you can actually is that these models are so you can learn one model
united states for the hidden units you treat those data
once the data you can i put in autoregressive connections between them
and at another hidden in the the next leg
and if you do that you'll get the best
and graham taylor shown that if you're doing this for modeling metadata adding second to
work much better
that's not what we're gonna do
we can apply this kind of model to motion capture data but we're going to
do with these three way interactions which like multiplicative things
so you can capture human motion by putting markers on the joints and obviously cameras
and figure out where they were in space the joint angles
so then frame is going to be a bunch of joint angles which are real
so can use against in binary RBM to begin with but this program is to
begin with but we got something better
i retract my work we're basically using kerosene binary RBM the visible units
we also had in the translation of the base of the spine
and the rotation of the base of the spine
for rotation we do the actual angles
for the
page and the world
but the change in angle for the
because gravity doesn't care about
the absolute value of your
so now we can do a three-way version of the model i showed you before
what we can do is take the basic model
a modulate all the interaction matrices
using a style variable
so the style variable is the one of and started
that gets expanded into a real valued vector of one hundred style features
those style features are used as one of the inputs to factor so each factor
is looking at some linear combination of style features some weighted linear combination of those
and then the
this mapping so little bit of area was there a little bit of because you
not perfect separation
so it's not intrinsically any questions
and actually there have been some a number of
application would have used methods like this so one can think of this as well
as kind of getting theoretical motivation for
a kind of approaches used in practice so
you take
basically trying to
should remember
the paper by
where we try
two your we might try to find things out there on the web for instance
that measuring similarity to those might give good feature information basically trying to invent new
finding objects to being i might be useful features
so so now if this is going to be an even
OK so so now the question OK so
given we're kind of thinking of these similarity functions
and they give us a different angle thinking about clustering so from a theoretical perspective
clusters are kind of funny problem because at least learning you can tell how are
you doing i mean you a cumbersome algorithm and
whatever you did something and then you can test your error on new data structure
dating scene
january ten percent doing pretty well for me to to be doing well for clustering
is now usually for clustering there isn't an easy objective measures so
so here's something to think about problem and in the dataset and not
let's say there
documents or web pages so here's my documents
and there is some unknown ground truth clustering is
imagine every object has some true label its top
OK so these these documents or web pages they it's about some part of that
everything is one time
these are about politics need about sports about economics everybody's got talk
so these guys from topic the some truly
and so there's there's there's
true labels though
purple one person the
barely visible light blue
and our goal
is to produce the hypothesis of low air so we want our algorithm to get
you know
good splitting of the data by topic of the correct answers to these guys topic
one topic two we were going to produce the clustering in which pretty much these
guys are in one topic and those guys running out
now we don't really care about the names the right answer is this topic one
topic two arguments as well as the one of the with the this clusters right
so up to isomorphism only one is we want to get to the ground truth
the problem is that we only have unlabeled data
right so i mean i got some labelled data the labels of the
so we can find separator something but what if we only have unlabeled
so i've got a bunch of documents i tell you each one about some topic
go ahead and one even for you
you do it
that's going to be a hard problem
but that's kind of what we want doing clustering released the way i want think
about how to think about clustering as a multi class learning problem we only have
unlabeled and zero job given these documents is the correctly
you know
partition the by topic even though
you haven't been given any labelled data and it seems like a pretty tough thing
to try to do
however according to imagine that we are given something and we're going to be given
to measure similarity three of pairwise similarity function between objects and so the question is
how related does that have to be the topic maps
in order for the help
that's the kind of question why i want to try to develop a theoretical way
of looking at this problem
the case of from hand you measure of similarity between objects how related doesn't have
to be to the notion of what objects are what topic in order for this
to be helpful for now to be able to use this to actually get an
what conditions on a similarity function be enough to allow one to cluster
this will lead to something like a PAC model
when i give this too
this this talk to people coming from algorithms community
i have to point out that so usually from say
approximation algorithms perspective the ways that the problem is a bit different there when you
is you
start with some weighted graph is some embedding of points in space you pick some
objective function
like k median and k means or something and you come up with a couple
algorithm that optimizes are approximately optimize that object for example the k median objective function
is find k cluster centers that minimizes the average distance between any point in it
cluster centre
the k means objective function is you find k cluster centers and minimize the square
of the average this
the average squared distance between points in cluster
so it's an objective function defined the distance based on the similarity function so given
OK you might find the cluster centers that maximize the average similarity of
object two
there are clusters at
that's so we really want we want to do is get the topics
so it's a little bit orthogonal but we want to do is to ask
how should the similarity function be related topic maps doing something with a similarity function
allows us to actually get the
to get the answer looking for
yes i'm going estimate there are some and think of the number of topics is
compared to this many clustering problems actually we have lots of little clusters like
comes up when you're trying to do disambiguation you know these three
things are all really the same thing in three and they think in a relatively
small number of topics fixed in advance and then a lot of objects so it's
like to be three labels for labels
and the question target how should the similarity function be related to the ground truth
to alaska
so i think in nice
the way to think about this is
imagine you want the algorithm the clusters of documents the way you would cost
but documents and you want them kind of clusters in some way
you know i do it yourself because too painful causes a million of them see
what i have now we do it
and you're going to hear the similarity function so how closely related that similarity function
have to be to what's in your hand about what you're thinking of was the
topic in order to have to allow the algorithm to do
you know the right thing
the resistance of the light bulb
i believe is twenty five
and half
is about two hundred and fifty ohms
you difference
so if the
this is right thing called resistance i would get
five and is
by the time the book hot would only get an and
so huge difference
what i want to show you
again with your service called
is the current
as a function of time
you switch on the lights
you would expect if law holds
you stress on the current
switched on the vault existence a
you see this
this is the new five mps
and then i will explain
first of all i here
that the voltage divided by the current remains constant
however what you're going to see is like this
current goes out
then the resistance goes down
then the resistance goes up and the current goes up the resistance goes up
and therefore the current will go down
and the level of an level which is substantially below this so you're looking very
at the breakdown
of the floor
so that's what i want to show you now
so we need to twenty five fold
and there's the light bulb
when i throw this switch
you will see
the pattern of the current versus time you won't see it once and then recreated
with your service
is often
so look closely now
get these little ripple that you see on it has to do with the way
that we
there was a hundred and twenty five vols
so you see horizontal time the time between two adjacent vertical lines
is twenty minutes seconds
so indeed very early on the current search story to very high value
and then the filament heats up
and sort of resistance goes up
the light bulb
the current just goes back again
from the far left
to the far right
on the screen is about two hundred millisecond
that's about two-tenths of a second
and you get the current levels
this is way lower
what you get there
that's breakdown
all of
it's actually very nice
that resistance is go up
libel when the temperature
goes up because supposedly the other way around
suppose you turn on the light bulb
and the resistance would go down libel got hot
resistance goes down that means the current goes up instead of down the current goes
that means it gets smaller
that means the resistance goes even further than that means the current goes even further
so what mean is that every time you turn on the light bulb it was
right in front of your eyes district itself
that's not happening
the other way around
so in a way it's fortunate
that the resistance goes up and the light bulb
all right
that's now
be a little bit more complicated
on some
networks of resistors
and we'll have
do were few problems like that
whereby we just assume naively
that small holes in other words we always assume that the values for the resistance
is that we you
will not change
so we will assume that the that is produced
i will not
play any important role
so we just use
on now
and if you can use it will be very
pacific about
i have here
three point eight
and point b
i have to resist this one
and r two
and suppose i apply a potential difference
between a and b
this class
this been minus the potential difference v
and you know v
it is known
will be
this resistance and i give you that one
i could ask you now
what is the current that is going to flow
i could also ask you then what is the potential difference over this resistance along
with call the one
what is the potential difference over the
second process was called to
very straightforward question
well you apply now owns law
and so between a and b there are two resistors in series
so the
because it has to go through both
and so the potential difference the
know is not the total current
times are positive
both these two resistors would say that the same length
same cross sectional area
people doing series you have twice the length
well so twice the length
remember resistance is linearly proportional with the length of the line
and so you add them up
so now you know i want you know are two
you know the
we already know the current
very simple
you can also apply only law
and was it holds
for this along
then you get he one
because i times
fifteen PSI
which is one atmosphere
so i've got one atmosphere here plus an extra atmospheres running at two atmospheres pressure
so that will raise the boiling point and stave off
the dangerous gas evolution
and i can do one more thing instead of running pure water i will add
ethylene glycol
o and ethylene glycol about fifty fifty
per volume you know this is anti-freeze
it gives the freezing point depression we'll talk about the next day
but also gives boiling point elevation so in the summertime you should always run with
anti-freeze because the combination of the pressure cap plus
the addition of the glycol raises the boiling point from two hundred twelve and talking
about cars somebody fahrenheit here two hundred twelve degrees fahrenheit to two hundred and sixty
five degrees fahrenheit
this buys you much higher question
so what are we doing were tailoring this by
making the boiling point of function of
pressure and now i'm showing you but it's also a function of composition
this whole business of
solid state stability i hope i'm showing you has a little bit more
two it then just looking up the
transformation temperature on the periodic table of the handbook so i want to talk to
the next three lectures about phase diagrams phase diagrams are atlases their maps their maps
of stability that answer the question if you specify
temperature is one of the stable phase
that's what you need to know so let's talk about phase diagrams
phase diagrams
as stability maps
stability maps stability of what the stability of the state of aggregation is going to
tell us if it's a solid liquid
and under what
circumstances so
let's look at some
simple phase diagrams forming do it i need to define some terms for you to
first of all it's defined the term phase the phase is a region of the
substance a region of a substance that has the following characteristics
and chemical composition
uniform and chemical composition
the second thing about it is that it's physically distinct
physically distinct now give you some rich examples i want to put this down just
to document and then after you see a few examples these words will mean some
pictures physically distinct and are in the extreme it's mechanically separable
this mechanically separable
physically distinct and mechanically set
so let's look at some examples of one face and two phase systems and you
this one of these days where we were using symbols to mean multiple
meanings of already used p to represent pressure if use p now to represent
number of phases you won't be able to tell one from the other side i
feel little bit western today so make it circle piece of circle p
equals the number
o phase is not to be confused with p
which is the pressure so number of phases i designated by circle p so let's
look at some
simple single
systems so let's look at people's one p equals one so how about pure water
pure water liquid
i have a beaker of water
it's a uniform chemical composition physically distinct mechanically separable about about like gold
white gold
why gold consists of an alloy of
certainly gold which we had silver we had no article
and these are all fcc metals and at the animalistic level you have them substituting
for one another on the gold lattice and so i have uniform chemical composition i
have no boundaries that could be grain boundaries but that's different but at the grain
boundaries do not represent something that is a difference in chemical composition so this is
this is pure
and this is a solution itself it's pure material or a solution
it will qualify as single phase
OK let's look so here's the liquid here's the solid let's look at a gas
about air
air is a solution of
our goal
increasingly sio two in the city when you get
coal-burning for electric power there's s o two
let's not forget our power nitrous oxide if you live near now call smelter you
have CF four if you live near magnesium smelter no chlorine but in cambridge mercifully
we just have to enjoy
these cells and this is all single phase you don't see
the gas settling according to density they mix intimately
in all proportions and one more solid
calcium zirconium
we talked about this before this is the line stabilized zirconia for oxygen sensors and
i'll show you later that this is the material that used for
the full diamond this is a solid solution calcium
i'm sitting on zirconium sites this single phase there's no calcium islands
calcium oxide ions are commonly marks site islands this is a solid
less than linear
OK the curvature flatten out OK what that means is that pointing to something that's
far away disproportionately faster than point to something that's nearby
because the the finger travels your hand travels
at a higher average speed the greater the distance
nothing happens if c
target is small
small terriers are disproportionately hard to point to
this see how the curve rise up as target size of what that means is
that if it's if the target is tiny it takes disproportionately long to point two
OK well profits worked this out as verified by a lot of experimental studies and
it turns out that there's this interesting quantitative formulas
he but
just had a battery failure
interesting quantitative relationship
people have made very heavy use of a very good chance that you hear mention
that this conference has
it's something very fundamental about when you give people
device to interact with the computer
especially when do we
he was the first thing that happened with graphical interface needed graphical pointing device turns
out the mouse is a good choice and
this is the
basic empirical fact that explains why the mouse is a good choice in many circumstances
but can be a terrible choice in other circumstances OK when the very first macintosh
appeared it did not have the cursor keys
OK only the mouse
right away about
i was amazed how painful was to get the cursor position between two periods
well first refusal do that very well because that's where the mouse does not work
if you want to zip around the screen point something here point something years and
here's something here
we're in this regime over here
i can be very fast and very efficient
so the mouse follows
properly designed mouse follows fitts law and that's why it works so well
very well for long used small targets can be a problem other devices and this
has been measured the classic card moran and newell book included some of this
work christakis are linear with the x and y distance so if you have to
go a long way diagonally across the screen they don't work well at all compared
to mouse trackball can be good but not better than agood mouse if you have
to stroke the trackball in different control regime
potentially much slower than the mouse if you don't have to struggle to be the
same thing joysticks can be very different because there's a lot of different ways of
controlling the position and velocity of the mouse depending on what you do the joystick
there's some control regimes that are very difficult to make
to use you often see those in computer games OK so
but is this point here is that he can be faster if you only need
a few keystrokes an important principle here mention these numbers more later is that this
is why well designed keyboard interface can still be very good
you even know people rarely bother with them these days there are
a certain user domains speed is important for symmetry once told me really like having
all keyboard interface for that reason
good idea because pretty by hand is actually relatively slow compared to the typical user
of the keyboard these days in the and about a quarter of the second right
hand writing a character can take credit along with an extremely good typists are remarkably
fast so the lesson to be learned from this immediately is that depend based interface
can have a lot of advantages but speed is not one of them compared to
americans i guess english people from england are used to the query keyboard
there's a lot of legends about the critic keyboard and there's a lot of basic
it lies and slanders and then made about shows the guy who invented the first
practical typewriter and accordingly
if you ask me i will be delighted to tell you about what i'll try
to write a paper about one of these days but what he was really trying
to do
and how that turned out to be the right answer is first typing speed even
though the time he did it nobody was touch typist
after i can see more also something that talking the whole resttime about the story
of you
what it shows is keyword turned up doing is taking advantage of the fact that
you can keys on alternating hands faster
then you can make use of the same name which is how your hands work