adapt nicely to data effectively using gradient descent heuristic will kind of obsessive lots of
stuff around you could also just sort of to bridge back to this morning's tutorial
no networks then fuzzy approaches use fuzzy rules to sort of visualizing all network has
structure that resembles that holds the parameters of the the fuzzy rule system in the
news network training algorithms thank you
the the the the rules and then data you can sometimes even extract the rules
again and try to understand them so there's a lot of work also been done
in this
this crossover between the two disciplines
this is the term for that soft computing sort of encompasses neural networks fuzzy logic
and evolutionary methods together
now arrests last section i would jump into fuzzy arithmetic fuzzy numbers just to give
you an idea what would you do if you actually going back to this example
of the insurance predictor if you wanted to use the fuzzy set not just fuzzy
he fuzzy hired and then we a crisp number describing risk but actually use that
to go into your fuzzy calculator and use degree this this membership function for risk
and then calculate what kind of premium the person is supposed to pay just having
some the rules in some some equations fuzzy patients is allow to solve all multiply
it by risk by about one hundred euro and then we have to build age
and sex factor and that results and that's what is going to pay per month
so fuzzy arithmetic may be useful
often nice also rule systems if you don't even have to precision to measure or
if you you get very imprecise inputs people just briefly look at someone to figure
out you know is a little bit overweight you don't want maybe if you have
life insurance company give people first quote you rough quote that even an idea it's
interesting to producer for for that person you're not going to ask him to step
on the scale and get the exact weight so the agent is just going to
say all little yes heavily overweight so you get fuzzy inputs into a rule system
so you want to be able to process these imprecise inputs without having the agent
actually sit down our he's and and twenty seven kilo right
you get all these bizarre numbers that are far from being true
so in order to do that you would need to be able to add or
multiply these imprecise concepts of numbers fuzzy numbers and even apply some functions normalisation or
others to fuzzy numbers
OK so that's what i'm trying to explain you in the next sort of twenty
but you
classical crisp will do the same game again you can describe the crisp numbers is
single simply say characteristic function for my number a small
should actually be down here is simply a characteristic function that you're one hundred only
one ball those effects that are precisely equal to a right so this is the
a fuzzy number is very similar to a fuzzy set the idea of about eight
understood about five minutes can also be a
and about is the same idea membership function that describes ball but numbers around eighty
still belong little bit to this has embraced again have a here let's say well
everything down to london minus two in a plus one also the nominal to our
concept of about about eight so we could now say well today's and what's outside
now before was maybe twenty five degrees i wouldn't claim that it was outside it
was twenty five degrees sharp service and is about twenty five degrees and you would
implicitly know
this zero degrees he doesn't that dumb but it was could be twenty three could
be twenty two could also be twenty six degrees so you you inherently have building
this idea of when i say it was about twenty five degrees outside you have
an idea what kind of fuzzy sets one be able to paint the exact membership
function but you know which numbers belong to my about twenty five degrees which don't
OK they difference that's why also this triangular membership function before usually fuzzy numbers are
normalised so you have these one point with the degree of membership of one
they're monotone so usually the membership function will just increase monotonix here decreased one to
right if you're caught and this in usually only have one point that has a
degree of membership once for this about otherwise more be a fuzzy interval right if
you had a plateau up here say well this is really more describing the concept
a fuzzy interval which you could also case so that's a fuzzy numbers
and then of course
the question is how do you eat to fuzzy numbers adding crisp numbers is simple
we go back to the original you have these two singletons for a and b
well that's the characteristic function for the addition of these two numbers the characteristic function
for a plus b
for any value but it's one
when z equals a plus b
only at this point is my characteristic function one and for every everything else it's
it's a very complicated way of writing it down but it makes it easier to
understand how fuzzy numbers can be added
well we could also write it differently and make it even more complicated all but
really doing is
if you want the characteristic function for a plus b
for arbitrary value of set for doing is we're going to look for all combinations
of x and y that you can plug into this being be look for the
but the degree of membership for a for this value x times the degree of
membership for b for this value wines under the constraint that x plus y equals
z so looking for all combinations of x and y that results were the some
results in that
so we have this principle of islam comes from
and then there looking for the degree of membership for this value
for for a whole whole this x to a part of this life to be
in multiply those and we'll deriving the next so the only time that this actually
works is when x equals a exactly a and y equals b then this
is fulfilled
and these actually non-zero otherwise products we get a one here we get a one
here eighty the here and set and then we get this one so this is
OK so
business like amazon netflix wal mart it's virtually this phenomenon with that pain this still
it's the short head and the long tail
and you have you of course he had about his apprentice lori eighty percent eighty
twenty rule
so not because of this web
and then people with the long tail is extended
so people is
based on this book chris anderson spoke
now it's possible for it to reach the long tail to get
more things so
for example how big
i don't know which bookstores do you visit usually
but as
definitely has the largest number of books you can find OK
i usually visit the borders
i would like to buy some over there as well
no comparison so
amazon i i can find a lot of books many books i have ever never
thought about
but because of collaborative filtering
you see
i don't know if we have this conspiracy i have to explain
i bought this book and i was recommended to some of the books than about
other books as well
this is about to like in the new
how can we make take advantage of this long tail
and the so wal-mart sells more long tail items in short head and it's it's
from that book not from us
and then the question is who are familiar strangers
we already talked about in the real world and but in the blogosphere
what we write
what you write is or what you are
OK so
have similar blogging behavior interests
the community games technology and politics et cetera but
but you never cited each other
we have some examples here
later also
this is not
returned as pop hits if we have many many these
bloggers familiar strangers but basically similar brothers there there but they are not connected
but the number is so small
people just don't want to study them
then what's the disadvantage disadvantages
you can not designed ads
probably relevant ads to so these people right
again at the end it's the number of clicks on one of the
popular models used steal the number of clicks
so the assumption is that
more relevant it is the more clicks are going to get
then we need to aggregate
these malicious in the long tail
i hope
i just want to mention this aggregating will help
a lot to these other
i want to work on this this is the exact example
we show you
like the blog is single block and these are the
it's irrelevant at
what's the disadvantage disadvantages if i'm bombarded with too many
i will be trained as a human being i will be trying to ignore all
so it's not a good idea to have
two frequently
many irrelevant that sometimes you have some irrelevant ones that's
that held
will help you to expand your interests right you buy this you also by something
else but not to
many irrelevant ones these now we have the definition these other examples like how do
we define familiar strangers
and for this problem
i just want to shoot the challenge we we we want to study OK and
then we have like partial strangers total strangers
and the but i we usually we want to study this total strangers
types of familiar strangers
these the examples
OK these other examples
you sense i'm rushing right i'm rushing because i want to move on to the
case study our the
convinced you that
there are familiar strangers
the blogsphere and
good idea to aggregate them
but there are challenges
to find them
it's not easy
these are the different types of familiar strangers
so challenges link analysis doesn't work OK
because some of them they're not they're not connected
so you know this is like a you search of the blog posts
do that that's one way
another way is is search via context
it is that you try to find one blog then you come back here the
head you've tried to make use of the short head short hair
people in the short of bloggers in the short head that well connected so you
hope that you could go back to them you can find
the relevant ones
so this is our approach
i suggest i come to work on
to work on this problem that idea is to use the collective wisdom
OK based on one person's
category clusters one person scalar clusters on the left-hand side
we try to use this collective wisdom
use the collective wisdom what's the collective wisdom
collective wisdom is user-generated content
and then we will
try to find relevant categories and we search
so this actually is the nexus the next to kansas case studies called employing collective
however as i said
i find
proper is more interesting and so we go will visit i find the first
and then we come back to
employing collective wisdom if we have time
so i find
basically identifying influential bloggers IN a community
so this is the part of the book presented at conference this year and the
video is also available online
by the same darkness
so you can actually go to the site and you can find
full of presentation there also
because this in any way you have to buy a of camera
the following year
the term for the story in red cross
the theory in the fall for a moment before both states in eastern european country
something of interest to intelligence analysts
trivia country
so some things about a lot about but some things
dummy reversal
i don't even know what that is
not done the reverse dummy
dummy hoy
there's not very nice to name from william hoyt w
w w it's another card game so now we know that someone was working on
cards in dummy companies but not only was one of the universe
so not comprehensive of respect kagame's ridiculous ridiculously heavy coverage nevertheless someone else
o side of things like this is some sort recessive
and so on and so convolution
just inside
in the project
they type of interactive program is kind of vision programme which isn't actually true anymore
i was great that
it's it's interesting that is inadequately represented as well as and i found out
tutorial listen conceptual work that's the one we are after
the trio
tutorial distance so better represented the only because we were foolish enough not to use
this interface search for it
this to to this tutorial here is a information during things was not be of
into the tutorial is the actual tutorial the contents of the tutorial the time producing
it's sort of tory was document some l i think the other one
is there
toy on this
know that
so that's a different types of this tutorial what i'm doing now
is that type of it to listen
o thirty tissues
i've organised as constituent type of inference spatial stuff like thing so again
these things sound ridiculous but there really
useful you can do inference as you can tell
because of this for example that you can count on
in two pieces of minutes till the bone marrow
tell all that stuff about
as an instance of men are some bone marrow side is about
is that
yes so when you hover over anything in here
do you think of a more challenging medical term
how do you spell out
well we have some reasons but we don't have that one
the call the oncology department is not your home board
during going somebody for cardiothoracic surgery
always a year
there are no i wouldn't be surprised if every reason school
so joke the conceptual work
so that's the joke itself the idea of the talk this particular joke here three
civilians into a day after shop
you know whenever i tell that there is the information bearing thing so if i
write down a
a basis for
the atom-pair and this is diamond cubic so diamond cubic is the crystal structure but
it's derived from an FCC lattice so again the the overarching theme here is the
integral of the brevity lattice this is a set of points right this is the
point set points set in 3 space the brevity lattice and then what you put
at each point gives you the crystal structure and you can go on and on
and on because of distance
all here this is show you into space is an integer print is the dogs
so what's the crystal structure here
so let's start looking might go 1 2 3 4 5 you might say well
this looks like a simple the face centered cubic actually face centered by centered the
same into space right
the body is
the how describe a sponge into space
think about it OK the trouble is this facing in the other direction so that
will work
instead all these dogs facing the same way enough you look carefully taken as the
basis see those those could be lattice points the brevity lattice is the red dots
are the basis is the set of for dogs the 2 facing the right and
these 2 facing the now to right to left to right to left so it's
the 4 dogs set
both for dogs are the basis of bingo so now we have we have simple
cubic is STP simple cubic puppy that's into space and I go to this 1
I put the dot here on the abdomen of this
creature of OK so we we know that this is a problem for some of
you might initially have called this the triangle
but you see that when you put the 2 together this has translational symmetry and
in fact look at how many of these entities belong to that lattice point all
of this all of this all this because the tail to this is up here
so the repeat doesn't start until down here you could cut it this way I
don't care but the point is that this is the concept of the basis the
basis is many many units that are repeatable and can be positioned at each lattice
so now what I wanna do is talk a little bit more about that cubic
system because we're focused on cubic system in 309 1 largely because it has a
simple geometry most of the periodic table you find is in fact cubic system FCC
your BCC and the math simple because you can in accordance Cartesian coordinates so let's
take a look at that what we've got all force here
at the properties of cubic crystals so here we are this is a table your
lecture notes and a lot of work through this table I urge you to get
our friendly comparable with this table so that you understand the properties of white and
making you learn this stuff because I think it stands to reason that if you
look in this crystal you see that atoms touch certain directions and Adams the far
apart along other directions while we've already seen in 309 1 that there is a
correlation between atomic contact and bonding
and bonding is related to a whole host of other properties for example mechanical strength
the people in this room think about the mechanical engineers aero astro engineers nuclear engineers
you need to understand the relationship between the crystal structure and the strength of the
material obviously if I look down and Adam direction for look down on direction rather
high density of atoms that's going to be a directions of straight if I look
down direction has a low population of atoms that's going to be a directional weakness
subsequently if I wanna cleaver crystal then where my going clean
I have to understand crystallography the electrical properties the optical properties
what's the index of refraction is the bending of light in response to the field
set up by the bonds
so in order not to electronics you better know this stuff everybody has to know
this stuff because chemistry is central and it's all chemistry
this conversation is brought to you by secondary bonding in the fall it so let's
look at this 1 in some detail and wanted to 1st of all is the
unit cell let's look at the unit cell
so here's FCC face centered cubic so there's lattice and uses a hard sphere model
so I wanna make this the atoms so big that they actually touch belong there
axis of contacts or face centered cubic the atoms touch along that face diagonal and
the unit cell this is called the unit cell this is the repeat unit
this is the unit cell is that which repeats in free space and fills 3
space it's it's that it's the basic unit of the crystal system and the edge
of the unit cell is given by the dimension of a
so the edge of the unit cell this is the cube so it's all the
same so the volume of the unit cell is equal to a cube that's trivial
so we get that all last points 4 unit cell last points unit cell let's
look at them
let's look at this
this red 1 comedy lattice points while we can count lattice was becoming Adams if
you see there's a corner atoms and how much of each of those corner atoms
lies within the bounds of this unit cell
this 108
In case so lattice lattice points
per unit cells
per unit cell is going to equal 8 times 1 8 this is the corners
this is the corners and then we got the space at the time Sunday is
1 and you see these blue ones these blue ones are half inside this unit
cell and half inside the adjacent units only about 1 2 3 4 5 6
of them
2 in this direction 3 principal directions and 2 times so that's 6 times 1
half which is this is the face atoms and incurring 6 times ahead of is
3 3 . 1 is 4 so I have effectively for
lattice points for yourself financing atoms because I could replace each of these single atoms
with methane molecules of 5 atoms 4 points that's on being a little bit festivities
here lattice points per unit cell
what else are we looking at whole number article nearest neighbor distance one nearest neighbor
distance that's that's kind obvious this here there's a there's a drawing this is a
this is and that distances the root 2 times a and this is half of
route to so
that's given here a over route to nearest neighbors well you can see that nearest
neighbors let's count from this 1 is that for at the corners right and it's
. 3 in this plane 3 in other points so that's going to add up
to 4
+ 4 plus 4 is nearest neighbors is equal to 12 some people call this
the coordination number coordination number and this has got the highest this got the highest
number of nearest neighbors when you have hard spheres of equal dimensions of any of
crystal system you can see here body centered cubic and has 8 nearest neighbors were
simple cubic only has 6 nearest neighbors
of silicon anymore
and then the packing density of history the packing density that's an interesting calculation but
the packing density indicates is how much going back to democracy if we model
this and was the first is
his wife and son little reasoning on the
so you can see
it was also
the conjunction
you want to
i'm relationship is that this for the thing to find in this view
is the class of top
so each of these alternatives to find an axiomatic relationship between the function class expressions
as with these are here because expression can be assembled
if you want to see how this works in other formats which you can easily
so most of these are the formats have some
not all
and so on
o also
so we're trying to figure out how to relate
throughout the particular
o on the season one
this is very
and also see the RDF
sure in the functional syntax two pieces of
so far
are some
so we think that this is
all necessary sufficient conditions in
and all you know they want one is
more than a year
so this is the only one this
complete here is exactly the same
you notice that hyperlinks in all these views are long so you can navigate in
any of the views involved
so the architects inside
the ontology of the work they do
i think
for short
so my
materials in one nice thing that we're not very non neutral view is that because
the contracts themselves are represented by regularisation
i think this is well
and you can click on them so
it's a good way to start with and that will take you to some help
text from taken from the album
which is again i was struck
understand that some of
so that's what i'm going to stick concise
the other thing to do
so in the morning at the top level
you can pop up
so so
we know which classes have properties of functional reason can hyperlink from this is two
kinds of links here one is the direct link which takes you to the definition
of the term
the other one
sixty eventually takes it is sufficient to nest into which doesn't have very much you
know the one is cultural references
this also shows if you
options right click
but actually paying you can see
the references in the references at every
four property that has the maximum makes use of this
so in this case
the thing that i was looking for the references four was has gender
there are four
he asked and this is really useful for
actually there is no but also for just taking
has to take
prince was able to debug difficult
come on the absence of
we have to discover that
one of the whole
these are exactly what they are doing it right so here
pop up the show a public assurance i can go i can see
has gender is used to define
since so LC three dollars is defined gender male students fifteen authorities to define
his children
so is no
you know
obviously also to define male in general
it's also define animal which is a little bit we're right
but i guess there were going to go
is that
are already on the
i just want
in these two
a big you compare between them you'll notice that here we have
who knows one
you only have one and you look at the particular instantiations male and female you'll
see that he just using its essentially you know the better
you want
you can see on the right
five try five to
give him
another gender
some public from
you don't need to follow this yet
time the product of the transition
f of x given xk minus one is the markov
so i'm basically the likelihood
one of the of salvation
which is part of g of white jaguar x XK OK
these guys
is simply the normalise target distribution in this context which have called before
in the more general context as gamma and x one x two x so let's
apply this essentially agrees amidst see very specific context so in a very specific context
at so
so as to approximate the sequence of facilities solutions for the latent state given the
acceleration at time warner so-called
capital and particle according to q one of two want to be made dependent on
the first of salvation you collected you can do that not part of your reweighted
particle OK
o ninety six but in this scenario the normalized target
distribution time one is simply the joint distribution of x one y one so this
is initial point of x what time the conditional distribution of y given x y
w divided by the
importance weights
your so called turbulent times
from the associated weighted empirical measure of the approximation was still distribution of x one
y one
that the following time index
when you have time and basically
new song paul x the components and according to conditional distributions
which can you may depend on y or x and minus one typically we tried
to basically
use for this conditional distribution
the posterior distribution of xn given y and x minus one and the target distribution
it's possible to be better
you compute the associated
basically importance weights
of the city and the importance weight in this case this is the ratio of
the successive normalise target distribution divided by the importance distribution but because of the specific
structure of the target distribution support OK when you do gamma x one x two
xn divided by gamma
n minus one x one x two x minus one the only time the remains
of the essentially the point here
the transition point from x amount of one to extend and the conditional distribution of
y given x and you write
you are basically an approximation of the conquest
as the weight of correctly measure if you want your sample basically capital in times
to obtain new particles approximately distributed according to the time
so let's see on twenty on to kind of get an idea was that it
works well i'm going to call could simple algorithm a simple case where i know
what forces OK
so i'm considering a simple in the sense that they
so it's really important for autoregressive gaussian process europe's xn in some notion of
so in this case
you know to join the facilities solution of the first lady during because of salvation
is gaussian
on these parameters can be computed using kalman type techniques OK so in particular
the marginal distribution of x and y one y two y is basically the kalman
basically i know what's the global truce in this case
i'm gonna compare one proves to essentially
particle algorithm the SMC sequential monte carlo methods so what do i need to define
basically to my multicolour well the only degree of freedom i have now is the
distribution i use so as to sample the state and extend time
i believe the so basically what i'm gonna do i'm just going to solve paul
xn and according to its publisher while OK very simple important is to generate per
CPU can always
so i use my glory
OK i'm not going to have a look at what's going on so
the figures they have been provided by only the capital feel so they are using
his book you are not of model that was published by springer in two thousand
five so
what i'm going to present here
he's basically what's going on a few times that when you're running those particles categories
first let's start let's go bowling together at the top to stop just look at
what's happening here at the bottom so i time basically
at the initial time index is important particle x one
on your way down
your resource pool
basically the particle that survived or some things that are propagated basically using
the condition part my scenario because i use that is in part of the solution
so what happens is basically
among all the particles that have been sampled at time warner
because some of them have been survived there are some things that were some of
the some of us have admitted offspring
then basically
you have quite a few that died on the essentially what you have is that
you have a particle approximation
of the joint distribution of x one and x two given y one y two
OK on each particles some on the real correspond to this by disguising you've line
basically indicating this is the passed x one x two OK
so you have capital and of them
those past here
basically you have in your acceleration coming
we weighted by the importance weight your for capital n times form the weighted empirical
so obviously some of them are going to die some of some of those are
gonna basically in every multiple copies on they can be propagated for
that basically positive sort
so let's say this is what's happening
when i'm at time so in this case twenty four OK so what you have
these guys corresponds essentially this
they correspond to
there description
of all the particles
that have been sampled in the joint space x one x two x twenty four
so what you see
is that
essentially what happened because of the successive resampling step where their first initiative first components
from time
i want to in this case then they all similar
OK so some are because of that they should all or some things that you've
introduced basically
their own sister that have coalesced this was quite sense like in that basically genetics
on essentially they all have the same on sisters this is due to essentially success
equal to infinity
for all
other vertices for all vertices not equal to us
but less
now we have to cheque that this inequality holds well we have delta as common
as we've already argued that that's zero
because you can get negative when are only
nonnegative edge weights so that's the best so certainly zero is greater than equal to
and we have everything else well
delta of
comm is certainly less than or equal to infinity so this holds everything is less
wrinkle to infinity
this case is that so now we do induction
and i'm going to write it is a proof by contradiction
so let's say i suppose
the this fails to hold at some point
so suppose for a contradiction that the invariance is violated
so we'd like to sue the violator and find a contradiction so it's going to
be violated so let's look at the first violation the first violin
so this is essentially going proof by induction
so let's say
we have some violation
is less than delta company that would be bad for somehow can estimate smaller than
the shortest path
and i think about looking first violations we know sorted by induction that all previous
all other values are correct
of is the first one where rick schroder
so the very holds everywhere else
well what cause this to fail this with this invariance is violated is some relaxation
OK on DVD so we have indeed we we replace it with some
the idea of you
the weight of the edge from u to v
so how this made it
OK so
so dv
is now somehow less than this we just said the to this
so this thing
this must be less than
delta best comedy
claim is that that's not possible
that's that's me write a little bit
we have dw
plus w b
we have our induction hypothesis which holds on you use some other vertex we know
the diffuse at least delta that's coming you
this has to be at least
delta s come you
plus w w
now what about this w comedy well that some path
from unity
OK so
it's got to be
bigger than the shortest path or equal
certainly this is critical to delta
view comedy
they can be larger there's some multi edge path that has smaller totally
but is certainly
no smaller
then delta if you come to the
and this looks like a good
summation delta s t u and u two v
trying to inequality
so this is upside down here but the trial s t u to be
so this is only longer than rest to be
OK so so we have this thing which is simultaneously greater than or equal to
the shortest path way from us to be and also strictly less than the shortest
path weight from s to v so that's a contradiction
maybe contradiction isn't the most intuitive way to proceed the intuition here
you know whenever is assigned that dv you have path in mind you are inductively
had path from s to u when you this and so that was the real
perhaps it should be no
we always know that every path has weight greater equal to the shortest path so
it should be true and here's the
inductive proof
moving right along this is easy warm-up
great article to now we have to prove less than or equal to at the
end of the album and this is true all the time less recall two will
only be true
we can improve
a single two quite yet proven another lemma
which again
so both of these lemmas are useful for other algorithms to so we're sort of
building some
shortest path theory that we can apply later
this one will give you some intuition about why relaxation
no it's not only is it not bad there actually good
not only does it not screw up anything but also makes good progress
in the following sense
you know the shortest path from s to some vertex
OK so you know forrester summarises in your view then you gotta be suppose that
is a shortest
from s to v
and also suppose
that we already know
india view the shortest path weights from s to u suppose we have this equality
we now know that we always have a great article two suppose to equal for
OK the vertex just before b
in the shortest path
OK i suppose
we relax the edge u v
which is exactly
this stuff
this is relaxing the edge u v died in discoloured relaxation here
then after the relaxation
d of e equals
delta s so we had the correct answer for you we relax u b
suppose i just
i have employees and because of hundred
but i got that would just
two variables
ninety eight constraints
and generating these things randomly so now i can do this i can plot
i get a right
ninety eight have these things that are
ninety eight them that's the intersection always
now i chose those few lines of code that they didn't explain to in such
a way that i know that there is a feasible solution so the intersection of
all these things is not the empty set it's something here let's say this
well you can see even though i've drawn ninety eight
half planes
my polygon the just here only has four vertices
so it's probably very easy to solve so i think when you when you are
more than a small and the other one is large it's probably fundamentally much easier
than when they are both about the same size
and so my little experiment was was
the interesting to me i never realized
that makes a big difference and so then it differently
i plotted
against the minimum
the sea
since there seem to be the more relevant measure of if the minimum is small
it's an easy problem and so let's just say it's a small problem with the
anyway so plotting with them men now it looks like a really captured what's going
on here
and so i plotted these points under regression here and i get that approximately the number of iterations approximately two-thirds
times the minimum and raise the four-thirds power now what these two-thirds of authors are
actually fundamentally the truth i don't know
it seems kind of
compelling because point six eight or six nine
pretty close to two-thirds one point three three four so i don't know maybe is
that just like i only this experiment wants but i do with a couple thousand
i don't know
open question
if that's true theorem that's very interesting but i don't know
here i just plotted on i a logarithmic plot plot of linearly
it is so you can see that it doesn't it doesn't look like it's not power one does
look like it's growing
with some power higher than one such as four-thirds here
so you can
and this was important to me because i actually thought that this power was gonna be one
and so the fact that it's a little bit more than one
surprises me
but it looks like it
least in the way of generating these random problems
it looks like it's real
and i think the way generate a random problems is fairly the german
okay well i also made ample model which may be in the interest of time i'll skip this is
coding is other language i like
that does the same thing also fits into pages so it's not
and you can download the sample code if you like
all right now
and now worst-case and average-case analysis so the simplex methods for the time being
talk about
another topic that's really a fundamental
duality theory end
this is really why
linear programming
is a fundamentally important
well okay there's two reasons why the approach things from an important one
there's lot a real world examples
describe some to you
o and later
from a practical point of view
lots of examples but mathematicians
theorists are also interested in linear programming because there's some very fundamental
ideas here and it's called duality
and so
and this tells us this gonna tell us a lot it's going and former are are newer
versions of the simplex method it's going to inform us and how to derive other
variants and gets in the three point five algorithm
so every problem has a dual
this is our primal problem in standard form
the dual
this is that is a minimization problem
right hand side becomes the objective coefficients
the objective coefficients in the primal become the right hand side
the constraint matrix and its transpose so are here i had em constraints and and
variables here i and constraints and and variables
we just introduce another dummy later why for the dual variables
so here it is it looks very much like this except for t greater than
or equal to constraints and it's a minimization but other than than it looks very
much like the primal problem in fact if
the fact that these two look very much alike is really why
i preferred to uh to
to start with problems in this form
which is at
we edit just as in this in this decision i diverge from many other r
standard textbooks but i think the reason is that is that there is a beautiful
symmetry when you do it this way
the original problem
it's called the primal problem
the problem is defined by its data
and so we have an maybe and see that really define the problem
and the dual problem has the same data
but using a different way
and actually if we write the dual problem
it's standard form so i convert the max the minimize to maximize how do i do there
minimizer function what take its negative and then maximise it and then you're you're done
negate that again so i maximize minus be transposed why
and i said that you gave my answer
i want less than or equal to constraints to be in standard form how do
i do now is multiply both sides this article quality minus one i like this
so now we see that
the the the the
o typo
i never noticed this type
response to be a transpose and they matrix right there
the dual problem is
simply the negative transposable the primal problem
in fact a few
look in the dictionary right the
really looks like the negative transpose because the sea is here and the these here in the eighties
those are the original and the bees here this is here and it is here
think about is just one big matrix and take its transpose the being the sea
get switched
but do
you'd have some over
to that end which is to the one thousand
and to the one thousand
let's put it this way imagine that you had access to all the electrons in the universe
this tend be eighty
electrons in the universe
imagine that you managed to turn everyone those electrons in a powerful computer
and they can do operations
that you have in the universe to do it in
is actually due to ninety eight sentence
so this is
two thousand two hundred sixty six
so if you have every single electron in the universe seems to be still you're
doing operation and repeats the whole eight universe do
multiply those to invite travel and see how many
operations you can do the job
the biggest international efforts to two hundred sixty four
so you can't some
o all states of the enlightenment and an exhaustive enumeration even with
universe of supercomputers
so you can't do this even though
energy is a very simple thing
right at the same time you can do it by exhaustive enumeration
so that's one thing you might want to know anything you might want to know
what you know this is what's the fluctuations in its energy so you might want
to the variance reality work really well know the average energy per square that nobody
what the variance
fluctuations are interesting thing know
so you might want to know
you might want to know what the mean
the magnetic
or you might want to know what the variance it's like citations so define the magnetisation in some way
function to invent it
i'm interested in knowing its meaning or its variants
you might want to know
the entropy of yours that's the average
one over
you might also want to know
the normalizing constant
he said that this is very exciting you don't have the
bayesian inference about that
this is z
the log
is essentially free energy
the free energy fantastic things that you want to know in order to understand
all sorts properties
things like cities as well
i can all be expressed
in terms of x expectations and you anything on this list that can be expressed is log z
which is an expectation is normalizing constant
and that's got a lot
well this is roughly the average energy that
that's the second example
the problem is that all the we have
probability distribution
it can be written in lines and energy
energy can be evaluated and at any x quite easily it's easy that the entire
distribution itself difference thing work because you
give you and so
what article states
promising samples show me ten random samples this
what you can say well i don't know how to draw
ten random samples from this distribution
one thing to note is we want to solve the problem of
so problems
the interest
solve problem to
which is you know these expected values of things you don't actually have to solve problem
but if you have solved problem and then you can use them as a way of solving problems
if you want problem to have
be solved
problem is solved
gives you
some points
usually with that of a random sample
they give you a set
which do
really come from the distribution because you have small problem one
you can
expectations are functions for example if someone says what is the average value of
on the
so want to know this
the expected value
can be estimated by saying
well i'm gonna write down
just talked
several points that you've just given in the training set
i'm see what the main event is
on the
empirical distribution
that means that any functions
i can just take you are random points that you make
and i can be estimated their expectations
using those are points
the figure are is
the better the estimate will be
the closer they will be the true value
the expectation
solutions so therefore it's all one face now let's contrast that something that's to face
to get a sense of what the differences so instead of pure water just liquid
suppose i have i skewed
iswc cubes in water
iswc tubes in water it's still pure i didn't change the composition but i've got
two different states
i've got two different states i've got a solid state in liquid state and this
fits the
fits the definition in other words the ice floating in the water is uniform
in chemical composition and it's physically distinct or i can say i can put boundary
around it and i can isolate all the ice cubes and in fact these are
mechanically separable i could pull out all the ice cubes and be left with only
k solid and liquid two different faces because they're are two different states of the
same material i think we also looked at milk
we looked at mill
and milk as fat globules
aqueous phase
in aqueous solution right so
i've got fat globules they're very tiny they scatter light but if we got down
to the micro level we could find these globules as something that's mechanically separable physically
the state and of uniform composition in different from this so this is two different
phases because we have two different compositions
we have two different compositions
and lastly
there was vision
the visions where the piracy around the piracy around that was the glass ceramic
the glass ceramic it's ninety five percent crystal and five percent glassy so what you
have here is you have a glassy phase
and crystallin
crystalline precipitates
OK so again we don't ever change in composition but we have the change in
order in atomic order so the glassy phase and the david five days so we
can actually draw boundaries around all the crystalline precipitate so i hope this gives you
a sense of what what's going on here the second thing is that this phase
diagrams are drawn under conditions called equilibrium
that's why we talk about stability so let's define
equilibrium is the condition
which represents the lowest energy state of the system
the lowest energy state
richard you take all of the constituents and give them infinite time and the energy
they need to achieve the lowest energy state this is where they will get two
and we'll know that it's the equilibrium state because the properties are invariant properties are
invariant with time this sort of like a steady state but steady state is something
that could be sort of locked in on the road to stability so this is
the ultimate stability as contrasted with metastability
metastability is
something that steady state but could get
stabler you have an example of metastability is diamond
which is not the stable form of carbon with temperature but diamond was formed under
different conditions and then brought under ambient pressure and temperature but the activation energy to
convert is so high that it stays apparently
stable but in point of fact its metastable another one is metallic glass
the italic we know the metallic glass was formed under
hi quench rates if you take the tower glass and heated
you're given sufficient activation energy to then jumps
from this glassy states of the crystal in state and ultimately achieve its its equilibrium
so those are examples of this
equilibrium metastability and the last thing i notice i talked about pure materials and then
multicomponent materials they have different
elements that are mixed and so we need to counter a metric that details what
the level of chemical complexity is and for that we call in to play
the local
maximum correspond to any of the locations of the chairs here
just all over the place but it can even get close to
one of the things that people have stopped doing at the beginning was OK this
promise to hire let's simplify so instead of trying to the genetic images with genetic
of just less work with simple world let's the block walls in which we have
found a mathematical models that explain absolutely everything that goes on in the image and
try to organize the objective that here simple blocks
of course this
it has the problem that doesn't really get to five cannot do other things with
a big family of different models for object recognition appeared in the literature and here
i'm just
clustering them into five families by the war models in which just a distance of
an object and the representation just like above words like what is typically done in
a language modeling in some models for language
you forget all the special locations that to become family of object models or the
models are based on both in the that many many different small pieces of objects
and each one is going to vote for one of the centre for an object
then you have shape matching in which
you have a germ of an object is shape and you are trying to find
instances of the shape on image and just apply smaller formations to the shape until
if it's what you can see on the image
the constellation models in which you have a few parts is similar to the voting
models in some cases but generally have very few but not many many just a
few of them
and you have a very costly model how these parts relate to each other and
to try to protect them on images and then attempt models that is a little
bit like the game of the chair in which you just have a fixed played
juvenile for the formations and you just apply scanning just kind of normalized correlation
and if you do it on the right feature space it may have to work
quite well
do it directly on the pixel intensities it doesn't work very well for genetic up
just four faces can mahler's work a little bit
so all these models got really a big push when people manage to solve basically
the face detection problems
and so
people have been working on for the vision for a long time and this classifier
based models have been extremely successful detecting faces so here just one typical database of
examples of faces generally frontal faces and these are some examples of of is the
and people have been working for this for a very long time and it's been
just and only thousand in which people actually managed to build systems that will work
in real time and they are quite successful at this task but this kind confession
because when you look at this image is all these faces the only one to
be detected that's the only one the only thing they want their competitive looking at
the picture they should be easy easy to detect and he has taken so long
to detect them but not now
there are commercial products that combine the use face detection
and they were pretty well so you have a camera with a face detection
unit cite them is going to use it in order to do a focus
and automatic focus selection and so on and light
and they work pretty well there are very few false alarms so most of the
time they were the the faces in work pretty well
so one of the few set for systems that bannister to solve this problem very
efficiently was the one interview by viola jones
in which the trick was the one two important contributions one must adjust very simple
features those were rectangles of based rectangles which can be computed very efficiently with only
four operations independently of the size of the rectangle and also the use of the
cascade which is you were going to play a set of different classifiers it's one
more and more selective
so that at the beginning to have a classifier that is very cheap but to
get rid of model most of the background and then play another five it's more
expensive but only apply to the locations good that still good candidates to contain the
face and the idea was also interviewed by florida and argument
at the same time
in which they also had this cascade of decisions
so that made the system to be extremely efficient so you could detect faces in
the right
which make it available which make it possible to develop the is this and commercial
then for generic objects of course this simple rectangles with just based on intensities they
don't work very well for generic objects
then all of the features that are very powerful like edges
and again there are a lot of different families of
classifiers based on edges
for instance that is this war by capillary
in nineteen nine in which they will use global silhouettes of objects and they will
do again template matching by doing by correlating the template with
with an edge extracted from the image
and that's my extracted from the image
and instead of just using just a single template they will have a family of
this block here is the set of virtual addresses the set of physical addresses the
correspond to the virtual addresses in a space that day
these are the only physical addresses they can talk about so if we for example
have different blocks
memory addresses the correspond to virtual addresses the beacon reference we can see that there
is no way for a proper model a to be able to reference some of
the members for any of the memory the users were able to totally separate physical
memory pieces of physical memory to a and b and talked about by into posing
this by by using this page map mechanism the virtual memory gives us
what we want so basically what we've done is we've sort of added this extra
layer of interaction with virtual memory system that is it look they gets too
gets to map virtual addresses into physical addresses
so the rest this lecture is really going to be details about how we actually
make this work but how we do things like how we actually
decide when to change the how how we decide to change this how we assign
the speed this email register based on which one of the modules is currently executing
about things like what the format of this page that people can look like so
this is this is really the key concept
if you think
so what i want to do now is returned to the first question is the
second question i asked which is what it how does this page thing actually work
what does it actually look how how is actually representing so one very simple representation
of the page map might be that it's simply is a pointer to the page
map just says where his memory begins on the processor
right so it's just one value it is memory begins at this location in the
physical memory and all
the virtual addresses should be resolved relative to to this beginning location memory
the problem with the problem with that representation is that it is not very flexible
so for example it means that supposed has both a and b
are suppose there's a third process that third model c
which is laid out in memory very right right next to it so it's storage
is is placed right next to a memory and now suppose that a wants to
allocate some additional memory can use now in order to do that work it with
its if if these virtual drive if the graph is simply a single point at
the beginning of these address space are kind of trouble we can just add memory
on the bottom because then we would overlap sees
we had overlaps c so we're going after to to remove all of these memory
around in order to be able to make space for this is that the same
like a little bit problematic to simply have a pointer thing we could do is
that we get suppose we could instead have different option where we could say
for example for every virtual address in in eighties address space so for each
thirty two bit for each thirty two to be value that it wants to resolve
there might be an entry in this page map table right so we can for
every thirty two bit virtual address to the corresponding thirty two bit physical address and
they're just be a one-to-one mapping between all these things have a good reference a
million box in memory there would be in a million entries in this page table
and so
if you think about this for that sounds like kind of a bad idea too
because now these tables are totally huge right in fact there is almost as big
as are there is because the memory itself right because have a million entries in
the table if it can reference million blocks that i many million entries in the
table so the table becomes just as big as the memory itself so we need
some in between sort of alternative hybrid between these two extremes
and the idea is again a very simple and you are of six were four
so the idea is to
take this thirty two bit virtual address
so i suppose this is a thirty two bit virtual address now we're going to
do is we're going to split up into two pieces
a page number
and offset
according to some size for these two things for now i'll just arbitrarily twenty to
twenty billion page number and a twelve bit offset
OK so
what this page so what this is going to do with so now we're going
to do is instead of storing a single
a single word of memory at each entry in this table restora page of memory
that each entry in this table so
so this table is going to look like a mapping between page
and the physical address
OK so what pages so if so if the page number is twenty bits long
then that means that the each page is going to be
two to twelve bits b
which is all to say four thousand ninety six
so the idea is that we're going to have
two twenty pages within each address space and
each page is going to map to one of these four thousand ninety six bytes
we have our memory here
this is this page the page one is gonna map into some physical address
page two
is gonna map into some other
physical block so each one of these things is now
four thousand ninety six bytes
each block here
just expanded so this is now page
and this offset this twelve offset is going to be used in order to look
up the word we want actually look up this page
so if
the if the if the virtual address is say for example page one
offset zero what that's going to do is we're going to look in pay when
you look up on the page map we're going to find the page number that
corresponds to
we're find page number one we find physical address that corresponds to it or come
down here and look in the physical address and look at this block of memory
and then within this four thousand ninety six block memory we're going to take the
addresses are all the time the first world within that thing
i can give it any random
the phase angle delta
and that would then be
y direction
so clearly
this satisfies
the wave equation
because it's
separately it satisfies the wave equation
it's not only evaluate delta equals zero
you still have linearly polarized radiation
look at the x y plane
this is x
and this is why the radiation is coming straight to you
at a certain moment in time
he factor in this direction reaches a maximum
he zero x
and that is
if delta is zero that's the moment in time that effective in the y direction
also reaches a maximum because delta is zero
this one is zero why
course at the same moment is that one
so what is the net effect that is the vectorial some of the two
so in effect or
is this
this is the total
which is the square root
one of zero x squared
plus are widespread
and if you
c is coming to you
using an electric field going like this shift linearly polarized
no longer linearly polarized in the x direction no longer in the y direction but
in this direction
i can also
make the phase angle between the two
ninety degrees
so i could make delta
by over two
now you get something very interesting
so this is no x
and this is no wise for the the radiation comes to x crosswise in new
and i think a moment in time
the zero x is maximum here
this is the factor
zero x but now is zero why
effective in the y direction is now zero
because they are ninety degrees out of phase
so therefore
this one which is the maximum this one is zero
a quarter period later
this one becomes zero
you have you y
according to period later this one is back to zero
and now this one
and the quarter period later this one is again zero
and this one
so now what you're going to see
there's never a moment
the vector
e vector rotates around in an ellipse
it goes like so
like so
and so on
so it rotates around like this
and we call that
electrically polarized radiation
there's nothing very special about it is the perfect solution to maxwell's equations
you have
one component in the x direction and not in the y direction offset by ninety
degrees you can choose this angle any value you want
he zero x is the same as easier y
that's the circle
and then we call it circularly polarized radiation
in this case
going clockwise but of course
if you make delta minus by over two it will go counter-clockwise
i thought there was question
now suppose you were asked to calculate the associated field
that's a piece of cake
because you just follow
these simple rules
you take the component in the x direction you calculate the associated travelling wave in
in b
and then you do for the y direction
you calculate associated
travelling by the way if you add them up
that gives you then
in b
so this situation is
and simple
in two d
but i think i o u
a more general description
to white in your
and i want to go at least in terms of the
math going three d
so we now have XYZ coordinate system
we want
the option of having effect or not just in the x y plane or not
in the xy plane
but in a random
and so when we do that
we now get the vector
as a function of r and t
and r is the vector in space
which is x
x roof
that's why
why rules
this zero for any position vector in space you prefer
now i get this is the zero
it is now vector it's not the actual y or and see it is in
by at least approximately three meters per second
three meters per second
that means seven miles per hour
and so to a billion people
will go around like crazy
in that
and that's exactly
what happens
in the dream
and i'll show you here
picture from the book
mister punc is always in pyjamas just to remind you that is dream
need to say to professors are very old man has a very nice b
as the prestige
another each year from this book
i read you very short
paragraph that deals with this
professor says
look here
i'm going to port
definitely meets on the position of this ball by putting it inside
a wooden triangle
as soon as the ball was placed
in the enclosure
of the whole inside of the triangle became filled up with glaring of ivory
she said professor
i define the position of the ball
to the extent of the dimensions of the triangle
this results
in considerable uncertainty in the velocity
and the ball is moving rapidly inside the boundary
can to stop it
as mister tompkins
it is physically
anybody in an enclosed space possesses certain motion
we physicists call it's zero point motion
such as for example
the motion
the of electrons
in any at all
so here you see
quantum mechanics at work
when h four
this one
this is a very
non classical idea because
you and i would think
we've always dealt with that in the one
that you can take an object and place it at location a
and we say at time t zero is a and it has no speed and
we know them mass so we know
both the momentum and position
two infinite accuracy
but according to quantum mechanics that's not possible
let's not return to the real world
where h bar is not among the rage burst to the minus thirty four
and that's not good a billion people inside this triangle
delta x is the same
but since it's bars ten to the minus thirty four
delta p
is of course
ten two thirty four
times smaller
and so the velocity is ten to thirty four times smaller
undetermined degree to which the velocity is now undetermined is so
ridiculously small
is three times ten to the minus thirty four meters per second
but if you
allowed the ball to move was that speed
in one hundred billion years
it we would move only one hundreds of the diameter of an electron source meaningless
so again you see
that quantum mechanics plays no role in our daily microscopic world of baseball
and billiards
and pots and pans
and therefore it is completely OK
for us to say
i have a billion people
which is at point a
and it passes one kilogram
and it has no speed
it's completely
kosher completely acceptable
quantum mechanics has no problems with that
let's not turn to
and adam
take a hydrogen atom
the diameter of the hydrogen atom
it's about ten to the minus ten meters
sorry electron is confined
delta x
of about ten to the minus ten meters
that means the momentum of that electron
becomes on the term according to heighten works
the uncertainty principle
about ten to the minus thirty four
divided by ten to the minus ten
about ten to the minus twenty four
a second
what is the mass of an electron
it's about ten to the minus
thirty kilograms
so this
delta p
is also and delta v
so it means that delta means the velocity of the electrons
is undetermined according to heisenberg's principle
by an amount which is at least
ten to the minus twenty four
this process is delta p
divided by the mass of the electron
his ten to the minus two
that is about ten to six
the second that is
thirty percent of the speed of light
sorry electrons
is moving
only because of the fact
that it is confined
that's what quantum mechanics is all about
electrons motion
is dictated exclusively
quantum mechanics
i'm going to show you an experiment
in which i want to
very true
how non
i works uncertainty principle is
i have here
a laser beam
and this laser beam
going to be aimed through a
narrow slits make drawings
so in this light
that's it
which is a vertical slits
can be made
narrow and can be made
here is the sliding
and here
is is opening is split
it's only going to be confined in this direction on in this area
so the lights
come out here
and then on the screen which is going to be that screen
large distance capital l
we're going to
see that light spot
o two
the light beam going forward
this separation
happy file
i started off
with this little the
so you're going to see the light sport
like this
and then i'm going to make this let's never never
unless i'm going to cut into the lightly
we're going to see is exactly what you expect
you expect this line disappears
and when i can't even further
this is exactly what you expect
i've observed these two points x here on this point here
what are drawn as these lines are just samples of
lines that are consistent with the data so my posterior
probability over lines
it is
good look something like this
OK so
essentially what the data is done is eliminated all lines that are not consistent with
the the
observed data
and then
what you could do is you could compute just the
the mean of the mean line in this posterior distribution is called the bayes point
and that gives you
a reasonable estimate for your class boundary
but you have a lot more information here as well you have a kind of
uncertainty about your classes right the fans out like this
as you know this point here maybe it does belong to this class i don't
know maybe
if the class boundary look like that in this point will belong to the blue
and essentially if we have different kinds of data sets then are
distribution over lines which would look quite different
the main
the key idea is we have
in this approach to classification we have
we define a prior probability on our class boundaries
then we observe some data and we come up with the posterior probability of class
so that's very
easy to do that
and you can do this stuff
with kernel methods as well so this is just linear
linear classifiers you can have a prior
probability distribution of linear classifiers we can also have
the same thing in some high dimensional feature space
and that relates to calcium processes
which i can explain people interested
and if anyone here about gas prices
all right
let me give you some of the motivation behind as it crosses the gas in
categorized into the non there for nonparametric models so again here's some terminology we can
distinguish between parametric models and nonparametric models
in parametric models we have some finite fixed number of parameters theta
regardless of the size of the dataset the dimensionality of our parameter space is assumed
to be fixed
so that given theta the predictions are independent of the data that you got the
data from
so the probability of
data predictions x and theta
independent of the data that you actually got it from
so in a sense what this is the parameters are a finite summary of the
OK so we can also call this model based learning for example we have a
mixture of k gaussians
then when if k is fixed this is a model based you know once we
know this mixture of gaussians we don't care
if we know the parameters that make we don't care where this premise came from
if we send is it true
in nonparametric models
essentially what we're doing is we're allowing the number of parameters to grow with the
data set size
OK alternatively we can think of the predictions as depending on the dataset itself in
other words now we want to make predictions
we tend just throw away the data
we have to use that data to make those predictions
that is if we want to predict some input x the probability of where x
depends on the data explicitly and maybe a few
so-called hyperparameters
alpha as well
but the parameters alpha don't summarize everything about the data sort of additional things that
you're using
so we can also call this memory based learning so for example
kernel density estimation is a memory based learning that you know you put to death
scene kernel on each data point let's say in
that investment of your density
nonparametric bayesian methods
basically it as
you basically follows following line of thought
which is that the real world is complicated OK if we really want priors on
he was which we that
each image point
and then you use labelled you cycle through the labels was not ten labels and
say OK want to switch to one
so something which to what you say you want to switch to something
and three and four five and set train you keep going
one passed through the key passing through and if you go through a complete pass
no pixel wants to switch to any other label
you're not going to get any further
so that's you
that's the final solution
no it doesn't converge because
at each moment
only switch if it results in a decrease in the energy function
so you decrease the function of time
the general
you can definitely have local minima yes
if local
so going through so many times
the solution
there is initial solution
it doesn't apparently appeared to what might imagine our initial solution is not important
for each label
in random order
you compute the the optimal alpha expansion in other words you
you switch
which has the lowest energy subject to
only switch
two alpha
or remain the same right
maybe not
could be
if you look at that way
now the important thing is when will this
there are two questions here really
two questions
do you get a good solution out of this
and secondly
when can you efficiently solve each of these binary problems it is the step the
binary problem
binary problem is each pixel has the choice to switch
well for what i say the same
binary choice and so that's where it becomes
just the binary problem and you solve using usual
graph cuts techniques
to answer the first question does work
the answer is
yes it works pretty well
right empirically
the second answers mathematical answer
and that is
that is guaranteed
get within some fixed bound on the absolute
that's the cost and here's the potts model versus it gives you
today different parts model then you always get
maximum engine
the problem with that
rather better
so there's a mathematical bound is currently it seems to work well
so the other question is
to look
this is the this is the
and the which
it will work
article about that in a moment
the a this is the
function for the individual cliques of size two
the functions of two variables right
and functions are two labels
and the if the two labels the same you can always arrange zero
so the a b grade and recalls i don't actually think that
necessary condition
he said cities and second for
we have this
the IB is necessary to be a sleeper PCB
right which looks like the triangle inequality
triangle inequality which means you know the distance
triangle inequality
the distance
from a to b
list distance you take the two vice
if that conditional examined condition just a bit
the conditions hold then you can solve each of these problems
this examples
you can solve each of these problems
the model
you rather good segmentation
in this case truncated
well the noise is the fact that it's the edge weights which had always zero
and we're not trying to situations which analyse the edge weights are
for the so called regularisation to this sort of trying to mitigate
the effect
the noise
by saying
there is some expectations
of the relationship of
all pixels which next to each other whole
do about you don't have to be a weights then get very noisy with the
edge weights
don't you don't expect to get
zero cost
this would be a non-zero cost of
and in fact
that's that's all i can say about this really
the seven look at
this again
there's another article see simulated annealing which is being suggested that that's what the game
is game in paper which i
is about
so thanks very much for inviting me to come here and talk about what might
not seem to sound too much related to memory
can you understand me
i can't tell you so
i'll start off
by showing you a little
and the movie i'm going to show you
i don't normally show it when i give scientific presentations
but i think because this is the last talk i thought everybody could enjoy something
a little bit relaxing so i thought we'd starts by this beautiful scenes
from the movie future world
i don't know if anyone have you seen this movie but it basically it's it's
very nice film
fort reading device
and there's basically there is the need to know too much about the story there
is the bad guy
and the the two good guys the two reporters and she's going to go into
this fantastic mind-reading device that this guy here is built and he's gonna look at
her dreams and she is a little bit skeptical about what you might be dreaming
in this guy of course is quite eager to find out what she's thinking what
you can see
it's quite nice because what you're going to see is a mind-reading machine which looks
like the current state of the art images system but this film is for thirty
years old
the second thing is you're going to see
nice statement that the thoughts
are generated by superposition of a large number of independent brainwaves and you'll see a
nice rendition on on the screen
and then you also see the introduction of emotional states because one of the workers
is going to ramp up the pain pleasure gradient and then you can see what
happens if people do that
so i'll start this very short sequences just two-and-a-half minutes
she never trust journalists you know
i i i i i i
i guess you get the picture
so this is i just showed this at the beginning because the research talk about
it is related to the decoding of mental states from
actually it's quite interesting because in that movie
this machine doesn't play any role really they just go there is the new about
something completely different and i guess they thought it it would be cool to have
such a machine and then they build as the three-minute sequence in that city at
the and but she actually has a very nice dream afterwards where she dreams about
your bring their fantasy lover in great detail and i did i didn't want to
put that up here because i'm not sure
if somewhat and all this kind of stuff you appear not to show this kind
of rousing seen so i decided against that
so obviously what i'm going to be talking about
is so our research uses multivariate decoding and pattern recognition techniques
and applies them to brain imaging data specifically FMRI data but also EEG data
one thing you can do that is you can trying to decode mental states for
for example technical applications you can try and build lie detectors find out if someone
has been at the crime scene
and so on but a different thing you can do with it and that's actually
more interesting is you can try and ask specific cognitive neuroscience questions related to the
encoding of specific representations in the brain because conventionally
from my research
is and i think that's why i was quite nice to have this point reyes
also yesterday
from my research is often you talk about the whole brain areas active or not
and this is not very revealing about the mechanisms of processing that's happening in brain
areas and instead what these techniques allow you to do is to really look at
the information stored in the brain area and how this information changes under different task
conditions and also
we can help you to find out where representations for specific contents are stored in
the brain for example in cases where not really known for example as what i'm
going to talk about today is how
our intentions are coded in the brain which is something that people
i do know about especially when kind motor intentions but if you kind of look
there are some models around in the bayesian nonparametric literature which are actually not in
this class is so for example there's
in the nineteen seventies after the process was first introduced people try to come up with generalizations
along several lines and one of them is something called
neutral to the right process which is some
form of levy process essentially
i'm not going to
to tell you exactly what that is but it's basically
it's a class of models which contains the process special cases has some nice properties
and one thing you can show about it is that its conjugate in the sense that
if you take the posterior of neutral to the right process again a neutral to the right process
but it is not
conjugate in the sense so
we do it so you should write process but you don't know which one
and you need to find some other way to to to figure that out
so that's not very useful
okay so what we need is this we need basically we need to construct models
that have this kind of this kind of conjugacy and then we don't need a
basic wage
that's not say that this is the only way that we can possibly substitute for
basic creation that many many others
but this is the only one pretty much the only one
the analytically is that i know about
and that's in any way used in the nonparametric bayesian literature
okay so
when we construct
on nonparametric bayesian models can we basically have to
try and make sure that they are conjugate how can we do that well if we
one thing is we
we are we using components right we use here a bit i reckon models for example
and in that case if we
if we use
if we use models that already are cont
then we can handle the individual layers of the hierarchy and then we do keep sampling
so basically
the way to
to get this to get
utilizes and hierarchical models is
use components which have this property
it's also possible to show that that if you use these constructions that i showed
you before this project linear constructions that are used for the girls process process over
the last half hour and
that if you use
marginals which are conjugate
which have this property
then under under suitable conditions
the model that you get out is again conjugate
so in that sense the dirichlet process conjugate because the dirichlet distribution
its conjugate
now and the girls and processes contribute because the girls in distribution is conjugate
and since conjugacy
in parametric models like the directly in the gas in distribution
is something that occurs up to some borderline cases only an exponential families
you have a rough rule of thumb
models which has this property
one is that you can get this projective limits
of exponential family models
like the girl selected
so much
before the representation problem
and time
now the young
the final thing that i would like to talk about in the context of how
we can construct models as exchangeability once again
i'm just going to quickly review the two slides on exchangeability de
showed yesterday
but the real question here is if we
if you want to build a model on
four four data that doesn't come as a sequence
then what can we do
and what
what can be used as a substitute for exchangeable sequences
quick reminder
exchangeability room from recall that exchangeability was what we the kind of property that we used to characterize
the case where we can make this assumption here that the data that we see
is decomposed into a pattern ant ant independent noise
so the pattern was our parameter
and independent noise is
basically given by the likelihood given the parameter value how does the data in this
case scatter around the parameter which is the red line
i told you that if we if we have this exchangeability property so if the
order in which the data comes in
doesn't change its distribution
doesn't change its probability
he orders relevant then
we have this property and it it
i am
i should do this
this integral representation you definitive theorem which expresses exactly this conditional independence right
this is
in the context of mixture models we also saw yesterday that mixtures are stage sampling procedures right
first sample from the mixing measure
and then sample from the component this is exactly what you see in on in
this case the mixing matrix a prior
and and then the component is
this distribution of an infinite i i d equals
so you can you can
in the sense you can
interpret all
bayesian models at some form some form of mixture you can also see your can
also regards hierarchies that i showed you earlier this is repeated mixing few well yeah
from a technical perspective
but really the important bit is
we have
invariance property
which is this this
invariance of the probability of the data under permutations
and that gives us the conditional independence property
i'm not going to show you two examples of where we get this kind of
where we have this kind of principle we also have
invariance property on kind of permutation invariant property
and you get quite a form of some form of conditional independence property that we
can use the bayes models but the data is
is now more
more sophisticated random object and
and the first one is
the case where we really have
random partitions so that's something only already mentioned briefly yesterday
if we have a random partition
in which case can we assume that the random partition comes from a discrete random
error right the whole set up we looked at yesterday clustering was we generate discrete
random measure
using as mixing distribution and a mixture and then sample or data from the
and that's how we explain how the clustered data
is generated
in what cases can we assume that that's really true
the result which addresses this is something called commenced theorems looking theorem is the random partition version of
and you objects that are involved here are the following
we need to
remember in indefinitely theorem i told you that this
this random object that we draw here
that's a probability measure right we have a random probability measure
we fix that measure
and then we sample i i d e from that measure
and now here
the random object is
of the unit in terms
and what is is if you think of the discrete random measure this
these late the length of these intervals here these are exactly the weights
OK that gives it way too
do policy improvement given the current values how you had improve
the policy
get policy
so now we get to what's called monte carlo control
there lower than
it with and policy pi you're evaluating q pi
thank you
from q you can determine
for improved policy
five q
or a and he
here they called the greedy policy
so do the really was respect with with you q
the new
and iterate this process is just like policy iteration except that the policy evaluation from
sampling not from solving linear systems
the only difference
under certain conditions again this will converge
with enough samples for policy violations at each step this will converge to the optimal
policy so now you can find policy blackjack it's kind of cool
just without knowing transition function
generally find the policy
in any in p
without knowing it and the transition or reward for doing this method
and because taught generalized policy iteration
so the generalized form of what we saw earlier from obvious solution
OK it converges at all you need to know
OK now this is interesting
you may not want to go to casino
new samples from your casino
to learn
OK because
here's one issue with with with reinforced learning you need to know USA
which means you need to know accurate estimates for all actions from all states
OK if you want to guarantee convergence to the optimal policy
OK so i because you know you know
and i'm you know i'm
i've got the value
you know playing blackjack and i i've got my card three
and i say stay
because i got to sample that actually from that state in order to know what
value it is
OK clearly and it was a lot of money
if i try to learn blackjack because you know
so the interesting so
if you can simulate of programs
on the computer then of course experiences for users
theory compete which were lost that's fine but if you have to act in the
then you're exploration has to be
a bit more
that is still simple active most days but
you may want use prior knowledge
you may lists i'll show you some tricks are going show you know in a
later lecture
i think in the next lecture
which is realized you had two exploration here you have to explore all actors from
all states if you want to get convergence
so for example here
how how they how they guaranteed
convergence where they started with the random state and action in policy pi
so a course you can't go into blackjack table and say
starting was eleven story twenty one
you know by OK but on in tintin in simulation you can do this
so now from now i will do things that no economist
a new
any degree of self-respect will pay any attention to probably by which history physicist get
so what do we get off
we often data by now you know that so the first cloned the first step
is to get data i was
and leaving out some early work are much of the work here
it really took off
when when we got under cover of night from MIT
which is the ricci university
i did a database that was so huge that we had to research our university
to increase in this space just to hold of these and what it is is
a database that contains every tree
again this is something economists were never or even thing to do to analyse the
material i would you want to do that
to analyse a given sector may be given company to understand that one company why
analyse every trait but you know in particle physics we
keep keeper took the molecules apart to get out of his hands apart to get
nuclear and thereby walks
so this is the equivalent
sort of going as low as you can get
which is every time street and and then
there's this concept a so-called universality in quotes
which means that one market could be like another market one time period could be
like another time period
and to do this some other databases had to be analysed
OK what what comes out of moving right along now
is a graph which i find exciting
but what i emphasise has its serious flaws
what is the first of all it's a log log plot one
local applied every child learns to laugh because everything is straight on log log
but so it's very hard to persuade an economist even look at the log log
one economist and his referee report when we tried to get into the top economic
journal said that if we took out all the figures
and replace them by
maximum likelihood estimates things that came out of statistics books
and then you might be willing to referee the paper again but not until
so what is this this is a log log plot
and on the x axis has exactly what we're looking at a minute ago the
price returns remember we look to the point twenty ten and
so three of these dots we are looked at for stock average except now this
is not to stock averages every tree
two hundred million trees you treat
y two hundred million because the data are straight line with the relatively big slow
of three
and that means events out here
since the slope is three and the one hundred standard deviations the events out here
i ten to the
times more rare
ten to the eighth because this is the cumulative distribution if you look at the
PDF you differentiate one so x minus three for canada becomes x minus four for
the pedia
and x minus four with two decades here becomes a decade here so these events
are eight times more rare and that's why you need so many data you need
two hundred million data going to see rare events
and what they show is to my mind the most striking thing i i was
obviously didn't believe this
it shows that whatever is going on out here these very rare events
it is the same thing that's going on everywhere there is one fundamental scale free
they are not different laws there is that one regime here for everyday events in
one regime here now today this was done some time ago but today this is
less less surprising but it still is surprising in sociology for example in stockholm frederik