there seem to be
some topics
on which there are no nodes
in normal years this
the course is to it
this year contracted to six
and we seem to have been over-enthusiastic chopping bits out in hopes
such talk about some things
least on which you don't have but
you'll survive
it says in here that the next thing i talk about the natural deduction that's
not true
and i'm lecturer so i get to say whether it's true or not
i shall see whether i
i get to talk about natural deduction tomorrow morning
the some advantage to talking about set theory instead
there's is a lecture that sometimes died summer school called the joy of sets
contains everything you need to know about set theory in fifteen minutes
that's quite good fun is better than plodding through natural deduction rules
and i do that
and the next
i'm going to do
quick overview quick introduction
proof theory
this is it
among the things that are not in the numbers
that's quite an important
way of presenting logic and will be relevant to things that happen in the rest
of the summer school so
i need to go through it
albeit briefly
we have
so far this morning
we have two ways
set of
intuitively valid derivable
first order logic we haven't characterized semantically
in terms of satisfaction truth and
the notation and all those things
and we haven't characterized deductively in terms of derivations
you in an expert system
there is another
important way
of capturing
desired set of sequence
and that is to axiomatized
the correct sequence directly
rather than going through
and a story about
about about derivations
so we can lay down as axioms that certain sequence
accepted approval of allah
and then give some rules for transforming those trivially
sequence into non trivially valid ones
does axiomatized in the set of
prec sequence
and what's called the sequent calculus
this as an excellent properties
they are not shared by the hilbert
fraga systems
and we need to look at them briefly
let me start those somewhere else
you probably know
done some
elementary logic
that there is a certain amount of work around
on representing
formulae in certain normal forms
there is
for example while for example we had a normal form in a sense
this morning in the deductive system in which i presented them all in terms of
implication and negation and said well everything else gets to find the way
the point being that for anything else that's outside the vocabulary there is an equivalent
in the capital was
the one we going to do
stepmother other normal forms
perhaps more important on more more widely used these days
one of those is
is the negation normal form
usually written NNF
in which
we use is binary connectives just conjunction and disjunction
this can be nested inside each other as we wish
we have
formula of the form and a where
sorry and not a where a is atomic
and of course atoms
lawyers said to the judge
o now first show
that my client never borrowed
the main base from the plaintiff
second he he returned the vase in perfect condition and third that the crack was
already there
when he retired
so this sort of thing is is the feeling you can get when you go
through group theory course it's quite well because it wasn't there now because it's the
it's not so
there with me we're going through lots of different nations and i will show a
little bit of a so when i get call that you are a bit confusing
you probably see of asia again
so intuitively this idea of course as i said
it's essentially a generalisation of power
you have your group you have a group you have sub-groups
anyone copies of these groups
why i want copies of this group probably because this subgroup you chose
has some nice properties
you want all
all of them
that have that property
so you start collecting parallel violence
this is quite lively
in this case i showed before
this was
this was very easy for us
only the translation of the cleavage
eclipse space
but groups can get can be quite is on the first of all
groups can be finite and continue
and we went through the going to touch a little bit and both of them
here in this
how do you construct a general course
here the definition of group which is natural
it's just any subset with the same operation
that's two former group
and you just
two to construct an cos it's just a
this supergroup shows
and multiply this subgroup by
an element
in general elements in the group
so you collect then you want
is your subgroups
which is one element
in that case there
should before was the constant c one
to generate a course that the multiply that by the group
and collect all new elements
this is caused this is one of course that
left course it's because i want to play here by the left which makes difference
in group multiplication if they are not the values
a billion groups is another set in groups has a lot of the same name
middle names and
and family names so
this battalion is when the water
of multiplication of then doesn't matter
which happens with being taken with the
number with been taken with the multiplication
if you take into use
model number
these forms are group
and it's some value doesn't matter where you multiply fits left to right
but essentially we will be dealing with left cosets you all the time
so here the this this sentence has to be clear
it's one
of the cosets of h
in old
h using
using g
and this is in this this element choose
so here's an example from the natural
you have the group there which is just the set zero one two three
it's is called c four
the subgroup
it's zero
you see that
zero has to be there because it is the identity in this case
and to construct the cosets
you multiply
you know age by all elements
of the degree
so you get all this
is always the course
it's always
in general is the only one
that forms are group
the first non trivial here
this here is
trivial again
and is this
other one
so this is subgroup h has
two concepts
eight itself and one three
and you can note that
if you
z can be decomposed into union of this two
the this one here and this one
so this is always the case
here we show this for
g from naturals
but it's always the case
so another surname forward
so group can be enormous
normal subgroup
and normal subgroup follows this property here
you take one element of
and now it's so group
replacing the age
and if you act
g is general element of g
and h is an element of the
of the subgroup
it is something i did i it because it should be
represent an element from and i changed left
so really this of the man
and what happens here is that if you multiply an element of this subgroup
my general elements of the
and multiply the other side by the inverse
is still
you don't move out from this of course is doing in this
this is called the normal subgroup
it's it's important information
but for us here it's not is not that important but it's a very important
thing in group theory
in four here what we
we want this will need here is that
if this subgroup is normal
then all cosets form a group
this is one example
all of this
can you
you probably cannot read that can see that
so in this sense
these are is a generalisation of the division
so you have that is the vision of twelve but for everybody knows this three
you can take a zero
this is this is from natural right
the operation d one here
it's when you some
you know you get
all the elements in the other
and you have some again you get all of them
we have this to this three
core sets
and these three cosets form a group
now i know
the final phase
and i use the small angle approximation which is more than adequate
i know no where on the screen i get
again maximum
that is when you one point two centimetres on this side and one or two
centimeters on the other side you get of course was
as well as my
and then i can continue for n equals one then equal to
i'll just do it wasn't minus
so then you get
minus twenty five
then you get twenty four
times ten to the minus three so you get minus twelve
almost linear because the sign of data
for the small angles
it is still the same as they
in regions
before i show the demonstration
i want a little bit more information on the
on the shape
of the dark and light areas that i'm going to see
well plot here now
it is
i love this bar is later
i want to work above my head
so you can see what i'm doing
so plotting year
the sign of data
you might that is linearly proportional was ax always prefer
what the signs data
so here is
here the have divided by is where my first maximum will come you can see
and then here
the same distance
i glad to land that divided by p
and on the on the other side i have
minus led and all of these are maximum
constructive interference
and the destructive interference clearly falls
back in the middle
i did not have calculate
so the destructive interference here
so you get
like curves light intensity
it's like this
light intensity remember is always
poynting vector
this is light intensity
and that is in what was for me
the first thing
i want you to notice
and you will see that today in various demonstrations
is that the location of the maxima
depends on the wavelength
that means if red light
six hundred fifty
not only
that falls years max
and it falls he was the maximum
and it has a maximum
and as their next that blue light
which would have a wavelength say i think four hundred nanometers
will not
i have a maximum at the same location therefore not mean i e
because look at the
the song is and finds lab
so the angles of things different
and so you would get you roughly about
no way
year after the maximum
but you get the maximum
notice that for n equals zero
the red and the blue and the maximum at the same location
but you would get the first
the rule
get the second maxima
you get the maximum almost exactly at the location where you got the second maximum
for red
the reason being the prime
six hundred and fifty
is very close to three
four hundred
that's the reason so need to live a life of its own
the light intensity that you see
is the call sign
square function of delta divided by two this is so fundamental that
first i thought i'll ask you to derive
then i decided to spend one minute on it
and the right for you because it's extremely important
that you will use it later in our
so let's assume that source number one
and the other michael source number two
but the source number one
these are one thousand e
you want or not zero irrelevant one
as an individual zero when it reaches the screen
and then of course you of cosine omega t
this is the frequency of the light
electromagnetic radiation
e what is the other source
as easier to
nine cosine omega t
u is the crucial delta which is the difference between the two
interface that's why you get maximum and that's why the minimum
that's the whole idea of interference
now if you very far away from the two openings
then these vectors are of course very close to the same remember is proportional to
to one of our
but if the distance are is very close to the same
then we can assume good approximation
that the
with the expected value of the states that at one time step away
and the policy pi
so for all states s
you need the value of state s is the immediate reward plus
the discount gamma is missing this of expected
value the next day and the policy pi
this is set this system of equations
one for every state
who solution
value for policy pi
like this this system of equations one for every state
or the unknown to the system of equations
the value function
what's known what defined by a markov decision process as a reward function and the
transition probabilities
there and states that n equations in n unknowns and you can solve this if
you like before the
value for the value function policy pi
it turns out to be very useful to also define alternative definition for
the value function which was called q values
or state action values which defines a number not for states has here
but for state action pairs let me i come in handy we we talk about
sort of the the most famous contribution reinforcement is q
so here's the definition of the state action value for policy pi
it's just the expected value
of the discounted sum of rewards if you start in state s
the first action UK
is a
and thereafter you follow policy pi
so delays policy pi one step and prescribed action a in the starting state and
ask how good is that starting state action pair rather than the starting state into
what we define here
and you can similarly define it ecosystem of equations
q value for state action pairs immediately what you get if you take action a
in state s now
the action as
plus the discounted
missing again expected
value for the next state but you have to be able to policy pi the
next year or
can you have a system of equations now
was solution is these
quantities of interest which is the value
of these actions but it is unclear why these values are interesting become too limited
ability anticipate that is to say the value function the interesting because this summarise
the long-term consequences of this policy
by the pyre this is a summary statistic numbers
that says
what's the long-term utility of being in state s
if you're in state s
what's the long-term benefit you get
he be called upon so it captures this together
right all of future it is one of
we define a similar system of equations for the optimal control problem and then i
think we only talk about algorithms and about to get you out of your feeling
that giving it too many definitions let me go to one more by definition of
the algorithms
OK so the optimal can here is the optimal control problems
that equation so that control problem is defined as learn
compute the optimal policy of the optimal value function so here's the
because the system of equations that i found that is said of that
the solution is the optimal value function
from state s
the best you can do
from states from state s
is you consider all possible actions in that state
and for each action you ask what is the immediate reward i get to that
this can get this kind of missing in this county expected the best i could
do for the next day
that's the best i can do in the state is i consider every possible action
this day
three jackson ask what's the immediate reward i get
but what's the best i can do it expectation from the next state get ready
been at point
nine point zero
kilometres per second
and and i'll give you five zero
six hundred twenty degrees
everything else we should be able to calculate now from these numbers
first of all
which equation five
you can convince yourself sticking in these numbers that the total energy is in the
because if i make the total energy positive is not an ellipse
is all of
is negative is an ellipse
so was the creation number five
i then pop out a
right because this one equation with one another
and i put in the numbers
you can
confirm them and check them at home
and i find that is quite large
he is about
fifty thousand
that's huge
that is almost
infinity not quite
remember it starts off at nine thousand kilometres
eight fifty thousand kilometres leads to a hundred thousand kilometers
why is that so large
well the answer lies in
evaluating the escape velocity
escape velocity
all of this
the last when it is at position
which these ideas input parameters
is the square root
of two mg
divided by are zero
and that's nine point four
kilometres per second
if you need nine point four kilometres per second to make it out to infinity
and you have nine kilometres per second pretty close already
so that's the reason why this so a major axis is indeed such horrendous number
no surprise
if no i use equation number six
i find
and i find that it takes about thirty one hours
but is object to go around
the earth
so far so good now we want to know
what the situation is
and with
can we calculate the distance
can we calculate the speed
at location p
and at location a
columns are superior knowledge
now we're going to apply for the first time systems like this conservation
angular momentum
angular momentum is conserved
about this point q
but only about the point q
it's not conserved about any other point that's OK
all i want is that point q
that is where
capital and is located
one is the magnitude
one of the angular momentum
well that first
o point d
when the object is at the
the magnitude of the angular momentum is an
the zero
times are zero
i'm signed
o five zero
this is the situation
why do we have assigned by zero because we have a cross between r and
and was across product you have signed rank
that's the situation point
what is the situation
at point p
that point b
the velocity vector is perpendicular
two the line q
so decided angle is one
so now i simply get an
times the of
time the distance
you can do the same
four point eight
you can write down
and i'm of a kind of QA
i'm not doing that you will see shortly why i'm not doing
nature is very kind just going to give me that last part for free
this by the way
is the conservation
about that point q where the
last is located
i have you one equation with two unknowns the of
and QP
so i cancelled
so any the equation well of course
there is another one
we have also the conservation of mechanical energy
so now
we can say that the total energy
must be conserved
and the total energy
is one half i do it at point b
equals one half
the square
that is the kinetic energy
and ng
divided by the distance
this is the potential energy
the distance between capital and and the land is QP
but this number we know
because that is minus divided by two
that's our equation
number five
i slipped up here
you may have noticed it
i dropped a little and
it should be in here
sorry for that
so now we have here
big moment in our lives that we have applied both laws
this is the conservation
and now i have two equations with two unknowns
and of p
so i can solve for both
notice that this second equation
is a quadratic equation in view of p
so you're going to get two solutions
and the two solutions
i will give you the distance QP
the other one will be a
which if you the
distance qn
how come that we get both solutions
the whole
this is only stupid equation
this equation
doesn't i use the subscript p
i could have used this subscript here and fourteen your QA
the term that i left out
therefore when i saw
equations i
get both VP
because those that situations that the velocity vector is perpendicular
to the
position vector
and if i use now
our numerical
and i sold for you that quadratic equation two equations is
two unknowns
but i find that
you may want to
check that
it's about six point six
times ten to the thirty three kilometres
it means that only two hundred kilometres above the earth's surface
that low altitude this orbit will not last very long and the satellite will re-enter
into the earth's atmosphere
and it leads to a speed at point p parity
of seven to ten point seven
kilometres per second
my second solution then
is that q
it turns out to be
no surprise because we notice so my major axis is fifty thousand kilometres
we find nine point three
times ten to the four
and we find for the of a this value is fourteen times larger than this
and so the velocity will be fourteen times smaller
i think it's o point seven five
dreams slips of the tongue and so on
the first idea the idea of unconscious motivations
on the other
involves rejecting the claim but you know what you're doing
so suppose you fall in love with somebody
and you decide you want to marry them
and then somebody was asked to ask you wanted
and you say something like well
i'm ready to get married to stage in my life i really love the person
to person is smart and attractive i want to have kids whatever
and maybe
this is true
but freudian might say
but even if this is your honest answer
you're not line
anybody else
their desires and motivations that governor behavior but you may not be aware of
so in fact you might want to marry john
because you remind you of your father
because you want to get back at somebody for betraying you
if somebody wants to help you this
you say that total nonsense
but that would deter fraud in fourteen would say that these processes are unconscious
so what you just don't know what's happening so the radical idea here is
you might not know
what i want you to do
what you do
and this is something we except for things like visual perception
we accept that you look around the world and you get sensations in you figure
there's there's tree person and you just unconscious about this happens but it's unpleasant and
kind of frightening that this could happen that this could
apply to things like why are now studying at you
why you feel the way you do
torture friends torture family
the marriage cases extreme
but freud gives a lot of simpler examples where this sort of unconscious motivation might
play a role
so have you ever like somebody or dislike and not not know why
have you ever found yourself in a situation where you're doing something or you're arguing
for something or making a decision for reasons that you can fully articulated
have you ever forgotten somebody's name at exactly the wrong time
have you ever call the running in the throes of passion
this is all
the freudian unconscious the idea is that we do these things these things are explained
in terms of of cognitive systems that we're not aware of
now all of this would be fine
if you are unconscious was a reasonable rational computer if you unconscious was really smart
and looking out for your best interest
but according to freud that's not the way it works according to freud there are
three distinct processes going on in your head and these are in violent internal conflict
and the way you have to know where you think our products not of the
rational beings but set of conflicting creatures
and these three parts
are there it
he goes
and the super eagles
and they merge developmentally
the according to freud is present at birth
it's the animal part of the self
it wants to eat drink people
get warmer
and have sexual satisfaction it is outrageously stupid
it works and what freud called the pleasure principle
it wants pleasure and it once it now
and that's according to freud how human begins
freud had this wonderful phrase polymorphisms perversity
this pure desire for pleasure
now unfortunately life doesn't work like that what you want is and always what you
and this leads to a set of reactions to call with the fact that pleasure
is and always there when you want either
why planning how to satisfy desires
planning how to suppress the
in this system is known as the eagle or the cells
and it works on
the reality principle
and it it it works on the principle trying to figure out how to make
your way through the world had to satisfy your letters or in some cases had
to give up on
and the go the emergence of the go
for freud symbolizes the origin of consciousness
finally if this was all there was it might be simpler world
but freud had a third component that i disagree go
and the supreme goal is internalized rules of parents and society
so what happens in the course of development is you're just trying to make way
through the world satisfy your desires but sometimes you're punished for them
some designers are inappropriate some actions are wrong in your punished for
the idea is that you come out you you get in your head
a supreme court conscience
in these movies would be like the little angel above your head that tells you
when things are wrong
and basically yourself the goal is in between
the it
and the super
one thing to realize
i told you it is outrageously stupid it just as o
hungry for sets always get warm o
the super eagles is also stupid
the super eagles wonderful is not some brilliant moral philosopher telling you were right and
wrong the supreme that you know you should be ashamed of yourself that's disgusting stop
doing that all
and in between these two screaming creatures one of the one of them
tell to secure desires to other one telling you should be ashamed of yourself
is your
is the goal
now according to freud
both of this is unconscious
so we see
bubbling up to the top we feel
we experience
and the driving in the forces of the it enforces the super eagles are unconscious
in that we cannot access them
we don't know
which is like the workings of our of bar
kidneys or stomachs
you can introspect and find them rather they do their work without conscious knowledge
developed this is the freudian theory in broad outline
he extended and developed it into a theory
of psychosexual development
so freud's theories as i said before a theory in everyday life
decisions of errors of falling in love
but is also the theory of child development
so freud believed there were five stages
of personality development and each is associated with a particular erogenous zone
and for i believe as well
that if you have a problem at a certain stage if something goes wrong
you'll be stuck there
so according to freud people in this room are what they are because they got
in oral stage or anal stage
and and
that's not the
the overall stages when you start off
the mouth is associated with pleasure
everything is stopping chewing and so on
and the problem for freud is pre-mature weaning of the child
depriving him of the breast
could lead to serious problems in this personality development it could make him
as the phrase go
goes into an oral person
and it's all relative could be described literally it produces has an explanation for why
and the covariance now if we do that what we get is we finally get
the missing missing update equations right so
we get
the update equation for the mean and we get the update equation for the covariance
matrix so these are just
these are just sort of
technicalities if you will
and now interestingly this is the identical same equation we had for k means this
is how we computed the updated means of our of our classes right
except now
we have soft responsibilities so this is the reason why i ask you to try
to keep those responsibilities in mind
and of course we get an additional equation obviously right which looks very similar to
all right
it looks it looks very similar to this but instead of having y i hear
what house they have empirical
covariance is OK so just build them i just compute them empirically
so that's it that's mixtures of
this image is of course is for you
OK so i'm going to try to tell you about the in my career in
ten minutes
so i may have us already again but i sort of losing my mind slowly
how o
many of you have actually
has anyone ever implemented in the EM algorithm for anything
about two people OK
and and who sort of familiar with the EM algorithm even if they haven't implemented
OK so let's i'm going to try to not bore you too much
one thing we need before we start with the EM algorithm is we need jensen's
inequality OK
what this is what is jensen's inequality say
what it says is
if i have
a function that either convex or concave
this is just a convex
to start with
i have
to data points x one and x two and i can compute the value of
the function
at x one and i can compute the value of the function at x two
and now what i say is
OK fair enough now if i were to compute the value of the function somewhere
between x one and x two
i just think point somewhere
this point is going to be necessarily
the straight line that connects the two function evaluations OK
that's it
that's instance inequality
all right and then you can sort of writing in form of equations if you
OK so the important thing actually let's remember it for concave because
because what's going to happen next is that we're going to take the logarithm
although likelihood right we're gonna take log likelihood and what we're going to do
is going to write the likelihood as an integral which is pretty much the same
thing as the some OK here we have the sum of two terms but and
works for for four more terms in the sum
and the log is actually a concave function all right so let's think about the
inequality for a concave function for a moment so what does it say
it says that if i take if i evaluate the function
so the concave one of course is going to be the opposite so the function
is going to be above the straight line that connects the points for
so what he says is if a value of the function at any point between
x one x two
basically the important thing here is that i have a convex combination of them OK
then i know that this function evaluation is going to be greater than if i
took the convex combination of the individual function evaluations around
is going to be bold
so why is this useful
think again about
the factor analysis model
where we had invented those variables x
i said to you
but you could go in and take the derivatives of the log likelihood right and
then maximise and then sort of
so the two zero to learn wonderland
matrix and to learn the noise sign matrix right
to say
it's a little bit use
and it takes a few pages of
of derivatives it is possible perfectly possible visible is it is the pain
it actually turns out that
instead what you could do which is strictly equivalent is you could use the EM
to achieve the same goal
so let's let's
six ideas here
think again about among similar to the to the factor analysis OK
you can also do this for mixtures of gaussians so what are the latent variables
mixtures of gaussians
i tell you
exactly the size
so the the class memberships of the latent variables have all these customs but i
don't know
which one to choose to pick right
so i could do the same thing OK and actually
you can you can derive equations we had from mixtures of gaussians you can also
derive by using the algorithm
OK so we have some latent variables that were not very interested in in the
sense that we're going to be the joint distribution and we just marginalize them out
just like we did for factor analysis OK
and those were the axis so luckily it's the same notation as here
could have been different
and then there's there's actually parameters that i'm interested in learning by maximum likelihood
and the parameters in the case of factor analysis where the land matrix and also
the matrix side of the knowledge OK in the case of mixtures of gaussians these
were the pie case the means and the covariance matrix is already
OK for enough i know that so this thing here obviously is
p of y given x times p of x right but i've just written the
joint distribution here OK
so you all agree that so far so good i we have logarithms here but
it doesn't matter OK so we know about marginalization
so now
OK now we have this equation far enough
what can we do now now we do allow we do a little strange trick
we multiply
and divide
by an arbitrary distribution
over the latent variables OK
you might think
but now observe what we have now we have something where we can plug instance
inequality why is that
it's because we have a convex combinations weighted by q of x
all some function evaluations OK so i take this whole thing as my function f
of x OK
the latent variables
OK so how would i apply instant well what i have now is how
the logarithm
of the comics of the convex combination
and what we saw earlier is that this is basically a convex
liquid phase separate into two groups in order to answer that one that's recall we
ask a similar question when we study
statistical physics of magnetism we ask how
it is apparent that know how to spontaneously water itself
and we understand
the answer to that paradox
in the following way to neighbours
experience a moment in time
interact with one another not only directly through the exchange interaction but also indirectly for
example you can interact with its neighbor the north
which interacts with a the east and the neighbouring the sound
here's a similar in the past but this is the human twenty is a measure
of the exchange constant divided by temperature
and this comparable contributions of order p fifty seven three nine three eleven three thirteenth
and so forth and the exact enumerations of all these
configurations is the robot actively promotes but highly accurate way of learning the properties but
others that actually tell us scientifically it tells something really quite interesting that at the
heart and my opinion of complex systems
what is that what it is is that
well there are a lot of each of these powers of necessity must decay exponentially
because of the one-dimensional
on the other hand non has already
one to six is increasing and in fact it that increases exponentially because the numbers
of marks between any two points increases exponentially
so we have
so we have two exponentials an exponential decay in the correlation among but an exponential
increase in the number of
the first of these is temperature dependent the second is about
therefore by tuning the temperature it becomes possible to define the critical point where these
two warring exponentials have standoff continued standard just like the politics of the world that
you mentioned
that's the current at the critical point no matter how we use the exchange interaction
with infinitesimally we will still be some temperature infinitesimally small with these worrying exponential balance
my appreciated that when he asked them
question how does the liquid no independence he a simple jones type liquid
and he said that the
the condensed when we think of this as a surprising model potential tools
approximate distance apart
regarding the interacting otherwise not and then as particles in the gaseous phase get within
the region and start interact there will be the same sort of propagation that described
for the simple magnetic system
but if we accept this sort of reasoning
then what is the consequence when we look at the liquid with the bifurcated minimum
one might be bifurcated minimum because in the case of what
we used to do
it's possible
the two tend to be more active infinite number of ways but two of them
are particularly important
one is this which is shown as well number two in that's the way we
that because that's what we get in the ice
this is the typical hexagon gunawardena the second we can interact
is in which the case in which one of these two categories are rotated ninety
so in that case the perpetrator
so former tango right configuration and this kind of configuration can approach more closely than
single configuration
and that's what
so it's really weird experiences these two
possibilities to link scales on the
at low enough temperatures there will be a condensation of the liquid into well number
two this low density liquid density because our larger and smaller larger instances small
so in general lengthscales implies of
the transition and there's a host of of
model systems with two length scales where we can find that
the this simple reasoning
it makes predictions since the challenge for all who worked in complex systems is to
make predictions and compare with experiment because basically physics is an experimental science that's going
introduced three from here the compressibility for typically
it decreases below the temperature we understand that because in statistical mechanics relating the compressibility
is the fluctuations specific what is anomalous because not only the susceptibility like but buffalo
forty six sources that actually increases by roughly a factor of two
we can understand that increase in volume fluctuations as corresponding to the fluctuations between the
two wells that we saw here in the microscopic potential and windows systems work and
decide which was the charmed and it's exactly like gas which can decide whether to
jump in the world will not be evenly divided fluctuations increase similar remarks entropy fluctuations
because this jumping affects also the entropy and across fluctuations of the most interesting for
typical liquid across the regulations which are the coefficient of thermal expansion with positive
and we understand that because of two local by means more arrangements in contrast
this quantity is very small and below for sources goes negative and again that is
come up with the clever was resampling algorithms that it doesn't matter OK what is
more important is basically
the importance sampling
so there's a lot of valuation essentially on the
on this title resampling agrees generally speaking well what you're trying to do when you
have the resampling egories is that you're trying to build the new approximation of a
weighted sum of the mass so that each particle
x y has been we copied into good number of time which is denoted capital
and so this is the number of offspring of copies of the particle size of
those guys there are selected figures number they selected such that the sum to n
because what do you do you want them to some two and simply because you
don't want the population of particles to increase over time you want to fix computationally
fault so you really want to have those
those numbers to sum to one
and if you think of the algorithm was just describing before which was consisting so
as to be approximation or sampling approximation to support capital in times of the weighted
empirical measure or you know what it means actually just equivalent to say
that all these offspring or the number of copies of particle one the number of
copies of particle in the number of copies of particle capital in that time and
are just distributed according to multinomial distribution with parameter n on the probability of appearance
given by the normalized weight okay so that that's about it
you know because
when you're doing that you're using this information
so clearly
clearly once you're doing that you just listed
it's from
is an importance sampling
distribution is good enough this problem but i agree that that's what i was was
saying before that is it is not if you have an importance sampling doing that
doesn't help me in the sense
it's too bad is not
that's not going to solve the problem so the key is indeed coming up with
good importance sampling distribution
but it what it's not doing so you can come up with better egoism
what you have to understand is that
when you're doing this kind of resampling operations
locally in time it's bad
you have an approximation
for example let's go back to
the graph of
you an approximation here
of of your target distribution
in this case is not very good but even if it was going to be
the same thing in for example capital and times on these distribution
you just know noise
it is not going to get any information
what you're doing is you're just
i didn't know so you could tell me
it's not very clever because now if i look at the violence of estimates
the expectation was that time distribution
and we all is that the the violence
my estimate was picked the recent motion is i the variance of nice team it
was picked on the the on that they approximation so it seems that it would
crazy what you're doing because we are just introducing locally some all OK
so it is bit useless
but the key
is that what is the well was the the time when you're doing the resampling
you're using in terms of science
what you can show is the resampling will be beneficial at each time steps on
this in that we should be thinking what i'm telling you you can point me
to articulate and i will give you expression to write it
there are but there is still no reason to do not apply but we can
establish to degrees of there's a wall to wall collection of theoretical results on that
when we present some of them
so it's possible to steal to obtain valid article results on showing consistent the approximation
OK so
there's a variety of resampling agrees that have been developed in the early church
i just don't want to go for them it's not only for me i really
believe that
this is not the sampling idea is key
in in particle filters after that
understanding all the violations of the something stuff is irrelevant in my opinion so that's
why i will discuss them you can find them you can find description of the
basic sampling basically in any of the
they need to toil on the subject the only thing i'm going to mention is
that typically we always going to try to design a sampling algorithm we shall search
the expectation of the number of offspring of particle i is equal
two n times to normalise weight
so that's all you need to know
and when you do that it is in many ways to do it but
that's king the king
so now what the new algorithm
the modified version of the categories so i told user contrib something wasn't working so
now what you're doing is that we just having an additional step that consists of
resampling OK so
let's go back to this question of categories
at time when i'm interested in approximating prx one given y
i sample capital in particle x one one x one two two x one p
and according
two part distribution
which is a function of y one on the like that to be as close
as possible to p of x one y one but
because you cannot use an approximation i compute importance weights are normalized importance weights which
is the ratio between the joint distribution of x one y one divided by the
importance distribution
we normalize the weight
i know what i'm doing
is that essentially i'm gonna resample n times
from the
weighted sum of the masses located in x one essentially but this was something operation
getting one of particles the of the particles with low weights w one i respect
one of them on line particles i went OK that's that's what that's all i'm
doing well
now when i have time
we can only sabbatical to two i'm just using the standard basically
so what i've done is because of the station the resampled particles instead of calling
them x one i want to that i just do not then also x one
so be careful this one this set
of particle particles is not equal to the set is just to avoid having notation
which after complex at time two
basically you extending all the past by sampling the company xn are according to your
approximation of p xn y y and x minus one u
basically no you can compute
so you know it's just two times
sample value
summer i one to k
data i
five as
times iterative of the inside of the constant just cut value
so negative here
and was sort of this
function suspected data i
times by
OK what is this this is
delta t
and this is our feature values so the gradient for every
way is going to be
the current mayor times the contribution of that feature
to the air
so the larger feature is the more probably contributed to this
OK and so now i can add the gradient
so if i get the samples in to dissemble knowing that the gradient and update
this data ised to move
two better progress in order to reduce this air
now surrounded only implicitly earlier member we only had we've always adopted that look like
this was doing was the earliest and say what it was
OK but now i'm going to send in function approximation case
so just takes on this modified value
the degree of the value function
times the air
so it's very simple and a few lines
if you indicated
now what if you want to do gradient descent for td lambda
OK so
this is
a bit harder
because remember to implement the TV in everything we needed to have an eligibility trace
for every state
but we no longer referring to individual states so how do we have eligibility trace
in the function approximation case
and the idea comes from generalizations
is there some way to view
imagine that i had it tends to a problem
can you give me a linear function approximation
that would exactly model the value that NC problem
i've tried here
OK so i state s one
test ten
so what i could do is the value of
is the sum over
i cause one to ten
of data i times indicator function
that says
because they are i
this is zero one function one one single that i
in zero one s ninety one outside
so this is exactly the way that i can represent a tabular value function value
for every state simply as the linear value function approximation
see that
now if i wanted to plug this value function approximation into this equation i would
simply say the place of five as i just get the indicator
as eagles outside
one of the different weight that i for every state
i don't know what it is that this gives me exactly back the monte carlo
or the TD methods
the silicon alley elderly tracey's
kevin previously
it was for assuming that we had indicator functions in a river rivulet integrating view
you can see this working with indicator functions
but we don't have any kind of arch and now we have zero basis functions
so if you only ever previously on
state side in the function phi space in case they should now be
the other the operational beyond just the general weights data i
with that i no longer corresponds roughly to state
but in general to some basis functions so now we're going to say not how
notable the state to be updated how eligible is a parameter to be updated how
well how how much this parameter
i participate in previous
in previous states that we saw
just following inside so it if you have that inside then you can see
that the eligibility trace update is the same as before
the discounted version of the previous algorithms race
plus the gradient
value function in again when we just by this is that the value function is
the exact presentation
you get back exactly
the the case we had before
for the exact case
so that's a special case of this
OK because
the gradient right
the squared error gives a linear function which is a quite notable
OK certainly this is convex in the parameters
the parameterizes quadratic
what happens is when you're far away from the minimum
you know the gradient steeper
when it closer to the minimum degree is more shallow
so inherently
the squared error gives you a nice out of opposition problem if you look at
the absolute value here
you you you get the problem
and the problem here is
if you're up here
you don't know
if you look a little less information how far you go
OK so should you step a big stuff
you know if if you shot too far you might
get over here my oscillate
back and forth
but you get little the less information about
when to converge is really hard at this point exactly where is naturally the gradient
is the playing three
with the arab because it's just a randomized algorithm so and the more that we
run our upon smaller
we want to we don't want to run lots of
monte carlo simulation only want to round the monte carlo simulations so that we already
we know the exact answer
here the main idea of doing this is we just keep doing the monte carlo
simulation and then we just i have is that we check is answer is already
clear if are clear we do not really need to know the exact out with
probability right
for example if we have policy what five possible answers and we have zero one
as the range of the output probability
after fields that the monte carlo simulation
there are trueprobability has been constrained to a certain range
here we can see that g three
should be in the top two list
because the smallest possible probability article probability of g street is higher than the other
three people possible answers
and also we know that g five cannot be in the
because the highest possible probability of g five it's more of than g two and
g three
once we can determine that to which one is in the top two that we
can start with don't we do not want to continue their simulation again
so this is actually one hundred simulation is very effective and efficient method for evaluating
higher is considered data not only for the this ranking queries of the
so i think the more this year the proposed very efficient among kind of simulation
first of all this separated schema and uncertain variables
so for each each other's viable we start with the generation functions
so that it can be easily used to do the robot kind of simulation
and they instead of
the naive of information that we run one kind of simulation a few times we
have the following improvements
because database
i have some efficient mechanism to help with two out of the car in the
so we do not around one kind simulation one by one we run them together
we can have some
they improvements on this and also
because one uncertain about variable can have different possible values
if we start them all in the database should be very costly so we do
not do that we only material right one of the ranch but only when it
possible we generate value
and also during the carrier violations that of some sub queries can be discarded with
no need to store them all the time so we should be able to
produce them when necessary and discard it when we do not we do not use
the value so those are three in efficient implementation for the monte carlo simulation
more details can be referred to this paper
and the last quarry want to talk about is the efficient
the skyline query answering
so those got harry is very helpful in decision making
for example again we use the NBA data example
so we want to choose that if we consider the number of assistance and number
of points and the two techniques that we want to look into
so we always want to select NBA players who has
a large number of assists a large number of points
so for example here b b has
smaller number of assists and smaller number of points that c
of course we do not want to feel like b
so in this case being dominated by c
so the skyline of the quarry data that is the object whose not dominated by
nothing to show sky hiring so in certain they died
very you need to see causing the skull and i have a few efficient method
to compute the skyline by uncertain data sets at least that we have three doctors
in the heats up to have a few instances
it's even not clear to us who sing the skyline
so not to mention how to answer the curry efficiently
so the first task is to
develop a good
skyline definition in uncertain data with good meaning
so we again we use the possible worlds semantics we we suppose here we have
one possible world of this uncertainty data that we select one instance for each object
and here in each possible world that they live search
and the skyline is certain so
a one and b one day the skyline possible world
if we have all the possible worlds we can see that b is in the
skyline of the falling for possible world
so the probability that the thing the skyline
it the fan of the probability of of possible worlds
we call the skyline probability
that user may want to find the skyline found objects whose in the dialogue with
a large probability
so again we use threshold of p
so p skyline contains all of the objects whose probability of being the skyline is
greater or equal to p
so we want to tackle this problem
and we use the following framework
it contains three that's bonding pruning and refining
in the first that we found the and probability
and this bombing so we have a lower upon upon they can be used in
the pruning in the pretty part
if the but then all the lower bound and upper bound is not tight enough
to help the pruning we can do the refinement
so this is we just do this iteration
in the refining refining that we can see we have to
method to help the refinement why is the bottom-up method taken the top-down method
i just industries very simple idea very briefly we do not go into the details
so in the bonding
for example here
this is what method so the only but what the method
this is generally based on this key ideas
if we have two instances in the same up to it
so this is an instance of the same sort of two
the there's they have dominant relationship
right so
for example here use three is dominant by you one
so in some possible world is useful if you story is in the skyline
value one must be also in the skyline
based on this dominance relationship we can have this inequality of all the
instances of the same of the object
which means we only one we
compute the skull probability of those
some of the things that we can efficiently find those rest of the instances
so o
that's what we do in the bottom said we we compute the skull and probability
of the things that one by one from the most dominant player
that was my concern
i have to tell you
he and his wife was there at the time had been having a difficult time
in their marriage
they reunited that weekend
because you know that
it was very very emotional
suddenly you know objects
really get to the heart of things when you have to tell the stories about
when he left left
but now before the rest of us
and suddenly somebody came
one of the staff of the hotel where we were
said he left is behind
and they put on the table is farthest cup
he left further behind
i tell you
it's a wonderful way
OK i think a lot of things but i'm trying to say is rather elaborate
you know we need to concentrate a bit more
on the fly
management education and of suppressing the to do it this way
but it's the way that we found i i have to tell you
i think it's terribly terribly important
you know how you do things
that's very important of course but it's not whole
in this funny world war i i really believe that we got to make capitalism
work for everybody
businesses in the times
they are the instruments of capitalism
people have got to understand why they're doing what to do
the people in them
i got to understand why they're doing what they're doing i mean if only the
bankers to set
one often and why was he doing these things is not supposed to be doing
this suppose we translating money
people who got more of it to the people who need to use it not
just running around taking half of one percent as it goes but it not meant
to be
but they got caught up in the house
the summary in the box
because that's kind of why
i have
one more thing to say to you
when we done all these things
i tell the story
i said some years ago
two years ago as well and i were in delhi
i the the the call centers
that worked actually for AOL and l
basically they were working for american customers
we went there to five o'clock in the morning
the people were just coming to work
and the call centers
so they could respond to the americans in the data back in denver colorado where
the image these indians
and that's our
indian dress
and they went to the changing rooms
and they changed into american clothes jeans and t-shirts
they they change their names
parameter names to american name
and they set down for half an hour
a much american so
so they could get
back into an american world
learn to speak once again the slight american ex the whole idea being when you
ran the call centre in denver colorado decent american you don't want to think you're
talking to delhi india you want to think you're talking to someone in kansas city
which leads to here
so they pretend that
to be american for the night
and in the morning
they change back into being indians again
and this one i will horrify
what life must be
to be two different people in one day
and i thought oh my god when i was in charge
i would put on a funny dark suit that normally wear
i was going to that below
i have to tell you
i really
i think my values changed a bit and i entered that building
i left by other cells by i talk to the different voices
i bought differently i behave differently
in england
it is always
well understood his young is technically better is able to make new things
so the goal of that
is not to make this to them close to the teacher is to make this
a better teacher
well if you look at machine learning is the the way we see things and
we certainly one
well to explain these movies this kind of stranded language the
it seems to be very non objectives
that's going to help
this to them
to improve and even get the teacher
so let me idea of using this as the input more than using the kind
of language
so there is technical and actually say we're going to be again
we have pixel space for the commission
and there was a holistic language where you're going to have some
which is going to be understood and what did you know it's more on the
is small
it's more feasible party everything helped the machine
to organize better
isn't it looks like a crazy idea
you know the original digits
if you think that means that if the rule is easy
so we make them was weaker than the system again
now is getting really difficult commission problem
from digits
but many edits as one of his find is the point in russia
to write poems about the digital
so think each of the example not so many of them because writing lots this
it's very
these are expensive features
so here is the description of five new
so the mean
when of being within russian translated into english
so can we help machine recommended by feeding it
with this kind of information
so they met some kind
including the point
it's shocking
when i to partners planting this has
shock piercing to during this running this flexibility so that fifteen features that are extracted
from the poem and he the courts to classify the points according to that
here's what we get
this is not music this is individual this is a very strict domain
the training data size
and the number of rules
you do on the test set i think it's recognising five minutes against that
the green line of the
also you do
when you take increase the training data size
from something like thirty to one hundred
the very more very small training set very corrupted digits tren now extremely noisy
and what you see that if you had to support description
at the beginning doesn't make a difference
and at some point you start to get a little bit better
not much
a little bit
and this has been hashed rehashed and getting statistically correct because for this thing we
can this world of examples from training we don't have so many points of this
thing can forward
that's very fine example where by using this for
language are made on the fly reported description of digits you can actually make the
commission but
of course
if you want an explanation of that
it's not going to be easy
but it works
so here is the big picture as letting you see
fifty years ago
machine learning researchers
that means he
but analyzing the parameterisation
they introduced the VC entropy VC dimension and show that there were the important thing
things of this is if you think about the US economy or an economy has
been depicted by an input output people most of you have some idea what input
output tables open up matrix that there are lots and lots of positive coefficients in
the matrix
and so there are lots of complicated interconnections within the economy
so that you know if if there's a bad harvest in indonesia
o clock saint petersburg across the river here will stop because of you know ten
layers of connection between you know the rice crop in indonesia and the functioning of
the clock and saint petersburg all this long string of input output connections that somehow
eventually lead to the
o clock stopping the saint peter's her
OK so this is complicated it's
and maybe that's complex people with complexity but that that's
slightly different than i think a lot of people
let's move on from this section
well the eldest item to be about minor elements through a little bit on this
company to computability so
we've got to the main part of it
group of people here i have some of them are listed here
a leader of this group is composed documents are made available online
is developing something called computable economics does define point distinction
many of you are aware of computational economics you may not be aware computable economics
slight distinction
computational economics courses
all the figuring out useful program for doing computer simulations running models and so on
and so forth
compute the economics of worried about the deeper issues are systems actually compute
in this trade off into problems of logic
and really the question how do you define computational or computable complexity
now there's been this long development starting really with shannon science concept entropy definition of
information several people talk about kolmogorov has falling off in china
well the various definitions try especially
link this to the old arguments about incompleteness really undecidability and uncomputability if you want
a the bottom line definition of what is computable true computable complexity it's a non
trillion uncomputable now
what does this really mean it means ultimately
that there is no
the halting problem i mean this was mentioned by christopher connor set of intuitively
the various definitions of computable complexity has something to do with how long the the
best program will take to solve the system
variations on the face of ways got about fifteen i'll show you some of the
equations for a better one met here
but that's sort of the intuitive notion of truly
computable system in fact has an infinite time it doesn't solve it goes to toulouse
or just wanders around it just never gets no results
the whole the problem is now
infinite time
now lots and lots of systems that people think are computable are
the mandelbrot set for
it's not too chaotic dynamics are not computable actually there's a series of papers by
some of the some of the localised allies
i don't have listed here
list this particular part of paper people like dora
brazilian mathematicians and prosciutto some other showing things like
actually the and should always in general are ultimately not compute for all sorts of
things that we take for the supermarket people that they really really
they are
if you look at the very very close
computationally comes might say well that's not such a big deal because is really
OK OK we know we we may not be able to the absolutely right answer
what is actually gets back proof of child labour in our fixed point there but
not going to foreign
i mean only going down again can you really really really get that fixed point
and for all
i say the computational viewpoint so we don't really want to get into that the
people wearing about all this terrible logical problems really matters you know if you get
within some ball from at one radius
chris problems if system is really not computable you can't necessarily guarantee even that may
not be the best properties with some degree of probability we are with walrus well
that may be notable enough for government work or whatever it may be good enough
for all practical purposes we that we don't actually need to have everything out of
how many decimal points it
we can get out a couple of small points with some degree probably had a
big enough for policy work or what
so that's that's sort of part of the target
a point x is that some others have made is that some of these computational
definitions themselves are not computable this includes the common graph definition all of you in
the track these are actually do i'll show you your mcsane and stochastic
after the stuff
you think you are right we go so here i have is extremely short spend
any time because we want move on to the fish but you have here if
you read this carefully and human
the current through it
about is compressed as you're going to get description
the stochastic
complexity measure which is a more generalized
definition of computational complexity that is computed
OK so people like philip like very excited this is great this is what we
have i gather
debates among people like assign in china and others about all this but
i'm going to buy that this quite generalized
definition is is computed so where does this leave in a sense the the computable
complexity people so high
once we finally get the same in stochastic complexity we have a really no solid
measure definition complexity
this is it and this is better than all this because he was the stuff
of dynamic revolutionary views of the emergence hand-waving about this and that
evolution we don't know what you know this
just a couple of comments here one is that
in this case
one one of my defenses of the dynamic definition is that we actually have a
sort of more useful
what if you will
between what's complex was not complex
a lot of systems are not complex
but many
in this new in sense everything is ultimately complex is really nothing it's not complex
what you have to have in some sense a measure is very degrees complexity but
there's nothing it's in some sense simple
he will not complex
the dynamic definition all kinds of models all kinds of systems are not complex
which i think is useful here you've got might say more precise
measures the degrees of complexity that that has a lot of these including up to
this point we make this going to jump to the higher level or
the halting problem
infinite time
it's truly company and actually that point you have like with some of the
some of the dynamic complexity some of these systems are not
like the mandelbrot set
do doing that underlie
are linked with when when you put them into some kind of dynamic model i
think this is applied sociology it certainly applies in economics
you get a dynamic system that will be
dynamically complex and the definition is given let me move on
because this must be logic
and it it doesn't have distribution distribution fails
a lot of people have fast about this
distribution fails in this mission or one thing they do like is this there
you might want to distinguish between us
the more you can drive
because this could be just read is
if you have any could derive you can one
and you can run into the same time we can do both
it is but you might have to pick which one
this tells us we can do about the same time so make that distinction but
there are some logicians
who just think that this is a completely irrelevant to linear logic and all want
is what he called is called multiplicative connectives right because
represented like this
the resulting logic that removes and the conjunction disjunction
the negation is called multiplicative linear logic and actually i can find multiplicative linear logic
quite a reasonable way talking about resources also it's a nice way of talking about
information flow
an interim it people interacting together
about information
actually i believe the information plus the side
so a stamps abramsky
at oxford has very nice website lots of papers that he's not about that
representing information flow and is beautiful slides but to to do all that stuff would
take me a while and not really i don't know
it's this this horrible thing when you get it start lecturing i could talk about
this ten i even i have prepared as well
stick to what i've prepared
a better idea the next
four of
of substructural logic
has to do with
uses in linguistics
in linguistics
one in the area of linguistics is the theory of grammar or the theory of
developed in the twentieth century most by chance a chance given his followers
back in the nineteen fifties joe lambek
a sequent calculus
four categorial grammars and it's quite radically
are so substructural rejects a lot of such a structure rules
think about english
and we'll have a
one of my dogs named lola
they're the ones named after
the mathematician
the smell of similar frankel separation called him a lot because she's she's girl the
absence of some of the boys name
time lola
and i should never frankel but the fact is not really a good name for
a girl and also
i inherited her i didn't give her name
he's an old man she sleeps on so i was when i wrote this i
would turn around and she was on asleep as usual
so little asleep OK
back in school you may have learned
to think of subject and the predicate here will be a little more technical think
you need to go to
there's something
with respect to what you will probably see in the next less as to what
we will less the neural nets in
neural nets modelling dynamical system can be seen sometimes independence of a kind of war
using it as non-linear out or aggressive exultant was put more so sometimes it's possible
here is the reality we have a linear out aggressive model in which the output
is not even by
he simple
linear transformations of the past
past years but is given by an order of the formation of the past
this is this can be implemented for example using a neuron
but it doesn't change the overall picture of modelling this time series when
let's say part of that was not known and we can model noise is we
can think about noise is unknown input of driver
one of the system
thinking about the i don't know if you
already had lecture about bayesian networks
yes no
so by the
in this way
to see this kind of dynamic from all those
in the more general
situation in the more general framework in which for example we can easily be represented
through dynamic bayesian networks
outer aggressive more the
which is actually of course non-linear if we think of discrete systems so we can
predict the next value
also you should be OK not
OK minus one
so we can predict the next value of the time series of in the past
and here we have a dynamic bayesian network this is a way to represent the
non-linear out of aggressive more
bayesian networks are also easy
that it's possible to provide a stochastic version
all the
this the equations in the state space
that we discussed in the in the first part of the talk
you see a bayesian network
you you have to think that here we have time so this this time
or k
this this time kate minus one so we have the dynamic which is practiced by
the transition of the state
then in most
and here we have the output variables
OK so here we have the stochastic version of the output function of the output
transformation that we previously discussed when we introduce the dynamical systems
and here we have the stochastic version
transition function between the state variables
three movements from classical dynamic systems theory
stochastic processes and by the way image was also part of the which we can
represent the same course it's the same system
using a different thing within a different framework which is here the the framework of
stochastic model in using bayesian networks we can use it present what is known in
the literature kalman filters or
he then markov models
everything is connected to everything in fact
this cytokine immune so can activity
is probably is the band's a network
as has been
describe compared to social systems of food webs brain neurons
it's about the same problem maybe twice as dense but when one looks at protein
structure transcription factors the world wide web
it's orders of magnitude more than so sister
that is managed complex system that's managing another complex systems it does it by
can of complexity within its subsets one complexity looking at another complexity and another feature
is that there are motifs
in these very these are just try three connection which are
a very over-simplification of the kinds of actual connection between cells in the body and
the immune system but even at this level
they have a preferred
organisations of elements talking to one another and in fact they are
interactions that outlawed that are not permitted interesting just as
you can observe that the kinds of interactions that are not
in these cytokine networks within the immune system between the immune system and the body
interactions that are dictatorial
there are known knowns
that only telling us what to do
the the the most prominent ones are totally
click so it's unlikely it's and one can organize
twenty nine are with a for fifteen different kinds of cell types according to their
twenty nine different connections and get very interesting
architecture structure
depending on whether
the edges are mutually whether the cingulate gyrus single-engine are multiple saying edges in whatever
and the different cell functions
really sort out
in a way that we can begin to understand their
they're biological function and just give you an example at the bottom here the same
as the most
one way control into what is the killer cell this is
a lymphocyte
now the capacity to carry
so is in the body
and it makes sense that in doing this kind of even very primitive architecture it's
so that has the strongest
two others which are telling it what to do
that's as mutual connections with these black
edges but it has a preponderance of tight control
if we take so the the macrophage which is the and its evolution only the
the in in the most primitive of multicellular organisms so that performs immune functions in
the sense of fighting off invaders are identifying and eating invaders healing wounds and so
on this macrophage the the evolution of the
the progenitor of the immune system is the sum of the parts to everybody
receives information from everybody and then through
the evolution of the innate system
into the adaptive system with cells that make antibodies recognise energies and so we get
the proliferation of
information and structure
we can take the same kinds of the edges
and look at the organisation cells of the body one gets really
a different kind of architecture
there's a lot of architecture seems to sort of
biological function and we can make some observations about what we see in in the
architecture the immune system in the body is
connected by
cytokines we can see that complexity increases over evolution as i said the first creature
multicellular creatures had only macrophage is that
as a through over evolutionary time we see
more complexity of molecules more complexity of functions being generated from these macrophages we get
all sorts of other leukocyte cell lymphocytes we generate complex networks
and if we
look at these particular functions
the molecules and so the networks themselves
results of the general there's no one to one relationship between any of them
but various molecules will interact with various
receptors a single receptor and to interact with various molecules and that goes for some
reason for the networks themselves of degenerate in their interactions are pleiotropic the same molecule
can do at least the way we define function carrier
a function in development
in in the area under the uterus the same set can perform an unknown function
outside and is the individual develops the same molecule can perform the function and aging
and cancer and so on in infection the same with with cells
the same so can do different things different cells
can do do the same thing different molecules can do the same thing different networks
so we have the system which is the general the tropics
and redundant
in which there
and one-to-one relationships and everything mistaken and when when they find the things that i
want one relationships and designs this molecule to do
one interaction you want your opinion without it so
this is a
these lessons mean things to us now is this complexity
that as i said in the system
is less complex and you want to measure it there's no antigen recognition of the
networks are few and very simple
but interestingly the massive multicellular life on earth
although plants all the insects
well the
what makes up most of the mass of life is so everybody
but to be linear functional
it's not
the integral over the differential operator you type three
right inside
again for the model from the past probably still past separator
in this case to great in ukraine you
so yeah in machine learning also quite often and have this minimisation problems and so
one idea that he may be can
yes that's all that's why we think this
maybe weighted uses background of america methods
coming from this
finite element ideas and partial differential like in machine learning as well
so if you minimize you can show that the same as
find a function space which satisfies this relation for all the other systems based of
the city clerk in variational principle
and there's my lax milgram lemma one of
is it
the results so if you have a certain conditions of the function space and f
of building up from is bounded sum obama from graph and really big techniques but
bounded from below in this regard so a u
founded by below
and you for your response from above and then the ethnic exist unique solution to
two settings of the equivalent essentially and this is also called the weak solution to
the original partial differential equations
because you need less conditions on the function u
if you look at the setting here
let us break down here so you have the second derivative in each direction
so you admit you
to be twice differentiable
but he unit you only once differentiable so much less
it's a different kind of function space in excess of the to big solution followed
settings you can show that some the same
and so this the setting we are mostly working
so before at some point always three since all of space was also
and that results in really this could is with some finite dimensional subspace
and now
at the same setting as before the same being are from same right inside but
now we're working in the finitary microsoft with the UN and we
and solve this equation
the same six six existence results hold
and there's the CLM r
again a feel take
and you and you know solution to the continuous the discrete problem and then you
can show that see a difference so the error we make through it having the
error between the continuous and discrete solution is bounded
the infimum over all functional discrete space
distance to the continuous solution the CLM makes all the analysis of this stuff much
more easier because two
the difference between the
the discrete and discrete and continuous solution you just have to consider the approximation properties
of the discrete function space
if we can
show some things
we can show how good discrete space can approximate any continuous space you know
how good we are to the continuous solution
with some constant warfare
so what kind of function spaces are using these are
the one-dimensional example these are the basis functions for so-called level three
so this is
one function which lies on the boundary
so we always working on bounded domains domains
so this is one of the boundary for sex is another one
this is the third one and so on and here again we have another one
the the grand cross of the boundary and we are and have coefficients associated to
each of these basis functions
a simple example for the interpolation problem
so skip the boundary functions
and then we have level three surface
again a hundred thousand to around the edges and another observation is that about eighty
percent of the edges are labeled with the plus and then the remaining twenty percent
of labelled data mining OK so now what i want to do is i want
to sort of start reasoning or see how can be some kind of information about
how how does the network construction these pluses and minuses how man on the underlying
network and here sort of the basic the first piece of information that i could
use from social science it's called the theory of structural balance and this was done
by hiding nineteen forty six and here is the reasoning he was talking about he
said if i have right he was saying a friend of a friend is my
friend if i have a positive match someone and they have a positive action someone
else then that person is also likely
then then i like to have a positive edge that person or enemy of my
enemy is my friend right or you could say my friends and is also like
so statements what they that what to talk about is the talk about of connected
nodes right so i can sort of translate into sort of graph theoretic terms and
here here here
they are right so a friend of a friend is my friend is this kind
of structure that i have a friend who has a friend so you would like
to be my friend right and this this case is the enemy of my enemy
is my friend or i could say my friends enemy is my friend
right so
and then
so this prior
sentences of this intrusion so called prior to balance right and then there are two
other possible labelings of
undirected triads with pluses and minuses that we will refer to as because they don't
correspond to this kind of information so this is the first one the way you
can think about this one is to say i'm here i have two friends and
they don't like one right so this would be like some kind of unstable structure
that it's very hard for me to
to have two friends and cannot you might have to go to get to work
twenty together because they don't like one or this one here is that people of
enemies and the idea was that sooner or later two of the enemy's will will
form an alliance and go after the first one right so that is
i don't think this is sort of how we can think about about signed just
in this way here is a different way how we can think about this and
this is what we refer to his status theory so here in the previous case
just one undirected so now we will think of it just as director and they
say that if a gives positive edge to be this means that has higher standards
than a OK m step this think of things to think of it as some
kind of
soft intuitive notion of matter level of achievement or something so if a user plaster
means because higher status than a and it's the opposite is also true so a
gives a negative edge to be dismissed because lovers that has the right and now
this is another way
so now based on the size of these edges i could again make predictions how
people will label one right and the important point is that the disappearance make different
predictions so here is here is an example right so if i can i want
to know what my intuition should be have about the design of the central repository
were negative
so the structural balance would say the enemy of my enemy is my friend so
that would put the blast here was that this was a of able say o
x because those that then i had access all because even though is that as
the mean so it has the highest because he has the lowest so
if the edges pointing the direction of the status then here i should put the
strike a higher status and this is what it can infer from this network structure
here's is so
in this case
special balance would say put the plus here
status theory would say put the minus here right so that all the explanations completely
here in one of the examples where the same when the same thing happens when
i what i did is i think the direction of the edges and every designed
so again then i would say
a friend of a friend is my friend status would say he has the lowest
at that has the highest and so is a relatively supports negative edge right in
some other cases the
so here is
what what do do not so what i'll do next is go into a sort
of devices
and experimental methodology how
how old how to tease apart how these two theories are expressed in the data
so how how much of status and how much of balance is going on in
the data and then and then we will sort of look at the publication of
this very say OK can predict whether the people who befriends or and so can
predict the sign of that much OK so that's the plan for the for the
next so here is the way the way we think about this so we will
think about is the following we will think about our networks as director so well
our networks can direction i will tell you i trust you i label as a
friend and now the question will be how many
how many
triangles or how many such conclusions creations of just my network can be explained by
the theory of structure so the way i i think about this is to say
half here in sixteen different possible ways of how to have our land to all
the same i right so so the idea is that the first this is to
provide some kind of context and then the question is what is the sign of
the red right and now i can go and whatever and of the sixteen possible
triads right y sixteen because i have tools for the direction he two possibilities for
direction here possibilities for direction here that's what i can put plus or minus here
put plus or minus that's two times three four four times forty sixty right so
now i can go and labour and then just by what would the theory of
structural balanced and so here i would say half friend of a friend is my
friend so i with my prediction would be that you would a plus i could
say half my friends enemy is my and i would put the miners then i
would say half a friend of a friend of my friend plus next one i
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
a couple of comments about the test you should get your test back yesterday and
here's the way things panned out class averages about 77
I said settle down perhaps you think you've come to map physics this is 309
1 we have standards here so 77 class and the standard deviation was 17 and
so you can say
where things up
lie 150 surpassed so congratulations a lot of people
I put in the effort and
learning going on I was at the same time as I say congratulations I want
to remind you that I think it comes as no surprise given the lateness of
Labor Day this year that this 1st testing rather early and for many of you
much of this material seen in high school and perhaps the data rate was a
little bit faster than you're accustomed to but you have some familiarity please don't if
you're appear become complacent because months from now will have another hour test and I
think you still which your continuing to make the investment in time by if you're
down here as far as I want you to do is talk to somebody talk
to your recitation structure come and talk to me we will provide tutorial assistance at
no charge if you want to amplify the exposure to question-and-answer and all you have
to do is contact with either hillary er lorry have my office and will arrange
for a tutorial on meetings
and maybe down here you just get rattled maybe you are
weren't feeling too well and they maybe have to bone on your test-taking skills but
I don't care what what the score is down here at the at the moment
Izard told you the 1st day I do look at trends in so let's just
make every effort to take the steps necessary to master the material and move forward
the good news is that we're going to be shifting gears very soon and moving
into subject matter unlike anything seen in high school and so you'll get a fresh
start so anybody feeling that if he or she is down here that it's it's
hopeless at this point it is not
quite the contrary and I've actually seen as evidence over the years mercifully not just
a small amount of evidence but there are in group like there's always a few
students who come in with a really strong background in high school is extremely well
in the 1st test conclude that chemistry in the bank and they can focus on
the other subjects and little by little they start creeping down here
it happens so as the model solutions will be posted as as a told you
in we pride ourselves in giving you a rapid return but there's a tradeoff that
is we're gonna make some mistakes mistakes not indelible you can come in and and
have your grades adjusted the 1st thing you do please talk to your recitation instructor
recitation instructor feels that there was an oversight rather than the restoration structural recommend you
come see me and I will change the grade it just in addition recitation structure
has authority to make that adjustment and and you don't have to go stampeding down
my office right away you can adjust those grades what's let's leave it alone was
there until next week and we can take a leisurely pace arm but there's no
time limit on and in fact you can be sitting 3 years from now
waiting before commands
and you can get that just I can adjust the grade right up until the
moment you get your degree after that the records are sealed so the reason I
tell you this is that I don't want people feeling that well
you know that the 2 papers that start to decompose or something I don't get
to him by 5 today don't build hurt yourself in the stampede in my office
OK and so congratulations again to those that this well and let's let's do we
can get everybody over to the right of the blue line on and just keep