good bye bye going through the generalisation bounds we're done with these experience we're trying
to keep the story we're just going to go over the kernel crfs
in boosting for structured case
and conclude
so k they were talked about four tournament it's
how we can see how we can use kernel methods for structured learning so we
were looking for some some of
s star
or some loss function plus some regularisation constant and this slow and actually gives us
our compatibility score over our structured objects and we have seen in quite a lot
of detail about max margin formulations for the setting where the loss function here is
actually the interest us with possible different margin definitions
and if we just
the loss function in a defined as is the log probability of the conditional
come the the conditional log probability we actually do get to a kernel a serious
so we're that they i guess
the only thing i should apply and this was proposed by lafferty last year in
the input the one thing i should point out here is that if we just
if we think about this
regularisation term as it is the prior on our possible functions
the little as you can think of this as the
the MAP estimate of of of our so in this era formulation we just do
not have any prior to any in any prior term or new regularizer which corresponds
to a uniform distribution so we're interested in the
so we're interested in the maximum likelihood estimate but in this setting kernelize here as
we can think of it as the MAP estimate of the
in the solution the optimal as we have seen before is just a linear combination
of the child over parts combined with some linear combined with some parameters
so one difference between the
maximal margin formulation this we have extensions of this matter too
two structure learning is that the log log probability does not have any
the the the log loss function does not have person property so you it again
in the hinge loss case in most of the cases for most of the parameters
we would have a is zero and then only for a few we would have
some active values but in our case in this case the loss function itself does
this just doesn't have social property
one thing to do that we will need to consider is to enforce some sparseness
explicitly to the problem and what does that mean really
so if we were to solve the optimisation problem exactly
we can we can either choose to do this is a convex optimisation problem right
we can we can just optimise it with some off the shelf toolbox either we're
using first order gave it to the second order gradient and it doesn't really matter
one thing is that if our data set is really large then we wouldn't be
computing a kernel matrix over all the parts of our structures
right in o even considering all possible instantiations of this to the kind of the
kernel matrix were considered might be
intractable to compute or you want to store
so we will have to consider some approximate that it's and do doing this we
will actually consider greedy
greedy optimisation technique
are we can call it the column selection optimisation
so what we're gonna do it again is to go over training instances so for
each each
instance in our dataset we have many parts and for each of those parts we
have corresponding parameter right
what we're going to do is the to enforce sparseness well we're going to do
is to pick the directions there that had the steepest descent
so we're going to be going over training instances computes are gradients which are actually
is it is in standard kind of a is an standards here as well this
will be the expectations and we can compute these using the forward backward algorithm
so we're going to computer gradients we're going to select
the steepest directions and then optimize over those actions
just simple gradient simple
o simple steepest descent
optimisation problem
this again was proposed by lafferty of last year a similar of formulation was presented
in the paper might
just let's go directly to the experiments again and pitch accent prediction problem so we're
looking at extending zero
where there is no kernels all we're looking at perceptron which can be considered as
an approximation of cyrus and these are the kernel serous with different kernel kernel values
a polynomial kernel one degree to degree three and indian we we see a support
vector machine formulation for the same problem and as you can see obviously
o using a polynomial kernel of degree one linear kernels according to zero right but
when we consider
o more complicated trials which corresponds to extracting tuples of of features we actually see
some improvement in terms of the accuracy
and the comparison between history and central serous we again see some improvement
all right here
just plot showing you actually the the
justification of the sparseness if you only select one percent of the features you already
get good accuracy in
but by by these by selecting only eight percent you do get no significant difference
between the exact optimisation
sparse optimisation methods
so this was the very first kernel seriously
presentation now two weeks till now we have seen kernel methods for structured learning we're
now going to switch gears and look into
of k
there's a slight chance that the photo should be that the electron may fall from
ten equals three down to ten equals one that's a greater energy difference and we'll
get a k full-time but k beta
OK data indicating that the photon
i felt to k from two levels up and i even just to complete the
picture but k gamma
well there's vacancies in the k shell if we have enough energy to dislodge electrons
from k shell we certainly have enough energy to dislodge electrons from l shell
they can see here what invited cascade from any cause three equals to this would
be l
alpha because l is the destination shell alpha meaning you came from one
shell above
in the event that you fall from two
shells about ten equals four down and equals two
this will be an l beta
full-time and
this was the way we left it last day
and the last thing was that the instant energy values here and therefore the instance
wavelengths are determined by
the chemical identity of the target if i change the composition of the target i
have different internal energy structure and i'll get a different set of
that's what was
that's what was left at the end of last days another question is is there
a quantitative relationship between any of this specifically is the quantitative relationship between the chemical
identity of the target and
many of these wavelengths that
are observed in the answer is yes
and for that
we go back to manchester
the person of a young graduate student by the name of henry mostly
henry mostly he was a graduate student working under rather for
nineteen thirteen
nineteen fourteen
he was conducting a study
because systematic study
for those of you who intend to become
graduate student so i'll let you know this is very dangerous work with systematic means
it's polite talk four tons and tons of measurements
systematic his systematic study was to take
the x-ray
and change
the chemical identity of the target
and he
conducted a study of no fewer than thirty eight elements
thirty eight elements systematically changing the chemical identity of the target and measuring the spectrum
the emission spectrum for thirty eight elements he started as low as
a lot
and we all the way up to gold
stopping thirty eight places along the way
he measure the wavelengths of these x-rays and he found the pattern
he found the pattern
what found was that as the
as the molecular weight as the atomic so we're just dealing with elements as the
atomic weight
the wavelengths
so i'm comparing apples and apple so let's say let's compare all of the
k alpha lines so
the lambda k alpha would fall as the
heavier and heavier elements were used
here is
here's the plate from one of his papers
this is a beautiful piece of work here he's
these are the photographic plates along the lines of
the bomber series
only this is from the x region of spectrum so here's calcium titanium vanadium chromium
manganese iron cobalt nickel copper and brass here is here's where is going is there's
solved with the
the concepts that we just saw in the previous slide
first of all the data we have in its raw form is now used
we need to have
something more informative about the kinds of things we're looking at
so let's do it
some spectrogram transformation of the data we want to look at
here's time here's the
the duration of the sample
and here are frequency levels this is actually plotted with lowest frequencies this site high
this site so each of these
each of these columns here is the full fourier transform
and we're at that instant there was some kind of low
frequency component in my voice that shows up as a hot color here
and where the frequency component was lower than actual physical colours
so three axes is
three nos
and now we can
you know if you if you really squinter this for a while and you try
to work out what's going on you can start to make some distinction between these
two types of classes
you are visually inspecting it we could start to see some differences like there's you
know the yes is have this kind of
yellow cloud over here whereas the numbers
i don't really
this kind of three stages to the yes
which actually is like the three different i guess it's like the
three different source shapes that my mouse to what i was saying the word yes
i guess that's the US
something like that was neural is
kind of one long
that vowel sound is is more consistent
this thing here could be quite informative the
the essence of yes when i make that's
noise that's
more like white noise which we know is something that has
frequent power across all frequencies so during the what i'm trying to and the word
yes than we'd expect to see
this high frequency components no doesn't have anything quite like that
all right so there's there's a start to enable distinguish between these two things so
we could
to some kind of
what we're going later call feature engineering
let's say
the most interesting part here is these these kind of bands here
if all my inputs are either going to be yes or no is
one informative part of this data could be
just this
this band here so here we expect to see something of high
power at some point not all time
and here we would expect it to be low power throughout the and
so we can do it
it's taken average of that band across the length of the sample
here after the
the yes is in red
and no those in blue
and this is for those
spectrograms of average that out over the
over the
frequencies are interested in
also that year so the all different lengths but we can start to see some
kind of distinction here the
there's this kind of pump in the in the yes
frequency is where we get to saying the word as well as the
and those tend to be low interact
now if i take two
samples to two features from this stills would make it even simpler let's say i
just take the
the max and the variance
each of these sequences here
and that gives me a two dimensional representation of each input data points then we
get something
like this
supporting this here we can now see we've got it right down to this two-dimensional
description where we might be able to use
some kind of linear classifiers
OK so now we're at the stage where we we've made this we've got this
input space which is pretty complicated you know several hundreds of thousands of numbers and
in one long sequence
with progressively made it simpler and simpler
just trying to keep the information we're interested in
and through extra information and we don't need
until we have taken maybe five hundred thousand numbers
variable depending on the length of the sample
and we
condensed all that down into two numbers
which are kind of features of this thing here
and these two numbers we
we think are quite informative about the problem that we have
datancode this are
little more what should find a link there on the software page
with all the samples if you want to me saying no no no over and
over again like a maniac them
the opportunity is there
all right so let's take this is are
r two d example something more interesting than classifying types of animals
and let's go back to
linear classification is to actually actually do this
right so we need to
we've got some idea that we have this
two dimensional data which somehow can be split up by by line
and we need to come up with some way of choosing aligned we need to
draw a line somewhere in the two d space
so that we split up are
are they send
in a good way
well how can we do that
let's take the simplest
o thing we could do the same with all these programming which is let's choose
a completely random line
when i say random there's actually some details our to kind of can obscure but
take the lines
all of which we before seeing any data we think are equally likely
and then we'll see which ones
match n more
or keep the ones which mention look
so i got two things too
people to work out their one is
how can we generate lines
and the other is how can we see if any one line
matches the data we have
neither of those are very challenging
if we
we want to generate many lines we can
represent line uniquely with a single point
and on the on the two d plane
if we have
you probably want to take the origin is the mean about data point something like
if we
generate any point somewhere
so we can have points at random
if we take the vector from the origin to that point
and then we have a scaled version of our w weight then this is something
which is perpendicular to the
to the
it's the
decision boundary so for all these random points we generated
thank you for the introduction so today i'm going to talk about the context initial
since the stroke width transform
this is a collaboration with alpha can looks like all of us are from microsoft
so in the beginning let me ask you a question
wouldn't it be nice if we took let's say this image
and using a simple transform
did something like that
text clearly stands out
that sure would be nice about it so
show you how to do it but first let's talk why it's important to detect
text in images so there actually
several reasons obligatory reasons first of all
image retrieval OK especially books of similar design because you know from the standpoint of
SIFT descriptors those are really the same book
automatic navigation is also a very important problems
help for visually impaired
translation of science
business you could
do-gooding means finding the exact coordinates of the businesses so all the important message here
to get across is that natural images all c are actually
it's quite different from the traditional c are used for
scans of books and foxes and so on because of lots of challenges for example
of large variability of forms
short texts
very determination
image nice
lack of defined page layout unlike books
and finally conclusions
the text detection is an important step for OCR it corresponds to the page layout
engine in the traditional OCR
sometimes all we need to start detection for example if our application is stitching
then we don't need to read the text actually just want not to stitch across
the text
so this paper deals mostly with text detection of jury
deals with other things so how to go about it there are actually two large
families of existing approaches one is called texture waste and the other is called region
based so let's start with texture waste approach in texture based approach
we take a scanning window and this can in the image
and then hopefully we find some regions that can be classified as text
but obviously since texts in natural images show such large variability of scale we cannot
do it was just one size of
so actually use several scanning windows and some of the regions will be will be
farm by this one smaller scanning
so and we of course we need to classify two text regions and nontext regions
so this is kind of sums up the
this scheme scan windows and different scales we classify them and then we need to
integrate the results
so there are problems in each stage of the first of all it's easy to
miss the scale if you're implementing an efficient system you can kind of your text
can kind of fall
between the scale
next to the features of the classifiers often target for example text some of the
most important features and integration also can be problematic because non maxima suppression in this
case works kind of flaky
the other family of approaches our region based approach here pixels are aggregated with the
local features usually colored
then we extract connected components and within those letter candidates that do some dramatic filters
filtering on those candidates and then finally we group them in text lines
so the first item here is also problematic because of the locality of the features
local features of can be very unreliable for example we can have colonize
which will
not let us merge
the pixels by the cut by based on color efficiently
on the other hand we produce initial segmentation here which is very important because because
of the consequent all
and this is kind of scale mostly because once we know
our letter candidates it's already doesn't matter which scale we can measure the connected components
and also grouping of little kind candidates in this method does not require us to
read only horizontal text can be in in every direction in principle
so our method is a region based no question about it the thing that we
set out to improve was the locality of features so we propose a new feature
which is called SWT for sure or stroke width transform so the outline of the
algorithm is very similar to what i've shown before which is we take an image
we compute the stroke width transform
we extract connected components based on the use of this feature then we filter letter
candidates based on some geometric considerations
after that the aggregated text lines with some more filtering because now we we know
more we can do more
and finally we transfer these bounding boxes that really covered in our favourite application that's
a and OCR
so the feature that we use is actually the stroke with it can be observed
that in many alphabets and in many forms
actually the ways of the stroke keeps constant or let's say slowly when and this
is the the observation that we wanted to leverage
so how to go about it
let's say this is our image
let's take a look at some small
window came
so the first thing that we do
we actually do on graylevel not on binarized image it's just for clarity of presentation
so we do
edge detection in our case we did can but you can you can think
your favourite and then from each edge pixel
we should the rate in the direction of the gradient
and we should it until it hits another edge pixel
with obama
you're going to see occurrences
running in one direction and when i call without
will be running in the opposite direction and when i hold my hands still
of the magnetic field is not changing
no current
going to see the current meter there
and here is my bar magnet
i come close to this
i pull back
in this new direction
now i will go faster
for the change of the magnetic field
unit time stronger
more current
i go out fast
he sees the change of the magnetic field that if i come in very slowly
which i do now
very slowly
almost nothing
right now the entire magnetic field is inside this
the strongest i can have it
nothing happens because there's no change in the magnetic field
it's only when i
so this
that you see
the current
so an induced current
is clearly the result
the driving force
there must be
just like we had with better ways in the past
there must be a EMF
there must be an electric field
that is produced in this
conducting loop
and so
i create now
the IMF we use that word you have four batteries
so now we have an induced EMF which is the result of this changing magnetic
and that therefore
is the induced current
times the resistance
of the entire
conductor whatever is in their in this case
the total resistance of all these
findings of all the copper wire that ohms law
so do you do news eleven
is the always the induced current times
the resistance
violated all of the experiments
and one of the experiments that he did
was that he
produce the magnetic field
so here in the current
some kind of let's say
even the current
going around
creating therefore a
magnetic field
and he was switching the current in in out article change the current
and so it produces a magnetic field
this magnetic field changes when you
closed and open the
this which
and then here
he had his
conducting wire just like
we have there
and he measured in there
the current
and what he found experimentally
is that the EMF that is generated in here which i will call
you may have generated in my
conducting loop number two
is proportional
to the
magnetic field change
produced by number one
go through number two
this field is changing so you notice that
if the changes as as you just saw
you get a higher you may
also notice that the two
is proportional
in these areas
so thirty area
of number two
and that gave the ideas
that the EMF really is the result
of the change
of the magnetic flux
of number two
i want to refresh your
memory on the idea of
magnetic flux
we do know
we remember what electric flux is
magnetic flux
very similar
this is the surface
the local
vector perpendicular
the surface
it's like so
could be in a different direction
and the local magnetic field
it's for instance like so
and the magnetic
through this surface
is defined we call it
phi of the
is the integral over the open surface
this is an open service
of the doctor dr
the electric fields
we defined in exactly the same way electric flux
except we had an easier
there's nothing there
so if this magnetic flux is changing
five they concluded
have an EMF
and this
conducting wire
so essentially is the change of the magnetic flux
if we take
some kind of a conducting wire
like so let's make it in the blackboard for now to make it easy
and i attached to this
wire a surface because the moment that you talk about
you must
always specify you surface
flux can only go through surface
so this is my surface now for simplicity
and there's a magnetic field coming out of the blackboard at me
and it is growing
it is increasing
i will now get the EMF
flowing in this election
that's all
if the magnetic field is increasing
then the current will be inserted direction that it opposes the change
doesn't want that the magnetic field to increase
and so it
goes around like this the current sort of that produces a magnetic field
that is in the blackboard
so what is the flux change of the magnetic field through this flat surface
the term and the EMF
forty you
is then
the flux change
the i dt
like the walk
i know
five more on like you
well one
we can be more efficient to
as used
the main problem here is
i love you
one of the rule right
for which
what is not covered by the rule
then you look into how similar it was
so how far apart
well all the people
in general
for all the way to four for the
the rest
i have
so this method
there are many out
available world
and actually on where
were born
the first thing that comes to
four more from
for maximizing the
the brother
the on before who
the second thing want probably time for a common
no it people
we have
some information about surgical oncology
the core
one or
you know
the on
of course problem
i come from
OK so
one or two
so some of the things that can
we with
well it seems like
i you don't want to know
mean it
one one
a different matter
and the use of those
one was
welcome to
lecture fourteen
today's lecture is about variational methods
we've been talking about methods for dealing with complicated probability distributions we made
have a nasty probability distributions because we are doing inference the posterior distribution is nasty
we may also have a nasty probability distributions for other reasons maybe work on physics
in the lectures we've discussed monte carlo methods
and now going to just discuss variational methods which are two possible ways of dealing
with nasty but somewhat tractable distributions
here's the overview of all the chapters in the textbook that we've been
looking out for the lecture so far hand
i should emphasise that there's some additional reading i'd encourage you to do
very short chapter
on the pluses methods which is another way of dealing with nasty distributions where u
approximates the nasty distribution by guassian and i'll just leave it as a piece everyting
before you
andy from time-to-time i will refer to ising model so it's a good idea to
have read the chapter on ising models as well so not essential
his websites before book and for the course
and the idea variational methods works like this
assumption just as in monte carlo methods is that there is a nasty red distribution
called be
is something that we can compute within a normalizing constant so it's got form e
to the minus he effects and we are able to
computer effects
and in variational methods are assumption is that if x is a fairly simple function
but not quite simple enough first able to actually answer the questions of interest which
are things like the expected values of functions on the peak
so what's the idea of variational methods well we introduce a simpler green distribution
we call q
and we parameterize the simpler distribution in some way
so q is intended to be simple enough that we can evaluate expectations and interesting things under q
and we make an adjustable
and then we adjust the parameters of q so that it is as close as
possible by some metric to pee so we just these parameters theta
you get the best approximation
and a very important question is gonna be how do we define best
once we found the best approximation
locally optimize parameters theta star
then we can
the expected value of the function phi that we are interested in by the expected value on the q
right so let's leave the big picture
you could think this is getting away from introducing random numbers with monte carlo methods
we settle peace difficult but let's
you some random numbers and some clever ideas and jump around in x space in some way
and you might have thought well that's a bit inelegant why do i need to
have extra random numbers in addition to the data that i've gathered
for my inference problem
it doesn't seem logical to need random numbers to
and my inference question
and so variational methods are an approach that says yes you don't actually need
random numbers you can do this instead well
whether it works well is is an open question i'm going to describe to you
how we do this
so we need an objective function that measures how close q is dippy
there's various ideas for how to measure closeness of distributions to each other
to that we have already come across are the kullback liebler divergence is between e
q which you can write to different ways around so you can have this
average on the q log q be
or the average entropy a logpy over q and these are both measures all
distance between pinned q
that have the property that when
he and q are equal these comes out with zero and you can't get any
smaller than that's so these are both minimized if q can actually perfectly match peak
we must remember that x we're talking about is a very high dimensional things so
these sums over x that we have here
are not necessarily easy to do a moment ago we already agreed that difficult we can't
represent averages
for example the sum over all x five x times x is a difficult thing
so why should we think that we can do anything with these
these kay else
befor i
continue without thought let's just look at an example so you understand how these scales work so his
very very simple nasty read distribution which is non uniform it's got
third third third and x long probability on
discrete points since in its
anne q is an a simpler distribution which is uniform and a quarter of awful places
so i'd like you did
quickly work out and discuss with each other
what's the
kullback liebler divergence each way round so if you look at the first one the
second one which then is biggest and roughly how big they are they so please
talk to your neighbour now
let's have some votes
on the board got
p e
first and peak is second so
let's vote for which one is bigger
is the first one began as a small
or do not know votes right now i haven't had enough time
that's four
the first one is bigger than the second
okay lots of flat and vote for
the flat ground okay
so well them
i've written in the way around for no particular reason hippie
measured this way around
it is about long forum
whereas if you have a q on the outside q goes in lumbers inputs quarter
of its probability mass on a place where peace there's no way that's got a
tiny tiny probability and it gets strongly penalized for doing that
when the toss-up up
when you talked up q like europe e
you get this
one over long which is
very large
bad news if you like if if this is your measure of closeness
and that's says q is a very long way from p e
i put quotes around because
the bad news and
depends on what we're trying to do
so something to be aware of if we use this sort of objective function
the measure closeness
is it appears a complicated thing
a complicated thing that in some places goes to zero and if we approximated by
green thing
that is nonzero in places where he
so it's still only three data points but i see the like is much more sharply peaked
so it depends on what the data actually turn out to be how sharp likelihood will be
it's possible with three points all the possible the left-hand side you can get quite
a good estimate a just from three data points
an approach that uses bins and a fixed size fixed before the data arrives will
probably be hopeless that this sort of thing but the likelihood function does the right
thing when when you can get a very precise sense if lambda
even given only three data points it gives you that's so we hate putting data
into bins and power of the likelihood function because you'll never need to use bins
ever again
i want to finish
in the next fifteen minutes
with another question
the topic for today
it's lecture ten
the topic for today is inference primate hand models
and if i gave you some data like this and if i didn't just say
they come from one exponential tell lambda
if i said
i'm not actually sure if it's from one lambda one exponential maybe there's a mixture
of exponentials
please tell me what you think about that
is it credible given this data that comes from two guassian rather than sorry to exponentials rather than just one
how do we solve the problem
let's write down
bayes theorem again
habitat your about how to solve this problem on a whiteboard
so what we're gonna do now is going to introduce to hypotheses
one is hypothesis one which has just been working on
hypothesis one
which is named after the number properties it's got
number of exponentials
here it is
and this is how we it want to the data
fifteen involves
thinking what its lambda it's one parameter lambda might be
the area
what we did
and the prior
o i didn't even specify what it was the sort of thing you might do
in this
if you were real life problem you might think a little bit about
if you know anything about lambda already you know if it was shorter than something rather than
universal exploded it was bigger than we'd all be dead or not at so might be
range values pretty sure lambda must be within
and if we really don't know anything about land apart from
you might be tempted to have which prior
between the values
it actually depends what the problem is what you should do about this thing it is subjective
and that's the way
i think it has to be
so the sort of thing that the prior might be
is some uniform distribution over some broad range of perhaps
is a log lambda
i'm not saying it has to be that way
that's just the way i often work if i have a rule of inference problems
if i've got a positive quantity lambda
the decay length
all tend to think that the longer the variable is a natural way to work
with it and then they put a prior on the love it rather than directly
on lambda itself
what this implies that the problem lambda is that it may be a bit
lopsided prior looking a bit like
this because this prior saying that
values such as
o point one one and
hand a hundred
are all just as likely as as each other
that means cover
bias if you like to
small values
so i haven't obsessed about this problem but it's gonna become slightly more important in a moment
well now introduce you have a second hypothesis
anne the second hypothesis says that the probability density of x if knew lambda one and lambda two
andy new
quantities lexical and pi one pi two which are the weights and the two exponentials
so these the lengthscales and these are how much probability mass is in each them
the probability vectors
given those properties and age to is
you minus x
lambda one
in might
the two
multiplied by weights by one
and for simplicity
we could pretend the left side window is that
zero from now on that
read and this
and that is
a mixture of two
yeah the tracklet this is true for all
you know be
zero otherwise
okay so it too has got to interesting parameters lambda one lambda two
and it's got another couple parameters i would like to
the probabilities sum to one
the positive
together with
i'm gonna
declared both are so well
just simplify life and say
half the masses in
one exponential half in the other
i don't have to do at
it just make it a bit easier to what we're about to do so the
model only have two parameters rather than three
okay so i've got one parameter model and the two parameter model
we can do inference with both of them
we can infer lambda one lambda two
hello data
and then involves looking at the
we all
which is the product of all these things
and suppressing the pies because i just arbitrarily decided that i was half
we have a prior on the lenders
the normalizing constant
the probably the data
the agency
so that's how we
to put it crudely fit model to
to the data
moreover it's how we infer lambda one and lambda two given the data
and it's got a normalizing constant that we don't care about because it's just a
normalizing constant if all we're doing is thinking what we believe lambda one lambda two
should be
if we know what to do model comparison
there's no the end down here all the valence orbitals are filled
the only place goes up here in the conduction band so here's the electron
it came from phosphorus it was donated from phosphorus we call phosphorus a donor
this is a donor electron
can you see that every time i throw phosphorus and i'm going to get an
extra electron in the conduction band so if i want to increase the conductivity of
silicon just keep adding phosphorus
one for one of i'm making wholesale here
no i'm not breaking any one factor in forming bonds here
there's an extra electron everything's fine so now
i can i've got a lover
i can i can dial in how much conductivity i want
you want to raise the conductivity was certain value i can tell you how much
phosphorus to add to get to that level of conductivity
and this electrons not in the valence band it's not bound so we can move
so this this goes back to paul drew to the these electrons are free to
roam because they are not bound
surely something
i'm sure something really cool
how far can electron rule
so think about it
phosphorus is o five
five a one
so it's got an extra proton two
so this phosphorus is the five plus lambda four plus
so the phosphorus you can think of as locally plus
and this electronic didn't go into any of the valence
band orbitals you it's locally minus the electron is locally minus that's deep OK so
i've got the phosphorus that's locally plus
and i got electronics clean minus do you know of a model that might describe
the motion of an anchored positive charge with an electron free to roam due to
model of my talk about such things
bore so let's do something really whacked suppose we said we took this electron and
we said let's let's ask the question if we applied the bohr model to this
what we come up with
i mean it's going to give us energy is it's going to give us radii
it's going to give us velocities do you think there might be a relationship to
velocity and mobility and conductivity and
well let's see where it goes
let's go
so what do is also a member in recall in hydrogen atomic hydrogen
recall an atomic hydrogen the ground state energy this is the electron at the bottom
of the is minus k we've been calling k
which has this full
full-blown formula of e to the fourth over eight
one zero square h squared
plug in all the numbers and you get minus thirteen point six electron volts
minus thirteen point six electron
let's think about this
what we have to make a few changes
epsilon zero that's the permittivity of vacuum but if you're if you're electron you're looking
down the phosphorus it's not just vacuum between you and the central phosphorus there's all
this stuff there's blanche there's silicon nuclear
so i can modify this i've got
i'm going to change the so what i'm going to do something to take epsilon
zero which is what we have four vacuum and replace it with absolute
absolute of silicon
excellent silicon silicon is the host crystal
so what is it does this capture captures all bonds all the silicon all of
this stuff
so that's the
the dielectric constant
that's the dielectric constant
of the host chris
and there's one of the things some esoteric physics i'm going to put up here
without without proof when you're in this situation you don't use the the rest mass
there's an effective mass
effective mass
that in invokes a slight correction
the effective mass
of the electron
at the bottom of the conduction band
one of
the conduction band is a minor correction the main corrections getting the dielectric constant OK
so the second one is there for completeness some of you are going to look
back fondly at that these notes and say yeah we get this was good otherwise
he said we left the effectiveness
so you can see that now are so here's the you're the values for silicon
first silicon the dielectric
constant eleven point seven and the effective mass at the bottom of the conduction band
is one fifth of the rest mass on these values into this equation and what
is it gives me is that that the ground state energy of the donor
is minus k as we had before
an electric field that can be measured that has a amplitude n of thousand falls
from either
so this now is the right time
to take a closer look
and how electromagnetic waves
are produced
in a nutshell it comes down to this
you can create electromagnetic waves
if you accelerate charges
charges that are stationary or moving at constant velocity
i surrounded by radial field
pointing away all pointing inwards depending upon whether the charges positive
or negative
and there's no king anywhere in the field so when it has constant velocity over
i really
electric field lines
the moment however that you accelerated as you will see today
you're introducing king
in those fields lines
and that came is responsible
forty electromagnetic radiation it manifests itself
as electromagnetic radiation i will follow
classic derivation
that is verbatim
given that way in back if ian embarrassed therefore advises strongly
for the next thirty minutes
not to take any notes
the try to follow
my arguments that will help you way more
then that you try to also take notes because it's really verbatim
from backfield this classical derivation
as many
simplifying assumptions
but it a very nice result which has great practical
i have here
a charge q
which is located at position eight
so we have the charge q
it is at a at all
and it is addressed
and i'm going to accelerate that
in this direction
so i'm going to accelerate it
the next generation
which is in this direction i will not have to factor in there now i
will do that later
otherwise the wiki becomes too complicated
and i do that for delta thirty seconds
only very briefly
and then it ends up
at location o prime
which is here
so now it has this
the velocity in this direction
and that velocity u
in this direction
it is now a
time delta t
a one
and so it's cruising now is constant velocity
and we just let crews all the way
it's now again
the charge was constant velocity
and i look at it where it three seconds later
and so at time t
we'll find it in o double prime and it's still cruising and we just like
the crows we're not going to interfere with it anymore
and here is then o
double prime
the whole
exercise from o to o double prime
took so many seconds
that means there is this sphere around point o
and that sphere has radius which is sometimes people is delta t
outside that sphere the world has no knowledge
that this charge was accelerated
because that message has to travel with the speed of light
so i'm going to draw a circle but in in reality it is the sphere
in all the directions
which has already see
people as delta t
delta t by the way is way much smaller than t
and outside that sphere there is no knowledge the world doesn't have any clue
the fact that this object
was being accelerated
so i'll mark again to make sure that you
i can make a connection so this long
has its center at all
and the radius
is c
times key personnel fatigue
and if you ask me what is the
electric field right there
OK so it's better is that the methods better
and now we are going to make prediction
so in fact as usual we need to solve the preimage problem
OK it's certain facts in the same way as previously
so it's
it's an approximation
it's not approximate meeting here but
we will do it better approximation so i tried to find why prime
which is the close as
in the sense of these
this transformation five
and close as to this is to try to use the feature space
of course i can do the competition we can value
and i can do this
well usually a cannot enumerates why problem y
so what i'm doing
i replace y
by the output that they have already seen
in the training data
which again
it's an approximation i
but fortunately
we have
we don't need to do this
for all problems so remember problems
network completion problem what we want to do want effect can then
we want to learn can then
between outputs
but from inputs
so what we can say we find
and that's emission of some candidate k between object one object two
and this approximation is just the scalar product
of the function f
phi of x and the function s
and phi of x from all x x one x two OK
this is the same the same spirit
of proteins
OK so it's on bit longer story
because he says the competition
give you this
OK densities to competition and
not going to go i just say that it's possible to do this we have
six degrees
so beautifully and writes school by mathematics i wanted to say that is that it's
the it's
what like
that's but you must be carefully weighed
OK so i just wanted to say that OK output can entry
can be used as a bugs bunny
because it can be written as this
it's not very easy
remember that
the tree
constant is so what do is constant functions so
in each leaf
you are you are producing prediction
and r
on average
and so you can
manage to right
this is
this weight function
which is equal to one of a number of data training data which fall into
a leaf
and if eccentric ex-prime which is similar
o zero otherwise
OK so only one pass from the wall from the root to one leaf is
is taken from each state
i will quote to do this it's so it's nice link was
freeman did with this
also seems
and also i'm going to skip this if you use a single tree you get
into a better interpretability everything true wizards show them symmetry is of course you lose
interpretability that you have better results and you seem to be able to answer future
according to their relevance to the falls how could
the for the prediction and it's quite useful
competitions zone
learning is OK but learning is again done learning is usually quite
complex user mentions that's it
it's comparable to problem is spreading from stage it's of course
n square and it's
it's something using cannons cost
a lot back to the linear complexity of trees
OK just if you agree
so remember problem
this is the problem we know how to use the function h five no so
we know that we are able to h five
making the inner products
we're going to approximate
OK of y
quite from
so in fact we are going to be able to learn again
so if we will able to run again and were able to predict
four two new proteins
what is it can
values again in between two and four and then using this we should be able
to say that couple of two proteins if there is an edge on
by using some threshold
so when we be very new when we very this relation we get different tradeoffs
true positive rate some false positive rates
OK so which camera
well there is one ten which is especially devoted for data
which nodes quarks it's the diffusion can there
you know some of you know notice cannot
imagine that you are
metrics and engines and jens adjacency matrix that describes the graph
OK for instance you
physical interaction between proteins
and what you are going to be used is
laplacian of the graph
OK so the question is a graph is the following matrix
you're going to say that is a very good you're going to put the degree
of note
OK so the degrees just as the number
edges that start from this now
and you're going to put minus one
if two edges
what i and j j
are connected
and although zero otherwise
once you have these metrics with
which is very interesting in
space for cereal crop of class because it's a good picture game value that's really
interested to know many interesting meaning what range is going to do is going to
take the exponential
observations here
so those are the two to the twenty observations
and that using this part time i'm going to focus on the length scale
and i'm going to choose three different length scales and see what happens what my
what my my
prediction look like and i'm just going to look at the predictive mean in this
case find the predictions predictions of course have the predictive distributions associated with it
have associated with
all right so in right here i've chosen all of a sudden blue
and blue chosen very long lengthscale
very long lengthscale says that the we expect a priori
that function values correlate a lot even if the points are quite for space quite
far apart
if that's my assumption of that my prior assumptions then when i see the data
then i get if it looks like this
and obviously we can see by either that wasn't good in this case
OK so my prior assumption didn't metadata very well
so i can try again try at very short lengthscale that use very short lengthscale
then basically it says that the covariance between the neighboring points drops off very quickly
as a function of the input
OK and what you can see what happens here with the mean function is the
mean function starts wobbling around a lot
because it only has to move to a slight amount away from the from the
data point before the function can start doing things basically
and this and i suspect it is because the fit here is an almost perfect
fit to the data
i think it's it's not quite hitting those two data points for the rest of
the point almost got my if i reduce the length scale by a little bit
more to be able to fit the data exactly right
but actually in terms of generalization this doesn't look so good right now it looks
as though is actually it looks as like a smooth underlying function and the noise
associated with
so and
here in green have chosen in an intermediate
lengthscale that intermediate length scale gives the fit in green here which looks like a
reasonable fit
right and when i look at what is the marginal likelihood associated with this i
can compute that by just using the expression from before
just plugging in to this expression it's only depends on the data
and the evaluated covariance function here
when applying to that it chose chooses the agreement as actually how i found we
model i just plugged in the parameters and optimized with respect to the length scale
i came up with this with this link scales
so notice that this is despite the fact
but it's very easy for the model to fit the data exactly if it wants
to it doesn't want to
and we heard already yesterday
some of the reasons why
what the mechanisms are that prevents the models from liking fitting the data too much
find out
right so the question is now i'm i'm i'm i'm i'm optimizing of one of
those parameters could i could do things and we know that we should be careful
if we doing optimisation could be do things the better could we actually put a
prior over the length scales and then find posterior over length scales and you can
do that but it's not computationally
so easy to do that because you end up with with a collection of different
gaussianprocess like that you you can integrate them analytically right to end up with when
you can use monte carlo for example to to do these things although
the individual
models for the money market chain of course involves these major cities that depend on
the size of data so for big datasets you know this might get out of
hand at some point but ideally that's exactly what you would want to try to
what we're trying to do here is to get away with just optimizing very few
parameters and this entire model have only three parameters so it's not like it's not
like a parametric model
where you wouldn't be able to get you know if it like this if you
only had three parameters so it might be that we live in in better shape
in this case because we can manage to specify things in terms of very few
yeah sorry
so so so the question is you know why is the why is that the
right form of the complexity term right so that's an extremely good question that's the
next thing i'm going to talk about rights and notice here is that the marginal
likelihood so sometimes when you're in the in in the sort of regularisation framework and
you have a regularisation parameter you have identified terms plus lambda times the regularizer right
projective actrt two
the project x on unit vector the length project is just five hospitals u
so to formalise my PC problem could to chance back to you
to maximize
so choose use
this is set to the constraint that the normal view the length of US one
on the to maximize
this is something like this one to m
the length of the projection of the vectors x one
in particular when the sum of squared distances the projections to be far from the
original one
projections of x continued to large variance
and just to simplify
so the math later put one over on front
and so that quantity on the right
is equal to
one of around
the c
you transpose x i time i suppose you
and so on
can simplify and i get the new hospitals
this was
so i want to maximize
you transpose times some matrix times u
subject to the constraint that the length of u
most people to one
and so some of you recognise that this means you must be the prince for
i vector
this matrix the goal
so just write it down as if was about it
so this implies that you is steepest like vector
all of the matrix just call this matrix where that in terms of the covariance
let's cheque how you of how how many of you are familiar with i can
called mostly on the
one of the same phrases is very extremely familiar but this is where this was
saying anyway on
right so from
or if you have a matrix a and you get back to you
and they satisfy a equals lambda you and this is what it means for you
to and i can vector the matrix a on
and the value on the appearance of an idea value
so the press like vector is just the i can better the response largest eigen
one thing be made that some of you may have seen the not really have
just just one relate to stop you already know as well
is that on you know optimisation problem to maximize you transpose u subject to the
norm of u is equal to one and
right that constraint is that you try to this one
and so comes to
to solve this sort of you constrained optimisation problem right down to the ground
just want
well that's the lagrange multiplier
on and so because the constrained optimization right so he solves optimisation you take the
derivative l respect to you and that is new
sigma you know you you said iterative because zero and this shows that sigma you
equals lambda you and therefore
the value to solve this constrained optimisation problem i must be and i can back
you see in the particular turns out to be the principal eigen vector
just to summarise
well we don't we shown the given a training set
if you want to find the place for axes of variational data we want to
find a one d axis on which the data is very modes
what we do is we construct the covariance matrix sigma
the the the the matrix sigma wrote than just now
and then you will find the prince what i can vector of the matrix
and this gives you the best one d subspace onto which the project
and more generally
more generally you would choose
more generally if you wanna k dimensional subspace onto which the projected data
you don't choose you want the UK to be the top k
so afternoon session five forty five
so yesterday we talked about
kernels and harkens correspond to
the dot product in the space of the kernel is a similarity measure
it induces a representation of the data
i also mentioned that today i'm going to tell you that the kernel and in
some sense that specifies the function class that we used for learning
and the day before yesterday
we talked about why function classes i important are in which the function classes are
important for learning so learning we always have
dataset training set plus a function class
and then based on the training set we choose a function from that class
and how uh well let function will generalize
in other words how different training and test error can be for such a function
will depend
not just on properties of the function itself but on properties of the class of functions
from which we choose individual functions
so it's interesting to know what is the class of functions
and that we are
dealing with when we run collaborative
but before we get to that i want to revisit and i algorithm briefly talk about yesterday
and tell you that actually
quite interesting and that was this trivial pattern recognition algorithms
where we had we had two datasets
and i'm using slightly different terminology now
we call one other datasets
uppercase x
because collier other won why so we have a data set x over here
said why
and yes they were saying we will classify a new point
just by taking the mean of the data set x the mean of the data
dataset why and checking which of the two
let's introduce some notation for the mean
we can think of this as a
a mapping more an operator
that takes
is the input dataset
in input space
end produces the output of the average
of these images of the these data points the feature map
so i'm going to plug each other points in the data x into the feature map remember that
one representation the feature map was simply to say
the point x i is mapped to the function okay of x i with one of the arguments open
so that's
just another way of writing the feature map yesterday we were sometimes calling it phi of x i
i think it is is fireplace i feel like
so this operator takes a dataset maps each point
into the feature space and then takes the average all these points
in the feature space
we can do this for both datasets x and why
to get these two means mu of x mu why
remember classifier
what's this uh just looking which that means is closer and if we think about
this what kind of decision or does induce
it induces a decision rule which is a hyperplane in the house and is determined by this vector
connecting the two means
and is orthogonal to the vector
and it intersects this
the line between the two means halfway in the middle
so it's all decision rule end
what i have glanced over or class
class over and was the word
and so what i have not talked about was
and that of course we get a problem if these two means are the same
in this case this vector would be the zero vector aligned
it doesn't specify a hyperplane
so one way to deal with this would be just say let's assume it's not the same
but actually it turns out it's interesting to think about when it is the same
so when is it the same
obviously if we use the simplest case and we working directly input space which means
that we use the trivial kernel the kernel is just the dot product in the
input space
then this would happen
if and only if these two datasets
have the same means
taken in input space
now if we did it in a
different space with different kernel
i think about it for a second what if we take a polynomial kernel of degree two
so we use in the polynomial kernel yesterday
end we've seen that it
computes all product features of order two
polynomial kernel degree two
and that was the homogeneous polynomial kernel that i showed you yesterday
so it looked like this
and we can actually also construct an inhomogeneous polynomial kernel
which looks like this
and if you multiply
this art
have you just get a positive constant actually that we're not worried about that
then you get a term in terms of this and you get another term which has a square for this
which means that
this image homogeneous following polynomial kernel
and computes not just features of all exactly two but also features a all one
they are in this
linear term
so therefore this is the inhomogeneous polynomial kernel computes all features up to order two
so now what happens if we
not all data points
so now we would be happy
one our algorithm is adaptive enough so that
number of states will depend in some detail in way of a specific property of
the stream of history the even streams or going on
how the strings or other
four four for same
that's right
one of the great
the question i can
so the idea here
we have have maybe
but think the flavor
so there's going to be in bouncer in the in the simple in the simple
about would be OK let's assume that the stream of property then my bound as
a nice
for me however
for all the others have more complicated but i think it will prove more complicated
bounds that they will hold for any
and me
stream whatsoever irrespective of the structure the stream
of course this factor the factories
has to be related with linear feet
so if the stream can be fit well by classifiers
and if i want to use your classifiers to classify that is going to get
to be you
and the more
so the the structure would be the
really fit with some and with family classifier of history however
boston will hold for any of the three stream of course the bound become worse
as the degree of people with family classifier get
it's work
but in principle was about to hold for any any
so about this
this analysis is very robust
doesn't hold for it because
as in the case of this learning
but hold for arbitrary individual sequences
and in the case of game theory analysis book you can do this is sort
of game theoretic counterpart of statistical learning
group so let me give you a little more words about motivation here
so why
this is truly be the learning is interesting
OK first of all you can imagine you can still have a training set
and what you do
you just cycle
you've been stream by cycling over the training
in the end you might converge to something and something will be the or
final classifier output by the
i agree
and then you can test this classifier found on some test set
and get some idea of its before
so indeed i we show you in the end the reduction from online learning and
so we give you
we show you how
this results in this framework can be very quickly deleted with one of the largest
statistical inequality application one
two risk bound on the
not this station but in probability
so really i will i will be able to turn this mistake bound into a
bound on the basis of the risk
four classifiers
big from this ensemble
the classifier that generates so
we can recover
recovery results in the standard suffering
OK we ever boston which is nice because we don't have to take these assumptions
in the
there are lots of problems with the material online so
in cold weather forecasting much market forecasting these problems are really like this
we make provision on the market today and tomorrow see how the market when
and then you can adjust your your things
time series analysis
but even when you have a different situation because in this case like weather
or market you see the label model
you know what is going to be ready tomorrow
you know what the market how the market will we go
the more accuracy
OK but even in cases where
and you don't get the label for free
because for instance
classification of the stream of new
you're getting is a news feeds you want to classify the new
according to whether they talk about politics or not
it's not hard to
transformers these two modified it three months to get the nature of active learning online
he which essentially
the learner decide when to buy the label
so they decide on the of the
potentially gaining information that people get by by the label
whether the label for the current currently examples should be
otherwise it just gets away i mean this label and doesn't doesn't make enough
but then this is an interesting area which is know classifier place that is analyzing
the news and from that as and human expert because it could you please be
labelled with new
this is the news for me
so i can learn something useful here
OK i don't think we have time to talk about this active learning things but
keep in mind that this is
this is done
even if i mean practically that
and these are the work reasonably well
that means
would be a bit more of selling here
in general these
is all arguments are
efficient to run
easy to code
the above spend lots of time it just just just few lines of code for
for many of them
in the
strong performance guarantees
no that is your assumption is that already
you can obtain response was said that and you can do nice things like tracking
so this is something that comes up pretty
i was already asked by
by him so what happens if you might have briefly of stream
that for the first time for the first part of the good faith with a
simple linear classifier
but then something in the semantic in the underlying phenomenon that is generated the changes
i was asked to
to get some lectures to this course i had to look into my crystal ball
and try figure out who was going to be here and what level of expertise
the hard and unfortunately i didn't give much information from my crystal ball
what i'm going to be talking about over the next three possibly four lectures
i'm going to be starting off in a very
gentle label
well introduce the whole notion of linear regression models
from a very classical was based approach
from there
i'll move on and introduce you to the whole notion of linear models within a
probabilistic framework so within the likelihood framework and will be looking at maximum likelihood estimators
and generalized linear models
from the take up step forward
and i'll introduce you to the whole notion of the bayesian paradigm was unknowingly and
generalised linear modelling framework
and then from there
i'll introduce you to the whole notion of gaussian process priors over functions and how
these priors can be used for
regression and more interestingly for classification problems
be warned i will be starting in very
basic and simple labels
and by the time we get to the final lecture
i would imagine most of you will be getting a waterfall for what i'm talking
about so i'll be introduced two mean field approximations variational approximations alternative likelihood functions such
as the multinomial probit and so forth for gaussian processes
OK so
i don't think that because this lecture is going to be simple and all the
rest are and all this is going to be simple i hope that you'll get
some insights perhaps into things that maybe you already know
and for those of you who don't know all of this work then hopefully and
it will give you a good foundation two
well to develop your own methods are or to
study this view little bit more
i'm using some lecture slides from a class which i teach at glasgow
and this is the
the web address
so you'll be able to download some of the lectures slides
and there are also sets of nodes which
give you want more detail
about the material in the slides
and then there are also some laboratory exercises
predominantly laboratory exercises and hollywood of a little
my klopschitz
which you can use to to study
various methods which are being considered and we'll be using some of these in the
lab so if you just take note of that that web address and mu
will use some of these scripts
and in the laboratory sessions
great and so
let's get started
no point in my starting off with linear regression when i meant to be talking
about kernel methods and
gaussian processes were primarily because these are the
well they did the whole basis upon which
all of these other methods about so i think if we if we cover these
and we have a good understanding of what these methods are
then we can
better appreciate the more sophisticated are settling more sophisticated sounding methods which will come
later on
linear regression
again you probably
some of you have probably covered this if it feels familiar to you so hopefully
this will be added pressure
and for those of you who haven't then
hopefully you'll find this some more interesting
now i'm going to try and cram two lectures into one
so let's see how we get on
the whole idea of machine learning
the end of the day is that we want to land all
those of us who are more statistically minded see what in there
a functional relationship
between a set of attribute variables
and some
of target variables
and for those of you who are listening to what keynes lectures are some of
the discussions about the work is doing in
microsoft one of the things that the
sweep about an awful lot of things like clickthrough rates and well click-through rate what's
that well it's
a response to target variable
and the
attribute variables that
the high for that particular problem are the
attributes such as
the set of web pages
there have been visited the amount of time that has been spent on those web
pages and so forth so this is a very
problem and is one which is is quite university
so learning of functional
the relationship between attribute values
and target of or response
the table
and of course the whole motivation is that if we have a good model
on the relationship between the attributes
between of predictors and our target values
then we can use this model to predict
target values and an unknown second place so different new set of attributes
what is the prediction that we can make about architecture target value so given a
new user who's been browsing on our website what is our prediction for the click-through
data this individual
so the question of course is hard to believe this relationship given that we only
have a finite set of observations
and more importantly once we have learned this relationship so once we even sent some
functional relationship how can we assess how good
the model is
as a predictor
how much trust in place in the model when we go into an unknown environment
and we start making predictions
so we need to be able to
objectively assess this
developing this shop understands by connecting that there
there actually data in RDF and connecting it with other data sources and they have
the potential to drive more traffic into the online whisky shop
so is the simultaneous publication this data in HTML and RDF
in terms of understanding how this the data in this in this whisky so i
might be might be exposed as linked data first of all we want to try
and understand what the the kind of core entities are in the second data set
so in the example of whisky this if we're talking about scotland particularly but the
same applies for ireland or japan the states only sort of whiskey
places the number of distilleries
in each of these is based on the number of in in one particular location
in these locations grouped together into a number of whisky distilling regions
i think the six or seven depending on how you choose to measure
in scotland that's
each distillery might have a particular found in a particular person historically was very very
important in setting up the distillery in one i have a master distiller who is
this kind of whiskey guru
and each one will produce a number of brands one or more rounds
and we that brown them might have a number of products so this is also
kind of rich relationships here the link together the information in the whiskey domain and
you can see that from things like the
particularly the regions there is a link between these particular distilleries and a particular geographical
locations might be represented in in other datasets such as those geonames
so as well as the more kind of factual information that we also think there
might be kind of photos and reviews and comments and office for people selling whiskey
so this is the kind of things in the core dataset and we need to
think about how these things relate to get and how go about publishing this this
data initially in RDF and then on from there on to how we might think
about other datasets
so that's the last slide in this sense hand over to richard
i think some so
what we're seeing now is
basically tom showed us the
thank you gave us the idea of the data model of
behind this site that we want to expose as linked data
so i want to talk about how to go about actually
get out the linked data from the technical point of view
and so
basically this is seven easy steps and i will i will work so that i
would have kind of i'm assuming that
i'm not going to talk about
rdf modelling here
of course the data is based on RDF so whatever they want to put out
as as linked data you have to
he was details of RDF modelling like you know there are these data types and
how do you represent lists in RDF guarantee the idea of listing out of sequence
and so on are not going to talk about these things
but will focus on the it's the part that is specific to linked data so
these seven steps are basically number one we need to select vocabularies because RDF involves
classes and properties which classes properties should we use that i find them to create
my own what holds this work
the number two the state is probably going to be huge
and it's going to be too big to publish on the web and just one
chunk so we partition the data into
into smaller pieces
step three will be
each of these pieces will have both
get URI we assign URI to it
in order to be able to fetch from RDF from defection RDF document from the
queue next it's going to be
to create HTML variants of
each of those they pieces of data
because that will allow us to
kind of people backwards compatible with traditional HTML web browsers so the stuff that we
do link they decide is gonna work also in HTML browsers and in the new
data browsers and
the semantic web crawlers and so on
the next step the first step is going to be too
actually assigned your eyes to the entities in
so too the distilleries and two different brands and to the reviewers and so on
this is this
p is pretty late in this list of seven times here but
as we will see
you actually have to kind of do these other things before you can
before you get the point where you can assign DUI's
four for the for the entities of interest
and the six it's going to be too
just improve the linked data a bit by adding page metadata into what i call
being sugar
and finally just to kind of finished something of a semantic sitemap and so now
i'm going to go in sequence two
these steps
somewhere in between i think ten thirty there's the coffee break and so
right so somewhere like this is a very technical technical like probably the most technical
section of the
of the tutorial so it's probably good to have a break in between so we
get some coffee
you can't get risky
so i will talk about this
the data we just assume you have at some it could be in the database
could be
maybe you have it in RDF already in the big rdf file maybe it's you
just pull it out of the web service whatever
and so i assume that you somehow have the ability to
get a piece of the data like you know with the database query quickly and
transform the output of this sequel truly to RDF you know to to just just
make a chunk of RDF all of this so i will not go like this
is very specific to the to the
two your concrete data set or to your concrete sites that you want to put
online how exactly you store the data and how you get it into
and how you get it from there into these
kind of data pages or HTML pages to talk about
i have a short list of two weeks later on that a few with some
specific specifics in areas like if your data in the database you can use the
tool called d two r server if you RDF already if big
RDF store was a and you want to expose this is linked data then you
can use the tool called b and so that we get to this
to this data
all right so
the first step is to select vocabularies
we do this because
we want to create an RDF graph and
so the basic rule here for selecting vocabularies
if you can reuse an existing vocabulary
that makes the data more valuable because it makes it easier to integrate data with
this was
stuff published by other people
like if there's you know if there's another side that deals with whiskies
then you if you use the same vocabulary you just can use them
then then it's very easy for third parties to just hold the two pieces of
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
announcement be the
on quiz 9
weekly quiz tomorrow based on the content of homework 9 which is remember what it
is but you know what
I made up of some already thinking about the next the next glorious events
others can remember this chemical kinetics and glasses that's right chemical kinetics of amorphous solids
that's right OK I'm moved last day we started talking about diffusion which is solid-state
mass transport by random atomic motions and we were drawn to the paper that set
up on the display which was published in 1855 by the of which gave us
the law that bears his name in describing how
matter diffuses through matter but if it was a very talented individual it might draw
attention to something else and in 1870 he described the way of the Member was
a physiologist he actually did some work in medicine as well and I he described
what survives to this day is the 3rd principle for determining a cardiac output and
basically equates the amount of uptake of oxygen by with the amount that should be
distributed the blood but you have to take arterial oxygen pressure minus venal oxygen pressure
to get the efficiency of the heart and so I found this a lot
the cartoon after the web that just briefly encapsulates the notion of the 5th principle
measuring cardiac output his nephew by the way it was as a young child can
also has the name out of fear and the young adults 6 of the nephew
of was strongly influenced by
the article
and he went on to invent the contact lens so this family has been quite
a prolific in ways that influenced many of us in this room were wearing contact
I think we're all thankful that there is some cardiac efficiency and I think we're
beneficiaries OK so let's take a look at in more detail and what effect Odyssey
said that if we have in grasp of species i into some solid on the
rate of ingress is given by
of the equation shown here which expresses the flux which is mass per unit time
unit cross sectional area as proportional to the concentration gradient and the proportionality constant is
the diffusion coefficient and what we see here is of a a sketch of what
that might look like and some initial surface concentrations and held constant with the interests
of material and since the
flux is the derivative you can see that the the flux but for some of
the multiplication factor tracks with the
the concentration we have the steepest concentration gradient at the surface and deep inside the
specimen there's
essentially no concentration gradient so the flux attenuate so what's shown here in future and
concentration shown here and profile when I say profile profiling means that something has function
of of
distance so profile in this case is a concentration profile already flux profiles so you
can see those 2 and then we started looking at some atomistic reason that there's
some jumping involved and with the jumping comes the notion of activation that we looked
at this and we concluded that there's an activation energy associated with jumping on through
that saddle arrhenius type behavior in natural log of the linear in reciprocal of the
absolute temperature remember this is not the Rydberg constant this is the gas constant which
is the product of the Boltzmann constant the boltzmann constant and you have to get
the number and units will give you a clue as to which uses the activation
energy is in units per mole then obviously use gas constant otherwise usable some constant
and we looked at the atomistic further we reason that when we have diffusion by
vacancy jump mechanism this activation energy up here in the equations is the sum of
2 components 1 being the entropy of vacancy formation which is really the negative of
the binding energy and then the energy associated with the atom migration which is the
energy of squeezing through that saddle point shown in the figure in in the case
of interstitial diffusion we don't have to do vacancies there's another vacant sites by virtue
of the fact that we've got so much free volume even a close close-packed solids
were really just paying for the sum of the entropy of migration and last week
we looked at how these 2 are related to the degree of confined in other
words the atom is restricted by the the the ease with which you can run
down it's appropriate raceway error and we're increasing that going through the bulk lattice is
the most tortuous path and has the highest activation energy loss diffusion coefficient grain boundaries
right so this is
philosophy one seventy six
the classes on death
my name is shelly kagan and the very first thing i want
to do is to invite you to call michele
that is where we need on the street you become talking me during office hours
yes in question shell is the name that i respond to
i will eventually respond to
professor kagan about the synopsis take a bit longer for that it's not the neyman
immediately recognise
i have found that over the years fewer and fewer students feel comfortable calling michele
when i was young seemed to work now i'm grey and august but is that
shelley if you're comfortable with it's the name that i prefer to be called by
now let's this is the class on death
but it's philosophy class and what that means is that the set of topics that
we're going to be talking about in this class are not identical to the topics
that other classes on death might try to cover so the first thing i want
to do is say something about the things we
i will be talking about that you might reasonably expect or hope that the class
and s one talk about so that if this is not the class you were
looking for you still have time to go check out some other class
so here are some things that class and that could cover that we won't talk
about it and what i primarily have in mind are
sort of psychological and sociological questions about the nature of death
phenomenon of death and so a class on death might well
i have a discussion of the process of dying and coming to reconcile yourself with
the fact that you're going to die
some of you may know about was nicola ross's discussion of the so-called five stages
of dying there's denial and then there's anger and then there's bargaining i actually remember
the five data we're not going to talk about about that similarly we're not going
to talk about the funeral industry in america and how it rips off people in
which he does rips off people in their moments of grief and weakness and overcharges
them for for the various things that offer we're not going to talk about that
we're not going to talk about the process of grieving
or bereavement we're not going to talk about sociological attitude that we had towards the
dying in our culture and how we tend to
you know try to keep the dying are hidden from the rest of us these
are all perfectly important topics but they are not as i say topics that we're
going to be talking about in this class
so what will we talk about well
things will talk about our philosophical questions that arise as we begin to think about
the nature of
like this here in broad scope have class is going to be the first half
the class is going to be metaphysics for those of you who are familiar with
the philosophical piece of jargon and roughly half the class the second half the class
is going to be
value theory
so the first step the class is going to be concerned with questions about the
nature of death
what happens when we
indeed to get that question the person might have to think about is what are
what kind of an entity
is a person in particular do we have souls
and for this class we'll talk about it so what i'm going to mean a
sort of a bit of philosophical jargon is going to mean something immaterial something distinct
from our bodies do we have immaterial souls something that might survive the death of
our body
and if not what does that imply
about the nature of death what kind of an event is there
what is it for me to survive what would have been from the survive my
death what does it mean for me to survive
tonight that is you know somebody is going to be here lecture interior to the
class on thursday presumably that will be me what is the for that person who
is there on thursday to be the same person as the person who's sitting here
lecturing to you today these are questions about the nature of personal identity pretty clearly
to think about death and continued existence and survival we have to get clear about
the nature of personal identity these sorts of questions will occupy us for roughly the
first half of the semester
and then we'll turn to
value questions
is if death is the end indef banned
now of course most of us are immediately and strongly inclined to think that death
is bad but there are a set of philosophical puzzles about how death could be
bad to sort of give you a quick taste
if after my death i won't exist how could anything be bad for me how
could anything be bad for something that doesn't exist
so how could just be bad so it's not that the results but be to
try to convince that isn't bad but it takes as little bit of work to
pin pin down precisely what is it about that bad and how can it be
death and the more than one thing about that makes it bad
will turn to questions like that if death is bad then one might wonder is
what immortality a good thing about the question that will think about or more generally
worry about how should the fact that i'm going to
affect the way
i live what you attitude be towards my
mortality should i
should actually be afraid of death for example shy despair at the fact that i'm
going to die
finally i will turn to questions about suicide of many of us think that given
the valuable and precious thing that life is suicide makes no sense you're throwing away
the only life you are going to have and so will end semester by thinking
about questions along the lines of the rationality and morality of suicide so roughly speaking
that we're going first half the class metaphysics second half class value theory
the next thing i need to explain this
there's roughly speaking two ways to do
a class especially in introductory class like this
in approach number one you simply lay out the various positions
pro and con and the professor
strives to remain neutral
so sort not tip is hand about what he holds that sort approach number one
and sometimes in my intro class is that the approach that i take
but the other approach and the one that i should warn you
i'm going to take this semester in this class is rather different
there is a line
that i'm going to be
pushing if you will or defending in this class
that is to say
there's a certain set of views i hold about the issues that will be discussing
and what i'm going to try to do in this class is argue for those
who try to convince you that those views are correct
help you know ahead of time quickly what those views are i want to start
by describing a set of views that many of you probably believe so i'm going
i squared of all these elements and i which each of the individual radio or
and this now
is what we call
the moment of inertia i
don't confuse that with imposed has nothing to do with polls
and this is moment of inertia
so the moment of inertia is the sum of and i are i squared
so this can also be written as one half
i put to sea there you will see shortly why because the moment of inertia
depends on which axis of rotation i choose
times omega supreme
and when you see that equation you say hey that looks quite similar
two one half
MV squared
so i had to this list now
if you go from
many emotions too
rotational motions
you should change them as new linear motion to the moment of inertia
in your rotational motion and then you get back to you one half MV squared
you can see that
so we now have a way of calculating the kinetic energy of rotation
provided that we know how to calculate the moment of inertia
the moment of inertia is boring job is no physics if math
and i'm not going to do that for you with some integral
and if the object is nicely symmetric in general you can do that
in this case for the disc
which is rotating about an axis through its center
any the axis it's important is perpendicular to the disk
it's essential
in that case
the moment of inertia
calls one of
are square
and i don't want you to remember this
tables in books and you look these things up
i don't remember that i may remember for one day
then obviously
you forget that
very quickly again
needless to say that the moment of inertia depends on what kind of object you've
already have this already have this sphere already have overwrought makes all the difference and
also makes it different about with which axis to rotate the object
if we had a sphere solid sphere
then so here have a solid sphere
i rotated about an an axis
through its centre
then the moment of inertia i happen to remember
he calls to fish and are square
if r is the radius
and is the mass of the sphere
my research is in astrophysics idea was stars and stars have rotational kinetic energy will
get back to that in a minute and not in minute but today
and this is the one moment of inertia that i do remember
if you've ever rolled
you that is rather rotate about an axis through its center
and this axis is perpendicular to draw out the latter is important perpendicular to the
and it has length l
it has mass
at the moment of inertia which i looked up this morning i would never remember
because one twelve l square
all these moments of inertia you can find in tables in your book on page
o nine
so the moment of inertia for rotation about this axis
of the solar disc
is one half hour squared
but it's completely different the moment of inertia
if you rotated it about this axis
so you take the plane of the disc instead of rotating it this way
you rotated now this way you can totally different moment of inertia
and most of those
you can find
in tables
but not all of them
tables only go so far
and that's why i want to discuss with you
theorem which will help you
to find moments of inertia in most cases
suppose we have a rotating disk and i will make you see the disk now
with depth of this is the disk
we just discussed
rotation about the centre of mass
and i call this
axis l
so it was rotating like this
and those perpendicular to the disk this is the moment
of inertia
i'm going to drill a hole here
and i have and actions
l prime
which is parallel to that one and i'm going to force this object to rotate
about an axis i can always do that
i can drill a hole
given x nicely
frictionless bearing and i can foresee to rotate about what now is the moment of
if i know the moment of inertia then i know how much
rotational kinetic energy is that's one of i'll mean squared
another is theorem
which i will not prove
it's very easy to prove
and that is called
the parallel
and that says
that's the moment of inertia
of rotation about l prime
provided that l prime is parallel to l
it is the moment of inertia
when the object rotates about an axis l
through the centre of mass
the mass of the disc
times the distance the square
this is the mass
that's very easy
i think to apply and that allows you know
in many cases to find the moment of inertia
in situations which are not very symmetric
imagine that you have to do this
that you actually have to do an integration
of all these elements derived from this
point on that would be a complete headache in fact i wouldn't even know how
to do that