the camera translation zoom and out of plane rotation
and the values of other right so
the see
once you notice that as you go from within the red black and green block
as you go from darker shades lighter shades you go from right to left that's
as you go from the deep seated as go from the shallow networks to keep
network and so the analysis of these results is that as the governor shall endeavour
to deepen were these algorithms actually do exhibit more invariance to a huge range of
invariances of honesty i have no idea why this is true is an empirical result
i think is actually fascin there questions still to figure out why why you get
this effect but you should on this morning mentioned one of the motivations for wanting
to do deep learning as that of the it's the theoretical motivation for doing deep
learning in terms of computing these circuits needed service the and i think of this
as maybe a empirical answers to the question of why i want to do these
in these results empirically invariant representations you and increases with the depth of the presentation
and i don't know why this is true
of it unless you get zero the zero of because this normalized with the scale
the features is divided by the variance there
i don't know i do not believe there is up with what about this i
haven't family tree but this stuff going on here so various hypotheses of i think
everyone all the ones i would do in common with the mean is that if
you want to work
the see so some conclusion one generally deeper features appear to be more variance
additionally sparsity also seems help make the features more there and with the exception of
one for two and three their models the red lines are generally lower than the
lines and so somehow sparse they to make the features one variant of game i
don't really know why other kind has has post giving you think lyrics and this
yes that was one of my other hypotheses i do not believe that's all that's
going on on that may get some of these but if visualizations units actually although
in a very different things so you can't so i don't believe this is going
so you are the
they are
right so this not the thing not in this specific thought so all of these
were forty by forty fourteen image patch so i have no idea how the album
was the invariants from which is
they just mention one more comparison which is the blue line here this template matching
game details the complicated some of the the tenth nationalistic an image patch learning that
p of p
and so with deep architectures here these we do
the more their features that have matching and this is another common i think when
we visualize in it
i work on the post as we saw a lot of our we tend to
visualize second third features by squashing down into flat image
and i think that's useful thing to do
but i think there's also captures that squash representation is actually not telling the entire
story in fact of these features are actually more invariant and yes simple template matching
the what you get with these things and squashed into factor
on internally
my sons using these sources in various tests to guide their own the development of
the learning algorithms
there are actually many other possible in the test that that you can use this
on this is one that i guess number of others that this made closer to
prior art in which you can show you a sinusoidal grating have an enormous is
my album in the face of creating the all the rotational gratings of various people
have done these especially common context modelling complex cells
this one in various has an extremely difficult i don't think any deep learning how
does long that was we tested do not but which is casually out of a
lot of images of objects and find the feature this the means optical i don't
think any album does one is but these are the sorts of invariants as we
called to give it another evaluation metric
so the second evaluation method is the application of these ideas to classification as the
sort of self learning
and you we do pretty much exactly what you expect we take the unlabelled natural
the use of learning a sparse coding of one or two or three layer deep
belief that almost sparse coding representation
use the representation and and off the shelf classifier and we find that for many
using these learned feature representations of learning from unlabeled images we get reasonable performance of
this was the table the whole at present the main conference like caltech one one
we get your sixty five percent performance which has come to the fore in many
cases better than the sort of had the features you get from computer vision
of and so the cost to the same thing from all the old this is
these also holds results and the cool thing about this is that hot a feature
resentation from label audio
and use exactly the same feature vector exactly the same you know what the representations
for the six different talks and in
almost all of them on youtube terrapins of the hand engineered features mfccs
and so on and over the years because the tried is a large range of
problems like text classification heritage everyone knows how to
OK on
real quick
comparisons i know polish comparisons are not
something i don't know but for inspiration that percy find it useful
not not as the ultimate evaluation metric for inspiration often find it useful to look
at possible brain what i was doing this even our own sun making this also
computations we think possibly may be doing
and so
very quickly
one thing we did was learned to their response model and compare that to visual
cortical area v two which is in a ball in the second stage of visual
processing pipeline
i don't know so so once again this is all the source representations you over
to their model where you the edges the first their combined age is the second
would tell us or an explanation for why they should all cancel and the true
value of the cosmological constant should be zero but perhaps there is one
perhaps son some unknown dynamics or principle tells us that the global vacuum energy is equal
to zero but we're still getting there we haven't reached this final state
there is some scalar field that you can describe and this vacuum energy is a
cosmological constant and the scalar field will eventually far in the future reach phi equal
to zero so these are the approaches to modify the right hand side of the Einstein
equations like adding something to T zero zero there are also approaches to modify the left
hand side of Einstein's equation by changing somehow the framework of the gravitational model in
which the expansion rate is calculated there was an observation in nineteen ninety-nine by Binetruy
et al  that in brain world models the Einstein excuse me the Friedmann equation does
not come from the zero zero component of the Einstein equation rather the Friedmann
equation if you have branes and certain extra dimension frameworks comes from matching discontinuities
in the derivative of the metric as you cross a brane and it's possible you know
the idea that the Friedmann equation does not come from something simple like the
zero zero component of the Einstein equation perhaps tells us that in some brane theory
we might get  of a Friedmann equation that's not H squared is equal to rho
then people looked in extra dimensional theories and there was some ideas that the gravitational
force law becomes is modified at large distances there is the idea that the universe actually
becomes five-dimensional at cosmic distances then there's this idea I don't think many of
you are old enough to remember people used to explain the redshift in terms of
something known as tired light that light as it propagates across the universe gets tired and
its wavelength gets  redshifted well there's an approach that I describe as tired gravitons that
when gravitons are  produced they're confined to our brane but if you go
over cosmological distances their wave function  could spread a bit and they could leak
into the bulk there are also extra dimensional theories where gravity becomes repulsive at large
distances there are gr there are  theories of extra dimensions well all theories of extra dimensions have
an infinite tower of excited states in the effective four-dimensional field theory this Kaluza-Klein
tower and there are some possibilities where the first excited mode of the graviton is very
light as the distance scale mass of smaller than an inverse gigaparsec so if we look
at gravity on distances of solar systems less than a gigaparsec it's essentially a
biometric theory but if you go to  very large distances the cosmological distance where
the supernovae are coming to us it is a a  single metric then there is
this idea of some colleagues of mine Sean Carrol and Mike Turner at Chicago who propose that they are
smarter than Einstein and Hilbert and they realized that  Einstein and Hilbert got it wrong in
nineteen fifteen the gravitational action is not the square root of G times R but it's the square
root of G divided by R and then there's the idea that it's the back
reaction of inhomogeneities and people here at CERN have have played a a big role in this one
of the things that I think comes out of these attempts to modify gravity at
large distances is the realization of how difficult it is to modify gravity at large
distances while keeping consistency with observations on solar system scales precision test of gravity and also
without leading to theoretical unpleasantness like ghosts or nonlinearities so you can't say that
it can't be done and some of these people think that their particular model does it
but it's not so easy to modify the left hand side of the Einstein equations
so we don't know whether it's the right hand side of the left hand side
so you might make the statement that nothing more can be done by the theorists
in this matter it is only you the astronomers who can perform a simply invaluable
service to theoretical physics by giving us more observational information about dark energy well this
quote comes from a letter that Einstein wrote in nineteen thirteen to an astronomer at Berlin
Freundlich encouraging him to mount an expedition to measure the deflection of light
by the sun and of course astronomers are very naive when an astronomer hears
something from a physicist they immediately think it's a good idea so in fact this
poor guy decided to mount an expeditions to measure the deflection of light by
the sun unfortunately he wanted to do it in nineteen fourteen and the eclipse was best seen
in the Crimea and while he was there the first World War broke out
he was imprisoned he never did the experiment was released a year later or so but
it was very unpleasant for him so maybe astronomers should be a little cautious in following the
advice of physicists also it's probably lucky for Einstein that this happened because in nineteen fourteen
he had the wrong prediction for the deflection of light by the sun that wasn't completed
until nineteen fifteen so he he would have gotten the wrong answer but Freundlich
would've gotten maybe the correct answer but it would not have agreed with Einstein's prediction however
one can make the case that we have all these theoretical ideas perhaps none
of them are good perhaps none of them are right and what we need is some
sort of experimental guidance some observational guidance to tell us  whether it's the left hand side
or the right hand side or something different so in order to try to wrestle with this
issue in the U.S. last year there was something known as the dark energy task
force that I happen to be the chairman of and there was sort of a cool thing about an
airplane when somebody would say why you're going to Washington and you say well I'm
on the dark energy task force and then they always ask do you actually know
Dick Cheney so what we tried to do is to suggest some sort ofs experimental
strategy and the experimental strategy I think is a good idea the first thing
we wanna  do is to determine as well as possible whether the accelerating expansion
because really solve the problem
so long ago a i people said this cannot be a good approach
what's happening on the web is the realisation that in this approach
you know there's something inherent about the web
the web you don't get to judge whether all the other pages on the web
as good or bad other i mean by some
abstract notion of that you just when you create your web page
link to the things that you know about and that you want to talk about
and those people do the same thing
and eventually you get now
according to the latest numbers i've looked and this now a little more than a
dozen web pages for each and every person on earth that doesn't mean describing each
that and that's just the open web that doesn't include stuff behind firewalls and so
there are now an order of magnitude more web pages and there are people
and what pages and is increasing considerably faster than people
OK so essentially the the amount of information out there
just trying very very fast in a certain sense an uncontrolled growth thing rather and
then how do we tell what's good information what's been information we use are human
reasoning powers
not the machine to do that so you google for something
google gives you some suggestions using an algorithm
if you look at the pages again gave you when you say i like this
this one doesn't sound right to me
who the heck is this guy
all this is one of my friends i really trust that
things are going to use a lot of your human flavor on top of what
an algorithm gives you
every single day on the web so this process
could we take that same idea suppose we have a whole lot of different
dataspaces i'm actually going to talk about this later in the afternoon
and we link these things together
right so
just as an example the one top of musicbrainz has a lot of information about
musical systems
the one over here called DDTD is a representation of the link space wikipedia with
things on wikipedia talk about which other things wikipedia geonames tells you about places so
you can intuitively see that somehow you could put together those three data
without boundaries without them
using different representation to find some way to work between the different data
approaches then you could you answer a question like
o i'm looking at a musician who grew up near i where i did
who else what other musicians grew up near where i
and you would do something like use musicbrainz to figure out the musicians are
then you go to the pedia to figure out which of who they are and
where they grew up
and then you go over to geonames to see which of those places are somewhere
close to
what someone say you know what famous musician grew up near where i did we
now have the data set to do it but of course
there's lots and lots of data about how do we find it back to the
problem so now we put the human back in with the data
so in this view the idea is that we break down the barriers between lots
of different stuff the the way we broke it down
in the web
and then our hope is that
we can somehow
use that same stuff from the web
to put it back together
so in this view
there's a lot of excitement
because now we're talking about something that looks like the web
and now we're talking about something that scales like the way
the notion is there's lots and lots of data out there
and there's very little semantics out there so if you just add a little bit
of semantics to sort of find the right stuff at the right time
you would have a big win
and again i say find i don't necessarily mean search it's answer queries it it's
find the right kind of papers for this
for the problem you are trying to sell things like that so
the idea is you want to declare very simple little
relations that can be inferred apply these at scale heuristically perhaps to a very very
data sets so
again i have lots of information i can grab from different places about different people
i see somebody named john dominic here and i see somebody with a similar name
here i see somebody with a similar name it
there's lots of people in the world with that name
right well if i can start saying hey but you know these four are actually
the same one
that can be very powerful
so this guy blogging this livejournal i have reason to believe is the same person
who is being described in this wikipedia page
who is the same person who came up in this google hit who is the
same person
you know is that this university now suddenly i can answer some very powerful queries
that kind of answer from those individual dataset so i needed to do
some fairly simple inferencing maybe the inferences if two people have the same email address
consider that maybe they're the the same person or heuristically assume they're the same person
will be correct
not one hundred percent time that you're doing
eighty ninety percent it's something the size of the web
you're doing very well
but the key thing here is that
now completeness is no longer
not only is it necessarily now what you're looking for
not only is it not necessarily what you're looking for its necessarily not what you're
looking for what i mean by that
it is remember time is money so
i saw a talk at an into internal google thing this was eight or nine
years ago when they were first really getting it up so
i can't really prove that this is today's math but they said at that time
if they could get google results ten times better
but it would take you seconds to answer a query
google would go out of business
right so if when you hit google you had to wait two two seconds but
you've got a better results people wouldn't work
furthermore if they could get it a hundred times is good
in five seconds it wouldn't keep them in business they become an issue business they
become the specialized search business
so again on the web what you want to get some answers fast here's my
favorite example of that
this is from a website called wine made by a company called radarnetworks it was
really maximises
this is sort of the top this quantity expected return
if from the next time step you you saying that the returns are going to
be defined or given
the function b
so if you believe that those are the future of the difference
this this is just the top unexpectedly turned
so this is my expected return if i take action a
and this is my top i expected return if i'm following policy pi
and that should be closed and then i call policy pi greedy
so that means
the policy is
is acting in a way that it tries to maximize this quantity right
that's very simple
and this figure one this fact
and so
we can conclude that he is a contraction
so ceased is a contraction has a unique fixed point and the next pair and
say that there is unique fixed point happens to be the optimal value function
so this is no longer to right
because from this
already you can you can sort of feel that
well if i plug in recent years
then this is the way i should i should always try to maximize the put
expected discounted return so if i shown that
from time step one
i will following optimal policy how should i
a concept c
if i should take a look at the
all possible actions
and other all possible actions the pope had expected
this going return assuming that from timestamp one i'm following an optimal policy so the
it turns out that is we start off at y
and i should just maximize this quantity
so it's it's
it's not to be wondered at that you have a six-man expedition
so this is just the mathematical constructions so that no women make that we know
everything about the environment
we don't care about learning at this stage
we are not yet there
so learning comes later i hope that well if you can finish to sing them
i don't know
learning to their today
very very little learning but tumour
you can learn the beach
the snow two
so to prove
so i want to show this group because it's so nice
and it's it's very simple as far
so one thing that you
you have to know
like i'm using innovation again here
it compares to operator something about that is more than equal to
some other operator
if applied this operators some back to apply the other operators some other vector
but i always had that one is componentwise smaller than the other
for the returns are smaller
so that's the definition of this thing
and there
it's very easy to see that for these operators tf client even pi is just
an arbitrary policy
this inequality holds
why because in you have max
instead of selecting their actions in a specific way
you're maximizing quantity so you should get something bigger
so they just immediate from the definition of t
if plug in
maybe select set and
the beach activations in the sand and
if you just like in the definitions and you can verify using this inequality holds
so this inequality holds
then we can conclude that the start
cannot be larger than b
OK so
so i mean
four or
keep i b
it's smaller than TV
and that
this competition is componentwise
so if you want
this spell like
even more
and they should hold for all for all the
but i see that he iceland he
OK so
these studies is not larger than the y
because the
we started so what do we know about the stuff so this is the maximum
of the value functions at the states is just about to maximize resource that the
policies right
so the definition of is that we don't have
any additional knowledge about it
OK so what we know know as well is that
if we keep applying t pi
so let's speak any any policies
and we keep applying t pi
to some
or the state space
then this is called matching two
is converging t
we apply the value function of the policy
we also know
that t by is is not larger than c so if we
apply instead of t pi
k times
then the again get something much
so p
applied k times to be zero
returning to do something
not smaller than if you apply here by i
OK thanks to be zero
and there is this guy converging t
well it's committed to be
the fixed point of t
we don't know yet if we was stopped right
the simplest maybe something called the escorts formulation where one simply decide that this thing
has not only the regular space-time coordinates but also anti commuting coordinate sign your site
fill them new left and right
if you don't like these where think of them simply as a string that is
it doesn't only have geometric motion space time it has some extra for munich
degrees of freedom that avalanche around the training and will give it some extra properties
and quantum numbers
if you really do the calculations before they just go through essentially in the same
way simply because they mention goes down to ten are that's better than twenty six
but still not very good of course for particle physics and the rest of the
analysis proceeds as before i want to discuss it anymore except for two crucial differences
so that's the only place where things change
this family owns that put in
to accompany the space-time coordinates surface thing can be either periodic or and periodic after
all the only observable are by linear unfair neurons in physics therefore if bailey linear
periodic around this
sorry around the closed training the families themselves can be either periodic or and periodic
this thing these conditions are known as the what's and that's why this thing is
called the pheromone schwarz string
if you use periodic conditions then this means that sign you
and i'm sorry so this for cross things
if you translate the corresponding fact for open strings when he tells you that shine
you cited them you will not have standing waves can be identified arbitrarily at one
point you know you can only absorb signed into the definition of in one end
but at the other end there is an arbitrary assignment game therefore this is the
analogue of
one of the swans boundary conditions was essentially an implication is that the frequencies of
these modes are integers environment sector and half integer universe wants
and i think in particular about sector sector who have is integer frequency for munich
modes going around the string
they have in particular is zero frequency counterpart and zero frequency means they don't give
any more mass or energy to this string
but this not commuting so the zero modes satisfy the canonical commutation relations
and if you look at these this is exactly an algebra of the right gamma
the article your data or of was say no zero easy you know that's the
dirac algebra this has to be realized on pheromone states because these will become operators
that don't change the must level of this thing
and which satisfy dirac algebra therefore there one states have to be spaced fine spinners
whereas i remember or look here we never introduced to start with spinoffs of space-time
these were simply spinoffs on a two dimensional surface
so that's how space-time far more the superstring from around one sectors
there is a second crucial difference from the blue explaining it turns out to be
consistent and necessary
to impose definite family two of the world she to make this theory consistent and
this is known as the archbishop called live
projection minus two VF is minus one
now i minus one i want to get three you can you have to get
your hands a little bit dirty she one minus and plus but that's the correct
i you have to impose now let's think about the spectrum of this object as
before taking into account this to new ingredients
so here is the open superstring
that must level minus the have that's the acllon
this is the ground state in the universe what sector were firmly serendipity object
at the first excited level which happens to be
zero mass
that's what fixes the critical dimension you get as before vector like particle if photon
excitation which is created by the half integer first half integer frequency of
so here's the four times before
how about that one sector well there in one sector of the family and some
of the boys and instead both periodic
they have integer multiple frequencies that zero energy fluctuations cancel out by two-dimensional supersymmetry therefore
there are one viking was directly massless
it doesn't have a document on the the other hand remember it realizes this dirac
algebra so it is a spinoff and it is actually gaugino it turns out
but it is a high dimensional gaugino lives in ten dimensions and in ten dimensions
digital can be both hierarchy majorana
and therefore that the spectrum of the lowest level of an open superstring it's basically
this super fall in ten dimensions actual is the bacteria is erased by the judicial
projection because it has even for municipality and one of the two chirality is erased
by the GSO projection and the reason is that minus two VF t commutes with
all the gamma matrices remember the zero modes of shy therefore it's exactly the chirality
operator and kills one of the two chirality so therefore dimensions you get the photon
you get divided by your and gaugino you can count physical degrees of freedom there
are eight of each of these theories supersymmetric and we'll come back to later
you can do the same exercise for closed strings it gets a bit more
missing because you have independent left and right sectors but let me now
got a bit more faster well at the master's level it comes from the what's
sector on both sides you get as before it graviton dilaton and some antisymmetric tensor
then there are these mixed sector is one of the left moving for me and
some of you are going to get the article right more than once set periodic
or vice versa
spinoffs from one side vector from the other side and they can be
actually exactly identified the supersymmetric partners of the gravity gravity need in ten dimensions
there is only one little freedom the chirality they can be of the same autofocus
and in these two cases are known as type two and type to be
this is the finance sector namely were both left and right moving fermions are periodic
there you have to realize two dirac algebra so it's been spin or in ten
dimensions so it's not fair municipal only has to spin in this is and this
if you analyse it
by using gamma matrix algebra you find that it really corresponds to yet another bunch
of the antisymmetric tensor fields which are referred to as or more and more about
and we going to be rejected
is it OK
a nondeterministic automata
there is no deterministic automaton
that can be
define two
if you assume assuming deterministic is is not the the language is specified initially also
when to accept the automaton except treat accepts tree if it has an accepting
so the languages
thirteen runs the language is a set of trees for which the system has
so all the acceptance condition i skipped here
all of them
it's frustrating to parity condition
so you should not
during the columns this is also about expressiveness expressive than parity
and so on so it's
so that the things
my hope was that by telling for example the
not so much on infinite words
finally connected components so OK
if true is given
by a finite
that represents the tree when you're probably
say if you're as the automaton is finite
only have trace much it is much more complicated than jets computing
but you have to compute some some
because of the automaton is addressed
and also so that you can
derive from this of exhibits a successful run on some of people
so what is see
the support
we use games
you know the
because of the
one of the lectures to show there is a bit and if you win it
then you will
you have found the weight of some
even colour
callers that are
yes it is complicated problem
as objects of finite
it's very very easy to see whether you have it
now you can
things would be great if you want to know
cholera occurs infinitely often
i think i have to say you look inside your cycle when you look at
the core of the what was
the presentation
it's a question mark
so so we answer immediately parity games
which is and so the question
again used two-person games two players
so all these things
what do they play with the we in
what is happening
so now in a very simple thing it's graph
with this so let me show you the pictures right away because
and run out of game
so that two players
circle is the same as the best
in general
you will use the tools will derive games
from the time of the one because has a winning strategy then the automaton has
a model
this is the game raising when you're in squared
player is zero player one
the way to this scenario
i don't need to tell you
formerly with it is
so what can we we have here we can play
so i can say here
so it is the want to play all he has no choice he has to
be here
so we have two choices so you can see here or here
three again it is his turn to play
he plays tracy place here and this one sticks to playing this with solar cells
so in thing
after some historians you mention here
can just two or three here but you can choose to play what here
and the other here
it can be able to generate
and the strategy is
for one player is the choice it makes she makes
some point
so strategies like you
around trail s two of the right play
that's another one so the strategy the function
which a
two propositional it's your turn because what to play next
and of course what to play next may depend on
so now i have to tell you how to win the game because now it's
just want how to play with doing is raising
have collars
when we play at your talk
so here if i have this thing here
i would have been
as you will
not be able to play any more
so to play where we reach a position when the one who was supposed to
this may happen in the west from it
no outgoing edges
well one loses the one who can play
and the loop is the one at the end of the play
and i look at the core of
this is not only a course for english majors
but for other majors two
the poets will be reading
well they they knew about science music politics economics and they presumed to talk about
those things
in their poetry and out of the poetry too
my lectures are going to presume no special
and you're part
i i see this as a course that's an introduction to the literature of the
to modern poetry
the will be studying several poets in some detail the presumption as well that they
they all
reward and demand a certain amount of close reading
at the same time i do mean to give you some
sense of the
period in which they are writing some sense of modernism
as is the field as one of the richest fields in the english language
finally though this really is a course and poetry plain and simple
i mean to introduce you to particular parts
to give you ways to
possessed them enjoy them
be puzzled or frustrated by them too
learn something from them
care about them into
carry them with you as you as you go forward
after this class
that's the sense what
i want to accomplish these lectures
it will mean reading a lot of poems
in writing about them some
the syllabus
you'll see notes the general topic of each lecture in the reading that i want
you to have done for that day
there's mid-term that will be a short answer test that's intended to give you a
chance to show how diligently you've been reading an incoming class
the the final will include both the short answer component and then some as a
there are two papers
a shorter and slightly longer one
the first paper is going to ask you to write about one short poem the
second will ask you to write about
two or more poems or poems perhaps by two authors or perhaps upon and some
other kind of text or image
the teaching fellows from this course i'm lucky to work with them and you youtube
they are trained and have have an interest in modern poetry
and this is a happy collaboration for me with them
as a so will start to get
our discussion sections organised on monday and they should be set i hope by the
lecture next week
i want you to come to lecture on time she wanted to that started on
i don't always do that but i'd like to and i can if you come
at eleven thirty
bring your books i'm going to be talking
about the text and i hope you'll have open
in the a course you will come to your discussion sections in the same state
as i say the the syllabuses
should be accessible on the class classes v two server
however i've had problems with that in the past and should please let me know
if it's not
there are just two books for the course
both labyrinth one is the first volume of the norton
anthology of modern and contemporary poetry
third edition
edited by johann ramezani
formerly a teaching fellow in this course
there's also
elizabeth bishop's collected poems
there will be a packet that you can order from RAS that's gathers if you
supplementary readings
there will be the visual images that going talk about in lecture and then i
will make accessible to you on the class server
there are also audio recordings of poets
that we will be reading that come from stirling
and you can get to on the centre for language study website
all those things we can talk about more as the semester develops
and i hope you will talk to me
you can do that on email you can do that in my office
which is downstairs on the first floor of this building and LC one o nine
you can catch me after lecture or before
we can have large all sorts of opportunities for talking and i hope you'll take
advantage of it
four monday
we're going to start talking about robert frost and and i'd like you to
pay special attention to respond mowing in in the RAS packet
into his palm birches in the norton
as you read
special attention to images of tools
read frosts
in short
poetic statement prose poetic statements in the in the norton called
the figure palm x
the norton anthology this but
this heavy book i ordered as as a way to
well reduce your expenses here is just one
big book to buy it also provides needed annotation
modern poetry is in need of annotation
this this new edition of this old
the book is an excellent one
you should read johann relies on his introduction
readers prose notes you know that
the preface his various selections
having said that there's really nothing said that is the norton anthology
you know or or ponderous and you know i i do agree with with a
little well
it is way
OK so
what i'm saying here is
we specializing two
limited class of motion the particle has a different activation a
in every situation where the body is an acceleration in the location has to have
this for
we this number is where it was initially
this was the initial blast
so when it through the thing up and you can't
what you're doing mentally
i was immediately figuring out where it started and what's
that was the initial
then in your mind without realizing it
you follow the trajectory at all future times
that is one other
celebrate formula that goes with this i'm going to find that
then we
i give you an example
now i'm fully aware that
this is not the flashiest
example in physics but i'm not worried about the right now will have you see
enough things that will come for you
right now
i want to demonstrate
a simple paradigm of
what it means to know the present and what it it means to say
this is what the future behaviour and want to do that the simplest context then
we can make the example more and more complicated but the full phenomenon will be
the same
so what we have found so far
and purposely going from x to y because i want you to know
the unknown variables can be colin x can be called the y
it doesn't matter
as long as the second derivative is it that's the answer
now that's the second formula one derived from
that's probably know that two from here
this is the day care i want to write the formula and put it up
and we can see
how we use the second formula
price to relate the final velocity
at some time t
initial velocity
and the distance traveled with no difference in time
so the trick is to eliminate high
from this equation
so let's see how we can eliminate time
you know that if you look at the end of it what is
finally of t
is the zero
was eighty
what that means is
if you know the last year the given time and you know the initial velocity
you know what time it is
time in fact the
when the zero or
they don't show you any argument for the mean to be at time t
and the subsequent zero means we have zero
so what this is
you can measure time by having own clock clock tells you what time is
we can also say what time it is by seeing how fast the particle is
because you know it started with some speed
it gaining speed summary a so speed was so and so now
and the time had to be time can be indirectly inferred
from these quantities
then you take that formula here
and you put it here that i would see at time t
you put this expression
what really get again expression in which there is no t he has been banished
i'm not going to waste your time by asking what happens if you put it
just tell you what happens
what happens is you will find the square
article visitors where
list two a
claims x minus x u
how many people have seen this
o thing before
OK that's alot look i know you've seen this
at the moment i have to go through
some of the more standard material before we go to the more non-standard material
this part of it easy for you
there's not much
i can do right now
so let me drop box
trying to box
you guys means
these are the two important things
i claim no
remember i want understand one thing
how much of this should you memorized was you've never seen this in high school
and with supposed to memory
i would say keep that to minimum
because what the first formula tells you
b so into that you don't have to cry
with the particles of constant acceleration
it's going to take two derivatives i want to get a
then you should know enough calculus and it has to be
something like it is where have come from taking to the evidence
the other two you know our stuff you can act
and you know what
well adding those things
because the particle
as the head start is good initial position even at quality zero
has an initial velocity
even without any acceleration it would be moving
from why not the when was vt acceleration gives you an extra stuff
quadratic time
once you get got that one that would give you the velocity
and in the crimes you can eliminate the input in this form
but most people and up memorizing these two because you use it so many times
UN statistics in you but you should try to memorize every
so we're not going to do
standard problem where
we will convince ourselves
we can do
we can apply the formulas and predict the future given the press
the problem i wanted do
there are many things you can do but i just pick one
this is the one with the all numbers so i can do to calculate
here's the problem
that is this building
and it's going to be fifteen meters high
i'm going to try something
and it's going to go up and come down
something i grew up
as the initial speed
of ten meters per second
we have to ask now know that my claim is
you can ask me any question you want what this part
and i can see
and ask me
where b
nine seconds from now it's taken from all of us will be moving
i can answer anything at all
but what i needed to do it to do this problem
i was to find these two unknowns you got to get used the notion of
what will be given
in general and what is tailor made for the occasion
so we know in this example
initial height should be fifteen meters
an initial velocity
the ten
and what acceleration
i'm going to use minus g
a learning algorithm or method of mapping that takes us from training data to functions
and we don't care what those functions i
right so so in particular you know have have here
it just takes as input x one y one through x and y and and
the function l
it's just some mapping to functions defined on x
OK doesn't and no longer restricted to choose f from some class it could be
you could use any any kind of functions
let's define the minimax estimation error in this
you know
n delta kind of way
we have a sample size and we have this
this company parameter delta
this is the best we can do
functions l over the algorithms or methods
right of the smallest error
we can hope for
and at delta level
OK so what does that mean that means
you know it is the
is this an excellent for which we can get
the risk
all this had the the function returned by
this method
within epsilon of the best
in the class capital
OK so here the criterion involves the class capital have not restricted choosing functions from
right for any method
any method here
what's the best method
whether tis from f or not
in the sense of minimising the deviation between
and minimal risk over that classifier
right with high probability
OK we don't want the deviation to exceed that's with probability more than delta
and this is going to be true all probability distributions
OK so whatever problem we faced with
we want to have the probability that we have we have worse than epsilon gap
between the best
we could for using f and the thing that our l returns
the risk of that if at
we want that probability to be small
OK so
for the sample error minimisation algorithm that shows that that this minimum
is no worse than
you know some constant times the square to the VC dimension of an essentially
right because in particular if we choose l as the element of capital f that
minimizes the sample average of loss
minimizes the empirical risk on the start of then we get
you know the steps along the deviation between the risk and the best in the
is of order something like this two-dimensional over in the square root of the at
that's for
sampler minimisation that that gives us this upper bound it turns out that that's the
that's essentially optimal in the minimax minimax sense
it's the
the right right anyway
so as long as his is theorem as long as the
confidence isn't it parameters is not too large can be treated as constant then
for a class that has VC dimension released the
is the least as big as something of order VC dimension of a skirt of
this invention over
we get we get exactly the right thing
and i put a minimum here because you know you can
come up with silly things when the sample size is small
to make this article not true
so this is this essential was not something to worry about everything just about the
OK so this this shows that the
sample error minimisation algorithm
if this is this upper bound minimax estimation error and that upper bound
can be
right so as long as you know the class your your comparing yourself to has
VC dimension at least d
this is the mesh minimax estimation error has to be at least as big as
grid mention of
going of square the average
should dr guess
OK that's
remember we're working you know we've got to perform uniformly well across all probability distributions
all right that's crucial in improving the converse result for the minimax right
we work with so so the idea of the proof of this lower bound
it is based on the probabilistic method we we
a probability distribution that makes life hard for
learning algorithm l
and we do that in a random way so that you know if if i
were to propose the probability distribution you could easily design an algorithm that would work
well for that particular distribution what we show is that if you choose the distribution
randomly from from some
from some set
then under the random choice you you do badly somewhere
right so there must exist the probability distribution makes life
right and so in particular when we look at the worst case of probability distributions
then you'll be doing
that badly
OK so
the set of distributions you know this this is all
classical that's quite nice
second process distributions concentrates
x on a shattered set and then chooses the wise with probability
you know it's possible minus one
so a possible plus one with probably half plus a little bit or probably half
months little little bit you choose randomly
right whether it's possible minus one here
plus one discipline over two
and you can show
in that case that for whatever
learning algorithm you have
the expected value
all of the excess risk
OK expected value expectation is now under the random choice of this probability distribution the
expected value of this excess risk is large
larger than its long
and therefore
there must be some probability distribution
that causes this difference to be bigger than epsilon
OK so this is the probabilistic method showing that under some distribution the expectation of
utilize the
parallel immersion learning algorithms
we were a a hundred performers
power efficiency
hard to do that
here's some interesting facts that lead to our
solutions approaches
the first think about the google datacenters the missions we have sufficient computing power for
of the
and each enterprise or individual only replicas that we care
for example and its
guys around the michelin there was some sort of the computations and the google around
the web search for the next thing and some kind of data mining
the general purpose computing want
designed for this specific task
four ethics that is specially designed hardware
it can lead to
the cells and
performance power
but it's very expensive
nine days they are more than
we want people to chip who created the mosque it me spend tens of
millions of dollars for the when past
but if you feel you when beta
that money will
will become neuhaus
collecting with this facts
OK let's move back
another is
application specific integrated circuits also suffers from the product design productivity
some design problems
a common solution is to have one
programming framework
four machine learning and data mining there's a very successful programming framework called mapreduce
there's many many work has been done here
so here comes our approach first
we will create
a supercomputer in a box
that is a combination of
actually g and suffused produce reaper when
got it is also semiconductor devices then you can create second was that i will
introduce more
the story
and the second
with this simple computer
have to design
a framework for programming it that from we can easily
programme the which in many ways of the money and get the palette that parallel
of this them automatically
you can hear the big picture left side is the programming side
we'll have applications
you designed the
the mappers or reducers i i think everybody here is very familiar with mapreduce and
with the members and to reduce you can utilize
the highway what this is cool
that's cool
can take the three also plus
programs as input
and the hardware circuit
so this is hard
the hardware the circuit will be programmed
so the so the circuit
will automatically
and the functionality we all
you can
implement many of the mappers reducers on percent
and also you can improve some user constant to let the system ran we'll have
some knowledge about the application
the right side is the picture side that's the supercomputer in a box
that's heterogeneous architecture refers to fuse and peaches
in the all the FPT we have
some pre
the final redesigned
building blocks
that's the interconnection network which
and that all the mappers and reduce errors
also on track on chip scheduler that can
scheduled the different task and they can manage management middle management module
and can fetch high and the
for the input and output
so this is the big picture
let's see why we select actually
first few the definition
five refugees field programmable
iterate is can changes functionality
after you you place
cheap on two young second bt
we sense
components you can create arbitrary logic
with guitarist
so what is guitarist is islands of recoverable logic
in the sea of reconfigurable interconnect
i have pictures for that
this is the basic
structure of music
logic block
for the PC
it is very
it's very easy
work but i want to
show that they had to look up people
there's a lookup table you can
design arbitrary functions all for your input model
also you can store the result in flip-flop
are we also need a way to express the relationship between members of these different
for instance one we like to say
that whenever an artist does something you create a piece of art
OK so is this property that relates every artist with a piece of art which
is named creates and you see out
you've write this down so you say creates is appropriate
if you think it in first order logic which are sainsbury's binary predicate
that links basically to intervene one which is named create cases
yes yes saying look very is this possibility to relate member of two different sets
and you can use any server then creates case
is basically a way to say that road in wikis are related by create
in four
one can do more
which is a kind of difficult to understand if you
comes from object orientation
if you comes from a variety of object oriented languages this is not possible you
normally can not to do is some type of the property
or at least you can do it but i mean it is not what we
normally think about in terms of property in RDF is possible so you can say
that there is a specific way to use the predicate
but also for a subset of all
the members of the previous property sue painting
being sick is a specific way to create a you can write like this
you can see painter is a subpropertyof creates any basically means that for each page
that are connected by being then you can claim that they are connected by create
good on this thing you can do for scones
a subpropertyof creates an blah blah
there is one last thing which is very important which is out you to connect
two sets so so far we have a year key
of sets any year kill properties but not really connected them together i mean creates
is still something that can be done by everybody if i want to say that
is not possible to create unless you are an artist i have to use these
the property that comes from rdfs it means that creates use is done by artist
and when he's done produce piece
so in this way i'm
basically stating that whenever you create something you are artist and whatever you create is
it masterpiece
and you can do the same for the subproperty so
a painter creates paints and scott to create scores
i mean can be wrong
but in a way and trying to represent these constraints about the data
and here i have representation in form but i mean
i don't want to go into them
what's the resulting ontology what we did so what we did was really
drawing an ontology is a very simple one but it's not that easy about the
world of arts we first of all property which is this create then using domain
and range
we use
to connected to artist so creates applied to artists and generates masterpieces
and then we have all the subproperties so we have the painters spain spain
and sculptor sculpt course
now i'm getting to explain why i
keep talking about all this stuff now
this is inference in rdfs these rules so that basically i used to derive the
knowledge from the knowledge that you put in RDF
and i put them in this way because they believe that it's pretty easy to
understand so if you have something like except that class of
it's and you have something a
which is of type peaks and then you can say that a is that keeps
what does it mean if you have
is an artist a u
then is it painter which is not true story then
then is also an artist
OK so this is away from a very simple no its ever tried to derive
new tribe which is exactly meaningful because of the ontology
you can do similar things so if you have a chain of subgraphs offer you
can unfold data and do the same but you did before so i mean we
don't have a chain of properties but one can image to have come from the
flemish painter or to have other kind of painters and then you have all these
different going on the same applies to properties and the these nice things that applies
to the main types so
if you have a
that are then scott wikis you know that the scots
is producing sorry
done by sculptor then
from just these then scored wiki so you can deduce better than is this guy
without any the average
which is also
and the same applies to range
imagine that you have his ontology
which is the one that produced so far
and you made that you transmitter
recipient to another these tribal so yes saying that from
two years
you're sending something like subject predicate object nothing more than that OK
the recipient
can always answer this query
but then
does it all that there is a sculptor
sorry the better than scott wikis
this is always possible because syntax right so i mean
i sent these
and i'm writing down some query that involve only these knowledge
so and this plain syntactic word and it works
but look
if the two recipients share the same ontology then you don't have to
to send all the information
but all the other queries down here can be answered so you can ask
is there then a sculptor and that's yes because you know that if somebody's got
something then is discussed
is it an artist yes
because if it is the skull is also an artist
and you can go to painter is a painter
well actually it is not be
because i mean it given that is the sculpture and given that we are making
some important things like unique name assumption
if it is the sculpture idea instead of it is a painter van is just
OK and so forth
this is what we call semantics
so i mean you over in pores over that tell a year which is RDF
constraints and when you transmit one element of the data more than you can derive
all the knowledge that were shared between the two semantic models
OK so you have a recipient
two recipients one shared more than the transmitter is simple tripod but you derive all
the implicit knowledge which is carried by the truckload
so it begins to swing back and forth
becomes completely chaotic you can no longer see what's happening
and it just so happened that about
six months ago dave
i had been was professor they've trooper
i explained to him that it is just unfortunate that you can never really show
it that you jump of the people have about scale and which and see that
way go down to zero in free
and he said
i can do that
he says i can make use scale
which has a response time
well maybe ten seconds
so when you jump off the table
in ten seconds you will see that things go down
two zero
he delivered
he came through
he built his wonderful device
united going to
demonstrate through
the first
give you some
reasonable light for this
and i would like to show you
on the scale there
this scale that he built is indicated here is the scale
i have it in my hands
and on top of this scale is a little platform just like on your scale
this platform ways four-and-a-half months
you can see that
it's about four and a half
you will say
i wouldn't want that kind of bathroom scale
if i want to see my bathroom scale once see is zero for i want
to go up i'm happy enough all by myself i don't want to get another
four-and-a-half pounds
the manufacturer has simply zero that scale for
but obviously also your bathroom scale as a cover on it
once you've seen these demonstrations you will be able to answer for yourself why we
don't zero this we really believe this to be four-and-a-half that's the actual
mass is on top of the spring what is not really is spring
it is the pressure gauge
but i think of it as the spring
four and a half pounds
we have a great
which is above their weight
which is ten pounds
this from one of your children that they are doing it yourself
ten parts
report on top here
what do you see
roughly fourteen and-a-half months
all right we're going to take it down
there we go
i'm going to drop it
from about one i have two meters
and we drop it in here
well cushioned because we don't want to break this beautiful device
when we drop with
the responses so fast that you will see indeed
that point to go to zero
october mind when he hits
that the way will go up
for now i wanted to concentrate only on the thing going to zero and not
what comes later
we'll deal with that
within a minute
fourteen and-a-half parts
you know what i think is actually jiggling back and forth
i can hold exactly still
and so
i slightly accelerated upwards and downwards and when accelerated slightly upward sideways a little more
when accelerated downward sideways less
interesting you can see on the surface
it is my nervous tension be there
look at don't look at me now
look at that
o point to
three two one zero
you see go to zero
all the way to zero
come something even more remarkable
he said to me
i can also
make the students c
the response on a timescale of about
the fraction of a second by the way this is the hero who made all
this stuff
i can show you
the weights
on electronic scale
and this weight
you will see as a function of time
ten pounds back on again
take the little
so the level that you see no
fourteen and-a-half months this is fourteen and have found and this is zero these markets
i'm going to
holding my hand
notice if i can hold it still you back to fourteen and-a-half months
now i'm going to drop it
you will see you go down to zero
it will hit the floor
it will get an acceleration upwards it will become way heavier than it was before
and then it will even be
bounce back up in the air goes again into free fall
we will freeze that for you
you will be able
we will be able to analyse them
after that all happens
fourteen and-a-half pounds
one zero
and now professor to freezing it for you look at this
look at this incredible picture
this is truly
i open for me when i saw the the physics in here is unbelievable
issue fourteen and-a-half months
take marks from here to here i half seconds
it was the second in free fall
and it goes to zero that no way
now it hits the floor the cushions
and its weight goes up
in something like tens of seconds
look this is about one
two three it's about three and a half times its weight now
o to fourteen and-a-half has to be multiplied by three and a half before which
is exactly what we predicted that it would be much higher
but now it's being
it bounces off because it's very nice because throws it back up so it goes
back into the air so goes immediately to weightlessness again
and then it oscillates back and forth
and then here
you would expect that this level fourteen and-a-half problems will be the same as this
the only reason why that's not the case because little cable that fell with it
which is pushing a little bit up on the upper
on the upper this this this was making the life
isn't it incredible you see in front of you
the weightlessness
and you see the actual weight when it hits
and again followed by
eight plus you pass the course
there is great interest
in doing experiments under weightless conditions
massa was very interested in it
if you would jump
a hundred meters up in the sky
you would only be nine seconds out
you wouldn't even be weightless because of drag
however if you could jump up
the at the top of the atmosphere
ready and raag is negligible
you would be weightless
for quite some time
and that is
what people have been doing
for the past few decades professor young professor oldman here at the
aeronautics department
i have done what they call zero gravity experiments
i keep getting phone calls in the middle of the night
we have but i don't
like his six goals
i know
OK so
i'm really get ahead but just just decided to bring about more of graphical models
because i will use them a little bit in the process of
like this all be on the same page
one example that so there's three cases you need to
keep in mind
so we see in this case
we've seen case one
if it's cloudy
it rained
and you get wet
and independence here being that
of course clouds given that it's right
if you know it's raining you don't need to know whether it's class
another case there's two more cases you need to know about
of conditional independencies
and then there's a way of formalizing all this
we saw this case we've actually seen both of those cases included in the graph
in this case here say
well is rain
or a shower
you could get wet
this is NOT causality but again i emphasise that these are correlations the dependencies
OK for the causality immediate counterfactual you need to consider the other possible thing
suppose you're trying to decide whether it's raining or not
and you know
you observe that it's wet
so we shape indicating some search
so you know the state of what
you happen to be wet covered in water
is the rain
it would help to know whether they are in the shower or not
in this case
i started this should be independent
in this case you say that range
is dependent on shower
given what
OK and then the last example was a thing of the frogs
and wet
and range
and that basically says that
where it is
whether you went to not
does not depend on
the state of frogs out there
if you know it's raining
held perpendicular as
i'm just going to
read the find the symbols the symbols mean
a word is just the word in the words of
this meant independent
well that's true correct
and you know what i mean
that is
given are these guys are independent
given are these two guys are independent
but watch out for this case because this case is different
this find something called
and here is more like a typical graphical model which has many nodes
and it indicates
you know people construe strike this huge graphical models to tell you how variables dependent
variables and you learn the structure of this graphical models
and hopefully next features here but that you can learn the structure of the graphical
models to learn all the conditional probability tables
and you learn all of these things
and fulfil sort of for this type of network you can all be learned this
type of size larger networks you need to use some of the first techniques like
some of the ones mentioned here today
the training data and the training error what can we say about
and one of the search
the most amazing results in
you know the theory of computer science and applied statistics is the result that yes
you can actually say something
the test error
if you just have to training under the assumption that the training has come from
the same distribution
so that phenomenal should result in applied statistics that goes all the way back you
know how to do that
and even earlier and
i think that that's really you know started off
people thinking
along these lines the
concept here is what called generalisation
OK so what's danger danger in the above setup is that we're going to do
really well on the training data but very poorly on the testing and that
do well in the training program i is called overfitting
so for example there's something called the sure thing hypotheses for the mccarthy is credited
with coming this case
sure thing i
you memorize the training data
any produce garbage on the test
but i want to conclude that
you might want to go through
now that function is kind of ridiculous
right i need to memorize the is of course
the result of training data it ran out of the supplies terror test
so why should we care about is one thing that's scary about this function has
very low
los test time time
so if we are only guided thinking functions functions that have the training loss that
function should hypothesis and this will be confuse us and cause it to become very
stupid learning so
the idea here is that you can learn anything about the world without making assumptions
so this is formalized in many many ways including the so-called no free lunch theorems
by walter
was series have their problems
they indicate an important point which is that if you really believe april any function
in the world possible you've never learn anything
so the ability to achieve small loss on test data is called generalisation and that's
the real goal
is to build a machine that that good generalisation we can estimate the training very
important so
in order to be able to say something stronger guarantee the ability to generalize to
get low walls test there
we have to control something called the capacity
which is the complexity of the hypothesis
so learning is really searched hypothesis learning is all about trying to find the magic
setting about not fade which gives you know you lost it test
well how we evaluate test loss on test data so we can make this sampling
the test come from the same distribution
OK so here is the inductive learning hypothesis generalisation is possible
that's a very strong state
that statement said
you make assumptions about the world you can sometimes actually improve that you're not going
to that understand
so in a in words what inductive learning
this tells us that if machine performs well on most
training data and it's not too complex it will probably do well on similar
this statement can break down
in many ways
the is we can bring is you can fail
the first condition
you can trigger classifier and it can be really bad training data when they really
should be that surprised at that time
and if you do well the training data
that's the old people
most people trying to correct this problem but there's two more things you need to
correct if you want protect one is you need to make sure that it's not
too too complex
the sure thing hypothesis which memorized the entire training was very complicated right memorize all
the training sets of training
we can back to this
classifier trained
three strategic types so very complicated beast so so that's why i'm sure hypothesis is
that because it's not a simple and this is the third assumption have to satisfy
the test data has to be similar
you will be amazed how many people go to the world
the the world this and machine learning in the collective
training data
and they trained classifier make sure
very complicated and
training and then applied to test it's completely different than the training data
and then it doesn't work in this sort of stuff
the inductive learning hypothesis protecting what is going on well what's going
you're going to totally different aspects so make sure please when you go human beings
you actually need to train the classifier can do that too big but is not
too complicated you have to control and three
do a sanity check that you're testing there is somewhat similar to training data before
start playing these things but the amazing fact if you satisfy all these then you
right than the ones that don't matter so the best solution is the one that's
the ones that matter right i mean these
large i mean that if the best solution had failed
it would have been an entirely different result altogether these large
returns here
which tau them sort of got right
it has basically move the sharpe ratio up
that's the best solution we get
at the moment i do not know could well general regression analysis and stuff like
this there's the issue of spurious regressions
so it could be that i mean i think one thing we need to consider
as well
which which is basically a subject to future research is
that our two minus thirty five full-time
eight just random you know i just spurious
but what is
basically will even all
we everything is an illusionary
so what we do and as you have
a series of integers strings
you have a set of rules
which is like a grammar
you're trying to find the right sequence of integers strings
that maps to solutions like this
so in the article in its evolution basically have a modular structure
you have the space but search space you're working on the search space
two in crossover and mutation
and you have the solution space
so in the so suppose you got into strings
you produce integer representations of solutions
you work on integer representations trying to
find that
the production rules are basically is basically a lookup table
and you're trying to find the right sequence of integers that tells you
how to learn how to go through that lookup table
and produced that
which is like in the solution space
natural selection happens in the solution space
crossover and mutation and everything happens in the search space
so i mean the main ingredients are just returns we assuming here that we can
actually use past returns
and projects in the future it has which is well
most AI models and econometric models sort of
assume that there's some sort of autocorrelation
between past returns in future tense
what we see what we see here is basically a comparison between the accumulated return
achieved by
the best solution which i just showed you
and by the but buy-and-hold strategy in our model
and like i said what you'll notice this
know the solution produced by GE
i happen to be you know fit because it managed to predict
all these large
like right
all right
i'm not sure if i make myself
sharpe ratio
which is
which is basically the
so if are at our team
is the
right you know the actual return
this time interval
where prediction
our CEO
it's basically
the prediction from model
based on that production
if the prediction is greater than zero if we projects in return higher than zero
we go along
has you know the positive side
else we go short
so you know if if we if we if we get the prediction right then
will make positive returns
if it's enough the goes up
and we predict predicted go along you get positive return it goes down
you get negative return we predicted to go ashore short
negative negative cancels out you get positive
the graph g
this area
this is the best solution produced by g
what i mean here
what i did not mention this we assume and it's basically
the individuals must trade at every time interval which is like five ninety minute intervals
was human that we're in in a frictionless environment no slippage no transaction costs
what we try to do is we're trying to work from
skeleton and put some flesh on skeleton than have maybe something that actually works
would probably work in the real world environment
so i mean maybe maybe maybe like you
the sampler of the earlier
maybe sometimes the best
strategy is not to train
what we have is simplistic rules so maybe i mean the future research what we
might want to consider is subject in the decision rule to evolution as well so
you're coevolving to model
and the decision rule which is something we presented like somewhere else so the decision
is evolved as well as the model
so rather than say the return greater than zero
the return less than zero short maybe your subjective decision or a decision rule to
evolution as well so such that you've all something
that works well
you know
process prior as a prior over phi star vector this infinite length vector and a
prior over the parameters theta and we know that the phi star vector is given by this
GEM distribution our stick breaking construction and the thetas are basically IID draws from our
base distribution H and given phi and theta we know that G is of this
yeah G is of this form right and what that states that if we sample
a value from G that value will be equal to theta star K with probability
phi star K so we can think of this phi star K as basically the mixing proportion  of cluster
K and phi star K and theta star K is the parameters of cluster K
okay so you if we now come back to this if we sample ZI from
phi star K according to a distribute discrete distribution over phi star K so basically ZI
equals to value K with probability phi star K and data item XI given that
we know that it be that it belongs to  cluster ZI is gonna
be sample from a distribution parameterized by that parameter so this gives us our stick breaking
representation of the DP mixture model and this kind of makes explicit that this DP mixture
model is really just a mixture model but with the infinite number of components now
and so this will lead to kind of different sorts of samplers which were explored by
people down here  which are called conditional samplers and is conditional in the sense
that is basically standard Gibbs  sampling where we just you know compute the conditional probability of each
variable given the other variables sample from that conditional and then we sample we compute
the conditional distribution of phi star given Z and then we sample from phi star and
so forth we're always computing conditional distributions the nice thing with this is that it's
actually quite easy to work with non conjugate priors in the case of the
Chinese restaurant process because of the way that we need to deal with introducing new
clusters into the Chinese restaurant process it turns out to be a bit more complicated
if you need to deal with non conjugate priors okay in the case of a stick breaking representations
is basically very straightforward but for the sampler to work well we need to mix we
need to introduce moves for permuting the clusters okay so basically once
we use the stick breaking construction we have basically limited ourselves to a particular way of
ordering the clusters and we need to mix over the orderings for the sampler to for
the sampler to mix there's kind of another approach which is I cannot call it the explicit G
sampler which basically represents G explicitly okay so basically we alternatively sample
the set of so we just directly look at the this DP mixture model and we
sample and we we derive an algorithm that was sampled the theta given G
and G given theta for the theta given G it straightforward because
of the Polya urn scheme in the case but for the conditional distribution for G
given theta that's also straight-forward because we know that that conditional distribution is DP
is again a Dirichlet process because of conjugacy and we can work out that
this Dirichlet process here can always be written up can we always be written in this
form where phi zero and phi one to phi K this vector here is
Dirichlet distributed with parameters given by this and G prime is independent sample from the same
Dirichlet process in the prior okay for both the stick breaking representation and this explicit
G sampler one issue is that this G prime here you know this is
a atomic distribution with an infinite number of atoms so it  can't represent all infinitely
many atoms in our  computer so there has to be some way of kind of
doing this truncate  of truncating the number of clusters to a finite number to
be able to represent it on our computer and there are kind of a few ways of doing this
truncation  yeah which I it's kind of described in this papers anyways
there're of course lots of different inference algorithms for Dirichlet processes there's split-merge algorithms
where you look at the clustering and then you introduce Metropolis Hastings moves
that take a cluster splitting into two or take two clusters and merging it into one and
this sampler tends to if you combine this with the Gibbs sampling algorithm it tends to
converge a lot faster okay and this is close quite quite close in spirit to the reversible jump
CMC methods that Peter Green may have talked about last week there are also sequential
Monte Carlo samplers which I guess Arnold  talked about as well alright which is this
is this are basically iterative algorithms where you just have one single pass through your
data set and  each  each step of the algorithm you introduce a new
data item into into the model and then you assign it to one of the clusters
and you move on to the next data item there are also variational and kind expectation propagation
algorithms right any questions about yes personally
I think that the sampling algorithms in the case of the Dirichlet process actually
works really well  the variational algorithms the nice thing is that you could
it will converge to sum mode and then you could analyse that mode you don't have to
worry about the problem of label switching where the label of the clusters gets switched around
you don't have to worry about convergence because you know exactly when it converges when
the variation of parameters stopped moving so in that sense is kind of easy to
analyze but I find that when you look at predictive the predictive
ability of variational algorithms as opposed to sampling algorithms the samplers the sampling algorithms tend
to to do better  they're kind of easier to analyse but how the but worse at doing
predictions that's variational yeah yes that's right yes
well I guess you could try it on
kind of syntactic data sets where you know the clustering and then look at
the harmonies how long does it take to converge to the kind of to the neighborhood
of the true clusters you can also do things like kind of more
predictive sort of things right so give it analysis which is a clustering of your
data set you can then take that clustering and then do something else with that
so in the case of for example of  object recognition people often do clustering
it might have zero entries that means those two notes are not connected
and the entries are guaranteed to be nonnegative
so that's your w and the you create a diagonal matrix d d where they
element on the diagonal PII is simply the sum of the weights connected to node
i so that's the degree of node i see of this matrix and then the
laplacian in which i
you start here but i will also use l
OK so the laplacian matrix is the man to stop you
and the interesting thing is well in the graph energy we wanted to minimize is
have transposed w delta f
that's the quadratic form of it
and then we can write our
objective function as follows so again that funny infinity is really just constrained and then
you want to minimize the graph in
so the solution is simple
a matter of linear algebra
if we
arrange the notes
in such a way
so that the first l are labeled nodes and the remaining you are unable notes
i sort my nose this way that you can partition your matrix into four parts
to do have this label part and the one unable part and so on
then it's easy to see that
you're the solution
the factor on the unlabelled data portion is
which involves this block here but inverted
that block and then this is short given labels
you can also use
other forms of not bloodletting in place of this down here so you can use
the normalized version
or you can raise it some is power
there's another variation called local and global consistency yes
it has something to do with the
this is called the harmonic i think it's called harmonic property
that the
the function value is a weighted average of its neighbors
so let's look at this
this variation
the only difference is
that now we don't have this infinity here that we have some tuning parameter lambda
so this model was the fact that maybe you're given
labels on your small labels that it's not always
one hundred percent correct so you want to allow for some label noise
you want to say that now let's allow my prediction labelled data to be different
from the given label but i'm going to penalize it
OK at the same time i also want to minimize the graph energy
so far
these methods they work
but they are all trasductive
that means my as is only defined on this graph because it's just factor rate
is not defined at any point p and my given training set
so therefore if i want to predict new
that's a unseen test point i can not do that
i cannot do that easily
one way is to create a new graph by adding that new test point
you have to create some edges and then
some of the system
or you some heuristics
but so for example look at the test points neighbors but that's beyond what we
discussed so we want to find
inductive semi supervised
graph solution and manifold regularisation is one way to do that
OK so
here we start with an as that's define everywhere so here it defining some kernel
reproducing kernel space but don't worry about the details basically start from some after define
over the whole space
and then you also want to view this graph has already instantiation of
some underlying manifold
then what you do is this
turn this the prediction of your
a function on the labeled and unlabeled set look at that factor to minimize this
eventually you want to do something like this so OK so i'm going to explain
this later don't worry about that that's the hinge loss
but you could just be square loss or any other loss so this is the
labelled data fitting
term how well your efforts here labelled data and then you have
some norm
that regularizes your functions
when we make the decision of which class this image comes from which cluster of
comes from we just do it according to the bayes rule that the
the poster is proportional to the likelihood times the prior which is in general just
uniform distribution
and then we make the maximum decision on this on this
on this poster so that's the basic setup of her mother
it's very very simple but it's tested on how meaning can always think seven
seven categories and it actually was quite successful in terms of
how how well they do it
so what we do
two or more sophisticated model here we have several flavors we have the error corrected
told you this is really the
the starting point of all these latent topic models is the hoffman latent semantic analysis
model we call it pls and then we'll see the how related to originally allocation
that's a visual object categorisation
here i'll take this image ICCV o five paper has an case study were they
use the probabilistic latent semantic analysis model where here all describe to you the visual
meaning of these variables so d is a document response correspond to an image as
it here is the latent topic the they put it into
so test face versus bicycle
and then of course w here are patches of this of this image another flavor
is what i proposed using latent dirichlet allocation because of the weakness of this model
in my opinion is that course you have images like this
you can not assume there is only one topic
for this
for this for this image especially objects are embedded in backgrounds so in this model
where we actually know we we pooling contributions of different topics to specific category so
what we have here as in this paper in ICCV o five paper we used
it in a natural scene categorisation setting so it's a little different from objects but
very similar where the categorical among the label c is at the image level so
it's outside of the patch and then we have these parameters i think this is
the theta parameter in eric's lights we we
just label the pi which is mixing proportion of the topics the potential topics that
are in this image so we can say there's thirty percent water or twenty percent
rock and eighty percent sky o it has to add up to a hundred or
one and then each each patch
get to pick its own topic according to some kind of this distribution and of
course w is the fifth
actual patches this is the LDA model used for cattle categorizing visual images and then
the PLSA model is some some just going to show you
i think it's
and how we formulated here it's pretty simple we have for every for every document
we want to know the probability of the probability of this
image or document is the image sorry and it is actually
like eric it's basically a mixing makes mixture model of the topics so we have
the probability of the particular topic in this in this document or image and then
we have the probability of the words words in this a given this topic and
and they can be viewed in a very nice linear algebra way and on getting
into the details of this
and then what we want
o what the savage and his colleagues he did is to look at what of
the probabilities of different topics within this document and select the most probable one
and you can choose to do inference you can write down the likelihood of all
the training images and all the patches in this training pool and then use maximum
likelihood and then you can just use the same expectation maximisation
methods to iterate
between the parameters and arrive at at you're on values
so OK so
order will be never be visited twice so this one is an example of a
directed graph
this one i sorry directed acyclic graph and this is an example of a directed
acyclic graph because we added this link here from x four two x five so
for example the
the park x five
x seven x four x five will be the norm x five twice
OK so we made it to define our for this type of graphical model namely
the belief network
relief mentor is a directed acyclic graph in which
each node has associated the probability distribution of
the conditional distributions
of that node given its parents so for example if you look at the graph
and we do not eat it as aspiring to be and c and the four
these will have associated the conditional distribution of a given b and c
and a joint distribution of all the nodes in the graph is simply obtained by
taking the problem this condition
OK i give you a little bit of an example of all to use ability
make talking let's assume that sally
a burglar alarm is sounding
was the butler or was the alarm triggered by an earthquake sally to the radio
on for news of two
so in this problem we have four random variable a b e and are
representing the lower the burglar earthquake and radio and if we start writing down the
joint distribution of these
we consistently conditions the distribution they on the order side what you want to apply
by the joint distribution of in the is
we learn how to do it
similarly for this to you
we can condition of our on a and b
and multiply by
the distribution of a and b
and similarly for the last and so we obtain a factorisation of our
initial distribution and the belief network presentation of these is
even here in which for example
a despondent he
we are
and this corresponds to the standard
we see here
are assessed by e
and b this correspond to stand here and so i don't know if you think
about this problem with more carefully realized that
the large certaintly is not causing any
any broadcasting on on the radio and therefore we can say that
the radio is not causing
the lower and you know the reward
this distribution here is independent is independent of all of
and therefore we can remove this link
from our graphs
the delete from two to a
similarly this in a week
understand that
the burglary
is not
the iranian therefore we cannot remove these
valuable here and the associated link in the graph and finally also the burglar is
directly causing the quake and therefore we can remove it
the final link from p two p and we end up with what much simpler
type of believe it or
that they wrote down here
now we can use these
matter to make inference
for example we can ask
before actually doing that we need to specify
what if there were entries are for each conditional distribution that we have in our
so so for example we have to to define what the probability of a human
being the ease
and so then delete if they
but they but i was in the house and the walls
an quick then their lower
the probability that a lot of these something is very high
for everybody so there's no CU which tells you what is the right loss function
so this is really application dependent or user dependent
specify the loss function
and your goal is
to minimize loss
or if you use a negative sign maximise profit
you take your past observations
compute the loss
the expected loss
and try to minimize that
so what you can show is that in this predictive setting where your decision does
not influence
the future
this greedy minimisation of
the lost in the next time instances optimal so you don't need to look ahead
but it's important that the decision to influence environment
so here are some examples
of more generic loss functions
and the relation to the estimate for instance if you start with the square loss
and you do this minimisation
it's just the mean
not the absolute loss
then is
you get the media
if you start with the zero one loss
you get the mode
so there's a close relationship between some loss functions and some standard statistical estimators
if you actions influence environment so you have now this action here
and influence environment then you
o operations so these are the axis and these are the x and y
and then you
get into the enforcement learning
and things get much much much more complicated
because now
you need to be farsighted you can't really maximise your reward in the next time
this would lead to very bad behavior
very simple example is the bandit problem
there you have to go to casino
these bands of slot machines and you can put on the probability and you have
two of them and many probability is different
could i mean pull each then look for you when i mean
wait until you the first and then you look at one and then always take
this army
and it's clearly i mean not good study what you should used first explore some
political both arms makers statistics and then
ideally gradually switched to the slot machines which
seems better
once told that
research grants committee and looked at me and i can't sell that in this case
sorry to medical treatments treatment a or b you can either sector two more you
can read the two more and you have some success probabilities
and you don't know them and you want to lose as
if you like possible and but you have to explore a little bit so what
is the optimal way of doing that
and he was much much happier
but mathematically i mean it's exactly the same
yes i mean this simple case i mean it sounds really really simple
but there's a closed form solution but it's still a whole book
there's a whole book about it
and if it gets slightly more complex
you have to approximate the solution
and the solution turns out to be really i mean explore both at the beginning
equally and then you gradually shifted to the
two there are
well to the treatment which seems better
so that's the famous
exploration and exploitation problem
OK you some agent with some more details inside
i think
florida board
OK the previous slide explicitly specify the rewards
so you they more explicit so you have these agent influence environment you get some
observations but occasionally you get some reward signal
i mean he's not every time step but it can be zero and sometimes you
get reward points you win at chess game
for every one of the negative ones
and sri forced learning is concerned
with how an agent ought to take actions in an environment
so as to maximize its long term reward
if your environment is finite state MDP
and you know the MDP
i mean then
you can find solution easily
if you go beyond that
then it
nearly all cases gets already so even in the MDP case if you don't know
the MDP make some bayesian model and you make an average over mdps an MDP
anymore throughout the framework and it's difficult
i think it even more difficult
if you're
if you model i mean if you sort of passively multimedia environment some probability distributions
which may depend on the action but it's still not
really symmetric but in games
your opponent is also play also learns
well phrased differently is also quite complex probability distribution your own
the new layer can learn through self play
o point is like and became an autosomal chequer programme but
there's not even a theoretical optimal solution i mean the people don't even know what
it means
i mean this the concept of nash equilibria
but in this equilibrium can be quite bad
for instance
in the prisoner's dilemma
so you have to
victims who
rob the bank or so
and they got caught
they could either