we need
it will be
but we don't know
we get
they all the
four or
and they gave me
one is a
you can do it
i mean
i don't know what
it's one
you want do it
if you want to know about
you one
and you do get
now you have
one of them
you know this
that is
i mean
you want
you got me you know it
where you
in your application
and created the semantic web client object specify sparql query
execute the query as you usually do
using the query engines
the only difference here is to create model
you must provide
in the modern view of the semantic web client object
that's basically all the take
to create the web of data in your applications as more extensive additions or changes
to applications needed
however if you want more control
you can use these methods you can reload you can reissue URI lookups in order
to reload more graphs can clear the location
furthermore you can
but i look ups explicitly
and again
customers site listening to the requests in order to
execute application specific code
four retrieved graphs
can set configuration options
what interesting for applications that
consider the qualities of retrieved data
the pull provenance information
the library contains several sources of provenance information first of all we have this the
class which is
it represents is in
the retreat graphs
and or and
in this class officer method get force
from which you can
it returns the URI of the of the the graph which which contains this
second we have been looking graphs always contains the provenance graph which is especially graph
this provenance information about
the retrieved graphs provenance information such as the source you have the retrieval time
and the library provides lists of
we bias that has been retrieved successfully or not
as well as
information about redirected eyes
so to sum up
the semantic web client client library enables you to consumers data
from the web
you can issue sparked the careers of trying steal curious
and the library
executes directed browsing algorithm to dynamically
retrieve RDF graphs from
during query execution
further information about the lives as well as the library itself is available from this
and for future versions of the library i'm currently planning
the development of the genes for smart caching replacement of local copies of root crops
since this library is free software project everyone is invited to not only use the
library revert to contribute
so now i hand over to talk
any questions in the state
they are there other libraries and other
and i don't know
i don't know about this but there are people
this one is for java
i think so but i don't know
in the
quite useful to things like
like the rest of the thing
is there anything
the what
we just in general
but you don't know to use line
not that i know
the library
javascript language
and it is here too
the have
XML documents
then you have
in the java sea
nothing like this
imagine that
but i
OK so long and just talk briefly and trying to wrap up the session
and we'll get on some questions afterwards so in summary
the data centric approach for publishing structured data on the web
rather than using proprietary web API is built on on web standards
it reduces the
four hundred and letting it has do with parameter of
you can afford it for the french
and if you have material that
four other by for example have to a lot for all sure that everybody in
this room is a that
i'm sure that you have
when people
i call this whole things
and the lower level of the tree of
o one hundred
because it compared to the fact that the high
and have dealt with the electric
what i'm saying is that society can do different things in the atmosphere of the
five people say it's important to have
why have ours
why all have seen or
that one more than
because it's it's a a driver of innovation the drywall while also fighting to look
for the difference
by the way benefit and that the
why was this kind of information could have another but like that what people call
for of my which happens
everybody liked him but they were to cross the path you
thank could be
so whatever the cost all over the world
what want
what we have to
the product
one of two
what do
we have to cope with what we see
good for
couple of
so that was not always directed towards
like this
we need to know what you have
for example very simple
you know what i'm about
so that's the one that i so we have
well developed field for the proposed
for example
university things to to search for example that
we also the find some to kind the
two different cultures have additional holes five hundred two bands or the
four months
and this is the world war
product conditions tools
there was also a long
the production or both
we have a process in place for example where we tried to two
the above with the body
two countries with
and this is the last
of the
is about one point
just a brief out
next on this friday you are writing tutorial
it's two PM there's only one tutorial this week at two PM it's going to
be in this room so i'm actually come to talk about sort of
the issues involved with
comparing presenting the two and really important that you
some attention to
so today we continue our discussion of
networking and network layering if you remember the last time
talked about
three layers that are in any typical network stack
and these three layers he said would be and then later
the network layer
and the link layer
and we went through the example of how
these three layers interact with each other as a message is sent to the network
on a typical
he said that these three layers
and there might also be a receiver node
and then there could be several each
time messages
centre the network
my pass through any number of
intermediate gateway nodes
or in the intermediate switches so
what impact did send in
it gets sent through the anywhere
in the network layer down in the link layer
the link layer chooses the next link to send the packet out over
since it's one of these which is
the switch
looks at the packets ended up to its its own network layer which is in
charge of determining the next
link the message will take
and on the next play and the next stop the message goes after to the
link layer the link layer determines
yet another way for the message to take
the network layer determines yet another like message for link for the masses to take
and finally
the message reaches the receiver the message propagates through the link layer into the network
layer and then finally to the end and layout using
we talked a little bit last time about various things that happen in this architecture
we said that the there's this process of encapsulation
it happens at each step along the way
you can layer may attach headers on the packet
the header trailer on the packet network layer may tetrahedra trailer and only player may
attach header trailer but at no point does anyway look at the data that higher
level higher layers set
you also notice that in this architecture
we we'll we've shown here is that only the link layer in the network layer
of this which is the reporting packets are actually looking at that are actually
processing the packet so there's no
the into and layer by definition is not involved in the forwarding the packet the
and and layer is only involved when one of the endpoints of communication is involved
so i want to talk about today we're finished very briefly our discussion at the
link layer and then we're going to turn focus mostly
on the networking layer
the remember the last time we got as far as saying that the link layer
is in charge of the number of sort of important issues with the transmission of
data across
one link of the network we talked
for a while it in the class last time about this
to digital
backwards digital
the analog to digital conversion
we're going to talk about the other issues that we need to to talk about
in the context of the network layer the link layer
it is
the issue of framing so idea with framing is when you're sending a message out
over a network link
receiver on the other end is to have some way of knowing that this is
a packet starting work packages and or as we call these packets when a link
layer frames so
she reframing is to identify the sort of beginning and end of every
one of these frames as it transmits over the network and there's a fairly this
sort of fairly obvious way to do this is well attach some special symbol put
some special symbol at the beginning and end of every packet
so for example through an ethernet the payload of an ethernet packet that might contain
the destination address the source address
the type so
talk more about what the title means in a minute
the data and some text some information can be used to detect errors
and the preamble
it is a special code that is attached to the beginning of every one of
these messages and this is used to make manchester encoding remember we talked about last
class which is used as this this is you start to make a lot of
things like loop to lock into the message which we talked about the last class
and it might be
now in the case of the genetic sequence a well-defined sequence one zero one zero
one zero one zero but remember that with manchester encoding that the data is actually
transmitted over the network looks a little bit different
and then following the preamble there's the start of frame symbol
and at the end of the message there's this and simple
so one thing we might be concerned about is a for example
what is the
network layer tries to send the message that contains the and symbol in it
i would be a problem right because then the and layer would have you know
in it's the BN layer would have inadvertantly
terminated the message even though the really and the message this was just something happened
to be the same code is whatever the
link layer it shows inference and code symbol
and the reason that this is concerned we don't want the network you have to
understand lots of details about how the link layer
operates underneath by the link layer of the network layer shouldn't have to make any
assumptions about what are valid symbols for transmitting what invalid symbols for transmit
so the way that we're going to solve this is through one of two techniques
the first so the first technique that will talk about for a moment is this
idea of bit stuffing
it's about in a minute another simple thing we could do
would be to simply use a code that can possibly be generated by see for
example the the manchester encoding scheme so only if the network layer sends a message
like one one one one
the link layer is going to convert that into some sequence of ones and zeros
once it applies manchester coding so if the the link layer on the receiver sees
the message like one one one one one it the that can possibly be a
valid code for the
there can possibly be invalid messages that could have been generated by the by the
network layer only the link layer can actually send a sequence of bits out so
we can tell that would be terminated symbol
another simple way though to send one of these encodes is using this technique called
bit stuffing
it's pretty simple and kind of any technique can be used in general when you
your possibilities even though some nodes
my question was in this process i believe this is something that you know
to select some actions in the future what would you do
so the question is the question was supposed to have prior knowledge of the posterior
distribution somehow
after the same
you will probably
what actually hard
OK so this is a misunderstanding make sure
because what is
this method is
this estimation
it's not really
what action should
it's estimating
five the water
hard choose actions we choose actions by computing the policy
the optimal with respect
so the centre half
so it's a
the planet was
but that's all
OK so
so we face the exploration exploitation the strategy
exploitation will be
choose a policy that all the respective more
she actually
so as to obtain information
so as to improve my model
so that later in time
maybe i can get a better one
and that's the exploration exploitation dilemma
again not faced faced in supervised and unsupervised learning but the key key question in
reinforcement learning and michael littman is going to present an algorithm called the cube algorithm
michael collins and i developed some years ago that will actually address this specific thing
you asked me not to talk about that so you can talk about
so there are many different formulations of the problem of exploration exploitation one version
you know when it is a little house steps
and we want to maximize the world
you can call that way
or weighted EQ is that we
what about how is going to live but instead simply as that it is always
doing about where could about how know how was going
something like that so
they are very different ways of formulating the problem so
i think we have a good question which is we rarely in reinforcement learning assume
training phase in the face and the phase testing phase
there is
rarely that thing
right because in some sense life is not like that it is not
like the test training phase testing you can argue that education a bit like
the has to be that it's the but not part like just continuously which is
going to live we're always trying to choose actions so as to
improve what happens in the future so there is no so the separation between training
and test sets something that's what
is it really that we will be forced down
you can certainly ask many questions from the formulation and people
yes yes certainly
certainly you can
you can make you can make the exploration exploitation problem precise in different ways and
the choice is
not addressing this point
what the different choices are
how the how to formulate exploration exploitation again michael littman we'll talk about a specific
i think l
do it
i say that because a lot of people are not aware of solving the exploration
exploitation let michael talk
OK so let me just say something very simple and obvious
you can imagine that
as long as we use efficient exploration that is we
in the living try every action
in every state in the office
the following simple the results obtained obvious that
if i visited every state action pair the limit my model the converge
you want to live there for my so called policy
will converge to the optimal policy
now is sort
an interesting results but
wait for the discrete discrete finite
and the said
and like
so so the
yes i am i'm not quite ready to to make the connection between supervised unsupervised
reinforcement learning but actually so so modern buildings like supervised learning problem in the sense
that given these mappings state action actually given examples state action next state
this whole process
later it was
this is the graphical
directed graphical models
so we have
he sees
so we can be presented as late as patients some document
the documents
research topics
this is a small change
and then for each of these samples from the two so you can see
you might in the text have two topics
one topic money
more important than the others
and there are certain words like you is that for bit
they fit the first topics one of the things that fit to
this was just three years
it could be a
holds topics represents
so now we can describe our document
so the joint probability model of the document and its work we can describe probability
document and then this is the actual document generates work
but now we can split this into two
top and this is of course
this is made this page
that you have to know in advance a certain number of of topics otherwise computation
for this but this was the case with latent semantic analysis that i mentioned direction
it's not for the us
i feel
given these topics
we can model document
as the distribution of topics each topic has distribution
we to delete so if we have a large corpus
we train the score was by maximizing the likelihood function loss of
the joint probability we by the frequency of words the change
and we we
get to collect these values
these are can of only words and
and you can change with the
which is why are not actually which ones belong to topic
and what is the probability of the word belonging to topic and also for each
document you know it is
the topic distribution
why not
so we have this
we have this document
and then we want to know
how much in what is the distribution of topic one topic one topic two in
this the same
three c is very useful
that it has limitations that
you have your training set
you today
and if you new document
there are two ways fold a few documents into your model
but if you have many new documents you have to be true
and also you have to estimate
each time
you have
if your document collection
you also the number of
but you have to estimate is spending see grows linearly which documents so
it was
we have that actually that
so it's late should keep
which was published in two thousand two
july two thousand genes in terms of machine learning research
and in this model
you can
we need treat a topic topic mixture which is the key
he did not know
ten times here
it's it's quite
so now we can cage
also in that
which we have to estimate
and this allows us also document to infer that the construction
now this models
similar models
due work
this set
it is composed of
and you
so they to which
condition now these not
i possible to
between the value
all these bands so long as lead to model
more simpler model the
the term is also come
with the first topic distribution was
but i go well i
well actually what is
you can look at his publications
it's not going to that is the location is very expensive it gives you
in the appendix all
the necessary
computations that you need
this may
the source fuel
you can change just sort called
four of her soul
and so
our experience is that the light and so on
now if you you have questions regarding certain implementations will change
so actually
what i'm trying to do
in its explain this publication you learn simple splits models
and how can you predict that those words
so this is what happens in machine learning
the simple thing which we did in the out of this competition was first predicted
like the single gene structure and then try to extend the scene gene structure by
including what
based on against sequence
OK but this is not
i mean this ignores quite a few facts how are the mighty ducks
and the points that you cannot
you cannot
in predicting the effects of that it's hard to find out the sex so i
mean it's better to find excellent together with idea this it's
and this is essentially what you would like to do would like to predict these
kind of splice products which are shown you on the previous slide based on the
DNA sequence so this is more difficult inference task on input sequence of inputs like
you just have a sequence on the output side problem
these graphs have to have some structures about it but it's not easy to come
up with the dynamic programming algorithm can actually be called this
but if you can do this then you can just use structured output learning and
all the time
but it's it's
so and you think i mean we started expanding this to a certain kind of
i mean this subset
OK so i showed you some results i mean this result i think it so
d structure prediction still be challenge that continue to the i've shown you that the
accuracy for quantitatively genes the is already quite a bit accuracy of ninety five
so the first version of finding system seems very promising
also compared to create was actually in this comparison that's another discriminative gene finding system
it's right here
right now
so we have believe that this was comparison compares favourably to
and it's computational challenge how to build a twenty five in this picture
and of course not we can use this finding system to rehabilitate the norms and
also for the newly sequenced genomes
but you challenge for instance how can you want you know to apply what we
learned to another jail maybe parameters
to change had to be changed only slightly
so we need some way of
getting information from one organism to another which is related
i think this is
it so
they actually quite a few contributors dimension i would like to mention the ensemble
that i've worked together with a lot of people and supplies but also the other
guys including those with the of
and y in g w h five e of the alexander seems to have a
lot of work on this
OK so find topic which i think is on
resequencing hiding every for the detection of forty
one part of this is again
applications of structure of the so
it is the technique should be understood by everybody
the idea is what the question is a the ballot question behind that is to
understand the genetic basis of variation in plants what so what you see here is
a plant growing in different places one in which one getting and
i mean these are common seems to be the same species you across the i
mean there
almost has the same you know
and what you would like to understand the differences between these two you know and
to understand why this one looks like this and the other one looks back so
this is a very important question about it
and one
i would like to understand what kind of sequence changes fewer in short time frames
which kind of polymorphisms and gene underlying action
unlike adoption so that means maybe cambridge but the different than getting it has to
adapt to the best there and what are the consequences of these polymorphisms fourteen
so and with this analysis arabidopsis tion chosen to you know with a one hundred
twenty pages long
and the
i mean there's a lot of resources on the on this terrible to see
OK so and in this study we consider resequencing of twenty
ecotypes that means
strains which come from different geographic location
all over the world so it
i mean
you see you there in two thousand different strains collected and this was spread all
over the world
i mean everywhere but
OK so what is the we can think harry
we expect that
so let's say i mean
we have the sequence of the reference genome sequenced you know the the genome center
also in
the idea is that you would like to determine small sequence variation among the different
strengths with you could
so what we have
which i fixed to some error
and those nucleotide complementary
two with the reference sequence
and that's why every position in the sequence there for
four probes in the position of the problem is very
and whenever this snippets position and you will see
e there i mean that one of those reference products will bind to to the
this piece of DNA
and by
by observing which one had actually bound you can find out
which is the position that
i mean which is the nuclear
so do this now we have two sequences those complementary many of the edits the
position of the eight active here and then you see he on the web position
you like one
but you know
and you do this also in the first round three x eight measurements position that
you know this means that like a hundred twenty times
eight million measurements which is like a billion measurements is quite big
so like ninety nine percent of all faces very simple on and you know and
it is very important because friend billion oligos and twenty
twenty billion membership
last time
we discussed
acceleration is caused by pollution
well by paul
today we will express this more qualitatively
three laws which are called newton's laws
the first law
really goes back to the
the first part of the seventeenth century
it was galileo who expressed what he called the law of
inertia and i'll read you
is law
a body
anybody in motion
continues to move at a constant velocity along the straight line
unless acted upon by an external force
and now i read to you know tens
on words in his famous book
perseveres in its state of rest
or of uniform motion
in a right line
on less
it is compelled to change that state
by forces
upon it
and newton's first law
is clearly against our daily experiences
things that move don't move along the straight line
and i will continue to move and the reason is because gravity
and there's a lot of these even if you remove gravity
then the friction
as an
so things will always come to hold
we believe those
but in the absence
of any force is indeed an object
if it had a certain velocity
would continue along a straight line
and never
now this law
it's very fundamental law
does not hold in all reference frames
for instance it doesn't hold
in reference frame which itself is being accelerated
but i accelerate myself right here
you john my so i take my bicycle
o my
motorcycle my car and you see me being accelerated in this direction
you sit there
and you say
its velocity is changing
therefore according to the first law there must be a force on him and you
you feel that force actually i do feel that i feel someone pushing me
consistent with the first law
perfect first slow works for you
nine years
i'm being accelerated in this direction
you will come towards me being accelerated in this direction i say first of all
should work
these people should feel a push
i said hey there you feel push you say if you must
there is no pushed is not there for the first law doesn't work from my
frame of reference if i'm being accelerated
so now comes the question
when does
the first floor
work well
the first law works
when the frame of reference is what we call an inertial frame of reference
an inertial frame of reference would then be afraid
in which there are no accelerations of any kind
is that possible is twenty six one hundred is this lecture hall
in inertial
reference frame
four one
the earth rotates about its own axis in twenty six one hundred goes with that
give you centripetal acceleration
number two
it goes around the sun
that gives you the the centripetal acceleration including including new including twenty six one hundred
the sun goes around
the milky way
you can go on and on so clearly
twenty six one hundred
it's not
an initial
reference frame
we can try to make an estimate
on how large these accelerations i
that we experience
in twenty six one hundred and that's part was the one
that is due to the earth rotation
he is the earth
rotating with angular velocity omega
here is the creator
and have had a certain radius
of the this is the symbol for
i don't have twenty six one hundred is here but let's just take the worst
that you're on the equator
you go around like this in order to do that you need the centripetal acceleration
a c
which as we have seen last time
it was only because we are
how large is that one
the period of rotation for the earth
twenty four hours
thirty six hundred seconds
so omega
because two pi
divided by twenty four
nine thirty six hundred and that we can be in radiance
per second
and so you can calculate now what omega square are surface if you know
at the radius of the earth
is about six thousand
four hundred kilometres
make sure
you convert this to me is of course
you will find them
that the centripetal acceleration at the equator which is the worst case is less here
o point o three four
the second square
and this is way way less
this is three hundred times smaller
then the gravitational acceleration that your experience here
and if we take the motion of the earth around the sun
then there is an additional factor of five times slower
in other words these accelerations even though they real and they can be measured easily
today's high-tech
in some entation
they are much much slower than what we used to
which is the gravitational acceleration and therefore in spite of these accelerations
we will it's except this whole
as a reasonably good
frame of reference in which the first law
then it should hold
can newton's law
we proved
the answer is
because it's impossible
be sure
your reference frame
it without any acceleration
i do we believe in is
yes we do
we believe it since it is consistent within the uncertainty of the measurement was all
i have been done
now we come
to the
the second floor
newton's second law
i have
the spring
get gravity for now you can do it somewhere in outer space
this is the relaxed length of the spring
images the images are taken independently you know and you want to
two to build the probability probability model for these images
this is what people in optimisation called the sample average approach however the real situation
many combinatorial optimization problems is that the definition of your problem instances noisy
you most get one or two cases so maybe ten
but there is much more to be learned about local smoothness and segment statistics from
a very small number of of of
of of let's say images so that you are forced to use a you know
statistical relations between neighbouring feature descriptors in order to build up your model
and i think that that is one of the challenges at least i perceived so
far if you have a setting where objects are independent then the whole bag of
statistical learning theory volvo like you know you have you have large deviation recites you
have IID contributions of your empirical risks to build up your costs and then you
can easily define what you mean by expected costs and so on and then couple
it's no longer so clear
it's probably one of can discuss later
OK so so maybe this example also makes it clear
what at least one possible road is i'm not saying this is the only one
but what one possible wrote two to learning the more complicated setting here you have
you have protein data they are pairwise compared you get these these these sort of
these little bit structure but otherwise randomly looking matrix here is symmetric so some of
the structure is coming from symmetry here if you permute you're you're you're columns and
you're rose then you clearly see that you have
big groups in here three and you want to find these these groups for example
data are abundant here is an example from biology molecular biology we have first use
that falling up the the
research by gaming gaming coffin you dont we have used it for these landsat imagery
basically what you do is you have a and a local image patch here you
have look image patch here you get some empirical distribution of your features in that
area and that area then you apply a statistical test whether these two area as
below come from the same source are empirical realizations of these cells and if if
if a high square statistics for example tells you these are very similar then you
should have a small the value otherwise you get the large one and then you
have a pairwise clustering problem and this is the the ultimate labeling of three classes
now it's not so clear how you will generalize from this solution we basically have
a bunch of of simon variables of all my different local image patches with the
local statistics extracted there how i would i would use how i would use the
solution to my training image and then sort of
just copy it to the test image without actually optimizing on the test image from
and i should also say
in that setting you know you compare all possible image pairs here so you want
to take a one up here and compare it to that one down here so
all these all these these sites that come between each other
now the cost function is sort of rebuild according to k means for that for
that new data type basically what you do is you some up the dissimilarities between
object i and j whenever both objects belong to the same cluster so that's the
compactness criterion which also have been in k means when they belong to the same
european commissioner for
two hundred forty million network called messenger communication over one month
microsoft messenger right scale structure
global population but of course this not just that it's just
making this
thank you
there's really much more so the question is how does massive network data compare small-scale
and the newly appointed intrinsic
july KDD efforts
inference for example you see
this is necessary you
more in line
right so more
it can be observed
really close the
that are truly there are literally invisible at at smaller scales rates and
the point of view
talk something where
you can see what you have a hundred million people
thank you
you can see thirty four
ferrari two hundred people
at the same time less
namely the security
according to this he knew exactly who these people were
what is social ties is able to interpret the data and get some information processes
the rivalry is decision
the groups and so itself
well we got a much larger scale
i don't see any one of these
because of the the human inspection and so on
a lot to
it's much harder to pose nuanced questions and so i think one of the big
challenge area
it's really try to find the point where these two things beta or
OK we have to
tracks social research one
very complex questions about small groups focused on processes and outcomes and there really is
measuring massive data mining is not significant
but when trying to get back to the question
in the inference process model
and so that he
an issue
the tag
in addressing
the methodology
come come into play the
this is also kind of talk
now data is really much
don't try to draw pictures of nodes connected to
connected to
much much more
in this context and
and what can be can be free
second the first half the talk is going to be the most models and conditional
basic vocabulary for expressing
complex of expressions and complex
it's a wonderful life data
this created
i think in some of the questions of really interesting social networks and large
there train something that
into the system that we can do and think about all the issues that come
into play when you deal with large
ten years
is found in this certain
data which are really in some cases particularly extreme context right question whom
the fantasy
data going to
and that's then roughly following talks for this happen is more expression
OK and starring
three one example
you have to talk about
for small social networks for an analysis this
or between
the basic social questions moving into
interesting mathematical models and as because some valid
it relates more closely
the story is possible and also raise more conceptually difficult questions
possible sources
three slides but this
so this is my work
so social psychologist in the the nineteen sixties experiment the
six degrees of separation experiments many maybe
for you may not
not understand with all
six inches apart in societal small energy difference friend of a friend of a friend
of yours be honest
in all he developed experimental
now in which she picked up
for reasons of cost sharing messages etc it's and trying to make sure that
effect of the people
at random
citizen kane son
no trespassing
all right that seems to form
just this and this the same trying this
the story
we sent this letter to a friend someone you know is this
with the goal of regions named individuals on the target perspective
the name address patients personal data has some reference for finding but you can be
able to read militants
for with the goal of this process can now
so so far this a different from something we study which again
typical hundreds of studies of social networks in this
this small contains just because is you want to study the global financial release the
french in their entirety
united states can help to measure and so in a sense
stroboscopic method methodology directly after this industry is led to the top of the tree
and the
definitions of medium was far me was
six chain
natural plant sixty four changed completing the number sixteen separation but interesting
of course
if you want to formalise your prior knowledge rate is five
ah now centred at the end with the edge weights change to what they plus
the number of times you cross that it just the same as the irish like
and if you wanted to read about resources
the was in the paper and it was so clear that any and all sins
a couple of years ago bayesian analysis for
markov chains so
the next transparency
the store
go through
mixtures of conjugate priors are dense it's easy to simulate from prior posterior by using
random walk with reinforcement that is very easy to run this random walk with reinforcement
just start off new london and that the proportion of times that you cover image
to the to the prior
the probability of an edge i just i just wrote down it's very convenient the
connection between random walk with reinforcement and and this conjugate prior analysis is convenient computationally
computationally this w johnson style of characterization so and haven't told you about it and
this is the wrong
first the talk so we want is what is this five and there's a reason
for my showing it to you to come from x transparency
OK now is
if x is a vector indexed by the edges of the graph is the edge
the original weights of the graph
everything looks kind nice was the product of city that
the rate of descent understanding the notation
six v
it is the sum of x
so in this way leads out of the
so those exhibitions in the are in fact sums of the edge went to
strange sort of sort of the way it should be whatever that means that strange
is that the term and this a conjugate prior what's the square root of the
determinant going on
going on there about ten years so it's the determinant of matrix indexed by the
edges and a and so
well no it's indexed by the homology of the graph so i the dyad
sons around cycles of x being
and the i assigned around cycles with signs on them
OK let me try to explain that got this graph
have to choose the basis for the cycle space and is the standard
the minimum spanning tree of graph that the tree and its that's not tree if
you have a cycle if you take all the edges that are tree
and take them out one at a time that is the basis for the set
of cycles in the graph and
the size and
you've got to orient the cycles it doesn't matter how we you have to into
the standard problem that you have to do and
just as a plus sign if the orientation of edges the same in the two
cycles and the minus sign otherwise
the only thing that was so the normalizing constant of you know as you know
if you try to compare two different markov models no normalizing constant is an enormous
benefit in computational and of
bayesian statistics so we can resolve this
but i think you need to know
direct apology comes in the probability
and is now trying to come into statistics are are the
first the first multi group of the graph is just an integral part of this
because i know that when i was a graduate student i can recognise when i
met it
in this problem and so
that means that
what next transparency OK
next to step
this is a test for processes markov chain OK if you do this in tests
you put a prior on the markov chain you can compute posterior is and i
would not have test to markov chain versus independent because i could put a prior
on independent reasons space factors it's natural to test the markov chain something
with a complicated dependence for example second order markov markov something like that
so the problem becomes hard to put a prior on
for markov chains are we talk about article to turn
now i see
of the maximum likelihood estimators not some sort of derivation
that they are the correct ones
OK so here is an example of how this works
suppose we consider an exponential
so i've written in here with a random variable t
so that might represent some
decay time
and the parameter tau
represents the mean lifetime
and suppose you can measure and
life times and values of t
right so the likelihood function is the a function of this parameter tau
and that is simply given by the product over all the elements
of the data sample
and then what i have is the PDF each time evaluated with the key piece
of i and so i simply have to find the value of tau
which maximizes that function
and that's easy to do
as i mentioned it's much easier to work with the log of the likelihood function
and you can see why that is because when you take the logarithm of that
product to get gets converted into a sum of logs
right so it is it's numerically easier to deal with some of the products and
furthermore if the PDF contains an exponential terms than when you take the logarithm that
exponential term goes away
so that is the expression for the log likelihood function
so i simply have to differentiate
that with respect to how
and set it equal to zero
and so for tau
and when i find the solution i write it with the perhaps because they had
represents the estimator and in this particular case the function happens to turn out to
the arithmetic average of the individual t values so that's
very special simple case i mean this is not always so simple
OK so to illustrate how that works i again wrote a little monte carlo programme
which generated
fifty values
according to an exponential distribution given the technology that we learned yesterday are two days
ago you could easily do that so those tick marks represent the
p values
and i use those in my maximum likelihood estimator of theta generate i used the
true value of tau equals one
and my maximum likelihood estimator lo and behold comes out very close to one
so that's a very simple example
the estimated value
and the true value of course are never exactly equal
because the data are subject to random fluctuations
and so on
i need to somehow
the statistical uncertainty in my estimate the uncertainty that arises from the fact that i
have a finite data sample
that leads to general
topic of the variance of
and there are a number of important ways of
determining the standard deviation variance of these estimators
so we'll discuss
three or four waves
the most straight forward way conceptually
would be following what is the standard deviation of an estimator represents how much
estimators value would fluctuate upon repetition of the measurement
so find let's write a monte carlo programme to simulate the entire measurement and then
repeat that a large number of times
that's what i did i
generated somehow
and a large number of times the entire sample of fifty
measured values coarsest different sample each time
for each repeated experiment you get a value of tau had you put that in
a in a histogram
and after some large number of experiments you get this histogram here
so then if you just compute the standard deviation of those towers values you get
the statistical error
of of tau
and i like this this example because it illustrates
most directly exactly what you mean by this standard deviation of an estimator it's the
level of how much the value would be distributed how widely the value would be
distributed upon repetition of the entire experiment
you get some value sigma had of tau
is o point
one five
you can notice this distribution here this is roughly gaussians shape it sort of has
the bell shape
that's kind of interesting because the original distribution of p values is exponential
so can we understand roughly wide that gaussians
well that's actually pretty easy because the estimator itself was the average so it is
to the sum
of those random variables and so recall from the central limit theorem the central limit
theorem said that if you take the sum
of a sum of random variables as long as there are sufficiently large number of
terms in that some
then it's distribution the distribution of the sum
becomes gaussians
and that's exactly what we're seeing here
that's that's almost always true for maximum likelihood estimators as long as you have a
sufficiently large number of
measurements in your data sample
the monte carlo method is a little bit difficult in the sense that you actually
have to sit down and write a computer program and usually you make lots of
measurements and actually have to write monte carlo programme just to analyse the error for
each that would be a lot of extra effort
so fortunately there are some approximate methods that
are much faster
and one important one is based on an inequality called the information inequality is sometimes
called the
the whole come out fresh or cf inequality but anyway never mind the name
the inequality sets a lower bound on the variance of any estimator so this is
love this inequality applies not only to maximum likelihood estimators but estimators
but you derive
in any way
and what it says is that the variance of any estimator theta hamas must be
greater than or equal to this expression here
b is the bias
and here i have the expectation value of the set negative second derivative
of the log likelihood function
in many cases the biases either identically zero or is very small
so very often that there can be neglected
so that means that furthermore
even though it is an inequality
in many
problems of practical interest
quality almost holds
so in in many cases we can simply approximate the variance of data had by
this expression here minus one
over the expectation value of the second derivative of the log likelihood function
now find what we really want is not the variance of the
estimator of a parameter we want
of the variance of the estimator of a parameter that is to say we really
and it takes
the set of stocks simulate
a big figure number this is play but for a bunch of graphs
i want to say what graph it is
and whether or not i believe in big mo
it sets the mean to zero
and then for as in the stocks it moves it
giving it the bias the momentum
and then it shows the history
and then computes the mean
getting me the mean of all the stocks and we've seen this sort of thing
many times before
and then got some constants
by the way i want to emphasise that i've name these constants to make it
easier to change
starting with twenty stocks
a hundred days
and then what i do is i stocks someone
stocks one
will be empty list stocks two is the empty list
why do you think i'm starting with bias is zero
what do you think the mean should be
if i simulate various things that the bias is zero
i started one hundred dollars is the average price of the stock
what the average value of the property
if my code is correct which is the average price p after say a hundred
if there is no bias
one hundred exactly
since there is no upward downward bias
they may fluctuate widely but if i look at enough stocks
the average should be right around one hundred
i don't know what the average would be if i chose different bias
a little bit complicated
so i chose the simplest bias
important lesson so that there will be some predictability in the results
and i would have some if you will small test for knowing whether or not
i was getting
my code seem to be working
all right
and initially well maybe initially
just to be simple on the start of momentum equal to false
because again it seems simpler
have a model where there is no momentum
i'm looking for the simplest model possible for the first time i run it
and then we looked at this little loop before frying range numbers stocks
i'm going to create two different list stocks
one where the moves
are the distributions are chosen from a uniform and the other where there
some sort of curious as to
again which is the right way to think about this
all right
and then
and then just call it will see what we get
so let's do it let's hope that all the changes i made nine introduced syntax
alright aleister did something to what it did
the test on the left you'll remember
i was the one with
test one i believe was the
the uniform distribution on test two is the gaussians
so but let's what should we do first
do the smoke test number one is the mean more or less what we expected
well it looks like it's dead on one hundred which was our initial price
in test two
know how to solve it
and furthermore
every algorithm that follows the divide and conquer paradigm will have occurred to pretty much
the same form
very much like our good friend the master method
let's do it for so we sort of already know the answer
get a bit practice
this is the commercial recurrence you should know i love this recurrence because it comes
up all over the place
it comes from this
this general approach by
just seeing what are the sizes of the subproblems you're solving
and how many there are and how much extra work you're doing
so you have here
the size of the problems
it happens here the pose problems have the same size roughly
there's the sloppiness
we have which really should be t o four manova two post you've ceiling event
at two and when you go to recitation on friday you'll see why that's OK
cause ceilings dark matter this if you can prove that
that's happy you can assume that n is a power of two
OK but we're just gonna sing that for now so we just have to problems
of size and over the
two is the
number of problems
and this water and is all the extra work we're doing now
what's the actual work potentially conquering is always just recursions sort of no work there
except this we are
the dividing in this case is trivial but in general might involve some work the
combining here involves linear work
so this is the divide and conquer
running time
so this is the non recursive work
and that's generally how you convert divide-and-conquer argument recurrences really easy
and usually get to apply the master method here
we are in case
this is case two
and k is zero here so
in the recursion tree all of the costs are roughly the same they're all and
log base p of a year
and so the log base
two of two is just and so these are equal so we get an extra
large factor because of the number of levels and recursion tree
remember the intuition
behind the master so this is an login and that's good merge sort is a
fast learning algorithm and morgan social circles and squares
in some sense in logan is the best you can do will cover that
in two lectures from now but
today we're going to do different divide and conquer sorting is one problem is all
sorts of problems we might want to solve
so how it turns out a lot of them you can apply
divide and conquer to
not every problem
like how to wake up in the morning it's not so easy to solve the
divine comparable
maybe you could
maybe it's a good problem set problem
the next divide and conquer algorithm we're going to look at is even simpler
sorting even simpler than merge sort but it drives the whole point
drives home the point when you have only one some from how many people seen
binary search before
anyone hasn't
i will go very quickly and so you have some element x
you want to find x in a sorted array
how many people had not seen it before the sun recitation
no OK go visit another class
probably six double winners get detector the prerequisites OK
so i just want phrase it as the divide-and-conquer because you don't normally see it
that way
so you compare the device that is to compare acts with the middle element
in your right
then the contra step so here's your
here's the middle elements you compare acts
with this thing is that say x is smaller than the middle element and you're
a you know
the axes in the left half sort of
nice looking very very whatever we're just think about recursively i'm going to solve the
problem of finding x in this
so in paris in one sub
mike mercer we had two recursions
and then
the combined step
we don't do anything
i mean if you find that if you find x in here then you found
x and the whole room
there's nothing to
bring it back up really
so this is just raising binary search as
in divide-and-conquer paradigm this kind of a trivial example but there are lots of circumstances
really need to recurse on one side
and it's important to see how much of a difference
making one recurring versus making one two recursions can be
so here we have
this is the recurrence for binary search
we start with the problem size and we reduce to one
there is an implicit one factor here one problem subproblem size and over two
OK i guess we
OK so it's probably worth pointing out that we
when we compute the rademacher complexity this linear function as and also called the
boosting case
we compute its
the thresholding your remember i mean we didn't use the actual
classification of who
rademacher complexity of the classification functions
as we did with the VC class
we computed of this
past that underlies
the thresholding
and you know this would correspond in the way
the move from the BBC
sounds to the margin bounds
if we went to the thresholding we know that BBC
so we went to the
to these large high dimensional feature spaces we know that the
we see dimension it's very very high
and so
we will be lost so what we're attempting to do is to
this and she would be seen again and uses marginal
aspects to get away
and so we can we compute the
the rademacher complexity the underlying function class and we've seen that that's actually the nine
that's not a problem
what we have to do now is to get from that
underlying function class to the actual classification we're interested in
and in a way this is starting to give us a hint of how we
might do it
what we're going to do is going to take this heavy sight loss
and we going to approximate it with this
a loss hinge loss
and then we're going to apply the rademacher complexity to that
treatment on top of the underlying function class
so this is the sort of
like loss function that we apply
so it's a piecewise linear it starts at zero and then it goes up to
between minus gamma and
zero sum between minus cameron zero
it goes in a straight line up from zero to one
so it has slope
no one over gamma in that in that region
in that way
we can
upper bound this is the thing that was sort of interested in well without that
minus one that's what we're interested in that was what was on the previous slide
which was the
although the misclassification was just this expected value the heaviside function thing
so we can sort of
and all that i have added minus one will see why nominator worry about that
but it will go away
here's what i've done is shown that this age is upper bounded by the way
when you know the the thing makes it straight up from zero to one before
we get to zero the heaviside jumps up to up to one zero
and so
this is actually a larger value than this one so we can say less than
or equal to this but this is now
it is actually a smooth function
in fact we can therefore apply
the rademacher complexity to this function
bound so the true expectation of this function is the empirical value of its
estimation of its
plus the rademacher complexity of the underlying function class
plus this normal
so we have with the rademacher so this is applying the basic rademacher bound this
what is the function class of surely there should be at some b here i
or sorry if someone because we had a restriction on the function on the norms
of the weight vectors to be one
that's why we did that make
so that if someone here
and this is the function a minus one which is the function that we're effectively
applying what i mean by that is apply a two
and then subtract one from it
and f is
sort of this function here minus one here that OK
so that's basically the way
we're reviewing it
this is the composition of every function from here with this single function here
that's what i mean by this
so that's
so we went about to this
by moving to this sort of soft versions
the second inequality is basically just an application of the
general rademacher bound
to this
so i to this function here
so the true expectation of this function
is the empirical value plus the rademacher complexity of the function classes drawn from
plus you know that's the standard directly
maybe i should just go back to the general
OK so every want to say
OK so that's that's what that is the only difficulty is that
it's not immediately obvious that this function is drawn from this plan that's what i
was trying to explain
OK this from what i mean by this is the functions that you get by
taking a linear function of norm one
multiplying by minus the classification output of the values
applying this function a
and then subtracting one so that converts every function
every linear function into a function
and that's the function from this class sort of what i mean it's a bit
of arbitration but
and in terms of representations with graphical models allow us to do is they allow
us to represent conditional independence relationships between variables
without bothering with the details of their parametric forms of the probability distribution
so we're just representing the relationship between these variables that helps answer questions like
is a dependent on b
given that we know the value of c
we can cannot just by looking at the structure of the graph
without having to know you know what it
probability distributions are
and then computationally graphical models are incredibly useful because
they allow us to define
general message passing algorithms to implement probabilistic inference efficiently
so we can answer questions like
what is the probability distribution over some variable given that we know that the variables
be takes on the value see
without enumerating all the variables
in our model
just by passing messages in our graph
graphical models really borrow ideas from different fields there fundamentally statistical there are representations of
statistical dependency you obviously make use of some of the elementary graph theory
and in terms of
computer science when you think of actually implementing algorithms for doing inference in probabilistic models
you make use of
basic ideas in computer science
develop efficient algorithms object oriented representation of the earth
the main thing graphical models do is represent conditional independence so let me introduce some
notation and let's talk about the cost of the conditional independence
so the notation is the following we say that
is conditionally independent from y
it can be
that's the notation that we use
and this means that the probability of x given y and b
it's not dependent on y another the probability of x given y and b is
just equal to the probability of x given the
in this condition
it's just that the
playing on the conditioning by have been possibility shouldn't really conditional something that's impossible
so whenever you y and p is strictly greater than zero
another way to see conditional independence is as follows
the probability distribution
for x and y
x and y are conditionally independent given v if the joint probability between x and
y given the
factors into the probability of x given the
and the probability of y given
so is the usual notion of independence or marginal independence
which i have down here except that we condition on having observed values of variables
the variable p
and in general we can think of conditional independence relationships between sets of variables
so we write down
this that act is conditionally independent from the set y given the set b
what we mean by that is that for all
the variable x in the that acts and all variables y and that really why
these are independent given the entire set b
having observed all the variables in t
now that the traditional independence that we all learn about in elementary probability
we're going to call marginal independence
and that's just conditional independence condition on on nothing condition on
not observing anything represent that the empty that here that is the probability that and
back the probability that the probability of y
so here are some examples of things we might think about as being
you know satisfy conditional independence really
if you get a beating find the amount of your speeding fine
it is independent of the type of of car that you're driving
given the speed that you're driving right that
we should really penalize you are driving a porsche or something like that
obviously these things are not
you know they're not marginally independent because presumably some some types of cars drive faster
than other types of parts
and so on
you know you just measured types of cars and amount of speeding fine you would
find some dependency but it should be conditionally independent given c
now we know that both smoking causes both
you know your keen to get yellow
and one cancer
given that you smoke presumably you know in
fairly simplistic model of the world where you don't do other things that are in
your the yellow lung cancer is independent of you smoking
if you are modelling an object this could be
for example modelling the movement of objects in video or modelling some robotic joint or
something like that
if you measure the police
position and velocity of that object at time t plus one and following some sort
of newtonian dynamics any measure the position and velocity and he minus one
then these two things we presume are conditionally independent given the position and velocity at
that was what she was
that so one the princes
this is only small
that is to all of us
is the loss way
right across the UK
so all
and reproduced in the right hand
when i said well written
the virus
thirty five is a relation
that's the that's what chains
because all sorts of hundred years
many different varieties
she are of you know that
that is why also we as long
right by the the way working with that's reason
well they
the best solution for
to sing
you can also use the rest
we want to see the
that's what it
you know there's a lot of these cells
one city
this is shown
i agree that really is this is the
that is here is the outline that
and the y axis of
this is the
and all the rest of of us
so we're not part of europe
a zero cost
but we must also handle
this is is that the sun
the green line here is
of these losses athens
one way
this is this one
no just
right now you can see all these things they
it is the as that of this
this one
you just the way it did not fall no
so this is more so can
that's what don't
to those years all these things
he has
he the
this one is
this is one
have been lost which
in the reason i thought
in this the machine
at the extended to solve
where is will be
so the context of the
it is located in the problem is this
three strange
to use
to use the one which is the
approximation to what you want
to work with
you want to present you a little not too
there is
be able to restore all these properties
that will be
the hardest part
the first thing we do is prove that these properties imply
the tree has to have higher order log and therefore all searches and queries on
that data structure will run fast and the hard part will be to make sure
these properties stay true
if they initially held true
when we make changes to the tree
let's look at the height
a red black tree
and from this will start to see why this why were these properties come from
why which was these properties
so the claim is the height of a red black tree with n keys not
saying those here because i really only want to count the internal nodes not these
extra leaves that we've got
as i did last two times larger than plus one so order log n
we have pretty precise found
factor of two
there's proof of this is the textbook
by induction agreed that
what i'm going to give us more proof sketch
the proof by induction because
all the practice you can get to find action is good the proof sketch on
the other hand is a lot more intuition what's going on from the red black
and connects up with recitation on friday so that means
i tell you that instead
i believe
like or here
the first thing i'm going to do this and i'm going to manipulate history until
it looks like something that i know
the first thing the the main change going to make
is to merge each red node into its parent
we know that parent average node must be black
emerging trend into its black power
let's look at that here
take this road merges into its current state for now merge into its spam and
so on this one which i can reach but i'm going to redraw this picture
so seven
so the top node
now becomes in some sense of the
and it's a
they got merged together but no one else joined
then on the left we have three
nothing join that there some leaves structural
if you look at me i'm going to have to draw
so four
so some merging
these notes together
an emerging all of these nodes together
because each of these red red-nosed merges into that black
an emerging these tuners together in this remote into that blacked so now you can
see from the root which is now seven slash eighteen there are three children hanging
so in that picture
like two
draw that fact
so something like can get this support
this is a
between seven and eighteen
i have this
conglomerate node
and there are four
leaves hanging off of that now
and after the right after eighteen
i have a conglomerate twenty two slashed twenty six
and there are three please hang up there
kind of weird tree because we deal mainly with binary trees so far but this
is a foreshadowing what will come on friday
this is something called two three four tree
i guess is why it's called the two three four tree
every node can have two three or four kids here
except the leaves they have zero
OK is another nice property of two three four trees
maybe hinted that so there's really no control over whether you have
two children are three children or four children
but there's another nice property
all of that
all the leaves have the same depth exactly all of these guys
i have the same depth of the tree
why is that because the property for
on friday you'll see just how to maintain their property but this transformation we get
all the leaves have the same depth because
their deaths now
or they say are hiding the tree
is there black kite
the death of these leaves will be the black eyed of the room
because we so we're erasing all the right notes and we said if we look
at the past and we ignore all the red nodes than the number of black
nodes along the path is the same now are basically just leaving all the black
and it can be sparse because in this part of the dictionary
so that
is it true that way of motivating that we should be learning the
the idea is that we learned
well only for a number of things here by one of the top on the
web so you can complete the fill in the blanks so you're forced to do
that now
but we're going to learn the
to sparsify signals
we're going to learn the for the task so we're going to have different dictionaries
if you wanna the noise
or if you want to classify
we also learn the
four sensing different sensing devices
OK so that's the whole that i have freedom
of learning the of course i have to show you how we do that but
that's going to be there
main concept here
dictionary learning is the main message here
and there are a number of ways
of doing that
but the basic idea is the following
we're going to have how are we going to learn b
and have a lot of image
so i put all my images as columns here
OK so this is and that was my dimension but this is a very large
ten thousand
you can have a lot of images images are not problems today became the problem
that we have too many images is the problem
OK so
if you go to flickr there is a six thousand images loaded i mean
more or less
so so that's not a big problem today
we learned dictionary in such a way that every single one of these images
it's sparsely represented with distinction
that's the whole got
our optimisation problem looks like this and the sum over all the images
i want to a good approximation
of every single image
by a fixed dictionary and alpha j and i want on my alpha j is
for all the images for the p images
i want them to be spies and you're welcome to put here in the one
norm and make this alasso problems
is to find and el zero problem
but the optimisation is in contrast to what it was before
that he was only around five
the optimisation silver balls
the dictionary under representation both at the same time
even if i put a one
here this is a non convex problem
OK base convex if i fix one and optimize forty out if i put on
a one here
so the basic idea of that is to do i the optimisation animation that next
so once again it example is a linear combination of atoms from the
and each one has to be sparse
is a partial list of a lot of work that has been done in this
OK just a partial list
so how do we learn addiction and tell you just one way there are other
ways of learning the dictionary but i just want to give you
from the pedagogic point of view one way of doing that is not the there
the only way and sometimes with don't we used to use this a lot we
use it to be less today
in our group based very good way of learning the dictionary an unfortunate there's a
lot of red but we can still work here
so the idea is that we have been initialized dictionary let's say without wisconsin plus
forty year plus higher function
remember normally this is overcomplete
so we're going to initialize the dictionary
and we have done that
matching pursuit or a one
so with this dictionary
so let's look at this
this is like was prepared by by making it's a very nice light
so the basic idea is that they go every
every single one of my images and i represent leaves sparsely with the given action
OK so i have aspires school
i mentioned if used in one this is a convex problem
if you use the zero then you do matching pursuits orthogonal matching pursuit in chennai
i have for everything that i have is sparse representation
and i'm going to have the dictionary
in the particular case of the case
the basic idea is that you fix
what's called the active set
and that's that basically by almost all the algorithms that are out there
so i'm not gonna i'm going change the
atoms of my dictionary but i'm not gonna i'm not going to change this iteration
that means that are being used by the city
and the idea is very simple
so you go to the first item of the dictionary use alcohol use me
and you see that this
images you
and these images
and then you say OK and change myself so you that you like me you're
going to like me even more
OK and that just honestly the problem
then you go to the next atom as a whole use me
i might find seventy images use me i'm going to say i find myself i
the change myself they use seven likely more is like a weighted average of all
you guys which is an
and then you keep going
so you've got a new dictionary
one column at the time
and then you iterate this cuts
what you have in your dictionary the new sparse coding the dictionary and got
the basic idea in every dictionary learning out there is that you fix the active
fixing the active set makes the problem of dictionary update a convex problem
so so
you fix the active set by doing and then one or or or in p
and then you optimize to
and then you're iterate
OK so that's the basic idea
yeah all images or or we have now online learning that we are learning as
images but this is the simplest form the set of all the images but that's
a good question just to give you an idea we train
three thousand images for by just a few thousand patches it by a so we
talking sixty four with a thousand or five thousand ten thousand
but you can do that online this as they can
thanks by the way i am happy to entertain questions during the the talk if
need not too many but just a few
and we were all
he will be
you our
we talked about hierarchical Dirichlet processes and the idea of hierarchical Dirichlet process is that you
have to processes by using a shared base measure which is itself a
Dirichlet process distributed and that allows us to share topics across multiple documents
and that works pretty well let me see okay yeah so I think this idea of
hierarchy and building more complex models from simpler ones is a a very important idea
in in bayesian modelling and also in Bayesian nonparametrics because it allows us to
build well more complex models and we see that hierarchical models are kind of
quite natural technique forcombining this building blocks and we've seen lots of applications in
computational linguistics time series sequential models and so forth and vision and genetics that's a
different way of constructing this of more complex models from simpler ones which kind
of kind of comes under the name of dependent random measures and this I used
mostly for things like spatial and temporal type of data where basically every data
points so that you either with a points in space or points in in time
and you want to build dependence across either in a spatial domain or a temporal domain
that`s also then an idea of nested of nesting multiple processes together to build kind of
a more complex ones as well so I'll just briefly tell about dependent random
measures so this is basically a measured valued stochastic process so G indexed by phi
wherephi is some value in the covariate space okay so if think of phi
as a point somewhere in the space so that basically at every phi we might have a different
stochastic process G G ofphiand we can construct this on dependent random
measures such that each G of phi is gonna be marginally Dirichlet process so
that that's called a dependent Dirichlet process so basically we have a bunch
of Dirichlet processes and they have some some sort of dependence that is related
spatially so if twopoints in space are closer together then they then they`re corresponding
Dirichlet processes will be somehow more similar to each other okay and this is this can
be used in in various spatial modelling type of applications as well as in things
like density regression so density regression is a problem
that's kind of more general than just simply regression or classificationin regression or
classification you have an input and you want to predict the mean output at that
point in space and in regression you mayassume say a Gaussian noise around the mean
or in classification you're simply trying to predict the class and it's only a
finite number of classes in density regression given a point you given an input
points you'd like to actually predict a whole distribution over outputs and that distribution can be
very complex and you'd like to learn about not just the mean of this the
the distribution but also the shape of the distribution and you'd like to learn about
how things things like not just the mean might change with the with the
input space but things like the variance may change with the input space as well okay
so this is a kind of a much richer type of problem and that's I guess
people have explored this in things like biostatistics where you do want to to model
the the complex distribution on your output space given your input space that`s it
okay soin the next two sections I`ll tell about two
extensions of this idea of a hierarchical Dirichlet process the first one is gonna be
a degeneralization from a Dirichlet process to a Pitman Yor process
and we see that`s very important for doing for modelling languages and the second one
will be to build infinite hidden Markov models from this idea of hierarchical Dirichlet
process so let's start off with the language modelling so in language modelling the most popular
approach is basically N gramlanguage models so we'll start with that so what is the
problem here the problem isthat we have sequences ofwords or characters they're typically discrete
objects so things like this okay and basically this sequence of words just think of it
as a sentence coming from some language so English orJapanese or Chinese and so forth
and what we'd like to do is to build a model probabilistic model for
these sequences such that it assigns high probability to the sequences that you typically observe
and low probability to sequences that you don't typically observeand the idea is that
you'd like to model languages so that you can you can have a model that
can tell a system whether the sentence is a typical sentence or not okay and this is
used in things like speech recognition and machine translation and so forth and the simplest
way of building this sort of language models is to basically take this as sequences
ofwordsand build high order Markov models ofthis sort of sequences so a N order model
is this the N minus first order model basically assumes that the
probability of a sentence is gonna be a product over each word in the
sentence of the probability of that would given the previous N minus one word okay so
you care us assume that basically given the previous N N minus one words the
word that you're trying to predict next word I is independent of words further back