when q
when you choose the proposal mechanism to keep the particles
to be
the transition prior
which is what i did in the pseudo code that i showed you before
i took the particles that first put them through the transition prior
and then i weighted by the likelihood
the reason is because i was using a proposal mechanism that was the prior i
was trying the particles from the prior distribution
if i do that if i choose q q is arbitrary you can choose
but just keep to read prior then this councils with this
and the way is just the likelihood
when the algorithm was proposed in the early nineties and so on was proposed and
the names like survival of the fittest likelihood weighting
and so on and no one actually had bothered to the right thing in its
full generality
so most people are just using this kind of
condensation which is another ignorance computer vision was doing that
in fact they don't even have resampling
the algorithm actually technically speaking with four from one of his sisters
arnaud doucet
so the decision was the first one version formalise this properly
that's one application of it but it's now there's many more
OK and this is the equation i expect all of to memorize
that's rather this equation you can see if you watch the video two white and
it would seem like an hour
that's the question about chronic you haven't seen it i got it in my laptop
a player during the break
and if you have a differential equation lecture bigger particles in boxes and so on
you can transform this an integral form
and what you have here is basically nineteen equation with iron functions
i can think of this as the a matrix i can find
and you have this kernel of the kernel integral the green function
and you don't need to know this because
the details
the important thing is that in that in the area of quantum computers
quantum physics
you can also think of
when you have these particles and you want to find the i can functions of
these particles what you do is you keep passing the particles the
but the kernel of the system in order to solve danger
in other words if you have a vector that's that's all entries that up to
you multiply that by stochastic matrix enough times
that vector converges to a single fact
that's the google algorithm basic
it's a random walk converges to a single fact
they take the web
to construct the matrix for the web
which is a lot smaller than this one in fact this is continuing
and then from that
this is just matrix vector multiplication and if you do this repeated enough times will
converge to the effect
it's called the power method
numerical computation
so we can do the same thing here even though this is continuous we approximated
with particles
and we propagate is particles in the same manner is this is
has the power method or q
if you will the surfer method of google these particles are surfing the web
and out of it you get the i can functions
which other quantities of interest or the eigen values which other ground energy states
so this field of monte carlo even though we knew in machine learning and so
for particle filters
there was a sort of parallel track called quantum monte carlo
they're not as good
the state of the art in the quantum monte carlo world is not as good
as the state of the art in the machine learning literature now
OK so in general the algorithm then it's like this
if we don't make the simplification of sampling from the prior we really have something
from an arbitrary distribution q
and then we awaiting the particles
probably because think the expression that had
we normalize the weight something
the advantage of doing this is that now you have a proposal distribution can depend
on the current observations
you can have a data driven proposal distribution
so if you have an algorithm like
for the hockey players for example what we did is we use a deposed
to generate detections of the what the players were on the scene
and that is this proposals of what these guys might be
we also used
the transitions of the play the dynamics to get her to get likely proposal mechanism
sister where we believe that play with be
so yes all sorts of heuristics to extract good q
and usually that you can look at the data sets data driven
there's a guy in UCLA that has made a career of
doing this sort of thing they prevent what he calls data driven MCMC and statistics
most of us to data driven stuff
to get proposal distributions
in moderate dimensions up to ten dimensions was recall we're doing importance sampling
not expect around the particle filter nine hundred
continuous dimensions and that will work
mike work by because you happen to have a simple model
playing with fire that
this this weighs around
and this the sort of thing that should be you yes so you can see
you're running here by interparticle forces in parallel parking football players and so on
and of course if you can try
player track person
this is the guy called
all these algorithms and this is the
robert this tracking
kenji signed
one class of models for these methods have actually been very useful
the size of the image tracking popular is methods that have this sort of hierarchical
and the reason for this is that
it is the semantics of the graph
given x
y two does not depend on z
if you knew the axis that breaks the dependence of the y and that
and that is an extremely powerful things to note that because
what that allows you to do is that means that all you have to do
is inferred these guys
given those guys you can infer that the guy
so you will win
we will be able to a lot of analytical computations so i think the most
particle filters out there are these that combined
analytical computations
my name is the bush from general electric corporate research
global research center
i want to talk about an introduction to active networks
discuss little bit about not only active networks introduce the topic but also talk about
security and active networks
as well as commander of complexity
and the trade-off between
computation and communication
that active networks is brought about
i also should mention that you can click on the hand icon to submit questions
and click on the globe icon
to download this presentation
so first one like the knowledge that a lot of this work came out of
the dark but several years ago
and i want to thank all the people that helped to put together a lot
of these
i won't say standards but rather frameworks that are being used
to define what active networks are
the outline of my talk i will introduce active networks
and the assumption is that there is no
strict background required and communications two to understand this talk i hope
we'll talk about a little bit more detail about active network execution environments and a
testbed called be able
talk a little bit more about the security behind active networks because that is the
big question is
they offer a lot of flexibility but
they also bring up the question above management security because they are
so flexible
and in that part of the
solution to security we think can be found in understanding commander of complexity in the
of code versus data inside the network
i recently went to
presentation in course
it was told that people
generally come away with only three things after presentation
so the three things i'd like people to come away with from this presentation are
active networks are really cool
it's a neat idea
there is active networks can be secure
at least as secure as legacy networks and
again i think
for people to be throwing stones at active networks they should also think about how
secure legacy networks are
as well
and that the data and algorithm are mutable and fluid within active networks
and there's
the needs to be a real fundamental understanding the trade that can occur
in active networks between
both data and algorithms since both can be injected dynamically inside the network
OK let me start off with the motivation
for active networking
first of all legacy networks u
i have a piece of data static piece of data
you want to send it
to the destination put packet send and
it gets there
with active networks were starting to include code dynamically with the data that interacts deep
inside the network to change the function of the network itself
and why would we want to do this
well first of all hardware is becoming faster and faster
and more efficient and there are times when it is not fully utilized
so can we better food more fully utilize active or networking hardware
and we think active networking can help people to utilize the hardware
it certainly enables more flexible network
in fact extremely flexible network capabilities change on the fly
in fact we illustrate that with the darwin project in network where we put this
on top of a
wireless communications network
but there is talk that i'm giving his focus strictly on active networking which can
be both an fixed network wireless network
any other kind of network
it decouples the protocol
from the transport
so when i go through the slides i'll be talking about a framework for active
it's a very general framework and the idea is that the code is going with
the data
and the code can essentially carry the protocol
with the information that's going with it
one of the host was can minimize requirements for global agreement again because you've decouple
the protocol from the transport
we were
the hope was that you can avoid taking years and years to build
right standards
because people be injecting their own standards dynamically on the fly
obviously it enables on the fly experimentation if you have an active network testbed you
can inject the code for new
types of behaviour
on the fly
and it enables faster deployment of new services obviously
OK two primary goal throughout this talk i've incorporated
quite a few references so the hope is that if you download these slides
you can go right to these references and get the details that you need
the website would point to the work by darpa on this topic
and there's an email list for a
conversations going on related to the development of active networking
just to reiterate again
if you look at it as an evolution
traditional packet networks
there was a header data
and you
inject your data on one side
networks it takes at the other side through routers switches bridges hubs et cetera
with active networking
code can now appear inside the packets
so every packet that you send not only contains data information that you want to
but it can
actually contain code
which can change the behaviour of the network
as the packet is flowing through the network
and it can be
that could behind
to operate in change the behavior of nodes
as it flows through the network
so you can imagine all kinds of new possibilities with active networks that the monitoring
predictive control
making devices even more intelligent and responsive
reducing deployment time
and devices become more
the where their environments
if we look at it again from high level changes in the inevitable if you
look at the internet protocol
some people might claim that is becoming fossilized beginning to become more resistant to change
it's becoming extremely complex is there were four thousand rfcs describing the internet protocol now
and they're coming out at faster rates all the time
takes all quite awhile ago of IPTV fought IPC these six
there's is a lack of
strong security paradigm downward you know
but this one it will be can associated with
and earlier customer native wild fish two thousand my only appear
once we see customer number
o five thousand one thousand something
so the first thing we have to do to see that this thing is infinitely
it's kind forget about the ordering of the dishes
in the original paper in griffiths and ghahramani they count
what with this forgetting of the ordering of the dishes by looking at equivalence classes
of this
of these metrices
where each equivalence class is obtained by
ordering reordering all the dishes
but the way we're going to do in his covered that simple i think was
simply cannot name each dish
so this k is going to be named lambda stocking well under stock is going
to be drawn i i d from
some base distribution h
and of course the the name of the first dish is going to be drawn
from h in the name of the two thousand this is also to be drawn
from h so
if we
replace each dish
the index of each dish by its name
then we have effectively forgotten about the ordering of the dishes
so once we have named this dish is a customer now will in a set
of dishes
this i i simply going to be the set of
lambda stockade whereas i k equal to one and this set is independent of the
ordering of the issues that we can work out the joint probability again this is
not quite a density but
you can easily work out the this probability here because to something which looks like
and it is independent of the ordering of the customers
and now we see that this thing will be infinitely exchangeable
so we can apply definitely this theorem again and that states that there is some
random measure
that makes all of our customers independence
and this measure is what's called the beta process
scott not surprising that is called the beta process because
this random measure we can think of it as the infinite limit of this meals
which are
beta distributed
technically the way they but better process is defined the simplest way of defective of
defining process is as follows is going to have
i can introduce new parameter see here but this is another parameter in the previous
insurgencies equal equal to one so we say that b is distributed according to a
bit process with these parameters if it is a random discrete measure
it's not probability measure is that is a discrete measure
so it's also as an infinite sum of atoms except that the weights on the
atoms in the not sum to one
so b is going to be some from k from one to infinity of UK
delta theta stock so this is a point mass at the test rk with the
mass of UK
and again just as in the stick breaking construction
we can specify the beta process if we can describe the joint distributions
of the weights and the locations of the atoms
and we can specify desired follows so the points here
if we look at this point statehouse star one we wanted to start to be
to disappoint in the two dimensional space
if you think of this as our data access
and this is our email access
right so meal is
atoms and it turns out that the same user the mass on their terms and
ten so that
there will always be between zero and one
so this space goes from zero to one
and this is i think that space which may not be one-dimensional that we can
visualize this in a one dimensional space
and this set of points so for example this could be
they data one mu one
this could be
eighty two
me too
and this is the first tree
new tree
and so on so we lots of points we have infinite number of points here
it's kind of points on this space
and this b is
discrete measures so we can can visualize this as
delta functions right
where the height and location is going to be the tag
theta in UK
and this infinite number of
now look like this
and the way we can express the joint distribution of
both the mass and the location of the
of the atoms
by simply
s basically is the two dimensional puzzle process whether it measures is given by something
like this
is the right measure has can be decomposed as a
measure over state as it is it should be
alpha HT theta and a measure over the email axis
so if you look at this
this bit here
it kind of starts
and it has mu mind meal to the minus one
so it kind of
i'm going to be
draw this as this thing
this is
catholics this thing around so we usually
the way we withdraw this function is
that except that you take this and they around
ninety degrees and goes to infinity here
because of the mill race to the minus one
so this process what this is is that it has
and the total mass and under this curve is going to be infinite
because if you try to integrate this thing from zero to one you gonna get
infinity because it has lots of mass in this tale here is what we want
to say is that if we draw from this to the person process this
people know what suppose some process
the probably most people know
we're gonna get lots of
points down on this axis
on the
on the x axis and a few points
that's further away from the x axis
car high up
a draw from the beta process looks like that
right so the
beta process with
this the parameter goes to one is the affinity measure of the IBP that we
just described and when c is likely to one we have two parameter generalisation of
you can find
but it all
one of
on going
well they
and the problem of
in i
it is
we can
is it a highly specialized
they typically optimized for particular now domain
doesn't work very well
and often work much better than humans
now to my
that operate
although in fact the medical break them and go elsewhere
so that's the kind of
i think they want to achieve
and i guess what i'm trying to do is just one component of intelligence
we should be aiming for
the ability to operate
in many different domains
and i'm not sure i would say that the total machines within of intelligence
o will compensate the hand
first of all i had to be doing
ask how we did was well
any casual when you when you when you see that kind of intelligence you recognise
you just have a conversation with
and that's the whole point we're going to come back to the end
what i want to
a quarter past made before
what i might do was
a little bit of history
and and the end we get on this kind of questions that we just started
how to control them is really important questions
let me try to be a part of history
of artificial intelligence
this is a really rich story
and there's a nice summary this sort of ten to fifteen page summary in in
rosslyn all the
lots of references
and from a good follow-up
of the details if you're interested so this just like the one i'm going do
is just get appointed history as the first part of this impression of the brain
and then
and then i want to go into some of these
philosophical questions
but what is intelligence when we can do it all
and what happens when we get there
we still have control
i suppose you could try say i back
well i guess you can trace back to the greeks if you really want to
go back
presumably before that
but the story starts
in the forties so
there's some work people call mcculloch and pitts
nineteen forty
i made a model of an artificial neural
so the idea was that it was a mathematical model
the try to model
neurons in the human nervous system
roughly speaking the idea is this is a bunch of neurons connected to one another
a particular neuron can either on or off
and it's on with this big enough signal coming from it's connected neurons
the neighborhood neurons causes new under five
and of course it causes the neurons to fire
that's the basic mechanisms going around the time neurons are firing when something input gets
to a certain level
so the metamathematical model of this
which is the start of new networks
amongst other things
they were able to show that they could live with the with the network of
neurons artificial neurons
they could model
computable functions
they can model and the northern not and so on
so mathematically this had some nice properties
was computation device in effect came from
psychology cognitive science
but i had some nice mathematical properties
so that's one input
the artificial neuron from
mcculloch and pitts in this two famous these days because of their work
the other
famous input
and this is more famous and almost everything else put together
is a paper volunteering
nineteen fifty
in the journal mind
the paper called the computing machinery and intelligence and this is
the origin of the famous turing test which i'm going to come to
a little bit later
the theory was
the guy guide say this in the second world war from
the machines to the
the germans cipher
bletchley park
the genius of the first order
very great mathematician a very great magician like the contributions to logic
and after the second world war having built and machines placed plug were
to kind
german signals
he started thinking about
with the machine can be intelligent
and this is the one of the very first
very explicit
whether machines can be computers can be intelligent
so he
the rice festival raises the possibility of the nineteen fifty there were hardly any computers
almost no one knew he was talking about in that sense
just a very small number maybe half a dozen in the world
it's like many more
but already at that stage
if another editor doing
comparatively trivial calculations like ballistic calculations on solving
could gram problems
he was already thinking about the possibility that can become intelligent
and in that paper he suggested the turing test
which i'm going to come back to later
OK a little bit later nineteen fifty six
the some famous names
that college
this is
a very famous meaning in fact fiftieth anniversary
two hundred years ago
so that the college after fifty years
fifty years on from this meeting
thought the occasion was so important that it was important they try to get many
people back
what is there before
the original mating and had a big celebration
the k nine there's john mccarthy
one of the founders of a i say he was that the college at phd
and he over the summer he got some people to come to mind
to think about a nineteen fifty six five six years after the mine paper
and here is the name some people should know some of them
and if you do this you know the rest as you go on to say
john mccarthy
marvin minsky
in some cases stands in miscues it might take
claude shannon
the founder of information theory
one of the one of the great scientists of all time solomonoff probably these information
theorist friends information theorist
herbert simon won the nobel prize in economics and alan newell is famous computer scientist
and i brought along a system called logic theorist
newell and simon
had themselves the theorem prover
was that what this meeting so
thought well i i would be a good idea actually never mind to begin with
and they its transpose and everything is exactly right so this really is
exactly the negative transpose the primal
so first theorem
which is such a trivial thing i like to word down next to it
is that the dual of the dual is just the primal
and that's why it's called the dual
the dual the dual something else we would call it something else
so the first theorem is that the dual the dual is the primal trivial the
second there is also very simple
end fundamentally important
we have the current values of x
there are feasible for the primal problem
and somebody gives us values of why
there are feasible for the dual problem
then the current
objective function for the primal see transpose those those x
will be less than or equal to be transpose why
feasible primal objective values are smaller than
feasible dual objective values and the proof is really trivial
you don't even have to remember it all you have to remember is start here
right down why transpose x
and the news the two assumptions x is feasible
why is feasible
let's try to do them on
let's see here let's take the why transpose eight that's a real vector
being multiplied by a column vector x
let's take a real vector and right is a column vector transposed to make it
a real vector so that is why transpose aiz eight transpose why transpose right
but the dual problem
eight transpose why is greater than or equal to see
as part of dual feasibility
and part primal feasibility is all the become
all the numbers agreement zero
so this is such
summing up
the elements of this vector multiplied by elements in this vector these things are all
and so if i can put smaller values for these and make the whole some
smaller and smaller values of the coefficients in this and see because this inequality
so see transpose x is less the why transpose x
we're doing exactly the same thing on the other side this equality
we just say look okay
i can rewrite why transpose x is x transpose why
obvious but any x
is less than or equal to be
that's part of the primal feasibility
so the same idea all over again we've got this is less than or equal
something and all these things are non-negative therefore though
the whole sum is less than or equal to
those coefficients times these was so
is completely trivial we've used all of these
conditions ov feasibility we use all the conditions the primal feasibility here and here
we use all the conditions for dual feasibility here here so we have an under-used
are over-used anything we used everything exactly once
and we get this nice result that
the primal objective must be smaller than or equal to the dual objective
so we can look at this on a on a plot and just the real
line we just plot objective function values
if i plot the primal values in purple here
that gives me some interval values this interval might extend to minus infinity
and if we plot the dual values
we get another shown green which could extend plus infinity
but all agreed values must be bigger than all the purple values
and the one of the fundamental questions is is there a gap
is this possible or not
where is that as the situation always like this this will be a nice theorem
if you could prove that there's never a gap between the primal and the dual
the answer to this question will come from the strong duality theorem which will have shortly
and it's not quite trivial
now let's think about primal simplex methods in the context of the dual problem
so we have
a primal problem here it is
i write down its dual
so i will put the tools version with which
uses dual notation so i've got wise here
i guess he's ok so on the dual side always uses e for the dual
slacks and inequalities
so in the primal axes and w and do i always have wise enzi's
and the dual is exactly the negative transpose so the to the the minus three
to one become a three minus to minus one
zero three becomes a zero minus three
and this matrix this to a three matrix becomes this three by two matrix which is the
negative transpose
now let's do the simplex method on the primal problem more feasible so i can
do the primal simplex methods and see what happens in this watch what happens to
the dual problem
so i think
x to be my entering variable
and w two has to be misleading variables actually my only choice in this case
and we'll see what happens
so after i do that here's the new primal dictionary
here's the coefficients
if i do exactly analogous to that in the dual problem so i clicked on the uh
the middle column and the
last throw
if i click on the last column in the middle road that's this white to over here
that's this this but here
is that
transpose slot corresponding to the x two but here
was there is the fourier as the minus forty here
this is this button corresponds there but if i click on this button i can
do the algebra it doesn't look like the simplex method because i'm not even feasible
nothing i said befor makes any sense for clicking on this button
but i can do it i could do the algebraic in these equations
and and and and see what i get so i can click on them but
there are in this button here
p of x at time t
given my if i met some values x zero times so basically we interested in
this transition
PDF which defines this
and basically
one can show that
the equations that
the government the evolution of the transition probability
is is p
second what's just dt by p on the
the on the left here and we get terms from the drift
and also from the diffusion
a second order derivatives here with respect to the
the diffusion terms of first
during his respect interests basically what we want to do
is we might want to understand
even this evolution of this transition probability
in terms of fokker plank equation
so basically have to derive this is just just sort of continuous time version of
chapman kolmogorov equation basically we have some probability
time exterior zero what
at time t zero we consider all possible paths to get to
how we can be some next time to
and so this is actually the forward fokker planck equation and is also a backward
fokker planck equation as well
so yes
that sounds bad OK
i guess the square bracket is wrong
so yes
i think because deriving it from the jam content of questionable it is actually it's
guaranteed to do that right you have new building in that condition that's how you
actually driving this thing is actually
let me give you a simple example very simple example of a fokker planck equation
if we just have to be in process with scaling and drift then we'll have
i mean we said this was the stochastic form solution
is then very easy to see that the mean the mean value of this is
the time t is just x zero plus a
and the public
variance in fact which is
going is
sigma squared t OK so this is just because the gaussians distribution at time t
with mean exterior plus eighty and this variance is the square c
three simple example
i think that perhaps the main
o point where
fokker planck equations have a particular value
is in relation to
when we have
certain boundary conditions for
this speedy is for example
one problem which relates to to neural computation is that
if we start off with some
time zero here maybe and we can think of this is likely the resting potential
the neuron after firing we drive it with some noisy input signal and the potential
so in response to that maybe for the wiener process then we might be interested
in when
that potential crosses the threshold for firing neuron would be interested in this passage time
here but when this actually happens OK
in these kinds of conditions i'm looking at
one thing we can do course then is that we will be interested in the
first passage times density is essentially what's the probability distribution function of time when this
when this process
some business process first up across the
this disparity this very
but we can also be interested in maybe if we were just interested in the
probability distribution
at each of you know at some particular time here of what the what the
value of x is
at some time which essentially what we have to do is kind of siphon off
all the probability
there's already crossed here all the positive already crossed we normalize look at that
of these
of the process is sometimes
then we we can obtain this through
fokker plank kind of analysis basically
fokker planck stuff depends crucially on the markov properties of these processes right it's the
mark of structure the chapman kolmogorov equations actually allow us to do this analysis
and so the various
so you can you see that this is not a radically new
there go back to fellow in nineteen fifty two one can characterize various
there's kind of boundary conditions can be interesting make have absorbing barriers we could have
for example of collecting there is maybe could track this particle
in between two barriers here be interested in evolution
of the
from the transition probability as a function of time so some other conditions here as
well the thing that was mentioned in the introduction of course is that we
described a lot about
how we can actually
simulation this process and understand properties of one thing that certainly as machine learning might
well want to do
it is to actually
two maybe to do some parameter estimation
and in the system in the simple case actually fairly straightforward because
if we have some observations of various times
then the
the key property that actually makes casting process to work nice to work with in
respect is a parameter estimation is we can actually just write down a likelihood of
these observations
given the parameters
this is just
this is just a sort of multivariate yes it was just basically saying
i've got some covariance
matrix corresponding to these
he's he's and different points x one and to x t i i can look
at that covariance matrix got me
i got some covariance i really got it just one data point
and then dimensional data datapoints
in that
five thousand someone trying to do is to change the preferences of the gaussians so
as to
to maximize the likelihood that
these in in the simple case that's actually a misconception is fairly straightforward one can
that's essentially probabilities are intrinsic properties of
natural objects say so dice as an intrinsic property and in probability of landing on
one or two or something and this intrinsic property can be measured by experiments may
be in the frequentist way you use for the next over time
and at the other end of the spectrum there are the subjectivist will say
probably do not probabilities do not exist at all is just something that is in
your mind is just
i believe that you have about how likely the dice is to land up
two and to land on
the specific value
OK so
the next slide give more details about this and
i already told you so the frequentist interpretation is that you measure how many times
the sum ever occurred
as the number of
as a function of the number of times due to repeated the experiment and you
take the limit of this ratio
as the definition for the probability
the problem with this approach is that you often can not
do a repetitions of your experiment so for example you
if i tell you
what is the probability that the sun will rise tomorrow
sixteen of february
you cannot the sixteenth of february two thousand six there is only one such state
so you cannot repeat this experiment
so you cannot really define what is the limiting problem limiting frequency of the sun
rising on this specific day
so now
you can still say well even though i cannot measure it maybe still exists this
probability of the sun rising tomorrow may be in the intrinsic property of the sun
itself that's
tomorrow it will rise or not
so that's a matter of
believing that the physical system itself has this property
and some people
do not want to make this
i do not want to believe in that and the rather save
well probabilities are not something the probability that the sun rises tomorrow is not something
property of the sun about the property of someone talking about it
it will not let me
well the right
an interesting thing is that
we have seen these properties these axioms of probability and it happens that if you
try to formalize what it means to believe
with some degree
in some evidence so you try to define a function
the belief function that assigns number two events
and you try to ensure that this function
kind of rational corresponds to natural intuition about how you would combine
belief degrees
but if you do do that
you will end up with the same actions as the one satisfied by probabilities so
you could very well say
degrees of belief
satisfied the same problem properties as probabilities so maybe probabilities are just degrees of belief
i mean there's no no way to tell between them you know
another thing about probabilities
the famous bayes rule
from the previous sections and from the definition of conditional probability you can derive
this rule that tell you how you should update
probabilities are degrees of belief
whatever they are
so whether you're objectivist or frequentist or subjectivist you have certain probabilities
before observing the data
you observe some data and you want to compute the new probabilities after having observed
the data
well the natural way is to use
this bayes rule
OK the only thing is that often
the prior probabilities
cannot be defined in a frequentist way like the prior probability that the data is
generated by some function
cannot be defined in the way that you can measure the frequency
like you cannot repeat
your experiment usually in learning problems you have a learning problem you can
you can maybe get more samples but you cannot get more problems you you just
that one problem
so in this sense the probability that the function that the target function is some
the function h
it is more degree of belief that frequency
OK but it doesn't matter because
these rules they just make sense in himself in the way
but it doesn't mean that because this will make sense
using them
i will give you
good induction system or rather
it doesn't mean it doesn't imply
that you can
justify using these rules
and that's what i see here
it doesn't prove anything but you have used probabilities so if someone comes and tell
you well i have a very nice algorithms for learning that i derived from the
very rigorous statements in probability theory and they have use bayes rule
and they have used this and this property of probabilities so it should work well
that's not the case
it's just a nice way of reasoning
but it doesn't prove anything
see other cover set at this level
and you have to compute the distance from here to here it is in upper
bound of the system and its neighbour because
in the worst case the root is the nearest neighbour
if you go down the tree
at this level
of the tree
we can always do is occurrences can start eliminating
as we go down eliminating branches
but we can eliminate this one yet
up and down the tree still of a great deal from here
to here
but the scale
if you recall
into the back
so we have this scale
so this we can canada to
the children
but there's no could be at least this by the way
and then
that children could be this far
and then the children can be this far away
and keep and an exponential series
which actually get you closer and this upper bound
so that means you can eliminate
in one this note here
because one of his descendants
might be nearest neighbour query point
and when you go one well well well down you can eliminate
to this guy cannot descendants which are national average
so in these two satellite possibilities
these people walking down the tree
and only these three can be like possibilities
and now
the only two possibilities left and at the lowest level of the tree
see just you brute force amongst these two elements
everyone i make a cover tree
is actually several different ways
one is you can do single point insertion so you can you can insert
given the cover tree you can insert a new point into it
you will see that the same way as you do require you walk down the
making this cover that with the semantics is different it's the set of elements
will lead to the parent of the new point
is in doubt
and then you insert when you find the right point
it about construction c
was little here but
you can do it only once
it's a little bit faster period we you can prove any
there's no improvement theoretically
in addition you easy construction this is maybe the most it's interesting one
so now
we do you just say OK at pool of points
and then get one query
figuring out
one is there is is good
he points
which is
and a query
you kind of organised things but the distance to the query
and then you can construct
essentially and i think that the query is being the root of the cover tree
so i think the queries being the root
then you associate
all the points in the set which are nearest to the the
this note here
i wanted to look for the way this now runs all the way there
and so forth going out
and then new query
maybe it's going to be this point
and then
if you take some of the point associated with this no associate them
with this new the ones which are closest ceos kind of meeting the point issue
with equations critical says to
and then you can put some basic things you can prove it
this construction is fully amateur is we just entering
so a node is the query
the test points to the nearest query nodes
prove the answering queries
requires more distance evaluations then
the structure
so if you about about the integration time
you can set the set so that
it is never going to be seen if the worse than brute force
this is the insertion of them
michael skip
it's basically it's
one thing which is
it is an interesting about the size of the campus so well
so for the insertion of an can prove the size the campus it's going to
be see the fourth
the crime rate slightly larger it see the fifth
the whole here the first lecture
can i have
will back
text mining information and fact extraction
i am
b and i might change my
almost surely
in the math
so what about the rest the lack
the school for
but of course they don't
so what
if could write in a whole
well i'm very few
because we have to define the type of steel have been talking about
first of all thanks
we think about things we have need
alan it so are called in natural language
and so the
elements of the linguistic
which we could use it for information extraction or take my
and also important we text tries to accomplish certain communication it's
you interpretation in common gate ac
now we will hear more on right
of course you can do all the information extraction and text mining
OK context speech
our time all of the knowledge
so we need have to take into account the area of transcription
but here
we speak about
they take
now make it all kinds of the john that so you have
well the text
like the news
well maybe not really
you know the greek but the
we have a new which are usually one four
to the right
this is in fact a very
that was very well for
on the contrary
we had block
on the web and is some of range blocks
and if you know french
then you need to really it should be hard work
someone like care
because really the language
contrary to what some call a lot of excellent application that use and also this
in this
tactical for completely
and we have we have emailed we have to take
like his medical encyclopedia by members a group of people
there were two to one
the MIT and text text it
we have affecting many
many forms
now if you want to my
mind the
to gain access
on to the track comes source
ambiguity is somehow and we heard
which personally i think prefer the first of all in the mind
information extraction find information in the text
on the other hand once you have extracted from each
different space
so you can see that in fact if you look at PCA
it is nothing but another optimisation problems are you trying to do is
give me the ten features such that
the in the loss of information in the context is minimal
so you're trying to find those things
so when you do the orthogonal projection like dealer's showing you is basically an orthogonal
positions of that means all these
points are projected to
to that particular dimension
such that
the variance of the distance queries from each point in the plane is that the
minimal and that's PCA
so this is across quite a nice book i'm sure
and in time you must have told you the book by christopher m bishop
you must have said
that that's a brilliant book and is it's what's writing and reading
i i read twice and
quite quite nice and you feel a little bit about it when you read the
but i think that repetition is good makes you
you know that you learn fast and second is that it is up to do
because the techniques on from one chapter to the other
and always you're trying to find some kind of normality or
try it
so the the mathematics is this
quite good you don't really need to complicated mathematics but the locations you have to
get used to
so therefore what we trying to say is that tell me the discriminating features would
like a single quality measure or useful for
feature ranking for example
so basically what you want to say is that you know each feature
we was some kind of value
and then you say the higher the value means the benefits it is in
in making some kind of decision on for example
emphasis is less on finding
the contrast and more on evaluating its power generally that that's what is given
so i give you
very very simple example
and this is not a real that i just made it up for exploration purposes
so let's assume we have a data set with three feet not the feature space
except that the first one is randomly
uniquely given
so therefore we have prior knowledge that the first column doesn't carry any
meeting with respect to the data except
that uniquely identifies each
toppling that relation
so this correlation because it has to be fixed features
and each feature has a specific meaning the first one is the identity
the second one is a feature which is high
and the third one is
a class which tells you this individual is a happy or unhappy
now again classes like any other feature except that we are giving some specific meaning
to that because we have a purpose
OK some kind of a target feature and we call it is the class
but from
from a mathematics point of view
it is like any other feature supply as does not hold any special meaning except
the way we're going to use
so in this case
what we would like to ask ask is that is the height somehow
predict whether an individual is happy
so that that is the question is is the height is important
to make the decision
whether this individual would be happier
so the question is we can we can do various ways
we can apply
some kind of signal to noise ratio kind of algorithms or we can use
information gain ratio or we can apply some kind of
a statistical test for basically you're trying to say
while you know the height is going to
this communities
and you have a hypothesis and then you do some statistical test
OK so we give a very simple one
let's say wilcoxon rank sum test the nice thing with wilcoxon rank test is that
it doesn't issue
any prior distribution
you are not doing any parametric estimation
are we doing is just sorting them
based on
their values
and then we find the rank of each individual
and then we sum the ranks and then of course we look at
some kind of statistical tables that tells you
that they are significantly different
so so let's say here in this case what we've done is we've sort of
this data set based on the heights
let's say
the highest height would be the top of the list and the
the shortest first in the bottom of the list
and then
we have the first thing so so i have done this year as you can
in this
the tallest person is a two point two meters
and the shortest is one point two
so let's look at the very first item
this person is happy
so what we're trying to see is how many people below me are set
ideally want to say is that suppose let's say arguments say a all the happy
people on the top all the shock people on the
the bottom of the list
and it's very clear
that happy people
right because
all they happy to work on the top of the list
you know or unhappy ones one
there clearly knows that the height is a an important feature
in determining the per person is happy so that's what we try to do so
in order to do that properly what you do is you look at the first
one and is allocated is that person
so for this to be happy
you would like to many many to be underneath to be sacked
so in this case there are one two three seven people so the rank of
the first individual three
then you go to the sad one
the sad one
so the implication that this we want to do is
tower meteosat person so that means you want all the ones below
so in this case i'm looking for the once
OK so
sorry the the opposite ones happy ones
so so you look at the there are only too happy one so therefore ranks
then you go to the next one is so happened to be said again rank
two happy one set one of so now
we establish the rank for each individual
that's not new
here is a case where you have almost no noise
and here is a case where you have a large amount of noise
so it's a bit exaggerated as
o point but it is the same the same distribution
there are there exists also wasted relation for centuries reach regulation
but here i show you to to be consistent with the support vector machines presentation
i usually use epsilon insensitive regulation but if you come if you start from all
like your classical relation classical innovation was regularisation then you can go for which relation
and cannot which relation
OK so i won't go into details about
it was just too
to prepare the party position this afternoon
and now
i want to show you
and also limits on
which still fits into the representer theorem follows last method of course support vector regression
also feeds
the representer theorem so relates exactly is the same case that support vector machines
that may be issued over the principality component analysis and maybe you use so that
at the last week maybe seven times
the information that i want to insist on can in principle components because everybody knows
the reason
and the
it's not usually easy
to make
and i know that there is a close link and fits perfectly with the we're
of so
this is very interesting because it it is about also space remember we the input
we have feature space and have also the
the inverse space function this space so the
producing can then
space where you can
it was function and you can inspire you for other reasons
so we're going to to see you can in principle components with this point of
so i put these references in fact there are civil works in team of
at that time it was the team of close my eyes should go
and i think that's what i contributed as well and also
and this is a slide of the energy
so remember your linear PCA so you have some clouds of points
so what you want to do
you you want to change
in fact your representation space and find a more appropriate replenish space when where when
you project the data
on each direction you maximise the variance of your data
so you really what you're going to do is going to be in
this new were present in the representation space
by incrementally find
the directions that capture
the most the largest variance of production
so it so well that in fact he doesn't work for the of data
each time new are for instance
different cloud
of data it for you to be very nice way to
to get a representation of the data that if you have some clout like here
which is not there but which is really
alexis then you can imagine that it is better
to change your presentation
space before doing
this year
so this is of course the idea of cannon PCA so do
PCA but in the future
let's consider the
classic principal component analysis you have a set of tangent picture
and what you want to win
i want to work with is the orthogonal projection
of x
on on two direction w
he space after the core the annual projects it's just this kind of product of
the direction w
the case that the average length of your compressed file will actually be as good
as the source coding theorem says it's possible this thing we call the expected length
of the code
here's what it says on the tin
it is the average length of the next codeword gets encoded so is the average
of the number of live by these probabilities
the expected length
the theorem that says you can't be the entropy which is right
there's also a result says if you use the hyphen algorithm you will get within
one day
but the source coding theorem said you can do which sounds pretty good
within one minute of optimal wonderful
any more questions
OK guess the question is does the receiver have to know the lookup table in
order to be able to decode and the answer is yes they must have
the huffman code at the other end and that's a great question yourself anticipating one
of the issues of huffman code which is in general you don't actually know the
probability that the receiver doesn't know the probability is so then it got to invent
some way of communicating the probabilities to the other and so they can run the
algorithm all you've got to send the table so you actually little head the head
of your data files has by huffman codes output of sufficient information to reconstruct it
and that's a bit of a pain is a bit ugly and it makes it
even more suboptimal and this plus one indicates any other questions
OK is obviously can smashing together that punctuation well we can just look for example
of so we encode BAC with this thing one
and one one o that
so that's how you would encode BAC and the question is is it easy to
decode this or the receiver going have to some difficult inference to figure out what
is going on well
they know
every time they start receiving bits that when we started you can we always start
the top of the tree and then we walked down the tree speaking out characters
until we reach the bottom
so the code can just follow this rule you can say top of the tree
reading the next bit to determine whether it goes left or right it's one that
can come down now reading the next one is the goal of o spit out
to be
he has to be and returns to the top of the tree
OK that's the decoding algorithm so it just follows the tree so you just follow
pointers and you will
we recover
was encoding right so
the have algorithm is just optimal it is really easy is one really easy to
run and real easy to decode yes
OK so
the question is if there is an error
in the compressed file so one of these bits may be split
then what happens and there is a whole literature on that on what happens to
your huffman algorithm if you have an error and what you will have noticed with
and tags and things like that is maybe get whole patch of the image it
gets messed up and then recovers so you can design have algorithms and codes perhaps
to have some sort of recovery property that there won't propagate forever
maybe there's a big literature on on that the best thing to do better assist
is a really good error correcting code of of course
this is separate the so called for the
so what i mean by that is you can you can
every node in the tree is associated with some particular level some some integer
and that is one point in every node
you can
proof that if you think about the structure given expansion constant
in the number of children is bounded by c the fourth
you can prove imagine that the is quite sorry
so we have expressed constant is going to be
and not too unbalanced tree with
maximal number children born out
so this is the cover tree and a one-dimensional this might look like
three invariants
this is the the first one
the first one says that because of resources about the no other notable so this
she said maybe three it's easy to see someone support so the index goes down
as you go down the tree
he says
i what's the point appears to resemble this point appears
at this level
it appears in all levels
there's also a scale
associated with
the levels so
OK let me
there's this covering tree invariant it says that
o point
this low
just some of the points in a high level
just the distance between
the point
in the high and low levels is bounded by to do that
i so this is is made the distance to the
that grows exponentially as you go up
in levels
what is the
this is is
this is the cover tree invariant
OK so last one separation
this is that if you have to put some level
and this is between the point is that we least the scale of the problem
so this is actually the the
invariant which forces you to have the integration time
in the worst case
the reason why it's very simple dress here
you could
the tree
which looks like this in the worst case
so between every point is basically one
one plus my sets on
and then
if you want to maintain separation invariant
we have to do this for every child
check for every other child
separation advertisement maintained
because all of these children at the same level
in children protect every child every time and that's going to be integrated
show that
it is
is in a sense
it's not something
they don't need to tell or together
first of all
said these are natural numbers
in the negative
so we can support misleadingly scale you care about
and what you want to
practices you can just
in basically go as deep as you need to go
this is how i need to go
and as you see the data points distances
so this is not actually quite cover tree
there's one more thing which
doing scale which is important
if you want to get the
the exact i told you
then you can cope with the situation where you have two points which iranian one
but is very far
this is
o light years and that's an angstrom
it's going to be a lot of levels of the tree that in many maybe
under something that is not going to have scale
he was the number of points
so if you want to do that right
we have to do
the discrete implicit tree
every time a child node has only itself as a child
and itself was apparent
go back
this one is eliminated will this one
this one this one that one
this one is not because it does not have itself was apparent
so this implicit representation which sources can skip all the intermediate skills which don't
OK so that's the basic cover training maybe
you care about how you use it
so if you have some query point you can think about this kind of being
defined at every level of the tree
and what you can do is you can compute discovers that
the current set
as invariant which is that
the the elements of the set of the nearest neighbour of the query or the
distance of the elements
national neighbours of query
very far away
because the
why do you think it's too left using minus one wins
by was
the mind
five solution right if the test charge
that's all that's avenue
you think this this is madness
who thinks the forces in this direction
o things is in this direction
could you help them really
the force is obviously in that direction because if you very far away
the field will be the same as if you just had a plus three in
the minus one somewhere here which is plus two
so if you far away from the configuration like this even if you're here with
review there which you way there
the field is like a plus to charge
and falls off as one of our square
so therefore if you far away the forces in this direction and now look was
is very interesting
here's a few closer to mine is one of the forces in this area
he when you very far away we are to be all the way here
in that direction so that means there must be some way you point where
the field is zero
because if the force is here in this direction ultimately clones of in that direction
must be somewhere point
he zero and that is part
of your assignment
i want you to find that point for particular charge configuration
so let's not go to
some graphical representations
a situation which is actually
plus three
minus one
by two
improve on the light situation
and let's see how these electric vectors
how they
show up
the vicinity of these two charges
so here you see the plus three in the minus one
relative units
let's take a look at this
in some detail
first of all the length of the arrows again indicates
the strength to give you a feeling for the strength not very qualitative of course
so let's first look at the plus three which
it's very powerful
you see these arrows all go away from the plus three and when you closer
to the last three years stronger which is the representation of the inverse square field
if you're very close to the minus one
pointing into the minus one because one of our square
minus one wins
and so you see there clearly
going into the direction of the minus one
if you're in between the plus and minus on this line
always the field will be pointing from the plaster the minus
because the pluses pushing out the miners sucking in the two
support each other
now if you go very far away
this charge configuration anywhere but very far away much farther than the distance between the
two charges
so somewhere here was somewhere there were somewhere there
four years notice that always the arrows pointing away
the reason is the plus three and minus one is as good as a plus
if you very far far away
but of course when you very close then
then the field configuration can be very very complicated but you see very clearly that
these arrows
all pointing outwards none of them
come back to the minors one of them point to the mines one direction
and that's because the plus three
it is more powerful and then there is here this point
and only one point one by the electric field
it is zero
if you put a positive test charge here
the miners were attracted
plus will repel it
and therefore there comes a point
whether to cancel each other
now there's another way
electric field representation which is more organised
and we call these field lines
so you see uganda plus
and you see there
the minus
if i release right here
well i place here
a positive test charge
all i know is
that the force
will be tangential
to the field lines
that is the meaning of these lines
so if i'm here
the force will be in this direction
if i put the positive just charge you
the before will be in this direction and of course
it's the negative charge
forceful itself
so the meaning of the field lines are
it's always tells you in which direction a charge
a force force
the positive charge always in the direction of the arrows
eventually to the field lines on the negative charge in the opposite direction
how many field lines either in space well of course an infinite number
just like these little arrows that we had before
we only sprinkled in a few
but of course in every single point
there is
an electric field
and so you can put in an infinite number of field lines and that would
make this
OK i guess we may as well start thinking everyone
actually going off to catch their flight and things to go to the beach was
so try not to be too too long
right so
this is
second lecture
on the object
all kinds of things to do vision basically with machine learning
things said yesterday will kind of
generic feature types of things
and important to know that but today there will be a lot more machine learning
things but i really just pulled out a number of different
methods the people replied and giving a serious examples so i'm not going to go
into series called bibsonomy on anything here
i think it's more appropriate because we're kind of the end
long two weeks of work and have probably know what's society three a theory and
also visions applied field you have to get things working so this is the listeners
really and what kinds of theoretical techniques actually work in practice
OK so
yesterday we saw something about the visual signal
low level feature extraction today we'll see some things but object detection
human pose and motion analysis
and image classification and indexing and a little bit about
more general image understanding that i haven't got much about the order is a little
bit problematic in the object station simple
this stuff gets
a little bit more complex than something be used in this get simpler again
but there is no good order this these are two different sort of complementary things
and this more sensible to put the detection of the human pose and the classification
of understanding so that's what i've done that
OK so object detection
just to kind of reminder
we're going to want to detect objects in images
they could occur at any scale at any position in the image
so typically what we're going to have to do
is we're going to have to run some kind of it take to across the
multiple positions and scales
in figure out what's in the window that we see
and when we figure out what what's in the window we can calculate a set
of features
we're going to typically run some kind of classifier machine learning discriminate talk mister
probabilistic estimate probability something like that on the window and when will then be clear
detections particular places
in order to train the model going to need a set of training data
typically which has the positions of the objects max and so that we know we're
looking at the window contains energy which is well centered and things like this
which gets very tedious
so is also interest in the community and learning things automatically
for images without really having to go and knock them
of touch on the line going to any detail
it turns out the posters
important the negatives are also very important position in this limited two giving good negative
but i can't really talk about that because it's it's kind of
have i
so misinformation there's not really anything concrete but i think
in order to get machine learning methods working
and in particular in situations like we're vision where you're detections are only a very
small fraction of the classification c a almost all windows don't contain you should be
looking for
because of that the negative team to overwhelming positive sets triples very important to you
could make
so we typically will bootstrap an extensive but having failed things false positives victories citizen
object is not knowledge
just to bring this home again so the
typical detection is going to be scanning image at all scales and locations looking in
a window
running some classifier and then typically what's going to happen at the end of this
is that we get multiple detections around the local region
because the the classifier is really designed for different problem is it's designed to get
just a isolated examples coming in and to classify them as here we have a
whole series of examples that some of positions and scales
and typically take two five someone's going to fire and the others but we don't
have multiple objects it's just the state has a little bit of
spatial freedom and so we have to
to fuse there's multiple detections and reliable way so as not to lose good ones
water and bad ones
which is also something of an art
so just onto list of different kinds of object detectors that people have thought up
we start with a very simple one so this is an exemplar based method that
means it's based on basically just comparison two examples
in this particular take to be examples are going to be represented
this two-dimensional silhouette so each
from from
of the trying
and the points inside the triangle
are the points where a has some probability p has some ability in c has
some probability so that might be that point
OK every point of the triangle is some points in the distribution space over distributions
of three items
the dirichlet
the place is a distribution over that space
and the dirichlet one one one is very special if all alpha is equal to
one then they actually one one one is the uniform distribution on the space every
there is nuance here which is that
these actual edges the point on the line are not possible you can have something
have zero probability hundred years later has
that has zero probability
but you can get arbitrarily close so one one one on the interior of this
triangle puts you put the same probability anywhere
it's called the uniform distribution
all right
in general
so we're in this triangle
base where a b and c have equal probability
OK thank you so
one one
so remember
the dirichlet is parameterized by alpha and alpha is the vector of length k
of positive values they can be anything so in the first three years out has
three components
in one one refers first to alpha one equal opportunity equal to three
and so those are the parameters of this distribution and what i'm saying is that
when you set those parameters exactly to one
like that that leads to a distribution where any point on the simplex has the
same probability
but where is the point where alpha a b and c of probability one-third is
that point
it's in the middle right right here
so if you if you have a lay where alpha one alpha two alpha three
also by
what that does is put a bomb in the middle
and read the contours around the public
in general
some properties of the dirichlet later work knowing the expectation of data
given alpha
so think data that the expectation of the i th component so
the have random we have a distribution over the space we can contemplate the expectation
of any of these components of the multivariate distribution expectation of data i given alpha
equals out over the summer
OK so with five five five the expectation of each of the components is going
to be a third because five or fifteen is the third
and that's always true expectation and that i give alpha is this and so if
you have a and not in a symmetric dirichlet distribution if you have like alpha
one and alpha two also say so here we have
are simplex and here is the distribution centered somewhere not in in the middle
here's the distribution centre not middle all these are all distribution centered on the
OK so that that determines the location of this home
yes that's the next thing i mean
no yes and no other answers your questions the first question was the greater alpha
less peaky yes the next question was you can add up to less than one
but i mean i'm going to explain this in that the
OK the first just to look for the location of the home location of the
home is is determined by the expectation
OK now let's get to the of the heart
and let's assume for now that alpha is greater than one the alpha less than
one case will deal with stuff
OK go or
and you see that can you all see the board over there that we only
have to work with one set of lights
are so
so this is one important
a piece of the dirichlet parameterisation the other important piece is the sum of the
alpha k so the sum of the alphas determines the peak this of the dirichlet
when the sum of the alphas is
it is
small then the deviously is can be very spread out and the greater the sum
of the alpha is the more peaky hideously becomes at this point
at its expectation
and sometimes you see this called
sometimes called as
and this is sometimes called and
so this is like the mean and this is the scaling
OK and just to to so an alternative parameterisation of the dirichlet is as a
point on the simplex the mean and a scaling parameter s
which is which is which term topic it is around the mean and
i'm saying this to foreshadow the various lectures on nonparametric bayesian methods that are coming
up next week where you parameterize the infinite dimensional dirichlet in precisely the same way
OK but
just put that way in your brains
somewhere safe
now i need to go to my safe brain space think about what is in
taking us outlets one
and then posterior OK
this i think will be useful
these boards are heavier than at my university i can see why
yes so posterior
very solid stuff
not all mathematics is for these boards
it's kind of invigorating
alpha less than one
what happens
OK equivalently
as last one
that was enough is less than one
is you get a sparsity
OK so on the
three simplex
these are are friendly triangle
so you have an joint easier ways like somewhere in the middle of the simplex
but on the on when alpha is less than one you end up with a
different shape
and i would say that
computer architecture
so that are not shell gives you a feel for
the space of EECS
OK this jonckheere here almost a vignette of what easier for might is all about
this is
this is the world according to aggarwal because it's teaching double two OK so this
is this is six two
the mister vcs is you know something out there
OK so what right now
is through discourse
i want you to think about
which part in this vignette we are in
so right now i'm going to start here
and peculiar
OK and as you get closer and closer things get simpler and simpler and simpler
to build the final abstractions are
steeringwheel that's the abstract interplay game right to fortify very simple interfaces and that's all
you need to know
and everywhere in the world can place
so remember
this stuff is complicated
this stuff is very very simple
OK and the more people that fractions and come to this i think it's simpler
and simpler
a large part of what to cover today
is make the biggest simplifications
the biggest simplification will make it go from access equation very nice some very very
simple algebraic groups
the kind of maxwell's equations myself
and i tell you that there very interesting stuff but complicated
you can imagine
so the equations
so let's take an example OK
so let's say a
let's say i have a battery
six foot to page three if you're of course notes and let's say iconic that
OK and so i
and about batteries apply some voltage v
and i ask you a simple question
what is the current
for the world
OK so you something that i can build using objects you i can pick around
from stores and so on and i can connect them up in this manner the
question what is the current i
before you have done a lot of maxwell's equations can all this misleads
and so on the first step is to write down all of michael's equations and
you can say you know
the graph is a minor detail
go on and on and on
OK and all mass of equation and then now how do i know how to
get from there to here
it's because you can do it
OK you can do it but it's very complicated
OK so instead what you could do
is there an easy way
so i will remind you is that this course is actually very easy to remember
the building fraction of one abstraction make your life easier
but think lives are getting more complicated than you not using intuition enough
can just remember the the i work
it's all about making things simple
so i'm going to give you an analogy
so suppose
OK and i apply force to the object
in analogy get to get some insight into how to do this
so here's an object apply force and ask questions
what is the acceleration of the object when apply a force f
so how would you do it
eight the ninth tenth grader can do this so they would ask me
what's the mass of the object
kaski was the acceleration you don't ask me for the mass of the object
i tell you the mass of the object
and then you say sure a is
if you went by and then
it's as simple as that
OK i i i could have gone into
often the differential equations and so on to figure that out but
you asked me for the mass
and you give me the answer is estimated by
you ignored a bunch of things you ignore the shape of the object
you know its color
you its temperature
OK and you ignored the software harder what
a whole bunch of things
you focused on one thing
OK you focused on its mass
and it turns out there
the process
really was developed from a stable set of simplifications that is called
you remember this
o point classification
OK so up in physics you before q simplified lives by viewing objects as point
objects having mass point and for acting at that point
but it means that the property of the object that is of interest for this
process is called
in physics
o point mass discretisation
use that analogy and i'll show you is similar simple process to do the problem
with the
light bulbs
so take my labelled again
and the focus on the filament of the light bulb
OK all i care about is the current flowing from the label
OK i don't care about
that this is related papers in the literature
it is i looked at the internet and this is what it looks like and
if it doesn't really say anything beyond
just what was found for particular network
in fact it generally it's and modeling classes networks so we said idea of the
class networks is is formalising idea of an ensemble
so the idea of selling an ensemble class networks is that obviously
you want to identify kind general principles underlying what you might observed in real network
so for example
what sort of networks we talk about here well
new york
dealing with their own meta ecstasy is if you ask the top we had
social networks things like collaboration networks epidemiological network involving people basically
information networks
things like the internet and the web maybe telecoms networks
biological networks twenty those neural networks
things like
protein protein networks that metabolic interaction networks cells genetic regulatory networks and so on should
probably be left out through there
it's exactly what you might call technological networks like air traffic control
power grids and so on
and geographic network such as retail networks which are being studied in this project transport
networks and so
even citation networks and the starting from a geographical point of view
so basically what we mean by ensemble we mean such a statistical ensemble
to be more
the philosophy behind the summit in statistical mechanics way
what you don't know understand if you like your model is essentially random
you can view an ensemble of networks as a probability distribution on the set of
all possible networks perhaps of a given size whatever
and then what you what you do is sample networks randomly from the statistical ensemble
in other words from the distribution of all possible networks
not not quite nice way to look at is that the adjacency matrix a matrix
now becomes essentially
the elements the adjacency
i matrix now become random variables which are jointly distributed
so it's it's actually quite equivalent to say
well i've got random matrix that that could and say got a probability distribution on
the set of networks
so if the write to the cap
i j
big a little changes so we talk about random variables now
so i'm going to go through the
it's like a study of the of the simplest random
the networks the simplest ensemble of networks if you like
which are also known as sports on random graphs in particular what's become known as
the as then the model which is
it's the simplest and most most study most well understood
model of random networks for random graphs basically way it works is
pick and some number n nodes
and then you take the probability
some probability p
and those the two parameters we also model and then what you do is basically
assigned each to any two edges its origin each
two tina and ten potential edge if you like
flip biased coins probability p and sticking an edge or not and this
he is one
we prepared earlier
don't need anything to this
distribution of notes that this tournament circle but they just like to completely random
the first thing to say about this is that
expected number of edges if you take one what kind of mean number of
of connections of links i'm going see also noted
and that turns out to be
to point to the
and times that he so one consequence of that is
as increase in fact health p fixed increased at the graph actually
it gets bigger more nodes but also extends that means that in particular now it
gets more and more connections which is
well you might not necessary wanted one that
the point is that the if you look at the adjacency matrix for that the
the entries are only
random variables and system fancy name for a biased coin toss space
and the independent which is
a distinguishing feature of of
these parts on random graphs
now as i mentioned
these networks actually gets density just cranked up the number of nodes so what you
tend to look at is is
something is large networks one question is why
might we be looking at
interesting looking at large networks as people generally do in the networks literature well
society of songs might be that
actually makes maths more tractable
which is certainly the case
these gradients
timestamp so you
the gradient there
and then you just multiply by w transpose w
there are some very funny theoretical justification so why you would like to do is
they say that you know we are not optimisation optimizing in space of matrices which
was quite
over the same rules as the ordinary vector space so that's why
these multiplication of the gradient by this kind of the fact that gives you like
better direction of steepest descent
and there are also some complicated statistical justifications for this kind of stuff but
it doesn't really district you are searching anyway just modifies the direction in which you go
the gradient algorithms and it is proposed that this
this direction is actually like better
i mean it's kind of you know like conjugate gradient all those methods you always
try to make for find directions which are better than just the direction of the
gradient so the idea is the same system was much simpler than what the band
but so for some people say that this gives you a better direction and the
bonuses that the same time you get rid of this matrix inversion here because you
spend is you can see that in there and what you end up with this
kind of very simple reason
so actually nobody uses the original gradient descent everybody who uses
gradient algorithms uses this
what this version which is called either natural or the adaptive gradient
but then now then
some advertisement for my algorithm
and then what i developed is fixed point algorithm that is trying to be a
kind of
approximate newton
the point is that course in the need in algorithm one of the main problem
is that you need to estimate the hessian and then inverted at every step which
is quite quite cumbersome but the the point is that because we know
something about the specific form of of the objective function that we have here
it turns out that we can actually find a very nice approximation of the needs
of of the hessian matrix is diagonal and can be
trivial inverted
what is so
if we assume that the data follows the ICA model
we can actually find another reason
that has the good properties of of the newton algorithm that means it has quadratic
convergence actually in some cases you have a cubic convergence
well it is also the nice thing that you don't need to figure out what
will step by step size parameter it automatically
so after some twenty algebraic manipulations what you see is that for estimating one independent
component you actually get this kind of a rather simple algorithm
which really doesn't look like anything because it's it's really
one of the setting sun completely completely disappear when you when you make some assumptions
and right
and you can do the same thing for the likelihood in which case you get
what you see that
what you get is is something very similar
so the case of the likelihood we just well this is in the case of
plasticity is not an adaptive stochastic algorithm we have expectation and then we have
instead of the identity we have here some diagonal matrix that is to be estimate
that is to be computed from the data and here we have another diagonal matrix
which kind of gives you
the optimal step size and this may explain
OK so this this whole
simplification is possible only if we assume that the data exactly follows the ICA model
and we have infinite data so it is certainly in reality what happens in practice
we don't have exactly what convergence but it seems to work quite well in
so yes some examples so
here we start
we estimate we have this whitened uniform data as previously and then we start with
the vector which points in this direction also you can see from what actually happens
we start from the back that's in this direction
actually pretty close to one of infinite independent components then
now sorry we we start somewhere else that the starting by starting point is not
shown here
but then which is a bit stupid but then the after the first iteration we
get here and the second iteration we get here
so in the second iteration is practically oriented in the direction of one of the
independent components which are lined with these so edges
and also what you see here is again this this
one of this indeterminate is in ICA it doesn't really matter whether we were the
vector points in this direction of i the very opposite direction it is just the
same independent component because the size of the different components are not defined
of this one thousand back again
and then some words about relations to other matters
so i ordered mention this technique of projection pursuit that has been proposed by
statisticians for completely different purposes that i see
it is expected data analysis where people those people claim that when you find among
the most nongaussian directions those argued so visualizing your data and so you know
getting some insight into what happens in and especially people claim that when you find
the most nongaussian directions projections of your data those will tell you something about the
clustering structure
of the data so here is an illustration of why that might happen
we have basically so god sent clouds
which are clearly separated
but now
if you if you take the principal components of the study that they will be
and while the projection on the vertical axis will not tell you that you have
two different cluster
but if you look at the most nongaussian
projections while the most nongaussian projection will be
the horizontal line so that we will tell you
that there are exactly two clusters so the point is that if you have for
example if you have a bimodal distributions which take to show you the clustering
the those projections will be