i mean function
and then the covariance function
let's get started
a gaussian process
defines a distribution is a probability distribution
over functions
where the function f
max map some input domain
on two
the real line
this is actually a stochastic process
and is defined by
i mean function
so this is a function u
which operates on
let's just call these are set of attributes of this point
and the tons and expectation
all of
the value of a function
at that point
so it has a mean function
not i mean value i mean function
and of course because it's gaussian process
it also has a covariance function
and the covariance function we've looked at
covariance operators already and is basically defined by
the expectation
the function value
two points
x i and x j i
so how does the the functional response
call vt
either different points
in space or whatever speech i happen to be working with or or in time
the probability
of the function
is a gaussian process
if for any finite subset
of x
the marginal distribution
right so this says running juice
right so the probability of the function values
computed that
each one of these endpoints for this
this joint distribution
is a multivariate gaussian
so we have a multivariate gaussian
which defines the probability distribution
of the function values
at the end
points we are considering
so if we have n samples of
whenever r
x happens to to define points in some data space
objects from some
the phase space whatever
the n dimensional vector if
which corresponds to the functional responses
each point x one up to examine
random functions
it will be distributed as a gaussian process
where the mean function
has been evaluated
at each of these points x one up to xn
and the covariance function
has been computed at each p
of x x i and x j i
and as i said
this gaussian process
for a finite
the set of points is then just the multivariate gaussian
to do that if
with a trained function
new and covariance e
if we assume that the mean is zero then
the expect the set the matrix of second moments defines the covariance
i should also point out if you remember from yesterday slides of course the covariance
is the expectation of
the cross terms
the product of the expectation of each of the individual terms
but at the end of the day
it's it's defined just by this if the mean function is zero
well that's good summons awake
so what it means is that this prior to members of functional prior this is
not a prior all and any parameters which
somehow or or other define
function this is a prior directly on
the class of functions that we're going to half
so this
gaussian process
really chords any assumptions of knowledge that we have
and those cases are the dramatic exception
and they do tell you something to tell you that is not enough to have
a brain from language somebody does have to use it with you
it doesn't have to be that many people
so this is golden meadow
has study deaf children
that nobody sign two
but what she studies is deaf children of deaf siblings
and these children don't just sit there they create their own language
it's not a full-blown language like american sign language along this cuba choir
but it's own language nonetheless with words and syntax and phonology
it's an interesting question
on the other
it's a good question the question is are their inherent limits on our abilities to
come up with grammars
and most linguists would argue yes
that languages are
highly constrained in how they do things
so for instance one example is
there's no language in the world that ever
constructs are question by switching the order of words around
in the sentence
there's no language in the world that has a rule that says
the fifth word has to be over
and linguists have all these conditions they no language and were works this way
this is
so these are constraints on grammar and really interesting to they tell us what the
human as humanly natural language queries what's not humanly natural language but notice
even if is incredible constraints and grammars still
we can still produce an infinite number of sentences
it's just like if you restrict me to only a subset of numbers
only the odd numbers
still there is an infinity of odd numbers
so grammar can be restricted
but still give rise to an infinity of possible sentences
well there's a radical claims
about the origin of language associated with the guy who we met when we talked
about behaviorism who who wrote the review verbal behavior the linguist noam chomsky
and chomsky makes his radical claims
and this is that we should view language learning
as learning at all
instead we should view it as something similar to growth
so he says no one would take seriously to propose of the human organism words
through experience of arms rather than wings
or to the basic structure particular organs results maximal experienced language proved to be no
less marvelous intricate and these physical structures why should we not acquisition of cognitive structure
like language more or less
as we study some complex partly or
so you might work
to play baseball
you might learn about the american civil war
but if chomsky is right
you didn't learn to speak english
rather what happened as you heard english
but the capacity grew in your head
it's something a lot more similar to the development of arms or legs are visual
well should we believe this
we know there has to be some
effective the environment shaping language obviously because in order to knowing what you have to
have heard much
in order to know that you have had to her to add to have learned
and heard that
in fact languages differ in all the ways that we were talking about
in some languages like english has had the distinction between l and are other languages
do not
for language like english that creature there is referred to as the morphine dog
historical accent of english
in french it share
and in in in
greek it's
something else
and each of six thousand languages
and people in the room no other language like in vietnamese is this interview with
in check is that
finally to syntax
so in english
is what's known as the subject verb object language
that means if you want to convey the idea that bill hit john
you would say
bill hit john
but not all languages work that way
in fact the majority languages more languages
are actually subject object verb languages
so you would say if you wanted to convey the bill was to header and
john with him
bill john hit
all of this has to be learned
and all of this has to be learned through exposure to language users
on the other hand
there is considerable evidence that the development of these language skills
in some way
it is similar to growth
in the way that chance he suggests
there are some basic facts about language development
one is something which i mentioned before
all normal children learn language
there can be specific impairments of language
now again we spoke about them before when talking about the brain some of these
impairments could be due to trauma
on the phase fascias trauma a blow to the head a stroke
can reduce your language
but also there are genetic disorders
some falling under the rubric of what's known as specific language impairment which already
are born
without the same ability as the rest of us to learn to speak
and these are interesting in many ways
one reason that the interesting is that it illustrates something about human language
it is not it would not be unreasonable for you to think
before listening to this lecture
all you need to know they have to learn the language
it is to be smart
or all you need to have to learn the language is to want to communicate
or you need to have to learn a language is to be a social person
wanting to
having the ability to understand others into your father's
but the case specific language impairments suggest that all of that is wrong
because your children in this world right now
who are plenty smart
who really want to communicate
and you are entirely social creatures
but they can't learn language
and this suggests that the ability to learn language and understand language is to some
extent separate
from these other aspects of mental life
continuing on this thing we also know that language is learned with any sort of
feedback or training
there are many americans who believe that they need to teach their children language is
a huge industry with DVD's and flash cards and all sorts of things are designed
to teach children language and i think many parents believe that they didn't persist in
using these things are children would never learn to speak
but we know that that's not true
we know that isn't true because our communities
they and they don't speak their kids
they don't speak their kids because they don't believe is important as because get
some linguists would interview thing was would interview adults in these communities and say why
to minimize the dispersion of the states
in other words they have a home eustace is
general homeostasis beyond physiology home eustace combined any attribute any measurable function that can be applied system
so that's that's where i know most of not using all those would be
in order to sort of developed the idea slightly more formally and link it to the sorts
constructs that we heard about this morning i'm just gonna
introduce this the variables that are going to be talking about andwill imagine that we can divide
the world interest of any outside the world and stuff that is internal to the system in question
so we have here some immensely complicated stochastic differential equation
governing the dynamics of
hidden from the point of view the system states in the real world
these things
maps through some sort of observational sampling function used inputs so sensory samples for the system around found these determine
through some yet to be determined function or deterministic mapping
these internal states of the system
and then we have the system coupling back to the external world through active state
action variables here so this could be for example
at the you know the bated breath web leaves on the tree all the way
that i move my muscles in terms of sending command signals down to
at down the spinal cord to
to my body my most plant
these internal states can play a very special role going to play the role
all of these parameters of all the sufficient statistics some arbitrary probability distribution
and if it is going to turn out to be an approximation
so the posterior distribution
the causes of sensory input
given the sensory inputs
hand cut a long story short what we are going to supposes that
all the principle i try motivate
is that
but can change that is part of this biological system
will do so
to minimize this free energy construct here
and those the things that can change and improve internal states of the system
and the way that it acts to affect the way
evolutionary dynamics of external states producing sensory data
attraction can change the inputs
found action and internal states minimise free energy that is a functional of this what
he has access to which is simply the sensory information
samples those internal state so those so
variables and the constraints under which i'm gonna
try and develop medium
the argument
so this slide just summarizes
the free energy
hands ends up with its fundamental motivation
i started the talk a little bit like a sort of definition elements
in this context free energy has a is basically constructed
a lower bound on the negative log probability of these sensory outcomes
any particular model system in question
and creating the bound on this bound is created by simply adding to it
they cross entropy of scale divergence
but is going to be non-negative so that this thing is always going to be bigger
and this thing and this divergence is they kill divergence between
this approximate distribution
well specified by sufficient statistics of internal states
the posterior distribution over the causes of sensory information
i'm gonna come back but in the second round some useful points of contact with talks
today and talks late late today but i just want to
for the moment just state why
how to motivate why
this quantity should be minimized so if i can minimize this quantity i'm going to
do two things first of all if i minimizing with respect my internal states
i'm going to suppress the difference between the approximate arbitrary distributions
hand this post distribution until they are equal
in other words i'm gonna make the q
the distribution q over hidden states
equal to the poster distribution so i i'm implicitly creating a bayesian engine inference machine
at the same time i can use action to change
the sensory inputs
now if i minimize this be
this term with respect to action forward as a function in in terms of changing the sensory input
that each point in time going to be minimizing this quantity here which i call
surprise surprise or loss of information
which is by assume that the system is gonna make
then the long-term average of this free energy
upper bounds the long-term average of self information
which means that i'm minimizing
the entropy
so i've got to where i wanted to be
if you remember i'm trying to understand how
things move or act
how systems act upon the environment
in order to minimize the dispersion
all of their sensory states so the states that correspond to the exchange with the environment at
so i want to minimize age but i can't measure range directly
it's the entropy hear directly what i can do
is minimize an upper bound on the quantities whose time average long-term time average
to the entropy that i want to minimize so that's the overall motivation
all and it's sort of subsumes
action to minimize this term
hand change internal states do in principle in the world
so i'm going
in terms of action and perception speaking to the title the sessions the duality between action perception
you can be sure that all the max maximizing the
yeah absolutely very good point again last
there are three points and possibly many more that we could develop the lots and
nice perspectives on this so this is also the likelihood
so it's the marginal likelihood of my sensor observations
margin i marginalizing over integrating out
the hidden causes all the all things that produce them
so this is the marginal likelihood so maximizing free energy would also correspond on minimizing
the entropy of the dispersion states
implicitly or can be guaranteed under gothic assumptions by maximizing the likelihood of the marginal likelihood of the data
this is also known as in bayesian statistics is the evidence
so it's also evidence maximisation
so it's a form as a bayesian model optimization as well
the system and could be thought of as a model so maximizing the band on this quantity
it's just maximizing evidence for my model of the world in the model that entailed
by me as a biological system
but you would see that we need really precise measurement precise calculations
and now
it's a little bit i think too early to truly had the test of these
so much more precisely what can we extract
so you know that start out with an is what that implies unitary combination of
that people could be actually must go on the streets of these things
as we are dealing with nuclear physics on the UNDP works are a old so
that's why we can extract
information on these there
through these mass measurements
and the old terms
are given by
but in physics
fundamental symmetry
so what test is that we are looking at the speed of moment of the
particles involved with j
we want to see if this data
including exotic interaction like terms or whatever
so but i recall that reminder that that need you need for that very precise
experiments very precise calculations
was different corrections of different terms
similar summarise what i've presented today
i talk about these exotic nuclei
where the drip lines not experimentally reached and that more than five thousand nuclei are
predicted and that the served to now
there is a question of new shared structure right now we are interested in and
was twenty eight the then we are going
so far away
concerning exotic structure i don't know i i to chip away the stone
are currently interested in old age
also isomers search for super heavy elements there is the fundamental symmetries
thank you very much
so you don't really the problem is we don't have any information i think i
fixed capital
for the reaction diffusion
yes so
for instance even measuring the spin of gazebo zone
the way you can do that is looking at angular distribution so the angular distribution
of the decay products depending on
however was produced tells you something about the spin but it's rather
correlation is not
very narrow i mean it's not very clear
and the problem with the is that you generally on a very very large background
so you still have a huge background on top of that we trying to measure
some rather weak anchoring
so that's the on some thoughts of doing that
for instance actually makes to gamma gamma case if the photon converts into an e
plus minus sparse then you have actually additional information on the orientation of the photon
pairs so there are some thoughts hasn't really
been demonstrated how you can do that
at hadron colliders it's very hard
generally this is that the linear collider plus minus collider
you have an extra constraints can do it actually better
you know if you want to do
five or something like this
there should be some
there is
one side by the
first of all i
one side of
rather programme which program
it's not really wants more
four years
four or even more
same percent of
one of
and as a result of this pioneer
made hundreds of millions
ah maybe billions in
which i received course
brawling over mammography
this is science two thousand ten
um a little bit of history back i mention this conference
is in
nineteen ninety seven we were presented with all the available data
on the benefits and harms of
screening mammography for women in their forties
and this was are conclusion
the data currently available do not warrant a universal recommendation for mammography for all women
in their forties each woman should decide for herself whether to undergo mammography
what happened after that's
all i did it i did
analysis and meta-analysis a bayesian method that's why mentioning
other trials that were presented in nineteen ninety seven
and this is a figure from these journal article from the journal national cancer institute
what they do is they randomized women between getting control that is
no memory mammography versus screening that is
mammography there's some contamination
in both directions
the control mortality rate
is in the x axis here it's be rate
hundred thousand women years
and this is the screening mortality rate so if you are above the line
you did better on
control and if you below the they forty five degree line
you did better on screen
plotted is the difference percent reduction
you see quite a bit of variability across here but a few
each one of these calculate the percent reduction in breast cancer mortality
for the screening group you see the spread
so what i did was to bayesian meta-analysis and you know it's usual
and got these estimates
so this see which is canada
get shorty here
this disagee which is gothenburg in sweden get shocked here
so they also put in it which was uh sorta my undoing of
i was
this was the actual
plot vi
per thousand women over time
over time since randomization
andy few integrate between those
you get an estimate the mean
per thousand women
converted to women
got a fifteen years
life saved per woman
it was one point four days
and i said well there's some more coming here so let's set in
a simplex extrapolate
and i calculated five days
per woman before getting
mammography over ten year period
i was accused of minimizing
i said wait understand the risk is a really turned the risks
and one of the things i said was that
this was equivalent getting
eschewing mammography in the forties
was equivalent gaining
two answers a body weight
and that really my own doing
i inspired the evidence and the expert panel the us-allied
voted ninety eight to zero dictating that mammography would be effective for women in their forties and i'm not
it's not a typo
if you reedy
it was essentially telling god you know the more if we had to be
the fact
but more importantly they
withheld in sea ice budget
national cancer institute budget until you can see i agreed
to recommend screening for women in their forties
so naturally they wanted to continue to exist
and so they did
on the bayes estimate again
in two thousand ninety these were updated
and where do you suppose they want
i have to confess to reason i keep moving fields not circulate around biology
anthropology and mainly psychology problems is that
eventually after about five years they discover that belong wherever
i get the message and move
so that explains why what i do is is very interdisciplinary in the sense
okay oh i forgot change my title but it's the same
should be and why why facebook but you and your friends
that's my
my which is going to be really to try and explain to why
i guess the internet in general actually and for but social networking sites in particular
don't necessarily mean
that they will enlarge your social world and they are trying to explain the biological
and psychological reasons why that might be so that it doesn't leave us with the
challenge in the modern world at the end because i think it's terribly important
actually we rise to the challenge and use digital technology to try and enlarge or social world
let me start with a really what was three
promissory note on on the tin can
both when email started but also more recently when social networking sites typically facebook started both them
promise that they were going open up a whole new social vista four you're going
to be connected to the global village you're gonna have thousands of friends and this
is why facebook
the upper limit on the number of friends who could have relatively high at five thousand because they figured that
presumably that people would eventually get up there
but the question is has actually worked and the answer seems to be for both
this is very very clear
in the context a facebook i think
we need data in the graphs are similar
cameron marlow is
analysis is solved
facebook's own data whose what facebook sort of
sociologists say were that those data analysis the
what he's done here is simply to look at
people who have
different numbers and friends registered on their pages
essentially very small medium and very large and then look at
how many people actually have traffic with reciprocated traffic with basically the people they spend
most their time talking to if you like
and it's just measured in three different ways and they don't matter too much
is just fun and get some perspective on this and the pink and the girls
and the blue the boys and you can see the girls have slightly
four friends than
boys to
however images measure them but the real key is the
having lots more friends of your facebook page doesn't actually mean you talk
two proportionately more people this
order magnitude difference in the number of friends this only a factor of about three difference in
the traffic density if you like
and this seems to be
positive picked up again
and these are facebook's own
but if you look at the modal
number of friends
that people have listed on that page is somewhere between one hundred twenty hundred thirteen actually give
on the on the website a hundred and fifty is the mean and the moment
this is despite the fact that some people obviously
have several hundred and maybe most people in this room claimed
several hundred
friends listed if you're on facebook
that the key issue here is in some sense that what is happening is most people
probably all
having on their facebook page is simply the people they actually interact with what have
some relationship with in everyday life
and then there are a few people who create as long tail to the right
which gives this sort of urban myth that her face will in enlarge is your
social world now some of those
okay professional users so that people like songwriters hall
the novelist or whatever right is using facebook as a kind of fan base if you like frank
you know that we think
so the somewhere between
probably a hundred and fifty and
two hundred two hundred fifty that's what
space there
a probably blokes
who we think about the early in the competition because they discovered that if you
have lots of friends are very attractive to the girls
i think this is the way usually very attractive it's a mate advertising like a peacock
it's the girls that typically have
smaller numbers in this context by and large in their total
number friends list that's about suggest because they're focusing explicitly on their real life social workers okay
so here's just some more data vase
try to look at this
explicitly so is simply looking at
layers network size your best friends if you like
clique size and also the emotional closeness teachers
these individuals in that little subset of your social world
measured very simply on the southern not attend scale
a zero
you fairly neutral about them
ten one hundred on the scaling here
you love them dearly
and this is simply split into those who are active social media users mainly facebook users
and those who are passive browsers as you might think that and really there appears
to be no for saying no statistical effect you active people know either have small
nor do they
i have great emotional closeness to those friends they have
one of the reasons perhaps
may come out and this is another four
recent studies where we've asked people to rate on a kind of satisfaction scale
as it were every interaction they've had
with their five closest friends on the day by day basis at the end of the day
they look at all interactions i've had with those five friends and their rate them before
the kind happiness or satisfaction is a standard happiness scale from psychology although i think a very bad
name for it
and the there
we're looking at
again we're not really gaining much in terms of structure just improving the this sort
which this guy
which is a little bit too wide very wide here two y here
it's getting smaller and if you go to three hundred sixty dimensions
that's actually all the structure is the matrix rank is only three hundred sixty so
this is all the structure in the data to basically just refining the which the
sort of shape of this valley
to make it sort of narrow and our region there you increase the dimension so
getting a lot of the structure of the data with only two dimensions or ten
dimensions of the data so it's are very good approach to dimensional reduction
if you believe in distance matrix presentation
so how do we find these directions where we find directions in data with maximal
wait a second
that's what principal component analysis does
so there's already an algorithm for doing this for principal component analysis says look for
directions of maximum variance in the data
so PCA
rotates the data to extract these directions
and it works on the sample covariance matrix here
so let's just a bit of a review of principal component analysis
so PCA says find a direction in the data are
so i think it was one vector from rotation matrix so you can rotate your
whole data
and are is like taking one of those rotations so two projecting and one dimension
but it's from that larger rotation matrix
so is the first
principal component is well actually will be turned out to be
so we project onto that axis we got y had times are so this is
the nice compactness this notation is the center data matrix and this is one
vector rotation being applied to it gives this one dimensional
what we want to do is maximized variance so we look to find the one
which maximizes that subject to the fact that it's
normal and
you always maximize that by scaling are forever and ever we want to be part
of rotation matrix
so we scale the normal to the unit norm
we write down the variance of x we can really express it
as the product of these two guys because they centered so x will be sent
as well one n times the product of y
how why had one transpose what one
turning that around so that we just flip that guy because of the transpose
we can bring the one outside source one transpose
one whatever and why had transpose y hat
times are one now we recognise that the sample covariance
from my definition of annotation earlier
so it's basically saying the variance
in the x one direction can be written by aaron transpose SR one
the well and PCA results
so that's what we want to maximize that this guy basically
to ask questions if you're coughing reminded me of question if you've got any questions
to ask i can still hear well i'm coughing so that's a good time to
ask questions
how do we look for this one well is the solution to the constrained optimisation
what we do is we use grounds multiplied to apply this constraints so the ground
multiplier lambda one one minus one transpose one
taking the gradient with respect to r one
leads to
we do back to gradient for two as one minus two lambda one r
now if we rearrange that we find that the sample
covariance times of one is equal to lambda one r one which is recognised as
an eigen value problem
so this is basically the first guy is the solution to an eigenvalue problem
but which i can value is it so
and i can value problem there's lots of laws that solve this
they're all the i can vectors have
matrix s
which are is that we need
well we can find that out by
i premultiplying
looking at the gradient we premultiply the gradient by aaron transpose we get two r
one transfer as one minus two lambda one
art one transpose aaron but aaron transpose aaron one we're constrained to be one
so it's
aaron transpose of one minus
two lambda one
that is the greatest must be zero the solution
which is also of course how we were finding this looking for fixed points and
the gradient equal to zero
we can reorganize to find land one must necessarily equal rights
what do we say that was
well we've already said that the variance of x one
so lambda one
is equal to that land one is also
the eigen values
so here we can solve full and the one and aaron simultaneously
and what is the eigen value and that i can value is the variance of
the data in the experts
so which i can value do we need to extract to get the largest variance
the largest i that
so maximum variance is therefore necessarily the maximum igon value of s and that's called
the first principal component
what's next well the next thing to do is to find other principal components and
those are basically orthogonal directions to the earlier extracted directions with maximal variance so there's
right there is no overlap all what's different about these countries
in these countries the goal is not to donate your organs but you have to
sign explicit make
but this is too
for these people is to donate and you have to make explicit decision to sign
papers you don't want to
so deep boltzmann
now we usually think about defaults as for be people by is that people make
because it because people make stupid
uninformed decisions but the default buys can actually be used to help people
as well
and so i changing
so stranger but
changing we can change people's
in two d pose that we think are good people and people kind of mindlessly
follow those defaults that are are that are good for them
and this really is maybe the best example of light paternalism and fits the definition
of both libertarian and asymmetric paternalism
first there is no avoiding a policy on defaults so for example default on how
much salary should be allocated to form one k
it's almost unavoidable to have some kind of default even if the default is that
you have to make choices
defaults on salary salary put aside for savings
asymmetric into respect
that's first desirable defaults can improve the welfare of people who mindlessly adhere to the
default without restricting the options of those who don't
and carefully and this second sense in which these asymmetrically paternalistic interventions are asymmetric and
that's the following
suppose you have somebody like gary becker
who is the true believer in rationality
and then you have something like dick dale ergenekon doesn't believe that people are rational
well the people who believe that in rationality
this should be perfectly happy to change the defaults because after all defaults to
the people who think that matter the behavioral economists to be very excited about changing
the default to develop this good for people so
not only
is not only are
these light paternalistic policies asymmetric in the sense of helping people
are irrational and not really people are rational but they also be
palatable to a wide range of people with a wide range of academic perspectives
in fact there is pretty good evidence
that defaults matter is one of many papers by this one is by and share
a it's called the power of suggestion inertia or one participation savings behavior
four by the way for one k planned
a tax-free savings account you know in the united states we've got rid of pensions
pretty much
and everyone is required to now we have to save money for retirement we still
have social security
but we have very company pensions anymore
and so for one plans are tax-free plans usually there's a company match the company
if you've got a certain amount of money the company will measure
so in this study they looked at changes introduced into the benefit package of large
and the two cohorts were particularly interesting
the new cohort is our employees who would be folded into automatic enrollment there are
automatically enrolled in the four one k savings plan
and automatically three percent of their salary is allocated to the fore when planned
and a hundred percent that is allocated to the money market
the window cohort these people
came just before the call the
and the new and they are eligible for the world war one k they can
immediately puts as much money as they want to but there is no automatic enrolment
so it's very good compare comparison is not true
randomized experiment it's about as close you can get
and here is the bottom line
it is a general rate of people who are people
and what you see is looks like eighty six percent
and when people who have tested to join immediately they wanted to
only fourteen percent of them
are enrolled in the four one
plans in the first year
if you look at contributions right so is so low
and not that powerpoint but
he's the dark one to the
these are the
so i would like to is the new people
and you see
there's a huge
three percent
aside three percent of money
for the people
so for that
and if you
people the people of the window or
who could join one but were required is sixty three percent of them contributed nothing
on the other hand
i'm going to talk about the rest of the graph a little bit later
so i think that once you start thinking in these terms in terms of light
it has a lot of ramifications
the first is
we need a new welfare criterion all explain why that is it encourages a focus
at beginning and you only have a few moves left OK that's kind of planning
horizon case you only care about some numbers that in the future
the event horizon cases more like the male robot
goes around delivering mail day-to-day tomorrow
ten years from now
OK lily this robot should act the same today as it does tomorrow because it's
easier for the future
in front of k thirty two to two types arise in that we can see
so if you want to reward over time we we didn't talk about
average due to return i i could say our goal
all the future wars
people tend not to use this because
the average for the case give
during a hundred dollars today one dollars ten years from now
OK well the average of those choices is is is is is a hundred
for whatever action you take
today are ten years and you'll get dollars OK clearly do and it doesn't one
to maximize average reward you want to maximize discover work she wants more more now
OK and and the same to the same word in his worthless so what see
more practice is discouraging with return is this again discovered gamma
so he reward you get two tons of the future this kind of i gamma
now there is justification for gamma
which is
if i assume that robot and his robot can break down
with probability point three get the reward after that every time step night choose gamma
equal point seven
this clearly defined over finite time steps i survived point seven to the
provide time timesteps so so there's a very natural if you process can tell me
with some probability at every step is a very natural interpretation to to discover factor
and i think that's probably why
i would have more examples of what i wanted this to torture anybody myself OK
i do one hundred dollars today
rather than one hundred hours ten years is really i don't know what we run
in ten years
so i will be but i don't know for sure that everyone in in ten
years to collect by a hundred dollars k
hopefully that's enough to be around
you see the discount factor is asserting team can the probability of some termination
get it have t
OK so if i time steps if i survive the poisson probability that are five
times subtypes arrive with point seven to
OK so for model
again if you want any questions at this point
throughout the talk
it's crucial that you ask
recovery action states observations OK these but also sets describe the problem that we have
now season access next states with more community assumption
observation function ninety six observations
reward function
telling us and we will were for
opposition criteria we words every time step how do we trade off toward the isn't
time steps formalise the problem you've got to know this because given different out of
given different opposition criteria different gamma you will act differently
this is crucial note optimizing
and finally there's still one more aspect which is whether you know or don't know
some of these things
is vital all the examples in the world i know them i can just compete
with the model
so OK so the model in case OK now this is called planning in my
case because there is uncertainty
everything and uncertainty so you see retirement will cover planning
the more classical sense a more classical deterministic sense doing summer school
OK the approach taken his conservative the person taking my in my case you know
you you have to maximize expected utility in this case you just a single particle
because you know how the virus behaves
OK so this is called an uncertainty
because stochastic things can happen
you know they have sufficient condition or you know
if someone tells them
so think of
OK will ask questions like
OK planning usually by by some planning are usually means
goal oriented you also use the term decision theoretic planning like male robot maximizing expected
future just carry words as more a called the decision theory cunning as this just
simple goal oriented planning
i get a lot of free case is probably a bit more interesting for the
OK so a least one of the observation transition and reward functions is unknown
i think it
there are no but i seem like an accident by connecting can sample these functions
you blindly come world and i make my daughter the way a hundred times and
maybe still fail sometimes the wall
business and like work with a good actions were that actions OK without knowing exactly
how my actions affect
OK if you are like this is called reinforcement learning
you have to interact the right to obtain samples
if you think these are two very problems but you'll find the solutions for the
model three case are just sampled versions of the model in case
if i get this idea across today
it's it's what it's like to do it a bit trouble if i can get
this i across a w prickly these are really the same problem just
with the data
the second hastings sampling version of the first case
and this OK so you have to solve the answer
right so that's what we did one electron has to go here one electron has
to go here you can put two electrons in one of these states and we
know the one empty that's not the lowest energy configuration and
to put those electrons in
with parallel spins
not opposite spins that's not the lowest energy configuration
right so that the electron configuration here for more until
one sigma one is two
sigma one r stark two sigma two s two sigma two s started to
and now
i two px one
part i
two px one
let's calculate the bond order here the bond order is two four
five six bonding electrons two
eighty four antibonding electrons six minus for over two was one we got a single
two hundred eighty nine killing tools from all that's pretty good single bond pretty strong
single about
that's more until
let's do current
carbon has got to go to p electrons
so we follow the out about principle
carbon two
all four of those electrons then are going to go into these i two px
two py two py y states
and here's our electron configuration and we keep going here's the pi two px two
py two py y two
OK let's calculate the bond order
bond order number of bonding electrons
four six eight bonding electrons
the number of antibonding electrons to
eight minus four is four divided by two bond order is still and we have
a double bond
let's look and see how strong double bond is five hundred ninety nine killing joules
per mole
the that's pretty good double bond a member of the double bond ashoura the double
bond is stronger
right are single bonds were three hundred four hundred killer tools this is almost six
hundred killed tools
that's the strong band
and this molecular orbital picture tells you
it you've got this double-blind here
by virtue of this find work
but i'm just about to treat the two PC
alright i'll tell you what our convention is a good question
here comes the two PC
two easy atomic orbitals by convention
two appease atomic orbitals we're going to port
along the into nuclear bond axis
so in the case of the constructive interference of the two peasy
in that case these
two p
wavefunctions look like this
there were no longer coming in and
no parallel to each other now they're coming in and out
so that's our convention
the two peasy
it's going to be a long the bond axis
four EP easy is going to be along the bond axis
right so
we're going to bring these two
atomic wavefunctions and we're going to let this overlap with that part
and the result is the weight function that looks like this
lots of electron density or
the weight function right in between the two nuclei
here's an all right here's note
all these are known to because there were no roads in the atomic wavefunctions to
begin with
we're going to call this wave function
the sigma two pz sigma because it's
around the into nuclear bond axis right so that's the symmetry call that sigma
what happens here
it turns out
but at the same state
is a little higher in energy than the highest states
in the next molecule
it's going to be some exceptions here in the moment
nitrogen has one electron in each one of these states
let's use the owl the principle the film
well there's two year to here two
the electron configuration as
the one says and pi two px two
i two p y two and now saying not too easy to
let's calculate the bond order in molecular nitrogen
well it's the number of bonding electrons two
minus the number of antibonding electrons to four
ten minus four six divided by two bond order three
and hate this means we got triple bond why this better be on a lot
stronger today as you look at the bond energy molecular nitrogen it's all whopping nine
hundred forty one
killer tools from all get triple bond this is strong and this is a short
next ones can be molecular oxygen
so now we taken care of
all the way functions like you the way functions that we can form
from the two p atomic wavefunctions using constructive interference
it's now time to form
some molecular wavefunctions using destructive interference
let's do that
let's go back to two px and two py y
they're the ones that come in parallel to each other
all right so as we bring them and then we're going to go
destructively into we can do with destructive interference the spiral wave function
is going to destructively interfere with this part this part destructively interfere with that
and this
all across the world
i was just
she was
so what
this is
he belong to a
you should be able to
so this is
the who
she is hard
so n
it is hard
and as you
and use
most variance
so have to drive through one more piece of notation before i give you the
algorithm which which as the promises not more complicated than doing PCA
a number of times
and it is robust it is robust variance estimator so what is this
for any so think about having just one principal component you project all the points
good and that you can tell onto this one principal component and you compute what's
known as the trimmed variance
so basically
i look at this i look at the squared distance but only of the points
that are not the points that are farther away
OK so let's say i'm expecting ten percent outliers i would look at the ninety
percent the ninety percent closest points and compute the empirical variance
OK so the idea is that if the outliers are small
their impact is controlled on that they're not going to influence satellite the and if
the allies are very big their impact is controlled because and i can tell there
are going to be counted this
OK so just to show you that again in pictures there's there's basically two settings
that can
that can happen you project onto one dimension if you found the correct direction then
you're going to have a good healthy variance for your authentic points and even though
you can you going compute the robust variance estimate that's going to give you something
big and something it's not influenced too much by those outliers if you chose in
that direction one of the then what your points all concentrated then when you compute
this robust variance estimate again it's not going to be influenced by
my those points
so you win either in either case the trick is that you need to find
something some good direction so again let's focus on that example that i that i
gave so if you if the outlier
if the adversary concentrates on the bad points there and you're for the new choose
the direction this is what the projection is going to look like y
because all these blue points i had huge that had and large very large magnitude
when the projected on to a particular direction and not just look like it's like
but the univariate normal so they're going to be quite small
and the black points are are going to be out there and if you choose
the right direction
then then you're going to get something like this and so the key idea is
that if i were to choose between those two directions robust variance estimator will be
able to distinguish and tell me that one of them is better than the other
so here's here's algorithm and i think it's quite simple
the only computationally challenging part performing PCA but presumably we were prepared to do this
in the first place so you perform PCA on empirical covariance of the original of
the points all the points you may get something that's terrible
but let's let's move on so you get you can get you cannot directions and
then you look at what the robust variance estimate is in the highest in those
higher structures
OK so i guess i get can ten principal components
i compute the my robust variance estimate on those almost components if it's the biggest
one senior i recorded and i write down what those principal components of that's my
vote this is my best guess
then regardless of what this step did i randomly remove a point in proportion to
its variance
along these directions
so let's see what could happen if i find a good direction here
i know because this is big
and then when i randomly remove a point i might remove about a good point
but who cares i've already found in the direction if i find it very bad
direction so that my robust variance estimate is going to tell me ignore this
and also
the only reason i chose this direction must have been because
principal component analysis and support was for and that means that step three will will
very likely remove one of these
one of these
that points
OK so
so basically this this means just you have to just two PCA a number of
times here i repeat until all points removed but you don't actually have to do
that you can be you can repeat until just a small fraction of them are
are removed so you have to pay a price it's an order of magnitude more
expensive than PCA because you have to run PC many times there are several things
that can go wrong you might remove authentic points
we might not ultimately reported that outcome this robust variance estimator is just a proxy
for what we really want and corrupted points may contribute
to what we ultimately report this is not an outlier identification technique
however all of these things are controlled and basically not to put all not to
drive through the
this there this algorithm gets you breakdown point of one half which is the best
it gives you perfect recovery if you have little of interest points and you also
get explicit lower bounds for all the way up to breakdown point of one half
the basic proof ideas is a blessing of dimensionality concentration inequalities in high dimension and
this idea that random removal either something good has happened or you're about to remove
an outlier and therefore early on before moving too many good points you find a
good solution
how much time to have minus one minute
one to look at
so what
then i'll just just tell you what collaborative filtering is so the observation is that
similar to what alan talked about before
robust principal component analysis really looks like separating a mixture of not lowering spas
which is what what he briefly mentioned but lowering boats columns sparse and so if
you read this paper then you say i'm going to solve it using this this
and so
we would expect the solves that this gives the solution the problem is it doesn't
this is not the solution to this is not going to recover the true l
and the true c
and you can see
that function was taken weight put them on the ground
and you can verify any
of vertices
assigned zeros and ones gives you exactly
exactly cost function take the just because one
under sec
it's supposedly q
in fact
it's really close to
in these situations do
well this all the time ahead had
the polar bears from the reviews dynamic graph cuts through becoming going close to
sixty years or thirty seconds so
maybe not quite on pixel image it
well as i say it's to be just run the whole thing together
not really
i mean
after all this is close to linear in the case of this
there's a limit to advantage
people that i don't to eat and often run this on a ten megapixel image
the reason
why shouldn't
this is something about flow on the graph
get once again the
details precisely what
the correlation between flow is
monograph have a graph with vertices vertices
it means assignment
so these two and the important thing is five the i j minus the phi
j i know the words if you think
in terms of electricity if you think of five employees direction
i think that is being minus five times helps direction
then it simply
satisfies kurchatov
which means
at any node
the total flow into the vertex
is zero or total flow in the total flow out
the flow
nick to me
that's what the flow is
that's where the flow is
permissible flow
on the graph
is one in which the flow
is less than the weight on that page
must be less than the weight of the edge
here weighted graph
five the DJ this
as set
there is no permissible fly
i unweighted graph less
two edges
and to positive
but age weight w i j
the weight w j i
they must be positive
otherwise there's no
before is that
well because
you know phi
seven five
i j
plus say phi i
j i
equals zero
i said
the negative each other so had to zero
but you have
i j
this article w i j
that gives you
i j
j i was raised five
i j phi
j i
zero so
two weights
and zero otherwise
there's no such thing and this will flow in any case
but in the useful thing is if
you don't have that condition all weights
got w i j
j i possible this one minus five that one
seven right
there's some positive
each but not positive so can you now run
max flow algorithms on this graph the question
yes will be yes
yes this is the same i am this is the important thing
this is based the most important theorem connection of flow
and the function
i told you how to represent the function on the graph
suppose you have two different that can be done in more than one way
it's important thing can be done in more than one way
but the important thing is that whatever way you do it
the difference
is a fly
they just differ by law
right so if you w
BMW prime two different weights on graphs
and they represent then
the graphs replacing the same function if and only if
those two weightings differ by flow
well lecture twelve
today we're going to be talking about what elements
what colour methods are one of several methods you can have your probability toolbox whenever
you complicated probability distribution that you are interested
when we were first looking at simple inference problems we just did a brute force complete
enumeration of all ten million hiv-positive the data
so that's always available as an option but typically complete enumeration just enter into long-term
more than two or three parameters in your problem
the classes that is in the book i'm not gonna talk about it
the idea of course is that you take this complicated distribution is a bit too
big to enumerate the approximated by a simpler distribution
namely a guassian so that's a simple idea
approximation distribution addressed by guassian
and look at that point
not useful role models
talk about one column which are ways of dealing with
that's complicated
probability distributions
random numbers
so we're gonna use random numbers today
this can be to lectures on follow
lecture today
and the next lecture
well be on advanced
the column is really
it's the place
the elements that do things that
are these they can do it faster
then they
following lecture will be about variational methods which are methods that don't use random numbers to deal with these problems
we are setting ourselves
just remind u
this course has a website and the book
it's like this
this free online
on the web
so here's a little road that's where we're going with on government as well a very simple monte carlo methods
and markov chain monte carlo methods which are slightly more complicated
and then we'll get on to be
really fancy methods
andy lecture plan is already discussed clustering
in this lecture
on simple monte carlo was going to get up to
as shown by the red line
so get up to
problems methods and get sampling leaving be second half
the following
that's about
i want to remind you what we did in the last lecture which is about clustering
this gave us an example all probability distribution we were interested in and it would
it look like this
the probability distribution we were interested in
the age of
a whole load of unknown means you want you to
although there are no standard deviations sigma one sigma two
what about
although the
unknown weights i one i two
of age estimates
hollowed unknown assignments all
points to
clusters see one
see two
two three
see and
i think you see one in which class
but they are actually belong to any receiver cluster
one two three
up decay
still have complete list
things we don't know how it yes that's a list all the things we don't know
the data
which set by text one
it x
the probability were interested in is the posterior
all these things
the data
given the assumption
comes from
a probability distribution that is in the standard deviations and weights so on
given the axes are assumed to come from the mixture
of objectives
was the model we are assuming in the last lecture
and we discuss briefly the idea that you could
have alternative models instead of a mixture of gaussians and mixtures of some other sort of distributions
and still you would have an inference problem where you are interested in inferring the
unknown cluster locations and sizes and shapes
hands on the assignments given
the data
has a real world example of this
you can imagine that you have a thousand manuscripts that had been transcribed by describes
back in the air when everything was done with handwriting
and you take the
manuscripts feature official documents the
we you want to infer
it is these characters
which characters were written by which strikes because if you can and that's you can
deduce the interesting things about the sociology of the community
describes it as well
try to extract from all these different models we have trees we have these HMM
type thing sequences we matchings
all these things are kind of
diverse and hard to sort of
handel one unified way so this is the attempt to do that is to say
OK are structured model definition is is is this kind of
what some right now it's a black box basically it takes an input x and
output y
this thing is you know some complex objects this thing is also complex subject finds
the best one according to scoring function
that's our definition of structured models
right and this place is feasible outputs might depend on x
which is you know
the c
the space of possible matchings for trees
you know this
this space is generally
very large is exponential in the size of
of your input that the number of points and the point cloud right the point
actually fifteen million points
so so
it's basically say four to that
to that power for the number of nodes
in general so we can enumerate that
enumerate that set efficiently it's going to be looking at you know that specializes in
this into
models we can do this argmax some efficient way otherwise sort of
stock being to attract so
we can assume that the score
it is our favourite linear combination of features right it's very much like you do
understand by now the
the features are not only depend on x
this feature mapping function
but also depends on our right to get it together are
so in the sequence of images with the potential labelings
and we create
features on that and also exactly what they look like right
same thing for matchings and
there is a joint feature map that takes input output and produces a big vector
you can think of them as sufficient statistics of x and y
i can think of them as
this is some kind of counts of what's happening with x and y
this is the vector and that is the thing we're trying to learn the prime
director that basically preferred prefer certain
and forms score
OK so the question
well it's not very restrictive i mean
so i'm saying this is my claim is mild assumptions
i mean if you
i mean if you want to score to be something else i can usually basically
put that function into the
into the feature mapping and then making minor edits the same thing as
and i can use kernels here two later
i mean just standard supervised
i mean in the nonparametric setting we make these things can kernelized disguised then you
know you can control the dataset
right so
it potentially could be an arbitrary function
not quite arbitrary but function that's
well i mean because we assume later on this thing decomposes nicely right we need
to be able to be the still doesn't give us the the ability to find
argmax which is that ability is this function further decomposed into parts
and then we can maximize over that i mean is quite these parts might be
in grammar school productions in a sequence of pairs of input output and the
you know output output
consider outputs et cetera so so we can restrict further the function to be some
a much stronger section
but they depend so the dependence on x
could be mill potentially arbitrary
and we can make nonparametric
OK so let me map the
chain markov net serum into this sort of w that have something which is you
know it's not that
it is that we usually written that way of that
although it's pretty easy to see so
so you start with OK so where x right a sequence of images
we have y
which is the sequence of labels twenty six possibilities and then this conditional random fields
are probabilistic models are defined distribution
mighty by decomposing it into parts and then
so far multiplying the parts together
more on that later today
the parts are
these node potentials which is potentials between
the image and the label and potentials which are
between consecutive labels and
also you could include the input as well if you'd like to crack so if
you if you are familiar with and right this is kind of correspond to a
emission probabilities and this would be the transition probabilities right so the difference here is
that these guys don't need to be probability taking the sum to one they just
need to be positive so
the decision then again there are nonnegative and we get further say there
positive they're just represented through this e to the again linear combination of things
yes this is more of an example in so that the
i mean for example we do the
segmentation of
o point clouds it's a three d great
or instead of regular grid but it's roughly speaking for so so
this is an illustration of what it looks like it
and in natural language and bioinformatics some biology
a lot of the problems are our chances the special cases very important
and this this
all of this extends to other things so again so potentially loglinear
kind presentation right next to the w
OK and then it depends on xj and y j
and we get this which is the index of the w
the corresponds the subject of
parameters are crisp on the no parameters
and the same thing here actually sold
i wanted to mention what of the features here's the features may be something like
this pixel in the third row and fourth column is on
and the latter label is
right so that's that's feature
it's basically saying i mean in so if that
pixel likes to be on when the letter is e then you probably will have
positive weights
if it doesn't then they'll probably negative weight because bugs negative weights for the future
will affect the potential
and so the large potential is the more likely it is
to me that label
so and again with so for edges you might have features like what's the previous
and what's the next across
so here doesn't depend on x but in general can
or something to
with this this is a little bit
like music
sure again this example only so i we can deal with non pairwise potentials and
you see i could have
the pairwise markov network but i could have XYJ
we can read get rid of it in this case is encouraging for the progress
of physics
as of now discussed in the second part of my lecture it can be used
this understanding of the origin of mass
can be used to address another class question
at the foundations of physics why is gravity so feeble
now if you have a hard time getting out of bed this morning
or if you try to hide the climber high
flight of stairs
you might be surprised to learn the gravity is feeble
but it really is
at a fundamental level
because we think
most of us think
same people think that
the the fundamental interactions
there are simple
at short distances we try to build up physics from local interactions at short distances
to understand how things happen at larger distances has been very successful since the very
big since the beginning
that's been the successful program
a theoretical physics
since the days of history well
since the days when we announced astrology
good experimental reasons
anyway so
so the the proper way to it
and that philosophy to account to discuss
the feebleness of gravity is to think about the forces at short distances between fundamental
and if you do that say between the proton and electron
you can calculate you can compare the ratio of their electrical forces to the gravitational
forces they both won over are square so it doesn't even matter what distance you
do it
and you find that the gravitational force is about forty orders of magnitude smaller than
the electrical force
so that's pretty feeble
another way of looking at it is in
if in my calculation of the proton mass i left out gravity
quantum gravity that's really scary and
why doesn't it fell the calculation well you can estimate how much the gravitational binding
which i left out
contributes as the car as a correction to the mass of the proton that also
gives some energy to see what correction it gives to the mass of the proton
hasn't been taken into account and about apart ten the forty is also
with the size of relief
we know we are justified in neglecting it in fact in
all of the
working in high energy physics at accelerators in fundamental physics
we have so far been able very successfully to ignore the direct effects of gravity
as of fundamental interactions
we really want to come to terms with gravity
in fact it's become more and more central in modern physics
to try to come to terms of gravity
first of all because it exists
but secondly
because it's part of the fantastic vision
applying first enunciated also at the beginning of the twentieth century
in his second paper on quantum mechanics
well what later became quantum mechanics i should say
and after the first paper in which introduced
o is constant
as a phenomenological parameter fitting black body radiation spectrum
the second paper on the subject was not about
the structure of hydrogen the structure of matter photoelectric effect anything that you would recognise
today as the funded foundation of quantum mechanics like second paper on the subject was
about a a very excited paper was about the construction of a new system of
applying for some reason
i was very pleased with the idea
that we could
information about ourselves such as our size
are ages things like that
hypothetical beings in andromeda without actually having to centimetres stick or watch
just by reference to fundamental observations of physics that would be the same for people
she three
you may be
we should be
well one
o five
or four c
we already
one of these
you're not that
i will give you
i really
five and l
these are
it's just one
on the
one is
similar articles
and so
the idea is to be about
well as
there are
so you
we should allow
if want
he is
so what's so please
the last point
now is
so not
he says
four would be the the
which is shown in the
this week
so the
that max
i mean
this is our
we draw
schools these schools is one
you've been
so long as she
two months
so we want to do
four so
is that there are
later on
in fact
this one which is this
well this one is just
which is called the generalized variance gamma process
we can
i have some more sophisticated ways of constructing the process is the normal inverse gaussian
processes such an example
well we take a two dimensional brownian motion
that we we run until it exceeds a threshold in one of its
the coordinates
and then we look at where the processes in its other coordinate
and and that random variable
the second brownian motion evaluated when the first brownian motion exceeds a threshold
as the threshold varies that
gives us a process that turns out to be only the process and it's called
the inverse calcium normal inverse gaussianity process because we sort of taking an inverse here
of the
and that brownian motion here
and then we
we take in
sort of make that the variance of a normally distributed other brownian motion that's where
that name comes from
so these are processes that we can construct distributions that we can describe without worrying
about infinite divisibility really what we do
but we we don't need to go into specifying mu sigma square new here
because we've got other means of seeing that we've got infinite divisibility
what is that
that gamma distribution if you add up to gamma variables with the same beta
you get another gamma variable
and if you
if you look at this construction
with some care you see that you've got a strong markov property which tells you
that again this
i t process is the process with
stationary independent increments and that property translates
to that same property
of z t
so the advantages of of this is that we get reasonably explicit densities
and that is very useful for parameter estimation
here we've got these three parameters or the four parameters that of course if we
want to do modelling when you to be fitted
disadvantages are that well we haven't exactly got a lot of modelling freedom and it's
actually not so clear how
with such approaches you
if you generate more generally
so this construction that we've gone through
is really
and bear fruit when we say well
why don't we use mu sigma squared and you
for the modelling
what are natural classes of
music muskrat new particularly new
what that what gives
the processes
well i forgot that i had some simulations of these just for you to look
at so here let's look at the gamma process
we can
vary the parameters
and i've chosen fake was beta because anything else will just have changed the scale
set of the scaling of our of our pictures so
this is
the behaviour
what kind of processes can express something that's pretty much dominated by the very big
jumps and you see smaller jumps infinitely many jobs in fact they
there are no longer visible at this scale and then as you increase the parameter
you see that the individual drums are becoming more and more important of of similar
and as you increase further and further you get the convergence to a linear
drift eventually that's sort of the strong law of large numbers behavior that you see
in these
classes of of gamma processes looking at variance gamma processes we take differences of two
and again have chosen to certain relationship between the parameters in order to keep the
of the variance gamma process is the same all the time
the one
a complex problem is let's try to extrapolate right so
let's use the graph today fit model and then try to make a prediction how
the graph we're looking at you from for example and the last point is about
a musician with the idea is that we have some sensitive gravity we don't want
to two
two days
so what we would like to do is create a kind of an anonymized version
of it
so that we can share it with other people and still this people can do
is try
and then for the cascades
why are they important is because once we observe how the influences spending and once
we can build better and more realistic models then we can go and select and
ASK which notes for the selected target for viral marketing or you know we
which nodes should be given free ipod so that will sell more of them
how can we like to quickly detect outbreaks and so on
and this is my the outline so for the rest of for the the remainder
of talk i will talk about completed work and we focus on the network structure
and the evolution the cascades and then i'll talk about proposed work and conclusions
john we don't slide eleven
this is how the computer what can be broken out again we have the two
setting of the evolution of the networks and basically cascades the processes taking on in
the networks and we have been sponsored predictions so
and first i will concentrate on this part but basically we first see what can
be observing growing graph that shows some models and how we can fix this models
make statements about that
OK so
the first basically we found two patterns in time evolving graphs and i guess many
of you already know that this thread so the question is what is the relation
between the number of nodes and edges in the graph as it grows so it's
a very very basic questions and so far people thought or the common assumption that
was made was that know the the
number of nodes grows linearly or number of edges grows linearly with the number of
what happens in the real real life is that that would become denser right so
the the degree is increasing over time and more what if we look at the
and plot the number of nodes which is the number of edges
over time on log log axis this follows the line
and the
photometric forum is then is is is described this equation says the number of nodes
at particular time
it is the some power a is proportional to to the number of edges we
find in the
right and the two graphs i show here one photograph of internet have like seven
hundred graphs one for each day for two years and the other one is here
are physics citations for ten years so these associations between high energy physics theory page
and in general
this exponent a we call the densification exponent in line between one interact if it
if it is one
then we we have a non densifying case where the average degree is maintained constant
and if we have two
then we basically having a quadratic growth with no links to
a constant fraction of the nodes are already present in the network
so this is one observation we we call a densification power law
so basically people for this thing that this would be equivalent statement saying our reference
lists are on the average getting long
what we are writing more maybe of something like that
and then
the second thing is about the same thing here the prior work intuition says of
the network gets larger the distances between the nodes in the network should slowly increased
right should increase like log log n so
logarithmically in the in the size of the network and then again if you go
to the data and c
and the amendments so here i show the same data set i have the diameter
which is let's say the distance at which ninety percent of all pairs of nodes
can be reached right and their bodies these
with the size of the graph it goes down
and again for the same physics citations
the diameter does not
right so what you see from this is that well so the network grows the
distances between the nodes get smaller so the diameter
shootings of stabilizes
OK now the question is
how can we model
we have several models but i show just one of them that we call kronecker
and this is based on the tensor product of graph adjacency matrix
but first
so what we would like to have that would like to have a model that
that will give us i know realistic patterns of static and evolving networks so what
we would like to do is