update of the model
if there is a change within this block of the data
you get new behavior and
no point start to
the group around here like here in this case
you will not be
amplified global update of f every of these
then in the data matrix
you will not be able to detect first point is anomaly and that sometimes very
important to detect
starting point is
he the new behavior
or anomalies in this case the this point of view this is an anomaly
but if the point of to group around these points these are not anomalous anymore
because they create value defined behaviour
and that's why it's important not to do this kind of periodic then you basically
have the model every one hundred attractors because you may miss
some data because that happened during that block so that's why
people trying to do this kind of incremental
anomaly detection of items and
there are two approaches
the research date incremental LOF incremental CF
in both of these approaches
updates then basically
the you update the model after inserting every data record
you know if you remember there are four steps
you're trying to
you're trying to compute this lf factor after every new data record is inserted in
into data that is that but by introducing new data record
the neighborhood
may change so how to update this
reachability density and
reachability distance
factors in this election
so whoever the good news is that the number of days that you have to
do for every data record does not depend on the number of data records
so it depends only on the number of dimensions so that's
that's a good sign that to do that the complete that it is computationally efficient
and it can be applied or applied in real time problems
we have the same thing for incremental CF
basically the CRF values computed after every new data record is inserted and of course
all of these
done before
basically computing this
a c
distance if remember from the slides of hall harvard
topic on distributed anomaly detection
sometimes as i mentioned in the beginning date
dispersed along several it the geographic locations or solar systems
for example if you can
network intrusion detection problem
you make
university network and university may have different campuses
so if you want to detect anomalies
they wanted to take this global anomalies and you may want to consider the data
from all the campuses
but is this approach is probably too
try to merge all the data together
but that sometimes not feasible because you to extremely huge
the benefit of huge datasets
and sometimes due to privacy citizens for example can credit card fraud
if you want to
here the situation when two credit card companies in sharing the models but not showing
the data
they may not challet data but they connection to model so
and finally aviation into the safety many aviation company say interested
in learning what can cause the failure but they may not be interested in sharing
the data so that's why
this notion of distributed memory cache is extremely important
i want to
talk about another
application area
where optimization plays an important role
and this is a statistical thing
so i think this one is
this topic is
close to
the kinds of things
people in machine learning are interested in
so there's many things one can talk about but i want about something simple regression
i wanna compared least squares regression
to least absolute deviation
and show you how least absolute deviation regression can be solved by linear programming
in the end this might actually get deferred until monday
i wanted
o regression analysis the parametric self to simplex methods the number of iterations as a function of
the problem size
for the for the album i just showed you
motivate all this stuff and i hope it's not too elementary
but i thought i would give a little
introduction to means and medians and how they are related to regression in general
so i wrote my book
seventeen years ago
so i took some data
i was able to find
and the
internal revenue service's website
in the united states
well adjusted gross incomes and individual tax returns
this was several million
data points i forget exactly how big and was
but those budget data points
and each for each individual
it was
given therein
adjusted gross income is the income minus
various deductions are allowed
so there's just five people
the actual data that i got from them is summarized here this is that the government didn't get all
several million
returns i just got this little table
and in this table that tells you how many right
this is the number of returns
and this is the adjusted gross income so the total
adjusted gross income is this and this is and thousands of dollars it yes and thousands of dollars
so let's see that's five thousand five million five million four trillion dollars
divided by
one hundred eighteen million
returns will give you the average
in the united states
but the table and i found interesting was that they broke broken down into categories
and told us how many people
in these different company returns in the different categories and the total energy to those
the categories
end so you can use this to find out what the median income is and
i think i have it on the next slide with the median of course is
the middle person and that's a little bit this we just are counting these appear
thousand here
well we get tired eighteen million so i get halfway
so this is about a million that's about fifteen and have that the
fifteen twenty eight
forty one
three so somewhere around here is the halfway point are one hundred eighty million so we
average adjusted gross income that seventeen years ago
i think with some more between twenty and twenty five thousand dollars
here the actual number will
so i don't know i can deduce from a table the exact
the median but it's somewhere in the middle ring in the middle and i mean
no one billion in this twenty twenty five thousand range and so i just took
the middle
a this
and got the
twenty two thousand five hundred sixty
the median is my estimate the median whereas the mean if i add up all
it's the
three lines in the middle
i think you know
this to me
let's look at the second line there this
a zero
that's the
precondition of the first action
and then there are people who effects of actions
this is when the action is taken up one zero
and then there is the
o stations assign then this correspondence
formula for the second action
and of course notes that the
the midline sites like the same except that the
all the time points
the implemented by one would be good
x y
one could
even by using them quite this is why is satisfiable
this value that satisfies the formula
one value of these properties
it was listed on the values
what the state variables in this that's fine valuation
we can see what other the states
the execution of this plan
the corresponding let's so the initial state
because they knew each is called describe uniquely so a of these through time three
and in the intermediates that something happens all
what has happened between one point zero one is that it has become falls
so this must be
because the
actually what they
actually it falls
then there is also difference between these
this standpoint point
what has happened is that it has become true
the walls
and this is what
what the second action
but does
what the plan system the first action
take the second action and in
the last difference here is again
can the first action so
the plan reactions first action a connection to the action then three rules
you may have noticed that this actually sort of
sort of like has
because actually the
well you know is the variables
the one
or satisfies goal one
if we have picked sort of planning you could have well defined simpler shorter life
i have out you'll have a nice example later but this is by using
if n
the definition of the
one slide different kind of translation from the formula
how this
translation be presented so far we call
efficiency of SAT solvers of program for testing the satisfiability of propositional formulas is strongly
depending on the
the size of the form
in the planet is this means that it's
very strong depending on the length of your eyes
this the horizon b
what is the
this that's always been trying find the black
for these reasons
one way of improving
translation from planning from set problems is
i've already used or i think one way is simply tool
more than one
every time so
o definition so far was based on
translating every action in this way
so that a reaction
something well this formula here the that
this actually takes place and of course nothing happens
not nothing else happens nothing that's
isn't that course action kind of course is implicit many of the same
so instead of using this definition where is
it's like the one that they have to be done
he was definition in which several actors and can take place simultaneously
this makes sense those
actually cite independent of each other and on into one of the ways
in ways i of images
you know many kinds of problems this allows to reduce the horizon length from by
by the fact like from one hundred ten
which means for example that the most points
perhaps selected simultaneous like sinatra simultaneously i
this is of course not applicable or from the many practical problems like this
are all of this is
the idea
of paralysing the plans while allowing
so well actually given by
it is based on the following conditions will be using so
consider those two actually the first line
the preconditions of this is actually saw
it consists so compatible with each other
and the effect also don't want to be so
what do we
take these actions in order be well have definitions of plans that allow these two
well been maybe forty b
london underground
which is expressed in english arguably uniform which should be easy to understand because if
it's not easy to understand and defeats this purpose you might as well not say
so look at these sentences
the first one press the alarm signal button to alert the driver
the set look like a sentence of logic
or does it look like gold reduction procedure
what is the goal to alert the driver
what is the so-called press the alarm signal button how do we represent goal reduction
procedures and logic programming as
conclusion condition rules the justification for this procedure is that you will alert the driver
if you press the alarm signal button
so the very first sentence is a procedural representation of logical
those people who love logic programming and say
logic programming is the declarative representation and that's what knowledge representation should be all about
would have us rewrite the sentence
as a declarative sentence
they would have to say
you want
they would have a say if you press the alarm signal button then the driver
will be alerted
probably a lot less effective than this
procedural way of
putting it
the second sentence obviously has logical form a lot and will form conclusion the driver
will stop condition any part of the train is in a station
there are things left out of this of course the driver will stop what
will stop feeding you are creating the problem
creating an emergency and of course not the driver will stop the train so natural
language has
features that are not present in the language of thought in the language of thought
if we understand the sentence we understand that the driver will stop the train
now you might say this that mean we should say the driver will stop the
the train maybe
but it goes for granted if you can take it for granted in
and we often leave out important
considerations context in particular which is necessary to actually understand the meaning for example the
driver will stop if any part of the train is in a station
provided the driver has been alerted to an emergency
so the second sentence has hidden extra conditions
coming from the first sentence but none the less
to understand this sentence you need to extract its meaning
and that meaning has a linguistic form has the logical form and it has a
simplified form of logic which is what we call clausal form
if not again another logical structure
the train will continue to the next station
blah blah blah
the last sentence there is a fifty pound penalty for improper use
if then
but is there a hidden
implication in all of this
what is the meaning of this if you put this in your head how do
you store these sentences what is it significant
i will tell you
figured out
i think you i hope you will
this is your problem not mine
so what is involved in understanding natural language
my argument is
our thoughts have linguistic forms that linguistic four is the logical forms that logical form
is a simplified form
which is
causal in nature
well we know
we all know that the first problem other of understanding natural language is to identify
the intended meanings to get rid of ambiguities obvious ambiguities at least he gave her
the book who who
who gave home the book
well let's say it's john gave mary the book
so the first
problem is to identify to be
to get closer to logic
logic does not have he in her doesn't have these indefinite pronouns
the second thing is to represent the meaning in a canonical form john gave mary
the book john gave the book to mary mary received the book the book was
given to mary by john
you can
x you can store
that kind of knowledge
in your head
the only way to to
deal with the world is to represent knowledge in the standard form in the canonical
form to process it in canonical form
OK this is this is an old-fashioned syntax
john gives the book to mary say as event one thousand
this is the this is the classical symbolic notation but you know that that's just
notation is not even syntax
you know you can invent any other notation you like without changing the syntax but
the point is that
to understand natural language we have to have a canonical form we we have to
represent knowledge and conditional form clausal form is the canonical form is the conjunctive normal
form of first-order logic
where there are no
existential quantifiers anymore and the existential quantifiers go away because they don't provide enough information
it's more expressive to have clausal form without existential quantifiers then to have a full
unstructured of first order logic
so my argument is the clausal form
before we use an abductive logic programming is much closer to the language of thought
then say first order logic
for example in clausal form we we would say that
that if x is the burden x has further john bird
we wouldn't say as we say in standard first order logic these crazy things
standard first order logic
is gobbledygook
no wonder natural languages so hard to understand this because it allows us to say
what first-order logic says we don't want to first order logic we want to canonical
form which simplifies representation so we can manipulate them easily and understand what people
attempting to communicate
so the argument therefore as i said is that clausal logic
it is
a potential candidate for
the language of thought
and the advantage of that is that reasoning in clausal logic is far far simpler
than reasoning in first order logic
it can be reduced to forward and backward reasoning as in the abductive logic programming
agent model
as in production systems as in logic programming
and it can be extended to include resolution so you can compile
you can compile complicated beliefs into simpler beliefs
you can
lemmas is if you like
the second theme of my talk
is that
artificial intelligence can help people not only to make better smarter decisions
you have ten days left
for your model
so it's a nice project for spring break
i'll give you some hints
keep the fraction of year low as you can
you can use any or of course that's not allowed
balance your road
the best you can
and try to avoid that the rotor begins to bond begins to vibrate
because when it vibrated loses contact
with the current when it needs it so there's no trick
i will be test
your motors
we don't just destroy was called
and i decided to
demonstrate to you how are we going to do that
that's probably
the best thing to do
we have this
we're going to rotate to disk
thousand RPM let's assume that is your model
and we're going to struggle with it
with a strobe light
until it stands still
in this case
i've said this rope
so to stand still roughly
and the problem is now going at five hundred rpm and the motor is going
at thousand rpm
so this clearly is not
the rotation rate of your
in fact you motor goals twice around between the buildings
and we have no way of knowing that so we double the frequency
i'm trying to double it now
double the frequency of blinking
of the
strobe light
and outstanding skill again
so now we may think that your motive is going thousand RPM but we don't
know yet maybe it's going three thousand two thousand rpm
maybe three thousand rpm
so we're going to do now we're going to double the frequency
so we go now is the strobe light
the two thousand rpm
and what we see now
see double image
so two thousand RPM is out
in any multiple of two thousand rpms is out so four thousand is out six
thousand and eight thousand is out
and what is not yet out is three thousand and five thousand and seven thousand
so we would have to test for that
on the other hand i told you already that this model is going one thousand
RPM so there no census testing that now but doing the actual contest of course
we will continue all the way until we are convinced that we have the right
rpm for your motives
so that's the way we will do it will put a little bit of white
on one side of the road
so that's the way it will be done
of course if your model is highly unstable in terms of rotation rate
i will not be easy
to get to right correct number
i want to talk with you about
the heart
heart has four chambers
looks for like this
he left a tree
and the right him
maybe that's why this is why it's called the heart
and here is the left
and the are on the right
and here's a order
the soul
the purpose of the heart
is to pump blood
about five courts community
which is seventy five gallons per hour
which is seventy barrels day
it is about
million barrels in seventy five years
and it funds
about seventy times per minute
if the block to your brain stops for about five seconds
you lose consciousness
so was five skips of the heart beat
and you down on the floor
four minutes later
brain damage
the way hard work is absolutely mind-boggling
extremely complicated
nature had one billion years two
design but nevertheless it's impressive
each heart cells
these are many
chemical batteries
and poems ions it around as it pleases
in the normal state
it's hard sell
these mines
eighty million fold on the inside
relative to the outside
there are some cells which are called
pacemaker cells
they are located
a very small area about one square millimeter
the right atrium
they change their
o tential from minus eighty million volts
plus twenty million people
why do that is a different story which i will not address
once they go to plus twenty manifolds
the neighbouring cells
anyway propagates over the heart
make your drawing shortly
so the way first
move over the age will chambers and then
over the
ventricle chambers
and when the cells are least twenty million falls inside relative to the outside
the contract
today former muscles
the whole heart
is one
big muscle
and after about two-tenths of a second
the cells return
two miners eighty manifold
in this way
goes from below
two above
and then the whole thing weights again for another message from the pacemaker cells
takes about one second and then the whole process starts all of over
now i want to be more precise
he is one
heart cells
but this is about ten microns in size
and this cell has eighty manifold
with respect to the outside
but that means
it has repel positive ions
so inside
and there is no he feels outside
he put gulshan service around here there is no net
charge inside
but there is of course a
electric field across the world here
from plus to minus
now the depolarisation which this the change to the
and then we can see the different variations
so only using the geometry important results
o nine using the hamming embedding
four three thousand feet combined two of them together we further improve the results
and you can see that the improvement is actually substantial so if you look at
the data set of one million images here
we have
mean average precision of three and then by just adding make dramatic and having these
double mean average precision
and then what i said before actually if we had this reranking step
we can see that it allows to further improve the results right so actually what
this picture much even the hamming embedding that it gives us back much more true
positive in the short list and if you apply the real ranking can still further
improve the results so the two of them be geometry and fortunately the complementary
one is really big filter which improve results and the second one really verifies the
results and so based on the three ranking most results actually correct
the ones which have been found correct
and you can see here as well this is interesting
if you look at the CPU which is
it is consumed so there's
this is for computational which good quantisation and then if you look at the search
time for searching we can see that the overall search time for hamming embedding and
weak geometric consistency
is comparable to the baseline
actually had before the hamming embedding allows to find much matches scriptures and therefore less
memory access to reduce the search time the geometry the joint constraint
increases that both together and others to have the same same search time as before
so it's really it's feasible to use this approach is time consuming
and if you're a real example so this is the query
and this is what the for the first five without which system returns and is
actually nice like this example because they only give back the images of the
the retrieve stored explicitly in the dataset but also find similar images in flickr flickr
has expressed interest which is similar to the query found automatically
and if you compare our approach to the bag of features and si
in green
the ranking obtained for the images our approach to the first fourth and fifth these
are the ones which we have in our dataset and then refused to the bag
of features we can actually see the very far behind this decision for five thousand
eight hundred to basically even with this geometrically ranking being their removed to the top
and similar further mathematical so we don't find all images here in the form of
recall i don't find all of images which you have put into our dataset but
only a subset of them so here for the first six retrieved images with ninety
again we find also images from flickr which show
which correspond to the query
and so i don't know what we want to get the demo because but because
i just laptops to
conclude so we're seeing that we obtained excellent results for large scale image search
how did this online
and the one million people think dataset contains request expanding with quite extended this work
two videos and
here i show just one result from the trecvid competition to the competition is two
hundred hours of videos and have is to find the deform video in the dataset
so you can see here
the upper
the upper left the upper right corner here corresponds to the image in the czech
the dataset
and what you want to retrieve the corresponding image correctly from collection of two hundred
twenty hours of video sickening feeling our system performs extremely well
here the images he scaled so so it's much smaller it inserted in the image
and there some ways the in which it is so this is the tricky task
right attribute is because have the data set that set of videos and you want
to find deformed copies in this dataset and i think
applications is that for example
mean producers want to see where their copies go to basic there is a large
market for this and if you just
compare one of the results we have obtained the trec competition so
the most difficult the
difficult transformation
was the combined had fun for information so having this is scant end of the
video noise and insertion you can see here
but our three approaches
also called perform significantly better than the other best once right again here you have
recall and precision and
if submitted three different ones
this one is just based on the key frames the ones to the key frames
the red and green once still more frames for for short right
and you can just outside you can idea can we see that our system outperforms
systems of the other people
maybe you can take questions well so now the the second part is the demo
but it can quickly questions well
frank is
any questions
so we have to
i could lead to ask the question
in the most unusual with the video
well you
do you know if you have look at the face
two months
you're saying on the
you want see
one four
and what
these people
well the
the face of
we are not really
it is
so although our
you are right
here it is
the one
he said
o and one
of what
in my
right now
one he
the result
i'm sure
then this would have been
i couldn't have used that as the pivot but i could have exchanged again
in this case
in this case because what when can i when can i get out of trouble
i can get out of trouble if there's a non-zero below
this is this troublesome zero
and there is here
so i would be OK
in this case if this was the sixth i would survive by rho exchange
of course
might have happened that i could do the romeo that that there was zero below
it but was now
i can also got in trouble
this number one was a little different
the that one became of five i guess by the end
so do you can use the what numbers there would have got me
the trouble that i really
i couldn't get out of
trouble that i couldn't get out of wood mean
if the pivot is
o right
if if zeroes in the pivot position and i can't
i've got no place to exchange
so the must be some number
which if i had had here it would have meant failure
negative for good
was the negative four here if it happened to be in negative for the night
i'll temporarily put up here
if if this event negative
for the
and i would have
gone through the same steps what have been the minus four it still would have
been my four
but at the last minute what have become
and there wouldn't have been a third pivot
the matrix would have not been invertible
the inverse of a matrix is coming next week but
you've heard these words before so that that's not always we identify failure
this temporary failure when we
you can doro exchange and get out of it
or there is complete failure when we get a zero and
and there's nothing below that we can you OK
stay with
back to success
in fact i guess the next topic is back substitution
so what's back substitution well
that the
now i better bring the right side
so what would matlab do
and what should we do
to bring in the right hand side as an extra column
so there can be so it's two twelve two
this is i i would call this the augmented matrix augment means your something on
i've tacked on this extra column
because when i'm working with equations
i do the same thing to both sides
at this step
i subtracted two of the first equation away from the second equation so that
still i even brought some color chart but i don't know
if it shows up so this is like that
certainly the wrong thing
OK here's the
here b
OK that's the extra column OK so what happened
so that extra column the right hand side of the equation
when i did the first step so that was three in this away from this
so it took
the to stay the same
but three two twos got taken away from twelve leaving six
and that to stay the same so this is the
how it's looking halfway along
and let me just carry to the end
and the six the same
what i have here
o cash
help me out now what so now i'm i'm this is this is still like
forward elimination
i got to this point which i think is right
now what did i do with this step by multiply that payment by two the
whole equation by two and subtracted from that
so i think i take two sixes which is twelve away from the two
you think minus ten
is my final right-hand side
the right hand side that goes with you and we call that
once and forever
the vector c
so c is what happens to be
and you
it is what happens to a
OK there you've seen elimination
what's back substitution
so so what are my final equations that can i can i
copy these equations
x one two y
was the
two is still there
and two y
minus two the
six there
and five
the miners
those are the equations that are
that these
numbers are telling me about
those the
ways in the u
x equals the
OK how do i sell them
will also be optimal
so this is the policy improvement theorem and it's the basis of the policy iteration
three try to use this fact to
somehow use developer emaar a monte carlo based approach to policy improvement
so i
computing pi prime amounts to maximizing this q function
how can we use the bandit ideas to solve this to compute pi prime
that's the question
so set up our bandit were some state as we have our k actions
well we're going to do is to find a stochastic function which we can implement
we're going to call it simpkins
we defined so stochastic function
and the expected value if we run this function
over and over and over is going to be equal to the q function
so intuitively is i show you in the next slide this is simply going to
simulate taking action a in following the policy
and is about the reward
very simple to implement
if we could do this if we can generate figure out what this how to
simulate this function and how to implement this function since the expected value is q
we can use our
uniformbandit algorithm to get a PAC result for selecting an approximately optimal improved action
and in approximately improved action
how do we implement simq u
it's actually pretty simple so
so say we pull this arm
and this is the function that we're
get implemented
it somehow using a simulator so what do we do we are just going to
put the simulator in state s
so that's the first thing we do
we're going to use the simulator will take action a wall and up in some
state according to our transition function
and going to simulate then at each day we can look at pi
figure out what action it suggests take that action we end up in a new
state we do that for each minus one steps
we sum up the rewards that we saw and this is what we output for
some q
this is a random function because these trajectories are random trajectories because our simulators random
so that's how we do some q four a one
do the same thing for the other actions
so so some q is easy to implement if you have the simulator i think
we could agree on that it's also easy to verify that the expected
that then q is the actual q functions sort sort of by definition
it sort of doesn't even need to proof it's it
we have an algorithm for policy improvement now
using our simulator so
for each arm
we're going to run sim q w times right
these are these are
basically different runs of the same q function
and these
values are just the total rewards that we observed when we ran some q
and then we're going to return they are has the highest
its highest average these values and according to our uniformbandit resulted tells us well if
we really wanted to pick w so that we get a PAC guarantee we get
a PAC guarantee on
choosing an approximately improved action
right right so so the situation you want to imagine is your robot
you're in the state of the world
that's as
and now
you're trying to pick an action
so in in your head you're going to do all of this stuff with pi
and then you're going to pick the one that that that maximizes that so you
don't change pipe that leads into the next thing
i think it's fairly
you could nest rollouts right
so we could stick and here's sort of pi we could stack it stick and
the rollout
policy of pi
i think that's the next slide
no so without becoming a moment so this
it was just finish up the rollout so so basically what we need to know
how many samples we need to generate well for each machine
we need to generate h times w samples there are k machines so the number
of calls to the simulator which is sort of
the dominating complexity here is khw everything else is just a constant we're doing additions
over k things and what not
but no unique origin
just like the plane or vector
so in other words i can't
say that the translation moves us from here to here
or from here to here it's all the same thing magnitude and direction no unique
in fact all of these
i have translational periodicity
is the translation in this part of the pattern and another translation from here to
to here in the middle
the thing that makes a crystal crystal
is that
it is an arrangement of atoms or molecules
which is related to one part to another by the operation of translation
if you don't have translational periodicity
you do not have a crystal
so that's
come to the essence of what crystallography is about
you can imagine
in one sense
the generation of this pattern by
a rubber stamp sort of operation
because i have a rubber stamp
and i put on the rubber stamp
the pair of motifs like this
pick it up move it over time
pick it up move it over to i can stamp out the pattern that fashion
notice that my statement about no unique origin in these terms can be so stated
that doesn't matter where the two motifs are on the stamp
it could be up in the upper left-hand corner right in the middle down on
the bottom as long as i move the stamp through the same distance in the
same direction
i get the same pattern
that's not bad for an introduction but i want to be more
general than this
because one idea in in terms of a stamp operation is a transformation that involves
taking one little chunk
of the two dimensional space picking it up and more putting it down in another
location to another unique
location in space
so i'm going to make another generalization is that
o operations which was begun to the final
act on all of space
so i don't want to think of this repetition in terms of a rubber stamp
although we could get the pattern that way and it's conceptually appealing
but i'm going to say now that this
string of motifs has translational periodicity
if one might pick it up
move by t in a particular direction and throughout the whole incident chain back down
again it is mapped into congruence with itself
which leads me to another definition
an object or space
possesses symmetry
there's an operation
or set of operations
that maps it into congruence with itself
in other words in plain words you can tell that it's been moved
he is or anything else that is the transformation which leaves the set
in very
OK if we look at the first order
there are
o site such as this one here
or this one here
about which i can
one motif into its neighbour or for that matter pick up the entire chain and
flipped end over elbow
through one hundred eighty degrees in it will be mapped into coincidence with itself
and that is an operation and another sort of the sting operation of transformation and
this is one that i could call rotation
for obvious reasons
and there are two things i have to tell you about the rotation operations
the first one is the point about which the rotation takes place
and that's going to be some point in that we call this point here eight
so this will be some labelled point that is the location of the
rotation axis
but then the other thing i have to tell you is the angle through which
i'm going to rotate
our hands to be a as the subscript the angle of rotation
so this particular operation called the two fold rotation because it rotates through half the
circle would be the operation a pied
this point is a we rotate through an angle pi
this pattern here has
rotational symmetry
in addition to the translation there is the rotation operation a pie in the lower
so the
going to do is give you an updated version of the tutorial i gave at NIPS so if you
came to my NIPS tutorial in 2007 there's some new bits, but it's mostly the
same as the NIPS tutorial in 2007
and what you'll learn about is
an efficient way to learn multilayer generative models from unlabelled data by learning one layer
of features at time, that's basically the main content of the tutorial, that's it is we you learn
about you learn about ways to extend it to have markov random fields in each
layer that is lateral interactions
how to
having learned these deep nets
how to make them work well for discrimination and classification
and how to combine them with modern kernel methods like Gaussian processes
how to use these methods to do explicit dimensionality reduction on very big data sets
and how they can help with things like fast document retrieval
and also how to apply the same methods to sequential data
first for
making background characters from movies for example
so to start with i want to draw distinction between two types of machine learning
task. there's what i think of as typical statistics
where you typically have low dimensional data maybe less than a hundred dimensions
there's often a lot of noise in the data
there's typically not much structure in the data set typical
thing would be say some medical statistics on who died after some heart operation who
didn't, you have sort of the blood pressure and their age and stuff like that
the main problem is not
thinking that the noise in the data is real structure
so financial prediction typically is in this range whereas almost all noise
that is, all noise
artificial intelligence is the other end of the spectrum where
you typically have high dimensional data
this is the sort of perceptual artificial intelligence
there's a lot of structure and the noise isn'tsufficient to sort of completely it's
obscure the structure if you look at things right
and the problem is to have some representational scheme powerful enough to be able to
represent the structure
but simple enough toallow youto learnit fromdata
so typically what we have is we have methods that will learn from data
like EM algorithm
butwithoutvery powerful representations of
or methods that
how very powerful like classical AI
representations but you don't know how to learn them from data
so a little bit of historical background. I'm gonnatrash neural networks in three slides
in the nineteen sixties
people developed perceptrons late fifties and sixties and this is what the a typical perceptron
looked like
you had some
inputs and i will focus on process images so let's poses the pixels
you had some features that were designed by hand, these could have been little bits of computer
program but you could also think of perhaps fixed feature detectors
and then we learned weights connecting your features to decision units
and there was a very nice guarantee that if you
did things in a simple way
you were guaranteed to find a set of weights that would always make the right choice
if anysuch set of weightsexisted. the problem was, in an architecture this simple
for complicated problems, there wouldtypically be no set of weights that coulddo the job so
the guarantee was rather vacuous
nevertheless people like Google use this kind of algorithm a lot onbig data sets
what i think as asecond generation neural networks allowed you to learn multiple layers of weights that
was seen as a big breakthrough you could learn the strengths of the connections in multiple
and back propagation algorithm
which was invented by lots of different people
you start withan input vector
and you go--you go feed forward through the neural net, you compare the output you get
with the correct answer
and then you take some measure of that discrepancy and go backwards through the neural
computing derivatives for these weights
i'm not going to the details of how youdo it, but it'sessentially just the chain rule
and the time it seemed very exciting because it seemed we could learn multiple layers of
representation, andindeed on toyproblems we could
but was ratheradisappointmentwhen used onbigproblems
it basically has been supplanted in the nineties by support vector machines
as the sort of method of choice for tackling some problem you don't understand
so you could think of the support vector machines
as having
instead of having hand coded features taking training examples and for each training example
automatically creating afeature
this isn't the sense of feature they talk about when they talk about high dimensional
feature spaces, it's the sense of feature that perceptrons have. so you turn each training example into a feature
the feature isessentially: how similar isatest case to this training example
that's the value of the feature
and then you have a very clever way of
eliminating most of those features
and simultaneously as you do this elimination figure out the weights to put on the other features
to make sensible decisions
it turns out that works
views there already are just kind of in the summary of the views often it's
a good idea to kind of put a similar amount of information into the RDF
redundancy in this case is OK it's not a problem i have to say proposed
symbols these these documents thing of web pages web pages incredibly redundant orders navigation stuff
around the continent the same on every page
and it's not really a problem
OK semantic sitemap that's the last step
you need to do this makes alot of sense to do this if you want
to publish linked data but you also have a sparql endpoint or
RDF dump of data
in that case the semantics that simply away
two let callers like red cross an RDF crawlers find
those times into sparql endpoint
basically you put a simple XML file online just a few lines
when you say
what is your data set and basically you just
at the end of the day you say here's the location of the data that
appears to do you by of the sparql endpoint
so this is just kind of
so that's the finishing touches that you can apply to you
this i'm afraid i basically have to skip but i would just say
popular tool if you already have RDF data you have it in an RDF store
you can use pubby
to add a link to a different to this
set of RDF like to the RDF data
he to if you have an existing database
relational database
you can use the tool server
two to expose
the linked data view on the data and the server in the database
tool if you have like the this this lamp applications like linux apache mysql PHP
perl or whatever
in for these applications to advisory very nice simple php script that you can use
two to eat some linked data
used to to the applications
and yet but in any case it's also not such a such a huge effort
to your to build your own application
if you ever actually working dynamic HMS is already then it's fairly straightforward to
at these RDF versions of the HTML pages and at the continuity equation in there
and then you don't get to
all right so
that these have been the seven steps
and i just want
look back at those principles that we saw in the
at the beginning of
of the tutorial
and just just just let's see how these are like how are supported these principles
are supported by the
by the steps of this before
visualise names for things you we did be assigned
your eyes to the entities
is actually you are with this
so they can be looked up
provide useful information in RDF we did this by having these these these data pages
chance of RDF and by having
each entity
connects to one of the data page is either by opening hash or by doing
redirect to see redirects from the URI to the data
and finally included include RDF links to other UIC
we've done this to some extent when we have sliced data sets of course
description will also still include the UID of of the other and related entities so
the the
brands that includes the URI of the whisky often
of the of the reviews and
but we have not yet talked about external links
two other datasets
and that's of course and other kind of RDF link that you should definitely include
into your data and that's
what's what's coming like
OK so what we're gonna do now is just to give you a quick overview
of some of the the methods we can use what we want to take
data published in RDF on the web and the web now
in particular domain it it's not just to other data within our own dataset but
to data that comes from other datasets and other other namespaces
as you saw
earlier on this
a great many other datasets already you can link to this is quite an old
copy of the diagram
but there's already an histogram you can there are things like the
like g aims you might be interested in linking to
datasets but that they are KB stuff really needs to be to be split out
into individual
into separate distinct datasets and represented as such but i think that i don't know
whether they all available as is it this effectively crawlable or is it just there's
lots of data in each one of the individual and point
in that case it should certainly be be split out this for thirteen or more
OK so
triangular sort
so obviously can use any
predicate you want
so that's designed to be used for filling in different bits together to actually connect
across different datasets you can do so you can take any recovery has appropriate predicates
and then use those for creating links different datasets
there are few kind of patterns that crop up again and again we talked about
al-samoud which is one of the most commonly used predictors which is really about saying
this thing
their own
grace what we call people only care about their own greater technical term for them
in england i think we refer to these guys
ten or not
as evil deeds
it this not perhaps the most moral people in the universe
all right
so now we can ask a different question suppose with these actually powerful not pretend
they often have
that's suppose your payoff now we can ask not what did you do
but what should you do now we have secondary switch the questions in order question
what should you do and it's come back to close the clarity was paralyzed for
mike and you get to just explain what you did and why again
why is some sort of
you should you should alpha doing is we're up to your payoff small as well
you can make a great featured
so what need features of the people support is that
two different after that were high shows
so what you are saying it's important idea is this and tell me if i'm
paraphrasing you incorrectly but i think this is more of a saying
it is no matter what the other person doesn't what the pair does
she obtained a higher payoff
i choosing alpha to see that if the pair
choose alpha
and she chooses then she gets zero
if the patches alpha teachers be that she gets minus one zero is bigger than
minus one
if the player chooses beats
the future alpha to get three
she gets one
three is bigger than one so in both cases no matter what the other person
she received a higher payoff from choosing health
so she's issues out
well that that that line everything that's a stronger line of reasoning than the reason
we had earlier so that's what i merely forgot the name of in the red
his name was
courtney so-called also gave a reason for choosing alpha and the perfectly good reason you
have nothing wrong with it but noticed that this reasons a stronger isn't it kind
of implies uris
right so let's get some definitions down here
can find it here
rather than
we say
my strategy
how far
strictly dominates
my strategy bees and
if my payoff
from alpha
than that
from these
this is a key part of the definition
of what
regardless of what others to read that back
we say the my strategy alpha correctly dominates my strategy set my payoff from alpha
is strictly
greater than that can be regardless of what others do
now it's by no means my main aim in this past to teach you dog
right a few bits of jargon to be helpful in allowing the conversation to move
forward and this is certainly one evil gets is maybe one with the system
structured lessons from this actually so it's a good story that we bring down here
on this board
so the first lesson of the classes lots of lessons
is lesson that emerges immediately from the definition
the dominant of the dominant strategy
and it's this
lesson one of the course is
dominate said
right so i with apologies to strunk and white this is the passive form dominate
passive voice do not play
is strictly dominated
so it otherwise why
i'm going to get this guy not
his right
it is
the dominant
come on everyone would result
like were should
it's possible also looking for something more direct is
we look the definition is dominant strategy saying never play one
the possible reason for that is that can we get the woman
i always knew well was about winning and losing
what else can we have we can get this this kind of thing
the payoffs alone
the payoffs alone OK so
so here's here's an abbreviated version of that but that's not the
that's precisely longer the reason i don't want to play strictly dominated strategy
it is but it if instead
i play the strategy that dominates states
i do better in every case
reason never want to play strictly dominated strategy is if instead i by the strategy
that dominates it whatever anyone else does i'm doing but i would
that's a pretty convincing argument that sounds convincing arguments it sounds like two obvious even
to what we were thinking in class
right so let me try and shake your face about in this in this answer
somebody wanted by the FBI
how about the following on
the payoff matrix again
and i suppose the reason as follows
suppose i reason and say
if we if we knew my
both reason this way and choose alpha
we'll both get zero
but if we both reasons a different way and should be
they were both get one
so i should use beta one begins are i use
what's wrong with that argument
now i must be wrong because it's less the past lessons the plaza got the
wrong ever so what's wrong with that are from that
this guy just as good
right so involve some notion of agreeing about national agreeing so certainly part of the
problem here
with the reason i just gave me the reason that said i should choose beta
because we both reason the same way both by the way
it involves some kind of magical reasoning it's as if i'm arguing that i e
reason this way and reason myself to choose some i'm going to make the rest
of you
the reason the same way too
it's like i've got yes prr i'm some character out of
what is all the x-men that was called right now in fact becomes priced you
i'm not i don't have ISBN to be another character of the x-men so you
so this is now
the desk
desktop so each one of the coloured regions was one seperate depth map
and then we can glue them all into a in reconstruction the whole scene
these are just some different
renderings these so that we can texture map it
this is a normal map which gives you a good indication of whether you've got
accurate reconstruction and the smooth surfaces
a fun thing
we can do with this is to revisit the yeah
augmented reality and
but now
with our new level of capability because we don't just know where the camera is
now we know what's in the same so we have a full model of this
desktop scene
so now when we drop this virtual currencies seen the queen cars
is virtual
you can see for instance we can make it disappear behind a real
cup because we've got a model of the cup
we know that the cup should include the car
the other thing we can do is actually make it physically interact with the same
so we can
make ramps out over
the stuff that we find in the same
so this is just by loading the mesh that we generated into free um
physics simulator
and then make the car drive around on on the surface
so there was
that's system we could live don't reconstruction
and there was
you know big big advance at the time but that's still didn't fully
satisfy us because we are pretty much still riding
the point-based system
and then using
optical flow on top about we wanted a slam system that was kind of dense
but a place where there is relevant to this
pacitti student in my lab steve lovegrove that the time was
he boater
aslam system four
mosaicing so this is if you like
so panoramic mosaicing is a type of simple
slam problem where
you want to estimate the three d e rotation over the camera so it's three degrees of freedom
it's only rotating it's not translating
and you want to build a map and the map is basically
the panorama so there's no depth about markets just lies on the sphere
but he did this by our whole image alignment approach so there's no features in this
system at all
what he's doing is he's building a map of the
the panorama but basically laying down keyframes
the relative
oppose the camera all times it is found by
taking the live image and doing a whole image alignment using a whole image looks cannot type methods
the find out what's the
transform of this live image that brings it into the best
alignment with with the map that i've got where alignment is measured by
you know some squared differences over all overlapping
it depends on the cheapy course it's very fast
there's a pyramid implementation so it goes from low resolution the high resolution that makes it
faster and more robust still
and so he was able to attract really quite fast
motion against this
obviously we can combine those last two things pretty much so
once we've been able to build a dam surface
model of of this desktop type scene
why not then turn off
the point baseline system altogether and just about track the position of the camera
by real time alignment
of the images that i'm getting for the camera against the model and we've got
a textured model of the world
i need to know where the camera is so what i need to do is
find the projection of the texture model
agrees as well as possible
with my new
live image
and it's not we don't have to solve them from scratch all the time because
we knew where the cameras and the last frames so it's basically a lucas kanade
optimization still
but now in six-degrees-of-freedom
other than three
so we also made some improvements on the actual reconstruction
part so in this paper that we call detail
which is really released
i to
last year we now not using
the graz optical flow library anymore we have our own
variational u
solver for depth maps which is directly solving for depth maps rather than
trying to
you know fit optical flow into depth map estimation
but then we now doing tracking the camera against this
holden's dense model
so here's an example so here festival which is showing
building a model of the scene
so it's building several depthmaps
basically just sticking those depthmaps
next to each other
to make a reconstruction and the whole scene
so you can see this is you know the speed that actually
runs out you can see how fast it's able to build the reconstruction
and now we can show how how tracking works
this is a kind of per pixel
demonstration of
so so we were optimizing for the position of the camera
by minimizing the difference between
the re-projected model
and the live image
there's a gating built into that's as well so if the difference is too big
add any particular pixel we throw pixel it's not used in your optimization so that's
what the yellow areas are
here the regions been gated out so for instance if there's something including
and now he we have a head-to-head comparison of the quality of tracking
we can now get soapy term on the right the points-based system which is actually
very very good software very very highly optimized
and now we can test if a really really fast motion
the quality of tracking is displayed by this
augmented car
but the tracking is good it should stay
in the same place
the tracking is not so good you should see it
what around so we can cope with rapid motion shaking
and even more remarkably we can
just just for the hell of it we try defocusing
the camera here
so all of the point features that peter using get wiped out but i don't know it still
tracking pretty well because
you know that's methods which is just subtracting all the images in the pixels in an image
i can still give you something pretty sensible at
and the essentially the asian situation that you have
first order interaction second order interaction fair order interactions and so on and if you
is not modelling the right
interaction order you are incorporating minds
and so in this framework in a decision tree interactions into the model
through the path from the root to a terminal
so if you have j terminal node tree you come interactions orders
interactions of order up to JIS
so by
building and symbols of trees where you can control
j you can control the interaction order if you're approximation and that becomes another case
what is problem dependent
and so on
i'm going to speak to that
jenni murray and i think this is the
this is going to final slide here a gradient most in slash marks
a again when that those papers were that of worth reading was not choosing the
coefficients in a separate step
and so then what the recipe where we're calling it the importance sampling recipe which
calls for this step was not being user however boosting is still understood as an
incremental forward stagewise regression procedure with lasso penalty with this shrinkage controlled by absolute so
not dissimilarity
between the four starting regulation that we saw
a few slides back
as an approximation to the last so and the forward stagewise algorithm by which we
then simple here
and so
this is a comparison so the this this is what we had before so bagging
random forests on on the same hundred
problems and improvements and so here we are at
what i call
so we have marked
so much
we call them sequentially so because it is in the sequential approximation
that's that's what they secured stands for the sequential approximation where
and and so on
this is so marked is equivalent to using the sequential approximation with absolute equal to
point one and it i equal to fifty percent
so i
i guess this p should be there if i'm correct
because mark that's in the post processing and there's this uses the same the same
as smaller gaps along but i
but few data so this these two parameters has a one increases the diversity so
you have to control it by
for using the what we've both processes that we call this symbols back in the
forties and this iterative parallel again because since each day doesn't depend on the others
you can go on but i said but we call this equation once again so
you cannot take
each tree depends on what you don't have to appoint so
this equation while so this is an i
seems to outperform the parallel ones and this is consistent with response in a monte
carlo integration where you the group importance as opposed to the single point important
what do we do now
finally to begin
if we look
if we look at this
previously this is truly extraordinary
you see the improve the news
further generalisations of
the ensemble idea
it is similar to the improvement you
from the single
to the
using ensembles in the first place so if you
remember we're hitting the hitting wall here with how well
we can do
with various types of sampling and now there's a further breakthrough
so this is really exciting time
so i'm going to do a little bit about rule ensembles but
for the sake of those of us who think visually i want to show a
little bit from
the appendix first
o holy
boosting idea
i remember one of the ways that we
it's going to look at
one of the was six
and exploit that
let's look at an example
the simple problem that shows the
now it was talking to
july ran through the
versus the template things are very valuable thing to do
but let's give a little bit of detail back again to the algorithm will visualization
because we're very different things here one of which is the weights we ignore some
cases are double some cases and others the algorithm will either
don't look at all the variables
or look at all the variables and then
and the loss function and so forth but one of the ways to very weights
in a real way rather than individual way as you do with it
with bootstrapping the although the case where role integers but you could very them according
to performance which cases you need to do better and so the idea of boosting
mister here's two class problem or trying to estimate is a versus non eg if
you will is trees which are
poorly suited to curb curving decision boundaries
so if it data with the tree and we get the best sort of to
sketch approximation they can give a certain amount of complexity for the two classes
well the idea there is to know which cases are causing this problem will start
banging first of all we take a subset of the state and for more trees
have average them together so near one hundred trees averaged together you get
this blurred boundaries the white part is the part of the trees disagree new so
the threshold would draw
the more complex square around there
on the other hand
fits street to the data and then weights the cases that are causing the problem
so the cases that are on the boundaries they're misclassified gives more weight especially if
rare amongst those that are misclassified as opposed and down weights
the case you're getting correct
and then it seems that all
one page and not even one page that on large variance terminal but one page
it's on this tiny little projector screen this is the whole thing
actually the little bit i had utility file that has this
you some utility for about basic probability
this is the way to split up
the segmentation into all possible splits the probability of the word is just a sequence
of words just the product of the individual words probabilities and segmentation is just repeating
this recursive idea of the best segmentation and then you realize it
to get the dynamic programming
so very simple approach
how well does it do
what happened at one point seven billion words hanging around on my laptop was trying
to do this seriously ever taken from a larger corpus
but one point seven billion was fine
and i actually the test case for myself like ninety eight percent word accuracy there
are some errors
this one can you guys segment that
well i got
base rate sought to initiative in base rate sought so both pretty good
segmentations i have choose the wrong one
this one
i got small and in
significant when it should have been small and insignificant so this is the case where
knowing some semantics would have helped or
just knowing some probabilities over multiple word sequences rather than just one word at a
here's another one this one's harder
news segment that
i got g in or mouse go
but it should have been generously go so this was an example where i want
to have an out of vocabulary words out of all one point seven billion words
i'd never seen j enormous before
and that's kind of the hard part is making these models for what to do
to smooth when you haven't seen words before
my trivial program didn't do a good job of smoothing so
we got the right
and this stuff really matters so obviously matters in chinese and other languages like that
we wanted segmentation right on the web there's also segmentation problems people type in queries
and they get them wrong they leave out spaces they put an extra spaces and
we want to fix it for them and of course people right URL's without spaces
in them
and we want to recognise that get them right
and people have made mistakes both in recognizing these and i claim that webmasters have
made mistakes in the URL the register and so i applied my algorithm two
some of these possible URL's
here's one
so that's the course who represents great site where you can see which hollywood stars
are represented by which agents and of course that was the only possible
segmentation right there
released that's the best segmentation algorithm who would have thought of another possible segmentation
here's a therapist finder you can find somebody for therapeutic all means
nobody could have segments that ran theories expertsexchange
where you can hire an expert
and not get any kind of medical advice
i used want go wrong
ten ireland purveyor of fine writing implements
my little test test bed tormented air their expected ten i but i actually got
was cut off
should i don't know what i actually got but it's it's obviously i got something
that has a which contains the word with high probability among about one point seven
billion record
and one more example
purveyor of fine art art supplies
the predictions would be that if these are on different chromosomes he would get twenty
five percent twenty five percent
twenty five percent twenty five percent
if they're on the same chromosome under very simple interpretation of the chromosomal theory of
inheritance he would get fifty fifty fifty zero zero
and in fact what you get
nine hundred sixty five
nine hundred forty four
two hundred six
and one hundred eighty five
what do you make
which which theory is confirmed
maybe this is just the statistical fluctuation around the first line
i don't think so
how come
one way to while but these are wild type so maybe
what do you think those numbers too far off quarter quarter quarter be believable
much relation between us
i mean
not only are they are the way of quarter quarter quarter quartered something is fishy
the two parental types are much higher than the two non parental types
that saying something to you
interesting what about this other one fifty fifty zero zero can this be fluctuation one
now this one is really pretty easy to reject because zero this is not like
close to zero there should be zero shouldn't see any of those right because they
go and if they are on the same chromosome so when you were acting like
mendel good we're seeing something funny in the data here you even see saw something
that is beyond just it's a little weird but it's actually a little weird some
interesting direction
how many of them are the parental type
that's my sixty five assigned forty four how many of the non frontal type
nice to o six plus one eighty five so let's figure out what the proportion
the frequency
of non parental types
well it's r two o six
close one eighty five
over two o six plus one eighty five plus nine sixty five
plus nine forty four
which is
seventeen percent
OK so seventeen percent
we now know what the answer is
when you take two traits
and you cross them in this fashion two recessive traits do it just cross
the racial neither be accorded quartet quarter or
it's not going to be one and a half i have zero zero
in fact
it will always be seventeen percent
what went out
i the look is data set three to one it's trying to say three to
one is trying to say seventeen percent
how well
so that's the thing is is what to make of this number what is the
seventeen percent me
that was she well known
but this is genetic recombination
right you know
these chromosomes are strange material i can kid about that but i put yourself in
the days of thomas hunt morgan looking at these data trying to figure out what
is the seventeen percent trying to tell
there were people around colombia and elsewhere who were saying all the seventeen percent number
says a lot about physiology to statement about the rule developmental relationship of genes and
were trying to read all sorts of things into these numbers and the first thing
is that test more pairs of traits
how about another pair
you do that you get seventeen percent
now it is that get a person to do it with another pair maybe at
nine percent
so it's not a constant we can reject the idea of seventeen percent is some
constant like e or whatever pir something like that but we
we look at these numbers and a lot of folks wanted to interpret these is
it was something about the biology
of these traits
so are
i think we get this thing named the frequency of non parental types we can
call this the recombination rate because we got new combinations
i this recombination rate might mean and i and you know already that you're thinking
what it really means is
we have black
and the f one
we have
this stage all
this the job
and that somehow
these two chromosomes have exchanged genetic material
so that the new chromosome you'd get
is like this and you get combatant type
you get recombination between these crimes
and there's recombination rate
and the recombination rate is how often this kind of exchange occurs
and what the recombination rate depend on
the distance between those two genes
you know this because you've been told this since kindergarten right to know all the
high school textbooks and things like that are summed or whenever they start they teach
genetics earlier earlier these days so it any edits in it's on TV and stuff
that's a nice idea that the recombination rate depends on the distance and this rate
which might be seventeen percent or it might be one percent or it might be
a centre knows what depends on the distance is a reflection of the distance
golly what's the evidence for that
are we just making up the theory to explain the data here
we don't have a theory to we were just trying to fix the chromosomal theory
chromosomal theory would predict these are common types it would have predicted we only get
parental types out so because we do get pregnant parental types that we say well
chromosomes are promiscuous and the parts
because we don't always get the same ratio
we have to make up the fact that somehow
the ratio is different because of something distance
we can observe this is no way that morgan was able look at the chromosome
and see where the genes one so
basically any number you want to give up
just say it's the distance
this is not overwhelming
that's what even the evidence to chromosomes exchange material
why do what we think stuff like that happens
turns out you can take
fruit fly again meets another things and look at the microscope what you do is
to look at them closely the chromosomes during meiosis you put covers labotomy squashing down
a little dying you look
and it turns out that really truly
when you look in the microscope
you can see stuff like that
of chromosomes lying on top of each other i
these are called high as marked
hi as much or the world kind smart
you can see microsoft so does that convincingly demonstrates recombination occurs
obviously a there is difference
many years ago
this yes of problems
and that is
two things one
but i like to start with a little puzzle
so the interface
we lose contact have something to do with this
just came with me
i believe that this part of the and this is actually a problem that's a
thousand years old i guess
well exactly to do the
sometimes in nineteen within the monthly as an element we call them
and a problem with stick
it's one hundred something as well
and smartmoney
they placed randomly
they are signed to action and they start moving
when they reach the end of this state
the question is
moving the weight of a one
a set per sec
how long will it take them to the
this is a very old it's a very simple answer
some the answer is obvious by the way for
you the answer right away and the answer to my hundred
and reason is very simple thing about it is the ants are in race
in each one of them holding the stick and went to meet they just change
it back
that means that the battens always moving the same direction
and they move the rate of oxygen per second
and all
one hundred second all of the time in the hundred and one is just
is not significant the
OK so i came up with an alternative form
and i call it this
on the seventh of is as follows we come from the pacific northwest with the
seminole warriors they get
born in distance between the go you'd sort of the ocean and then back to
the later they were born the
so i came up with this level of and like this suggestion of the
and here is the same thing you start with the bottom sediments
at their first place and they start moving in
and random direction at a constant
when they told me they change direction
and windows seven returns to its eyes were just these guys
so it was clear examples
the city of
the the question is actually two questions
made by way
the label
and really is
is it true that always the second in the design and are in they will
tell us what will be the last survivor
just one
if two of them collide birthplace of one of them
then that takes precedence
so by comes from
OK i know i want
and you go on to the
OK thank you for the invitation with the opportunity to to come to the city
i like first of all
express want to dedicate longer going well my
meant for source of inspiration
in france
this switch on the basis of terms what this
question why some problems become popular in
why other problems like the one on the shelf nobody touches them
and i will provide sample of fundamental problems
eventually you will get a good definition what the mean environmental problems
and here is
several of them
the first one is the obvious distance well
the second i call it a white newspaper chopsticks
we can actually hope to recover something
that's in the network OK
the phase
maybe rather small
depending on the network and all
speak about
how this transition point here moves
possibly to the left of the properties of the network changed
OK in opera enough ask
what is the computer during OK so
what we have this transition and
we tried to pose this problem
so that it would be
independent of any algorithms
that's why we say OK we have equal sized groups
the the the whole thing is parameterized only by essentially the probability that links lie
between groups versus light within
well they could before that before they could be five
pardon me
that that's that's very true i show an example of forward support
to make its
independent of an algorithm
we said OK what we give to the to
their potential
computer is we give the number of
we give their respective sizes so
we have to find essentially a partition
it corresponds to what you already know is in the network but we don't tell
you the parameters of the partition
so we don't tell you what's the probability for link to be inside or to
the outside but everything else you're given
and what it does is it transforms the problem of
well you'll find clustering problem into well-defined partitioning problem
because i tell you what is the size of the partition
and you're supposed and the only strategy that you can now have is to look
for maximally separated clusters right
i give you the network to tell you
the sizes of the partitions and the only thing you can sensibly do is
try to find the partition that minimizes the number of links
run between the different parts
as if you want to do that
you would miss the trivial cases
then what you optimize is
this cost function here it's very easy to understand
you go over all the links
you signed
of inference now sigma i to each other
and when the link runs between two nodes which are in the same
in the same group that gives you
one of the two
but this is zero when you account
the sorry should have probably minus one here
what you do is you can all the adjusted rand between nodes in different groups
right so
this is the cutsize as it threatened sure
and you try to minimize that
and the way to minimize it you change the labels assign to the no
change inference there
so how many possibilities you have
to assign inference one principle
you have to search among all the
and over two
possible assignments into two equal sized groups for or
trivial case here
and if you find the minimum of that then this is probably a bayesian
maximum aposteriori optimal estimator
we you should know is that
for a given p in
the eyes that you know
linearly dependent on this incipient is one then you cats zero and in is one
cutsize is just one quarter of all the edges essentially
so this is the problem is defined
the nice thing is that statistical mechanics allows us
to give expectation values
one these quantities here for the cutsize has for this ensemble of networks and we
have defined
about that
we actually able
to calculate
the probability that a given that particular node has
assign labels to design custom made
what is the probability that we will theory
in group sigma
so essentially
well we study is what is the overlap
of the configuration the assignment of labels
that minimizes the cat's eyes
the assignment
of pre assigncluster so we put in place
in statistical mechanics allows us to do that rigorously
and then the accuracy show plots
there's nothing more
then the sum over correctly assign notes
so you just go over all those and ask what
just count how many get
is that
but that's OK
now i
why do we have this kind of transition
and the reason
is to be solved in this picture here what this shows is
a cartoon image so to say of the landscape of cutsizes versus configurations
so here you have to imagine
all the
and half the and possible assignments of inferred labels
and they all the outside
and then one of these configurations in particular the one year
that's our designed configuration is like the true things that we want to infer
if we're down here
is not completely stupid is not completely we baseline it just doesn't quite know
how to analyse the which is what the demonstration tells you that there is
i see it works as well so we so as in we
we were i mean for about a month physico you know try to hand to
what functions and that actually does not work and it was afterwards i had to
for a long time it actually didn't work so a couple of albums and that
actually was what made the difference we were not able to figure what function
so that all the
reward function was which trust the vote
the dynamics of the expression problem
politics for right i think you know a state-of-the-art on it's city the theoretical answer
to how to do exploration in reinforcement learning is given by the two thousand as
well as many other theories like dr max algorithm shankar they don't have their own
variations of number of people worked on the follower
but how peaceful the theorem eight theoretical answer given by humans the following
let's have the a whole culture and i want to build a good dynamical model
from helicopter
there were explores as follows my helicopter starts of on the ground i'm going to
ask myself to i have a good model of the dynamics of i am i
happy with the dynamic model of helicopter
if the answer is yes
then i'm going exploit that maximize reward function going offline and i give improved that
doesn't work well if you if if you exploit
the answer is no if you do not have good outcome although what you do
is you explore what you what that means is you aggressively drive the robot to
the edges of the export state space to try to deliberately visited states that you
do not have good models for travellers to visit states in the end you find
on the
on one consisting shows remarkable result with MO's polynomial number of iterations through the cycle
you will then a good model and you can exploit you've near behavior
o more than the state transition probabilities says piece of the
the station's about these
so the show a video of of us doing exploration on the helicopter does actually
issued prior to find the helicopter but this is our our execution of this exploration
process of aggressive driving helicopter to the edges the of low so they can model
four dynamics the whole
you see here the human pilots jerking control stick aggressively fought back was many camera
that they write about their
it's when the roads had blows up and the helicopter crashes
and so
on many systems i think aggressively exploring is this is not a good idea and
you know
caching a polynomial number of helicopters
OK running with the theme of apprenticeship learning this sends out turns out to prove
the following result which is that they can get the human expert pilot to demonstrate
the top demonstrate you would like to use it just five helicopter normally no no
exploring on one the state action sequence fetuses data and to learn the model the
the dynamics of the stations are
well i think the model
reward function which assumes given feed into enforcing learning our and just fine and exploitation
policy pi and they're willing to take exploitation policy pi and use that to find
seven also sells i'll be satisfied with this on behavior is a result of control
good enough and if the answer is yes they are done and the answer is
then we take the autonomous behavior we love the state action sequence feed that back
is as additional data which is the
dynamics model
and it keeps the second from this