so this morning we looked at
maximum likelihood
and we look at the algorithm for maximizing the likelihood function
what i want to do
in this
lecture is married to look at the bayesian approach
and talk about variational inference in the context of
bayesian learning
so in the bayesian
framework we introduce prior distributions over the parameters
much of the discussion will be very general
but i will again illustrates
the idea is simple examples including things like the gas in mixture model
so that's
all OK with everybody is a new feature
we're doing user studies at the moment to see
so we introduce prior distributions over all the parameters
and so this is just
this can be represented graphically
by simply adding extra nodes to the graph representing these prior distributions
so have an expander graph so learning in a bayesian setting of course corresponds to
finding posterior distributions over parameters and then using the posterior distributions to make predictions for
test points
because this is an expander graph learning is really just inference
learning just inference on this expander graph
so we have this rather nice
results that
learning in a bayesian setting is just just an inference problem again
and in particular there is no fundamental distinction between
the latent variables hidden variables
and parameters
in one sense is a sort of the distinction if we have a whole set
of data points we have one latent variable per data point may be a shared
parameter so in that sense the distinction between
latent variables and parameters
fundamentally in this framework there is no
different they just
variables stochastic variables in some big complicated graph
and we're going to observe some of the variables that sort of data
and then what do inference two
find posterior distributions of other variables which countries trying to predict
so for example we can take the mixture of gaussians model and we can make
it a bayesian model
so this is the structure that we had before
these are the observations
capital and for each observation each of the
data vector
it's a binary hidden
variable z which is the indicator variable
yes which component generated each of the
data points
the prior distribution of z is governed by some mixing coefficients
and so we can put a prior distribution
of those shown by this notion
and this is the guassian so we have a conjugate prior
over the mean
and the precision of the gas in
so conjugacy in this model
so p of pi
just to dirichlet which is
products of k
i k and is usually written alpha k minus one
the summer
normalisation constant at the front and you can see that conjugate because
recall p of x given pi
it was the product of k
pike k to the set k
so when we multiply this by this
the posterior distribution of the pilot can be high
raised to some power
alpha tilde minus one
the posterior distribution has the same form as the prior
we can similarly write down the
prior distribution for the mean
and precision which is the inverse covariance
of the gaussians
and that's the thing called the normal wishart
so we have the prior
on lambda
which is the wishart distribution
w is governed by matrix and the parameter that is essentially
so exact form is something like the
well both the trace
of lambda
and some matrix which you can write w inverse w is the matrix
the parameters of the distribution
and again you can see the controversy structure because the
in the gas in the exponential
of the trace of lambda times something with the something is x minus mu x
minus neutron stars
and then he is
new prior to me depends on lambda in order to have a conjugacy
and this is the normal distribution
which is
has some means
but it's
variants are precision rather
it is
proportional to
b so my notation is this is the means the covariance
so the
inverse covariance the precision to the precision of this prior is proportional to the precision
of the original gaston lambda
so again it's sort of an exercise five minutes associated paper to verify that the
product of these is the joint distribution of immune lambda
is the conjugate prior for the gas in
is an intuitionist why depends on lambda i don't have an intuition but if you
look through them as you can see that it's a few minutes with sheet of
paper just to work through and see that it does
i have an intuition for that
i don't have an institution five one by tomorrow morning i'll let you know
any other questions and place the very place of questions by the way
OK so
we've got we've put priors all the parameters so the know what bayesian mixture of
we're interested in doing things like finding
posterior distributions of these parameters for example
or in
proof and proof theory
we had to to do it
what know
consequences of structure
and it isn't something that you see
well know people we will see an influx
i have been discussing
classification of course it is
ten amount of schools really be verified by machine
i'm not going into that argument is an important argument
i mean discussion there
i was showing how
working through the proof
but the assumptions out
you know those versions of
to improve several
of the things that's been created by ideas
professor of logic at the ohio state university
he very much concerned with
five out of liverpool's
and he relates common problems somewhat similar to ramsey's theorem about configurations it says if
you have a configuration with certain properties and you can find a set configuration with
some of the properties but are complicated and then use
and you have these combinatorial principles
to prove the consistency of axiomatic theory
so he discovered that you can understand what it is
i just copied this stuff in here
from the FOM was
but this time
comment property about finite
so he says that there
proposition that these kind of
have a nice property
is equivalent
two that consistency
and set theory
assumptions about
but transform icon
so not only are those
simple finite combinatorial principles not by the usual methods that theory
if you try to have a proof of it you to prove the consistency of
most assumption about
well what
the problem is that
he has been able to convince applications that they want to know the answer to
this combinatorial well
and this is all kinds of users
many books written about him
applications and people really like
unfortunately personal haven't caught the imagination of mathematicians
he's working on that all the time
it could very well come out
five combinatorial principle can be applied to solve problems but then you say
oh gosh
the proof that requires
something is wrong is the consistency of like microbial numbers
o point was to see him do that
i'm going to skip ahead in the
on account of time here i have some comments on
approaches to
plus you mathematics
he is a very fine author on
our philosophy mathematics she written two books realism in mathematics
and i want to call bachelors in mathematics
she discusses many issues that she is a professor at the
campus of university of california
and i recommend writing
she's been taking
as a point of view
development from
o forty three of
naturalized epistemology
and so that's really what about but she does have
because it's a it's hard to explain
what naturalism is
we understand by doing it
you can list
the point of view the
discusses naturalism and other issues in philosophy of science is by our
ryan giggs
i thought it was interesting book too
points from the
the development
all the reviews of logical empiricism period
empiricism THE internationalism
question of explaining rationality or
o point four per
and so
it still needs to be more thought and discussion many people in this area
four to six years
structuralism and one reason i
put the picture in this that such an alarming picture
unable to
so stewardship should is written for a long time on
the structure of point of view
we understand abstract mathematical
are concepts
in the vector space model between the document and query right would just be fixed
but perhaps you know it's useful to have to not commit to particular function but
rather to parametrized by some
parameter w let's say in and for instance restricted to linear functions of that type
so we might extract certain features from the document and the query let's say we
have the dimension of feature representation and then we have some linear function and the
feature representation can the idea being you know these weights they might capture all kinds
of tuning parameters that you have for your search engines like you might have all
kinds of knots and and parameters and you can optimize
OK and so the idea is now we can maybe optimise
the wolf also known as the retrieval status value or you know this is ranking
function based on click-through data
OK so what could these what these features b
so in the way they should describe how good a match
we have between the document and query
now in a
setting for instance where we have a bunch of
retrieval systems available or ranking systems available this is this is also known as metasearch
right say we have several retrieval system and we want to combine the results somehow
from these different search engines
then you know these are a couple of features we can look at some in
the first of all they are the ones that really depend directly on the content
we could say you know the feature could could just be the number of words
shared by the query and the document
we could say
we get restricted to certain HTML tags like title or something like that we could
take the cosine between the query and the document all the document title of the
document abstract that would be what we do in the vector space model like could
just make the future and then if we take away vector to be one for
the future and zero elsewhere then we would just get the vector space model
right so we have the vector space model building there is one option we could
also say well look you know we compute the page rank of a document that
should also somehow be factored in higher page rank meaning it should be better and
we can also say well we have other search engines and they produce
you know a list and for instance we could say you know that
the rank of a document with respect to that query when using that search engine
is in the whatever top five ten fifty and so on and so forth OK
would mean we run the query to google and then we checked whether the document
shows up in the top five ten fifty and so on and so forth and
we make the boolean features
OK and it could also you could also imagine features that have to do with
the properties of the URL in a web setting right the length of the URL
or whether it's the EDU domain domain or what have you
OK so we control these features in there
and now we take the pairwise constraints i mean we look at our click-through data
and as we said we would interpret interpreted as the pairwise constrained and in the
following sense that what we want is if d is preferred over DC prime with
respect to q OK so this was the link
showing up later in the ordering that was clicked on where that was not clicked
on OK so this is the should here
then we want that
this function assigns the higher value to d comic you've entered the prime comic you
OK because you know he was preferred over the prime
with respect to that query
OK so in the linear case
right we set this function f should be of the form
w common and then some five become q and of course you know and we
can we can pull these two we can pull them inside here in the inner
product and that's what we would get
now what we can do is
basically apply again the large margin idea from support vector machines
by requiring not only that this is actually greater equal to greater than zero
as of here
but by requiring that we actually
do this you know including a certain margin we can just fix to be one
here is just a function of margin right so we said we would like
that difference between these two f functions to be at least one
and if we if we can make that we might introduce like a soft margin
constraint here with the slack variable
that some of the prime got lost here you know that depends on this q
dt prime
right so for every click click through triple that we have
we have a constraint we introduce available like that
OK i'm not sure why this is this should be here
so and so
and then you know we could basically
an objective function like that right so we require that the norm of the weight
vector is small
and then also we penalize violations of the margin constraint
so it's really
you know if you think about
binary classification and it's really you know usually you would just have five some exciting
here right and then y in front of their fine you could pull the signing
you have something like why i times you know five x
x sort of some sort and you can see that that's the same role is
now played by these differences so then there's the question you know what can we
actually do with that
you know the the ideas well the click-through data is is is probably too weak
to do
to do any good with immediately helping users with the information need right so we
might not want to use it perhaps in a way that we improve the actual
results for the query but rather we think of it that is the whole population
of users and that we have a system that self tunes itself
to the user population and tries to improve its performance automatically
so you know and you could also improved
optimize the system with relative to
you know the whole population but also the relative to specific user groups that say
you know you have users coming from finland was somewhere right in your search engine
and you might want to adapt your
ranking function somehow to everyone comes from finland or some other country right because you
feel that there might be some you know just specific things that people infinite interested
in that other people are not interested in and basically you know you could imagine
doing these types of things
you know or you could even think of actually personalized ranking functions for individual users
but there's the question of whether you will have enough data to really do that
and in particular the you know what you what you can also use this for
is four of course metasearch engine combining different search engine results
OK can use some some results from pollster in paper
a learning problem
so i think some generic learning problem just so for instance a bunch of images
and we want to learn a rule to distinguish men from women
OK i don't know anything about your other than when i learned yesterday
a four
i'm just using images as kind of an example of someone could be chairs from
tables were decided to make some distinctions and where we have a kind of of
problem where a particular problem or natural representation
our natural feature space is not great for us like we represent images by pixels
it's not clear you want a weighting of the pixels is a good way to
have a rule distinguished
so one given that kind of situation a powerful technique for these sort things is
to use a kernel function
and so using kernel functions kernel functions kind of pairwise similarity function it takes into
in this case it
the program ran anyway taken into objects does some computational and outputs and
OK so it's the kernel function is a special kind of pairwise similarity function takes
into objects the number
often in practice when you're thinking about what kind of kernel you want to use
the thinking of one that will act as a good measure of similarity
between objects for the type of learning problem
there's a nice very nice theory of kernels that talks in terms of viewing these
implicit mappings
and what i want to talk about is
do we kind of need is here so we have a very nice theory talking
about them in terms of implicit mappings but can we developed some alternative ways of
thinking about kernels that just view them as measures of similarity and so the the
the motivation here
it is
if we can have a theory that talks about them just measure similarity then given
learning problem perhaps that might help in trying to choose to design a good kernel
function for the learning problem
in addition the standard theory of kernels which requires them to have certain mathematical properties
of positive semi definiteness perhaps perhaps we can we can we don't need that perhaps
we can just think of similarity without needing extra mathematical problem
in the second question look at the we only have unlabeled data
we have no labeled data at all just a bunch of objects is a kind
of clustering setting our job is to cluster its objects some good way
so can we develop also theory of
properties a similarity function would have that allows to cluster well presumably would need stronger
property that is if we want to do well without any labelled data at all
we had some
so we need stronger properties in that case for this
OK and this will be kind of like a PAC model for clustering effect that
model means something you
so starting with OK so kernel functions you guys have seen kernel functions this is
purely quick into the kernel functions so back to our generic classification problem
we give a some of images are labeled by gender one learning new rule distinguish
men from women
we want to do well on new data
i mean the problem we're having is that there are many more advanced algorithms learning
linear separators
OK great albums when separator by the natural representation maybe there isn't it good yourself
OK maybe instead looks like this and there is some other function that separates the
positive and negative but nonlinear
so consider kernels so it was a classical approach to i get the machine learning
with people use neural network
more complicated functions problem is there kind of
difficult to train everything is not so easy to deal with incidents of model approaches
using a kernel function the lightest kaluza a linear separator algorithm but
apply in cases where the separating
surfaces knowledge
so so what's the kernel
OK so kernel one particular mathematically the legal definition of dot product the function
pairwise function
x two objects but some implicit mapping phi
you can view k f x y x five x five y
this is a similarity function to pairwise function that has some implicit mappings even though
we don't need to actually
how does this have to exist we don't you have to have a very
she has also encouraged to this project
so just to give an example
x and y were actually point some n dimensional space and taking XLI plus one
would be illegal kernel corresponds to
an implicit mapping in which these and dimensional points are taken to and in the
d dimensional space that could be very high that we have
we're not actually explicitly going to be we're just doing this simple computation
the so having so positive semi definite just as the math is just a way
of saying that these
five exist
it's just a legal definition
and the point is that many learning algorithms can be written so the only way
this the other day that is by taking dot products
svm perceptron
very tolerant and they can be
maybe in the naturally would view them you would actually do something directly data but
you can write them in the way
that's the only access they
after data is dot product so they say please ended up to these examples we
not be as you with a look at their data if you're out the mille
lacs indians stated by taking dot products if every time and after the dot product
of two examples x y
you replace it with the kernel computation then this algorithm is acting as if data
was living in the phi space right so if people in in the dot product
and that
of an independent you know the right number of independent possible and should be or
is an orthonormal i vectors
i just leave that opposed
and i i can that's where the in some paper the answer doesn't appear but
i retro series of papers
on this topic and they all have a sort of
shot at
but now we're really satisfactory so there you go i mean if if legal that
comes up with a good description of the eigen vectors will be
or you will be deservedly famous OK
so that's a digression
and this
because it's not the eigenvectors it's the inverse that we really want OK
so how could matrix b easy to invert
let's put let's put this square then and for the present
as as i've done now
OK so how can it be easy to invert
well actually one way here is to say well what does that tell you about
the inverse of f
that's killed right
the inverse of f is f q but we don't want to do with the
we really want to see that the inverse of f
so here's the main point that the inverse of a
it the
complex country
course at the so that symbol
by that symbol i mean replace i by minus i every time you see it
so that
so that its entries the entries are
the complex conjugate
of these
so it's and reason i'm putting in this would and now
the complex conjugate of those which is w larger the j k
take on tickets
can i just be sure on this picture that i know where w boris
the words w bar the conjugate of w and its powers
in the
in the complex plane are they on the unit circle
for sure they reflected the x axis exactly so this will be w bar right
it will be either minus
two pi i over eight
so we have the same as w to the
n minus one but
w bars much cleaner OK
all right now why
why social and claiming that
the point is that is
well so i'm claiming is that i guess i'm just claiming that
our times that gives me either right that's
that's it's just this
it's just as simple as that
i just
i have to check that f bar
if i take this matrix and
it will be more familiar
they have f part transport
with added symmetric so we really do have for transfer
so so i copied transpose up here was going to say in like letters but
if i do it and you know it to be
transpose has no effect because the matrix is symmetric but but what kind of matrices
have this world we have a name for matrices like this where you take a
matrix f and you take what's a matrix for which f transpose f
is is the identity
unitarians the words we use
especially when the matrix is
we use the word orthogonal matrix and certainly have in this course
the real case
we could stretch that word but it's
better to use the word unitarian that societies signal to the mind that
complex numbers are in there and you're not only
it's not it's not have transpose f the complex case as always you
one of the factors should be conjugated that's just
the fact of life in in fact of complex life because its conjugate one of
the factors
to have the
a proper analogy with the real
and not just just tell me what identity is so
what if i write that out what what does that tell me
let me multiply
let's take a typical roadside take
all together diagonal
yes but how why do i get zero off the diagonal
so the two questions why do i get one on the diagonal
and that is should be not too are so like list let's do on the
diagonal suppose i take this guy with this one
o but what is conjugated so on the diagonal
so it was on the diagonal is taken typical case
one times one
w times w bar
once you've defined
a graph kernel
you can use the whole family of kernel methods
which is a huge
of machine learning algorithms for data analysis on graphs you can do graph classification graph
feature selection graphs two sample tests on graphs just to name a few examples all
things that are
intermediate steps
in the other things that XiFeng presented in the first half of the tutorial
so is
this concept of a graph kernel the solution to the problem of graph comparison
one of the first papers
on graph kernels
this question by a clear no
this was a paper by
flasch and wrobel in two thousand three
they showed
computing a complete graph kernel is at least as hard as deciding
whether two graphs are isomorphic
what is a complete graph kernel
graph kernel k is complete if its corresponding map phi is injective so if two graphs
are not isomorphic phi
will map them
to different points in feature space that's the meaning
of compete
graph cut
and what can i show
is the following
if phi is injective
the distance of G and G prime
in feature space
that is zero if and only if
g and  g prime are isomorphic
to each other
but the fact
whether the distance between these two graphs in feature space
is zero can be
established by computing three common values
namely these
we can use up here the square root
of this term which consists of three
common values so computing the common value is here equivalent to finding a solution to
the graph isomorphism problem that's why it's at least as hard
it's deciding whether two graphs are isomorphic
so this was bad news
in the beginning
for graph cuts
but people came out
this alternatives to
to complete
graph kernels. they studied
graph kernels which looked
certain classes of substructures
of the graph
and the first one
was the class of walks
in the given graph this work by
because she man
you could see
so the
by gardner et al in the same year two thousand three i think one of
these original authors is actually in the audience
could you do this in the audience
and they all came up
this idea of of measuring similarity
between two graphs g and g prime by counting common walks
in these two
two graphs
and walks here just to be precise are sequences of nodes that allow for repetitions
of nodes
and get and out
came up with the very
elegant way
of computing this number
of common walks into graphs
by using the following trick
well they
they remembered that you
i can count
the number of walks between two vertices i and j
in a graph
taking the k th power of the adjacency matrix
you get to that the number of waterford evidence k between these two nodes i
and j
if you look up the i j th entry in that
adjacency matrix to the power of K
this was the first trick. the second trick was
work for so-called product graphs
and in particular of the so-called direct product graph of g and g prime
a product graph explain that
by using an example of the next slide
actually let's go
and have a look at the product graph
between two input graph g and g prime
it is constructed by
forming all pairs of nodes
from g
and from g prime
as you can see here we form pairs of
nodes from the first and from the second graph
and these nodes
in the product graph then connected by an edge
if the corresponding nodes in the input graph also connected
by an edge
so for example
there is an edge between one
one prime and two two prime
in the product graph because there is an edge between one and two in g
and between one prime into prime in g prime
so again that i
use this construct
and then they showed that each walk in this direct product graph
corresponds to exactly one walk in g and to exactly one walk in g prime
and then
by counting
the walks
in this product graph
they were able to counter to common walks
in g
and in g prime
and that's formalized in the equation below
as i said
you can get walks of length k by taking the case
power of the adjacency matrix in this case the edges in matrix of the product
and then you need
so called decaying factor lambda why do you need this factor because walks obviously as
I what
from here and then the rows of when I when I look at animated we've
got rows and I multiplied by and what is that with mixes the rose up
and make it creates combination of all the roles of the same rose
that is the
that is better
I can see where leads the coming on the road and communities as combinations of
but column in the interior of the various combinations of the
analysis so that everyone not say OK
what's the
the less know that like the
the column
what is less
1 of the things that I wanted to tell you about what columns and rows
what happened
if I multiply out of this world column again
OK now have fewer problems finding out what was going on on
and of role of the
what might be aware of the problem and the role that definitely different from thinking
was 1 of the state of problem and by the 1 in the following way
is to come back and entries and 1 it and what role the 1
and the
the what's this thing was going the right column
if I multiplied by
I guess this is 1
and columns to 3 4
and role 1 thing
that is the product of the following rule the matrix multiplication of vectors things like
that is the kind of small
because of that the rules your of your that of sort of the same length
1 and so what the what the enterprise to reform and 1 of the press
well what's the 1st row
and the 2nd row growing
and the
actually what that
varies especially the very 1st matrix will be coming out on the columns of the
there are multiple
right multiple that which follows so we said that although the answer were combination but
this is a combination of 1 . from all the rows of the answer what
is going
there are multiples of this
there are multiples of 1 of the as well but I'm getting closer to me
and now this a complete thought if by hand of now that the right of
the water right it is
some of the problems that we have road the good for example if my mind
it was to be more than half of the 79
and matrix here
as they started with 1 thing and then another problem lies own
here we OK but that's the problem there are to roll over there so the
beautiful rule
the thing by columns and rows is that I can think of 1st
so time 1st
and then the 2nd part of the
the lessons were aware that there is a place columns and rows 1st column were
frozen government 2nd row and then actually well I guess what will the answer to
well this 1 is going to be a 0 so in fact I'm back and
that's the end of that kind of thing that I'm I'm certainly happy because 1
of the areas these facts about matrix multiplication within the chance that right down special
this is especially but also rose things
1 of the lighter ones
if I'm not here of all these vectors they're all the same direction
about development
these 2 problems that have same
later on this line
not much we have scenario
road space which is like all the combinations of the road is that align with
the rows the line through the vector of then all the rows of life in
hand column space is also
so as you can see that this is the tool of this is the fundamental
difference between these two method.  likely this method - apriori based approach will generate
a few infrequent graph pattern candidate
however remember this
we have to do this joint operation in some
cases if the number of the k edges
patterns is very large basically you have to do the N square join operation
because it is too huge so in many cases we find that actually
pattern growth approach sometimes even
is faster than a-priori based approach
so this is about the generation of candidate graph patterns
the second main property of
this graph pattern mining algorithm is about the discovery order
so some algorithms adopt free extension method
for example whenever we find out graph pattern we can append a new edge
to any position
in these existing graph pattern this is called the free extensions
for example
suppose we have already discovered this six edge graph pattern
then we can append new edge to any position of the six edge graph pattern
it will generate actually
twenty two new graph
patterns and then we use some sort of isomorphic
routines to test whether this newly generated graph pattern candidates are really frequent or not
so this is the basic idea about free extensions
however we discovered that actually we can put a more structured version
on the extension of the wild patterns we call is the right most extension
suppose we have pattern-ids, so we pick any node
for example this node as a starting node, and then we do a depth first
search tree
so called rightmost path is the path from the starting node
to the end node in this depth first search tree
and do we
required extension can only
take place
on the right most right most parts
as you can see that with this kind of restriction
this graph
pattern can only generate to four
new graph pattern candidates
and we have some proof to show that actually we can still using this method
we can still
exhaust the search trees that means we still can guarantee the completeness of the mining results
so if you compare the right most extension method
and is free extension methods
you will find that
using this method actually can save the generation of a lot of
duplicate  graph particles
OK the third characteristic of all existing graph mining algorithm
is about to the duplicate part elimination suppose we already discovered
graph patterns
and then we find a new pattern - g
then we have to decide whether this new pattern is really new or it is
just a duplicate part
which has already been discovered before
so that's three options to do the checking the first option is OK
let's just do a hard - a head-to-head comparison
we check the graph sub-isomorphism between g
and each graph in g_1 through g_n
this method is slow
the second option is OK we can transform each graph pattern into a canonical label
and then create a hash value for this canonical label then whenever we discover a
new part in g, we can translate it into
canonical label and then we can check whether this canonical label has been
discovered before or not. we can use the hash function to do this
so you can see that this method is much faster
and the third option
which is more automating that we actually build the canonical search order
when we generate these while patterns and we just just generated while patterns is that
by this way, we actually needn't actually check the previous discovered the pattern or not.
because all of these patterns are generated
in set order. this is a faster method we discovered so far in the previous
OK i have discussed a lot about six characteristics of the of the existing graph pattern mining
and mapped it. so let's
show you some performance comparison between this methods so basically you can get some idea
how fast they are
OK so in other words loggers miners
minus the entropy of x
so what this means is the entropy is really telling us the distance from the
uniform distribution
measured according to this
distance measure the KL divergence
and just this this one formula tells us many things for instance it tells us
we know that the KL divergence is always positive
so this tells us that the entropy can never be more than log
this is an upper bound on the entropy
it tells us
that's the maximum entropy distribution we know the most the entropy can be as large
and wednesday the entropy august when we're looking at a uniform distribution over s outcomes
so the distribution that maximizes the entropy is just a uniform distribution over all of
these outcomes
so so many questions about
but this sort
so let's look at one more justification of entropy
and then apply to our problem
so to understand this
maybe there may be the way to say it is that we have a distribution
you take one sample from it so much stochasticity in which output could be
you have if it the distribution of the coins and the coin is biased point
seven five it could be that zero or one you know there's a lot of
randomness and what the output be it's not
so so one way to make it is one way to come to
to reduce the level of stochasticity is to draw many samples
that's when you get a more accurate picture
that's how you reduce the stochasticity in which is
OK i suppose we draw suppose we have a bunch of draws from some distribution
so x one x two xn
i i d draws from some distribution
OK and now we've got a lot of them so we can look at the
sequences that we get
so these are conflicts we just had this sequence is zero zero zero one one
one of several pages long sequences of zeroes and ones
so now let's look at these sequences just put them into two groups
we just because the sequences whose probability is roughly ten to the minus
this according to a distribution and all other sequences
and it turns out that most of the sequences that we observe are going to
have roughly the same probability
this is called the asymptotic equipartition property
so what this is saying is that if you look at the space of all
the sequences that you can possibly generate
OK so in the case of according with say bias
three quarters
this is all to the sequences is the sequence of these these all the sequences
of zeroes and ones j
you can possibly generate
there are just a few of them
that are typical
and these are the sequences whose probability is about
two to the minus and times the entropy of one of those random variables
but in this case the entropy of a coin with
whatever by seven point six o point seven five
he sold aligned space of possible outcomes
there is actually a typical set
and when you draw a large number of sequences
although you know if you need so we need a large number of points although
the distribution of any one point is really stochastic
we've got a large number of points in the other sequences
it's a little bit like a uniform distribution
over about two to the end
so the distribution looks
it's almost like a flat distribution over a smaller set of outcomes
is sensitive to to the and outcomes
two to the end times the entropy
which is going to be at most one in the case of the conflict
so in a sense entropy tells us the volume of the typical set
this typical said
has volume two to the end times entropy
OK so let's look at some examples of this right so for a fair coin
if we draw and if we draw and samples from a fair coin
and we look at the sequences we get well then we just have a uniform
distribution over all possible outcomes
in that case
we just occupied the whole space of all possible outcomes are about equally likely
and each of them has the entropy is one in that case and each of
them has probability
two to the minus and
OK so the nine and the number of outcomes is due to the end
now let's look at what a biased coin
suppose we look at the coin with bias three quarters
in this case we've got a lot of them when you got a lot of
a lot of coins you can find that in the end about three quarters of
them my hands
OK so the typical probability
of the sequence like this is going to be about three quarters
three quarters of r
three quarter and the
of the coin tosses are going to be heads
and the remaining ones are going to be tails
and this is the typical probability most of the sequences will conform to this
and when you look at the log of this
you find that in fact it is minus ten times the entropy of the quarter
this difficult sequence does have probability to to the miners and the
can in that case the typical set is much smaller
the field of that two to the possible outcomes the typical set of size just
two to the end
that's the entropy of all three quarters which is twenty one
so what's the wisest thing true lies this property true
OK so
so we've drawn withdrawn and
samples from some distribution p
these is i i d samples
let's define a new random variable y survive
and this is defined to be logged one of the p of x and y
is a random variable
the way you do it is in the case of coin tosses
you flip a coin
if you look at the outcome heads or tails
it's had its log one over the probability of heads
if it still one of the log with log one of the probability of tails
now one way we defined entropy was just the the expectation of this quantity
i want of
i really don't
she also
see well my talk i didn't take the blame for people that are already sleeping
non-resident good morning you know where michael berthold and one of the
editors of this intelligent data analysis book of constance university and and they're heading the
timeout chair for bioinformatics and information mining interesting i'm trying to give you an overview
of very rough
trick overview in the next two hours over what fuzzy logic is all about
and we approach paul talk about statistical approaches to data analysis
the talks about other approaches this morning it already got a little bit more
well imprecise using neural networks trying to manage what brain like learning in all networks
to build complicated well models hopefully easy models from complicated data sets but today i'm
going to go not doing this to carry on trying to go a little bit
further in the direction of trying to build models that are human understandable interoperable by
humans by using sort of
real world in which OK good so but i'm trying to cover
i'll take to give you the to try to motivate a little bit better fuzzy
logic is all about some of the key concepts that will pop up during this
tutorial are things like degrees of membership and fuzzy sets we'll talk about linguistic values
and variables you'll hopefully know what all this means by the end of today today
we'll talk about operators and fuzzy sets how can we combine sort of imprecise knowledge
in fuzzy implication will then go towards fuzzy rules how can you express
human knowledge in terms of really nice understandable rules how can we deduct these types
of rules from data and then i'll briefly also jump into fuzzy arithmetic can be
know the fuzzy numbers this concept about about twenty five this is something like twenty
five degrees celsius in deal with those addition multiplication normal of the arithmetic operators country
numbers so these sort of the three main things fuzzy logic sort of the basics
fuzzy and fuzzy numbers
but interested in fuzzy concepts this is something that a lot recently from berkeley university
back then he was still columbia he wrote a paper in nineteen sixty five introducing
the concept of fuzzy sets and the idea is to model imprecise concepts such as
age weight height very fast if you if you think i'm actually not going to
ask you to itself if you think that i'm
not young
the may realise that young is the concept that's not that precisely defined
if i'm just barely above thirty which kind of sort of that may not be
young for you anymore but i mean just the fact that somebody turns thirty that
specific day doesn't mean of seventies this is not something is just a little bit
less then sort of he gradually declines to belong to the set so these are
concepts that we use in our everyday language and you can't really formalise them by
saying there's a crisp boundary between them not young people there's just no crisp boundary
that's not how you use it may just the same someone who's fat doesn't mean
that he's his body mass index is above something
this sort of grey zone in between waiting in our kind of sort of a
little bit about on then they of course because what are fat especially if you
travel to america OK this is sort of we are trying to model imprecise concepts
and using these imprecise concept was also nice to model imprecise dependencies things like when
you crank up the heating system it's not something very in the morning you get
up look at the same says twenty four point nine degrees OK i'm not going
to touch the heating system today twenty three yes i don't think this is something
that i feel cold and let's crank it up a little bit so things like
if temperature is low and then maybe you're cheap so for instance don't have money
is a like that just low and oil is cheap then i will crank up
the heating system otherwise i'll rather save the money and go buy myself
the origin of this type of information is usually
comes from either trying to model expert knowledge or trying to represent information extracted from
inherently imprecise it's going to become a little bit clearer throughout the tutorial
OK so about the fuzzy sets try to go back just the findings they chris
set to classical the classical set is one that you described by saying elements belong
to the set of don't but if set elements are in parliament i'm not so
we have something to say about this we can describe it using a characteristic function
the characteristic function essentially says this function for a set a foreign element x this
one is this element belongs to a and it's terrific simple
so a of x is either zero or one and we can draw a little
four datasets
and the a would be all the numbers that are between a and b small
small thing and then you could draw this characteristic function this
just to get the feeling the course the making things way too complicated but in
the middle i want to do that that this function in a from x which
is zero four numbers smaller than a just one
including a and b between a and b and which so again
it's an immediate idea how we could model fuzzy
so this is another government to model something
there is a very trying to
model the concept that this is a tool just but i usually to denote fuzziness
where we want to say this is all the elements that x is roughly in
a b is kind of sort of in a
exactly but some something like that and then we can define this fuzzy set by
using a so-called membership function which is very similar to the characteristic function that we
used to the crisp set but now this function assigns values in the intervals sort
of one so now we also have intermediate degrees of membership
we can look at the characteristic function of membership function in this case here could
look is just an example it said
of introduce cycle where you criticize the model perhaps then if you if it was
found to be wanting you'd extend the model add add additional elaborations of some kind
that perhaps further down the line make some formal comparison between them and so it
it gets formed now in in in Bayesian models one particular and obvious source of
potential conflict or well potencial criticism is there being conflict between the
prior and the data the prior says one thing the data says the other
how we are we going to resolve this you could look at that
in a various ways but another way to think about it is that the observed data that you have
in front of you is actually very unlikely to have occured under the prior model if if
if if nature really was sample from the prior you've assumed than the data probably
wouldn't have come out like that now as I'll show you a picture in a moment the in a
very small model it's very easy to detect that but we are now talking
about building Bayesian models with huge numbers of variables and there are many many different
model factors in that in that big model we've made not just one prior assessment
we made lots of priors assessment about the way different groups of variables influence each
other and there's so there's a potentially is a lot of different model choices that you
may want to criticize now you know we're all in principle we do like
to do this infinitely well right we're always have plenty of time to properly assess
our our distributions and and we we wouldn't of being forced by any kind of numerical
tractability issues into approximately anything at all and so on and it would all be fine but
we know that in reality deadlines you know limited knowledge all sorts of reasons why you
know we cut a few corners and we need ways of checking whether you nknowin wheather
we possibly made any mistakes now this isn't of particularly good example of a complex
models this is not very complex but it already has a few a few features
this is a model whose I'm gonna illustrate a little bit later it's a geographical epidemiology
models so it's a model for analyzing data of the form
of perhaps disease counts over a lot of different spatially distributed areas they
the idea is that perhaps in cases with rare diseases there may
be some covariance perhaps environmental factors something of that kind that are influencing the
pattern of disease they have not been measured so we might be interested in models for
the for the disease incident that have spatial correlation in them so we want to
build a model in which there are random effects that are spatially correlated and then various
other things downstream so you got you got a number of different sets of variables in the model
and you've got quite a few different model terms we've got a model for the
disease counts given random given the random effects we've got the joint distribution of the
spacial random effects and so on so you see a number of different model components there
and they're all into relating and the question is are any of them in conflict okay so model
potentially the the there's a lot of possibility for for conflict in a complex
model I mean how do we disentangle this now when we think about priors
specifications we typically think about middle and spread you know you you you think oh I
think it's about five plus and minus one it's quite a jump from that to
say I think it's five plus and minus one it's got a gamma distribution it to to to
say something about the shape that's valid even into the tails of the distribution I
that that's quite a tall order to expect your scientific judgement to support such a complicated
assessment yet the problem is the posterior inference could really depend on those choices because
it can turn out that the posterior distribution have not just the those
quantities but perhaps many others as well crucially depend on trading off of tails of
the individual model terms so it's very easy and complex model to get into a
situation where the inference can depend strongly on the past of your prior specification that you have
least confidence in and that's an issue and is more of an issue if you can't detect it
so let's try and think about detecting okay well what do people normally do there's a big there's a rich
area of model criticism in Bayesian models that are based loosely around the idea
of Bayesian P values and the way this usually works is something in this
kind these are about quantifying discrepancy between the observed data and the model
the ideas we choose a test statistic and if we're going to  it will would have to be
and so on
this other is actually converges pretty quickly and it's eminently or very practical
as long as the number of variables is
these small
the iterative scaling algorithm starts with an arbitrary constant and compute the probability
for the state
then we accept what
how often the constraint is true
normalizes and repeats
so it's like satisfying constraints
by just saying that can expect constraints lead to enforce it if take another constraint
and continue this
and until all the constraints that
the surprising thing is that
OK so this is exponential in the number of variables
linear in the number of constraints
up to ten to twelve to fifteen it's OK
empirical results
extremely good accuracy
so now other
open problems so inclusion exclusion
and maximum entropy there are two ways of using the frequency of information
find something
more about the underlying distribution
what are the summary statistics
good one computer and frequent sets to get some information about the underlying distribution
i guess
i don't know the answer and i haven't heard anybody to be honest
all right
so the
frequency approach of the frequent pattern approach is that we compute lots of frequent patterns
and their frequencies
so let's now think of how
could we do something and post processing of the
so at the end of the first prime minister that the one can
these on the basis of statistical significance
but i'm not going to talk about that
and i'm going to talk a little bit
about how to or pattern so how to begin
first the patterns that in the most information to the users
so how do we formalize this section
can we want first
finally gives the most information
so that p one the powder
then we can two that is the most information given that the user already has
seen you want
then they came with give pattern pk gives the most information given the user has
seen the minus one
OK what does it mean that
gives most information
useless definition or in the feasible definition of what are
the amount of information in the
so suppose we are given a set of patterns p and every one
if we could compute let's assume that we could compute pi the
an approximation of the joint distribution by
then we can say that the the quality of the
p in this distance
all this approximation given the financing
from the through
he do so we could take l one very long distance or all
four but live or whatever
so you could for example use the maximum entropy method to compute an approximation for
and then compare it against the data
but unfortunately this only works for a very small numbers of area
so what we can do is
instead of looking at how much information do pattern of the underlying distribution
we can replace this we can use as a proxy
how much information the pattern and used as of other factors
for example assume i tell you that the frequency of ABC is ten percent
what does that tell
well it's obviously that that the frequency of ABC is that person
but it also tells you
the frequency of eight
is at least one first
OK the frequency of
something up here to use
partial information about the frequencies of
staff which are so subsets of that
for example we can
if we know
the frequencies of x one xk
then you can approximate frequency of an arbitrary acts by maximum of the frequencies of
those guys
which i so that instead of
so in that way we can test
new frequencies of certain things that are higher up in the
in this subset lattice that does
kind of levelwise method
this leads to a way of approximating but frequencies
in the beginning
everything is approximated as zero
after the x one
after we are told that x one is treatment has this frequency
then all the subsets of x one
their frequency is approximated
there should be x one here
level but how that knowledge itself might be learned
if we want to solve these basic kinds occams razor complexity trade-offs well one elegant
set of ideas that been developed recently coming from bayesian statistics and now taking on
a life of its own in machine learning is what's called nonparametric bayes sometimes infinite
model complexity doesn't have to be set in advance but is in principle infinite
and effectively finite and then just tailored to the retailer just to the to the
needs and capabilities of the data so imagine think about clustering where instead of saying
k means clustering fixing came advance you let k be infinite but the but but
you but you don't worry about both those clusters you only introduce clusters into your
effective representation as the data seem to require and as you get more and more
data you might seem more fine grained high-resolution picture what your world structures like and
thus effectively introduce more clusters just as you need them
and lastly to try to address this question of how can inference actually work in
a practical way well we look to various methods of approximate probabilistic inference in machine
learning and certainly this is true even just in bayesian statistics what the problem is
much more challenging in machine learning there is no way to actually literally
implement bayesian inference or really well this is particularly true for for bayesian approaches but
it's true for other statistical frameworks as well the actual computations you need to exactly
implement bayesian inference on a large scale problem or what we computationally intractable so engineers
have had to develop approximate methods and they want to find good approximation methods which
you can you can make formal statements about how well they likely to work and
how long are likely to take and we look to some of the same ideas
for inspiration about how the mind might implement these bayesian inferences
so that that's the toolkit of ideas and in some sense there you know they're
all drawn from the modern state of art machine learning but we think that by
by looking at how they interact we we can make progress on how human understanding
how human cognition works how we our minds get so much from so little so
quickly but also make progress on the machine learning side because while all these ideas
have been developed in machine learning they haven't necessarily been combined in some of the
ways according to scientists are trying to combine
for example there's not a lot of work in machine learning in in
the building hierarchical bayesian models over structured representations with you first order logic schemas or
functional programs it's mainly left to some of us more adventurous cognitive scientists who don't
have to get one percent improvement on some standard dataset but we can work out
what the machine learning person might think of some kind as a toy model on
it hopefully illustrative
that is human inspired to to make some progress on i think for fundamental ideas
about how you might learn about the structure of the world and then we we
also want to work together with people are more in the engineering side to make
those be the base those ideas the basis for practical and efficient algorithms
OK so what i could see how much time you have
thirty five it's OK good so
now take up
a little bit of water
so so i want to do two things in those thirty five minutes
i just want to to show you just with pictures mostly how these ideas work
and then you'll see over some of the rest of the lectures and in the
course of a much more practical details of this course is too short to really
covered all these ideas so if you know i i can point to papers or
we can we can talk on
and then and i want to give you just a very brief introduction to two
one element of these ideas the deep
the first bullet point there how we use that in some very basic ways to
think about
so here's one slide introduction to bayesian inference i hope this is
this is not new to anybody here is anybody here hasn't seen bayes rule
that as neil said you know that so that may seem like laughable question now
that's that's progress
OK so so you're all familiar with these rules but just to give you a
sense of how this itself with intuitions well
taken taken what i would call an everyday application of bayesian inference you see your
friend around the office john coffin one day
what do you think
or sneezing so what do you think you think john
you think he has a cold you think he has lung cancer
do think he has a stomach flu
most of us without really even consciously thinking are deliberating probably will think that he
has a cold
right or maybe something called like not but yes lung cancer some of those only
three choices definitely called now why is that well the bayesian logic says that the
the you know says look at these two terms likelihood and priors which which combined
together to make a joint score for any hypothesis how well that also explains the
data and then we divide that by the joint score for all the other hypotheses
in the hypothesis space to compute the posterior probability of posterior degree of belief in
these different explanations given the data
in this case there's a very intuitive interpretation for likelihood and priors the likelihood is
the probability of the data under the hypothesis that favours colon lung cancer intuitively because
we know those cocktail cost coughing so they elevate the probability of coffee over some
baseline the prior favors colon stomach flu or lung cancer because fortunately lung cancer is
rare so that's the most basic way we might think of setting the prior on
the joint which is the product of those two was only high for one which
is high for both in other words that's only going to be one and thus
it's it's the combination of priors and likelihoods here which favours having the call over
having cancer stem now the claim that your mind follow some kind of bayesian logic
like that to make this automatic inference is the claim that you actually
you compute this explicitly certainly not consciously and probably not unconsciously because as i was
saying real world medical diagnosis problem or any other kind of causal inference you can't
exactly enumerate the hypothesis space of all possible combinations of diseases and all possible symptoms
that you could observe exactly
compute all these things exactly do those something the nominator there's probably many where but
there some approximate mechanism that achieves this inference and this is the logic by which
works and we think the same kind of logic can apply to things like how
you interpret the sentence or how you were but word means
so for example if you want to think about passing as a kind of bayesian
inference we can say that we can make the following three level probabilistic model the
the bottom level of observed data is a sequence of words at the top is
some knowledge of grammar some rules of how to combine abstract categories like noun phrase
and verb phrases to produce this mid level of representation which is a hierarchical phrase
you know we'll see a little bit more this later on in the in the
summer school but hopefully this is fairly intuitive it's it represents the structure of the
thought that underlies this per cent sequence of words
and constructing this past from this data can be seen as a sort of bayesian
inference where the grammar provides the prior over possible structures and it does that by
attaching probabilities to these rules to generate and by sort of applying them generatively to
say give you put a prior probability of any tree by multiplying together the probabilities
of the rules that context free probabilistic context free grammar and then that the the
combined with what you know about pronouns verbs articles announced puts the distribution on
linear sequences of words you could observe that this probability here and finding the most
likely structure here as
knowledge of grammar and given the utterance well that's just based bayes rule just combining
prior likelihoods in finding structure with high posterior probability
now that same kind of ideas can be scaled up to to model with multiple
levels so we might recognise that that the the utterance here in terms of a
sequence of words is an idealisation of the actual data coming into your senses really
more some kind of sound wave
and so we can put on
the level below to capture the problem of recognizing words from speech and if we
want to understand how grammar induction or language acquisition works then we have to put
gouty legs her ankles hang over her shoes her feet stink she breed lice a mere changeling
a very monster a slut a scold a nasty rank filthy beastly
quean dishonest peradventure obscene base beggarly rude foolish untaught
peevish he even loves her once he admires her for all this he takes no notice of
any such errors or imperfections of a body or mind he had rather have her
than any woman in the world
as for male ugliness we have already seen in the past era
Priapus but Hegel pointed out to in his aesthetics that
it started with the Christian art when he had to represent the Passion of Christ
since Christ
for for representing Christ from Mantegna to Mel Gibson
art could not use the form of Greek beauty to portray Christ scourged crowned
with thorns dying on the cross but at the same time ugly was Christ
but ugliness was also
the typical feature of the prosecutors of Christ of the enemies
and since in the Christian world sanctitiy
is none other that imitation of Christ atrocious suffering was the
lot of the martyrs and of saints appearing in all the splendor
of their bodies made ugly by penitence
if saints
had to be ugly but lovable
for the Middle Ages
even monsters were not always terrifying beings like
the one of the apocalypse or the dragoon and so on
there were
amiable monsters who populated beasteries in the books
of mirabillia
gentle creatures whose form and habits were certainly extraordinary and equally far removed from every
human ideal of beauty or fitness but were considered as bearers of symbolical and moral meanings
such where for instance the panotti with enormous ear the cynocephali
the sciapods
in the middle creatures with a single leg on which they run very
fast indeed and which they hold upright when they sleep in order to enjoy
the shade cast by the single enormous foot or you see
the monocols at the right and the at the left the blemmyes who had the
no head everything on the on the chest not not to speak
of the most beautiful among the monsters the unicorn which could be captured only
by leaving a virgin beneath a tree so that the are animal attract by the odor
of virginity would go and lay its head on her lap and in this sense it was symbol for justity
monsters didn't disappear with the medieval Mirabilia but returned in the
modern world albeit in another form as portents
portents were
amazing and prodigious but natural events
like the birth of an hermaphroditic two headed babies strange animals
and so on and so forth and the attitude toward this creatures was no longer
fright or an attempt to decipher their mystical significance but of scientific curiosity
or at least of pre scientific curiosity
an important chapter in any history of ugliness was the physiognomy pseudo science which
in della porta or other author associated facial features
and the form of other organs with characters and moral dispositions
so in the human physiognomy della porta compares the faces of various animals with
human faces starting from the philosophical persuasions that the divine power manifested its regulating
wisdom even in physical
following this scientific growth of these researchers from Lavater
to the nineteenth century phrenology we arrive to to criminal antropology of cesare lombrozo
who by studying the traits of criminal personality didn't simplify things to the point
of saying that ugly people are always criminals but he did associate
physical stigmata
with the moral stigmata
and analyzed the
head form of the prostitute of a murderer
and so on and so forth
the identification between ugliness and wickedness in fact appears every time it
was it was useful to represent the enemy
like for instance the pope on the part of the Protestants or the the sarrazin
of the proletarian
but it reaches its peak in the racist representation of the features of the
let me only quote a passage from the famous fascist journal
la difesa della razza entitled how to recognize a jew
what are the car this is representation during the republica of salo
of the typical Jew who was at the same time American you see but having
a redcross he was at the same time Soviet Union link there was a
quintessence of the wickedness and the text says how to recognize a Jew what are the characteristics
of a Jewish type a strongly hooked nose different according to the individual often with
a prominent nasal septum and marked flaring nostrils certain individual from a sourthern
and Eastern Europe have a vulture in profile so pronounced has to make one think
of a selected type fleshy lips the lower one often protuberant sometimes very noticeably
eyes not deep set in the sockets with usually gaze that is rather
moisture and clemure than that of other types and more hooked eyelids
curly hair and regarding to the body slightly curved shoulders and
flat feet not to mention rapateous gestures and the slouching gate
however between the end of the eighteenth century and the flowering of romanticism of we
witness a sort of redemption of ugliness
and it's gonna be easier than doing it directly from x if we have somehow
separated these factors a bit from eachother
there's a nice
great on-site here which
comes from
burnout shock of
gives an explanation as to why this is what actually happened that he
x appeal why given x be
tied to each other
and it has to do with
the causal relationship between x and why
if the way the data was generated
actually the cause of x is why and other things
if one is one of the causes effects
then by bayes rule
appeal why given x
can be written in terms of you
x given line
and he
you see that if you want to next now incorporates in it
peter max
introduces eight dependency between here that's you why given x whereas if the causal relationship
is in the other direction in other words
wives were created
as effects of x then
this whole thing
this prior is inapplicable
anymore fortunately
the kinds of data we see in the world around us
is of the kind
where x is the raw sensory data
and why are
the causes that humans have in mind and talk about
when they speak to each other
because the thing that are are brains trying to do is figure out the causes
so these are the why these are the things we really want machines to predict
and so this fire works
you can generalize this notion
our multi-task learning
wear now
you don't have to x and why that you have a bunch of different ways corresponding to different tasks
he that's what you want that's flying
and now the pryr
saying about
these different have been the wife
can be
by a subset
all the factors that explain x
and that's
different half share
some of these explanatory factors so
that's how we can be able to transfer from one task to another task that
the traditional multi-task learning setup
it is not test have something in common so what is it they have in
common but they have in common is that there are underlying explanatory factors
some of which
explain are useful fore
more than one task
so when you learn about these underlying factors by training on one task
extracting features that may be useful for another task
there's another way you can share between different kinds of data that's kind of very different
something that's practically relevant
when you look at the way we get data from in real world applications
very often
you don't get data is a nice
single table where each example is a role and each column is is a feature of the y variable
that have multiple tables you have a
but these different tables correspond to different
types of occurrences
in some of the variables can be found in multiple tables right so you have
keys that relate to the same keys can be found in multiple tables
so they have something in common
so it's a different kind of multitask learning
there are again
thinking about representation learning can help us to share information between the different tasks
for example
if some of those he if you learn representation for each of those features
each of these objectives
make a soft margin
case like this where very simply say well that lexi has to be greater than
one minus sign i
now demise of this
this is to ensure that allow for some outliers
the other thing that you might want to do is you might want to
you know
i mean
picking c is actually not so easy
because you know you could get the scale completely wrong get the terrible solution
you pick a different rerun the optimisation problem and keep on doing this fairly boring
so what you would want to do in state is you would just
i like to say well hey i'm willing to accept about five percent false alarms
are just
tell me the five percent of earth observation
not necessarily
i guarantee but you know something there o five percent
how can we do is
well let's look at this hyperplane here if this hyperplane with shipped over there
four further out i could change the number of points they would have on the
wrong side of the hyperplane
if i pull it down here i would have none
for pull it out there i would have three
what i can therefore do is
i can just
make this constraint namely wx
being greatly equal in row
i can make this road after
before that depicted to be one now we make about but of course they have
to pay for that
is it again if we just made the free variables
the optimisation problem would be very easy i just pick wrote to be minus infinity
and the problem is to solved
they really do anything
o the chronicles sierra could also to resolve
what you do is
you basically have to add a penalty
having wrote in the objective function
and you just just in such a way that the right number of observations is
considered not
this is what you get
that's our standard optimisation problem
so i've been great with zero
now what happens is
the we have to do this i must say i created equal in wrote
but now
i'm paying penalty
because what i want to make sure is what want to is larger always possible
find subtracting road from the objective function
all to the point finance attacking in time you can draw from
the so-called new trick
we i think spend more time thinking about
this debate terrible name then we
i spent and actually the math
and portraits not start with it
anyway so what it really means is
if i have more points
then the fraction of new which sit on the wrong side of the margin
then i could gain
by making wrote a little bit smaller
and thereby decreasing the II's correspondingly
and so therefore
i would actually improve my optimisation problem until i have exactly new points in the
likewise if i picked my margin to larger could make it smaller thereby
kick points out of the margin their why decrease those terms
now if i go and compute the dual optimisation problem i get something very similar
that's what you get
if i didn't have that that the margin i would not get this additional constraints
but since i have free variables this is what i
again you can use the centre of the sphere and optimize for that
the really nice thing is that basically
with such a setup it's pretty much parameter free
or at least three is the set the prime
he said new two
well so five percent
if you want to get five percent novelty
you pick an RBF kernel
you pick the with to be the essentially the median
for the past
you just do that
efficient an example
and they just one thing
so there's a couple of fairly robust setting forget
solutions that will give you at least a reasonable estimate
it might not be the best thing and you will probably not win competition with
but it will probably give you something that's pretty good and
you'll need to spend quite some time to get something that's considerably better
that's what you think about it
and you can see
arguably that those pages are even more likely than the ones they showed before
the same decreasing degree of ugliness
this is actually quite an interesting case that's the one
now four europeans this is perfectly reasonable that someone
for americans it completely throws them off because they just draw a straight line
americans don't put the straight line across the seven
whereas european state
so this is a little bit of european detector here
well here i think that the things wrongly but is these are USPS postal service
digits there are not that many european states just picked up on all the europeans
the really nice thing is it's really
it's basically
specifically tuned for a small number of outliers we get the levels
all the way
if we set new to be one so basically everything is normal
this is also plunged into the sort of feature is actually very small
this is only the a point zero eight
o point zero a sort of is very small and full of false feature it
is also large
this is one hundred fifty
so we have the situation that instead
features are in different numeric ranges so some i actually realized large bridges so these
exciting minus exchange this is going to be very large
then taking explanation as to why
it is approaching zero
then of course now we recognise that this is not the situation so you give
such a kernel matrix like an identity is is not good
well you can try to locate the optimisation problem to see how to do optimisation
problem looks like when you replaced we that the identity matrix you can do some
showing that at that time
well the performances and this is just as good
OK so surgery there's one thing we want to mention here is that they are
scaling is sometimes important using support vector machines
because if you don't do scaling maybe they should be used in greater new
range is limited dominate the whole calculation of the kernel
OK this
so this one one one is very large the actually all
four other issues don't play any role he
so security is sometimes important
so let's look one one example
so you should be the instances
and the two features
the first is about
the height of a person in a high correlation in the second feature is about
gender information so
is one of the range
from one to fifty two four hundred
but for the information you have only two values zero or one so geometrically you've
a situation like this
so x x is high information y axis is the information so they are very
far away along the x x six
so if use of SVM
you're going to get the separating hyperplane please this is almost vertical line
so what does that mean means you only use the the first educated to classification
system is used
but before the second is more important
so so you have to do something
so by using over you want to make the laws
features equally important you can do a simple linear scaling so for example you can
be in scale free
so here is policy which is the first feature two zero one because i think
it should be is already range of zero and so this is the way of
doing a simple linear scale
of course we know
we don't know six the second feature is important or not is not so it
is OK to use only the first we don't know so only you can see
here is skilled generally helps but not always but but you want to remember such
a thing
when are dealing with a real
i would also to mention this idea that before we have always and will always
the question so
so i used to be an optimisation research for
so when i started doing session
so i got some papers is in their accuracy while ninety seven
i we give us and they said you you are you
got to the so-called
the kind of paralysis i tried and i just couldn't get the same accuracy
the videos as the image and the
they they they have something that is not reproducible
then they have to change things papers that in one favor in a small paragraph
of the experiment section of the show centers all i to scale some of them
and is that the problem is that you have to real estate then you know
it takes quite too long to explore the space and therefore to get to the
right value for the two
the empirical mean stabalize is much faster and it is also translated
histograms for the
skills here
roughly normal this one is more notable than that one that that's one for the
number of iterations
fifteen thousand
this one is too far from the norm for depending on the scale of the
speed of convergence
to the true value
when barry
you will see later
if the scale is too small
the speed of convergence may just be too large
your patience or your computer
i believe
then you are likely
more realistic example
which is again the make picture
let's speed we don't
try to pay attention to the specific structure of the mixture that is the fact
that it is two layers
with one their meaning
the distribution to make sure the second layer being simulation from that distributions in each
so we have a function here that we know to compute and we don't to
pay attention
the specific structure
but we can still use
sting metropolis
the parameter space
by just modifying the current value by a factor
accepting this value or not depending on
the usual probability ratio
and although we have to do is compute
the pressure distribution out
the new value
and the participation is just proportional to these functions that we know to compute and
you cannot is that
this ratio is the same
then the ratio
of these very
we don't need the normalizing constant
here is an example in rather large
a data set with three
companies in the mixture and all parameters are known so
is difficult to see that this is sigma
the via the standard deviation and the mean
the mean and the weight
and association
and the way and you can see here here is very visible and there are
two you three
three blocks
that other the three company and so this is the posterior distribution of the first
companies mean violence second competitive environment company invites became histogram
reflects the trained model
i agree it's not very
so here is the same for example that the dimensional spaces i two
he said before it
if we don't mean
four the two two companies between all the other
as i said earlier this phase of the log posterior
and there are two modes
one is
the one high
and just to check
the performance of the algorithm i started out
which is close to the lower
if i start PM and from that point does converge to that mood
and and because it's about a dozen
it was that the random walk
in this two-dimensional space
with the scale it is not
two small
this is the pattern of
by random walk
it doesn't reflect a fact which is that the chain spending
a lot of time there
and this is about
are actually
one hundred or two hundred values of the markov chain is the chain markov chain
for quite awhile
and then moved this value in the one of the two hundred iterations you stay
there and then it accesses value and then again takes
a large number of iterations to move from one side to the other but eventually
you can see that this might run walk
directed markov chain
the right mode of your distribution of interest and after four
the remaining iterations between states so we can complain that the chain doesn't explore all
the possibilities a lot
first there
so far so if i have plotted to serve face
posterior scales
in terms of
and red colors would have had read everywhere but
white in this region very p
it's a very peaked was because they have
fire observation and so in terms of concentration year
the mass of the question
OK so we have to have a lot
representation makes things visually more interesting but in terms of concentration of the distribution of
this is really where the math
OK so
it is normal that
out of a million iterations i don't see
anything else but this region we need millions of iterations to get a bit farther
for instance to come down here
the difference in log
is is about one and
in between these two points
these two books
another example can
i mean rather complex
distribution and status
the random more similar to previous
good work is the product model the right model
in a sense
like a censored
model you observe
the chosen one
and the probability that it
is one
of why i would be
that means that
it's like
regression models
but you only observe
the regret regressed value y
is positive or negative
because is like censoring
of of kind
this makes
distribution in detail because they interested in beta which is the only known this quantity
so we have the likelihood in beta that is
not closed form
other the
because canale five
is the CDF is normal distribution we can compute it at any specific value and
that we can again use
this standard
gaussian regression model
saying that the problem will be
the random walk
we can have here a specific virus
look at the conjugate prior for the family of exponential distributions
so this is a prior over the parameters must have the same functional form as
distribution itself with respect to eta so it has a duty to at the front
and it's linear in each in the exponential
and this parameter new
it is rather like that
OK well
OK this is is to see if we look at the likelihood function
this has the same functional form and this is the normalisation constant for this distribution
so we take this to be multiplied by the likelihood is not going to get
so there's the gvt
from the
raise the power n from n independent observations of the likelihood function
and his duty to raise the power new from the
conjugate prior
and then in the exponential we have eight times the sufficient statistic from data set
times new times car i from the prior
and so again we can
think of this parameter nu like a number of pseudo observations in the same way
in the newly posterior
we had
a norton being or like the number of prior observations of heads and tails
these are like the
number of prior observations of x of some sort of a fictitious x with
sufficient statistic high i
we all have the same sufficient statistic
and again because this is
in the same form as this
it can be the prior to the next
observation so when we absorb more data
again multiplied by the new likelihood function
and we're going to get every time we absorb another data point get another factor
of g
and we'll get another term in this sum
forty happy with that
we need
let me give you example OK right so
what i've done is shown you one example now have notion in the general case
and i'm going to relate back to spiffy examples so i asked me getting three
full view graphs if it's not there yet so i don't know how to introduce
the general give one of you is limited ability distribution and maybe of companies let's
collect this answer that in the context of the any distribution
so let's take the distribution rights it in that in what's called a canonical form
general for the use nature's energy is christ
so this is the probability of a coin landing
the probability of of the binary x given u
and it's the x one month beta one minus six to do is is right
that is the exponential of the logarithm
and bring down the powers of x x exponential xlog mu plus one minus six
small one minus mu
now we want to write this is the form of the exponential
a parameter times x four times you that's in general
so you want to write as a function of the promises time the function of
of the of x so there are terms that are linear in x who gathered
together here
that's not have one minus p times x all in the exponential on the term
here the
one times one minus mu which doesn't depend on x i'd pull that out of
the exponential can just give the coefficient one minus mu
so now i got that into that canonical
it's pretty simple in this case
well almost we'll we want to identify the coefficient of x with the parameter eta
so long over one minus we call that eta was going to rename eta
and so i give each as a function mu we can reverse this and find
new is a function of eta
and it is given by one of one pluses and minuses to exercise voice do
and that's called the logistic sigmoid that's the relationship between
and peter
so we're going to do this thing is going to be eta and no one
minus mu can express that in terms of eta
and so we get we get this form
well thanks for coming to this
1st in a series of lectures so on this board I wrote the title positive
definite matrices and I'll try each time to
make a little list of the main topics of the lecture
the if I think about applied Math generally asserted 2 parts to it 1
find the equations in the 1st place maybe put this just over in the corner
so which part part of Applied Math a big part is defined in equation
create the model
you could say that's the applied mathematics
and then a 2nd part of it is solving the equation
when we had the matrix or the differential equation or the integral equation and the
problem is how do we solve
and you could say that the scientific computing part of this is really the the
twin parts of this course
and the applied math and the scientific computing
and it so I'll go back and forth
and maybe today I'll start with
my favorite matrices
which are already here on the board OK and actually I realized and in planning
these 1st lectures that a lot
that that these these particular matrices come up so much and illustrate so much about
applied math that there if we can get friendly with them
you get to know them it's very much worse than we can refer to them
as the example that we're familiar with now and I wrote down the 3 by
3 version
I'm going to ask you in a minute
and flora and let's start with K 3
and for some of its properties
what what we see in that may but but let me emphasize that this was
the the 3 by 3 cases but in my in my mind I have a
whole family of matrices so what would for local OK for would be 4 by
and it would have to lose down the diagonal
main diagonal minus 1 above and below and otherwise 0
OK 100 we would get if we had can 100 we would really begin to
see the structure of just just that 199 and 99 nonzeros otherwise 0 now
the 3 things
has the same structure except
I expect he asserted for top right and the the top row is
for both the both the top row and the bottom row of are different than
those of the President of the so the 1st row on the last row often
reflect the boundary conditions in some problem solving these have different boundary conditions but otherwise
we're seeing the same structure so so 1 thing you might do
I just like
get the hang of Matlab is create right right
little file that would create
caravan and here there and the other
you don't find Matlab commands that will help to do that
and then
and suggest what to do what you gotta make OK so
that we just take these matrices that others
at my 2nd lecture the today
that's something that be giving up so I can use the 1 I think about
the next lecture at some time for the future and have time to prepare for
it but was the 2nd lecture will be within minutes of the 1st uh cells
that will
discuss that
this aspect of where the matrices come from right now let's just take a and
say what are they like what properties that they have because they are important
OK so as and I guess with the microphone you can see that I don't
think I'm unable to teach without involving the without getting the class teaches that teaches
a course like this stand back but uh here with the microphone I have to
I'll try to remember to repeat what you say so what permanently so you could
say anything actually getting might not break you up and then I'll repeat
OK so tell me some facts about that and let's start with that make waters
in fact about it now just write them up as we see and he's symmetric
that's that's number 1 that's not key 1 that's the 1 I was hoping for
it's a symmetric matrix OK what else non thing about this whole family not just
in case 3 itself 1 of the properties so that the key property how what
I write that I would write patterns k equal k transfer
all that'll be my notation for the transpose MATLAB's notation would be a prime
I'll use a trend OK so
axis of symmetric matrices show up all the time and applications that we're lucky they
do OK what other properties
of this family criteria
0 1 now that's a that's a key question I had to decide whether the
matrix has an inverse whether it's nonsingular OK I'm going to put that in this
sort of more difficult problem because you can't just glance at the matrix and decide
where we can glance at it and see that symmetric so but it's true that
it's nonsingular
or which is another word for
but invertible so will be interested in what those inverses are
and I can do 3 by 3 and vs.
right 2 by 2 was also 4 by 4 is that will have fun OK
but what are the properties and so that's a property to be
to be determined
what else about these matrices