so we've created a permanent magnet
so in the location at the location e
we have
being vacuum
is zero
but b prime
which is the result of those lines
magnetic moments
is still in this direction nothing is to scale of course
so you still have a magnetic field
now i reversed the current
i go counter-clockwise so i'm creating a magnetic field back you know in this direction
now what happened this curve i come up here
look now here
this location q what we have now
i have something very bizarre
i have now situation
well by the vacuum field is in this direction but there is no magnetic field
the materials the magnetic field inside is zero
so when we have one q
so we have the vacuum
it is in this direction
the inside the prime
we're not primarily
the total field inside is zero
the reason being that b prime is still in this direction
the reason being that the domains are still alive in this direction and so the
vacuum field
was the prime field which has to be externally at it
that's up was in that field zero
these are
now i increase the current but i keep going counterclockwise
and so the magnetic field vacuum
this direction
i go into saturation again
in a similar way that went into saturation here
now i stop here
i don't want to lose my approach
and i stop here and i say to the current go back to zero again
so my current now goes back to zero
there we go
now i arrive here
point as
and again i have a situation
that my vacuum field is zero
i could take the material out of the solenoid
just walk around with it the street it will be permanent magnet
the magnetic field inside this material important people's in this direction
if i take it out here that is necessary
now some domains stay aligned in this direction
the reason was that i had counterclockwise current so those domains flipped over and then
all willing to flip back again so i've also made a permanent magnet here
vacuum field zero
the b prime
now in the opposite direction
and then
if i continue now
go clockwise current again and increase
i and the there
and and this is bizarre curve we call this the
his stories
if you look at this curve
it's really
amazing is that hard to
to digest this you you have to give it
a little bit of thought
for one particular value of the current
for instance
one a particular value of the current i noted the vacuum is given
i have two possibilities here
for the magnetic field
and for the current year
i have two possibilities
for the magnetic field
and so
i cannot even know when i take this material and i exposed to an external
field i can even calculate what the magnetic field inside will be
it depends on the history
of this
look at this point here
and at this point there
if i asked you what kappa
it's almost ridiculous questions
one is kept him
i have
i have the vacuum field
but i have no field inside
so the field inside which is b is zero
back in field is non-zero so you would have to answer kappa and is zero
the the only thing you could say
quite bizarre right
right here is vacuum field
no field inside
kappa amazonian kappa m is zero here and remember it was one thousand
look at the situation take this point of the curve
this point of the curve
it's less than zero is negative
because here the vacuum field is in this direction
b prime is in that direction so in opposite direction sort the net
it in that direction the vacuum is in this direction and he has also refers
so the bizarre situation
that you are effectively having situation to pi kappa m is zero
kappa alpha and can also be
for those
points that i have there
i can show you this hysteresis curve
and i do it exactly the way
i explained to you except that i will not be able to run
this current very slowly up and down i do it with sixty hertz
alternating current get out of the
the wall
so i run through this
the solenoid and sixty hertz
alternating current
that means we got through this curve very quickly back and forth
in this morning maximum current
and this point maximum current
current clockwise counter-clockwise clockwise counter-clockwise and we aims at sixty times a second
then we see that there is a role not so very
well you're the only very systematic and you see is that the thalamus pick speech
much earlier than the
the cortex
that's what you see that there are not so very systematic differences between right brother
point for instance typical point
and now this
another point is I have to be computed wouldn't response so far maybe thousands of
points in the brain and I have shown only 4 of them but the question
is how can we get a little bit more insight in the rest of the
hemodynamic responses because well maybe I just selected the wrong 1 Soriano some of them
the 1 just selected some points and I we don't have enough responses there but
how can we visualize what's happening in all the other points of the brain
now that was the problem we by applying theoretical clustering and very short of that
most of you are very familiar with this but nevertheless
are also very briefly through it's it's also an hour and a half an algorithm
and implemented in C to do have a few two-dimensional points here could also be
an n-dimensional but
dimensions and that the difficult to work with them to draw drop them of these
these items there are grouped by 1st selecting the 2 closest points and the
of the remainder to look at to get the points toward and closest groups who
were closest closest
and then they are connected
and so on
and then finally you end up with a dendrogram which suggests that summer and you
if you go to the value of 1 and 3 are in 1 group 2
4 5 in 1 programs and tuition and separate that that's the algorithm that applied
on the estimated permanent responses so we that for all these 10 thousand points
and then we got something very systematic at least in the subject that show here
so what I have so what we did is we applied this clustering algorithms on
behalf of American responses
the shape of the hemodynamic responses and I get this same goal or to all
points uh well from the same cluster
and and probably get and it is only of course for the for the most
government responses
now this year 2 clusters representing the activity of the eyes so for summary the
motion of the I by assume that this is motion because it's been instantaneously and
now from the motion of the items to be correlated to the to the alpha
and therefore also to bold
and the fire and here I probably have remember responses all these different regions and
I ordered them but 1st I call this the positive ones and the negative ones
and these ones are ordered in time
and now we see here the first one corresponds to the Deuteronomists this 1 into
corresponds to the ventricles and these are the ones that correspond to the cortex and
if you look carefully at the order of the order of things
the photos and is assumed 7 temporal order in these curves if you follow this
course than it seems as if the pattern starting and spreading out from here to
there but you should have more clearly in the next slide vertical account is chosen
the bits that are usually the peak times over
of the cluster that ranges from 6 to 12 seconds so dark means that it's
speaking earlier and then it's so starts here and it spreads out from here or
familiar to the outside of the cortex and here have another problem which starts here
and and also spreads out
so that we could interpret this as as a kind of wave which is traveling
corporations vectors to to be algorithm however and this could also be used 1 and
the potential could be adopted some of us really something to do with the alphabet
geology patient could of course be just simply hemodynamic responses vary from point to point
in the brain and there and you can and then the happened the shape of
the responses also determined by the by the infrastructure the micro and anatomy of the
of the blocks fossils in the cortex and if that's the explanation that this picture
picture shows that we should be very careful in analyzing and interpreting time delays which
you get from fumbled signals
the ultimate test of course would be to determine heavily responses from
sensory motor task and compare remark that for the same subject but there will be
so that dominant responses of artificial of tasks so that you know what I but
this is just a general relative something to do with the the the movement of
the operator
now being that these data there are recorded from Subject 3 hour for half an
hour in the scanners eyes closed and where they were instructed not to fall asleep
at the end that that was only an instruction and of course everybody says knowledgeable
to probably don't know ahead of time uh that we recorded the heart beat the
to correct the EEG signal
and we also have used the heartbeat to correct for artifacts in the fMRI but
and for that we use the method of universal that's that's what I want to
stress here is that the heart of this not meeting regular marginal it's almost 1
per 2nd but not extremely regular it's not extremely regular there are some variations in
it even if the subject is lying in scanner eyes closed trying not to fall
asleep you see here that the heart the intervals of hardly are high hired and
in the fall so short review faster beating heart and and here we get to
the 2nd part of the determined the heart rate so that are in the false
over time for every 3 seconds to get a signal which looks like this problem
leverage in this case subjected source 1 1 . 1 . 2
and varies between 1 . 4 and and approximately
if you have a very good memory for signals that have the right to recall
on the longer side
let's see
this sort of one more piece that i want to show
to get there i had to write down
unfortunately large amounts of that this was postponed
so the m step we want to maximize
and all expectations are was where respect as you are drawn from the distribution q
y sometimes i be sloppy just made this
and now all on
this distribution
here's the i p x i give the i that is the calcium density
because of its size differs e i
this is calcium given by very new
and covariance i
and so on in this step in the derivation i will actually go ahead and
substitute in
the formula of the gaussians density so i will go ahead and take this and
you can see here one of the key to be able to do
on side interest you to
so will go put the
gas density and when you do that you find that you get
on notation
i forgot to say
to maintain so the
one of the two two two not make the derivation too complicated and actually just
going to maximize this with respect to the parameters lambda
it's so just another the
so you want to maximize its respect along the side new but just to keep
the amount of mapping saying just going to show how to maximise is
respect to the matrix long pretend sign
and so on it's such an accountant as you get some expert in expected value
for constant on because i may depend on size but not on longer
the mine is on
this thing
on and the quadratic terms essentially came from
the exponent in your house in density when i take longer one
they end up with this quadratic term
and then
and so if you take the derivative is
the expression of
with respect to the matrix longer
and you said that zero
right so we want to maximize this expression prospective parents longer
so you take the derivative of disrespect along there
one on
this editor to visit expression
of zero set there it is easier to maximizing
when you do that to simplify
you end up with the forward
OK so that's the
on the m step this is the value that does the value should get on
that use of europe parameters lambda
and again the expectations
all i with respect to zeid drawn from the distributions q i
the very last step of this derivation is are we need to work out
what these two expectations are
and so the very first term i
again it's just mu of arms given x i transpose because because the QI distributions
has mean given by the
to work out the other term
just remind you idea is that if
if you have a random variables e
this calcium music sick well
the the covariance matrix the
i minus e
that you know one of the definitions of the covariance
and so this implies that is easy transfer calls
so what you see
and so the second term here
on becomes
i i
was so
OK think
multiplication that's required over and above what you would've
done if you just done the com computatation anyway in the
feature space so it's certainly not an overload of a of computation here you know
this might be a D dimensional vector so you'd have to
do D multiplications and D minus one additions anyway
I'm always saying is do one more multiplication okay so it's a very minor additional load now what I
can claim is this actually corresponds to an inner
product in a in a complex feature space well why okay this is what I've written I'm now just using a different notation here X prime Z
squared is just another way of expressing this but now
I can actually swap one of these two round the order
and change the bracketing and I get Z X X primed Z so
X X prime is a matrix and so this is a a matrix
with a row vector time to column vector and in fact this is now the frobenius in a product between
two matrices or the inner product between two vectors where you
vectorize the matrix Z Z primed and the matrix X X primed if you're you know if you're not sure that you're
happy with that derivation here it's very easy just to write it out explicitly just write the
sums down on the piece of paper and you'll see that it works out it's very
easy this is just a a you know a slightly maybe slick away of showing it but if
you're not happy just write out the sums and you'll see that
it it actually words that this actually corresponds to an
inner product between these this feature vector for X sorry this where I've gone this a wrong way around but anyway what whichever
this feature vector for X and this feature vector for Z so what it what it corresponds to is taking instead of just say
D components they're now D squared components where the components are the products of the features of
the original feature vector so there's a feature for X I X J
and there's actually another feature for X J X I so you are sort of double counting actually you get
you know repeated features but there's certainly N
choose two different or N plus one choose two different sorry N choose two
different features here so the features space dimension has
been significantly increased compared to the original input
space and I'll make that explicit with an example of say
doing a regression over a set of images so think of
pixel vectors which might be thirty-two by thirty-two pixel images so the input space dimension is a thousand and twenty-four dimensions so D in this case is a thousand twenty-four if we use the quadratic kernel we're implementing
regression in a million dimensional space right roughly thousand squared or well five thousand dimension if you take into
account some of them are the same but certainly a very very high-dimensional space and the
cost of doing it is actually lower than doing it in the
original space because we're having to invert the thousand by
thousand matrix that's the dimension of the training set as
opposed to a thousand and twenty-four by a thousand twenty-four dimensional
matrix which we would've had if we done the explicit computation in the input space so
we're running ridge regression in a hugely more powerful space
at no extra cost or in fact reduced cost compared to the doing
a primal sort of normal ridge regression without the kernel trick
okay there's a slight caveat to that that when your evaluating on a new test point it is gonna be more complex because you have to run over in order to compute the let
me go back to the evaluation on a test point here in
order to evaluate over the test point all of these alphas
are gonna be nonzero and so you're gonna have to compute the inner
products between the test point and each of the or the kernel function
sorry which means the test point in each of the training data so
it's gonna be a thousand of these to compute so it's a
thousand times a thousand cause there are thousand dimensionals so that's a
million computations to do this whereas in if we had an
explicit vector in the input in in in primal
space it would just be a thousand computations so that that
is a slight caveat here but certainly in solving the the problem actually learning the alpha vector is less expensive than
learning the primal vector in the original space okay so
what are the implications so what we've actually done we've performed linear
regression in a very high-dimensional and in fact even can be done in
infinite dimensional spaces efficiently through
this kernel trick it's equivalent to performing
non-linear regression in the original input space so we've
effectively moved to doing a non-linear regression in
some sense in the sense that the final function that
you're actually learning has a form in this case where
we use the quadratic kernel this is the form it's a sum of
alpha rhi inner product X I X squared so it's it's actually a
non-linear function i's a quadratic polynomial function of the of
the components of the input vector so we're actually doing
non-linear regression but in a way that retains the attractive features of linear regression that
there's a unique global solution we can find it fast by
simple inversion of a of a matrix so it seems to be you know magic the best of all possible worlds
in a sense but you know there must be some warnings there must be
some problems here and clearly there is the curse of
dimensionality working in high-dimensional spaces is dangerous and you are liable to overfit your data I kind of aluded to how that's overcome by
controlling that weight vector norm is effectively controlling
the complexity so it's sort of giving with one hand and
taking back with the other you're giving lots and lots of dimensions wtih a kernel trick but you're
actually trying to you know keep a tight control on
their use trough the regularisation of the weight vector norm
so it's a kind of a let's the data decide in a sense how much complexity is
actually needed and that seems to be a very effective way of operating you
you kind of don't try and a priori say how much complexity you need you give a lot of complexity but you try and keep a tight control on its use and hopefully that actually ends you up with the right
level of usage of complexity for the problem that you're actually trying to solve so that's one of the ways in which the curse of
dimensionality is handled within kernel methods generally and the
same applies to support vector machines and and most of the
other techniques that very similar approaches adopted in
terms of controlling complexity so I'm doing a hand waving
argument here I'll I'll give a little bit more of a concrete
example of statistical analysis in the support vector case
with respect to some information need and that's because relevant entities so
you know
we could think of concepts or topics categories are named entities or user interests are
not directly observable but rather we can only indirectly
in front them
you know based on
what what what's given say just text based on the text we we might be
interested in identifying concepts and topics and things like this so the observable we will
in industry and we can talk about text annotation document structure link structure user actions
and so on and so forth and the idea is that just having the raw
data is not enough to get to this more semantic level
of information content OK so there's an inference problem here that you know how can
we get away automatically inferring for information content based on
raw data so this will be the the
the topic of my tree OK and now to give you an overview of how
the tree structured part one is today in part two is on friday
so i will mainly deals just with what's called adhoc retrieval which just means search
OK search engines if you like today and then with some supervised learning techniques in
information retrieval on friday
and this will not cover
kind of everything but rather i'd like to
pick a few
topics and then go more in depth with these
topics OK so
so we start today with the
the adhoc retrieval problems
adhoc retrieval
you know everyone is familiar with the situation
we assume that you know there's some document collection we have some interface there's a
user that has an immediate information need usually we don't assume that we know anything
about the history of the user and the information need is expressed in terms of
the query right so we have
there's the magic here really in the talk retrieval
that you know we have a search box like this and we type in very
one or two key words very short incomplete ambiguous
but still somehow you know based on the able to identify pull relevant documents and
are able to identify what the user wants right
this is
this is the goal and you know of course
if we look at the web nowadays search engines and
you know finding information using
these forms of search is very popular and and about a third of the internet
users use search engines on a typical day
OK and this is from two thousand two it's probably increased since then
OK so
so where the challenge you can certainly try to illustrate
should be trivial so one of the
major challenges has to do with what's known as the vocabulary mismatch problem OK so
assume we have
a document here
CNN news
germany tackles labour shortage and we have query saying
consisting of three terms labour immigrants germany
and we would you know interpret this in the standard way we would now to
kind of the term by term matching right and we would find that all the
three terms occurring in the document
right and that the search engine like google or any other would basically be able
to pull out this document as a rather you know relevant document to the query
however we also know that as we
very the query
right in the way that the meaning of the query is really not changed at
least not dramatically
right we might run into problems so if we say german job market for immigrants
you know job for instance does not occur here but the labour right and have
the terms like economy here in terms like market over there and immigrants have matched
and sometimes there are morphological variations germany german and so on and so forth so
you know these are variations that show up of course and you can get worse
right we can have things like foreign workers in germany or queries like german green
card where there would be no overlap at all right so there is no term
in the query that occurs in the document so the question is you know how
how can we figure out that the document is relevant to the query but it
can just be based on
the term by term matching
so then
the way i'd like to think about information retrieval and that has actually become
a more popular paradigm in the information retrieval community since nineteen ninety nine is i'd
like to think of such as statistical inference problem or at least there is a
statistical inference problem is part of the problem of search information search so
to give you an example you know usually what people of course to information retrieval
and we just you know do this here as well
it is to ignore the syntax of the document and break it up into terms
terms can be words or phrases so multi you know words say
we here intellectual property for instance could two word phrase
OK we represent so this could have been a document that would be represented as
the set or bag
four right now is the inference problem so
if we have a document like that in the query
so here you know there
there is a query china-eu trade relations in the terms china trade and in their
what we would be interested in somehow
to estimate based on the context right so we
the things you like beijing
right where we know based on are you know in our knowledge geographic knowledge that
that has of course to something to do with china right so that's beijing in
the document in the query china right that you know some chances that that might
data and
so how do you make
best use of
OK i think move on
i have
so the next thing
it starts out pretty solid and then kind of peters out into like things that
don't work and we don't know how to get them work
is this kind of training
so this suggests the evolution of from generative to this kind of models as a
little bit more about what i mean by that
so the original statistical models for generative models
but what we do nowadays is there's no error training
so this one component the system
and there's a big temptation to put more features into these models
i think it's the way of introduction i should first say what i mean by
so general models is the idea that you have a nice mathematical derivation how everything
fits together
so what do here you know you probability of for instance deciding to english sentence
and you want to find new sentence as the maximum probability so those are max
formulation here
and you do things like you apply the bayes rule which is mathematically sound rule
compliance you can ride this equation is true is a really call sign some made-up
stuff so it's mathematically sound
and then you kind of the original little bit from the past so when you
say what is the probability of english sentence given for instance an alignment well you
throw in some independence assumptions but mathematicians we have to do that you know that
a one phrase is not independent of the transitional the phrase in the sentence but
you can have considered that's about it so it's still fairly
you know consistent story
and this is a very straightforward formulation of the problem mathematically
by just applying standard probability rules may be thrown in some pros some independence assumptions
some point
but even nice model that captures the whole thing and then you can
basically fitting figure out how does this model applied to the data so you can
for each sentence pair you can go with possible derivations can have and these formulas
give you nice
probabilities and these cases
so there's things like the EM algorithm
that you can use to discover automatically the alignments
and all that
that's generative model
one thing you realise though is that OK you have a nice mathematical derivation where
you should have a language model multiplied
with the translation model certain based
and the star model so it in there
this maybe additional models
it is part of the station one way
but one thing we realize that we should wait these things
we can basically given exponent to all these models
for instance if we give the language model twice as much weight if you square
all the language model probabilities all differences that exist language model scores of them
you know even bigger
so give more weight the language model we can get better station performance and we
did that for a while
you can handle all these magic numbers should be used as a smaller point five
language model point seven
well are the hallways and all that we just try different things
so we did that for y
and then maybe this is second and i which kind of showed well that's actually
very principle thing to do is to
these things are called log linear model so you have the product of all these
each of them has
waiting components lambda
so if you take the lot because log linear models because if you take the
the first is a linear equations the sum over
the weights times the the log probability
and that kind of man opens the door to throw all kinds of things
so language model multiple language models reordering model
we're in machine learning we'd like to make computers do this right and it's an
interesting problem because it's saying that there is enough information in these two shifted copies
free to recover debts
how do you do this automatically and so what we discuss a bit later is
you can actually formula is very naturally as as the problem in a markov random
and it's a markov random field in which you measure the the shifts between the
two images and you try and optimize those shifts
and so we get a bit more details of this kind of model later this
high level it's people use things like lattice models
what's tricky is again trying to find the optimal shift trying to sort of shift
things around to make the matching the best way
this again is computationally intractable but we'll see later that people are in practice using
message passing algorithms these are approximate methods here that are doing very well for this
OK so just one last example before i move on
this last example has to do with problems of communication and so some of you
might be aware of this if if you study communication engineering you might be aware
of these things but certainly all of you have i suspect experience with devices that
use this kind of technology so as a sort of his matching yesterday someone asked
about the killer application for graphical models this certainly is one killer application this this
is an area where graphical models and message passing have really revolutionized the field in
the last ten years
so the basic problem here is you want to imagine that you're trying to communicate
a source of information
maybe you're just talking to a friend on the phone but we're going to idealise
this is you're just trying to send let's say is zero
you want to send your friend is zero or one that would be the simplest
kind of communication you could do
and the catch is that
the channel that you have to buy channel we just mean something like a wireless
phone that you speak over the channel doesn't work perfectly if if you send zero
maybe will flip that zero to be one
so your friends not quite sure what you send maybe center zero maybe one year
she isn't quite sure
the idea here is that what you'd like to do is be clever and start
doing things like tom was actually mention these are called these are error correcting codes
you'd like to add redundancy to what you transmit so the simplest thing to do
would be to send zero five times
as long as at most two of the bits got flipped then your friend could
say well there's more zeros and ones and i can decode correctly
so that's that's a very simple example of an error correcting code it's called the
repetition code it's a very stupid example of error correcting code that's not what's used
in practice that's a very bad thing to do
but it illustrates the principle and this kind of problem of communicating like this has
lots of applications
the rovers they were sent to mars that were wandering around their using these codes
to transmit information back to earth
at berklee lots of people are working on sensor networks are nodes networks have lots
of little devices and there's a lot of error control coding the goes into those
your wireless card for those of of you are using
wireless right now is using error correcting code in your hard drive is also using
error correcting encoding so this this is all around you even if you don't know
about it
so i level the key thing is that
shannon back in the forties
sort of laid out of a very beautiful theory that said how well you can
ever expect to do this
but he was theorist he said in principle you can do this
but he didn't give any indication how you could actually in practice do it and
so what's exciting is the graphical models is work graphical models come in they really
enabled people to
so this kind of problem as near to optimally as possible
and so graphical models are being used for instance in your wireless cards right now
let me skip this just in the interests of time
OK so that's sort of some illustrative examples of applications with graphical models arise it's
by no means exhaustive i sort of chosen examples i think not intersect so much
with other speakers but other people talking for instance about text about bioinformatics
in all these applications again graphical models have have a role to play
so any questions
about those applications
OK so let's move on to the basics of graphical models
this again is reviewing but what's taught us over the past couple days
so i'll be focusing mainly on undirected models or talk briefly about directed models that
sam also spoke about
but primarily about undirected models and i'll explain why in a couple of slides
so again an undirected model that this means the graph that you're looking at it
means the edges don't have arrows on them is no direction to them is just
a link like that with no no directionality
so again you want to think you have a graph a set of nodes circles
and edges
you've got random variables at each node
and so what's important here is
what turns out to be important is
what are known as the cliques of the graph
so cliques of the graph are just friends it's a clique is a set of
nodes that all talk to each other they all share edges
so for instance here one two three this is the a clique
one two is also a clique
one two three is the maximal clique because
this is the biggest that that i can make things that all talk to each
similarly for seven is the maximal clique four five six is a maximal clique
so it's going to be important because cliques and define sort of the notion of
locality what's scheme graphical models is what you mean by local
on cliques tell you
what it means to be local what's local to use what you can talk to
an one step that's what's in your clique
well it's related to what's in your creek
something else that also important is what's known as the vertex cutset
and this again is a very intuitive notion it's saying it's a subset of vertices
that you usenet these that you took so in one step step step step step
the statistically significant part of the weight function
it was actually the weight functions where remember that we talked about taking
the wave functions wearing it
and the interpretation is the probability density
that was what was critical to our understanding of what we are the electron
so that's what we're going to do here
we're going to take this
sigma one molecular weight function now
and we're going to square
and the
proportional to were interpreted as a probability density out just to create by p but
this is the probability density remember that probability
OK well if that's the case
and i can multiply out
right because
sigma one
right here
that sigma one
really equal to the linear combination of one s they want to be that sigma
o let me take one as a
what i wanna be
multiplied by one as the
plus one as we
that's what sigma one hundred multiply the
when i do the
i'm going to get one as a square loss one has be
we're close two times one as a one as the
probability density
to make this a little bit more real for you let's fly
the plot the probability density
as a function of the position along the body axis
so in this case here
the on
nucleus is here
in the nucleus their rights we have molecule now
i'm just going to what the probability density
the function of the position along the
into nuclear assets
what's it gonna look like well it's going to look like
looks something like
where the probability density is the highest right nucleus you say
and the probability density is the highest right it will be because after all
you know the wavefunction anyway function in the west
the weight function
the highest value that function is rated r is equal to zero right at the
so that's what the probability density looks like
and i just
informed here that the zero thing and that particular figure turn out so well
right but that's what it should read
all right
the reason i want to this here
to contrast it with the following
suppose i take
just one nitrogen atom
and the other hydrogen atom
but i take those weight function i just where them
and then i add them up
so suppose i take the hydrogen atom with its function one SAIC swear it
and then i take another wave function for another hydrogen atom
one at the ice we're at
and i and those who are
in this case
what we're doing is taking two hydrogen atoms just taking a wavefunction is wearing them
in this particular case
what i haven't done
it is i haven't allowed any interference i haven't allowed
functions two
constructively interfere
i didn't up these wave functions first
before i swear
i swear that i ended the model
they have
then taking those wavefunctions letting them constructively interfere
and then squaring up
and you can see the difference is
when i was
compare to that's all right from that apply now this
what i do that it's going to work well it's going to look very much
like this
but then right at the centre right here
the probability density
right for this case
four two
hydrogen atoms which are now
non binding or non-binding because i didn't let those two functions
constructively interfere
the result is that the probability density right in the centre here
he probability density
hearing this one
so let's first start with a low frequency
of about two hundred and fifty six words
room anyone and you can not here in the room
that's a good thing we might as well be right now
the tone is quite low
i love being and so these problems
one of the tuning fork go back and forth two hundred fifty six times per
second so fast you can see it
this one is four hundred and forty it's higher simile of the piano
the on
merging ips
and here is one
that is four thousand
very high
even unpleasant isn't
four thousand is the highest only the piano can produce three and goes from twenty
the lowest key to the highest key
which is four
thousand words
just to make you feel at home
let me test you're hearing
and see how good it is
and for those of you who are all may be in for a surprise because
you may not here
all the way to the end so i'll start somewhere
around forty or fifty sixty hertz
it doesn't mean you cannot here twenty but it's very hard for us
to produce twenty hertz strength not so easy
so i will start a little higher than
you may like
so let's start at sixty
required no
we cannot hear this
o heroes
very loud it's not a course question
that's the limitations of our
this is
sixty years
number two hundred
in the end this value
four point is that
we were
i'm not sure
two large or is
on the whole o
the other
i could france
now go to
four thousand
the this
not just a single which we use
same place places no you get into data
it's as i can tell
who can only list could use
i don't care
i can cannot it
of course i in a position because creates so
eight thousand that's it i can offer you a thousand
so let's go to work
to ten thousand
o canal here ten thousand
of the four here is that the way go
twelve thousand
you can hear it just raise your hand and then we'll know slower
it's not a competition
the winners
fourteen thousand
forty thousand again would overwhelm
with respect to twelve
sixty thousand
so the whole
about this
you never hear never need sixteen thousand when you
the bus ride to anything or television station never eighty thousand
OK eighteen thousand
very quiet
OK here
well adriana world
can you twenty thousand
i got twenty five thousand first roots
twenty thousand now
twenty thousand
OK twenty thousand
twenty five thousand
are you sure
so what i can do is i can say, well let's keep the conditional distribution
let's throw away the prior, and make a new prior from above
actually i'll makethe new priormore powerful, 'cause i'll make it depend on the past
states of these hidden units as well
so it should work even better
so that, so we stack models, and when we, when we
make these the visible units, we can put in autoregressive connections
thosearebetween binary units now, so this is a logistic--this is a directed logistic belief
net in time
so now we can stack and every time you add another layer, it gets better
we can even put in labels like i did in the digit model
so we can have, we have data from CMU of a graduate student, a very brave graduate student walking
many different styles
we can put in explicitly the style and condition on it here
it would be nicer to learn the styles, but for the time being we're conditioning on them
so we just had thisas an extra conditioning input which we trained with backprop
so now we can take one model like this
in fact exactly this model
and train two hidden layers with style labels
on many different styles of walking
and then we can generate from the model
so it's actually deciding which ways to turn and so on. it has a tendency to turn
to the right
it will just run forever
but the
student who provided the data also walked in different styles, like he was told to walk
like a cat
thisiswalking like a cat, and again, this is new data from the model, walking like
a cat
and you can see it's a distinctly different style of walking. now the interesting thing here is
remember with the sort of 2's and the 8's? ijust changed one label at the top
and it changed
the digits itgenerated, right?
therei just changed one style label, completely changed what came out, even though all the other
connections were the same
so when itwas dreaming of 2's and 8's, that looked a bit boring
this is more interesting dreaming, because it's dreaming dynamic things and it's about people
you can tell him to walk like a
he's avery brave student
you can tell himto walk like
walk gracefully
he's a computer science student, i'm fairly sure
i think the only graceful walk he's ever seen is c-3po. that's definitely
and notice the model gets fed up after a while. this generative model, it's too hard holding
your hands up
all the other things it's learned had the hands down
soitjust gives up on that after a while
it overrides the style label
you can tellhim to walk like agangly teenager, he's very good at that
he looks really awkward right
he's not quite sure whathe's meant to be doing there
you can tell him to walk like a drunk
now the, the stumbling recovery
wasn't because it understands physics. there must be something very similar to that in the
training data, right?
but one thing that never was in the training data was transitions from one kind
walk to another
so he knows how to walk in a sexy style
it's all in the same weights
just change the stylelabel
and then you can be really mean to him
and you can say
tell him to walk in asexystyle andhalfway through you change the label to chicken
and he's never seen transitions before, and he does a reasonable transition
becauseit's all the samemodel
OK that's the end
i'm going to post the slideson my website
i have to get them onto my website in toronto but i'll try and do it tonight, certainly by monday
they'll be there
and these readings which are still being updated, there's already readings there which are old readings
i've got about fifteen new ones
that i'm gonnaput there
well maybe
i'll put those there over the weekend
so by monday you'll be able to get all the papers i referred to will
being here with little
a very brief description what it's about
right, i agree. so this was just for
i mean weweremotivated by the LSA people
who were doing document retrieval by using
getting vectors from documents and using them for other documents
and claiming that, you know,we can do amazing things and we just want to
say we can do much more amazing things, then we noticed that we could do this
semantic hashing that is
learn this hash function thatrespects similarity
and therefore isavery fast thing
i completely agree with you that what people really want to do
given a short query, find the relevant documents, and for that i think you have
to understand the meaning of the short query ultimately
google quite liked this and gave us some money to more research on it
we should probably talk about that offline because i'm not sure i understand what you're
saying but
as you probably realise my main interest in this was
not actually solving the information retrieval problem but showing that this deep learning could do something neat
i'm not an information retrieval person
you mean skip-like connections
you could do that even before the pre training. that is, there's no reason why
when i train a layer, i shouldn't treat as data several previous layers
the real answer to that is there's
too many things to be explored and that's not one of the things we explored
yoshua bengio's group has done a little bit of exploration of that and claims that it helps
so it's a sensible idea. it'sjust one of those many things that
needs to be investigated and occasionally one of those thingsturns out to be a big win
so far as i know it's not a really big win
my main motivation i guess was
the inferior temporal pathway in the cortex
doesn't look much like that although it does have some skip like connections
so let's see if i can draw picture of what you're saying
and then if i can learn this
where allthese are connected
then a multilayer thing is just a version of that with a few missing connections
in one dimension that has a local minimum right and a mountain and then another
a global minimum OK
in one dimension you can go through the mountain to go to this of immunity
can go up so the great this algorithm not find it but it's dimension
you may be able to go around the mountain
so that picture this million dimensions
i'm sure you can do that
then there's going to be lots and lots of dimensions that will go to allow
you to get around a local minima and in fact depending on the kind of
basic elements of sample in the network
it's very difficult to build the box right now you have a million dimensional stability
buttermilk dimensions you need
i have a lot of
each neuron basically the point because it does have space so answers could be
hardly complicated that
right so you have flat areas of course because the the weights become very large
something get saturated and a large so there was to compensate for this is just
not to get there and you can do this is with decay so there's a
few tricks like this to run the same with a lot of tricks if you
want to make larger and efficient this entire which about this
which means that means that expects was where we so
yes there are tricks but there are not any more difficult and
of instances
so a problem of course is that if you sort of
starting to play with things like this the first thing to try is you know
it i you're not on the exclusive or and happens to be very unreliable
so this idea of
so basically nineteen fifty seven people sort of figured out the perceptron work that you
the only new that convex optimisation and so with the figures that they
they had to make this a really large with what i'm basically random functions random
features and you know they is there was a good chance that the problem would
be solved was nineteen fifty seven
eighty five o o with backprop people forget women that you could on this is
sort of works in both cases but there are situations where it doesn't work
nineteen ninety two the
the kernel machine
sort of came out of the
of the
the bushes and said well if i said if i have one unit for each
training sample
smith's next to me this right
actually the three offices next to me
the was there
is a big wheel invented that make but anyway
if you if you say each unit to a training sample different training samples the
ways of each in unit two different training sample
but basically you've built around for your training set
that's like a decoder for random access memory right to plug you plug inputs and
then what going to it can recognise its its corresponding training sample and so you
just the way to the output you want and you don't you know it's it's
it's random access memory so you make the kind of smooth and then you can
get smooth minimizes memory
and the support vector machines
regularizer at this
so that's kind of you know
it's not beyond the perceptron
in fact there was several papers at the conference is one
people at the conference there was sort of arguing for
first layer is this is sort of drawing from theoretical results from compressed sensing which
are really interesting mathematically
so what's the problem with non convex learning
so when you mentioned before is that none of what you read in the optimisation
literature applied
and encourage you to see which is tutorial either slides and video which hopefully will
become available and that there was the next last year and the reason is you
need to use stochastic methods to take advantage of redundancy in the data
so stochastic methods are the methods were basically you the parameters after each sample instead
of kind of computing an update over the entire training set k
and that exploits the redundancy in the density of after this particular industry that's really
what you want to use and they will produce theoretical results on this a few
years ago that showed that we should talk about this tutorial that shows that you
know even if this does not optimize the loss function on the training set perfectly
this is as good as it's going to get on the test set anyway so
you don't need to optimise more
so the problem is that sort of of course stochastic methods of four balls and
a synthetic
asymptotics properties and so if you tell the musician person i'm going to use a
stochastic gradient algorithm says for series of convergence proof or they are but after we
and second you know the property are you know
your linear or or even sublinear is really horrible OK but they all show that
actually works really well
many people so there's really well but they will explain why this class
and the values of course is that the musician musician literature does not talk about
stochastic methods at all you can find anything about this anywhere
and so
you know conjugate gradient stories project which is causing you to sort out the window
you can use any of that any of those methods are quite anyway ordering two
you know when the sun
so you start with simple methods you can publish papers prison complex methods because you
know the simple methods of the ones i work best
how disappointing
so what this kind of the same for the earlier
right so so so you also
this is kind of the point that sort of making the this is a very
large sort of
basically sort of you know using this did the trick that is the tallest of
its kind of a good way of avoiding the problem of local minima really being
the problem
so another problem also is sort of breaking the symmetry in the system there's is
a a local minimum due to the fact that you can for example interchange to
denote in neural nets and you get the same solution
and so
that means there are two local minima are equivalent due to a permutation and the
user is kind of a set point between them
and you know by the king's military you sort of reducing the the space
and that might be one of the reasons why things like on social network so
well because they even though they're very very deep that's one of the few instances
very deep architectures that work well with backprop and one reason is perhaps because not
only otherwise in terms of so what probably had to solve with known as you
can make the
the himalayas very wide because the
number of parameters was really quickly with the you know quadratically with the number of
and then you get killed by over privatisation so it had to find architectures where
that's not the case we can increase the size of the number of variables that
are manipulated but not the number of parameters that are being trained
and commercial that's the way of doing this
and the other activities this new symmetry is broken it so not every node is
connected to the same set of variables and so naturally they ten two different things
a couple of molecules
so this was one of the first ideas of
elements that come together to form
elements that come together to form molecules
and then there was this gentleman joseph priestley
yes what his occupation was
he was a priest of course and what did he do
he looked at reactions with
deeply just dictated e
people just the kadir reacting with material and what he observed was
these materials reacted more vigorously in the village is located in
well what's def which is located the role of course now we know the which
is the key to areas oxygen here with the nitrogen predominantly removed
but i really took this gentleman well what a
took this gentleman to really understand what previously was doing in his experiments
and what they realized
is that there is a deep logistic air was kept going to the material
when it did this reaction
and he made those observations are came to those conclusions
by doing some very careful measurements of the
before the reactions of the mass of the people just the airports the mass of
the material
and found that indeed the math after the reaction was equivalent to the before the
and so he was one of the first individuals realize that a chemical reaction can
be written down
analogous to writing a
algebraic equations
well what he also
did a lot of work isolating elements identified seventeen medals and nine none of those
well for all of his efforts we all know what happened to look twice yearly
because of his connection to the french monarchy
judge at his trial claimed that the republic has no use for so long
grant at the time the french mathematician
so it took but a moment to
cut through the head but it will require a hundred years to produce another like
but what there was another frenchman at that time gl proved he was a little
more politically savvy
so he high-tailed over two was spain
and let to long and healthful life is professor in madrid
but what is a get some experiments
and he observed that when two or more elements combine well they combined
to borrow compound they always combine in definite proportions by weight and it didn't matter
what the method of preparation ones
and so because he made this observation over and over all over again with many
different elements that became known as the
here of definite proportions again some indication they
matter was the head of the discrete nature to it
it wasn't just the continuance numbers were involved here
right but
it really took this guy
john dalton
english schoolteacher
with a lot of interest
he was aware
of the operations of oil and priestly
and love a improves
and what he realized is that he could begin to understand all those observations
if you went there
all the way to democratise
in democracies idea of animals
four the atoms
these individual discrete particles of matter
so he
that for
some postulate
some postulates which force now know are known as dawkins atomic theory
what he said is that each element is composed of atoms
he said that atoms of any given element are identical
he said they compound formed when atoms more than one element combined
and he realized
of course from love idea is that observations that atoms are neither created nor are
they destroyed
now just on the side
the very beginning
of the competition but it took us more than a year
to understand how to do
use something like this
it's not for it wasn't revealed
to get
the with exploited and this is another effect
and writing of movies
it carries over time for the same movie
some of the some reasons for this less about their housekeeper reasoning you can find
it in the paper about yes at the date of the individual is the average
school tend to be the lowest
i'm just trying to motivate
the interest of the interest in those dynamic
effect in the data
so while i can give the that explanation to those global effects let's talk about
because of such effects on the local level so
i will split two item side effects and use of side effects item side effects
as to have to do with the the fact that
item popularity evolve over time thus and all effects
well that that's out of popular in the fall might not be very popular
the way in the summer
if we talk again about movies if we have the new good movie by
eddie murphy then maybe
all these all movies come back into fashion
and things like this
and also we have use of side effects which probably more pronounced and more complicated
this now we talk about humans which show
creatures i would say and some of them
fundamental like the ability to change the taste
and and and preferences over time
and some just reflect noise
so those are the people can be a bit differently on different on different days
and there
and the made challenges that one needs to address is first set up several sources
to bolster paul dynamics
and the
we want to address all of them all at least
the most the more important ones
then you have a unique characteristics of this problem is that we have my multiple
the usual classification problem we are tracking
well blocking some
the found that we want to separate
but it is on the negatives and overall that can
can go all can go forward some
change we're talking really many
different targets you can say that it uses the forms
the soil on time series conservatism also about items
this way there
the signal peptide target is
israeli scouts you don't you don't get much information values
and the the challenge with which
might be
even more important is that we know that while we have many targets we must
relate all them that's there
essence of collaborative filtering sharing information among many users so even if the user
acted on different time frames we we still want to borrow information between them and
establish patterns causing them
this tool as mournful and rendell
methodologies coming to concept drift
two to be unappealing gail because
we can do things like just underweighting older instances
it will just
the event relating different users for example
let me show you
briefly there
the headlines of what we did was to techniques first one is the matrix factorisation
model which is one of the most popular methods in this field
we take the
rating matrix
well they are also scale represents the user item rating the composer two into two
and metastasis in as first and
but to estimate
the rating by use of five light into for example we look on the
responding again
in fact those taking the inner product and we have the
the age of eighteen
this is quite similar to us do just that we have many unknown lighting so
people come up with
more specialized algorithms to be this
don't of missing that
and also
globalization is is known to be critical here because we don't want to overfit the
view given
ratings but to generalize them to the unknown ones
in this context of modern pinball it it's very important to realize that
some main effects in that and they need to get separated
what we're finding is that there was variability in the that
maybe as expected
is explained by some main effects so then in in this
in the more in the movie rating example we want to
estimate jo jo's looking for the movie six then we
start with some mean writing for
any movie
it just it
well i because the sixth sense is better than average and then a bit lower
because joe tends to lead lo and come up with
some stopped going to fall styles
this would do
quite well in explaining variability in the data
and also much of the temple variability lies field
and then on top of it we model the interaction between between between
joe and in this particular movie like think joe like supernatural thrillers six sense is
one of the kind so is going to like in the movie
so and so this is just nonsense stuff and
then the
in late else it comes out this
the predicted rating for user u and itemize some baseline predictor capturing the overall average
to use of bias the item bias and some interaction them
taking the inner product between the fractals and women were and we minimize the squared
now what's so convenient about this is that this separation tool
use of bias
item bias interaction let us
this temple have effects separately
so we
we expect change us
so in
the rating scale of individual users is mostly
so in the end the network you do sampling distribution because you can propagate points
in the non-linear weighted sum propagate variance points non-linear way it's difficult
so that's what i think was the first one of the algorithm in this community
to deal with this sort of thing you use the sampling approach to that
in the generative topographic mapping
well see some results from later as well
uses group points
into space and then use points of means guassian distributions so two different ways
thank you
probabilistic model
which is quite effective
so in the GP LVM i
the process latent variable model we can take a different approach
that that's the normal probabilistic interpretation of PCA
this is what we had before
we've got an image of the latent variable space and replace the distribution of them
with maximizing with respect to w
to take this to be distribution
they doing that
i consider flip between so you can see the differences
we're going to do something else now
i don't believe in bayesian approaches but on a pragmatic basis i don't believe in
integrating everything i can find i try i stop when i have to start doing
so what
i was interested in his
integrated x now
if x is the variable but also w as a latent variable as well because
parameters are treated such to stochastic variables
and that's the definition of the disease treating approach to stochastic variable so you can
and you have this marginal likelihood but what you can place a prior distribution over
the great
to obtain
the four
you know you might be interested in p of y
the question is well why not try integrating w
if we being bayesian
optimizing with respect to x which is the reason why you might not want to
do that but let's ignore the moment led to see what happens
in this case
bayesian approach w which is of the same form as the prior use ever act
and using the same likelihood we had before
we obtain representation that can be viewed as the dual
the previous marginal likelihood so before
is where all the axes are
well that is why there are
so split between the two
you notice here
we had before
and we've got axes
the other difference is well before
the product was
the individual data points
this is of the design matrix math
design matrix now the distributions over the columns of design matrix of independent is different
this covariance matrix is different
when you this
and you want to maximize the effect with respect to x
and you've got something like this that someone else's maximize expected you are strong position
because you have to have a
so extremely similar to before the maximum likelihood solution to this you can obtain a
solution with respect to x
the dual form before we transpose right here
now we have what transpires that inner product matrix
again we have a little issue with some our content for this the prime here
another unusual notation for prime number in this case you q of the first q
factor vectors all
one of the times e
in the matrix before we had one n times to compare well with the covariance
matrix that and the corresponding eigenvalues are
lambda q
in fact
and is identical because of
relationship between the organ that value problem on the problem and the covariance matrix
so it turns out
then in fact these two formulations actually completely equivalent
the solution for the you
tipping and bishop PCA
is on the covariance matrix and nineteen inverse problem on the covariance matrix now the
the solution to the dual probabilistic PCA
in in the problem on the inner product matrix
the equivalence is from the fact that you can write set satellite vectors projection
of y
along the other side by convective times the i can values which is shed for
both problems
so this is not
and one show you have to derive a kernel PCA i'm not
nineteen because they see what transpires and that's an inner product matrix so this is
the starting to PCA which bernadette developed i guess seven years ago now
but we're not going to do that
one thing to do that because that i did before
and what we do is is now
process likelihood is of this form the probability of some of the observed data given
x is the gaussians with the kernel matrix zoubin showed us this on
so if we select the linear kernel
we notice the likelihood model for dual probabilistic PCA is the product of downstream processes
but here
is on the latent space not on the observed data space
so the joint probabilistic PCA is what i call
to be
you want to be banned as he said love to be to be right and
so on and so on you make it constant number of those changes you the
parents as well
it's only a constant number of links that are changing because number
assignments you need to do
OK you have probably seen partitions before
but we're going to use them
in a complicated way
so let's look at how to do insertions
we'll see it three times in some sense
first outside the basic idea which is pretty simple
mention some of it already and do it on an example feeling
in our bones and then we'll get the
so we go home and implemented if you want it
because this is i should say red black and search
in the book is called RB insert
not for repair
red black
OK so the first thing do is i said is binary search tree insert that
no so x now becomes the newly researcher x were supposed to go
we created new
should call leave now it's now
and node
hanging off an internal node hanging of one of the original nodes maybe we added
right here it now gets too
movies hanging on
it has no internal children
and we get to pick a color for
we will have the color red
why red
would like to request to college because for the coin that might work but it's
going to make our job even messier so
we're adding and you know because no relief presumably so we don't really need to
be blocked by property two
three three every right now has the black hair
might be a problem
problem is if it's apparent is red
then we violate property two
apparently read
thirty three
the good news is that property four is still true
because property forces counting numbers of blackman's down very sparse that's really the hard property
to maintain
we just added red now and the black eyed change and the number of black
nodes along the path changes
so this still has to hold
the only thing we can violate this property three
reasonable we know we've got to highlight something
at the beginning just we can just do a binary search tree insert
let's give it a try
this tree
she so we're
power going to fix this
how do we fix
property three
we're going to remove the violation of three
the tree
so we're going to start node x up towards the roof
this is via three coloring only thing initially will do is we're coloring
until we get some point
where we can fix the violation using rotation
and probably also three colouring
OK so let's see this algorithm in action
copy this tree and you're going to have to copy it to sort of
instead of modifying that
so we have this nice red black tree
and we'll try inserting any value of fifteen
twenty one
twenty two is the new black
OK should be the same tree
so now
i'm choosing the number fifteen to insert because that will show
fairly interesting insertion sometimes assertion doesn't take very much work we just rotation and we're
here i like to look at
an interesting case so insert fifteen fifteen is better than seven is less than eighteen
it's bigger than ten is bigger than levels fifteen goes here
so we add a new
red nodes
it has two
black leaves hanging off of it
replaced one likely now we have two
we violate property three
because we added in the right child of red now so now we have two
consecutive red nose in route to the past
we'd like to make this black but that would screw up the black kites because
now this node would have one black node over here and two black nodes this
so that's not good
what can we do well let's try to re color
this is always
for the last remember
six is going to be to re color
and the first thing that struck me which doesn't work is we try to recall
around here
doesn't look so good because
you know we've got red stuff down here we got black net over here so
we can make this one red and one black quite work
if we look at the little higher
at the grandparent of fifteen
we have a black cloud here and two red children
that's actually pretty good news because
we could instead make that
two black children and the red parent
he locally that's going to be fine
it's not going to change any black kites because any path that went through these
nodes before
will still go through the same number of black nodes instead of going through black
always here it will go through black either here or here because that has always
going to leaves
to this degree of membership to the set of normal people is point three noted
have to add up to point three
and for car power sitting because his car belongs to the set of medium
powered cars to point seven two high-powered cars to point four
you can combine these two things of course
you draw inferences and how true is this will miss a lot and will use
imax operator for example just nokia planes are
a whatever it was i think the numbers should probably not help yes
the point eight the point four you together using the minimum operator both of these
conditions have been true it's will says if age is young and car power is
high so the degree of fulfilment for this was point for how true is the
antecedent to what degree of membership doesn't belong to all these conditions that we have
in our antecedent
of the world one an awful again they are combining these two degrees of membership
and i think it was point three eight point seven so many more for those
who simply point three so this rule this is is also say this is the
degree of fulfilment for a specific rule this point the this is the degree of
fulfilment for rule one which is point four
OK so now we can go on
try to figure out what do we do
without consequences obviously since will is not fulfilled
two two degree of one this consequent shouldn't be part of the result of looking
at this entire will this fall the results so we do now is we
we restrict the consequence that you have you combine them
can so that using again our our minimum one sort of the degree of fulfilment
how much does this person belong to the and the consequent of the world
so the this is the membership function the sort of falls out of rule one
and this is the membership function solid red area of the faults of two
then we combined the two essentially using next norms using in our case he or
operator and this is the final fuzzy set but this will the school system produces
so this is the this is the fuzzy set for the risk of this particular
driver but has age a and try to get insurance for car power to be
this is of course nice and if you look now wanted to use that to
continue computations plug that into some sort of a premium calculator you may actually continue
using the fuzzy sets in our case now want an american value because our insurance
guys are instructed to reject everybody who is in risk ratio of eighty or higher
so we want to create a crisp crisp value out of this one and the
classical way of computing crisp values is
goes on the defensive occasionally want to go back from this fuzzy set to a
crisp number the classical way to do do that the centre of gravity
the centre of gravity just tries to find all the centre of gravity sort of
try to balance this thing with the fuzzy set stick it falls down and they
really do that is you've got interval
why times the degree of membership of the
resulting membership function and you need to normalise it is actually percent of gravity which
is of course nasty to compute slightly easier approximation all doing is i'm going to
look at the fuzzy sets that i have these politicians much pain
now i have one way of doing this is essentially just you this tool but
said that we combined
the centre of gravity tries to balance this sort of a stick it tries to
find out of system has a certain mass this absurd must so probably the centre
of gravity somewhere here for quite abundant in minute just project this
risk and that gives me my are built on fuzzy five dollars that's one way
of doing that but alternatively i can of course also say well if i knew
the centre of gravity for this one
this is my s j
the thank
and if i knew the centre of gravity for this one this is what it
was was not a statement
cool had another membership function here and this is
and then i also know the degree of fulfilment that that's used before i think
that this will too
twenty of my of my to point three i think that's really are
the first world movies the
i could simply multiply those and do a weighted sum which results in
almost the same value right
two authors of the movie get same value here and that's of course and that
is the compute because you don't have to do the integral to actually find out
what that is you want to compute that
in the machine if you want to implement the fuzzy inference is that all you
needed to do was pretty compute the centre of gravity s two and s three
which are always the same for these fuzzy sets and then you can use the
degrees of fulfilment multiply them to and it's great something about
why is that not entirely the same volunteered doing is of course you're this area
you're incorporating that twice computation this weighted sum
and if you do and which is of course not quite the same as doing
the centre of gravity just for this for the
he was area
but in most cases you don't really care it's funny after all anyway
that is another way
to go back from our fuzzy set to a crisp value
and we can look at sort of the fuzzy inference process once again my valuable
such sort of the summary you have three main steps into the classification try to
convert your measurement that you have into degrees of membership for fuzzy sets using inside
fuzzy rule systems
in the inference phase you're evaluating fuzzy rule systems and you're essentially computing degrees of
fulfilment three rules so this very basic rule system if temperature is called and we
open the vault of our heating system if temperature small management half the temperature is
hot and we'll
the degree of fulfilment for this particular measurement of point seven for the first rule
point two the second will so for the third rule we'll combine them creates a
so what do i find i have solved now
the general solution
i will find the x minus
is one half c
and have zero plus
it is also one half c which of course should not come
as a surprise to you
four let me right down now
the general solution that we have
for this specific initial conditions
so we know everything
we know x zero one lenox zero
one minus axial not one example my as we know it zero plus
we know five we know everything
so i'm going to write it down here
x one
it's going to be one half c
number one one
times the cosine
of omega t because phi zero
one half c
this is the miners by the way cosine omega minus two
cosine omega lost
that is
x one
and x two
one half the
the cosine omega minus two minus
one half c
and the the cosine
we got lost
they could be breath substituting that equals zero
you see immediately that ecstasy
and substitute equals here in the second
and you see that x was it
no surprise because that's my
initial condition
i remember from my schooldays at the cosine
o five
was the cosine of data
is twice the cosine of half the sum
times the cosine of half
the difference
so i can write down x one
as twice
the cosine of half the sum
times the cosine of half the difference so that tool that i get each of
these one house
so i get c
times the cosine
omega minor
was omega
was divided by two
i'm speak
the cosine
of omega minus
mine only of course
divided by two
i've just rewritten it in a different form
and x two
as a function of time
i know have the cosine of of minus the cosine of data
that's twice the sign after some time signed
half the difference
now i get you to sign
of omega minus
omega plus
divided by two
times the sign
omega minus minus omega plus
divided by two
thanks to
when t is zero
the sign of this one is zero
consistent with what our initial conditions x two zero remember
all their initial conditions all there was written in different for
imagine now in your mind
these two
frequencies are not too far apart
these equations
the smell
of what
this year is the faster
this one that one
this one
is this love
and so
if these two
and what you'll see is something quite remarkable
t equals zero
this one stand still
and this cosine terms
it's going to be one because these
this one is going to oscillate happily with this frequency
but this still cosine term is very gradually going to zero
and as the cosine term gradually goes to zero
this one will start oscillating
but design for
comes plus one
and so the other one will start to oscillate
and then a little later in time
the cosine term will become minus one
so it starts to oscillate but when that happens is assigned to zero again
so it's pop
so you see a beautiful beach phenomena
the first one gradually come to wall and the other one will pick up
and then the other one will come to hold and then
it is of course consistent with the conservation
mechanical energy
and i want to demonstrate that
we have here
all i have to do is offset
x one over this and see that we can choose
and then
released this one and zero speed and then we'll just watch
now you've got you should see that
strange phenomenon
ready for this
this one after
all place
the set of all sets
and you need
it is the
we're going
that's what i want
you can get
of the two
it's like
you have not heard
so far and
when used
he is very
the same year
seven of
he ran
so long
and as you
it's not for
this is
or is
i don't know how
that where are more
these are
the first part
here he is
so far
what we need
are you know i mean
it is
and also
OK now nearly as well
so this and becomes an in times square
since all are how can you every time window don't do nearly as well the
best role for that time window i mean
what about this thing costly for
nearly as well only make sense of the time windows big if
if the time when the sort and this is not a very interesting statement the
say in that time window i'm only doing this much worse than the best run
time and again
the time and was only alive responsive that's really not a very good guarantee at
all so this can be only make sense for
rules the fire
more than this many times
we think of as for only fires once or twice the now we're going to
really figure out whether it's a good rule or just
you know it just maybe if rules firing randomly and you know how to it
actually stock markets great example
you've got this mutual funds you know the millions of they also it will be
a great the last
you know the last ten months with great but if it is behaving randomly just
by chance some of them are going to great lengths to months
so it's their advanced instantiate many mutual funds they can
like hope one of them that's when they get
students to make more sense later on
they can be so
so anyway it's the same kind of thing here if the world is not fired
very much we really can't tell what really good rule
this is so there is no way to tell verses just by random chance you
know i happen to be walking
so here again even wireless many times in order for this rule to make it
to be meaningful meaningful
OK that's one way
and you can have this property
switching you can instantiate new rules that say
basically just that they start at some point in time the future and so i
think you should use
we talk about that then we talked about things
we talked about minimax optimality and we talked about
place names i also money
how about some more money today
we saw the minimax theorem
the minimax theorem says that
based on a zero sum game in your competing against someone it's competitive game and
so you think that you know if you have to reveal your randomized strategy first
using the information the minimax theorem says that
the there's every zero sum game has a unique value where the row player reveals
the randomized strategy first they can guarantee value is the
one of those games that was four point cents no matter what the other player
does and furthermore the other player in the my strategy they can reveal guarantees they
will not be well defined value the game in particular these regret minimising algorithms give
away to play
the case of the regret minimising out they in fact have the property
so you use one your guaranteeing to do nearly as well as the best fixed
which you could have made in hindsight is what that means is that if the
opponent is playing
the minimax optimal strategy well
there will be some choice in hindsight that gets you value the
you'll you'll be doing this as well as the
but upon is not playing very well maybe it's a complicated game maybe your about
business and the game well maybe not very good at what you you're going to
do is do nearly as well as the best fixed wrapped in hindsight that could
be even better
the the fear upon is not the kind of night nice things you could solve
minimax optimal strategy using
linear programming but if the user and minimizing strategy
you will
they released as well except for the last term
majority i think of problems that people
a study in applied fields are in some way supervised learning problem
the other
it's called unsupervised learning and the reason it's called unsupervised because there's no input so
is no output unit given the signal this is the output i want you to
match you just given a bunch of inputs and ask something vague like fine structure
in the data or cluster the data so unsupervised learning is it's
one of the sirens of applied statistics is very appealing in some way it's very
fun to work on in some sense it's kind of you feel like it's more
purely scientific and yet it has a serious problem that is very difficult to define
what we mean by success in unsupervised learning right in supervised learning it's very easy
to define a very sensible measures of success like classification well what fraction of the
inputs are you going to get right when i test you on some more data
seen before i will talk about that second in unsupervised learning it's not so clear
by show you some data and i say he was measurements of a thousand customers
from the supermarket please cluster them into three groups and you come back and you
say OK i cluster them into three groups and how to evaluate whether you really
did a good job
and that's the problem with unsupervised
a very simple form of unsupervised learning which is very popular in data mining is
called rule learning
in learning and trying to discover
very common joint settings of measurements in the database so maybe it's very common that you see
in a sense this database very common that you see someone who is say
you know over forty
has a university education and owns a car
that triple might be very common and so you might say have a rule which
says if you're over forty and you have a university education that are predicted very
likely to your car
and then the sort of ultimate artificial intelligence problem at some level is called reinforcement
learning and reinforcement learning is really the
the formal study of how do you get agents to act in an unknown environment
so that the general setup for reinforcement learning is that you have a world which
has a number of possible states could be huge number of possible states you have
an agent which can perform actions and every time the agent performs actions and action
it changes the state of the world in the age get either some punishment or
some reward for being in the various states
and now what you want to do is learn what's called the policy which is
the set of rules for the agent to take actions but i don't tell you
the entire i don't reveal to the inner workings of the world that i give
you the big carrot in a big stick
and you take actions in the world and when you do something that i don't
like i beat you over the head and say that was bad and when you
do something that i like to give you some cookies and so that was good
and you have to figure out how to act in the world so that's really
the kind of ultimate agent learning problem right you can imagine that you just take
a robot and you throw it out in the world and it just does random
things and then you know it gets this reinforcement and eventually learns to bring you
the facts and the facts machine cappuccino with it but it's it's difficult it's very
difficult general problem and i'm not going to talk about that and i don't think
that anyone on the schedule this year is going to others
OK great good so
i'll that to that's a very tough problems that on the site OK
so now want to get into some more technical things about machine learning and hopefully
we can we can make some progress and get two
get some some problems
we actually have to do with these graphical models little talk about so
one key issue in machine learning is visual representation
so when i told you that i wanted to take a picture of this this
image represents my face and have you write a computer program that says all that
sam roweis how are you going to
represent the image inside your computer program so every task that you want to do
it involves accepting some input from the real world and that input almost always originates
in some kind of mechanical censor or data recording device or a lot of some
computers somewhere
and then before you can actually process that input you need to convert it into
a particular numerical representation that computer programming and machine learning algorithm can attack
and one example