that you can compute because it's the eighties and they can do with that and
the other is
can be seen as a sum of and to the k tractable dirichlet integral terms
which have been talked about in his talk on tuesday
that essentially you move this summer
z equals one decay out to the front and the integral over fatah
gets pushed in
and see what happens
right and you get into the k
there are usually integrals because their size conjugate to the multinomial but of course we
can't compute and to k
it takes too long
we appeal to approximate posterior inference
of the posterior
and these are things like gibbs sampling or variational methods particle filtering expectation propagation and
so on i know you've been hearing a lot about approximate posterior inference this is
one place where if you wanted to fit this model he would have to use
some form of approximate posterior inference
OK i want to go into some detail about gibbs sampling and variational methods here
OK so
gibbs sampling in general just to remind you
is that we define a markov chain whose stationary distribution is the posterior we care
then collect independent samples from the stationary distribution and approximate the posterior with so we
get like a monte carlo estimate of the expectation say using these independent samples from
the posterior
in gibbs sampling this space of the markov chain is the space of possible configurations
of the hidden variables actually that
true in general SMC
and what makes gibbs sampling special is that the chain is run by iteratively sampling
from the conditional distribution of each hidden variable given the observations and the current state
of of the other hidden variables so
have you seen gibbs sampling rate in the summer school
you've got so that's just review one city is burned and collect samples that lacked
approximate posterior that wagons used to assure us that the samples are independent
williamson yesterday that the samples don't need to be independent for first order expectations which
i thought was interesting
so let's do the gibbs sampler for LDA
so let's define an of the topic assignments to be the counts vector so if
a document has ten words in three them assigned topic fifteen and for them assigned
topic ten and
OK so so
if real time topic fifteen
fifteen gets value three
if for some reason can
if the remaining topic eleven
eleven history appeared successful table
OK so and some fifteen equals three
it's a way of aggregating the council of the topic assignments
so simple gibbs sampler for LDA
is the following
this is wrong
let me ignore that
all right down to give
that's the crazy gibbs sampler for LDA
the simple one
it's just that so the remember
the sampler operates on the basis of data we want
and so
the first step of the gibbs sampler is to compute the post the conditional distribution
of data
you get
w one
these are this is the current state of the other hidden variables
and this is the observations
of of course
you know from the graphical models lecture that a given disease early in the canonization
for now given disease that is independent of w
really data only depends on the disease and because it's the dirichlet and its conjugate
the posterior distribution of data given n draws from data is just a dirichlet distribution
right every following
cognitive psychology ideas started to become popular
works like that of george miller and others but
in particular
we have lots of useful
fragments of theories of learning
and if you you can find a book on
machine learning several books
and each of them describe the few systems
i think
if something a little bit wrong with all of them in the sense that
it's not enough just to learn
if this happens then the results
because if you're going to learn fifty or one hundred million
of these things
then there's the problem of how you retrieve the right ones
when you have to solve the problem
so when you store
memories away
you don't just want to store neural connection between
umbrella and brain
you want to know what kind of problems
you might need this knowledge for
another is i'm saying every fragment of knowledge has to be linked to
the six or seven things what kind of goals would help with
if that fragment of knowledge doesn't work what are the five most similar ones that
you know typical case where it was useful water its major bugs
and so forth
so when we make a theory of learning we want to embed it in something
like that
and the project we're proposing is going to try to do a lot of things
OK the book
has a whole chapter six
the book discusses the problem of representing knowledge and it suggested that whenever you learn
something you'd better learn it in six or seven different ways has this story like
script as
as network neural network
it has various kinds of traits
kinds of inference structures and so forth
and i end up with this sort of picture of the brain
as having
different ways to represent
things on different structural levels and
when we build
are a i version of this we probably don't need to emulate the very low
levels of the nervous system
because i think the middle levels of the nervous system are mainly
for getting rid of the biochemical
features of the lowest levels
synopsis have all sorts of interesting properties
many of which have not changed since we were jellyfish
same chemicals the same synoptic and plates
and so forth are
in all animals
however the higher levels of the human brain are made of these cortical columns
each of which have five or six hundred cells
and my bet is that the cortical column is an elaborate structure
you know what a computer is made of transistors it's made of flip-flops
why use flip-flops
because transistors are ugly they have these curves and
strange properties
but if you arrange to
transistors in the positive feedback loop
all of those little beautiful ugly properties of the physics go away
and the flip-flop is either on or off and now you can build the structure
like this to
with four billion instructions
and it actually does what it says almost all the time
whether you like it or not
so you see
i'm not a connectionist i'm an installation artist
the important
o thing to understand about the brain is how did we
is that we became ideas we became able to have abstract thoughts because we found
ways to get
higher level computation to be independent of the properties of individual neurons
that's not popular among my
x neurological friends
i think i'll just stop and
see if there are any questions because
this must raise
unlimited numbers of those
here we have assumed the microphone
one is
all use
moreover if you've got long list of parameters is really the joint distribution of cameras
you better be assessing how we're supposed to get right that's kind of becomes really
hope how do you do that well these start making independence assumptions for throwing the
man because if i say what's that i can think separately about this and think
sort about human domain experts get and start thinking about it i really mean you
based on the floor the question really is asking the right prior
simply for computational reasons you to start writing a list of independence assumptions and that
we we may have left kind of optimality behind
and now it's subtle question issue but just as important as the others is that
it's really hard to get domain experts to assess tail behaviour
what everyone real valued qualities which of course most of our models are as you
go higher up in the hierarchy they start to become real numbers with the probability
of some discrete thing probably the real number you've got a problem that
so has tail behaviour have to worry about what tailed behaviour
like i get my mother told about the mean and standard deviation something which she
kept telling about whether it's love plus tails or or t tails are
what right
i don't think you could either i don't think i could
it's really hard to assess those things is also hard to kind of learning foreign
hard to get an idea how that matter also bayesian models it doesn't matter that
much but lots of emails to really does matter a lot of that in some
cases determine the entire output of your procedure
and this is a really serious issues so you often hear people talking about bayes
factors and marginal likelihoods how do you so model selection problems of bayesian marginal likelihood
has the kneejerk answer calculate that
well the marginal likelihood is the integral of like that under the prior
so i think little under posterior which to sharpen up and tail behaviour is married
under the prior to the tails are there
the integral is very fat tails can be largely familiar tales that in the prior
so the marginal likelihood can be you know hugely determined you know affected by the
way your assumptions
these factors similarly bayes factors are ratios of marginal likelihoods and so one way you
might try to go say well use improper priors you know try to make them
flat sum up very assumptions under in i think you may know marginal like that
if you have any prior to have an improper prior has an arbitrary constant
and those things will tend to divide out when you things like posteriors but in
marginal likelihoods they and basically they don't have a ratio of arbitrary constants
so the bayes factor is meaningless in that case
it's really serious issues and there's a lot of statistical literature on this
there's things like
intrinsic bayes factors and fractional bayes factors various kind of ways to approach this but
if you don't try to please think about those things you you know it's not
it's not the solution it's not the hamlets of the model selection problem
OK so tail b is a big issue nonparametrics a lot of us in fact
when we're bayesian had is a researcher in various the nonparametrics have about a decade
they it's great it's awkward for subjective bayes because it's really complicated nonparametric bayes models
hard to think about the stick breaking things an infinite objects and so on and
what's my subjective prior on those things
so let's that debate that are not very happy with the nonparametric bayes movement
so you may eventually worked out but it is is currently an issue
OK so that's kind of some of the problems that arise i believe them her
because i really think there is the time sort say the bayes played so easy
and systematic you know how could anyone do anything else with the real issues that
come up in real life
in the last one is more philosophical which is just that a lot of frequentist
don't like sort of subjective bayesians storytelling the certain method i like the support vector
machine is works
right i got lots of applied situations i'll will roll it out and it works
really well is also capture everyone's happy i get paid in the company you know
it makes money
what's wrong with that
well it doesn't have a bayesian interpretation is obvious when you might really but it
was really hard to find one that's pretty that have one right
well have to wait around for someone to show me basically the user no i
so i'm talking about the identification of anglican vibration they that this is a joint
work with michael e christian was last team
o from the university of hildesheim in germany and which is why whom young and
mark waters from
so first i would like to motivate this topic and then present the problem in
more that
and show our approach of with identification
was an iterative hough transform using background knowledge
finally i want to evaluate our approach and conclude
so i think everybody knows jet engines after they have been designed need to be
certified before going into service
because the component
in the engines exposed to unsteady forces so this can cause high cycle fatigue that
means the image in the end
and at the moment most of the analysis is done manually
there where we want to help with machine learning
the vibration is the mechanical oscillation
of the response of
the stimulus and can be
expressed by the equation of motion
important terms here are the natural frequency so each component has the serial series of
natural frequencies has acquired quite eigen modes
and the second term is the excitation frequency which is the time has periodic excitation
caused by
there were two with vacation motion
if this too
frequencies intersect we have resonance
so very high amplitude
the high stresses which need to
high cycle fatigue
this can be
team here we have our campbell diagram
where we have the speed on the x axis and the frequency on the y
axis and the horizontal lines are the eigen modes
and diagonal lines are the expectation orders and you see the possible
resonance points in the middle we see more realistic camper diagram was acquired that might
they have the same access
and you have a color encoding which shows the empty
one of his vibration this idea can present this as a three d image
well you see the peaks the amplitude of the vibration there
so vibration analysis contains several steps you make some let measurements like you capture the
mode shape
i can frequencies you do this only for some components for
then you have finite element model so we have predictions for the i can more
for item frequency
from the finite element model
and of course you do all engine testing and the running conditions
then the engineers do analyse the vibration data on the left they then and data
and the first one to identify these i modes in order then to extract the
peak stresses so that the residents points
and to calculate and endurance
so where we want to help in their identification of eigen modes
and we have given a set of images containing a set of lines which is
sort is that the horizontal lines
which are usually numbered from one to in our dataset twenty five more
and you have background knowledge so let data this also aligned so it's there are
horizontal lines without the slope
i will show this later
and if the predictions for the i can frequency
so our aim is to take detectors lines in the campbell diagram
and to assign more numbers
to this detected lines and which the quality
of the last s e models
so our approach is to fold we have first the line detection which is unsupervised
and then they annotate automatic annotated edition of these detected lines with supervised
so we are using an iterative approach for the detection of lines we're using have
for this we also incorporate background knowledge from the left
data and from the from the FIM
so let's have transformed actually very old
technique feature extraction technique
he was image analysis
applied for extraction of lines are out of parameterizable shapes
so as you know line for example could be
described by y offset and
so in this case the slope is
and angle better
and what we do here is we
i have an image i and into the world that are mean that the money
when we go over all pixels in this
and overall
angus in this interval and calculate the transformation transformation is
minus x times that the tangent of that
and then we
this the colour value of this
at the position that and y o which is the transformation we don't do this
for the neighborhood because our lines he was see later are not
complete clear lines but they are blurred
so there is some
some kind of noise
so we ought to add some value to the neighbouring points
in the end we return accumulator array with this transformation
and we assume that
the higher value
correspond to the lines in the image
here an example
you have a very
however image in the euclidean space where you have
very clear lines and you have the heart
based on the right side
where we have the english so there is no on the x axis and y
offset on the y axis and to see where the dark points are these points
are maximise the accumulator array and correspond to the lines on the left-hand side
this is in very simple and easy
but now if you look at this image you see the real
campbell diagram see
there are several i can modes there are some
some expectation are those which are
this one
in front of the arrow will start the next lecture and go this way so
it's easy to do it right
if I added on 1 of these vectors it would go left 1 another to
those would were left 1 another
to would probably get that there may be other dotted lines
OK as 1 of color
tacked onto the end but I wanted to talk on 2 of to
so that the 2nd 1 with a lot of the left 1 to also would
probably there
and there's another so someone I put in here is to
of column 2
at all
and where did I and
1 of the coordinates of this
what do I get when I take 1 of the 1st 2 of them
I do get that of course
there it is there it is x 0 is 3 that's the
that's the that's the answer we wanted
and otherwise do it
you see I do it just like the 1st component I haven't you and and
a minus 2 produces a 0
and the 2nd component a minus 1 enough 4
they combine to give the 3
but look at this picture
so that our key picture I combined this column and this column to get maybe
I better forget this
that was the big
that's 0 3
so that the idea of linear combinations is crucial and and also do we wanna
think about this question
your why not what are all the combinations if I took can I go back
to x is and it is this is this is the question for review
what works
it's gonna come up over and over but why don't we see at once now
if I to all the axes and all the wise color combinations
what would be all the result
and actually the result would be
that I could get on the right hand side of
the combinations of this
and this would fill the hole playing
you can take that away you will
this is the exploring further
but this idea of what linear combination gives me
and what do all the linear combinations give 1 all the possible achievable right-hand sides
B. that's going to be based OK can I move to
3 equations in 3 unknowns
because it's easy to
picture of the 2 by 2 cases
let me do a 3 by 3 examples
OK started the same way so maybe 2 X minus Y and they don't take
note no diseases 0
and maybe a minus X is to Y and maybe I minus is is of
so 0 let me make that a minus 1
and just for a variety that take care of minus reasoning
minus 3 wise should keep the wise and that line and forwards is
say for
that's 3 equations
and in 3 dimensions x y z
I don't have a solution
so I want to understand the equations and solve
OK so how do I hardly understand the role picture is 1 way the column
picture is another very important work does let's remember the matrix form you
that's easy a matrix form
what's our matrix A R matrix a is this right hand side the 2
the minus 1 and 0 from the 1st row
the minus 1 the 2 and the minus 1 from the 2nd row is 0
0 the minus 3
and the form
of the 3rd
has 3 by 3 nights
3 equations 3 unknowns and what the right hand side of course it's of the
bacteria 0 minus 1 for
so that's the way uh will lets the shorthand
to write out the 3 equations
but it's the picture that I'm looking for today OK so the role picture
but but but but but but
right cell
I'm in 3 dimensions x y and z
and I wanna take those equations 1 at a time
and make a picture of all the points that satisfy that take equation number 2
if I make a picture of all the points that satisfy all the x y
z points
but some of this equation
well 1st of all
the origin is not 1 of them
x y z is being 0 0 0 would not solve that equation so what
what some pointed to solve the equation as the maybe if x is y
y and z could be 0
that would work right so there is 1 point
I'm looking at this 2nd equation here just
has to start with let's see also I guess if z z could be 1
x and y could be 0 so that would just go straight up that acts
and probably 1 asserted point here
let me take x to
the x to be 0 z to be 0
then why would be minus half right
so there is a 3rd point
when attacked business your horses that china given that his wife is that what do
you do not now what we do we in part of machine from south korea
that can be placed on building sites it produces building citing insulation together i don't
know much about construction of agreed efficiency that we put this machine we allow IP
here from some folks in self city we
exported to kuwait
i said you do not from here i said i seem to see
how to communicate with the kuwaitis
this is actually in the three point o edition of the book is all i'm
not making this up folks he says well you know we got the winnebago indians
here in winnebago indian tribes in the winnebago indians have casino with things
and when the biggest spins of an enormous amount of cash to the winnebago indians
from one of biggest created the winnebago indian development corporation which created ad agency for
winnebago kids went higher arabic speakers from the local university and the right to purchase
we can import the machine from south korea and our IP here they write the
the the directions forward from the winnebago indian development corporation
and he re exported to kuwait
you show me where that shows up in the economic statistics i'm sure it does
but that is people doing whatever can be done and
so much of that is happening today i see it everywhere i go
which leads to me the second rule
of the flat world platform
and the second rule for me is the most important economic competition
going forward in the world today is i don't believe can be between countries and
countries of the obvious important is that imaging companies and companies although obviously still important
i think the most important economic competition going forward is going to be between u
and your own imagination
because when you have the world is flat
and individuals are this empowered to act on their own imagination globally
what individuals imagine
and therefore how well a university country state schools
it inspires enables and empowers
individual imagination
i think will be the single greatest competitive edge
in the world we're going to
the third rule this platform is how well you horizontal lines how well you learn
to collaborate
on this platform
will i think produce
the most important productivity gains
and therefore huge competitive advantage
spoken about this before i learned this lesson really right when starting to write the
book quite by accident i was going to visit my daughter who was going to
school in new haven connecticut i live in the thousand
to get from this is the maryland in new haven connecticut is a complete pain
in the behind you have to drive almost an hour to baltimore airport take southwest
airlines from baltimore to hertford airport and red one hour from hartford new haven economical
london quicker
they remind myself and i know many of you flown south south west but you
don't look like the southwest crowd to me that's OK and southwest airlines you know
is el airlines you don't get to reserve it's going to take it this is
a b or c is bought first is bought second season were latterly thing you
need to know about southwest airlines is you do not want to be seen on
southwest airlines especially if you have two bags spring clothing for your daughter and you
don't want to get stuck in the middle see no problem mean get guided e-ticket
thing ahead of time but just in case
i got to BWI baltimore airport ninety five minutes before my life because i was
going to be in a
got machine took my visa card stuck in the southwest e machine out kim i've
take it said
i said son of this thing is fixed this is right this is what's the
las vegas there's no way i'm a b on you're ninety five minutes before his
flight there's no way i'm a bit
o hours me got my son upon set in the back of the lot
well forty five minutes went by and then they called flight
then i thought
all that is
seem to be getting getting carrying what looked to me like just crumpled white homes
as if they had grown wine
at twelve one PM the night before
and download print out their own barcodes and water masses well what i didn't know
back then
west southwest airlines
was that the world was flat
and this new platform
they can empower their customers to go online and download print out their own barcodes
and boarding passes
take up all the aces before transferring got to the airport
i looked at that friends freedman you are so twentieth century i mean really think
you're so globalization one point was a one was ticket is good employee number thank
you might want to go to baltimore then we can take machine we thought that
was cool
and then
while you were sleeping
you the individual
became your own ticket which
or look at another way you the individual became an employee of southwest airlines
or look at actually still another way you the individual if you value your own
time stirring up trouble one day and the night before actually a southwest airlines to
their employed
have a nice day OK
so i get smart next time i stay up till twelve or one am i
downloaded my own barcode boarding pass i get to the gate thirty five minutes before
this stuff
because i have interacted with southwest airlines horizontally now not vertically
what happened
i captured sixty minutes
of products
by interfaces southwest airlines on this platform horizontally not vertically
well that move from vertical to horizontal is happening as i said million campuses in
a million businesses and we get to the other side of the people who do
it best
i'm gonna capture enormous productive
think of the productivity gains if you can measure them
all these people
interacting with MIT
not vertically getting on a plane coming here to lecture but interacting
with MIT horizontally
i would be fascinated if someone could actually measure the incredible educational productivity gain you've
given birth to
so those are the to me the three rules of this platform that means several
things i think for our society and how we organize ourselves which makes the current
election campaign
make you want to really we
because it means that it means several things first of all i i used to
be freed
i'm not anymore today
i do not not free trade now
doing that is very simple it says that match the moments of the distribution
this is an example from some
real data from game played on the games console
and the red and blue show two players and this data set of of several
hundred players and all the bottom is the number of games they've played two seasons
over the course of several hundred games
and this is what happens with you know so this is their skill level you
see as they play games their skill level evolved for these two particular players this
skill levels actually been increasing as a result of playing games of obviously winning quite
a lot of games
this is what happens in
in two school system the bayesian ranking system
is that it converges very much more quickly about an order of magnitude more quickly
and intuition for this is the following this connector example you're one hundred thirty nine
hundred twenty in any low what happens in the rule says that if you find
the the winner my score increases a little bit yours decreases little bit
in the bayesian approach we have two variables for every person having mean and variance
so let's design and a hundred and twenty but i'm i'm quite new and played
many games huge uncertainty in my in my skill levels one hundred twenty plus minus
twenty or something we don't really know very much
about my skill level so you can play a long time you're a hundred and
thirty but we got you know down pretty tightly nine hundred thirty plus or minus
if i beat you
that kind of in one step we could increase my scale up to about one
hundred twenty nine we know that been somebody who scale is is very definitely up
so by having the uncertainty as well as the mean analysis when appropriate to make
very big changes
which is something we can't if we just have a single score for each player
and because the order follows automatically from the rules of probability we don't have to
put that into some sort of ad hoc factor that just happens when we do
the probabilistic inference so result is that the we can get good estimates of skill
factors in about of water minus two fewer games than with the live
we can extend the model
is that a
what does
although by as one of
you can you can certainly make bigger updates if you wish but then the problem
is that those of a lot us on
he is also
yes i mean you you know you're you want a principled approach is going to
do the right thing and you don't know how big to make those updates because
you don't have that uncertainty
so you can make more aggressive updates i won't
the risk of having an unstable
unstable systems
because you don't always want to make a big update
and if all variances with very large there isn't actually much evidence
if you've got very large variances strongly overlapping there is much evidence make big changes
to the means of distribution
the value of the system is
our model that we use to variables
i mean and variance
this is going to be
he used
let's keep that the key difference
it was the questions
you can't
great that's my next few graph great question was another question what are the
this is basically estimating the mean square is
one of the things
well i is the don't
but the problem is all
o form is something
different types of reality
we know what
and in addition
many questions
sure i mean if you want to introduce if you if you don't want that
if you don't want that title assumption then effectively putting extra links into the graph
that night in computational complex problems
i guess my glib answers show you design the graph and then you run the
inference algorithms effective you're asking to make fewer independence assumptions and therefore tried links the
the first is
great question so when when his EP can work well i might want to redirect
the number of species
and this can be done last case so there is called needs is that there
are and big projects nowadays running out there is that they be populations several thousand
or tens of thousands of people
that systematically look at that you know
not whole DNA because we know that ninety seven to ninety seven percent is not
just for us but that just focus on the regions that vary between my got
around each pole by the
make i can't
so this provides a huge amounts of data that there is something i will i
will talk to you the next which is called DNA microarrays
if you read the
journal of machine learning you in the world in my career because has become one
of the big topic that is using a lot of
machine learning thing the micro user way too
i will present second is a way to measure the quantity of furniture for that
picture of how the genes are used and what what has been done here is
that fall to make the DNA microarray there after to the first few minutes of
the technology because it is my is
all sorts of is quite small
so you need to have technology
to put it on the second sit around but what's more important is that the
designer career nature
because of the processes that one interesting this species sequences that you tend to this
original site of the gene is assumed the genome the of the genes that code
for the human the genome and we can estimate can find twenty thousand genes and
one the genes
there is no way to tell this user to put them on this my career
and i think we give you the amount of of
are this for the genes so this technology is only possible thanks to the genomes
technology can
the other technologies will no longer be further like this feature that was studying the
nature use and not where is very confusing at first sight but it is a
big graph
well it not corresponds to one protein
so this is not arguments for these you like one thousand proteins and
you have fewer edges between the properties that correspond to the fact that two proteins
can interact physically
so properties of molecules and when they did so they are physically and most of
the functions functions that made by interactions between proteins that form complexes draw and what's
interesting that this map was built using some automatic technology called used two hybrid is
not this the only one of its possible nowadays
to systematically and capture the physical interactions between proteins of between proteins in the wrong
so get this is quite well
it was made in thinking to thousand two for the first time we have some
overlap of
this is so this is one view of the set of protein of this of
with a global map of how they interact with each other so we see that
you can start with some ideas of the organisation of the thing is not linear
least of thousands of what is you start with some of these of who is
connected with whom we sit around and using in these graphs is becoming a very
important place
i was skip the things that one important things that is developing very fast these
days and times that we require more and more by the case
is the field of proteomics
so the problem is is is and you were just designed just two
refer to the analysis of the protein contains and one what technology very
one very useful technologies mass spectrometry so much different is what allows you to measure
the quantity of proteins
a simple and there were big advances in fishing high ionisation technologies that allows you
know this to have mass spectrometry analysis of samples the content of thousands of protestant
simple and because so here again there is these technologies of high position that when
you couple them with the genome because for the phenomenon of the genes
you know the sequence of the gene is something because of the sequence of the
proteins and then because sequence of the protein can analyse the results of spec experiments
because perspective to give you a sense of
short sequences
OK and you can add them to the genome to discover whether proteins
so it's a bit like DNA microarrays where we have a new technology that coupled
with the knowledge of the genome allows you to balance lies the global data in
proceedings of the cells
so what is to be here is that all these things are quite few
and they produce huge amounts of the suppose we want to simple
like yeast or like a consortium more you can you can have its genome you
can put it on microarrays gets expression of the genes you can put it in
my space to get the quantity of proteins you can compare people who can conditions
that there are and all the things to provide data that now we need to
analyse in order to get the better features of what's going on and it's
just one more DNA microarrays because as presence may be useful for you to know
least so this is the typical shape of microarrays used for cheap get what's important
is the square here despite the square well after exponential
idea is which is like a fuzzy picture with had this choice made of now
nowadays millions of the cells
each pixel corresponds to one spot
OK and its parts gives you
the quantity
one of our days
the corresponding to a given sequence of the
following this is this is a very big issue zoom on one ball one part
of the square what to do with simplified which is that the goal here is
to capture the are in this and the fact that the answer is our single
strand is very similar to DNA and that there is a very nice property of
chemistry which is that want to have two single strands with complementary sequences so should
actually works pretty well
there was some contest
so this is key
knowledge decision in data mining conference
as various prediction challenges
in nineteen ninety eight they had some
prediction sounds interesting importance weighted prediction problem
i think spam optimisation problem so
you're working for a charity
you want to send out flyers saying give us money
but you don't want to not fires because that their lives are expensive
in this somehow
who's going to give you my fusion and fly who will not and then
in the ideal case you can just send flowers on the people who will give
you money
the standard way to turn images in terms of profit
this is where the winner was
if use that very simple piece of code
with naive bayes you get here with this naive bayes do it was the winner
the decision tree
you do
and i would support vector machine you still have
and there
to earn problems were rejection sample so much the problem the complete
while doing that
i think it's worse than that
you could get really unlucky
nicky rejection sample
and it is so small you can solve the problem
serial always point five
no matter what
the most that data
could lead to problems
this issue is if you rejection sampling is smaller datasets
is that unless you have something to answer is certainly yes
my favorite example of how this can mess you up
is if you're trying to learn
so the function is trying to learn is a parody of a subset of your
let's say want to bits for a feature space
and you will learn a parody subset
and then the number of
samples you need
information theoretically is is is
according to the number of features
it's the same number of features because
you solve this problem is to try to get the nomination
and then you can with the bits stuck
if you lose one sample
you have system
but it seems that in practice
that's not the way
problems really are
so in practice it seems to work pretty well
OK so
some results performance i think we can assume that
basically every method was tried on this
o link is not how can thing about this is that we didn't do in
nineteen ninety eight we invented this later
but it still some fairly compelling because it's a very simple our them
which is sort of a tried and true technique and does reasonably well
OK so
how you from importance weighted classification classification
he questions about that
OK so this one is a bit more
and i go from
class probability prediction to classification
trying to predict that is the definition
it's the same
the problem is the same as for
but now we're trying to make a probabilistic classifiers
which predicts some value between zero and one
trying to minimize are area
minimize the squared
that's the probability
zero was point five gives particular axe
we would want this value to be
o point five
because that would minimize
expected value here
if you think about this right here realizes also regression
police special kind of aggression et cetera kind of aggression where
always observed zeros or ones
you want to predict the probability of zero one
this is like regression
but it is fairly common to use the log loss so the way i was
defined as
a b
log of one over
the probability of class that actually you
probably the predictive capacity observed
this man
so so long as pretty interesting and the reason why it's the interesting is because
about it
and is unbounded it turns out
you can't do it in this framework
this is the fundamental difficulty in front of the field is that man and it's
exactly so
if you have
the classifier
which exercises before range of values
there's no way
actually from reduction
in the free market i'll tell you
you can easily avoid that you can you can have a classifier clips totaling predicting
that's identifying common
so what the common it's words to you or to the reader of the code
telling you what's going on inside the
these comments
frankly are brain damaged or computationally challenging if you prefer
why in the world i have to tell the reader the non-binding next to the
value three and putting them in the to make a point
in general
good programming styles says you put in comments that are going to be valuable in
helping you as the reader
i understand what's going on inside the cover
it could be what's the intuition behind this piece of code could be preconditions i
want to have an input it could be explanations of specific things are doing but
you need to have those comments there
so this becomes a little bit of one of those motherhood and apple pie kinds
of lectures your mother always told brussels sprouts because it was good for you
this is the brussels sprouts common everybody goes yeah comments course course around comments and
they never do
so my challenge to you and know professor good taken do this my challenge to
you is
a year from now
come back and look at code wrote here
can you still understand what it was you were trying to do
john if you agree right if you can read the code a year later even
code you wrote yourself it's a good sign that you put good comments sense
second good pieces style theories is choice of variable names
these are lousy
deliberately OK
i'm just using simple things like x and y and z because i wanna make
to get through the lecture if you like but in general the choice of variable
name is a great way of commenting your code
use variable names that make sense
a little problem sets zero that you did
read in a couple of values probably store them away
my i bet is use simple names like x and y
much better name would have been first name last name is the name of the
variable to tell you what you're trying to capture the
the other piece i want to say about
variable names is what i have that choice of variable name i can use it
but in fact there are a few things that i can't use in terms of
variable names so
these an important way of documenting
but there are some things excluded and in particular there are some keywords
the is going to use have to be excluded
let me highlight that
as i said right now that's just text following when to say this away
not that way to say this away
with the subscript the suffix rather PY to make it a python file
you know know it's already there but i want to do it
and i get some wonderful colours
these are important
so notice what i have up to now comments appear in red i can see
there's a keyword
the highly right up here print
which is another with the colour is orange
there's a function in purple there's a string in green
and black i have the assignment statement
that print is the keyword
it's a command
i found to do something
as a consequence i can't use it as a variable name
think about it per second if i wanted to use printers variable name how do
i get the system is a system to decide to do i want print as
a value for something that i want print as comment
so there is a sequence of these are blocked out and i'm trying to think
about twenty eight
something like that he is right twenty eight keywords that are blocked
o find them as we go along
having done this now i can simply go ahead run this in fact if i
go up here to run you'll see of both an option to check the module
in this case i'm just going to run
that's what happened
ran through that sequence of instructions in particular access to the value three
and then it took x times ex-cop multiplied by courses nine bound that
the value of x
and then i printed out the value
now it's sitting there waiting for an input knows what it printed out that little
it appeared to ensure number and that's what is printed out so i can enter
and the prince it up
it's right again
actually for that i can just use unlucky function five
which works so let me try again
we were around that module
what happened
it into number i didn't give it strength and it still took it
well this is one of the places where i want to come back to that
highlighting what do things to do
even though my statements enter number
in particular i input here simply takes in a set of characters
treated as the strength
and in principle back out
so if in fact i wanted to make sure this is the number i should
have done something like to try and convert it to another which course fail here
or put the check their is
so way reminding you are going to be careful about the types of things i
put him
still boring so let's
step on accelerator
what i have now
the following
i can write expressions
combinations of things to get it
pretty much
but literally all i can do this stages right what we would call a straight
line progress
is a program
in which we execute
which we execute this sequence of instructions
one by one
don't want to repeat in there and then you go from
OK to j somehow using vertices are not
this should be
pretty intuitive again i can draw
picture so i you never go k that's
this was reminded of i j
using things only one to k minus one in other words you don't we here
we have to use one to case so this is don't use k
so does this thing
or use case somewhere in the middle there
it's got to be one of the two and this case you go from i
to k
using only smaller vertices because you don't want repeat k
and here you go from ten to j
using only smaller labeled vertices
every path is one of the two
so we take the shortest of these two
some problems
the answer now we have a min of two things stakes constant time to compute
so we get a cubic
so let me write it down
this is the floyd warshall
you give it the name again
given the matrix and it's all to now
because everything you copy see today a
that's the warm operates time zero sequels
and then
you just have this these three loops for every value can for every value and
i am for every value j
you to compute that men and if you think about it a little bit that
man is the relaxation
so i
that is the floyd warshall
running time is clearly
three saloons constantine size
so we are finally getting something that is
never worse than bellman ford and the sparse case is the same in anything denser
the number of edges superlinear this is strictly better than domain four
and it's better than anything we've seen so far for all pairs shortest paths and
this handles
negative weights very simple algorithm
even simpler than the one before it is relaxation within three loops
what more could you ask for
i mean you check that this is indeed what mean we're computing here except the
superscript remitted that's again a bit of
i'm handwaving and it is OK to limit subscripts because that can only mean that
you're doing more relaxations then you should be doing more relaxations can never
in particular we do all the ones that we have to
therefore we find the shortest path weights
again here we are assuming that there is no negative weight cycles
it shouldn't be hard to find but you have to think about that
a little bit
you can run another round of bellman ford c relaxes any edges again for example
and there's no nifty trick for that version
OK and we're going to cover this or second album
for all pairs shortest paths before we got the third out of them which is
going to be the cleverest of of
so one one ring to rule them all
this which challenges
we're going to take a little bit of the diversion side story i have
and talk about transitive closure briefly this is just a good thing to know about
and it relates to
the islands were some so far
so here's transitive closure problem
i give you directed graph and for all pairs of vertices i and j i
want to compute this number is one
if there is a path from i to j
so here
ten and zero otherwise
OK this is sort of like an adjacency boring adjacency matrix with no weights except
it's about pounds instead of
being about edges
OK so how can i compute this
was very
how to compute the this called the track this gives me a graph in some
sense this is the adjacency matrix of the new graph called the transitive closure of
my input graph
breath first search
only need to do
it's find shortest paths they if the weights come out infinity then there's no path
is less than then there's the pattern
so here
and then
you can do naive even depriving it of naive bayes
OK so
it's nice
and then you can have a decision tree
and you can just tell decision tree tell probability right now will tell you
vote at all these maybe some sort of
modified version vocalists
or you can tell you it's a tree you can runs bagging technique and of
the decision tree
how does bagging twenty nine works
particular data
new sample with replacement from
similar times you data
see this is the same size
but only have about two thirds of the data and be some duplicates
and you can only decision tree and this
repeat this process many different times
and then you can look at the vote across the different classifiers that you learn
to predict the probability
and you know this doesn't this is like the margin
it's not that this vote doesn't tell you the probability
i mean if it works pretty well in practice
and then
you can run the scrubbing of c four point five
they've also experiments with logistic regression which turned out to be much like support vector
if you look at what the smallest thing is here
it's often
probing into good college of
c four point five
it's a bit hard to see everything because
so far away and the difference is that too large
but it turns out there are some of the better than than everything else
most editors would
because closest competitor
four point five back to see people one five with withdrawing
it was the best known to qualify with bagging
and then
a few hours one occasionally
there was a question
the differences are
and the
with this graph to tell you
the first say
i'll tell you personally that
there there is no
throw it is for this to work right so it was kind
effect somewhere in the data or anything there is this is all about
so the the parties saying it works maybe has decided maybe not
it's not really significant
OK so
the french works
so this is track we're gonna use
throughout the rest of this lecture
which is that for the analysis
it's extremely convenient to analyse only one classifier to to to
and analyse the case released only one classifier
it turns out a time you have about of different classifiers
you can
i think about them is
one classifier
so what you do this
it is you just think about taking over here
protocols and
meaning union in them together and coming together
getting all these sets together
and in the major
but the real inspector lewis is sort of the in
the concatenation of the measures
the mixture of the measures
and then you can think about running
the learning algorithm
on the concatenated dataset
to get one classifier
that will take you to do
if you put the name of the classifier
inside the feature space
it's not that you want to this in practice
we actually have an experiment was very much
to do we just run
one different classifiers reached recipe
right wonderful learning our
theoretically at least you could just run your narrow and once
with the name of the classifier embedded in the feature space
and then
when she had this one classifier
you can get all your all classifiers
but just
you know putting the name
it is a threat to take me to compel call centre and one cup
this trick is theoretical at the moment there have been no experiments one way or
another about how it works in practice
so this trick means
so you can think about
from the distribution of c
it's going to be
evaluated on
so you can you see multiple times
and there's some
particular major
or how you
and the way that you you you draw from that major
you draw from the original distribution
need to be uniform ran away from p
you value it
think gives you distribution over x
cross p
forrest recipe cross while which is hidden when you annihilate
so this is the basic fact that we're gonna use over and over again
to clear
one of the classifier to do
once you have prospered
i think
now there is no
this all the training happens here
and in particular training have incentive of
a right so
are introducing two
importance weighted classification in importance weighted classification just binary classification
at the level of binary classification which is run a a
and everything happens all the training happens in this step
OK so
this district
is mathematically convenient
it's motivations empirically are unclear at this point
if we you want to maybe not
because you you one reason why might want to
one reason why we why we might not
one reason why you might want to
is that
this algorithm
is computationally intensive
right your learning learning over the multiple different times
and that takes a bit of work
here so
if you just run running is the waiter and learning and once then maybe you
can get the same result
questions about how to explain these observations and then i'll show you some more algorithmic
application but things where you will be how can we exploit this these things the
previous steps to do something useful
basically the plan for the rest is
the goal
and the first about the network evolution OK
to give you a bit of context
the idea here is that basically we've taken network the
do do some analysis find some
they do some empirical analysis and this empirical findings on real networks lead to new
network models so for example one such very classical example is the observation that networks
have something but is called probability distribution right so if i was a lot which
means the number of neighbours who having the networks the probability of seeing such an
island in the body so long as i get this straight line right so this
is observed
i think exactly ten years ago
OK and then you ask what is a good model of the
networks such as statistical properties for example such one what is called preferential attachment that
basically defines how a new node joins the network and how it creates its edges
so that if using such you would get such approach OK and basically then we
say that this model explains this problem and
many such models make assumptions or predictions about also the network properties i can generate
the network using such rule and met some of the statistics and try to see
whether it matches not
so it seems this model inferential evolution evolution that says that they specify how not
join the network we can ask whether this model say about the network evolution
and i guess it using this like many thanks so basically the first question we
be asking what is the relation between the number of nodes and the number of
edges in the network
right and for example the model i i have seen before
i showed before assumes that the average degree is constant over so any node overcoming
coming to create five percent
if you look at the data it turns out that this is not so important
thing here is the number of nodes a particular point in time in the number
of edges a particular point in time
and i'm putting this on log scale and basically what you can see that
the falls on the line
and the other observations that this line has a nontrivial slow
which basically means that the relation between the number of
nodes and the number of edges over time follows this power law relationship is polynomial
where the exponent equally densification exponent is greater than one right so previous work assumed
that his age was one what see something greater than one right able to do
that would mean everyone is connected to everyone and everyone is connected to a constant
fraction of the nodes and OK so this is the first observation that
that contradicts what was known
the second observation maybe even more surprising so
the creation
from from the real world
make that makes sense is that if i take larger and larger graphs there are
sort of you can the latter show the longest shortest path the network will slowly
increase or so
you know if i take a small graph because small diameter if i take bigger
graph it can be like
if you look at the data you find something something different
for example this is for you to see how the diameter
slowly decreases the size of the graph grows and similarly for the citation networks
this is a physics citation network like ten years
again the them slowly increases over time
so the observation is that they are sharing so it's OK
so now the question is what can we say
about edge attachment for example give me such and the network properties
so what i want to show you next is sort of
i we model of how
individual edges attached the networks so
in the US what they should just just now is basically analysis of set of
snapshots of network but now what we look at is if we have data we
directly observe individual
edge attachment the network so basically see the evolution of the network some of the
the finest granularity possible that individual nodes
as they have to so we actually have an exact edge another ireland sequence from
the first stage in the search OK
and as they said
this way we can we can define what creates fine models of what is going
on and there are two new to basically the things that what we can do
we can test various hypotheses about individual edge attachment right because we really see what
is going on with the see sort of the consequence some kind of
statistics of what is going on the network but we see exactly the individual humans
and the other thing that we can do is instead of comparing our models by
by some kind of statistics like saying oh i can generate power law now i
can compare the mothers by actually computing the likelihood of a particular model giving that
particular OK so this is what different
the network datasets we have twenty four large online networks meaning in flickr delicious answers
they have like
millions of nodes and millions of edges and basically we have the exact edge arrival
sequence from the first actually
in fact for
four billion and i'll show you just examples for one that will become a lot
so basically
in the model there are three steps one has to model the first one is
the model that i write how i know how and new nodes are added to
the networks i know that i could create a first edge and you go to
sleep then basically unless we wake up to create a new edge and go to
sleep and is related to the nodes sort users up its lifetime dies
and then all of a sudden wants to create an edge the last question is
then whether we say OK and i won't go through everything i just showed this
last so basically when the node wakes up how does it creates create dissension and
the b two two questions here the last first what is the bias of most
attention to high degree nodes so more likely to to attach to someone who has
higher degree
and the second one the second version will be more likely to attach to someone
who was closer in the number of hops stuff so is that locality and is
we can simply replace our
conditional probability with probability of second world
and in this case we can use the probability of graph
as the multiplication of probabilities of unigrams
and it's pretty obvious
that if all words are really independent
and this is simply random coherent
i think that you get very close results of what what what we actually can
get from all models
it's not true
in this war
depend on one or another like in our example britney spears
here we will have very different ways
because the second
the second part of this equation is not close to the probability of work
actually don't care because in this case they are not going to replace it with
this estimation but we're going to keep our real probability in the model
OK so
we can based on these
we can reduce a lot of
that actually can be very well
estimated by the by model of the lower order
but what we have
i cannot predict and what what what
we can do
we can introduce size of our
the language model significantly
i can assure you that in real life after you doing this brewing
close to real numbers
you can source it you can see that you still
cannot feed into memory this may by that we want
to achieve
we need to apply some little compression
we need to forward all this stuff in memory some more compressed way
and i remember also from the second lecture that you can create some compress structure
then can fit into small amount of memory
we can use this structure much faster than bigger ones
so maybe we also can increase paedophile
and it's especially important for our example we spoke are actually with this suggestion of
because in this case
the problem is that our system generates a lot of hypothesis is a lot of
variance of
queries and we want to select the best one
and and we don't have time to look into some big table all or some
pages from from afar
OK so how can it be
congress our language models
and then again coming as we already
we already have
i had this example
that's the
can use hash function
and i want to
i remind you that has function is some magic friendship that from our work can
create the numbers
usually has function
the main demand forecast function is to generate
the random number is possible
so all we need of all
binary representations of words should be
well hashed
OK so imagine that for all n gram model
we can convert all words to some numbers
pretty beaker range
and let's
so like you remember that when we discuss hash tables the dog that
rachel has found
should be the same size of file hash table
and therefore
i was going to
keep this number is not so be otherwise we can feed again in in memory
but in this case
let's assume that we can
as much as a big number of course
try to
select some huge number of maybe a month so integer on on this
however architecture
and you will see what are doing this and the next
so we can encode all models
we can
apply all hash functions in this case on every biograph
and replaced
we have some magic numbers
and in this moment it looks like the to the
i haven't gotten anything anything useful
first of all
we lost some information
every hash function always
i have college
you know are twenty on
so v a minus b
is about six curable
in other words if the power station which is on the line three hundred cannonballs
then you would get it here
with only four six skillful less is not very unreasonable
i told you that these
power lines have to stay away from the three million volts per meter
electric field because you get corona discharge
and when there is
thunderstorms in the area
you can actually push up
the electric field on the wire
and you can get corona discharge i have seen it several times
not only seen at night
my naked eyes and you see the following glow
but i've also heard it because you can hear it is cracking noises corona discharge
very fascinating actually
i have slide here which shows that
you see a high-voltage power
five transmission line
you clearly see the
glowing of the corona discharge
compare that with what's called the romance kite string
right strings at night when you fly them
near thunderstorms can also use
corona discharge light that's why they call with kite string
benjamin franklin did quite a bit of experiments at night with
that you thunderstorms
dangerous business by the way
so you see these high-voltage power lines can go into
the corona discharge
i now want to revisit
leiden jar
we have a
story absurd situation
whereby we did an experiment with a
jar which is still see here
and i will redo the demonstration
but it's crying for an explanation
because it looks like
there was something wrong with physics
and i want to
refresh your memory on what we seen before
and what is light and jar
it is all about
the lines are is nothing but a
passenger with the dielectric between two conductors
in the form in the shape of a
of the bottle
so the inner portion which is
o thing i appreciate
you see
you see there
this is certainly there
and then
we have conductors
conducting peak around here
and we have a conducting bigger on the inside
recharge up with the first
this is the reverse fishing
and when we do that
we get free charge on the conductor
so that sigma
right here
and you get here
o opposite signs of course
and you get sigma induced
on the dielectric while you get it because the dialectics is an external field
due to this sigma free
so begins polarize
so you get here
the induced charge
you get there
this site is positive
and the new start he will be negative
and vice versa
we have here
well so we can live out the inner portion
so what we did
charter that was the winner
then a certain amount of energy
the electrostatic potential energy of this configuration
is one half q free
times the potential difference the q free
if the charge which is on the
outer conductor
what i then did i disassembled it
very carefully
after we get charged up
in a portion out
the glass out
outer portion
and i took all the free charge of i touch the
and this charge
so there is no cure three left
the moment that that is gone
the induced
charge must also go away
because the induced charge is only there because of the free charge
the induced
charge density
is one
mine is one of the cap
i'm sigma free
so if glass has a couple of five
the induced surface charge density
is about o point eight
times the free
the surface charge at the moment that the free one goes the induced one
and then i assembled it again
and much to our surprise
when i short out in a portion with the outer portions
we show you just part
that means there was energy level
and that's very pleasant there cannot be any energy left
unless there's something wrong
physics i first want to show that again
to remind you of what you've seen before
and then i will make
a proposal
for a for an explanation
we check my
light configuration to make it all dart
i can charge it up while using it actually
the naked died now
now all these assemblies it
taking a portion of
class is a good insulator so i don't mind
touching that was my
so now
i think the inner
think it is it they call the charts off
the same with the outer conductor
but in my hand for sure is no cure free
left only more
on that anymore
i put a
class back in again
and i put the
in our
or again
and i make it a little darker for you because i wanted to see that
when i short is out
you going to see is part so i'm going to do
and the light down
very closely tell you what i'm going to do it
and the whole point of this is it works no matter what so i don't
cite statically i don't get it i don't
what's not that you can actually say what does converge white star so i didn't
write down here but that that's actually something you can say and is true actually
write so
and so
but you can say things that are true to
right and i certainly don't mind doing that but
but i don't do when i'm being recorded so well i try not to i
should say
so the plausible deniability OK
so if you think my feeling that this is actually very simple the more you
think about it the more you realize that in fact all those other statements are
utterly irrelevant i had heard screaming fights people who said things like like you don't
care xkgk don't converge to some optimal values and i said no i don't
in fact if you think carefully about it in any algorithm to implement anything you
don't care about anything but these two things because these these you're stopping criterion will
be based on this period
and it's it's utterly irrelevant that whether xk converges to next are zk converges to
an easy star anything like that so go backwards from me duty utilitarian approach and
you say
it's a numerical methods
well what would you consider to be an approximate solution and i think that one
would say anything other than that
what inequality constraints to identify
you want to get the active set right
if you care about active set then you you can actually stop at some point
and then switched to some active set method or something people do that
all right
so i should say i call it i mean i'm calling ADMM in fact it
turns out it is
related to and exactly the same as many other methods so let me explain so
that first of all the absolutely identical something called douglas stratford
douglas track for splitting operator splitting its identical i mean
if you choose the right operator to split and split the right way it's not
related its identical so another way you'll hear this is the last record dr splitting
so it's it's not that it's the similar it's the same it's related things like
douglas appeasement bradford splitting and this is the stuff goes in the fifties
let's see all of these it's also it is exactly the same as the proximal
point algorithm which is very general but applied to the write operator then
it's identical mean course you have to figure out what the right operator is but
a lot of this wasn't known until maybe the mid eighties
in fact i mean so there were papers on all of these kinds of things
all different it wasn't known the right kind of all the same it's identical
but a special case of it is dikes resulting projections method
reinvented again and eighty five it's the same as progressive hedging
it's really the proximal methods and then sort of the modern vein substitutes for the
quadratic a bregman divergence and you start getting other things like this
so i think that's the the stories but you whether you might ask why
what you know how is it that different well-known algorithms could actually be the same
and not because actually it's complicated enough i mean it doesn't look that complicated but
it's complicated enough
there you go something like that that if you really do the order and change
the variables instead of using you use you plus acts something like that i mean
then that can actually take quite awhile to take
algorithm an algorithm b
and actually certified that they are in fact the same
right it did this is enough complexity here that it's it's hard to do
precisely right that's exactly exactly right for so you have to do the base load
the first translation OK so i'm going to talk about this just common patterns that
you see and they were working
we're working towards actually doing something and anything yet but we're working towards OK
but it's just a couple of obviuos very simple observations
oh i should mention oh i should mention one more thing for move on because
i have had
the discussions with people about it
proof of convergence requires high school algebra absolutely nothing else has nothing complicated there you
have to notice subgradient is inequality coaches short i mean that's it
right so
it's very simple and you see anything more complicated
you should be deeply suspicious
so you will see things much more complicated than that OK the second is you
might as well what's the or
well how fast is the convergence and the answer is it converges with the worst
possible rate for these methods one epsilon squared steps
to get an epsilon approximation right so now of course order optimal right because we're
now with that it's not merely their not assuming election it's constant things
these things died in nineteen differentiable right so
it seems to me i mean this is part of the trade-off in this so
this is not going to win any contests any complexity algorithm complexity contests that's for
sure right but that's kind not the spirit of all this the spirit of all
this is
you know that should they should be like something like conjugate gradients right you know
even running numerics where you get a horrible roundoff error affects it should be something
like you know you what you're hoping is that you get something that's relative that
as a challenge to
or a rejection of the taste
of the majority
that he was cultivating what baudelaire called
les fleur du mal the flowers of evil
but such people
chose the horrible precisely because they had decided to make a choice
that sent them above the crowds over right-minded people
they want to be normal
but young people who flaunt an illustrated epidermis or spiky blue hair
do so to feel similar to the others
why their parents who go to the cinema to enjoy scenes previously only
visible in the anatomy theaters
do so because
cosi fan tutti
another case in which we come up against the dissolution of the opposition ugly beautiful
is the cyborg philosophy
at first the image of a human being whose various organs have been replaced with mechanical or electronic
the result of a symbiosis between man and machine could still represent a science-fiction
but with the advent of cyberpunk the prophecy has come true
what's more radical feminists
like donna Haraway are proposing to overcome gender differences through the creation
a neuter post-organic or transhuman body
does this mean
that the clear distinction between beautiful and ugly has really
why if certain behavior on the part of young people or artists were
only marginal phenomena practised by a minority with respect to the world population and what if
cyborgs splatter and the living dead were superficial manifestations played
up by the mass media to which we exorcise a far more profound ugliness
that assails and appals us
something we would wish to ignore
in everyday life we are surrounded
by horrifiying sights
we see images of children
dying of hunger reduced to skeletons with swollen bellies we see countries where women
are raped by invading troops and other where people are tortured just as
we are continually exposed to images from
the not too distant past of other living skeletons doomed to the gas chambers
we see
bodies torn apart by the explosion of a skyscraper or an aeroplane in flight
and we live
in terror that tomorrow
it may be our turn
we all know perfectly
perfectly well that such things are ugly
not only in the moral but in the physical sense
and we know this because they arrouse our disgust fear and repulsion
independently of the fact that they can also arouse our compassion indignation
instinct of rebellion or solidarity even we accept them with the fatalism of those who
believe that life is none other than a tale told by an idiot full of sound and
no knowledge of the relativity of aesthetic values can eliminate the fact that in such
cases we unhesitatingly recognize ugliness
and we cannot transform it into an object of pleasure
so we can understand why art in various centuries insistently portrayed ugliness
to investigate to see if this is
appropriately scaled the
total cost investigation so what we want to do is minimized the number here
number we miss subject to the number we can investigate
so that's
that's a very good question that's a very good question this is something we
look about and thought about
the question basically is
these are simply counts the number of transactions which are fraudulent and not fraudulent but
of course different transactions have different values isn't it much more
important to stop transaction for five thousand dollars for five dollars to both water
sinking on this was
and some systems try to do as thinking was the
fraud breeds fraud
we want to stop fraud zero tolerance we want to stop fought at whatever level
because if people get away with small fraud they will escalate and indeed you see
this with them
people testing cards they'll they'll use card very small transaction which is under the sort
of limit which some of the banks used to cheque fraud if they get away
with that no slack in the big one we would like to we'd like to
stop all of them so we regard them as equally it's therefore that bad we
wanted to stop but you can do
and then
you can do
produced performance blocks based on summarizing the stable currency plots based on summarizing this table
as the threshold
you're using to predict fraud versus legitimate changes
you can do exactly the same here you could use our c curves here we
think it's probably more appropriate
these are the axes used for hours he plots we think it's more appropriate to
block them in this way we got the same horizontal axis the number fraud which
misclassified proportion of frauds which are misclassified as legitimate on the horizontal axis
but on the vertical axis
the cost of investigating so these are the things which are with a legitimate or
fraudulent the things which are classified as fraudulent appropriately scaled
if you like that's the cost
in some sense these two plots require you can get from one to the other
you know as i say we've only got four numbers in that in that table
and because of the constraints on them we really only got two ratios you can
look at them in different ways we just think is more informative for this particular
just like misclassification rate is not an appropriate criterion for all classification problems and so
are c plots are not inappropriate
way to display
the performance of detectors all classifiers for all problems and in fact we saw certain
different kinds of
ways of displaying this already in this country
we think this one is right for
so we have a five-minute break
tell you about this sort of data we've been dealing with these sort of problems
so far been talking about the background if you like have been talking about the
nature of the data and the complexities of the problem what i want to do
it is focused down on
the details if you like and how you actually construct
suspicion scores sort of detection methods
broadly speaking there are three sort of core approaches
there are rule based approaches
supervised classification methods where you assume that you have examples of each class fraud legitimate
anomaly detection methods there are also sort of other variants of these kinds of things
and and different classes tools that used so widely so for example changepoint break detection
methods there are multilevel methods
maybe also a little bit about that
you know the transactions are not isolated
completely objects they are embedded in become complex relationship with other transactions accounts merchants whatever
and of course we can also take advantage of developments in link analysis networks and
it's a little bit about that
i want to define the term here activity records
in an activity records u
look at the sequence of a small sequence of
transactions you might look back at the last three transactions for example of transactions of
the last day or seven days or whatever and summarize those and use those as
the unit of analysis superficially this appears to sacrifice immediacy we're not just looking at
the track single transactions occurs
we are sort of spreading out averaging over the last three for example
if you make your decision your classification refers to the time of the current transaction
it means sacrifice immediacy and of course it's got the potential for more accuracy
the three core approaches have different strengths and weaknesses or released the first glance they
do a rule based approach is clearly need
expert knowledge of past fraud behaviour you need to know the sorts of things which
are likely to
the fraudulent transactions give you some examples in the moment they are highly effective at
detecting known fraud types
they're obviously ineffective at detecting novel types
if something some kind of fraud
which i haven't seen before is coming along a rule system is going to detect
supervised methods as i said you need examples of past fraud so you can build
your neural network whatever it happens to be
this can be highly effective at detecting similar
but again ineffective and all types
almost by definition
an anomaly detection in contrast a good for new kinds of deviations
things which are unlike for example transactions previously made by this particular customer this account
but of course behavior may change over time so that it be perfect either
that's good for known types
there is some evidence for
the source of the merits and demerits which are just listed are
broad generalizations there is some evidence that the true but they're not always going to
be true and you should be interpreted cautiously there's a little examples from analysis
on some of the data from one of the banks i referred to earlier collaborating
with us this is the
these are false positives this is time
these are is the trace of
two class classifier performance is getting worse
initially it's better than this other one which is an anomaly detection
one class classifiers are kind of approach initially this two classes better but it
crosses over at some point so there is some evidence for this sort of merits
and demerits that i mentioned
you should interpret them cautiously
rule based methods
rules from expert knowledge from the previous experience of
frauds and there there are
well we've already heard there are big rule around
for example two
nearly simultaneous transactions using the same card widely dispersed geographical locations is intrinsically suspicious
purchased happens in new york and five minutes later in london
it order to raise the flag
another example is small
between attempts to withdraw the maximum amount
i came across an example of this
so the only inequality years coming from convexity
all right
now comes the algorithms so this was just
basic probability stuff
it's good to practice
OK we can see in the quiz
which is not surprising this
the case for me too
a lot of intuition for algorithms whatever algorithmic it makes alot of sense
this is grounded in
something that you know computer scientists
something that
the purposes of this cluster computer scientists
but with sort of the basic probability unless you happen to be mathematician
listen to it therefore
order to get
and in quiz one
speed is
very important on the final speed will also be important
the take
certainly doesn't hurt
but is more interesting because it requires being
you have to actually
he created
and that really tests algorithmic design so far we tested analysis and just any work
probability tending to figure out what the
can you remember what
the running time of randomized quicksort is and so on
was to actually test creative
because you have more time it's hard to be creative in two hours
OK so we want analyse the expected height of a randomly constructed binary search tree
it is defined as before but did it because it was a while ago
was the beginning of the lecture
i'm gonna take the random variable of the height
of a randomly built
binary search tree
on n nodes
so that was randomized and values
take a random permutation insert them one by one from left to right
with tree insert
what is the height of the tree that you get what is the maximum depth
of any
i'm not going to look so much and i'm going to look at the exponentiation
still we have no intuition why
two the x is a convex function
it looks like
that is very short
my second if drawing
two the next
so hard to apply histogram
so we want to somehow right this random variable as something
OK in some algebra
the thing here is to split into cases
how we we usually go because there's lots of different scenarios of what happens
i mean how do we construct truth
from the beginning
the first thing we do is
we take the first node
we throw it and make it the root
so the first value happens to be in the re which we don't really know
how that falls in sorted order
we put up the root and it stays the rule we never change the world
and then on
of all the remaining elements some of them are less than
this value and they go over here let's call this are
and some of them are greater than or so they go over here
maybe there's more here maybe is more here than
arbitrary partition in fact uniformly random partition
what should sound familiar
whether there are
k elements over here
and and minus caymans one elements over here
for any value of k is equally likely because this is chosen uniformly the resistors
and uniform is the first element in random mutation
what i'm going to do is parameterized by that how many elements are here and
how many elements are over here
because this thing
is again a randomly built binary search tree on how many nodes are in there
because after pick are
it's determined who still often used to the right
and second is partitioned running quicksort partition the elements left of are owners right are
i'm sort of recursively constructing a randomly built binary search tree on those two some
permutations because some permutations of uniform
limitations are uniform
these are essentially recursive problems we know how to analyse person problems
you need to know is that there are
OK minus one elements over here
and minus k
elements over here
and that would mean that are
has rank k
the rank consensus
index in sorted order
so if you really are
rank k
this is a
the statement about condition of this events
the random event
then what we have is x and
equals one plus the max
xk minus one
x minus OK
because the height of the tree
is the max of the heights of the two subtrees plus one because we have
one more level of time
so that's
natural thing to do what we are trying to analyse those white
for y and we have to take to the this power
so o
and the max of two x k minus one which is why climbers
and to this which is why
is k
now you start to see maybe why are interested in
why since the axis
in the sense that is what we know how to do
when we saw the recursion
we solve like the expected running time even take x expectations here
but when we compute the expected running time of quicksort
we have something like two
times i mean we have
a couple of recursive subproblems which are being added together
here we have a factor of two
here we have max
but intuitively we know how to multiply
random variables by a constant because that's like there's two recursive subproblems of
the size equal to the maximum distance
which we don't have to know here but
there is
whereas one plus we don't know how to handle so well
and indeed
our techniques are really good at solving recurrences
except after the constant factors
and this one plus
really doesn't affect the constant factor too much it would seem
OK but it's a big deal
he submissions yet but
OK so
i thought of what i do actually is just give very brief idea
of the solutions to these three problems not details at this point because i think
it will break the flow
going forward
and then maybe this afternoon put something up on the
on the wiki for people who are interested in
in looking in more detail way solution
that's just quickly look at the
three problems and to give you an idea of how this also in this case
of the first part of this was the proof of novikoff theorem
if you remember the updates of the algorithm
we are given
in this way this is the perceptron algorithm
so if it makes a mistake
on one of the examples then use
that example multiplied by its label
two the weight vector
and you continue until
you get correct classifications
the theorem is to show that the number of states this is too
he said OK
the theorem is to show that the number of updates is bounded in this way
and the end was too
the bound two things one was the
the size of the
the weight vector after the teeth update so if we think of w t plus
that's of course the inner product
w t plus one with itself
and everyone see that back
i said OK
but we know the w t plus one is given by this update rule so
we just plug it in
we then use the
linearity the inner product to sort of
computer the components of the
the first component is wt and the product itself which is of course just the
norm of
wt squared
we then have the cross
components may get too
why i we can take out of the inner products wt common exercise
and then finally we get this one with itself
which the y is a plus or minus one so they can
one squared there are equal to one
and so we just get the
the norm of x square
now because this example was misclassified
we note here
but this first middle term here is actually less than or equal to zero
that was the conditions under which we made the
the decision to update
so this is less than or equal to just dropping that wt
and this one of course is by our assumptions
bounded by
squared so this is plus ask
so at each stage the
the weight vector can increase by most r-squared
and so
this is less than or equal to t plus one
r-squared after t updates
since sorry after t plus one update since it started with the zero weight vectors
so our assumption here
so that's the first inequality and the second inequality is two
the inner product with this w star
of w t plus one and the game is exactly the same technique
plug in
the update rule
see what happens
and we get of course the
in the product of the previous stage
plus an extra bit which is why i
w star
but why i w star common excise actually be margin of
the example
y i x i
with respect to this w star which is the
assumed example which has a margin of gamma so that here we have a y
i w star excise gregory to gamma so this is actually greater than or equal
w star common wt
plus gamma
so now with those two inequalities
the contradiction comes from the fact that the the weight vector is not increasing too
much in size but its inner product with w star is increasing
all of the time
and those two
we're going to contradict each other at some point in other words is going to
be a point where
there can't be any more updates and
just the way to so sorry i just should say this is therefore greater or
or equal to since this started again zero
again t plus one times gamma
so if we just now
start with this point here and take that actually squared and i'm going to do
with t
rather than t plus one
that is less than or equal to
w star
squared by the first
inequality there
and then i'm going to use the coaches schwartz inequality
which makes this less than
squared because remember w star was norm one
and then i'm going to use this
inequality here
which is less or equal to t times r-squared
and there you have it you just divide through by t
and by gamma squared and you have t less or equal to ask where overcomes
so that gives you the bound on the
number of updates of the perceptron algorithm
OK so that's that's the first
he might have switched off
thank you for
a second
so now two maybe the last problem the second problem was the hardest last problem
was this question of how many
you can actually generate many different weight vectors you can generate the sparse dual approximations
of remember
maybe i can show it
quickly here
so if we imagine
if we imagine taking the sparse linear combinations where the AI alpha rise are
integers positive integers
and their sum is most was equal to two b
so we have essentially
and we're asking how many ways we can put a b
beads into those slots allowing us to put more than one into an individual