well i have been attacked by a friendly frequencies
but i survived
because obviously things are
more involved than that and i apologize for simplifying the frequentist view in this way
so of course there are ways of deriving certain estimators and i was a bit
sloppy in that respect so in the second part of this lecture i would like
to give you an example of how we're bayesian methodology can be used in practice
and the example that i'm using is writing and matchmaking and this is a joint
work with ralf herbrich
and it's it's published so far
and this is a serious application as you know i'm working for microsoft and the
inspiration for this work
came from some of the employees at microsoft research taking part in beta testing for
halo two
and what happened was that several thousand employees at microsoft where
we were asked to participate in this test to test the online playing in halo
two and everyone was very happy to do that of course
i felt privileged over the rest of the world was a lot of fun in
this period and we also found a lot of
ways to improve the game but of course when we looked at our rankings and
other systems which became very suspicious because it appears that were only average players why
we need for ourselves that we were really the top of the world
we instantly knew that their system must be flawed in some way and we offer
them our advice
and from then on we also developed a new system which was not just a
slight modification of theirs but is trying to to do this from being starting from
bayesian principles so
i'll give you a short overview for this part i'll talk about the general idea
of playwriting in video games and then show you how our system works we
call it the mu sigma system for
various reasons
i want to talk a little bit about alternative rating systems and give you some
numerical results on some of those beta data maybe one question other chess players among
us and is there anyone who has an elo rating
other chess players
a little bit but not enough to have an either writing or
so you know this is the writing system that was developed by a particular for
and from which we took a lot of inspiration and which then would turn out
to be a special case of this system
as i said would
personal motivation was this particular game but there's also a real interest to improve service
for people and in particular there are now online services like x-box live where people
have the game attacked is essentially the name online and they can look into the
system and play various games on the system always with the same tag if you
can talk to each other and in particular interesting for this thing statistics are collected
about these players and there's service called up to match
and after much tries to find people in the world who could play together very
well you know everyone's online and the question is if we have to arrange games
who would like to put into the same game and there are various criteria that
we have to meet here one thing is we want to good network connection between
the people because otherwise there would be lag in the game the packages wouldn't arrive
quickly enough to make for fun and realistic game and the things that people want
to seem to set up but the most important for this up to match thing
is really that you have a good rating system so you can get people together
into games such that the game outcome is unclear from the beginning and the game
so here you can see here the typical structure of
network packets
so it
very very abstract level consists of two important part
so one of them is the head
which represents carries information from network and the
transport layer protocol so
for example IP TCP protocol and information in this had user has a fixed
it means that you know what few has which information
certain by have
address information IP address and port so this information really very easy to access
that's why the first idea first approach to network intrusion detection was
sort extract
flat file features fixed set of features
from the side information
readily available
the problem with that
is that
most of attacks
really use valid
so in order to deliver an attacked to target computer one has to
the user protocol in valid way
is going to have valid ity addressed
it is going to have some
valid combination of
TCP flags set
and in the case where doesn't use a very simple method to prevent such
there are some kind of attacks that use them
in funny sequence of packets
but they can be very easily detected by the network configuration
the result of the intrusion detection system that uses had information usually
very mediocre
and the classical
example of
this dataset is no
to use this information is the so-called KDD cup ninety nine years
back in the
late nineties people have already thought about applying
machine learning techniques and abilities
datasets for KDD competition
the performance of the best not was acceptable but not for computers here
in order to really be able
to detect dangerous
and dangerous that is using some application abilities one has to be able to analyse
and there are several ways to do this
the simplest way is to consider payload as a sequence of robot
an advantage of this is that one can
you can see that the
the way exploit that has some suspicious by sequence and one might try to
constructing features from those by sequences
the second
so the advantage also is that
this page is relatively easy to come up with and it does not require any
knowledge of the application protocol that run
was taken by students don't care
what applications running whether they should be piece of
piece of what
the cell easy to actually
processes information
another possibility is pass but so you can
you can do
i tried to build a particle passes dust a syntactic and semantic information
this is more time consuming but to get some more informative features
also it is possible to come up with
another kind of flat features
basically you some extra information from the application of
this might be
perhaps the most preferable approach but again utilised their ability
this would be very time consuming process analyse the feature
so this is usually
not done in the field
i will show you how to deal with by
sequential features using by sequences
and the key idea here is
you get the idea that
it also
the known machine learning community is that the sequences into a metric space
one can do this by using
language models
a simple language model and around the world of words and grounds
one can also unconventional defined
any language
that is generated by
the available also
so out bodies in this case two hundred fifty six
by values
they consider the set of all possible worlds from the alphabet
then you select so we define the language is a subset of the alphabet
you are
essentially defines some function
every world
in this language
into some dimension
so you can see for example
it takes three key words from
the foreground galaxy
get the space and you know this twenty four percent five
you'll see that
these points have been built
interesting data structures one can eventually traced back to
some features of the protocol
you can also see
the data points colored by
so the blue points on all the points in the the two examples of tag
these features carefully chosen
can be really very
discriminative for certain factors
for example
the kind of exploit that use the use in the end of the war
very spread out
two thousand four
so you can see that
here and here where the phosphate is just jumps over the state
and this hydrolysis spontaneously we get this molecule right over here fossil you know pi
pi pyruvate
at the end
and once again we harvest two
eighty piece
one ATP from each of the trials is
and we end up at the end of this reaction with pyro pyruvate and you'll
say this is terrific because we invested two ATP is
we harvested for
plus we got six from the NADH is right
two NADH is each NADH gives us three each so let's do the arithmetic
how much should we let's do the balance sheet
we investigate to begin with
with the with the one because we invested two ATP
that was early on
the return was
the first two
NADH is
which i've told you
equals six ATP
because NADH is worth
three ATP
this is so far good and now
we've gotten
subsequently we made for ATP ATP's
so that the
the net yield
looks pretty
six plus fours ten minus two
a profit of eight ATP one glucose molecule this is terrific
you may say
but this around
there's a catch
like if glycolysis
is occurring in the absence of oxygen
in the absence of oxygen
if that happens then we have a problem here
because the only way
these NADH is can generate ATP
is it there's oxygen around
to take these
electron pairs
and use them to reduce oxygen molecule that is by the way part of the
reason we bring
keep in mind when you generate NADH from eighty molecule you need to regenerate the
energy you can just accumulate more and more and the the ages you need to
regenerate the eighty
and do
and therefore this NADH with the electron pairs
they the electron pairs have somehow to be disposed of
you have to regenerate any do you get just make more and more and more
of this so how cells get rid of it
well how they get rid of simple you take the electron pairs and you slap
them on the oxygen
and that's really called combustion and you get a lot of energy out of that
but what happens if all of this is happening happening is occurring anaerobic lee
and typically means the reactions occurring in the absence of oxygen
well if you have a yeast that's growing fourteen feet underground
this is happening in real quickly if you have a nice used the fermenting in
a big cake to make wine or beer it's also probably happening anaerobic lee if
you start running in a hundred yards sprint
then or let's so you run a mile
then initially there's little there's enough oxygen
there's a lot of oxygen around two to allow you to get rid of these
NADH is
and on the electrons that they have acquired
on the the oxygen molecules and that's fine that's worth a lot because in effect
what you're doing is you're taking her oxygen and hydrogen you're combusting them together and
that's great
but as you start running down the street
so the oxygen supply your muscles
is going to run out
and soon a lot of the energy production in your muscles
happens anaerobic y
because you can get oxygen quickly enough to your muscles
and therefore for a period of time you start feeling that burning sensation in your
because the oxidation of
of NADH isn't happening and these NADH is instead are used or regenerated
by another way how are they were generated
the electron pairs of the DNA the ages must be
are dumped back on two
this molecule right here my roommate
they not used to make ATP because they can be used to make ATP because
there's no oxygen around
two accept the electron pairs of these NADH is have required
so what happens with these valuable NADH is
under anaerobic conditions
this doesn't happen
these NADH is are used instead electrons are donated to our friend pyruvate here
two but i these are the three carbon sugar and what happens
when they donated back to the power of eight
in order to regenerate any do you need more energy to pick up to use
later in the reaction to use what all over again another reaction when you donate
electrons from NADH back on the power of a what happens
you get lactic acid
lactic acid is what makes your muscles burn
when you're you're running very quickly and you can't get enough oxygen into them to
begin to burn up
the NADH
so instead of using NADH to generate ATP etc diverted
to make lactic acid that in one sense good because you regenerate NADE
why do you need to regenerate eighty
because you need a lot of energy around
for the earlier steps in the reaction
keep in mind early in the reaction
where is our friend and early action you need a here
if you know we generated than glycolysis grinds to a halt
so even though you make NADH and it's a good thing in principle in practice
it has to be recycled and it's not recycle to make more new energy to
allow the step to happen the whole likely reaction will shut down and you're mass
however sadly
in the absence of oxygen
the only way to recycle this is to dump these electrons not the oxygen which
what does that have on
one more
all of
we want to
thank you
you will
you of
well i
number of
one of
OK for all
the problem
all they
i believe
we either
they all
o point
the square is always positive and therefore i could not get the answer zero
but in the other cases i might get the answer zero and the theorem is
you always do
why is this well
i'm asking you there are three ways to prove this it's like many fundamental facts
in mathematics are different ways of going about
by the way along with the theorems i probably should have included so
i'm far away
we might as well include because we're going to need
what happens if you
use the same function if i take you equal to be in that case that
indicate he will not going to get the answer zero but what you will get
is so in other words i'm just asking what is the sign of entity
that's the case where two of them of the same
i use the same function
what's that
well the answer is it's the same as what you will get if you integrate
the cosine
because i swear and t
and the answer to either one of these is
that's something you know how to do from eighteen o one
or the equivalent thereof you know you
you can integrate size square is one of the things that learned for the whatever
exactly to that of integration
anyway so i'm not going to calculate this out the answer turns out to be
all right
the ways to prove that are
you can use trig identities
and i'm asking you in one of the
early problems and the problems
i invented scenes
identities for the product of sine cosine expressing it in a form which is easy
to integrate
and you can prove it that way
or you can use if you forgot the trigonometric identities and want to get some
more exercise conflict you can use complex exponentials
so i'm asking you to have
in another part of the same problem i'm asking you to do it do one
of these at any rate using complex exponentials
and now i'm going to use the mysterious third method
another way use i'm going to use the older e
i'm going to do that
because this is the method it's not just size and cosines which are orthogonal there
masses of orthogonal functions out there
and the way they are discovered in the way you prove they are orthogonal
it is not with trig identities and complex exponential because there's only work with size
and cosines
it is instead with by going back to the differential equation that they solve and
that's therefore the method you don't use here
because this is the method which generalizes the many other differential equations other than the
simple one satisfied by size and cosine
but anyway that is the source
so the way the proof of these orthogonality condition got so i'm not going to
do that and i song and i'm also going so i'm going to assume that
m is different from and so that i'm not in either of these two cases
what it depends on is what's the differential equation that all these functions satisfy well
the different differential equations depending on
the value of n but
they look essentially the same
these satisfy
the differential equation
now that's what they have in common the differential equation is
let's let's call you
it looks better
it's going to look better
if you let me call you
double prime
he was
well i mean square so
functions assigning to cosine
satisfy you double prime was and square time you know was the frequency is then
and therefore this is the square of the frequency is what you would here equals
in other words what these functions have in common
is that they satisfy the differential equation looks like that and the only thing is
allowed to vary
is the frequency
which is allowed to change
the frequency is is in this coefficient you
now the remarkable thing is that all you need to know
the fact that they satisfy the differential equations
that's all you need to know to prove the orthogonality relations
OK let's try to do it
well i need some notation so i'm going to live
and the
any two
one of the functions
in other words
i also in that m is different from anchorage sample
this one could be signed entity and that could be sign of m t
or this could be sign entity and that could be cosine of mt you get
the idea
any two of those in the subscript indicates whether what the end with the is
that are in that
any two
and i mean really two distinct well if i say that m is not and
then they positively have to be different so i again it's overkill with my tools
in this
and what i'm going to calculate well first of all from the equation i'm going
to write equation this way
it says that you double prime
is equal to
minus and square you
that's true for any of these guys
of course here would be
the double prime is equal to minus m squared
times v
you have to make those simple adjustments
and now what we're going to calculate is
from minus on a
paul i
and in
double prime
defines the
the team
what does
there with
why am i going to do that i can't explain why do that won't ask
me the question five
now the point is this is highly on symmetric
you use differentiated twice the years so those two functions but there is a way
of turning them into an expression with a
which looks extremely symmetric where
it turn
the same amount
the way to do that is i want to get rid of one of these
primes here and put one on here way to do that is
it's a great
is mostly up to now i've talked about
first order methods are methods that are not even first order
newton method is where you go one more time out in the taylor series
to you had on the quadratic term and you try to pick your the next
year by minimizing an approximation to the second order taylor series
in the classic method hk is exactly is exactly the passionately the latest point
and you can show that if you do if you got classic use method you
get super linear convergence in general
so the any convergence means that you knew where the ratio of your new to
the previous there is going to zero as k goes to infinity
so very very fast OK
the all kinds of modifications and use method if you look at any optimisation textbook
that has nonlinear optimization and it should discussed this method and it should discuss the
bunch these modifications for example you can add on approx to sort of stopped the
steps getting too long
you can have a trust region constraint
you can calculate the minimizer this and do a line search something so many many
things you can do
one big thing is how do you choose the age
so i've already mentioned the classic choice namely the haitian there are many other things
you can do many of which are already mentioned in this talk
you can for example reuse the haitian from a previous iterate so you don't have
to re-evaluate every time
quick and dirty and often works very well you can use the sample approximation not
just mention that that works in the case where f is like some of the
budget component functions like that block log likelihood function that we discussed you can use
a diagonal approximation to the two
to the action so you can define hk to be diagonal approximation of these against
the scaling right across a little bit more about that in a minute
the a class methods called quasi newton methods are also a favourite topic in
and you know standard optimisation community for the last forty years or so what they
these do is define hk
two explicitly member mimic the behavior of the true version
there's only a quasi newton method you you update HK after every step so that
would mimic the behaviour of the true version on the last step that you just
you keep doing this simple updates rank one rank two and so on and if
you use that to define hk
amazingly you can get super linear convergence and that was proved about forty years ago
some classic results
nonlinear optimisation along those lines you all you ever need is great you never need
to do quasi met the never need secondary information
and then finally you can do special things if the if the function f for
some special structure you can sort of approximate
the haitian in some problems specific ways and the classic example of that is non
linear least squares with the objective function is the sum of squares of some vector
functions some residual functions
when f has this
structure then the passion of f has this property here is just the jacobian of
this residual function transposed with itself
plus the second order term
so this the classic method in non-linear least squares which just approximates the haitian by
just the first here
just tosses away the second term
and that often works fine when
jacobian is pretty well conditioned and when the residuals are small often this is a
pretty good approximation to the true version so that's another way that you can get
sort of the cheap
higher order methods with that every actually evaluating secondary evidence
what happens if you've got constraints irregulars we keep asking this question if you got
an unconstrained problem had a generalized to the case we've got the constraints that we
want to regularize
well if if you've got the constraints you can just take exactly the model that
used to get newton like step and impose this restriction
if you can solve this problem economically which is big enough
then the theory pretty much goes through you still get two point conversion but to
be if you've got if this hk is not diagonal
if it's some sort of dense or general
matrix it's often pretty hard to solve this problem OK so you need some sort
of in loop to solve this problem so it's not so clear it's economical so
you have to do something else quite often
same is more or less true in the case of the regularized
the problem we've got this time appearing the objective giving explicitly at this time under
the new title
some problem the quadratic subproblems if you can minimize this whole thing
most theories in the new type methodologies go through just carry through
but again that's a big if
if this is no longer diagonal this can be a lot harder to solve than
the shrink operators that i mentioned earlier
OK but in practice you can sort of combined with the technical just introduced if
if you are able to identify the manifold
corresponding to signal corresponding to a maker corresponding sides
on which the solution lies then you don't need to do any of this you
can just go to to the manifold and start doing in a sense unconstrained newton
steps on a reduced space and you save yourself the trouble solving these kinds of
i think i'll skip this one
and he's come up in machine learning have actually been some papers on and quasi
newton methods in for solving machine learning to problems
this is just in the last few years
that appeared in the proceedings of a aistats and and JMLR and other venues
OK so this first one sort of does a quasi newton approach on this classic
SVM loss function and again it sort of gets that second order term by doing
some sort of finite difference over the of the estimated gradients now the difference between
this and classical quasi newton bunch difference is one of them is it's not doesn't
have access to exact derivative information center good estimates based on sampling of these lost
times and so
you don't even have exact first of information but still using it to at least
i some approximation the diagonal of the passion
so you might not least expected to get the scaling right OK even if it's
not even if it's only a very crude approximation to the true mission
and the second one is somewhat related to that was in a state of years
now the authors about these papers call these things quasi newton methods are not really
i would say the optimisation communities causing methods i would think of is incremental
was stochastic gradient methods with
you know a sensible interesting kind of scale rather than
real quasi newton methods but we can certainly argue about the definitions
i think the term quasi newton is sort means many things to many people
and i sort of describe what i think what i mean by
there are some papers in go to for further information on the things that are
just discussed again these slides are on the web so i'll let you download these
and and
and look at these if you're interested
so here's my last topic i guess i have a few minutes left and i
just got a few slides and this one take very long and i wanted to
mention this because a lot of you already do stuff like this now wanted to
talk about a couple of recent contributions in this area
this is the composition where we try to minimize f over many variables x as
many components a classic approach is that in each iteration you fix most of those
this is a
if should want
this means is useful
she she
what we need to do this
the one
all the
you use
and this was used to use this is
it's all is just
it is by
this is the
one here
she is
one of the
my have to
and the decision
and what is
if she can she was
he knows
they all should
you should
now there is also a member of all
you have to use do
do you
wanted to
and all the
i have no reason
you you you want
and so
users in this
i have
and now
she that he
he was
the have gone on for what they just saw
or you could tell me that they have address
o point guard the colour just to the left
what that has to be in the case the world get the flow is our
interface to
what we want to send messages to the
one of the ways in which was itself
if you borrow information from the
three structured then you get better model seek of ten
then the method that does not border information from the second
i'm skipping a lot of details but probably hopefully get the high level idea
OK so now some other methods which one could use but have not been done
so one could also use something
one could also use ideas in
collaborative filtering for instance right
so so this is what collaborative filtering does so let's assume
so you is use i is item and the rating given by the user you
to itemize the weighted average
given by the user to related items
so there is a new item and if you want to estimate the r rating
of user for that particular item you look at
i don't have kind of very similar to to that and look at what sort
of ratings this user is given to those items like if you in there is
a new entertainment movie and you want to estimate how the user has been to
rate that entertainment movie you look at movies that are very similar to that particular
we hopefully they use it as a weighted sum of those things and you take
a weighted average of those as your prediction for the new movie for this is
what is done in what is called a this methods in collaborative
the same idea could be used here right so the rating in all cases
whether the user has to click on that item or not
so the challenge here is how to come up with similar acts
so in collaborative filtering the similarities are discovered automatically from data so you look at
for a given item you look at all the use of the data that don't
look at all the users and then you look at the ratings so far only
two items you look at all the common uses the created what i did you
look at some cosine similarity and that is how you get the similarity measure here
in this case that might not work
because first of all you don't have rating kind of data you have like one
still kind of data and the methods which work for creating kind of data does
not work for the zero and one kind of data so you have to do
some modifications again even in the collaborative reading literature there is no
i work in the neighborhood based methods to address the binary problem
secondly how to use semantic information which you have about the acts to come of
suitable similarity measure so these are some of the challenges of each one needs to
address before these kind of techniques become routine in this application of computational advertising
so this is one way of doing it i mean again this is just
have not done it
i don't think anyone else has done it but this is just one idea maybe
may or may not work i don't know what the something one could do so
one could write a model where you see the log odds of CTR for a
given that on equity is some functions of this function is again as as it
comes from the logistic regression this is what we get from the logistic regression so
he supplemented by another to see some related terms e and then u
you put your body constraint on this latency which is looks something like what you
do in collaborative
well the good thing is that since this variable is late and you can measure
it is like a rating variables like continuous variable and you can actually write down
the rating function exactly the same way as you do in collaborative
now that the added complexity here is
this is a latent variable and you know you're trying to translate this latent variable
into the probability score so you have to write down a generative model using
the logistic regression formula that is going to involve this functions e which has this
constraint so you need to come up with some yem algorithm called the good estimates
of these guys so that's the challenge but this is a framework which should work
in principle there is no reason why it should work
yeah i can cannot so all that stuff which is done in collaborative filtering can
all go through here but it is in the latent space
so all the collaborative filtering models work but in the latent space so how to
translate the information from the latent space to the data is the challenge which have
not been addressed but it could be done
even for computational advertising
so again we have not done it i don't know whether it's going to work
on that looks like a reasonable approach to trust
the but other thing that this is actually being done
factorisation approach right so you say well
there is a logistic regression and then
there is some residual interaction between them
query and that's going to be captured by projecting the query then adding to some
lower dimensional space and then became across so this has been done on the people
have kind of dress that in some recent paper some of them will appear to
so so this is this this works you
you can actually estimate these latent factors by running in yemen gibbs sampling algorithm works
in the previous one has not been done i think this is pretty exciting if
it can be done
in fact what would be exciting is to combine this with that cover the more
realistic approach to the factorisation components neighborhood component combine them both
use semantic information which you have about the ads on pages about that and quit
to derive neighborhood structure the
so it would be very nice piece of
all o
yeah that the feature based at the local and the global global
the word error rate which one called down
things have been progressing well in the nineties
even though the algorithms themselves haven't changed that much
india in those years
i was actually working on speech recognition myself in the early nineties
when i completed my peach tea in ninety one
so there was mostly advances because if the
being able to train
bigger systems bigger models
faster with faster computers much larger datasets but there's only so much you can do without
and in the decade that followed things have kind of
and then progress started to accelerate again
with the use deep learning
that's the kinda reason why people have being attracted to this area
something similar has happened in object recognition
at about the same time a little bit later
there was a breakthrough in one of these e
was interesting
challenging tasks in object-recognition be imagenet dataset that has a thousand classes about objects and about a million
training examples are actually now twenty million
end you see here outputs of this early system which was getting around seventeen percent
correct in the sense if the
having the right answer
the first five
more modern systems that the latest systems have now are now down to
five or six percent these worthy
numbers as they were in two thousand twelve
so on the right hand side you see e
error rates obtained by by others systems competing in those days with the system could
buy extras asking yes discovering geoff hinton
one this competition
but it down forever from about twenty six percent heritable sixteen percent air
i said in in the
ure afterwards they brought it down to around eleven this year's down to six percent something
so our there's been amazing progress
thanks these techniques
you can try it out for yourself
russell could probably show this euro
this morning
just deep learning that's yes that toronto that you
u go therein you can upload your relevant and image
it will
uses these one thousand categories to try to identify the main objective in the image so here
it's in convertible
seeing chimpanzees
you're saying sports car and i just think those images
you know searching large using google image search and pasted them
it is it's not always perfect
for example here it says killer whale
with thirty five per cent confidence and tiger shark with ninety percent confidence in school would either
so it's not always perfect of course and there's a lot more to be done
this german shepherd was perfectly recognized
if you've tried computer vision and object recognition
in the past it was very brittle
these systems are just
called the change by the way in which they are robust to all kinds of
variations in illumination and background and things like that
in my lab with applying these techniques to
classification from movie clips from video using both the audio and images
and we want competition
i was held last december
using using
are fairly similar systems
so with these another advances in two thousand thirteen
you might it larger review declared planning to be one of the ten breakthrough technologies for the year
and then there's been a lot of
journalist talking about in new york times and wired and others
companies have started competing
four hour
before the technology and for the people working on it on a particular google facebook wear
in an arms race to
acquirer are
companies are people
one big event and this was the google buying deadline for about five hundred million dollars
anne now there's tons of start ups in this in this area
and there is also a very natural example submodularity so imagine this is the
case I have these sets A A one through A N and my function F is
the size of the union of these sets okay and
what I have here right I have this set of sets S and I have this
T and now I'm asking how much benefit do I get if I'm adding X right and this is
clearly submodular right because I'm interested in the union of green and blue and
once and the other time I'm interested in the union of blue of blue red
and green and now I'm asking how much benefit does does adding X give
me to my to my union right and if if I have my
S these three guys then basically the whole X is added so I get huge benefit here right
while if I already start with blue and red only this I get only this part of X so my
benefit of adding X is smaller and this is submodularity right and now in our case you
can sort of think that every node this would be like the influence circle of every
node so you say oh if this node would be active this many nodes would get influence so now you can
you can already start to see why we have this submodularity property okay
so there are a few more things we need to do before we see it why
why why we have the property so the way I explain the model right now it's not
clear exactly when the nodes when the coins get flipped but what we can do
is we can generate this randomness ahead of time so we can go without even knowing
what is the initial active set we can just go and flip and flip all the
coins and let's say these are the these are the coins that came up heads so
this would be the edges over which the the influence will propagate right so for
every edge we we we decide in advance whether if there if there is if if it
comes to the state where there would be an influence propagating over it we know whether it will
transmit or not and we call these edges being live okay and now what is what is
F of S what is the size of the active set it's just a size a set
that this is reachable by live edge paths right what I mean by that is
so for example this is the this is
the thing right this is the the active set right so if
these two guys are active then then this person could like influence these people
and not this one because there's no active path to the node F and now
actually now we see that the whole thing is submodular right we know that the the
the the linear combination of submodular functions is submodular and we know and these that like the
sets right it's a union of sets so what this tells us is that we are able
to efficiently find the most influential nodes in the network and maybe I didn't tell this
but why would you want to do that is I know if you if you
are a viral marketing company and you and you ask which people should I give a
free iPod so that they go and buy and they go and influence their friends right
so and this way we we found an an approximation algorithm for finding these influential people
now I can go into the empirical part and show and show a and ask these questions
how do diffusion curves look like so the thing I was talking before the diminishing
returns for critical mass and how do cascades look like always the structure
of the graph of the network is fixed by the ja it can work for a simulated display but when you go to real biases not like
that because let's say that withouth this is the time for all
you know he's a sum of time to be a through the
this is all I admit I agree on the item by the best I can
answer is just some model alright I mean you always have this trade of between having something really
complex but then you can't analyze it or having having something simple and this seems to be
simple enough but I agree that topology of the network changes and so on
mistake of the node sure I agree but but let's get back to this empirical part right
so okay these are the questions we'll ask so what what's the challenge or what
do we want to go to do so basically we need a large data set where the
where we can go and observe diffusion so we want a dataset where we can go and
actually measure how the influence propagates or we need a social network and we need these social
network links and behavior that spread pretty much similar and there there are three three data sets
or three cases three studies that I will show one is on blogs where we observe how
information propagates right somebody writes something and then other people cite it and this spreads over network so
second one are these product recommendations where we are asking how the product recommendations and purchases
propagate through the social network and the other one is community membership so basically you could
think that community membership is also some kind some kind of viral thing and I'll come to details
of these okay so first in blogs what do I mean by diffusion in blogs so this is the
like a schematic picture of the blogosphere right we have blogs so slash dot would
be this would be like a slash dot webpage and every blog
blog has like this time stamped posts right so the circles are the posts so
here we have six blogs and I know this is a big blog with like
six posts and this is a smaller blog what we also have is a a time stamped
hyperlinks right so what we can do now is we can go and see how
information propagates right so if these guys set something and then some other blog referred to it then we know
that he must have had read read the story and using a hyperlink they
they referred to it and now we can go and observe how the how the story spread right
the assumption here is that whenever somebody said something and other people referred to it
now we can say that this person in this is the flow of information right the the direction
of the arrows shows the direction of the hyperlink so the influence spread this way
ok yeah
normally would be that all three that would be the I
mean depends on what is the discussion right so if if if I
just want to if if these guy is someone who discovered an interesting story then this guy
could definitely point to here but maybe this is a political discussion so it
the the the
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
OK well welcome to see is one six people from interaction maybe make is on
that's interesting OK
the website actually was part of the most important thing to take away from here
it is working you find information about the class talk today gives them overview and
and stuff like that this is kind of the home base for all the material
so if you manage to get their hands on the way and you're golden otherwise
you can get from the website there's a lot of background information staff information office
hours also to stop their gathered his car one-stop shopping for figuring out things about
our course they wanted a first day a lot of your shop and try to
check out figure out what's the right thing for use so hopefully it and try
to give you some information to help you make the decision once a lot of
course is about to administration and logistics most that's pretty ordinary you can read about
it that was that marketing i get to give you my advice opinions of what
is the absolute best case you could possibly take i get paid for student you
that's not true and maybe we have time to to
check out all the possible language redundant today
and need to go it
i that is what is it
this is one of six in the introductory programming sequence here at stanford right with
our version of CS one where you start at the beginning when you are interested
in learning more about programming we have the two core sequence a and b that
kind of fall together they are not particularly tightly coupled which is to say if
you took a radical break you can come back to be or maybe you actually
took a variant of one six eight a course the summer and another institution are
probably fine place for starting the stream
we also have an alternate form of the this is one of six x kind
of honor version of the second course so after you've taken the first course and
you're feeling really jazz that there is an alternative more intense way to get to
the second course offered was offered the score in fact if you actually think about
that that is an option for you as well as stick with us what do
we do when i was six official title is programming methodology it's starting at the
very beginning and assuming you have no background in programming is teaching you how it
works right what languages look like what the syntax is like what things you need
to know about how to solve problems using a computer so it covers a lot
of the the fundamentals biological control flow in general i think of the the big
issues for one six a having mostly with a particular syntax or or feature that
you learn about the language but about how do you solve problems on computer has
somebody gives you specification of you need about a program that does acts and you
have to figure out how to make that happen how to break it down had
step through it how to develop it how to test it had iterate on it
how to make changes and later how to debug it one is not working well
and those things i think transcends any particular language we have to use the java
programming language and one six a course because it's a great tool for
introductory programming but i don't think about it being really critical so in fact if
you're introductory course was in some other language some of the fairly modern high-level language
you know so you you learned in pipeline you've say learned and schema something other
than java your but we still find is what we're really counting on to be
is that you know how to program you have to think like a computer scientist
and solve problems but not a lot of the details of syntax are going to
be important to us
the picks up from there saying OK you got some fundamentals let's start learning some
of the techniques that extend the range of problems you can solve
we look at recursion which is one of the fundamental problem solving techniques right involves
using something akin to mathematical induction to solve problems in terms of cells looking a
lot of algorithms for sorting and searching and hashing and doing things efficiently right knowing
how to compare and contrast alternatives and algorithms having some formalism which discuss the things
on some of the classics that are out there for solving these problems the dynamic
data structures which involves use of pointers to construct things like list reason he graph
that model certain structures that are very effective in solving different kinds of problems will
work through those and that a large part of our time is spent on this
concept of data abstraction which is why abstraction shows up kind of is the main
water title is how do we know if we start from more and more complex
problems write the code itself can can become overwhelming we don't have some techniques for
managing complexity and one of the big teams for one six b is how we
can use this idea of abstraction building something in dealing with a little bit of
closing up the box and now treating it as a kind of fixed entity and
building on top of that practice called another way around that as a way of
kind of working on something and finishing moving on from larger piece without having the
said by the character is excellent and
that's it
this is already more from the for
absolutely i will come back to this is very simplified model from
that's very interesting by combined total
is just introduce introduced to right so before we
we go about che forest it's not about the classification gives you all of this
is just my point so in classification random subjects observations y y y
which take place our time you want and what want to do is to construct
classifier just mentioned which is also one of the world in which one is best
for for specific just that's what i call prince you know
it is and so the decision not to accept some of the success was the
first one
what you want to do is is to minimize damage there is no advantages by
so called base classifiers
which is just one way
besides one where the regression function approach
it's not what you said you
it turns out
coming back i from just called bayes is a web two o
or you can
and of course
after this talk page try to design classifier which is called bayes risk
that's what she said
was he or she has said that he
what we try to do is to update such consistency
and distribution of the observation
now what about
randomized classifer we just think about randomized classifier this college and the use of random
to calculate
because the decision
that's just for example
trains run through the process the way to get on the call for
one is that of course
the probability of all of the search engine
it's just that we propose making that integrate the whole
of the she of was missing
now once you introduced from the our
you can of course find any recession and the realisation of human history and you
you ten
what we call forty five
which is just averaging over all realizations just turned around and
this means that the average over all tree
of the first
very ones war
of course
this is just average
just said one who your one of the results
the that same year
when you are just
and of course once this what want to do is to make first team
which is you think some kind of classifier
call the average classifier which is just the same way take expectation over the
instead of so
but in practice we saw last week and that she this kind of research institution
which is by
the average
now we have three
classifiers are one
randomized one average one so
what can we say about
there is the first
and as a result we said that
if the sequence of randomized classifier is consistent with the distribution of this one
that is that somehow we can just proved
that will end with the number of observations
if you classify even randomized classifiers can cause
the voting classifier
the average fifty five remain constant
this is what proposition which is a really interesting
it's pretty clear the original rather
this is the way
going to
can request services to
we can really prove interesting
and typically we can prove for example
we can prove the consistency of that very simple random for action to you
here we do this sort of course random forests
is a collection of randomized for what you want the first step
and this way
it's from the parameters capture with tree on
this variable is set to
the way
we performed a tribute
we can find same way was supported by an average fifty five
typically horsehair
the strings are
sixteen seventeenth eighteenth century
it's not for those people
so i'm sorry i we i got lots of things going on here this might
show just play a scaled quickly and then brought pizzicato tremolo
in the field
deeper dive
there is no uh
and in the
something that
i do admit coffee this morning
so tell us about what you're doing here so there are lots different techniques to
create different colors and
and think the
any one of is taken
he was well into the his string
the difference of play
so what
so that's that
there which is in
OK then just quickly play kind of four
OK finally tremolo
statement little village to the music
alright great thank you very much
so i don't know if i can whether technically this will work or not i've
tried all morning to get this to work i have it up on my screen
but i don't see it up on the screen there can have attack assistant to
all right we'll go back here to try this
it began nothing happened
last summer standard
it doesn't do me much good to have somebody in the back going like this
OK what i would like one i wanted to show you was a clip that
actually what my daughter brought to my attention just this past weekend she was watching
television america has talent
anybody watch this american talent
and she said you gotta watch this is the most amazing thing i've got these
two guys on here call not bit strings
so i did and i went issue it seems the links to
youtube here let's see if we can get this girl i no
to do something with the person that
so obviously the violin is not just the study thing from the red to have
some legs today are used in folk music used in sometimes you see them in
nashville playing with country music that kind of thing is this travesty to use violent
with with hip-hop here again this is part of course this is wonderful this is
the best thing that's happened the violence in the last hundred years there will be
millions of kids out there and she had like to play the violin two
so this is wonderful the sort of cross examination of genres here bringing this particular
in instrument traditional classical violin into the popular are so let's put that aside we
talked little bit about sound production here i've got two pieces i'm going to work
with here for the end of our session we have fifteen minutes left and here
are these two pieces the first you can see on the border there is by
another russian composer but that resort ski it's called polish oxcart
from his work pictures at an exhibition what happened was a friend friend died from
was an artist friend left these pictures as an omaha to the painter
source he sat down and tried to come up with create a musical response to
now getting back to the whole strategy of poliovirus infection
this raises the issue of what it was in the polio virus that was able
to evoke
the subsequent lifelong immunity
and in telling you that i mentioned the following you can make it easier from
you can make sierra
a individual who's been immunized with poliovirus
and regular recollect we
i mentioned this before the way to make serum is to allow blood to clot
the red cells and platelets aggregate in the bottom and what remains on top is
simply serum you can spin out all the residual cells and so on you get
sort of the straw colored fluid
and that serum from individuals been immunized with poliovirus staff can actually be used to
you can add to the polio virus
stock prior to
adding these virus particles to the petri dish
so here's the petri dish as before
and what you find is that if you had serum from people from an individual
is when realized to the polio to a solution of polio virus particles
and then you take that mixed and put them on the plate
you know longer get any of these plaques that i referred to before
and that indicates that was in the serum there's some kind of factor which is
neutralizing the infected body of the polio virus particles
i e the polio virus particles are in some way
prevented from creating an infection and their platform ability their ability to conform to corrode
these holes
in the layers of subsequently infected cultures is now compromised
and such a activity suggesting that that such an individual has actually increased serum i
e some kind of reactivity which prevents
the polio virus particle from doing it's thing
in fact i can tell you that such and this year or section neutralizing into
here can be achieved in a number of ways
one way to do it is just to take the protein capsid the outer coat
of the polio virus particle that describe before and inject that into an individual and
that will on its own already evoke a measure of anti-viral immunity will also it
will evoke a concentration camps here in the blood of a patient
or if you want to do it very much more modern way
you can sequence
the proteins of the polio virus and determine the amino acid sequence
and when you do that you can synthesize through organic synthesis although peptides of ten
or twenty amino acids long
and these are the only goal peptides reflect different parts of the polio virus coat
protein so here's the sequence of one of the capsid proteins
recall the capsid refers to the cold it's the shielding or protecting in this case
of polio poliovirus the single stranded viral RNA genome so here's one of the capsid
proteins what you can do is to figure out the amino acid sequence of this
segment of the capsid proteins and and then rather than cutting it out from the
capital you just synthesized by organic synthesis ten or twenty amino acid residues long
and when you inject that all legal peptide into an individual that may also evoke
some kind of neutralizing antibody response
in fact as you might guess correctly imagine if we can look in more detail
of the capsid structure i'm just going to draw to very primitive way here
it's it's obviously much much more complicated but this is the caps here it has
an inside and outside
and the
antibodies that you make against a and although peptide that sticking out on the outside
will be neutralising
i e did this year will be able to recognise the outside of the virus
particle and somehow inactivated but if you were to make a use although peptide antigens
from over here
which might be a part of the capsid protein that is deep inside
well even though you might have a good reactivity was only go peptide wouldn't be
and that suggests
the notion that whatever is present in the answers here
is recognizing some internal external
portion of this protein which is sticking out and the external portion is called antigen
so this is specific chemical structure which has been recognised by the answers serum
and we call that antigen
in principle there are
dozens of distinct pathogens on the surface of the polio virus particle
each of which one can in principle make an immunizing antibodies against
each of those one can therefore considered to be an integer
and how can we imagine this and this year was actually successfully neutralising the
the virus particles
and here this on actually the biochemical characterization of ants here because one soon came
to learn
that within easier or
what we call antibodies or keep in mind
in biology never should ever use the simple
anglo-saxon word if you can use much more complicated creature
latin one so we can always call these immunoglobulin you see the word right there
immunoglobulin represents an antibody molecule and it turns out that there is that much of
the protein in the soluble fraction of
are zero
these consist consists of such antibody molecules and these antibody molecules have a very interesting
structure which would like to dwell upon momentarily but before i do that i just
want to anticipate what i'm about to say by indicating that we now realise an
antibody molecule can recognise antigens on the surface of the virus particle and the body
molecule can actually physically blind
two this antigen
so we have an antigen antibody complex and that binding of the antibody molecule
to the surface of the virus particle is what results functionally
in the neutralisation of its in fact if it
or to put it another way
it given the fact that this particular capsid proteins might be repeated let's say sixty
times around the spherical surface of the virus particle there might be in fact sixty
different antibody molecules recognizing this repeated antigen which occurs
on each of these capsid proteins and therefore you can imagine very approximate way
but if you have an effective neutralizing antibody it's coating the surface of the virus
particle antibody molecules and that clearly obstructs the ability of the virus particle to initiate
a subsequent round of infection
here's what a single antibody molecule looks like and it has some critically important features
first of all
there is a specific region of the antibody that recognizes
the temperature
in this case i'm using is the example the antigen and although peptide on the
surface of the the
polio virus particle and that is located in this part of
antibody molecule
note by the way the antibody molecule is a heterodimer tetra more it has two
light chains too small chains here on the right and two heavy chains
so i heard this argument several times also well you know where the problem with
your nets is that you know this is the only endemic work
you know jeff actually made the made the joke in this
he doesn't the order of course but he said the joke anyway it was something
that jordan's tutorial and several people have talked about this and this is entirely not
not too is actually a guy called mike mike you who can also do it
he has never heard of michael like OK let me show you my cornelius
so my company produces really nice websites on could project car
we're basically took the papers on you know comes from that some of my papers
purchasing must be
and said you know what they are implemented this so
he we implemented it improve build this really nice little windows application you can click
on stuff and recognizing his digits you can download the code and he explains you
know everything
you do that you do this and you know high school were stand but
this page is an pages of that stuff and you know all the details the
experiences of different things are implemented you know
stochastic diagonal the remark or at least of all the tricks in the book but
just reading the paper is a very very nice
so these guys were petition in nineteen
but you get
OK we see
this is the guy macon is happening twenty seven california where he specializes in computer
and structural patterns if for a hobby
and in to keep
i understand technology
his current OK
all right so it's not like you know
and that's his real application here that works really well this is the next but
here running it on the one which means that there would nice
so again
OK so this is insult i just you know read the papers this on his
own for fun and then last year and this was actually and it's an email
saying you know introducing you know what you think so something called
that's true
he said that and so was about not only is OK
so i mean you no disrespect going but
but but it's not like
there is no mystery in there
OK you get this
the centre has
how much i left
they finished six minutes OK good
all right so i think what stops people from using non convex optimisation is just
the right tools in right central tools
all right
a software tools or theoretical tools certainly this surgical tools you know they can missing
but but the other tools aren't
so there is one really cool tool
there are some of us have been you know using four for about twenty years
were fifteen at least called automatic differentiation actually very very simple version of automatic differentiation
so automatic differentiation is this really is there's whole community on this mostly in sort
of numerical methods where you can write a program in fortran and c plus plus
or whatever and automatically spits out the code to compute the derivative of water functions
program computes
and i have to say the best reference on this
recent reference is not the best reference but the the people who really understood is
the best
it's going to take a few years for the community to really can understand what
they're doing but really people understand the best are barak pearlmutter and geoff siskind siskind
whose he actually did they published a paper they actually but this paper in programming
languages programming language on all basically that the whole type system for for automatic differentiation
using on calculus and functional programming and it's completely worked it out and they can
produce really efficient code that is so she can use iterative anything
since recall one insistence that one i implemented for the
system that use for research and all i could also
kind of picked up for storage system and wrongly which used for his mum monty
python systems
is a very simple idea doesn't use any complicated concepts you can implemented in almost
any language
but you have implemented in matlab which is why don't you know
and the is very simple in fact you could probably applies to make although probably
if you have a bunch of modules that sort of computer virus functions and the
pass information to each other in the forms of the former vectors or whatever for
each of the modules you had to write basically two
two functions two methods you want so this could be a class and then we
member functions the two methods
one could probably from does is it takes input to compute the output with the
input by pressing the function one could be proud and what the problem is is
that given the gradient of whatever loss function respectively outputs multiple of the jacobian and
compute the gradient of
whatever doesn't respect input so it's very simple thing to write you can write this
fall into modules you have you know the combinations softmax you know see whatever
and then by
assembling things like this and we have for the past from the probably property rights
new classes you can essentially build any complex function automatically and you don't have to
worry about actually writing code to compute the gradient is automatic
this can it's you know object oriented implementation of ten all right
it's nothing more than that
it would be consistent
so consistent here would mean to say two things
we say that so this taking this this function is consistent if
i have a convergence in probability of
the expected risk of my
optimized function
towards the end
the optimum value of the risk
also if the empirical risk
on this particular and
in probability towards conversion pretty towards also
disc these optimal value of the risk
so what you can see here on this graph when i increase the number of
the size of my sample
i would like that the empirical risk
of the this optimum function goes here and the expected risk also
the empirical risk of this particular functions
is over the training set it's called the training that's exactly what is it
we know that the
training error is by its estimate of the risk
so we have
that because we
you cannot anymore
super separate put it out of the text and so
it's something we zero and that's can be interpreted that
they do saying that the solution found on a particular
and the particular training set it's much better on this training set that in any
of the training set that could fall from from the same distribution
so that's what that means
so we know that
can we at least if we know that it's not by but could we
about this
the difference between
the training error and the six this will which is called the generalisation error which
is the
the expected risk of my of of my name
function over any
in set
on the other side of the training set
so the answer to this is yes we can bound that we can
i found that putting some condition on how we choose our our set
the function of the decision space of the function and this common conditions are related
to the
the notion of capacity
so what is the capacity
the capacity of of a set of functions
is the measure of its size or of its complexity
in the
so for each kind of a set of of function it's it's a it's not
an easy it's not easy to define distance measures and
so for the capacity for example
it is then the largest number h of examples for which there exists for every
a function f from the space which could be used as a perfect classifier so
for giving you an example here
let's say i have i consider
the set of all linear classifiers
two d dimension
if i have
three points
i say a
this one is is of class one and two others are from from class to
i can separate them
if these
on the way trained all the things that i always confined classifier
so it's the largest numbers are of examples so if i have treats OK
let's say had four
and i have this one which are of the class blue and these two of
the class
i cannot find classifier
you you are classified
of this class so the
the capacity of the set of linear our function
two d
is it is tree
because that's what these sentences
and that is more general for this linear functions
in n dimensions which has also have a capacity of empress one so in classification
we can compute the value of this page
integration and density estimation
it becomes more difficult
depending on what is the
what is
the function space
so but there's also way of
of deriving it
having now i have a way to characterize my my
my function space and
there's this risk this bound directed by
by the seventies
looks really ugly but
is you don't the the difference of a
the empirical risk and
the risk
and the
i see that that can be
seen as as saying exactly what we wanted that
the two things we wanted which were
that the empirical risk
tends toward the
there the smallest value
of the
risk on the expected risk of my
my optimum function of the training set also tends towards the
the same value then there was go to the same value
and it also
so the the bound from this bound i can also have
he said
this difference and the
so because here that provides many convergence weight here
which can look when i increase
here what what they have is like a bound of the difference of these two
value depending on the
on the capacity
and so
i can interpret this knowing that this efavorite the capacity i have from one side
the empirical risk
which goes up
and the
all the but here
which goes up
and this the difference
of these two
also the bound on the true ground
goes up and down weights so it's the sum of the two of these two
so what does it mean that
there is one point here
in which
four sent a certain amount of capacity
i have
and my value of my expected risk of my generalization value
in this region
in the status of some sort of islamic constructing goals
some of rules may cover examples from the normal class as well
so basically that's why you have this and phase
when you try basically to eliminate these errors that introduced in this phase basically
all of this point all this
later because of
the text by these rules here
will be eliminated in this phase
basically that's why you did so
this and always gives high accuracy and significant support and you know can be very
results when you're dealing with this kind of imbalance datasets
there is another
approach co-creators also
by my history article from was the minnesota he used there are people dials
which is some form of decision tree
basically in which
every node has a predictive rule associated with this
so this down rules
specialized genetic specialize generic form
of multiphase
you know model so so basically in b and all the model you have two
here basically for every of these
rules you have the the best sources this so there are again two
is growth and pruning
in growth
you basically using this people down to cover most of the positive examples and basically
by doing this he off the training data
and as a result he will get binary tree
each node is
characterized by the rule
the a default class and links to two
that is this is just the implementation and you have to grow this ripple down
structure in a recursive manner
and finally in the second phase
we should approach this the structure in the basically to improve the generalisation it's something
similar how you prune the decision tree in order to
improve the generalization
different people by using different forms of the world
the metrics tool
apply them or intrusion detection software engineering health applications and so on so this all
different types of the things people using them both
all the labels were available and i mean i would not go through
most of this because this just modification of regular networks
you have all these kind of references you can go to and
and because there is nothing significantly introduce here people just supply that was so different
there are class problems and
what is the typical in the common for most of them that they assume that
support labels from normal and of normal is available to them
people also use different forms of support vector classifier
to detect intrusions
the main idea
here is basically that
example this approach based on
the normal data records can belong to high density data regions
while the data from
the data basically that correspond to anomalies correspond to low density
eight regions
and then he used unsupervised approach to to learn high density and low density data
and then here's the standard support vector machines to classify this data that level
another approach
is by
i will come out
he assumed that he has both
labels available normal and abnormal
and he was the support vector machines for the problem of network intrusion detection so
i mean this is your application and not significantly is three is here
other type of
classification techniques for anomaly detection semisupervised to talk about it
basically they use modified classification
the model to represent normal only
and all the years from this norm here are may correspond to anomalies
so people use different approaches
people use
neural networks support vector machines some markov model based approaches which can be extremely good
if you have temporal data and you try to capture the transition between the sequences
and finally have different kind of rule based approaches
so this is
neural network which is called replicator neural network or some people called the oblong your
so the basic idea here is to use this type of
to learn the normal behavior
so you
put your input data here this input layer
and you're trying to reconstruct the input data here at the output layer
some form of this neural network is also used for dimensionality reduction so basically trying
reduce the dimension of these
let's say one hundred space one hundred much space into something small here
and if you are able to reconstruct your input data from this
reduce space so basically if you are able to
the same
data is the data on the input
you good and basically this layer may you may be used as the reduced dimensionality
so the idea here is to measure the
the difference between
output and the input
this is called reconstruction error
and to use this construction our as the
outline this so basically the smaller reconstruction error
that means that
data should correspond to normal behavior
the logical structure of the data respond to so basically in the training phase
you have only normal
data records you best single normal data records of this company let's look at training
this one network
and and then when you done you know took represent islam which pretty well
so now when you go to the testing phase
every data record that you pass through this electric
will behave in two different ways of this is the normal data record it through
here smaller reconstruction error if this is anomalous data record
it will have a huge construction
so that's the basic idea
people also use different forms of one class support vector machines to detect anomalies outline
people use different techniques and what the most common approach is basically to separate the
entire set of training data from the origin
and to find a small region and the most of the data
i mean this in all the different approaches usually you're dealing with
right so that's a high-level statement of if you make a book code that's what
we want some
the vectors over here that are very different from each other
OK now we want to more concrete prescription of how do make a block
we don't have to do book but let's talk about because anyone suggestion of
a way of making a block code and an explicit principle of how a block
code could work
pac that's great who sort of parity checks
so what's the parity check
so we take a source blog
and then the source what we refer to transmit the source bits in the class
and that was transmitted them
we send an extra bit of possibly more than one activity but you said one
experiment that is are some of so you have some source bits and
you take a block of and transmit their
and you also transmit their so here's some possible
things you could have
one one zero one zero one and we could add an extra bit
that is the sum of these
o modulo two one one one is one
one zero is
zero is an even number of ones
one one
zero more than two years after this is a way of getting from k
three minutes two and a four
this is another example
and the block code it happens to have eight possible inputs here so read this
mapping to four bits
this would have a rate of three quarters
OK we've got going the idea of we want to make a long things and
we want to be different from each other and maybe we can use parity checks
i'm not going to tell you one of the first block codes that was invented
it was invented by a guy called
and it's called the seventy four
hamming code
and it looks like this
it's going to map all
seven minutes
and it's going work by
sending the first
sending in the four bits in the clear and then attending another three parity bits
that are made in this sort of way i'm going to show you exactly how
and so we right before frostbitten has one s two s three s four
we call this
t five t six and t seven these of the parity bits which we have
and afterwards and the parity bits are going to be set in such a way
that the number of ones in each circle
is an even
let me give you an example
let's imagine that this
one zero zero zero
that's going to turn into t of length seven
and we do it by writing as the circle
here we go one zero zero zero and now we set the others
eighty six t seven such as the number of ones in this article is even
that means we need one
and then
this page is zero
and here
many to one
OK that was the encoder
here's a few more examples
please talk to neighbour and fill in encodings for those and will have a three
breakthrough to chat about everything has been going on
any questions
let's just checked that we all agree on this
so you transmit zero one one and the right rear one
and one zero
and the fact that one
there there
and this is a list of obviously sixteen possibilities inherent just giving four of them
and this final one one one one one one
one way we could have got this is all of these particular encoding operations were
doing here are linear involved modulo two
in addition which is a linear operation and we could have noticed one thousand and
zero one one them and you get all
so we can add this to this and this
these two codewords added gives you that code
so this is an example of what's called a linear
we don't have to do that is just an example
of one
OK so we send
this transmission over a channel
and something happens
let's and the one for for example let's pretend we didn't know that was what
was sent so will no doubt that actually transmitted
well on
will keep that information secret from ourselves from now on i will say let's imagine
what we receive is less
three flip one bit without telling ourselves
let's imagine we receive one one
zero zero one zero one
and we don't know what was transmitted and now what we do this we need
to invent decoder
what's the general decoding algorithm well we could write bayes theorem enumerate all hypotheses the
sixteen of them
and we can about how probable they are and we know
the most probable hypothesis will be the transmission hypothesis
it involves the smallest number of flips so that's two ways of saying what we
want to look at all sixteen hypotheses find the most probable one of the one
for the season
OK well this is something that
you need to know that is you want
why so
one way
so large your
so what watching paint dry what was really
seventy percent
showed up without knowing it to your
computer viruses
the we can
the same way that almost anywhere in the world
north korea cuba and the first it's you are read
one the closest all the more this is closely
of twelve and we want to
that telephone the most lottery you know several
trying so so the telephone is really really about
one way forward
on the other side
we know that he was late we're changing jacobs your many years she would like
their cities and then
i found that i really keep going
he said there was only space for licence you know in some problems
actually experience the one fringes is broken changing relationship to say
so that experience
it's one of those urban legends i've seen a when i
one of these cruiser that was
this is the environment world we know
from one
you have
many of
messages so although
in fact
among university students my colleague random killing
the most common usage among university students is falling five minutes before it arrived place
most change
all very coarsely face-to-face that you know that was wonderful and i also
do some gossip so this is the place where the goal of the school
it was a somewhat different cultures
so the
o similar to the citizens
you're sixteen year two hundred sixteen were there
notice from the right
so we're always accessible and we want to
and so this needs to be said more about
we can always on
on the basis that what you see here is that this is a
i expect you to know that
reason for the potential
by experience that
we have to go through some of these tools
do you want
the real
what more well known
internet sense to see
the rocky horror show
by right to
get weaker as
the other thing that i wanted has a really interesting
although follow
for all the parents
so this is really doing
if they call it
there's not much
three we to take some stories and its
you know the policies better
roman holiday
great movie
or to separate these she's the princess one
message to garcia of this kind and this is for you
since and that
one of the first america's wars
eighty nine
extensions so see us all and it's going down was going to happen
say something about fifty percent in america is very much you know you're
almost like
kind of get your head around recursion you can look at that and say i
can write a five line function that will solve that problem and this is the
kind of power we're going to give you up with our together so there's a
bunch of really amazing theoretical and algorithmic stuff to explore the that really increases the
things you can do with programming so i'm
first we find it
and as well has always i think the section leading program right that we have
created and for is a huge part of what makes someone a six-course successful and
having somebody who's individually kind of working with few meeting with weekly and giving you
that feedback the individual person personalized for you in helping you get to the response
is a lot of what helps to make the experience very fun and kind very
personal to sell and metal for second like what six to have here
number one was that the section leaders where are they don't
nevertheless i not know when i was going to class the role
i think going to go somewhere else with the wrong will get them
and so
one of the great you agree
well i convinced you are you sure
is anybody still hesitant
something else you worried about that i can tell you is the big deal is
a lot of work to do
just i just exude just osmosis you're
OK i want to know about logistics because
there are some
just random things right that you may want to know about how past works that
the first m supposed to do
one intermediate monday wednesday friday two fifteen three o five in glorious downtown scaling auditorium
it looks like we almost exactly fit classroom which is means were all to be
very friendly and cosy
the lectures are being taped available online and that has the nice side-effect that you
can watch them you can review them later you can watch them lots of time
to write it also means that we're pouring rain you're sitting on your bunny slippers
you could just say hey i'm not going outside you you could turn on your
computer and watch i'm a big fan having common person that's because one lecture in
the room but i also think there's a there's an interaction there i went through
the human human thing that i'm i'm confined and so i hope that you will
make every effort to ten person
as much as you can but it is nice to know that if you do
miss lecture or you
you know
get caught up with something you have a chance to review it later online and
will have sections that will meet once a week just like one six a and
section leader right who meet with you to discuss section is the one the radio
programs and sitting with union the conferences with them
what you need to do to get yourself in this section by section titles and
access and they're just totally bogus so ignore all that what you do is you
go to the online if you are class web page there's a link that
so yes section section on right now but they will go up tomorrow and will
be up for the weekend and you go going you put in your preferences about
what times they understand or not and there's this big
get you get computer program created does the magic matching the gets everybody into section
that fits into their schedule that what happened by early next week
so the the sun up from thirty five to seventy five technically so if you
if by some five years section here you know you've got a set of specs
then find if you happen to change after spending five mechanisms made at that point
it's a little bit harder we can we can make adjustments but it's very case-by-case
basis that where we have space and where we can accommodate is so the best
thing you can do is buy certified have a pretty clear idea what you can
and cannot do i mean always the preferences and then we just pick things that
you know will work no matter what happens if anything it's variable maybe just don't
offer things that you know might go away
so there's a list of you know twenty times and you say all that i
can make these five and that way you will get yourself in trouble on one
that might change
the the workload everybody was was no one much work it's o five class into
five units engineering class
you you get your five units were
i would say so don't don't worry about that i'm not sure changes
we we have a problem is identified what we think there's seven of them across
ten weeks so
you can kind calculated out but we can third for any particular one the students
report that it's you know about fifteen or twenty our project each of them some
people get done less than that simple take a little bit more but i would
say that's kind of the
mode range for what people are reporting i do think that the people who report
last some of those are actually innocent but is very naturally gifted and in one
of the one that has to with your habits about how you work and how
you make progress if you're with the people who feels he might be more likely
to be on the other hand you can come and talk to me and i
can give you some suggestions in particular things like choosing to work in the layer
where the helpers are on duty hatches really positive effects in that when you get
stuck right you easy access to somebody helping you work through it rather than spending
an hour to kind of fighting something that turns it becomes simple but just require
knowing something that you didn't know it although i am a big fan of learning
things yourself there's also times when actually a well placed a bit of advice from
somebody can save a lot of time so
the image and the final exam will be kind of an in class so not
take home open book open notes is actually technically outclassed having night because we need
more than fifty minute period to to get any coverage of that then final exam
schedule university scheduled slot sadly that is very very very and the exam week but
that's when the register put us and that's what we need to go so you
may want to take a look at that before you
head to acapulco
for spring break to make sure you here for example the
i well
you know i have a publisher will not allow me to distribute commercially electronically a
they're not exactly right in the modern age on this so
no i'm i'm working on on it is the truth so that you know by
the time the world's hopefully will have some other strategy but we we currently are
in negotiation let's say but they are not
the nice thing about the course reader is we have not changed in the last
years of you know somebody hasn't from my fall last brains like that it has
some minor edits typos were fixed but so if you can get hold old one
and it's good we are
getting the royalties publishing and production costs so it's actually you know what would have
been a hundred or textbook had been found and you know all snappy now you're