box if
let's make it
him to be simple
not box is p
and i'm going to actually just take the liberty of writing that is
that because you know in negation normal form works
repeatedly apply the usual and all rules together with the following rules to obtain blah
blah blah OK
so if i apply and then roll i'm going to get
fox if p
diamond if p
all i do is i changed the conjunction to ascend that was our andrew
and now
i'm stuck because i don't have any conjunctions and disjunctions so this is the stage
at which i would apply the k rule in the traditional blue
right now the problem is this
if you apply the k rule
you jump to another successor which is arbitrarily far away
but if you have some other formulae we don't have them in this case but
if you have some of the formulae which are of the form next something
then you jumped too far
so what diamond does it says you know jump to some of the tree
which is in the future of i
but if there is some extra stuff lying around here which says i know next
q and next next
not qnx next next q or something like that
you all those behind and you jump directly to here and make p two
and you've gone too far
so what you have to do
is you have to
take care of these guys by using the one stipulation
and this is the way the fixed point comes out that's exactly what these things
are doing so it says if you have
a negated next in just put push it through so this is part of the
next negation
if you have a box
then rewrite it this so we do have box
so i rewrite it as
next box if p
i said OK all i've done is i've taken that box
and we know that is that
taking that box
and we know that is
so this one here i've switched over thank you
because i would have got to the end and wondered why didn't class thank you
would have been able to find out why what else have we got we've got
so we can apply this guy
well let's break this guy down first show it let's that one we know that
it's harmless
now we've got a diamond so
what do i do
i turned it into a disjunction
not p all
diamond if not p
yes no
stop me
now what i got a good disjunction so i can split
again p
he PM just copying things
and now the disjunction goes down here
i copy
but this bit
and this is just comes here
OK now what
current node is now of the form next
for nearly z where z contains only atoms negated atoms and down for a kind
worried about the downfall of supposed to be copying down the formula star but i
can't be bothered because you don't actually need in the procedure
you need to the completeness
this is of the form the next something
and z ways that contains only atoms negated atoms in that
OK now i'm supposed to create a success but there isn't any point because this
is a contradiction right so i'm going to stop that
in reality what the
what the theoretical procedures do is they
keep going right to actually create a successor here
but we want
what about the other side we haven't got a contradiction so now we apply the
next rule what is the next rules say
a plus successor w one containing x in other words
what this is is that your success to make this true success estimate is true
there are diamonds in boxes which talk about for the points
right because i compile them way i use the fixed point
to compile them
the recursive equation to compile the way i compile them down into this
an element of the time
and in that element the thing is actually linear
so so i can do the same
that's the beauty of it
o piecewise linear is good
now let me ask you what's the basis what is in this language what the
what's the basic what
you've given me all the functions at once there
all pieces of suppose the boundary conditions are you have zero equals zero
and you have one equals zero
and suppose i chopped the thing into
one two two three four five l
so that i had really so i really have four degrees of freedom
so in this for you
but now tell me the four basis functions
that you want me to the
OK that's what will stick
he made them look like science and cosine
so maybe one of his
functions will have gone up and then another one will have had an oscillation another
one had to i'm looking for another option
basis for
center for fees
combinations give the
i i would be happy if they were
but i'm more
that's good but i'm the most important is
the calculation should be
so i'm looking may come as simple as you can
and your choice of making look like science and cosines was pretty simple
but let's make it
that's possible that's possible well but OK i could
now let's look some markers is exactly
what you want
more so to enable by animal piece by piece that's the winning idea
the here is one of our function
and then here's the second one
and well they didn't forever
so they do overlap and i don't get that orthogonality
but i decided prepared to live without it for the
for this local
and to be local is is
is it has to be up to date
i mean that's really local stuff that's what you'll see with wavelets to that there
is a local basis so there's one guy
the second guy peaks at point two
the third guy peaks at point three
the fourth skype except point four and their combinations
if any
let me know hope
now that's a court
it's a shift
the true
shift is OK
but if i
if i multiply that by two which is
make it bigger
year if you're you're all this is the right stuff to think about the is
exactly the right if i if i combine this with this
then i can get anybody who does this and then stops
but then i got number three and number four
pick up
it somehow
OK that's one way to see
that these four guys are independent that in fact
the the seas actually have a meaning
the this season the c one the one multiplies this guy is actually the value
of this
the c one
and this is the sea too high
and this is the c three
i have to be negative and this is the c four
you see that the phi
if i take those things so the
these weights
are actually
o point values
which is kinda nice
so all i do now
what i wanna do now that is
i'm limiting myself to this four dimensional space
simple function
and these would be piecewise these would be linear finite elements
and now
is my equation becomes
it determines the seed
right now we've made the big decision of the basis
and those are the basis you mentioned i mean like
you know there other those the bases not
this finite elements
is that choice
well i find it almost don't have to be linear
we could we could imagine
parabola little pieces of parabola are little pieces of cubic
so those will be
quadratic elements cubic element
those are all this highly interested i mean there was like a golden age of
finite element
when everybody was creating
new bases
and of course everybody hoped that his basis would be
you know his name would be like immortal
and a few people probably well
piecewise linear somehow
i guess nobody's name got associated with it that
that the
it's just because it's so simple
come back to that question where are my equations for these
four c
how do i find the best seed
i i can see i've decided okay
i'm only going to allow functions that are combinations of these forces look like that
what's the best way how do i get the best one
so i
i need a cost function OK so what's my cost function
i guess it's
this guy
OK so so one way to do it
like this
in there
and minimize it is a function of four variables i'm back to the beginning of
the last lecture
n is for
you can you imagine doing that
i've decided what these functions are
so those are fixed my trial functions
the ones i'm trying to
what i don't know is the fourier coefficients
so i plug it in
to the
o thing that i'm trying to minimize and i minimize on but i've only got
four variables so i've there
the rayleigh ritz that's associated with the names of rayleigh ritz
galerkin had another idea
galerkin work
with this week form
galerkin and said OK
now i'm looking at this
this of this whole thing and element me put zero in yellow two
we're seeing the whole
weak form
in the yellow
give us the right solution
it's not estimating the right thing but this a small bias
but since we can
prove that
that this stays finite
then since we only comparing algorithms relative to each other in the scale on which
we are doesn't really matter so this means that we can
throughout proof we we know that although it's
biased we can still use it
OK so let me just show you some plots
this uncertainty in the value
the max
deviation from the unit matrix
in all directions
if we
compute take state the TV set of algorithms which is the temporal decorrelation algorithms and
compare the root mean squared error
of the solution
so it's only make make an artificial example so we we actually make an estimate
of of all sources
and measure how good
this estimate is in the root mean squared error sense
and then we plot
against this this uncertainty measure
we hope to be on the line in the dying
because this means that the uncertainty measure that we have constructed ourselves by means of
bootstrap is actually
giving us something like the root mean squared error
and then you see
actually if the blind source separation algorithms that we're using for this bootstrap thing
if it
doing small arrows then this uncertainty measures is a very good approximation
remember this
not using any information about the sources
and this is just
knowing the sources so this really coincides
and this is fun other algorithms and you see
for a particular example
that's making a slightly more complicated artificial example
so let's take
sine and the cosine
some speech signals
white gaussian noise
uniform distributed noise so
in ICA we typically can only deal with one goes noise component
certainly gas in noise doesn't have any temporal information
if we
you know apply some algorithm i mean if we would know this if you just
have a mixture and we apply some algorithm that
it takes high order statistics into account then of course the algorithm that takes high
order statistics into account would be able to distinguish between this one
one of those
these two
and and also these
these guys
the temporal as the time information algorithm would be able to distinguish would be able
to pull this one this one
these couldn't because there is no temporal structure
but in any case all these algorithms would give us some projection directions and we
you know be forced to believe if we wouldn't have means to assess the quality
so what does it look like
so this is now
with jade
and this is the estimated sourcing so you see a sign and the cosine sigma
and they form very same stable subspaces
OK so so this is the the matrix s that i that we had before
on the slides that s was composed of of all these angles
i j
that we have computed also
so so what what does it mean it means that
most of these things are very
you know the
so there are two subspaces one or two that the sine cosine and five and
that's the goal since
i said in the beginning it's impossible to to distinguish between more than one goes
and so with some creativity
they may well have some benefits for helping to improve the performance of search engines
OK i'm going to continue where i left off with logistic regression and so
we're talking about
the probability of a label y
this label y
conditions on the input x
and then we have the parameters alpha
data and the model
is that the logarithm p of one minus p
is linear so it's alpha plus
some of the j
beta j
some useful terminology so p is the probability of the event y and it's probably
y equals one
and then peel one minus p is called the odds
log p of one minus p
it's called the
the log odds so this model says the log odds is linear function and this
is a reasonable function because
the probabilities are bounded between zero and one
so odds then
going to take a value between
zero and positive infinity
and logos take values between negativeinfinity plus infinity and
that's the possible range of values of the linear function and so
it it wouldn't be mathematically coherent to make the probability be linear function of the
and so linear functions of the simplest sort of functions so and so
if we want simplicity want linear function
but then in order to map the range from negative infinity plus infinity to the
range zero to one
then the logo then among
the log odds or the inverse translational logodds is the simplest way of doing that
so this is really the
justification for the money
form of the logistic regression model that it's linear which is the simplest possible and
then with the transformation
something and this
if you have here
the log odds
and this is the zero point
and here you have the probability
which ranges from one to zero then
the log odds of zero
corresponds to a probability of point five
so the point five o point five is one of one is zero and this
function so the driver it's sigmoid shape it along stretched out as shape
it is a monotonic
so p is a monotonic function of logodds and logodds monotonic function of p
and so
the bigger
the bigger the value of this linear function
the bigger the probability
and so
that makes these coefficients interpretable
but you
so xj is the feature
x was thinking of x bar is being
vector of feature values remember
so this is some from j cause one to g
we have expert
is in heart of the d
and there's a very common special case for the features xj which is that they
are binary so effect so if xj causes xj equals one then that's a special
case of xj being a real number
and so
you know if if xj is real valued and baby j is positive
this parameter is saying that everything else being equal
a bigger value for xj
it makes
y equals one more likely
and if xj is binary
and pages positive
baby jay is really the up in the log odds you get from having the
value of the feature xj equals one set of the features exchange was zero and
much notice that
if you're evaluating this linear function
and you have an xj
to which is zero
you don't even need to
you don't need to do any multiplication because you just get something time zero zero
and so
girls incompleteness theorem
and if you don't you'll get some great articles google
there's plenty of lectures given the sort of course since for more details
every semester
i have
taken the trouble with a view of how these things go
on the web and you certainly find me
i recommend that you do that
still for the very detailed treatment and checking whether
as a colleague of mine a teacher of mine
but it if you want to know whether
you know at step seven hundred twenty one
inside this land really follows set step seven twenty
you know you need to go to the table like this have always assumptions clear
and so forth
that's amounts
can i just do some history now
talk about
the the historical background released this is just my sort take
in what was going on in the nineteen thirties so this is now
good luck
but going back even a little further to the turn of the century to the
twentieth century
the nineteen early nineteen hundreds when
as you probably know
a number of philosophers and mathematicians were attempting to
completely embed formerly our arithmetic in his mathematics in psychology
the most famous person ten was initially
it was a good called fraga got fraga
and he'd written a whole lot of work on this which
true to form now i could understand the beginning
simultaneously around the same time anyway
russell bertrand russell
in cambridge
i wrote the a book called cricket mathematica
in which they set out
what i hope to be
a complete
reconstruction of mathematics starting from the axioms of logic just what was effectively first order
and all went well for a very long time until you
probably we all know this kind of story backwards
russell discovered that internally in his system
there were paradoxical conclusions that
the set theory that he
maybe i'll discuss to that the
and here
well make it easy for you for six
well i forget my wiki
really intolerable
he russell discovered this internal
problem russells paradox is called tell frank about no
you in the right
fraga didn't believe it
and all sorts of problems were not so there is a big issue
another issue was over in which in mathematics with
very famous mathematician called hilbert
and hilbert was at the same time
but that that was packed that problem
can say that set theory power from the sort of packed
erica stabilising and work with something else we used to get right you
and hilbert was attempting to prove things left right and centre through what are called
ideal arguments
that is sort of large-scale reductio
if you want to show that some kind of algebra has a certain property
while has a certain particular object in the basis set
vectors for the algebra from the algebra from which you could reconstructed for instance
if you want to do that
cool well invent this construction is also will suppose there is no such thing
and i'll show that whole thing leads to contradictions that whole situation
no we actually build the object
in building mathematics heating exhibit the number
that's that was sort of quite worked tall people so this is on the next
slide here
hilbert along with others have proposed the complete axiomatisation of mathematics
he was
we see whatever myself
the methods the techniques that help used were had this kind of existential nature
i'll show that something doesn't exist so this leads to contradiction so after all must
exist because
the kind of thing seemed contradiction fair enough
but that really did run counter to a lot of mathematicians intuitions
in this particular example here
mathematician called go down
who had
complained about this proof
that a certain sort of algebras had basis
so well that's not mathematics that's just
you know actually building you
constructing something and i guess that constructive
the idea
in mathematics is really inherit from geometry really starts
from the same thing as we all learned in school
let's see what we can do for a given the triangle let's take the triangle
and the lines that he lines out there
let's compare angles where constructing
so that sort of stuff my
a lot of sense to london the moving into this existential round didn't seem right
proposed that
we might try and get around this
you can see the criticism
it wasn't much moved by he said
well maybe you are trying to prove something like this
well point happens in these things
suppose there is some property phi
that i can prove in my ideal role
OK what you guys are worried about is that might not be provable in the
real world the real world of constructive finitistic methods mathematics
so what about i prove
super theorem around
this says
but everything i can prove my ideal existential approach is going to work in the
real world
in the real world
as you call
and this was proposed quite seriously it was a big program work
i spend a lot of time trying to classify what the real role was going
to make it very very small
k very simple
so the result would be correspondingly more exciting and strong
this was the context of all the work that we're about to talk about
the next part of this little these next few slides i
somehow failed to put in my little proof that
just use of the network generates something like twenty five about
one of them is possible for is actually responsible for
doing all this stuff we talked about before cleaning and all the good stuff dealing
with service don't respond all the
parcels of pragmatic
and then produces
targeting abilities produces insights into our users of these products have approved products which products
to invest in which stipulates
it's really a legal right it's it's
it's the space
typically use commercial databases because they don't scale you have to
build your own
optimized for that purpose
so it's pretty impressive challenge actually and i learned a lot from it
so that you use
i would like to
the four numbers numbers changed much
the distributions of the same internet sixteen percent but this is when you ask people
spend their time
online analysis is a bit about
the business side of the channel
that's roughly
in today's numbers about sixteen seventy percent of the time on internet
so the time is on
traditional media remember ten years ago there was
so the number was still
a lot of time spent things like newspapers magazines and TV shrinking in favor of
you ask another question which right
business of this which is this is what meant
well the advertisers dollars
and you know it is there is a very this can
i even though
hispanic something like six percent sixteen percent of the time on the internet in numbers
only about ten percent of the dollars go online
so this ship it's going to happen
it's it's
enough to
right advertisers who spending time
and eventually
you know without any of the online companies doing anything that mark is going to
i mean it
as we decided to get
the power of interactive media
that slice of the pie would actually grow
much more dramatic meeting people actually spend more time
and i believe internet will actually take more
index j
of advertising dollars why
because i give you some examples
but it's
in my opinion is one of the most powerful
marketing vehicles
because it does a lot more than others and now it's not
you always have to advertising
but what i'm trying to explain to you is that people have in the market
is really understood
how useful the internet can how to
so starting out i think about the internet business i started
asking somebody
naive questions like
what the advertisers what it so a simplified case
it is you for the top we all awareness which is when you
so that's just to make somebody where the company exists you have a problem
and the final is sort of the robot
i purchased you get consumers actually selected products
over the years continued to
now i think i
as a lot about this business especially
it's definitely in
has business about a billion dollar business problems
which is a graphical
those are designed to create awareness talk about
we also have a significant business
which is almost a million dollars
at the bottom
which is more direct marketing
that's the search advertising
by the way businesses in the US alone are over two hundred million that actually
marketing is over two hundred fifty billion just in the US
and on line of that money is only about
ten billion
so what
ten is about over two hundred million in the US brand advertising
that that's
it's the second all over the place
in the middle
well as marketers
so what
thank you
you established awareness but they didn't like
so that's called consideration
so is that the consumer spends most of the time
so was yes
said OK so what do we do with consumers into consideration phase
when i go
was blanked
don't actually have any solutions for people who are into consideration is which if you
think about it
is the majority
of the time
the majority of the
of your own life time spent in the middle of the middle of
imagine that this hopefully this time
the evolution of of life
this strategy and how we can become drive business
mister to start saying well if that's the most rich areas
one the working on ways
o two
and convince them to move up the
give you an example of that
finally go to market only think about convince them to move lower final into this
which in my opinion is going to make
well i'm not much much larger even
anybody that so all the
all of which it is not
and new ideas
so five minutes talking about data
and that's
he is
and after about
just interested in general some observations about the site
i mean that much
is getting a hell of a lot of tension
marketing dollars
microsoft has a search product if you know
search product most of you don't know
who has the search product is probably the only
that has the search problem
what about
because of its unique in one sense to me
and somebody has to find something that is right that interact
and when you something for for that moment in time i actually have a lnstitute
because they have a glimpse intent
i can manage to use
at about ten to hundred times that
that if i were to just do genetic sort of reaching out the math one
ten two hundred times better understand about two orders of magnitude
that difference
a lot
companies like ours
into the k
so for the ones that i for one for the ones that are equal to
to zero are not one minus and the then this is
the number of ways in which you can choose
OK among
and you have to some that
all the cases
o which
there are enough one
two by piece
i mean you can
prior to re write it down but
this is exactly
summing over all the cases for which this is true
looking at all possible number of ones in the sequence of zeros and ones
and actually i mean this is not necessarily easy to work with
and you can add values of bounds on this quantity
one of them being have been
again looking at the case zero one side of these being minus eight that they
had in the
but better than having you can have what is called bernstein's inequality
we're actually occurs in the in the same between
all of them
including this one and thing is that have been does not take into account
the probability that the losses is
zero one
it does not take into account the
this is one for any possible value of p and actually
the this kind of deviation is reached when is the worst which is one half
that's the worst case
but then when he is is dependent on how we can have better bounds
including this one standing which has
this key one minus factor
he one minus p turns out to be the violence of bernoulli random variables is
the variance of
these guys
we enter
these inequalities whereas does not enter here
bennett is another version of a slightly more refined version of
and you have also this exponential which is
yet another version and they are kind of
decreasing order of sharks so this one is the best because that's inequality this one
is slightly worse likely were slightly worse
even worse
you have exactly the words
it's a bit more work
this kind of thing if we look at these for example that we see that
there is here and here he is the size of the deviation
and we said before we have of gaussians kind of behavior
four things right where it the minus the squared kind of thing
here we see that
twenty small we need of the gaussians behaviour
when t is large then these terms
and then we have e to the minus
instead of into the minus the square which is much more but right much more
i mean decrease to zero much more slowly than e to the minus the square
we have the gumption behaviour
for small deviations multi
and these guys can deviation as corresponding virus you one be
and the light division we have actually what is called this last year
we have this e to the minus t
independent on the the the violence now he does not enter here anymore
so the terms are heavier than go
of course we can provide both cases
with the with the gumption was largely financed by this increase the the size of
the currently we can enclose what is but that bit
and this
how it looks
it's easy to see but within the next bout
these are the actual values of these are
computed with this some formula
and then you are all these about
the binomial
so for the binomial it this one that's the exact value than we
then bernstein green
well they are more-or-less equivalent
and this is for the worst case people
o point five
o point q or
for the worst case p
well the
you know most of them are
the same so i have these OK
so if you look at the case
even painter
if we look at the most cases like people is point one then
easy to see but
this is still
the exact values
and then
what is this
this one
you been which is
the subculture here
so that's
so i think the worst but then the other one and two because they take
into account the violence
they two
the closer to the actual values
and that's for the
kind of
small values of the deviation and if we look at the larger values we we
zoom in these
this week we're going to talk about cardiovascular physiology and the
cardiovascular system which includes the blood the blood vessels
and the heart
we're gonna
focus on several features this is obviously
a big topic not only understanding the basic
the physiology of the cardiovascular system but what can fail on the cardiovascular system in
disease and cause cardiovascular disease is the number one or two cause of death
in the western world and so it's it's a serious and important topic for medicine
and it's also something that i realised you probably all know something about
and so we're going to try to look at things in a slightly different way
to look at them the way that engineer biomedical engineer might look at the cardiovascular
system to try to understand the relationships in particular between pressure
blood pressure which is the force that moves blood around the circulatory system and flow
the actual movement of blood which is what's essential for distributing oxygen and nutrients and
everything else that we know that we that we move around in our circulatory system
so i'm going to talk briefly about the anatomy of the heart and circulatory system
will start by thinking about the whole
i'm going to talk in some detail about about how
differences generate flow in starting with a very simple
and building up to some of the complexity that we have within our cardiovascular systems
and one of the most amazing things about the cardiovascular system is its ability
to change
the pattern of blood flow
such that organs that need more blood can get more blood
it's not just that there is a static system where blood is flowing throughout the
body and flows at the same rate everywhere all the time it increases in one
region decreases another in response to physiological medium we'll talk about that sort of engineering
that the that the cardiovascular system uses to accomplish that
and then the next week we'll talk about what will talk in some detail this
thursday about how the heart generates the pressure is needed to move the blood and
how you can create this flow with the relatively simple
but durable machine the heart
and the next tuesday will talk about
cardiac conduction electrophysiology how the how the heart regulates its it's beating in order to
generate orderly pattern of pressure
a generation
so this is a cartoon of the cardiovascular system not showing the blood except by
the colors here but showing the heart in the centre of this diagram is the
and surrounding it is sort of a schematic diagram like you might see for plumbing
in in house but certainly not in anatomical detail this drawing isn't of how blood
flows from the heart
to all the other regions of the body
and let's just now i know that you that you that you've seen diagrams like
this before you understand the basic connections between things but let's just go through them
briefly and you have to start somewhere because this is a sick it's it's a
closed system right started one point and you go around and you come back to
the beginning and end and so
if we start
in the
in this side of the heart
this is the left side of the heart
and there are two chambers on the left side of the heart the adrian
and the ventricles
and you see the blood flows into the left side of the heart is coming
from the lungs the blood has come from the lungs and so it's full of
oxygen and this diagram is indicated is red and if you follow the arrows
here the blood flows from the lungs into the left adrian
into the left ventricle
and out
through a large vessel called the order
because so a fairly simple
so far two chambers in the heart blood flows through these two chambers
first then ventricle
and out
through the aorta so if i was able to measure flow
at this point here in the order
i would measure the total
the rate of flow of blood out of the heart
this is linear algebra r
lecture nine
and this is a key lecturer this is where we
get these ideas of
linear independence when a bunch of actors are independent
or dependent that's the opposite
of the space they span
a basis for subspace
the basis for a vector space that's the central idea
the dimension of that subspace
this is the day that those words get assigned clear meanings
and emphasise that we talk about
a bunch of actors being independent
i wouldn't talk about matrix being independent a bunch of actors being independent a bunch
of vectors spanning the space a bunch of actors
being a basis
and the dimension
is some number
OK so what are the definitions can i begin with the fact
a highly important fact that
i didn't
call directly attention to
suppose i have a matrix
i look at a x equals zero
suppose the matrix has a lot of columns
so that
and is bigger than and so i'm looking at an equations
i'm sorry and equations a small number of equations and
and more unknowns i have more unknowns than equations
let me write that down more unknowns than equation
unknown axes
then equations
then the conclusion is that
there's something in the null space of a
what other than just the zero vector
the conclusion is are some non-zero
so a x is zero there are some special solutions and why we know why
i mean it's sort of like seems like a reasonable thing
more unknowns than equations
then it seems reasonable that we can solve them but we have a clear algorithm
which starts with the system and does elimination
gets the thing into an echelon form
with some
and pivot columns
and possibly some free columns i don't have pivots and the point is here there
will be some three columns the reason so the reason is
there must be there will be
three variables
a least one
that's the reason
we we now have the complete
algorithm complete systematic way to say OK we take this is the matrix equals zero
we roll reduce
we identify the free variables and since there are n variables
and at most m pivot
there will be
some free variables at least one at least n minus and in fact left over
and those variables i can assign
non-zero values two
i don't have to set those zero i can take them to be one or
whatever i like
and then i can solve for the pivot variables
so that gives me this is the solution to a single zero
and it's the solution that isn't all zeros
crew that
the important point that will use now
in this
so now i want to say what does it mean
for a bunch of vectors to be independent OK
so this is like
the background that we know
now i want to speak about independence
let's see
i can give you the
the the
abstract definition i will
but i would also like to give you
the direct meaning when
the question is when
x two up to support i am n vectors
now i have to give you
or linearly independent
i'll all often just say
and right independent for short
if OK
let me give you the full definition these are the vectors in some vector space
i can take combinations of them
the question is
do any combinations gives zero
if some combination of those factors gives the zero vector
other than the combination of all zeros
then they are dependent
they're independent if no
the zero vector
and then i have all have to put in an example
combination so what do i mean by that
no combination gives the zero vector any combination c one x one plus the two
x two class one class c and x and
is not zero
except for the zero combination this is when all
the city's
all this these are
then of course
so so pivots means not zero whereas if I had only see this 1
continue mentally
heavily for me just what we were doing this so that's 1 of the pivotal
B 3
well the 1st derivatives of 1
and then what's the 2nd pivot for B 3 also
apart faster you're giving the want OK the 2nd parameter that once and I believe
the 3rd pivot is a 1 also
that ensure that because the product of the pivot is that determinant
that the way you refuse to talk about this and the determine element in the
right place now I'm looking here is what I show is where sorry yeah the
benefits are 1
and 1 and 1 3rd rate goes down I just believe right and I'll come
what is the pivotal this when the do these pivots all correctly 1 of the
pivot for that matrix as well as you said 1 and then 1 and then
0 which I don't accept
so I think I'll so the parents are well I never figured out how to
try to do the pivots are 1 and 1 and I'm willing to write 0
what can I put
will just a blank or something OK because I don't know I will call that's
OK and now what can we do the payments for this 1
well we can start anyway what's what's the 1st
to and what's the 2nd pivot
3 halves
well we didn't here
we got the 3 halves here and actually
this matrix starts the same way
so and when you're finally the pivots if you know if you're looking for the
2nd have all you need to know is that part of the 2nd derivative is
3 halves and actually the next experiment will turn out to be 4 thirds and
the next 10 but after that would be 5 4 and 6 and so on
have the fond of playing with these matrices between now and next
the cell templates are 204 this 3 by 3 the parameter 2 and 3 halves
and then the next 1 will be 4 thirds
I want to have mentioned where in the book
you might look for some some of so we so today's lecture is
most closely connected to section 1 . 2 in the applied maths but but
really what I guess I'm saying is you might look at some of these exercises
in that section as sort of additional questions about it this this time OK
so we have the idea of elimination
I wanna say 1 more thing about elimination
that we got from the matrix
to the upper triangular 1 there was no problem
0 but then
I wanna get there with matrices
related cut the
the can't I mean if we have a large problem I can't like
list all the pivoting operations they want to fit information probably some matrix which we're
multiplying this by
to get
so that it can can you tell me what that so I want say OK
that was much too much riding on that 1
and just go from the made from 1 matrix to the other and not worry
about all about keeping up with the right hand side Matlab deals with the right
hand side later
so I'm going from this matrix and what I want to do is multiplied by
a suitable matrix
that produces the answer leaves the 1st row unchanged
tell me what the 1st row of this matrix out of the
if you I want to
multiply this is my
elimination matrix you could say this is my matrix that that does the step that
carried out in
what does well rather priorities you can already tell me what the 1st row has
to be
and it's
1 0 that takes 1 of that role 0 that rose
what OK now what about the 2nd
OK the 2nd row was what did what did we do to get the new
2nd rows of the new 2nd row with 0 3 had
what what did we do
we took half of the 1st role
bless all of the 2nd row
so this is iYou're are elementary
will produce
that's OK
that's we're saying we're seeing at these were saying elimination carried out by military
I but the the beautiful place the beautiful way to describe it is that
what that over on the other side
and have k equal something
so what I'm
what I'm
saying here is that the key ideas of linear algebra
so this is not solved part
can tell you linear algebra hearing impairment in that small space
a slow but don't tell anybody it's so simple right and so the key idea
of elimination so everything you do in linear algebra
all the big operations elimination is the first one Gram Schmidt
orthogonalization of vectors is another 1 eigen values is another 1 the singular value decomposition
of the big 4
and each of those is described by
factorization as k equals breaking came down into a product of special
and I'm going to speak for the moment about the elimination
and the usual way the elimination is as l times
lower triangular times upper triangular let's get let's do that
so can we get to that did you see what's we have the k
and we have the
what 1 has isn't ready here is that I've got the on this side and
I wanna move over to be an L
on that side is that alright so so I'm just going to take that and
this is very intriguing because again the only difference was the fact this was the
the other thing that we found is just this is qualitatively different sense of the
emotional relationship that people have with the robot people would name the robot is examples
of the names of people give to the robot
they were close happens starts with personalized and it turns out that we can pick
up the robot a lot of people come out to the car and say goodbye
to the robot
they did not do this with the computer
so again this is something very evocative going on here
so the last little bit then i want to talk about is totally another related
the robots just as a communication medium in the cell can grow by being intriguing
way to help people
communicate mediated
the robot
so why is it interesting what we know if you look at human human face
to face interaction the body place a profound role
in being able to make eye contact touch partial changes sharing this with
all of these things that we don't get the result we don't get to scrap
don't give you any other kind communication technologies that we have today
you get ask maybe with these teleconferencing system that you don't get out you really
don't get good eye contact so really robot because of body in your space
could potentially really be the next best thing
two really being is intriguing to think about robots themselves as communication medium
and i think one very intriguing idea
is to really think about robots as potentially a distance learning technology
especially for very young
children so
we know there increasing data showing that
it's critical for the learning in the first five years of age to prepare children
for kindergarten and so forth and that if you start kindergarten behind you tend to
stay behind so in some sense you can imagine anyone so distracted takes improving our
our student product at the end of the twelfth grade be to improve the product
going into kindergarten so really starting think deeply about how my technologies play a role
in early childhood education i think is really critical really interesting and i think robots
have a very special role because if you think of the way that young children
learn so children five years of age and maybe around five they might be willing
to abide the computer but not necessarily want to spend hours sitting behind a computer
children even younger than that
i mean they learn from physical presence social interaction social scaffolding and that's the main
i have three young children four years and younger i know the fact that there's
a lot of time as a lot of icon there's a lot of sources covers
a lot of interaction how children learn and i think robots can be very tricky
technology by which an adult could essentially jack into a robot to provide the same
kinds of learning interactions the bring into children who would necessarily how those interactions otherwise
or to you know to to tell the second language so there's a whole bunch
of things i think we can look at
so why robot will again
we're designing a robot over here you can see the huggable
it looks like a q teddy bear
really it's very sophisticated robots twenty cameras in the i microphones and here's speaker in
the mouth of full-body sensitive skin is being developed to the robot consensus being tickled
had touched insofar as inertial measurement units the the revenues has been carried down there's
a computer inside of wireless communication
and there's a degrees of freedom for expression through gesture facial expression as well be
able to share attention so again trying to make this is this is socially situated
at communication technology as possible and again the core ideas through the internet from anywhere
in the world potentially an adult can go through a web interface to jack into
that's with
child that you can share story together you could play together you can do language
when you get do many many different kinds of activities so again really about bringing
people together mediated through
a robot so i want to do another demonstration living dangerously today we try to
live demo
i really do that
i have gone
i today
we can only be people
all right so we have a little bit of
the people of interface
so this is what you can see here that the yellow box is the field
of view
like from the video camera behind the ball in the box basically work
alan you the operator can use to direct the gaze of the robot as drive
box around this time he was in the there to be able to track the
object to eye contact to look at the attention of objects that you want to
you also have the virtual model of the
here that's running out if you want to be
able to be here
the one
but i was working
OK so you can see the interface here
and i don't know if they have not been able to use the head
one that
all right then i want to give up some information
there is an animation so as an operating in about a lot of different gestures
and expressions
with the remaining place themselves
OK as a sort of the notion of expressive sounds as well
so this is currently in in development energy you want to show the wearable
interface you can to control the there
so as
we're going on with our definitions
return summarize a lot of these
definitions into an notation
chemical location that will be very important
so for instance
if i'm talking about
three moles of hydrogen
and one bar hundred degrees celsius
i'm not going to write
given three moles of hydrogen and one part three
but what i'm going to write it in
compact notation you write like this three moles of hydrogen
which is same
one bar
one of the results
this notation gives you everything you need to know about the system
how do the number of moles
tells the phase
it tells you what kind of molecule it is
and gives you two
you could have
if i am on the temperature you have violent pressure
this tells you everything
i don't need to write it out in words
and then if i want to
tell you about a change of state or make this let's first of mixture
suppose that i want to to that
to give you an extra life
this is a homogeneous system with two components like
five moles of h two which is a liquid
one bar
twenty five degrees celsius us
five more c h
link where one bar
twenty five degrees celsius
after this describes roughly something that
is fairly common commonplace it's hard to provide
half water and half ethanol
that describes
the macroscopic systems
you're missing out purity so will flavor molecules are going to
but basically that's that's the home and homogeneity
describe two component homogeneous
then you can do all sorts of predictive
and stuff with that
all right
festival sequences and now we want to show
the notation how do we go from one equilibrium state light
this describes to another equilibrium states
so we take our tricolor basically just put equal sign
people signed means
so go from one to the other sort of talk
three models of our three moles of hydrogen
richard s
five are
and one hundred degrees celsius
and which is nice problem is they so i'm not going to change something new
you can do
an expansion that's
all right we can drop the pressure vines you go up
i don't need to tell you the volume here because
you've got enough information to tackle ryan
number remorse stays is the same
the closest
as doesn't come out
those against another pressures is less temperature is less than some sort of expansion on
one equilibrium state to another equal signs
go from this data that
it's not a chemical reaction where we don't have an hour
because we could go back to this
back and forth between
connected this means they are connected
when i put this i have to tell you how they are connected to tell
you that i had
going to solve the problem for instance you want to know how much energy is
going to get out from doing
this expansion
how much energy you out
and how far you're going to be able to drive the car with this expansion
so i'm going to tell you
how you doing the expansion
because that's going to tell you how much energy you're wasting
during that expansion was back to the second law
nothing is efficient you're always wasting energy into heat somewhere when you do
the change involves mechanical change
all right side to tell you the pattern
and i go from one state to the other
and the pattern is going to be the sequence intermediate states going from the initial
state final state
so for instance if i draw graphs
of pressure on one axis
and temperature axes
my initial state
is that the temperature of a degrees
and five bar
that will be used in the
the pattern discovery
what is important is that there is a constraint OK these descriptors are exactly this
subset of these descriptors
or can belong to the set of this we can define the with the background
knowledge so
they can they can belong to do to this difference
the but
knowledge is defined as the tool
link with there's some
no on the believe it is provided by gets for example for example in close
relation and the case that agent original relation between two objects is made to order
for reflexivity properties close to exceed say on x y x y indicates that close
to y axis just before symmetry
what i am looking in this case we deal with the is a hierarchy of
needs to moment and can define the following code i could be specifying going to
happen and the set of all
the child of these little evidence on which is the syntax we to represent the
i ching
OK so there are threshold can be defined the that that they found for example
in the case of the decision rules are treating the support and confidence of the
traditional school in this case we have the name of the parameters that to uconn
went to specify the keywords threshold and the idea that is associated to these
fish crucial to
are there are some i would to require some sort of bias in the hypothesis
space and in this case we can use some specific critique networks to explore these
spaces so we can specify a preference christina and so minimize maximize income and minimize
the number of an example money money maximizes one and so on and it's possible
to specify the value some tolerance as in this case
OK for an example of what are we we use it is the system is
the math but to
we have to install it in the system and is a mark of a part
of that is so its surrounding being elephant even from tree and OK the effrontery
is the parties crossing the south so the silent out of blue
the blob in this image or in this case the
task to allocate is too low an operational definition of the concept of landscape that
one to landscape as recognised as a sign that is characterized by these are
landscape that associated with the presence of the valley and the valleys these OK i
can learn to operational future for this concept then they can use these operational definition
to query newmark in this case the expert acidic recognised this allows positive examples of
landscape y and we say that to some other examples that are negative
some other sizes are negative examples for these specific
concept and this is the key to have formulated in this case we select on
the side of the market the nineteenth of of the month and we intend to
mine classification we did this battery morphological and so for the class landscape quite to
same we use these descriptors for generating the discrete description of all the cell cell
actin and can specify this script the same descriptors so that should be used in
the mining step in the first example we have and background knowledge and the defence
secretary will be was that they are specified you are in this case the mining
is performed with the operating system
while especially
but it's a relation that can be extracted from one
the data in its and so the
here the extension to their actual line triangulation it is most but i must be
equal to the distance and so on through
we are seeing with descriptors so we can specify the set of character that should
be effectively used in the mining sector and in this case that in this way
so the
average velocity
during this for second trip
it's zero
you may not like that
it may go against intuition
of course
i couldn't agree more issues but that's the way we define velocity
speed is defined differently speed is the magnitude of the velocity vector
and the speed therefore always has a positive value and i'll show you know what
is the average speed
zero and four
that is the distance that it has trebled in these four seconds
but first goal for the first second it goes from policy six two plus three
so it already travels
three metres
then in the second second it goes from plus three to minus three so we
one hundred six meters
and then in the thirty seconds
it's lazy it doesn't do anything so
the distance traveled is zero
and then in the last one second gets very active
and it travels nine metres
note issues OEC plus signs here and all minus signs it would make no sense
and this
cos in four seconds
so that is
four and a half
meters per second for the average speed is four and a half meters per second
but the average velocity
is zero
we could now
make a plot
of the
as a function of time
let me put here
four and a half
but i just have enough room here
to make the velocity plot
as a function of time
making new ones
this is my time axis
and this
the velocity
one second
two second
three seconds
four seconds
this velocity is in meters
per second
i go up here
plus ten
minus five
use minus six
so what do i do now i know that the
velocity during the first second
minus sixteen
for linear
and so the during the first second
this is the
as a function of time it started zero you can see that
and when it is here it has the velocity of minus six meters
the second
during the second
second it remains minus six meters per second
during the second second
the velocity is not changing
it stays there
during the third second
the velocity
john all of a sudden two zero you see how non-physical
so all of a sudden during the thirty seconds it becomes zero
it has to somehow connection of course between the two to make the physical
so in a very small amount of time that will have to occur
that's why you get a huge acceleration at that point
she also get an acceleration here at this point because there's also change in velocity
and then during the four seconds
the velocities plus nine meters per second
and so we jump up
it is
and so
we have here
during the last second
and again this is not physical
it has to be somehow
the transition
so here you see
the velocity as a function of time
now comes an interesting question
is it possible
so if i gave you this
but this is a given
you can see that
could you convert this back to that
and the answer is yes
but i tell you what the position is
t zero at t equals zero
and that is sufficient for you
to use this information
kind of idea this afternoon in my lecture but
the idea is very simple start off again with the set of all hypotheses and
while there is more than one viable hypotheses you select that just any
unlabelled feature for query but the one that's going to be in some sense maximally
maximally informative so what if are my hypotheses again our plus one minus one valued
by trying to find an exit minimizes the absolute value of the sum of all
the hypotheses responses if that's if the value of this this absolute sum is zero
means half saying
plus one after a minus one and so that would eliminate the largest fraction at
each time
find query for which is the most disagreement among current hypotheses aquarium at that point
and then again you just reduce the hypothesis space so this is just a bit
more aggressive than the callout for them in that callista taking any
query for example that there was some disagreement on this our trying to pick the
one where there's this maximal disagreement
and there's quite a bit you can say about this type of algorithm talk about
that afternoon
OK so just a little bit about what some flavours of active learning and analysis
there's many different ways you might vision using this one is query synthesis where you
can actually construct
desire queries or questions to this would be one one case here would be suppose
you could design experimental conditions to see what happens if i set various variables in
my experiment to some value what's the response that the outcome of experiment so in
many cases like that we can actually designed queries
pool based active learning would be a situation where you have a whole
a large collection of unlabelled examples and you can
selectively picked examples from that pool for labeling and stream based approaches are what i
was talking about a moment ago with
OK now we monitor stream of unlabelled examples as they come along and if you
find unlabelled example at some point the uncertainty your request label otherwise i'll skip over
it just wait for another more uncertain case
and then there are
ways of trying to
quantify how many unlabeled examples are queries you're going to need i'm not going to
say too much about this but from the query learning literature there's something known as
extended teaching dimension which is sort of a combinatorial parameter that relates the hypothesis query
space there's no notion of the disagreement coefficient which which measures the growth of the
region of disagreement this region in feature space where the hypothesis are disagreeing and then
there's the neighbourly condition which is more geometric relationship between the feature space in the
hypothesis space which i'll talk about this afternoon
so what if there is noise mismatch or just a couple things and that first
of all if there's no is how become noise tolerant there are
a number of ways of approaching this i'm just going to talk about a few
generic lines one way to deal with noise is to come up with service stochastic
notion of the version space and here we would consider all hypotheses that could be
explained by just noise alone so you can imagine i have a bunch of hypotheses
and after selecting some data may maybe none of them are perfect but some of
them could be explained away just by
random noise like here's another is really couldn't be
explain that way they're just more systematically wrong
the second kind of approach would be repeated squaring maybe you could run the procedure
like an hour this generalized binary search and every time you make query you just
repeat that same query a number of times until you're very sure
of what the correct label should be in that case and then finally there are
ways of serving waiting your hypotheses as in accordance with how well they predicted on
the features and examples you've seen so far and to put more weight on the
ones that seem to be performing better unless we don't others and that's that's sort
a more gentle way of
of handling this kind of idea for stochastic version space
so that's noise and we'll talk a lot about some of the
the next part is about specific examples of how to deal with that another issue
is this
the fact that active learning is greedy
and it can be a bit myopic and converge to
things missed things overlook things and so forth so what do you do
particularly if h stars ninety eight so that class of all the hypotheses are concerned
so when we had do to make this point so
active learning
he is using your idea
and the structure of your space of hypotheses in order to guide how it's like
samples so they can discriminate among the hypotheses are entertaining if you start off with
the wrong with the model is incorrect suppose you're assuming a linear separator type of
classifiers hyperplane classifier but the actual decision boundaries much more complicated you could actually end
up staring yourself in in very bad direction and converging to a suboptimal
linear separator even though there is
presumably some linear separator which is the best among all linear separators so how do
you avoid this issue this is what's called agnostic active learning so if h stars
not in the collection of hypotheses are considering making new least guarantee performance equal to
that of passive learning and there are a lot of
different ways you might achieve this i'm is going to have suggested one this
relatively simple and in general the idea would be to split your sample budget into
three parts one third of the data you would use some active learning modes serve
aggressive way of collecting information
is another thirty totally passively so you get two
hypothesis one from the aggressive active procedure one from the underground non-aggressive passive procedure and
then use the final third of your samples to discriminate among those to see which
of these two is better by just sampling in the region of disagreement between those
two hypotheses and you can show that procedure like this will tend to give you
the performance
of active learning that serve enhanced performance whenever it star is in
the hypothesis that you're considering but it will sort of if it's that's not the
case still do at least as well as passive learning to some constants and so
forth and so that's one way you can make things agnostic just kind of hybrid
of passive and active learning
OK so let me i've talked about
the classification problem we just say that again let me give you a sense of
some of the other settings where we can use active research question
this is one
well so so so so the question is how exactly do you divide the sample
budget let me and let me kind of try to answer the questions
number two
as a user talk
take the raw
injected into a mouse
what happens
let's about
because these are invariant
it's just do some simple controls
let's take this move bacteria
auto claims
keep them up to very high temperature to kill them
how do we know they're dead
the great triplet mapping growing more that there there that so take he killed and
you can verify in the lab that they're killed he killed smooth
checked that that they really were killed inject them into the mouse and what happens
the because i mean the bacteria i
last of all
we take the utterly harmless rock
the utterly harmless
he killed smooth bacteria
we inject them into the mouse
what happens
it dies
that is result
because the rough bacterial life killed this mouth
this the bacteria that have been he killed
well not kill this mouse
but together
they killed mass
this is very puzzled
what was even more puzzling
it was when you autopsy the mouse
you can isolate from the mouse
smooth virulent live
but you didn't put any
very strange
so this actually yields
smooth sailin bacteria
despite not having put me in there
during on bacteria somehow
we were able to create
smooth and very one bacteria not notwithstanding
now having put any in
so of course
then attempted to say
well what was it
that allow this to happen so you could try putting in dandruff bacteria with dead
smooth bacteria that doesn't do anything he does something alive together
live rough bacteria you could then say let me take that the dead
virulent bacteria and storefront shading it biochemical e
and asking what fraction
all of that material from the dead bacteria allows us to
to have this property of being able to now
produce real bacteria to kill mites and just how utterly tedious and painful experiment is
you take the dead bacteria
you fractionated into lots of different biochemical fractions for each fraction had to test whether
has the property
that should have about of mice
this is a very tedious procedure i mean it's it is it's you know you
can understand how important the as a is how how important it is to come
up with easy ways to do things in order to be able to accelerate progress
griffiths tried hard and roughly began to purify fractions and get information about what the
fractions were but in fact this work really never did lead to a clear conclusion
that to tell people that there was some material which got named the transforming principle
this is almost like an old alchemical kind of word a principle being a and
and a particular chemical
composition of matter what you don't know tissue called a principal living principles to make
up so what was the transforming principle
well it really took
work about fifteen years later by a mccarty in mccloud
to sort this out
when every mccarty mccloud
it was the same experiment basically
except minus the mice
what they found was
you could take
dead bacteria
combining the dead very on back the dead smooth bacteria
combine it with the
live ralf bacteria
by combining it in the right way in the test tube
you would be able to play it out on the patch reply and sees smooth
understanding the data are placed in this
the sensation of the ontology
OK i'm actually here we can make use of the link is not on that
applications are not industrial not that the solution but
thing solutions OK
and in general we know a lot of things already even in the con to
so few that because of the first thing that we know is that the pig
alley we can not
i assumed to be able to
the main
o in relation to the two sounds
and let me the some concept last year
this is considered obsolete due to poor it's considered to be very nice
and actually
what little shown is that we need to rely essentially on queen is that we
make and the sources so we can not
mathematically content there's also concept in the global view but we have to
queen over the sources two things in the long run
OK in that you
in provides us with a
by these kinds of mappings OK by this kind of mappings
mapping where we have a query over the sources that these maps
two one element of the ontology
this is the most kind most used kind of mapping in that integration
then there are also other things for example we map one relation in the source
to a query over the ontology became very nice and elegant mathematical tool
OK however in practice is of no use
as we see here in a moment of the data that no one you have
been the sources are either
OK so these are operational databases these are not clean things OK to clean things
up here
not here
it's so
this is the kind of idealised work
and in fact what you can do maybe it's to make the two of them
in a being a query over the sources
in marked with three over ontology is the most sophisticated kind of mapping has been
one important thing
we are dealing with incomplete information OK even in in standard thinking of that i
integration we are dealing with incomplete information and this is good news for us because
for incomplete information they are being to deal with incomplete information are particularly
a good in doing this
on the other hand this means that the way we do pretty answering of system
to make this we have to compute the answer key is going just say
actually computing connection
as we have seen can be very costly
OK computer set that all the ontology can be very costly
and so that's why we are going to use like a like a the language
for the ontology OK so so as to reduce the cost of its OK so
to make it happen feasible
so the solution that we all we are proposing here in the following we think
the sources we've them and presented as relational sources insist on the technology
we take all these multiple sources
OK we use if it is shown
to see them the single relational database OK
this is also standard technology and what we do
we make use of the allied to describe the domain in the ontology over here
and in this way we are able to exploit effectiveness of query answering for if
you live in particular we exploit the
the complexity low complexity but also we exploit the fact that we can do the
right thing in not only shape
relational queries OK
SQL queries to
these that federation tool
so this is the basic idea
we don't
not doing something missing steel
and the point is that even if this is now a
can be seen as a single database is still extant in independent from the ontology
OK it's all we need to really look at them up so how are we
the data from the sources and see them as instances in the ontology this is
the critical problem OK
properties of this optimisation problem
it was the first case it easy point p of five zero
if on the other hand
it's the point which satisfies this inequality
the if i can be non-zero
so the point appears in the expansion of the solution
and in this case the point is called support vectors
so just to be completely clear the support vectors
the points that
lie exactly on this line
where this quantity here takes the modulus one
and those who
you can have non zero five
they don't have to but usually they do
and i would support the
and and
the nice thing about having this expansion of the solution is that you can then
plug in this thing here into our form of the decision function so remember the
decision function is similar to
well actually the decision function simply say
i have to take this function here wx plus b and check whether positive or
negative so i decided i want to say plus one this i want to see
minus one so i take the sign of this
function here
and then
i plug in my
the support vector expansion assigned of this function like in w
gives me this equation here again i'm using the fact that the products are linear
and the nice thing about this is that
now with reduced it to the dot product between
training and test points
so this is something
now we can do in the feature space if we want to win we have
methods for computing this
not only based on the input points but also based on points living in
dimensional feature space
so this is the solution
i'm actually going to skip this one
and i continue and substitute
these two equations
they got by taking the derivatives with respect to the primal variables
these equations into the like one function
and i can eliminate the primal variables
and after a little bit of algebra
and that's again i would recommend this as a little exercise
not now
but maybe
in the break of time
six maybe ten minutes it's
straightforward it's just a little bit to be if you're not used to doing
such calculations you have to think about it but the
it is straightforward calculation so you substitute these things
and then you will find that the result depends on the i five so remember
is said we have to
minimize with respect to primal variables maximize with respect to do there was no we
eliminate the primal variables
so all that's left is the function of the dual variables that we have to
maximize with respect to these two variables
and it's so nice function here it's a quadratic programming
by which i mean something that depends on
five quadratically linearly
so here we have the quadratic parts
and again the nice thing is this quadratic part
the only thing that depends on the data points
and it only depends on the data points through dot product
again this is something
we can do in terms of functions
now we have both the decision function
the function that we actually to maximize in order to find the coefficients of the
decision function
expressed in dot products so we can use the kernel we can use everything that
we've learned yesterday
OK now we are just so beta to go to zero
so we just let beta be set equal to one of a number of
and just like in again
OK what you see here is essentially
except these terms here so what you see here is essentially out roles optimisation objective
when you minimize the subjective essentially minimizing this barrier function
and at the same time peter
also decreases because these these first go to infinity
so this is the connection between minimizing the exponential and solving the linear programme
so essentially adaboost role
barrier optimisation technique in order to solve the linear programme
other questions for that
this is the last slide protection
everything q
OK so then for the next part
so this part is about extensions and applications
more talk more about the application the the extension is not so much about applications
and of course there's also the relation of posting with support vector machines i mean
you've seen posting somehow maximizes the margin and support vector machines also maximize margins might
ask what is really the exact relationship
good so let me remind you
support vector machines solve this optimisation problem so there's a bit simplified i removed the
bias and are able to soft margin OK
so it right they try to find w so not norm of the hyperplane that
classifies essentially all points correctly with a margin of at least one
i mean with the distance of at least one
so we can reformulate this optimisation problems maybe somehow
replace this one with role
OK and then picks the one norm and two norm of w to one
OK so he simply say OK so we don't want to minimize the number of
w thinks the norm of w but on the other hand the big then we
cannot have one here we have to have very here and then we maximize this
very so this is actually equivalent if i think music equivalent if role is greater
equal greater than zero
and this is the equivalent
OK let's say this is in d dimensional space
and i'm using the style j of x and here is this is just adjacent
to mention so i just want to write this
so in boosting the try to find this a linear combination of hypotheses OK
and essentially boasting adaboost on TV and so on the basis of this optimisation problem
so it looks very very similar so also maximize margin here we also have this
form here
it's just instead of the pi j we just have hj
and the other is marked here so and here we have not the two norm
equal to one we just have the one on equal to one
and the dimensionality of the space is equal to the number of hypotheses
OK so
boosting the the user pages space which is generated by the hypothesis space and support
vector machines we just use a feature space which is generated by by the kernel
very similar everything is everything is a
but even more explicit so
essentially for any hypothesis that we can generate the feature mapping pi
just the this definition what we can even generator can also given the hypothesis space
we could generate suggested by taking the sky park and that the feature space
can explicitly defined it
OK i guess that should be pretty clear
and also like from from the kernel we could in principle if if you know
if you would know the feature map phi
then you could extract the the future i mean the the base process it
just projecting one-dimensional
so in support vector machines we have the two norm
so that's the euclidean distance
so we try to maximize the distance of the points to the hyperplane with the
two norm
in support in boosting the use it if we constrain the one that is equivalent
to maximizing the l infinity distances so and so when use the one norm here
plus the q norm suckitude i'm sorry that's for the
constrained so let's say you're constraining with the q norm you maximizing the
p not became the PAQ was really like this
so we'll see table three we have the infinity norm that infinity distance is maximized
given that
so you've also seen the bounds which have been derived for support vector machines boosting
also they look very much similar so this is the risk of the so empirical
all this expected risk of the function that empirical risk and then we have this
bound here also in terms of
OK that's margin
and boosting we have the empirical margin risk and then we have very similar formulation
so in both cases is independent of the them
dimensionality of the space
OK one more important thing
so what's called the machines seen the represented here
so that tells you that the optimal w
the optimal way vector to live in the span of of all the examples
and then the corresponding
operation is going to be just multiplication of of these two matrices right this is
what's going to happen if you first let x one xn you in the next
two years
this is of course
this compound operation is of course
the group element x two times x y
and that has the corresponding matrix growth two
x y
so the fundamental thing that these matrices are going to have to
o baby by virtue of being associated with the group is
this multiplicative property that grew x ten times for x one because really
x two x one
one way to look at it is that the matrices really kind of model the
and so you have a group which is the abstract mathematical objects it has the
multiplication law
one way to make it more
concrete is to associate with each group element the simplest type of mathematical object you
can think of
that can capture non commutativity
and the that type of object matrices so this is just way of bringing groups
down to to each group element i associate matrix that behaves the same way as
the group elements to this is exactly what the representation is
the representation is a mapping from the group two
the set of the by the complex matrices
obeying this fundamental multiplicative
so for example if you do this for the
quaternion group
you get out the famous dirac matrices
which dirac introduced in the late nineteen twenties to model the states of spin one-half
particles such as electrons
again a mathematician sees structure and the question you asked is what are the kind
of fundamental types of structured so here i told you that each group can have
you can think of many possible representations what are the really fundamental types of representations
one thing that you notice pretty fast
is that if you take any representations zero two
and the conjugated by matrix and that's cheap way of getting a new representation for
so if i give you one representation
then you can get this whole sequence of representations i just by conjugation by matrices
and that sort of doesn't count since direct representations which are related by such as
similarity transformations are called equivalent
another way to get more complicated representations from simpler ones it's just take the that
direct sum
so this is what is happening here two representations are one and two and
and putting them in this block diagonal form but i get out obviously obeys the
same multiplicative relations so
o itself representation even if i can't if i conjugated by matrix t
in this case through is called irreducible representation is clearly not fundamentally that it breaks
apart into some of these smaller representations
what's going to be important to us are complete sets of an equivalent irreducible representations
so there is some amount of freedom in choosing this usually because
you know you you defining these irreducible representations modulo this equivalence relationship so each equivalence
class you can choose which representative you want which representation you want to
you want to take
but mathematicians spend a lot of time describing
complete system the african continent irreducible representations for particular groups is itself often the major
task and we see that the that it's important to
to solve this task because because there
many things that we're going to do in the future depend on taking individual elements
from such set
i'm not going to
are not going to to explain why this is the case but it often proves
to be convenient to use unitary representations
where the inverse
so the representation matrix corresponding to the inverse of an element is just the
the commission conjugate of the matrix corresponding to the element itself
so in the following i will also will always assume that are particular set of
interconnected we saw representations consists of such unitary representations
the fundamental theorem very early on in representation theory representation theory is that you can
do this sort of
reduction into irreducible was four
any representation
and the reduction is going to be unique of course up to the ordering of
the of individual terms in the decomposition
so if i give you a general representation of a group then
you can reduce it into some
from your favourite set of an equivalent irreducible representations
and you can essentially only do it one way
asking how representation introduces into some other disabilities a well-defined questions
the final trick that we need from representation theory has to do with taking direct
product of representations so that's another way in which you can get more complicated representations
from simpler ones and it's easy to see that if you take two representations and
just take the kronecker product of direct product and then what you get is
also representation but usually it's not
so you ask how does that reduce into a sum of irreducible
well there is some sequence of irreducible is that
you get out and also
some matrices here which affect the right transformation
so this is called the collapse gordon series and these matrices clapped recorded
matrices and this is the famous problem in representation theory kind of right at the
beginning when you start exploring the representations of a given group
which is often surprisingly hard
the physicists will be familiar with the club's one coefficients of rotation groups and